<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 07:56:35 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>9 critically injured in suspected kitchen gas blast in Chattogram</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/9-critically-injured-in-suspected-kitchen-gas-blast-in-chattogram</link><description>Nine people, including a child, have been critically injured in a suspected gas explosion at a residential building in Chattogram’s Halishahar.
The incident occurred early on Monday morning at Halima Manzil in Block H of Halishahar, where accumulated gas in a kitchen on the third floor of a</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 05:21:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Man, son among four killed in clash between rival groups in Narail</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/man-son-among-four-killed-in-clash-between-rival-groups-in-narail</link><description>Four people, including a man and his son, have been killed in a clash stemming from a long-running turf war between rival factions in Narail Sadar Upazila.
The incident occurred around 5 am on Monday in Barakula village under Singasholpur Union, said Oli Mia, chief (OC) of Narail Sadar Police Stat</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 05:36:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tajul removed, Aminul Islam named new ICT chief prosecutor</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tajul-removed-aminul-islam-named-new-ict-chief-prosecutor</link><description>The government has cancelled the appointment of Mohammad Tajul Islam as chief prosecutor of the International Crimes Tribunal (ICT) and appointed Advocate Aminul Islam in his place.
The Ministry of Law, Justice and Parliamentary Affairs issued a notification in this regard on Monday (February 23)</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 05:51:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jubo Dal leader stabbed in Chuadanga</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jubo-dal-leader-stabbed-in-chuadanga</link><description>A local leader of Jubo Dal, BNP’s youth wing, was stabbed allegedly by some Awami League supporters near a mosque at Iswarchandrapur village in Darshana upazila on Sunday night.
The injured is Ripon Hossain, 45, a leader of Darshana Municipality unit of Jubo Dal and son of late Mannan of Isw</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 05:51:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt appoints full-time administrators to six city corporations</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-appoints-full-time-administrators-to-six-city-corporations</link><description>The government has appointed full-time administrators to six City Corporations including Dhaka North and Dhaka South until new corporations are formed.
The Local Government Division (LGD) under the Local Government and Rural Development and Cooperatives Ministry issued a notification regarding the</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 06:06:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gold prices rise again, 22-carat hits Tk 261,040 per bhori</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/gold-prices-rise-again-22-carat-hits-tk-261040-per-bhori</link><description>Gold prices have been raised again in the domestic market, with the rate of 22-carat gold increasing by Tk 2,216 per bhori (11.664 grams), pushing the new price to Tk 261,040 per bhori.
The price hike follows an increase in the cost of pure gold in the local market. The new rates will come into ef</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 06:21:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Lt Gen Mushfiqur Rahman takes charge as PSO of Armed Forces Division</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/lt-gen-mushfiqur-rahman-takes-charge-as-pso-of-armed-forces-division</link><description>Lieutenant General Mir Mushfiqur Rahman on Monday assumed charge as the Principal Staff Officer (PSO) of the Armed Forces Division (AFD) as Prime Minister Tarique Rahman adorned him with the Lieutenant General rank badge. 
Chief of Army Staff General Waker-Uz-Zaman, Chief of Naval Staff Admir</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 06:36:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>18 dead as bus plunges into river in Nepal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/18-dead-as-bus-plunges-into-river-in-nepal</link><description>Eighteen people, including a foreigner, were killed when a passenger bus en route to Kathmandu from Pokhara plunged into the Trishuli River in central Nepal's Dhading district early Monday, according to local administration.
The bus, reportedly with 45 on board, fell off the highway into the river</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 06:51:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Four of a family burned in Hazaribagh ‘gas leak’ fire</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/four-of-a-family-burned-in-hazaribagh-gas-leak-fire</link><description>Four members of a family, including a woman and a child, were burned when a fire broke out, apparently from a gas leak at their rented house in the Hazaribagh area early Monday.
The victims are Sheikh Roman, 35, his wife Pinky Akter, 32, their three-year-old son Mayan, and Roman's brother-in-law A</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 07:11:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Stocks rise in early trade</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/stocks-rise-in-early-trade</link><description>Trading at the country’s two bourses advanced in early hours on Monday, the second working day of the week, with major indices posting notable gains amid increased investor participation.
The benchmark DSEX of the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) rose 61 points in the first half of the session.
T</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 07:26:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>PM attends office at Armed Forces Division for first time</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/pm-attends-office-at-armed-forces-division-for-first-time</link><description>Prime Minister Tarique Rahman on Monday attended his office at the Armed Forces Division in Dhaka Cantonment for the first time.
The Prime Minister arrived at his office at 9am, where he was received by the chiefs of the three services, said his Additional Press Secretary Atikur Rahman Rumon.
He</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 07:41:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mexican military kills cartel boss 'El Mencho' in US-backed raid</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/mexican-military-kills-cartel-boss-el-mencho-in-us-backed-raid</link><description>One of Mexico's most notorious drug lords, Nemesio Oseguera, or "El Mencho," was killed in a military raid on Sunday, sparking widespread retaliatory violence.
President Claudia Sheinbaum has been under mounting pressure from Washington to intensify her offensive against drug cartels blamed for pr</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 07:56:35 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>