<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 23:22:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Forex reserves hit three-year high as December remittances cross $3.0 billion mark</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/forex-reserves-hit-three-year-high-as-december-remittances-cross-30-billion-mark</link><description>Bangladesh’s foreign exchange reserves have surged to the $33 billion mark, reaching a three-year high, bolstered by a massive influx of remittances and strategic dollar purchases by the central bank.
According to the latest data from the Bangladesh Bank, expatriate Bangladeshis sent $3.04 b</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 16:15:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tasnim Jara declares assets worth Tk 19 lakh, annual income Tk 7 lakh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tasnim-jara-declares-assets-worth-tk-19-lakh-annual-income-tk-7-lakh</link><description>Tasnim Jara, the independent candidate for Dhaka-9 constituency, has assets worth some Tk 19.14 lakh and her annual income is Tk 7.14 lakh, according to the affidavit she submitted to the Election Commission ahead of the 13th National Parliament election.
The affidavit shows that she is not a dual</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 16:30:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>World begins to bid goodbye to 2025</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/world-begins-to-bid-goodbye-to-2025-with-fireworks-and-icy-plunges</link><description>As Wednesday turned to Thursday, people around the world said goodbye to a sometimes challenging 2025 and expressed hopes for the new year to come.
Midnight arrived first on the islands closest to the International Date Line in the Pacific Ocean, including Kiritimati (Christmas Island), Tonga and</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 16:45:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Longtime caregiver Fatema’s family grief-stricken over Khaleda Zia’s death</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/longtime-caregiver-fatemas-family-grief-stricken-over-khaleda-zias-death</link><description>Fatema, longtime caregiver of BNP Chairperson and former Prime Minister Begum Khaleda Zia, and her family are grief-stricken following the leader’s death.
Since 2010, Fatema has been devoted to serving Begum Zia, even accompanying her to prison when required. Her father, Rafizul Mia, said th</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 17:00:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Macroeconomic management matters</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/macroeconomic-management-matters</link><description>The danger of macroeconomic mismanagement was aptly highlighted by Paul Krugman (1994) and William Easterly (2001), who cautioned that inefficient resource allocation can undermine the gains from openness and investment, leading to economic stagnation even amid high levels of public spending.
Soun</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 17:15:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Small traders deserve a simpler tax system</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/small-traders-deserve-a-simpler-tax-system</link><description>Bangladesh’s tax-to-GDP ratio has stayed low for years, which limits the country’s ability to invest in roads, healthcare, schools, and other public services. While most discussions focus on big corporations and wealthy individuals, the majority of tax avoiders are actually small shop o</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 17:30:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Restoring investor confidence biggest challenge ahead</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/restoring-investor-confidence-biggest-challenge-ahead</link><description>As a new year dawns, an economic post-mortem of the bygone year reflects a story of resilience, reform and recalibration. While public expectations were sky-high at the outset of the interim government, the economy failed to stage a decisive turnaround over the past one and a half years. Neverthele</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 17:45:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Developing a multimodal communications system</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/developing-a-multimodal-communications-system</link><description>A baseline study carried out recently finds that Tk 3.0 trillion was spent on railways, roads and bridges to develop the country's communications system in the past 15 years without achieving the desired results. According to a report published in this newspaper on Tuesday last under the National I</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 18:00:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khaleda's passing leaves irreplaceable void: Modi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/khaledas-passing-leaves-irreplaceable-void-but-her-vision-legacy-will-endure-modi</link><description>Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi has said that Begum Khaleda Zia’s passing has created an irreplaceable void, but her vision and legacy will endure.
"I am confident that her ideals will be carried forward under your able leadership of the Bangladesh Nationalist Party, and will continue to</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 18:15:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat-e-Islami open to unity government after February vote</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jamaat-e-islami-open-to-unity-government-after-february-vote</link><description>A once-banned Bangladeshi Islamist party, poised for its strongest electoral showing in February's parliamentary vote, is open to joining a unity government and has held talks with several parties, its chief told Reuters on Wednesday.
Opinion polls suggest that Jamaat-e-Islami will finish a close</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 18:30:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Russia's Putin, in New Year address, voices confidence in victory in Ukraine</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/russias-putin-in-new-year-address-voices-confidence-in-victory-in-ukraine</link><description>Russian President Vladimir Putin used his annual televised New Year's address to rally his troops fighting in Ukraine, saying he believed in them and in victory in a war that he has framed as part of an existential struggle with the West.
US President Donald Trump is trying to broker an end to the</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 18:45:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pray for mother: Tarique</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/pray-for-mother-tarique</link><description>Tarique Rahman, acting chairperson of Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) on Wednesday appealed to all to pray for his mother and former prime minister of Bangladesh Begum Khaleda Zia.



While attending the Namaz-e-Janaza of the party chairperson at the South Plaza of the Jatiya Sangsad, Tari</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 19:00:46 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>