<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 11:37:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Gaza father hopes reopening of medical corridor can save his injured son</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/gaza-father-hopes-reopening-of-medical-corridor-can-save-his-injured-son</link><description>The father of 18-year-old Hassan who says his son was shot in the head over two months ago in Gaza while out seeking food hopes that the reopening of the Rafah border point will save him.
"The Rafah crossing is our lifeline, for patients and for the Gaza Strip," Ibrahim Qlob told Reuters in Nass</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 09:07:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>RMG factory catches fire at Chattogram EPZ</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rmg-factory-catches-fire-at-chattogram-epz</link><description>A fire broke out at a factory at Chattogram Export Processing Zone (CEPZ) in Chattogram district on Thursday.
The fire broke out on the 6th and 5th floors of an eight-story garment factory named 'Adams Caps and Textile Limited' around 2 pm and spread soon, said deputy director of Chattogram Fire S</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 09:22:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Landmines that sparked Thai-Cambodia clash were likely newly-laid, experts say</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/landmines-that-sparked-thai-cambodia-clash-were-likely-newly-laid-experts-say</link><description>The condition of the PMN-2s in the visuals taken by the Thai military and Reuters indicates they had been in the ground for no longer than a few months, said U.K.-based independent expert Andrew Vian Smith.
There are tell-tale signs on older PMN-2s, Smith said: their pliant plastic casing becomes</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 09:37:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rubel Aziz appointed as New Vice Chairman of City Bank</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/rubel-aziz-appointed-as-new-vice-chairman-of-city-bank</link><description>Rubel Aziz has been appointed as the New Vice Chairman of the City Bank.
He is a renewed industrialist and entrepreneur. He holds a Bachelor of Business Administration degree from the UK, according to a press release.
Aziz has been in business for a long time now, fulfilling a humble role in the</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 09:52:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Emirates offers Premium Economy cabin on Dubai-Bangkok route</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/emirates-offers-premium-economy-cabin-on-dubai-bangkok-route</link><description>Emirates has unveiled its highly acclaimed Premium Economy Cabin on flights EK376/377 between Dubai and Bangkok, operated by its newly retrofitted A380 aircraft.
With the deployment of Emirates' newly retrofitted A380 to Bangkok, the airline extends its Premium Economy experience to over 70 cities</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 10:07:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Lutfey Siddiqi meets US Special Envoy Sergio Gor</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/lutfey-siddiqi-meets-us-special-envoy-sergio-gor-in-washington-dc</link><description>Chief Adviser’s Special Envoy Lutfey Siddiqi held a high-level meeting with US Special Envoy for South and Central Asia and the US Ambassador-designate to India Sergio Gor at his office in the West Wing of the White House in Washington, DC.
Special Envoy Lutfey Siddiqi expressed gratitude fo</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 10:37:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>RUCSU voting ends, counting underway</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rucsu-voting-ends-counting-underway</link><description>The vote counting in the Rajshahi University Central Students’ Union (RUCSU) election began on Thursday afternoon after the long-awaited polling ended amid a peaceful manner.
Official results are expected to be announced within 15 to 17 hours of the election, according to election officials.</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 10:52:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>FSCD forms 7-member committee to probe Mirpur fire</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fscd-forms-7-member-committee-to-probe-mirpur-fire</link><description>The Fire Service and Civil Defence (FSCD) on Thursday formed a seven-member investigation team to probe into Tuesday’s devastating fire in a garments factory and chemical warehouse at Shialbari in capital’s Mirpur area.
Director (operations and maintenance) of the fire service Lieutena</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 11:07:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>3 Bangladeshi nationals ‘beaten to death’ along Habiganj border</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/3-bangladeshi-nationals-beaten-to-death-along-habiganj-border</link><description>Three Bangladeshi nationals were beaten to death reportedly by Indian nationals in Tripura state of India on Thursday.
The deceased were identified as Pandit Mia, 30, son of Kana Mia; Sajal Mia, 50, son of Kuddus Mia; and Jewel Mia, 32, son of Asrab Ullah, all residents of Chunarughat upazila in H</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 11:37:48 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>