<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 04:25:32 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Earthquake leaves dozen dead, scores injured</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/earthquake-leaves-dozen-dead-scores-injured</link><description>Buildings rocked massively and residents made panic exit in Dhaka and nearby as a major earthquake shook Bangladesh on Friday morning that left around a dozen people dead and scores injured.
A large number of buildings in the crammed capital city, Dhaka, developed cracks or tilted, sending down de</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 18:50:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Most megaprojects, high-rises skip insurance</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/most-megaprojects-high-rises-skip-insurance</link><description>Bangladesh's major cities see rapid expansion of mega-infrastructures and high-rise developments but sans insurance coverage against earthquake damage, insurance executives say and experts make wake-up call over the latest tremor destruction.
They point out that key public projects, including the</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 02:37:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka at High Risk of Major Quakes: Immediate large-scale actions a must, stress experts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dhaka-at-high-risk-of-major-quakes-immediate-large-scale-actions-a-must-stress-experts</link><description>Experts on Friday warned that Dhaka remained at a high risk of a major earthquake, given the city's historical seismic records.
They urged immediate large-scale actions and precautionary measures to minimise potential devastating losses.
A 5.7-magnitude earthquake, with its epicentre only 13 kilo</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 02:52:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Agent Banking Expands: Deposits, loans up 20.6pc, 19.6pc in September</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/agent-banking-expands-deposits-loans-up-206pc-196pc-in-september</link><description>Bangladesh's agent-banking sector continued to expand steadily in terms of deposits, loans, and transactions, as of September 2025, driven largely by strong rural participation and a rebound in urban activity.
Deposits rose 20.6 per cent year-on-year, reaching over Tk 471.96 billion in that month,</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 03:07:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Energy ministry evaluating two foreign proposals</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/energy-ministry-evaluating-two-foreign-proposals</link><description>CHATTOGRAM, Nov 21: The energy ministry now seeks to appoint an operations and maintenance (O&amp;amp;M) contractor on a G2G basis instead of the Open Tender Method (OTM) for operating the Single Point Mooring (SPM) with double pipeline.
And to this effect, the ministry is now evaluating two foreign propo</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 02:24:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Technical textiles, machinery expos begin in Germany on April 21</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/technical-textiles-machinery-expos-begin-in-germany-on-april-21</link><description>The Techtextil and Texprocess-2026, one of leading technical textiles and machinery exhibitions, will kick off on April 21 next year in Frankfurt, Germany creating an opportunity for value-added garment producers including Bangladesh.
With changes in global demand toward specialised, high-performa</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 02:39:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>SOTSUKON: Redefining partnership and protecting children in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/analysis/sotsukon-redefining-partnership-and-protecting-children-in-bangladesh</link><description>Imagine a couple in their late 50s in a tranquil neighbourhood of Dhaka, let's call them Rina and Kamal. They have successfully raised their children, who are now pursuing careers abroad. For twenty-five years, their lives revolved around shared meals, school runs, and managing a household. Now, wi</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 02:54:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Vegetable, potato prices rise amid 'supply shortage'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/vegetable-potato-prices-rise-amid-supply-shortage</link><description>Prices of vegetables and potatoes have increased in the city markets within a week, while onion prices have remained stuck at their previous high.
Prices of almost all winter vegetables that have declined to a satisfactory level, have again increased within just a week, putting consumers in troubl</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 03:09:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>SHED proposes 53pc allocation cut in RADP</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/shed-proposes-53pc-allocation-cut-in-radp</link><description>The Secondary and Higher Education Division (SHED) has proposed a sharp contraction of its Annual Development Programme (ADP) for FY26, seeking to cut Tk 72.22 billion - more than 53 per cent of its current ADP allocation.
It recently submitted a revised ADP (RADP) proposal of Tk 64.03 billion to</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 03:24:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>RU Press Club holds 40th anniv</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ru-press-club-holds-40th-anniv</link><description>The Rajshahi University (RU) Press Club celebrated its 40th anniversary on Thursday through colourful and day-long programmes.
At 9:30am, RU Vice-Chancellor (VC) Prof Dr Saleh Hasan Naqib inaugurated the anniversary events though cutting a cake at the Press Club office. A vibrant procession then p</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 03:39:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>WEEKLY MARKET REVIEW: Bargain buying snaps three-week market downturn</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/weekly-market-review-bargain-buying-snaps-three-week-market-downturn</link><description>The benchmark equity index rebounded this week, paring more than half of the sharp losses suffered in the previous week and snapping a three-week losing streak, as bargain hunters showed renewed buying interest in beaten-down stocks.
Analysts noted that the market showed signs of recovery momentum</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 03:54:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Eastern Lubricants sees 74pc surge in profit</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/eastern-lubricants-sees-74pc-surge-in-profit</link><description>Eastern Lubricants Blenders saw its profit jump 74 per cent year-on-year to Tk 68.53 million for FY'25, driven by higher sales of base oil and a significant boost in non-operating income.
The state-run company's earnings per share (EPS) for FY'25 stood at Tk 43.18, up from Tk 24.82 in the previous</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 04:09:13 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>