<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 10:27:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>46 Bangladeshis arrested in Malaysia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/46-bangladeshis-arrested-in-malaysia</link><description>Malaysia’s Immigration Department on Wednesday detained 46 Bangladeshi nationals, aged between 18 and 43, in a major operation at an iron factory at Nilai city of Negeri Sembilan state.
During the operation, authorities checked the documents of 117 foreign nationals. Of them, 46 Bangladeshis</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 06:48:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>483 die, 1,317 injured in road accidents in November</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/483-die-1317-injured-in-road-accidents-in-november</link><description>As many as 483 people, including 64 women and 71 children, were killed and 1,317 others injured in 534 road accidents across the country in November, according to a report of the Road Safety Foundation (RSF).
Like October, Dhaka division recorded the highest number of accidents at 141, resulting i</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 07:03:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Apex Footwear holds Annual Sales Conference, honours top performers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/apex-footwear-holds-annual-sales-conference-honours-top-performers</link><description>Apex Footwear Limited on Tuesday held its Annual Sales Conference at the Samajik Convention Center in Ashulia, Dhaka, bringing together around 1,500 employees from across the country for a day-long programme.
The conference opened with a tribute to the company's late Founder Chairman, Syed Manzur</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 07:18:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rajshahi farmer killed by excavator</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rajshahi-farmer-killed-by-excavator</link><description>A group of locals in Rajshahi’s Mohonpur Upazila have allegedly killed a farmer by running him over with an excavator as he blocked them from digging a pond illegally.
The deceased, 25-year-old Zubayer Ali, was the son of Rafiz Uddin from Boro Palsha village.
The incident occurred in Boro P</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 07:33:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DSE launches Help Desk to improve investor information services</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/dse-launches-help-desk-to-improve-investor-information-services</link><description>The Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) launched an Information Help Desk on Thursday, aiming to make capital market-related information more accessible and effective for investors and other stakeholders.
The help desk was formally inaugurated by DSE Managing Director (acting) Mohammad Asadur Rahman at the</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 07:48:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Grameen Bank office in Feni set on fire</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/grameen-bank-office-in-feni-set-on-fire</link><description>Miscreants set fire to the Shorshadi Bazar branch of Grameen Bank in Feni Sadar early Thursday, damaging motorcycles and furniture inside the bank premises.
According to bank officials, the attackers poured petrol from outside the main gate and set the building on fire late at night. Three motorcy</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 08:03:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khaleda able to receive treatment, condition unchanged</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/khaleda-able-to-receive-treatment-condition-stable</link><description>Former prime minister and BNP chairperson Khaleda Zia is now able to receive medical treatment, and her condition remains stable, her personal physician and BNP Standing Committee member Professor Dr AZM Zahid Hossain said on Thursday.
He shared the update during a briefing in front of the hospita</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 09:05:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cumilla bus services suspended as owners enforce strike</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/cumilla-bus-services-suspended-as-owners-enforce-strike</link><description>Bus services from three terminals in Cumilla city remained suspended on Thursday as the Cumilla Bus Owners Association enforced a strike to press home their demands, causing severe inconvenience to passengers.
No buses have left the Jangalia, Shasangacha and Chakbazar bus terminals since morning,</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 09:20:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh’s economy moving towards stability: BB Governor</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladeshs-economy-moving-towards-stability-bb-governor</link><description>Bangladesh Bank Governor Dr Ahsan H Mansur today (Thursday) said the country has successfully navigated a difficult economic phase and is now moving steadily towards stability, backed by strong macroeconomic fundamentals and wide-ranging reforms in the banking sector.
Speaking at a seminar on &amp;ldq</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 09:35:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh to call back Mustafizur for key ODIs amid his IPL tenure</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/bangladesh-to-call-back-mustafizur-for-key-odis-amid-his-ipl-tenure</link><description>Bangladesh pace bowler Mustafizur Rahman will return home for eight days during the Indian Premier League to play a limited-overs series against New Zealand.
Mustafizur was signed by Kolkata for 92 million rupees at the IPL auction, the highest price ever paid for a Bangladeshi player.
However, h</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 09:50:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Subrata Bain’s daughter Bithi remanded for 5 days</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/subrata-bains-daughter-bithi-remanded-for-5-days</link><description>A Dhaka court has remanded Khadija Yasmin Bithi, daughter of top criminal Subrata Bain, to police custody for questioning in the murder case of Jubo Dal leader Arif for five days.
Dhaka Metropolitan Magistrate Sarah Farzana Haque issued the order following a hearing on Thursday, bdnews24.com repor</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 10:05:32 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>