<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 12:39:47 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Tongi cotton warehouse fire under control after 1.5 hours</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tongi-cotton-warehouse-fire-under-control-after-15-hours</link><description>Emergency workers have taken control of a fire that broke out at a cotton warehouse in Gazipur's Tongi.
The fire reportedly broke out at 11:45am on Saturday. Seven firefighting units from Tongi, Uttara and Gazipur subsequently rushed to the tin-roofed warehouse and doused the flames around 1:30p</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 09:10:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shammo 'killed while trying to stop drug dealers from selling marijuana' at Suhrawardy Udyan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/shammo-killed-while-trying-to-stop-drug-dealers-from-selling-marijuana-at-suhrawardy-udyan</link><description>Six months after the fatal stabbing of Dhaka University student SM Shahriar Alam Shammo, investigators have found drug peddlers responsible for the killing.
In its chargesheet over the incident, police said Shammo, a leader of the Jatiyatabadi Chhatra Dal, and his friends were attacked by drug dea</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 09:25:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump says no US government official will attend G20 summit in South Africa</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/trump-says-no-us-government-official-will-attend-g20-summit-in-south-africa</link><description>President Donald Trump said on Friday that no US government official would attend the Group of 20 summit in South Africa later this month, because of what he said were "human rights abuses" taking place in the country.
South Africa's foreign ministry described the decision as "regrettable" and rep</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 09:57:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ADB to organize Business Opportunities Seminar on Nov 12</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/adb-to-organize-business-opportunities-seminar-on-nov-12</link><description>The Asian Development Bank (ADB) will organize a Business Opportunities Seminar (BOS) on November 12, 2025, at the Bangladesh China Friendship Conference Center (BCFCC) in the capital.
The BOS will be held in Dhaka with active support from the Economic Relations Division (ERD) in collaboration wit</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 10:12:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Attorney General seeks political parties' pledge for formulating anti-discrimination act</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/attorney-general-seeks-political-parties-pledge-for-formulating-anti-discrimination-act</link><description>Attorney General (AG) Md Asaduzzaman at a programme today (Saturday) sought political parties' pledge for formulating an anti-discrimination act. "Political parties will not get our votes unless they make a commitment to formulate this act. We need a strong act as a vague act cannot provide a</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 10:27:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Constitution has no referendum provision, says Amir Khosru</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/constitution-has-no-referendum-provision-says-amir-khosru</link><description>Stating that there is no provision for a referendum in the Constitution, BNP senior leader Amir Khosru Mahmud Chowdhury on Saturday urged political parties to avoid heating up the streets over the issue in order to prevent political confrontation.
“The current interim government has been for</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 11:28:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sonali Life Insurance holds Team Enrichment and Business Conference at Foy’s Lake</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/sonali-life-insurance-holds-team-enrichment-and-business-conference-at-foys-lake</link><description>Sonali Life Insurance Company Limited organised its “Team Enrichment and Business Conference 2025” on Saturday at the scenic Foy’s Lake in Chattogram, the port city of Bangladesh.

The conference, held under the slogan “Mission – Let’s Double It,” feature</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 11:15:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat not involved in any activities that threaten election process: Azad</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-not-involved-in-any-activities-that-threaten-election-process-azad</link><description>Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami’s Assistant Secretary General Hamidur Rahman Azad on Saturday said their party is not involved in any activities that threaten the election process.
He made the remark while speaking at a seminar titled ‘Use of Technology in Election Manifestos’ organis</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 11:30:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pakistan Navy frigate PNS Saif arrives in Bangladesh on goodwill visit</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/pakistan-navy-frigate-pns-saif-arrives-in-bangladesh-on-goodwill-visit</link><description>Pakistan Navy frigate PNS Saif has arrived in Bangladesh on a four-day goodwill visit, the Inter-Services Public Relations (ISPR) has said in a statement.
Upon entering Bangladesh waters, the ship was greeted with a ceremonial salute by Bangladesh Navy ship BNS Shadhinota on Saturday.
A naval ban</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 11:45:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Salahuddin slams govt for 7-day ultimatum on referendum consensus</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/salahuddin-slams-govt-for-7-day-ultimatum-on-referendum-consensus</link><description>BNP Standing Committee member Salahuddin Ahmed on Saturday cautioned the interim government against ‘displaying excessive assertiveness’ by setting a seven-day deadline for achieving political consensus on the referendum issue, saying such an approach ‘does not befit’ a non-</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 12:00:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prime Bank organizes SME Women Entrepreneurs Training in Chattogram</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/prime-bank-organizes-sme-women-entrepreneurs-training-in-chattogram</link><description>Prime Bank PLC. recently organized “Prime Neera–SME Women Entrepreneurs Training and Development Program” in the port city Chattogram.
Prime Bank’s Neera initiative is dedicated to promoting financial inclusion and sustainable business growth among women entrepreneurs acros</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 12:15:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Police use sound grenades to break up primary teachers’ protest in Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/police-use-sound-grenades-to-break-up-primary-teachers-protest-in-dhaka</link><description>Police have been accused of firing sound grenades to disperse a procession of government primary school teachers in Dhaka.
The teachers, who have been demanding that their pay be upgraded to the 10th grade along with two other benefits, were marching towards Shahbagh on Saturday when police blocke</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 12:30:44 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>