<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 06:33:52 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Bangladesh's apparel exports can fetch $122.01b by 2030 thru investing in climate adaptation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladeshs-apparel-exports-can-fetch-12201b-by-2030-thru-investing-in-climate-adaptation</link><description>Investing in climate adaptation can help Bangladesh fetch US$122.01 billion in apparel exports by the year 2030 as a significant rise in heat waves and flooding in Dhaka over the last two decades severely impacted workers' health and factory outputs, according to a new study.
"In 2030, Bangladesh</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 03:10:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The train to Chalan Beel</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/analysis/the-train-to-chalan-beel</link><description>I phone Pobitro Adhikary when the Dhumketu Express lurches forward at 6am, telling him we have departed from the Kamalapur railway station on time. He is my childhood friend, and we have planned a train-themed exploration of the Chalan Beel. Our destination is the Dilpasar station in Pabna, but as</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 03:25:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Building material market continues to be bearish</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/building-material-market-continues-to-be-bearish</link><description>The slump in demand for key building materials, including MS rod and cement, continues due to a sluggish economy, investment slowdown, and limited implementation of public-sector development projects, sector insiders say.
They say the demand for construction materials remains almost half compared</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 03:40:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Border Road in Chittagong Hill Tracts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/analysis/border-road-in-chittagong-hill-tracts</link><description>A New Road to the Future
A quiet revolution is taking place in the wavy green hills of Bangladesh in one of the most distant frontiers of Bangladesh. The Border Road Project in Chittagong Hill Tracts (CHT) which is spearheaded and implemented by Bangladesh Army is not just a road passing through t</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 03:55:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>When hilshas jump on a ship out of Bay water</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/analysis/when-hilshas-jump-on-a-ship-out-of-bay-water</link><description>When serious issues like the February election and law and order are drawing the nation's attention, some extraordinary happenings of lighter vein are quietly doing their rounds. One such thing happened away from the land but within the country's territorial limit in the Bay of Bengal. Yes, no one</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 04:10:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BD lists 3.84m persons with disabilities: DSS</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bd-lists-384m-persons-with-disabilities-dss</link><description>Bangladesh has registered 3.84 million persons with disabilities in 12 official categories, senior government officials said at a national event on inclusive education and disability services.
Some 3.45 million of these persons are currently receiving allowances as beneficiaries, while 81,000 scho</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 04:25:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IndiGo estimates over $55 million payout to customers following flight cancellations</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/indigo-estimates-over-55-million-payout-to-customers-following-flight-cancellations</link><description>India's IndiGo on Friday estimated a payout of more than 5 billion rupees ($55.19 million) in total to customers impacted by the carrier's mass cancellations last week.
The airline had scrapped around 4,500 flights last week because of poor pilot roster planning, leaving tens of thousands of passe</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 04:46:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two arrested with spywares at HSIA</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/two-arrested-with-spywares-at-hsia</link><description>The Armed Police Battalion (APBn) has arrested two individuals with a large quantity of spywares at the Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport (HSIA) in the capital.
Based on a tip-off, Shaharun Ali, 38, and Md Iqbal Hossain Jibon, 35, were detained from the outer area of the airport on Friday.
T</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 05:01:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Stocks rebound as election schedule boosts market sentiment</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/stocks-rebound-as-election-schedule-boosts-market-sentiment</link><description>The benchmark equity index of the Dhaka bourse ended higher this week, paring half of the losses from the previous week, as the announcement of the national election schedule fuelled optimism in the market.
Market analysts noted that the political developments surrounding the upcoming elections of</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 05:16:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Lakshmipur election office set on fire</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/lakshmipur-election-office-set-on-fire</link><description>A suspected arson attack has damaged part of a district election office in Bangladesh’s Lakshmipur, while destroying several documents and equipment inside.

A masked man allegedly poured petrol into a ground-floor storeroom of the Lakshmipur District Election Office and set it alight aroun</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 05:31:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fire breaks out at Keraniganj multistoried building</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fire-breaks-out-at-keraniganj-multistoried-building</link><description>A fire broke out at a 12-storey building in the Babu Bazar area of Keraniganj on Saturday.
The fire started around 5:37 am on the ground floor of the building known as ‘Jabel-e-Noor,’ which houses a jhut (garment scrap) and readymade garment warehouse, said Anwarul Islam, Warehouse Ins</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 05:46:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Burglary reported at Osman Hadi’s home in Jhalakathi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/burglary-reported-at-osman-hadis-home-in-jhalakathi</link><description>A burglary has been reported at the village home of Osman Hadi, an election hopeful and convener of Inquilab Mancha who was shot in Dhaka.
The incident took place late on Friday night at Hadi’s house in the Khasmahal area of Jhalakathi's Nalchhiti, according to his cousin Sirajul Islam.
He</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 06:01:42 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>