<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 09:33:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Washington Post publisher announces departure, following mass layoffs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/washington-post-publisher-will-lewis-announces-departure-following-mass-layoffs</link><description>Washington Post publisher and CEO Will Lewis is leaving the newspaper, it announced on Saturday after carrying out widespread layoffs this week.
"During my tenure, difficult decisions have been taken in order to ensure the sustainable future of The Post so it can for many years ahead publish high-</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 07:11:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Election campaign ends on Tuesday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/election-campaign-ends-on-tuesday</link><description>Electioneering by contesting candidates in the 13th National Parliament Election and Referendum, scheduled for February 12, will conclude at 7:30 am on Tuesday, exactly 48 hours before voting begins.
The campaign, which started on January 22, will end in line with electoral rules requiring all pol</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 07:26:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>4 organisations write open letter to CA to keep Ctg Port operational</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/4-organisations-write-open-letter-to-ca-to-keep-ctg-port-operational</link><description>Four export-oriented trade bodies -- the Bangladesh Garment Manufacturers and Exporters Association (BGMEA), Bangladesh Knitwear Manufacturers and Exporters Association (BKMEA), Bangladesh Employers’ Federation (BEF), and Bangladesh Textile Mills Association (BTMA) -- have written an open let</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 07:41:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh, Japan sign MoU to boost environmental cooperation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-japan-sign-mou-to-boost-environmental-cooperation</link><description>Bangladesh and Japan have signed a Memorandum of Understanding to strengthen bilateral cooperation on environmental protection and sustainable development.
The MoU was signed in Tokyo on Friday between Bangladesh’s Ministry of Environment, Forest and Climate Change and Japan’s Ministry</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 07:56:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ctg Port remains operational despite strike, chairman says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ctg-port-remains-operational-despite-strike-chairman-says</link><description>SM Moniruzzaman, chairman of the Chittagong Port Authority, has said operations at the country's main port remain normal despite an ongoing strike by workers and employees.
He made the remarks at a media briefing outside the port building on Sunday, about an hour after it had originally been sched</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 08:11:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>International dialogue on responsible role of media in South Asian security and development held</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/international-dialogue-on-responsible-role-of-media-in-south-asian-security-and-development-held</link><description>Amid South Asia’s complex realities—political instability, border tensions, economic disparities, and development challenges—an international dialogue was held in Delhi yesterday to explore how the media can act as a force for peace and stability in the region.Organised by the Int</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 07:52:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Four EC channels to provide voter info</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/four-ec-channels-to-provide-voter-info</link><description>The Bangladesh Election Commission (EC) has introduced four channels to disseminate voter number and polling centre information -- its official app, website, dedicated call centre and SMS.
The initiative aims to offer quick and accurate information to citizens across the country ahead of 13th parl</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 08:07:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP manifesto targets 2.5pc FDI rise by 2034</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-manifesto-targets-25pc-fdi-rise-by-2034</link><description>In a major move to reshape the nation's economic landscape, the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) vows to enhance the country's Foreign Direct Investment (FDI) to 2.5 per cent of the Gross Domestic Product (GDP) by 2034 from the current weak trajectory.
The party will appoint "FDI Captains" to ac</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 08:22:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>20 remote polling centres in Rangamati to receive election materials by helicopters</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/20-remote-polling-centres-in-rangamati-to-receive-election-materials-by-helicopters</link><description>Authorities have begun transporting election materials by helicopters to 20 remote polling centres in Rangamati district ahead of the national election.
A total of 213 polling centres will be used in Rangamati, of which 20 are located in extremely remote hilly areas.
Rangamati Additional District</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 08:37:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ICC seeks explanation from PCB, warns of financial and legal consequences</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/icc-seeks-explanation-from-pcb-warns-of-financial-and-legal-consequences</link><description>The International Cricket Council (ICC) has formally sought an explanation from the Pakistan Cricket Board (PCB) over its decision to skip the high-profile T20 World Cup match against India.
While the global governing body is keen to avoid a direct confrontation, it has indicated t</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 08:52:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Plane crash in South Australia kills three</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/plane-crash-in-south-australia-kills-three</link><description>Three people were killed when a light aircraft crashed south of Adelaide on Friday afternoon, South Australia Police said on Saturday.
Police said they received reports of a light plane crashing into the ocean at about 4:20 p.m. local time and responded immediately, according to a statement.
All</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 09:07:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two Begum Rokeya Univ teachers suspended over sexual harassment allegations</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/two-begum-rokeya-university-teachers-suspended-over-sexual-harassment-allegations</link><description>Two associate professors at Begum Rokeya University, Rangpur (BRUR), have been suspended following allegations of sexual harassment, university authorities said.
The action was taken against Shamim Hossain, an associate professor in the Department of Geography and Environmental Science and assista</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 09:22:15 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>