<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 05:22:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Dhaka to send formal letter to Delhi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dhaka-to-send-formal-letter-to-delhi</link><description>The Ministry of Foreign Affairs has called upon India to hand over to the Bangladesh government former Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina and former Home Minister Asaduzzaman Khan Kamal, both fugitives who were sentenced to death by the International Crimes Tribunal on Monday for crimes against humanity.</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 01:31:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hasina's punishment milestone for future: Salahuddin</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/hasinas-punishment-milestone-for-future-salahuddin</link><description>BNP Standing Committee member Salahuddin Ahmed on Monday said that while the punishment handed down to Sheikh Hasina does not fully reflect the gravity of her crimes, the verdict represents a significant milestone for the country's future.
The International Crimes Tribunal on Monday sentenced form</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 01:46:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat satisfied over death sentence to Hasina</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-satisfied-over-death-sentence-to-hasina</link><description>Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami expressed on Monday satisfaction with the verdict sentencing ousted Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina to death in a case over crimes against humanity committed during the July (2024) mass uprising.
In its immediate reaction following the judgement delivered on Monday, the par</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 02:01:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCP demands execution of sentence on Hasina in a month</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ncp-demands-execution-of-sentence-on-hasina-in-a-month</link><description>National Citizen Party (NCP) has demanded the execution of ousted prime minister Sheikh Hasina's death sentence be carried out within one month.
"The convicted criminals responsible for enforced disappearances and genocide are the worst not just in Bangladesh, but across global history," NCP conve</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 02:16:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Next polls to fix country’s future course for 100 yrs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/next-polls-to-fix-countrys-future-course-for-100-yrs</link><description>Upcoming dual voting in national elections and referendum will determine the course of Bangladesh for over 100 years, says Chief Adviser of the post-uprising government Prof Muhammad Yunus while instructing deputy commissioners to play fair in the polls.
He asks the DCs to carry out their responsi</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 02:31:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rice imports go up to build contingency stock</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/rice-imports-go-up-to-build-contingency-stock</link><description>Bangladesh ramps up rice import to build a contingency stock with the buys having soared over 8,133 per cent in value during the first quarter of the current fiscal year, statistics show.
Officials say the import spree is driven by a sharp fall in international prices of the staple, particularly i</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 02:17:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Buyers cancel visits amid rising political uncertainty</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/buyers-cancel-visits-amid-rising-political-uncertainty</link><description>Global buyers of Bangladesh's readymade garments are cancelling scheduled visits and meetings in the country over security and political uncertainties, a development that industry leaders warn could affect work orders for the next two seasons.
At a discussion in Dhaka on Monday, leaders of the gar</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 02:32:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Major maiden foreign port venture to fetch Bangladesh $550m FDI</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/major-maiden-foreign-port-venture-to-fetch-bangladesh-550m-fdi</link><description>Denmark-based shipping-giant Maersk's outfit sets foot in Bangladesh's port venture with a substantial investment through a deal signed Monday on construction and operation of Laldia Container Terminal (LCT) in Chattogram.
The Chittagong Port Authority (CPA) and APM Terminals, a unit of Denmark-ba</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 02:47:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Police disperse demonstrators at Dhanmondi 32</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/police-disperse-demonstrators-at-dhanmondi-32</link><description>Police fired sound grenades and charged batons to disperse demonstrators who gathered at Dhanmondi-32 in the capital on Monday afternoon.
Earlier, police and army personnel took control of Dhanmondi-32, dispersing demonstrators, who had arrived with two excavators on two trucks in the morning.
Ey</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 03:02:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BB to halt five public services from Nov 30</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/bb-to-halt-five-public-services-from-nov-30</link><description>Bangladesh Bank (BB) will discontinue five major public services, including the sale of savings certificates (Sanchayapatra) and prize bonds, from November 30 as part of a broader effort to modernise its operations and strengthen security across its offices.
Sources at the central bank said the mo</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 03:17:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka tense as verdict sparks unrest</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dhaka-tense-as-verdict-sparks-unrest</link><description>Dhaka saw noticeably thinner crowds on Monday as the capital braced for unrest ahead of the verdict against former Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina.
Security was heightened across the city, prompting transport operators and educational institutions to scale back operations amid fears of sabotage.
Maj</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 03:32:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh's exports to China remain stagnant amid duty-free access</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladeshs-exports-to-china-remain-stagnant-amid-duty-free-access</link><description>Bangladesh's trade imbalance with China continues to escalate, driven by persistent higher imports of essentials for its industries from the country's top import destination.
On the other hand, Bangladesh's exports to China remained almost stagnant in recent years despite having duty-free market a</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 04:32:33 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>