<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 15:19:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Salahuddin slams govt for 7-day ultimatum on referendum consensus</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/salahuddin-slams-govt-for-7-day-ultimatum-on-referendum-consensus</link><description>BNP Standing Committee member Salahuddin Ahmed on Saturday cautioned the interim government against ‘displaying excessive assertiveness’ by setting a seven-day deadline for achieving political consensus on the referendum issue, saying such an approach ‘does not befit’ a non-</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 12:00:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prime Bank organizes SME Women Entrepreneurs Training in Chattogram</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/prime-bank-organizes-sme-women-entrepreneurs-training-in-chattogram</link><description>Prime Bank PLC. recently organized “Prime Neera–SME Women Entrepreneurs Training and Development Program” in the port city Chattogram.
Prime Bank’s Neera initiative is dedicated to promoting financial inclusion and sustainable business growth among women entrepreneurs acros</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 12:15:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Police use sound grenades to break up primary teachers’ protest in Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/police-use-sound-grenades-to-break-up-primary-teachers-protest-in-dhaka</link><description>Police have been accused of firing sound grenades to disperse a procession of government primary school teachers in Dhaka.
The teachers, who have been demanding that their pay be upgraded to the 10th grade along with two other benefits, were marching towards Shahbagh on Saturday when police blocke</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 12:30:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DMP defends police action to disperse teachers’ gathering at Shahbagh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dmp-defends-police-action-to-disperse-teachers-gathering-at-shahbagh</link><description>Dhaka Metropolitan Police (DMP) has justified the action taken to disperse a gathering of government primary school assistant teachers at Shahbagh, saying it was necessary to ensure public safety and protect key state establishments.
In a statement issued on Saturday afternoon, the DMP said the te</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 12:30:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Commercial Bank of Ceylon PLC Bangladesh Operations partners with DHL Express to advance sustainable shipping</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/commercial-bank-of-ceylon-plc-bangladesh-operations-partners-with-dhl-express-to-advance-sustainable-shipping</link><description>Commercial Bank of Ceylon PLC Bangladesh Operations has partnered with DHL Express Bangladesh to join the GoGreen Plus carbon-reduced shipping program, marking a significant milestone in the Bank’s ongoing commitment to sustainability and environmentally responsible operations.
The agreement</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 12:45:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Afghanistan, Pakistan peace talks collapse, ceasefire continues</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/afghanistan-pakistan-peace-talks-collapse-ceasefire-continues</link><description>Peace negotiations between Afghanistan and Pakistan broke down, although a ceasefire continues between the South Asian neighbours, a Taliban spokesperson said on Saturday.
Zabihullah Mujahid said negotiations had failed due to Islamabad insisting that Afghanistan assume responsibility for Pakistan</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 13:00:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Some political parties’ actions may endanger people’s rights: Tarique</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/some-political-parties-actions-may-endanger-peoples-rights-warns-tarique</link><description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman on Saturday cautioned that the recent actions of certain political parties, who once marched alongside the anti-fascist movement, may now be creating a situation that undermines the rights and opportunities of people.
Virtually addressing the ‘Hindu Represe</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 13:15:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Police-teacher clash at Shahbagh leaves 120 injured</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/police-teacher-clash-at-shahbagh-leaves-120-injured</link><description>At least 120 primary school teachers were injured on Saturday afternoon when police swung into action to disperse their protest march at Shahbagh.
Witnesses said the clash broke out around 4 pm when police intercepted the teachers’ ‘Pen Surrender March’ that began from the Centra</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 13:30:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Primary teachers announce nationwide work stoppage from Sunday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/primary-teachers-announce-nationwide-work-stoppage-from-sunday</link><description>Government primary school teachers have announced a work stoppage from Sunday after a police crackdown on protesters demanding 10th-grade pay.
Mohammad Abul Kashem, president of the Bangladesh Primary Teachers’ Association (Kashem-Shahin), announced a continuous sit-in and work stoppage at t</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 13:45:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Female expat tourist goes missing after boat capsizes in Mongla</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/female-expat-tourist-goes-missing-after-boat-capsizes-in-mongla</link><description>An expatriate female tourist went missing on Saturday after a tourist boat capsized while returning from a trip to the Sundarbans.
The missing woman has been identified as Riyana Azad, 28, wife of Touhidul Islam, from Bakerganj Upazila in Barishal district.
Surjit Chowdhury, officer-in-charge (OC</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 14:00:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCC Bank signs MoU with DNCC on collection of municipal charges</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ncc-bank-signs-mou-with-dncc-on-collection-of-municipal-charges</link><description>NCC Bank has recently signed a Memorandum of Understanding (MoU) with Dhaka North City Corporation (DNCC), enabling NCC Bank customers to conveniently pay various fees and taxes — including holding tax, trade license fee, hotel tax, market salami, wheel tax, other municipal charges — th</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 14:15:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BRAC Bank and IDCOL finance USD 67 million syndicated loan to BCRECL for large-scale solar power plant</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/brac-bank-and-idcol-finance-usd-67-million-syndicated-loan-to-bcrecl-for-large-scale-solar-power-plant</link><description>BRAC Bank PLC and Infrastructure Development Company Limited (IDCOL) have jointly financed a landmark renewable energy initiative,a 64.55 MW solar power plant, operated by Bangladesh China Renewable Energy Company Limited (BCRECL).
A ceremony was held on November 6, 2025at InterContinental Dhaka t</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 14:30:51 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>