<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 13:14:49 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Four election officials withdrawn in Mymensingh, Naogaon over irregularities</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/four-election-officials-withdrawn-in-mymensingh-naogaon-over-irregularities</link><description>Four election officials were withdrawn from duty in Mymensingh and Naogaon on Thursday following allegations of irregularities during voting.
In Mymensingh’s Bhaluka upazila, an assistant presiding officer and two polling officers were dismissed at Kansherkul High School centre over allegati</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 11:09:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Crude bomb blast, ballot snatched away in Bhola; one held</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crude-bomb-blast-ballot-snatched-away-in-bhola-one-held</link><description>Miscreants snatched away ballot paper after exploding crude bombs at a polling centre under Bhola-1 (Sadar) constituency in Sadar upazila of Bhola district on Thursday, forcing authorities to suspend votes for nearly one and a half hours.
Omar Faruk, Presiding Officer of Alinagar School and Colleg</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 11:24:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>47.91 per cent voter turnout by 2pm: EC Secretary</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/4791-per-cent-voter-turnout-by-2pm-ec-secretary</link><description>Senior Secretary of the Election Commission Akhtar Ahmed on Thursday said that 47.91 percent of registered voters had cast their ballots by 2pm at 36,031 out of 42,651 polling centres across the country.
He said the commission has yet to receive turnout data from 6,620 centres, he told reporters a</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 11:39:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Yunus calls for restraint after polls close</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/yunus-urges-parties-candidates-to-show-tolerance-after-election-result</link><description>Chief Advisor Muhammad Yunus has urged political parties and candidates to maintain restraint and democratic civility even after the final results of the parliamentary election are announced.
In a statement issued on Thursday after voting concluded, Yunus urged “unity” despite differen</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 11:54:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nilphamari groom casts ballot before going to tie the knot</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/nilphamari-groom-casts-ballot-before-going-to-tie-the-knot</link><description>A groom in full wedding attire has stopped by a polling station before heading to his own wedding ceremony in Nilphamari.
On Thursday, Md Samiul Islam arrived at the Syedpur Pilot Girls’ High School centre in the Nilphamari-4 constituency wearing a sherwani and turban -- not for photographs,</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 11:10:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>6 die in polling centres across Bangladesh during vote</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/6-die-in-polling-centres-across-bangladesh-during-vote</link><description>Six people have died at polling centres in Dhaka, Chattogram, Khulna, Manikganj, Brahmanbaria and Gaibandha during voting in the general election and referendum.
Five of them died after falling sick while one died after allegedly being pushed during a scuffle.
BRAHMANBARIA
A polling official die</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 11:25:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ADB appoints new DG of its South Asia Department</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/global/adb-appoints-new-dg-of-its-south-asia-department</link><description>The Asian Development Bank (ADB) has appointed Sona Shrestha as Director General of its South Asia Department (SARD), where she will lead the development and implementation of ADB’s strategy and operations in Bangladesh, Bhutan, India, Maldives, Nepal, and Sri Lanka.
“I am honoured to</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 11:40:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Want to run country with movement allies, if elected: Tarique</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/want-to-run-country-with-movement-allies-if-elected-tarique</link><description>BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman on Thursday said his party wants to run the country with all those parties that participated with them in the movement.
“We want to run the country more or less with those with whom we carried out the movement,” he said while talking to reporters in front of</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 11:55:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How a renowned seat of education in Mohammadpur witnessed democracy triumph again</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/how-a-renowned-seat-of-education-in-mohammadpur-witnessed-democracy-triumph-again</link><description>Government Jamila Ainul Ananda School and College, a familiar academic landmark of Khiljee Road under Mohammadpur, took on a different identity on election day—emerging as a vibrant civic space, like most polling centres across the country, where democracy was not only practiced, but joyfully</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 12:10:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>With no transport, postman travels 57km to meet poll deadline</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/57km-on-foot-and-rickshaw-postman-reaches-poll-office-minutes-before-430pm</link><description>A postman has travelled nearly 57km, partly on foot and partly by rickshaw, to deliver postal ballots just minutes before voting ended in the Feb 12 election and referendum.
The incident occurred in Mymensingh’s Haluaghat Upazila, a border area, said Salim Ahmad Khan, team leader of the Elec</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 12:25:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat Ameer calls for peaceful counting, says nation won’t accept ‘New Fascism’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jamaat-ameer-calls-for-peaceful-counting-says-nation-wont-accept-new-fascism</link><description>Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami Ameer Dr. Shafiqur Rahman on Thursday said that any disorder during vote counting would not reflect the people’s aspirations, saying reports from across the country suggest that citizens would not welcome any ‘new fascism.’
“The nation had regaine</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 12:40:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hasnat's opponent Jasim boycotts election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/hasnats-opponent-jasim-boycotts-election</link><description>Jasim Uddin, the BNP-backed and Gono Odhikar Parishad candidate, on Thursday announced a boycott of voting in the Cumilla-4 (Debidwar) constituency.
His main rival in the seat is Hasnat Abdullah, chief organiser of the National Citizen Party (NCP). 
Speaking on Facebook Live in the afternoon</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 12:55:07 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>