<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 14:41:39 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Four injured, apparent attacker shot by police near UK synagogue on Yom Kippur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/four-injured-apparent-attacker-shot-by-police-near-uk-synagogue-on-yom-kippur</link><description>British police said on Thursday four people had been injured after reports of stabbings and a car being driven at pedestrians near a synagogue in Manchester in northwest England, and that officers had shot the suspected offender.
Greater Manchester Police said officers had been called to the incid</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 11:23:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tourists flood Cox’s Bazar despite storm warnings</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/holidaymakers-defy-storm-caution-to-celebrate-durga-puja-on-coxs-bazar-beach</link><description>Clouds blanketed the sky and relentless rain battered the shore, but Cox’s Bazar still heaves with Durga Puja crowds, where every hotel room was snapped up as holidaymakers defied the storm to revel by the sea despite a cautionary signal No. 3.
Thousands from across the country have flocked</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 11:38:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Heavy to very heavy rainfall likely in Dhaka, 6 other divisions</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/heavy-to-very-heavy-rainfall-likely-in-dhaka-6-other-divisions</link><description>Bangladesh Meteorological Department (BMD) has predicted heavy to very heavy rainfall at many places in seven divisions due to deep depression over the Northwest Bay and adjoining area during the next 48 hours commencing at 3 pm on Thursday.
“Under the influence of deep depression over</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 12:08:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>None can destroy communal harmony in Bangladesh: Adviser Nurjahan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/none-can-destroy-communal-harmony-in-bangladesh-adviser-nurjahan</link><description>Health and Family Welfare adviser Nurjahan Begum on Thursday said no one can spoil the communal harmony in Bangladesh.
"No one can destroy communal harmony in Bangladesh. Humanity and service are respected like religion. It is important for us to remember this (spirit) from our respective places,"</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 12:38:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Army chief likely to visit India in October</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/army-chief-likely-to-visit-india-in-october</link><description>Bangladesh's Chief of Army Staff Gen Waker-Uz-Zaman is expected to attend a conference organised by India for troop-contributing countries to UN peacekeeping missions.
The two-day conference will begin on Oct 14 in New Delhi, bdnews24.com reports citing Indian media outlet The Statesman.
Banglade</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 12:43:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Durga leaves as Chattogram weeps farewell</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tears-rituals-and-crowds-mark-durga-puja-immersions-across-chattogram</link><description>The Durga Puja festival which began on Shashthi with the awakening of Anandamayi has drawn to a close on Dashami, as devotees bid farewell to the goddess with the solemn ritual of "mirror immersion".
On Thursday morning, after the Bijoya Dashami prayers were completed, worshippers offered flowers</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 12:58:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BYSA announces protest rally against Israeli attack on Sumud flotilla</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bysa-announces-protest-rally-against-israeli-attack-on-sumud-flotilla</link><description>Bangladesh Youth Synergy Alliance (BYSA) has announced a protest rally condemning the Israeli attack on the Sumud flotilla and the ongoing genocide in Palestine.
The rally will be held at 3pm on Friday at Manik Mia Avenue in the capital, UNB reports. 
In a statement, BYSA said, “We dem</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 13:13:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Equal status for nurses is vital for Bangladesh’s healthcare: Farhad Mazhar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/equal-status-for-nurses-is-vital-for-bangladeshs-healthcare-farhad-mazhar</link><description>Poet and political thinker Farhad Mazhar has demanded that nurses be granted equal professional status to doctors, alongside the immediate formation of a “National Nurse Commission” to ensure health services for the people.
Speaking at the Zahur Hossain Chowdhury Hall of the National P</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 13:28:28 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>