<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 07:25:32 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Security beefed up ahead of verdict in Hasina plot scam case</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/security-beefed-up-ahead-of-verdict-in-hasina-plot-scam-case</link><description>Law enforcement agencies have taken heightened security measures in the capital ahead of today's (Monday) verdict in a case against 17 people, including ousted prime minister Sheikh Hasina, her sister Sheikh Rehana and niece Tulip Siddique, over irregularities in the allocation of a 10-katha plot i</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 04:58:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BIWTA to set up country's 54th river port in Bogura</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/biwta-to-set-up-countrys-54th-river-port-in-bogura</link><description>The Bangladesh Inland Water Transport Authority (BIWTA) is set to establish the country's 54th river port in Bogura very soon, aiming to expand transportation of goods, mostly agricultural produces, between northern Bangladesh and Dhaka through river ways.
To this goal, a feasibility study has alr</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 05:13:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>TCB seeks procurement provider VAT exemption for all suppliers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/tcb-seeks-procurement-provider-vat-exemption-for-all-suppliers</link><description>The state-run Trading Corporation of Bangladesh (TCB) has requested an exemption from the procurement provider VAT for all suppliers of edible oil and sugar in local tenders, sources say.
It recently made the request to the commerce ministry, urging the latter to take steps in this regard.
The mo</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 05:28:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Banglalink unveils its new identity to power digital future</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/banglalink-unveils-its-new-identity-to-power-digital-future</link><description>Banglalink, the country's leading digital operator, has unveiled a bold brand refresh that marks its transformation into a modern, customer-centric, and technology-driven company.
This milestone reflects Banglalink's commitment to accelerating the nation's digital progress while advancing its pare</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 05:43:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UK military committed war crimes in Afghanistan, ex-officer says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/ex-officer-tells-inquiry-uk-military-committed-war-crimes-in-afghanistan</link><description>A former senior British officer has told a public inquiry that British special forces in Afghanistan appeared to commit war crimes by executing suspects and despite widespread knowledge in the chain of command nothing was done.
Britain's defence ministry (MoD) ordered the inquiry after a BBC TV do</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 05:58:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pregnant woman found dead in Gopalganj pond</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/pregnant-woman-found-dead-in-gopalganj-pond</link><description>Police have recovered the body of a woman, who was four months pregnant, from a pond in Muksudpur upazila of Gopalganj six days after she went missing.
The body, stuffed inside a sack, was found around 8:00 pm on Sunday in a pond adjacent to her in-laws’ house in Latifpur village, said Mosta</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 05:29:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Plot graft: Rehana, Tulip get jail terms alongside Hasina</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/plot-graft-rehana-british-mp-tulip-get-jail-terms-alongside-hasina</link><description>A Dhaka court has delivered its verdict in another corruption case against ousted prime minister Sheikh Hasina and her family members over the allocation of plots in the Purbachal New Town project.
Alongside Hasina, the court has also found her sister Sheikh Rehana and Rehana’s daughter, Bri</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 05:44:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka College students block Science Lab intersection</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dhaka-college-students-block-science-lab-intersection</link><description>A group of Dhaka College students have blocked the Science Laboratory intersection to press for the repeal of the Dhaka Central University ordinance.
New Market Police Station chief AKM Mahfuzul Haque said the demonstration began around 10:30 am on Monday when higher secondary students of the coll</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 05:59:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BTCL gets approval for virtual network operator</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/btcl-gets-approval-for-virtual-network-operator</link><description>Bangladesh Telecommunications Company Limited (BTCL) has received approval to operate experimentally as a Mobile Virtual Network Operator (MVNO) in the country.
Faiz Ahmad Taiyeb, chief advisor's special assistant on ICT, shared the development in a Facebook post on Sunday, reports bdnews24.com.</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 06:14:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Reza Kibria joins BNP</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/reza-kibria-joins-bnp</link><description>Reza Kibria, an economist and founder-convener of the political platform Gono Odhikar Parishad, has formally joined the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP).
He announced his joining on Monday at the political office of BNP Chairperson Khaleda Zia in Gulshan.
BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Isl</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 06:29:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Medical technologists, pharmacists threaten nationwide shutdown</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/medical-technologists-pharmacists-threaten-nationwide-shutdown</link><description>Medical technologists and pharmacists across Bangladesh have threatened a nationwide shutdown of healthcare services if their salaries are not upgraded to the 10th grade of the national pay scale -- a demand they say has remained unmet for more than three decades.
To press home their demand, profe</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 06:44:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nepal announces $200,000 in financial aid to flood-hit Sri Lanka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/nepal-announces-200000-in-financial-aid-to-flood-hit-sri-lanka</link><description>The Nepali government has announced financial aid of 200,000 US dollars for Sri Lanka to support relief and recovery efforts for people badly affected by recent floods.
Heavy rainfall and flooding triggered by Cyclone Ditwah in the past few days have resulted in the deaths of at least 334 people,</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 06:59:14 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>