<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 07:23:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Pre-Ramadan commodities market: Intel agency warns of artificial crisis</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/pre-ramadan-commodities-market-intel-agency-warns-of-artificial-crisis</link><description>A top state intelligence agency has issued a detailed warning about a significant threat to the stability of the essential commodities market ahead of Ramadan.
It alleges a coordinated attempt by "hyper-profit-seeking and dishonest businessmen" to engineer an artificial crisis through hoarding and</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 03:50:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ICT division working on policy for use of AI in govt offices: Faiz Ahmad Taiyeb</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/ict-division-working-on-policy-for-use-of-ai-in-govt-offices-faiz-ahmad-taiyeb</link><description>Faiz Ahmad Taiyeb, the Chief Adviser’s Special Assistant for Posts, Telecommunications and ICT, said that Bangladesh is working on a policy to regulate the use of Artificial Intelligence (AI) in government offices.
He said this while speaking as the chief guest at the ‘Bangladesh Techc</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 04:05:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BR to rehabilitate rail tracks, signal systems in west zone</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/br-to-rehabilitate-rail-tracks-signal-systems-in-west-zone</link><description>The Bangladesh Railway (BR) is going to rehabilitate the railway tracks, lines and signalling systems across its western zone, aiming to make train movement on the routes secure and smooth, officials said on Wednesday.
Since many tracks, lines and signaling systems have become old-aged and some of</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 04:20:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP may drop disputed nominees amid growing internal rifts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-may-drop-disputed-nominees-amid-growing-internal-rifts</link><description>Concerned by internal rifts in several districts following the announcement of its initial candidates for 237 seats, BNP is now considering dropping controversial and heavily disputed nominees from its preliminary list for the 13th national election.
A team of senior party leaders has been tasked</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 04:35:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>National Guard soldiers shot in 'targeted' attack near White House</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/national-guard-soldiers-shot-in-targeted-attack-near-white-house</link><description>Two National Guard soldiers were shot and critically wounded on Wednesday in downtown Washington near the White House in what officials described as a targeted ambush, and the suspect was in custody after suffering gunshot wounds during the incident.
The suspect was identified by the Department of</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 04:50:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IMF, Ukraine reach staff-level agreement on $8.2 billion, four-year programme</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/imf-ukraine-reach-staff-level-agreement-on-82-billion-four-year-programme</link><description>The International Monetary Fund said on Wednesday it reached a staff-level agreement on a new four-year, $8.2 billion program for Ukraine as the country faces mounting wartime fiscal pressures.
The IMF said the agreement, which replaces the existing $15.6 billion Extended Fund Facility approved in</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 05:05:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Youth hacked to death in Munshiganj</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/youth-hacked-to-death-in-munshiganj</link><description>A 25-year-old man has been hacked to death allegedly by his rivals over previous enmity in Gajaria upazila of Munshiganj district.
The incident occurred in Chauddakahunia village of Baushia union in the upazila on Wednesday night.
The deceased was identified as Joy Sarkar, son of Jamal Sarkar of</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 05:20:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Boeing to build Apache helicopters for Poland</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/boeing-to-build-apache-helicopters-for-poland-as-part-of-47-billion-contract</link><description>Boeing said on Wednesday it will produce AH-64E Apache attack helicopters for international customers, including 96 for the Polish Armed Forces, under a foreign military sales contract worth nearly $4.7 billion awarded by the US Army.
Deliveries are expected to begin in 2028, Boeing said. Poland's</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 05:35:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Verdicts being read out in plot graft case against Hasina, her children</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/verdicts-being-read-out-in-plot-graft-case-against-hasina-her-children</link><description>A judge has begun reading out the verdicts in three cases against 23 suspects, including ousted prime minister Sheikh Hasina, in a case over misusing government power to allocate plots in the Purbachal New Town Project in Dhaka.
The first verdict is in a case against Hasina and 11 others.
Dhaka S</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 05:50:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Purbachal plot graft: Ousted PM Hasina gets total of 21 years in jail in 3 cases</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/purbachal-plot-graft-ousted-pm-hasina-gets-total-of-21-years-in-jail-in-3-cases</link><description>A Dhaka court has sentenced Sheikh Hasina, the Bangladeshi prime minister ousted by the July Uprising, to a total of 21 years in jail in three cases over corruption in the allocation of land in the Purbachal New Town Project.</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 06:05:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Low forms into depression, met office advises cautionary signal for ports</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/low-forms-into-depression-met-office-advises-cautionary-signal-for-ports</link><description>The well-marked low-pressure area over the southwest Bay of Bengal and adjacent Sri Lanka coast has intensified into a depression, says the Bangladesh Meteorological Department.
All four maritime ports in the country have been advised to raise distant cautionary signal No.1. The BMD has also advis</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 06:52:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>158 UNOs transferred ahead of election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/158-unos-transferred-ahead-of-election</link><description>The government has ordered the transfer of 158 Upazila Nirbahi Officers (UNOs) to various government offices ahead of the national election.
The Ministry of Public Administration issued a gazette notification in this regard on Wednesday night.
The transfers, involving senior assistant secretary-l</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 07:07:26 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>