<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 04:37:18 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Tarique will return 'carrying the flag of Bangladesh', Fakhrul says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-will-return-carrying-the-flag-of-bangladesh-fakhrul-says</link><description>Senior BNP leader Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir has said the party's Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman will land in Dhaka on Dec 25 "carrying the flag of Bangladesh”.
The BNP secretary general made the remark on Monday at a Victory Day discussion meeting, recalling a statement made by a Chinese p</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 18:16:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CEC meant Hadi attack ‘will not derail polls’: commission</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hadi-attack-will-not-derail-election-commission-explains-cec-remarks</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has issued a clarification of remarks made by the chief election commissioner (CEC) on the attack on Inqilab Moncho spokesperson Sharif Osman bin Hadi, amid mounting criticism from political figures and student leaders.
In its explanation, the commission said the CEC&amp;r</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 18:31:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Development spending slumps to 11.75 per cent in five months</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/development-spending-slumps-to-1175-per-cent-in-five-months</link><description>The pace of implementing the country’s Annual Development Programme (ADP) has not recovered, with only 11.75 percent of the allocation spent in the first five months of the current fiscal year 2025-26.
The rate lags behind the implementation achieved during the same period of the previous fi</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 18:46:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ICC rejects Israeli bid to halt Gaza war investigation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/icc-rejects-israeli-bid-to-halt-gaza-war-investigation</link><description>Appeals judges at the International Criminal Court (ICC) on Monday rejected one in a series of legal challenges brought by Israel against the court's probe into its conduct of the Gaza war.
On appeal, judges refused to overturn a lower court decision that the prosecution's investigation into alleg</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 19:01:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US tells Ukraine it must leave Donetsk for peace deal, source says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-tells-ukraine-it-must-withdraw-from-donetsk-region-for-peace-deal-says-person-familiar-with-talks</link><description>US negotiators have told Ukraine during peace talks in Berlin that it must agree to withdraw its forces from the eastern Donetsk region as part of any deal to end the nearly four-year-old war, an official familiar with the matter said.
The source, speaking on condition of anonymity as Ukrainian an</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 19:16:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Four major trade orgs to seek review of three amended provisos</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/four-major-trade-orgs-to-seek-review-of-three-amended-provisos</link><description>Four major trade bodies in Bangladesh's industrial realm seek a rethink on three key amended sections of the labour law as they believe such new provisos could adversely affect employment and hike the cost of doing business.



As planned, the organisations will initially request the reigning i</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 19:31:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CA pays homage to Liberation War martyrs on Victory Day</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ca-pays-homage-to-liberation-war-martyrs-on-victory-day</link><description>Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus on Tuesday paid rich tributes to the martyrs of the Liberation War by placing a wreath at the National Memorial here on the outskirts of the capital marking the 55th Victory Day.
He laid the wreath at the altar of the National Memorial around 6:56 am.
After</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 02:45:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jubo League leader hacked to death in Dakshinkhan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jubo-league-leader-hacked-to-death-in-dakshinkhan</link><description>A Jubo League leader has been hacked to death in a public gathering in Dhaka’s Dakshinkhan, according to police.
The dead has been identified as Shahjahan Sheikh, 46.
Police say the murder occurred at Taltola intersection at 8:45pm.
He was involved in several businesses. He was also the pr</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 03:00:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>President pays tributes to Liberation War heroes on Victory Day</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/president-pays-tributes-to-liberation-war-heroes-on-victory-day-1</link><description>President Mohammed Shahabuddin on Tuesday paid rich tributes to the martyrs of the 1971 Liberation War by placing a wreath at the National Memorial here, on the outskirts of the capital, marking the 55th Victory Day.
The Head of the State laid the wreath at the altar of the National Memorial with</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 03:15:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nation celebrates V-Day today amid new ambiance</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nation-celebrates-v-day-today-amid-new-ambiance</link><description>As the 16th December dawns today, the nation begins to celebrate the Victory Day marking Bangladesh’s liberation from the then Pakistani occupation this day 54 years ago through a nine-month bloodstained war.
On December 16 in 1971, as history says, Bangladesh was born as an independent coun</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 03:30:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hadi flown to Singapore by air ambulance</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hadi-flown-to-singapore-by-air-ambulance</link><description>An air ambulance carrying fatally-wounded Inqilab Mancha spokesperson Sharif Osman Hadi left for Singapore on Monday.
At 1:40pm, he was transferred to the air ambulance, which departed 10 minutes later.
Hadi will receive advanced treatment in Singapore.
Earlier, at 1:10pm, an ambulance carrying</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 03:45:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>LGD proposes Tk 9.79b project for 18 DSCC wards</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/lgd-proposes-tk-979b-project-for-18-dscc-wards</link><description>The Local Government Division (LGD) under the Ministry of Local Government, Rural Development and Co-operatives has submitted a Tk 9.79-billion-project proposal to upgrade 123.53 kilometres of local roads in 18 wards that were incorporated into Dhaka South City Corporation (DSCC) in 2016, sources a</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 04:00:49 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>