<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 16:27:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Midland Bank inaugurates Saidpur Sub Branch</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/midland-bank-inaugurates-saidpur-sub-branch</link><description>Midland Bank PLC (MDB) inaugurated its Saidpur Sub-Branch at Sahid Dr. Zikrul Haque Plaza (1st floor), Dr. Zikrul Haque Road, Saidpur, Nilphamari on December 11, 2025, according to a press release.
Md. Ahsan-uz Zaman, Managing Director &amp; CEO of the bank, inaugurated the Branch as Chief Guest along</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 14:00:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>SBAC Bank holds Annual Risk Conference 2025</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/sbac-bank-holds-annual-risk-conference-2025</link><description>SBAC Bank PLC. has organized its Annual Risk Conference 2025 on Saturday, December 13, 2025, at the Training Institute of the bank’s Head Office.
Mr. A.N.M Moinul Kabir, Director of Department of Off-site Supervision of Bangladesh Bank, attended the conference as the chief guest, according t</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 13:30:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>National Bank achieves ISO certification</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/national-bank-achieves-iso-certification</link><description>National Bank has achieved the internationally recognised ISO 27001:2022 Information Security Management System (ISMS) certification, according to a press release.
On this occasion, a certificate handover ceremony was held on 11 December 2025, at the bank’s Head Office. Mr. K. Nagaraj, Count</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 13:45:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Belarus frees Nobel winner, top opposition figures as US lifts more sanctions</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/belarus-frees-nobel-winner-top-opposition-figures-as-us-lifts-more-sanctions</link><description>Belarusian President Alexander Lukashenko freed 123 prisoners on Saturday including Nobel Peace Prize winner Ales Bialiatski and leading opposition figure Maria Kalesnikava after two days of talks with an envoy for President Donald Trump, a US statement said.
In return, the US agreed to lift sanct</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 14:00:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BRAC Bank empowers 60 women entrepreneurs in Patuakhali, Khagrachhari</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/brac-bank-empowers-60-women-entrepreneurs-in-patuakhali-khagrachhari</link><description>BRAC Bank, in partnership with the Bangladesh Open-Source Network (BdOSN), has completed two ‘Amrai TARA’ training programmes in Patuakhali and Khagrachhari, advancing its nationwide women entrepreneurship development agenda.
Across two regions, 60 emerging women entrepreneurs embarked</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 14:15:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BMCCI holds 24th AGM, showcases achievements and future vision</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bmcci-holds-24th-agm-showcases-achievements-and-future-vision</link><description>The Bangladesh-Malaysia Chamber of Commerce and Industry (BMCCI) convened its 24th Annual General Meeting (AGM) on Saturday at Renaissance Dhaka, Gulshan.
According to a press release, the meeting brought together distinguished members, past presidents, and board colleagues, reaffirming BMCCI&amp;rsqu</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 14:30:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NHRC ordinance ‘trapped by bureaucratic control’, says TIB</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nhrc-ordinance-trapped-by-bureaucratic-control-says-tib</link><description>Transparency International Bangladesh (TIB) has claimed that the National Human Rights Commission (NHRC) Ordinance is being “held hostage by a bureaucratic takeover”.
In a media statement on Saturday, the local chapter of Berlin-based Transparency International, a global anti-corruptio</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 14:45:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fully extinguishing Keraniganj building fire may take yet another day</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fully-extinguishing-keraniganj-building-fire-may-take-yet-another-day</link><description>Firefighters have contained the blaze in a multi-storey building in Keraniganj after more than 11 and a half hours, though full extinguishment is expected to take at least another day.
Fire Service teams succeeded in taming the blaze at 5:03pm on Saturday following efforts by 20 units, but removin</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 15:00:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC directs police to tighten security at all election offices after recent attacks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-directs-police-to-tighten-security-at-all-election-offices-after-recent-attacks</link><description>In the wake of recent attacks targeting candidates and election facilities, the Election Commission (EC) has instructed police to beef up security at election offices nationwide, including those of the chief election commissioner, commissioners, the EC secretary, and returning officers.
The direct</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 15:16:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CA to witness flypast, paratrooping at Tejgaon Parade Ground on Victory Day</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ca-to-witness-flypast-paratrooping-at-tejgaon-parade-ground-on-victory-day</link><description>Chief Adviser (CA) Professor Dr Muhammad Yunus will witness the flypast and paratrooping of Bangladesh Army, Navy and Air Forces at Tejgaon Parade Ground as part of celebrating the Great Victory Day on December 16.
A release of the Inter Services Public Relations (ISPR) Directorate stated this on</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 15:31:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Aid is built for yesterday’s crises: Communities are building what comes next</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/aid-is-built-for-yesterdays-crises-communities-are-building-what-comes-next</link><description>The humanitarian sector is running out of road. I write this from the Regional Humanitarian Partnership Meeting 2025, where actors from across the Global South are confronting a truth it is no longer possible to ignore: the world has entered an age of overlapping, fast-moving crises that our system</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 15:46:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nation to observe Martyred Intellectuals Day on Sunday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nation-to-observe-martyred-intellectuals-day-on-sunday</link><description>The nation is set to observe the Martyred Intellectuals Day on Sunday to commemorate the intellectuals killed systematically by Pakistan occupation forces and their local collaborators at the fag-end of the Liberation War in 1971.
On this day in 1971, the country’s renowned academicians, doc</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 16:01:13 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>