<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 16:52:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>NCP alleges attacks on leaders, activists of its 11-party alliance</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ncp-alleges-attacks-on-leaders-activists-of-its</link><description>The National Citizen Party (NCP) on Friday alleged that leaders and activists of its 11-party alliance are being attacked in different parts of the country.
In a Facebook post, the party also claimed that the homes and families of its leaders and activists are facing threats.
Addressing the winne</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 13:26:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique thanks supporters for helping BNP win landslide victory</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-thanks-supporters-for-helping-bnp-win-landslide-victory</link><description>BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman on Friday expressed gratitude to his supporters for their affection and for helping secure a landslide victory for his party.
“I am grateful for the love you have shown me. Please pray for me,” he said while talking to people gathered outside his Gulshan res</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 13:41:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Winning as an independent was ‘not easy’, Rumeen Farhana says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/winning-as-an-independent-was-not-easy-rumeen-farhana-says</link><description>Rumeen Farhana, elected with the Duck symbol in Brahmanbaria-2, has said it was not easy to win as an independent after being denied a BNP nomination.
Speaking at a press conference at her Shahbazpur home in Sarail on Friday, the barrister said the struggle had been even harder for her supporters.</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 13:56:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India cenbank allows banks higher acquisition financing limit</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/global/india-cenbank-allows-banks-higher-acquisition-financing-limit</link><description>Indian lenders will be allowed to finance acquisitions up to 20 per cent of their eligible capital base, the Reserve Bank of India said in its final rules following a review of bank exposure to capital markets.
The RBI had suggested a cap of 10 per cent of a bank's tier-1 capital for acquisition f</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 14:11:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>150,000 ballots scrapped: Massive invalidation hits Gazipur seats</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/150000-ballots-scrapped-massive-invalidation-hits-gazipur-seats</link><description>Nearly 150,000 ballots across Gazipur’s five constituencies have been declared invalid.
These include both parliamentary and referendum ballots, though the cancellation rate for the referendum has been significantly higher.
Official records show that the highest number of referendum ballots</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 14:26:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Zimbabwe stun Australia by 23 runs in T20 World Cup</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/cricket/zimbabwe-stun-australia-by-23-runs-in-t20-world-cup</link><description>Zimbabwe caused a seismic shock at the T20 World Cup on Friday, defeating heavyweights Australia by 23 runs at the R. Premadasa Stadium.
This is only the second win of Zimbabwe over Australia in the T20 World Cup history, UNB reports. 
Defending a total of 169 for 2, the Zimbabwean bowling a</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 14:41:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Zonayed Saki thanks supporters after Brahmanbaria 6 win</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/zonayed-saki-thanks-supporters-after-brahmanbaria-6-win</link><description>Zonayed Saki, chief coordinator of Ganosamhati Andolon, has expressed gratitude to BNP allies, party activists and the people of Bancharampur after winning the Brahmanbaria 6 constituency in the national election.
Saki, who contested as part of the Bangladesh Nationalist Party led alliance, said i</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 15:29:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump: Too busy to be a defendant but plenty of time to sue</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/trump-too-busy-to-be-a-defendant-but-plenty-of-time-to-sue</link><description>Soon after winning reelection in November 2024, Donald Trump’s lawyers told a state judge in Delaware that a lawsuit brought against him by two co-founders of his social media company should be put on hold because a sitting president does not have time to deal with civil litigation.
Trump&amp;rs</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 15:44:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>SpaceX launches 12th long-duration crew to International Space Station</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/spacex-launches-12th-long-duration-crew-to-international-space-station</link><description>A SpaceX rocket soared into orbit from Florida early on Friday with a crew of two US NASA astronauts, a French astronaut and a Russian cosmonaut headed to the International Space Station for an eight-month science mission in microgravity.
The two-stage Falcon 9 rocket, topped with an autonomously</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 15:59:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UK congratulates Tarique as well as BNP on election victory</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/uk-congratulates-tarique-as-well-as-bnp-on-election-victory</link><description>The United Kingdom (UK) has congratulated BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman and his party - the Bangladesh Nationalist Party - on their victory in Bangladesh's 13th Jatiya Sangshad election.
The UK also greeted the people of Bangladesh as the country enters a new chapter.
"We look forward to working to</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 16:14:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>WTO chief calls for reform of global trading system</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/wto-chief-calls-for-reform-of-global-trading-system</link><description>The head of the World Trade Organization said that she agreed with US calls for reform of the global trading system ahead of a major meeting of the trade watchdog in Cameroon next month.
Last year, President Donald Trump signed an executive order imposing tariffs ranging from 10 percent to 41 perc</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 16:29:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP leader reopens closed AL office in Panchagarh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bnp-leader-reopens-closed-awami-league-office-in-panchagarh</link><description>A BNP leader on Friday has opened a closed party office of the Bangladesh Awami League in Panchagarh, triggering controversy within his own party.
The office was opened in the morning at Chaklahat Union in Panchagarh Sadar upazila by Abu Daud Pradhan, president of the Sadar upazila unit of BNP.
A</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 16:44:09 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>