<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 06:33:38 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Govt plans to merge Savar and Ashulia to form new city corporation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-plans-to-merge-savar-and-ashulia-to-form-new-city-corporation</link><description>Local Government Advisor Asif Mahmud Shojib Bhuyain has said Savar merged with Ashulia will be elevated to a city corporation, while Keraniganj will be upgraded to a ‘Class A’ municipality.
He said this in a Facebook post on Tuesday, reports bdnews24.com.
He wrote, “The governme</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 04:00:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nepalese envoy stresses deeper cooperation in key sectors</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/nepalese-envoy-stresses-deeper-cooperation-in-key-sectors</link><description>Nepalese Ambassador to Bangladesh Ghanashyam Bhandari has emphasised deepening bilateral cooperation in areas, including trade and investment, energy, education, tourism, people-to-people connections, and LDC graduation.
He delivered a lecture titled 'Nepal-Bangladesh Relations: Pathways for Enhan</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 04:15:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US may cut India tariff rate to 15-16pc in trade deal, Mint reports</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/global/us-may-cut-india-tariff-rate-to-15-16pc-in-trade-deal-mint-reports</link><description>India and the United States are nearing a long-stalled trade agreement that would reduce US tariffs on Indian imports to 15 per cent to 16 per cent from 50 per cent, India's Mint reported on Wednesday, citing three people aware of the matter.
The deal, which hinges on energy and agriculture, may s</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 04:30:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>31 killed in fuel truck explosion in Nigeria</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/africa/31-killed-in-fuel-truck-explosion-in-nigeria</link><description>A tanker truck laden with gasoline exploded Tuesday in north-central Nigeria, killing at least 31 people, police said.
The explosion occurred in the Bida area of Niger State after the truck fell and as local residents rushed to the scene to scoop up spilling fuel, police spokesman Wasiu Abiodun sa</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 04:45:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Airbus opens another jet assembly line in China</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/airbus-opens-another-jet-assembly-line-in-china</link><description>Airbus said on Wednesday it had opened a second assembly line in China, increasing manufacturing capacity for its best-selling A320neo family of single-aisle jets.
The European planemaker's 10th final assembly line globally, located in the port city of Tianjin near Beijing, is set to be fully oper</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 05:00:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Japan's new PM preparing large economic stimulus to tackle inflation, sources say</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/japans-new-pm-preparing-large-economic-stimulus-to-tackle-inflation-sources-say</link><description>Japan's new Prime Minister Sanae Takaichi is preparing an economic stimulus package that is likely to exceed last year's $92 billion to help households tackle inflation, government sources familiar with the plan said on Wednesday.
The package of more than 13.9 trillion yen ($92.19 billion) marks T</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 06:03:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>70pc banks yet to embrace AI in cybersecurity, BIBM survey finds</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/70pc-banks-yet-to-embrace-ai-in-cybersecurity-bibm-survey-finds</link><description>A recent survey by the Bangladesh Institute of Bank Management (BIBM) has revealed that the majority of banks in the country remain far from adopting artificial intelligence (AI) for automating incident response in cybersecurity operations.
According to the survey, about 70 per cent of banks have</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 06:33:36 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>