<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 07:23:41 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Teachers launch 'full' shutdown, schools closed across country</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/teachers-launch-full-shutdown-schools-closed-across-country</link><description>Assistant teachers of government primary schools announced that they launched a complete shutdown across the country on Wednesday until further notice to realise their three-point demand.
As part of the move, they have padlocked numerous schools, hampering ongoing annual examinations.
They also h</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 04:14:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DU regular classes to resume Dec 28</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/du-regular-classes-to-resume-dec-28</link><description>The Dhaka University (DU) has decided to reopen its residential halls and resume regular in-person classes from 28 December, following a technical assessment conducted after the recent earthquakes. To minimise the academic gap during the emergency closure, ongoing online classes will continue until</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 04:29:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Another Chinese medical team joins Khaleda’s treatment</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/another-chinese-medical-team-joins-khaledas-treatment</link><description>Another team of specialist doctors from China has arrived in Dhaka to assist in the treatment of BNP Chairperson Begum Khaleda Zia, who is undergoing treatment at Evercare Hospital in the capital.
The four-member team arrived at Evercare Hospital at 10:10 pm on Wednesday, said BNP media cell membe</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 04:44:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Editors' Council new exec body holds first meeting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/editors-council-new-exec-body-holds-first-meeting</link><description>First meeting of the newly-elected executive committee of the Editors' Council was held on Tuesday last (December 02), the apex platform of the editors in media outlets informed through a press release.
New Age Editor Nurul Kabir officially took the responsibility of president of the new committee</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 04:59:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BTRC conducts public hearing via Convay</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/btrc-conducts-public-hearing-via-convay</link><description>The Bangladesh Telecommunication Regulatory Commission (BTRC) has, for the first time, conducted its national public hearing entirely through Convay, a locally developed video-conferencing platform, marking a new milestone for domestic technology adoption in key government processes.
The sixth ann</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 05:14:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka may see shift in crime patterns ahead of national election: DB</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/dhaka-may-see-shift-in-crime-patterns-ahead-of-national-election-db</link><description>Dhaka may witness a shift in its crime patterns in the coming weeks ahead of the national election, as intelligence agencies fear a rise in sabotage, arson attacks, and politically driven violence.
In recent weeks, parts of the capital have experienced scattered incidents of crude bomb explosions,</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 05:29:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt revises school age rules</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-revises-school-age-rules</link><description>The government has revised age-related rules for student admission from first to ninth grade in public schools.
While the minimum age for first-grade admission remains five to seven years, the new policy removes the previous requirement that students entering higher classes must follow the same ag</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 05:44:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Child deaths will rise this year as aid cuts reverse progress, says Gates</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/child-deaths-will-rise-this-year-as-aid-cuts-reverse-progress-says-gates</link><description>Around 200,000 more children will likely die before their fifth birthday this year than in 2024 as international aid cuts undermine decades of progress, the Gates Foundation said on Thursday.
The projected increase would mark the first rise in preventable child deaths this century, Gates said, fro</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 05:45:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US lawmakers want war powers vote after Trump pledges Venezuela attack 'soon'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/us-lawmakers-want-war-powers-vote-after-trump-pledges-venezuela-attack-soon</link><description>A group of Democratic and Republican US senators filed a resolution on Wednesday that would block US military action against Venezuela without congressional approval, after President Donald Trump said a land campaign would begin shortly.
US troops have carried out at least 21 strikes on alleged dr</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 06:00:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Maduro says call with Trump was 'respectful and cordial'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/maduro-says-call-with-trump-was-respectful-and-cordial</link><description>Venezuelan President Nicolas Maduro on Wednesday confirmed he held a "respectful and cordial" phone call with US President Donald Trump about 10 days ago, framing the conversation as a potential opening for diplomacy.
"If this call means steps are being taken toward a respectful dialogue between o</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 06:15:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CRAB holds 21st Annual General Meeting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/crab-holds-21st-annual-general-meeting</link><description>The Credit Rating Agency of Bangladesh Ltd. (CRAB) held its 21st Annual General Meeting on December 3, 2025. The meeting was chaired by CRAB’s Chairperson Noor A. Alam Chowdhury.Also present were Board Members Tapan Chowdhury (Managing Director, SQUARE Pharmaceuticals Ltd.);  Asif Ibrahi</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 06:30:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pakistan to sell national airline PIA for IMF loans</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/pakistan-to-sell-national-airline-pia-for-imf-loans</link><description>Pakistan has taken a major step to sell its state-owned airline, Pakistan International Airlines (PIA), one more time on December 23, according to state media.
The long-struggling carrier is being privatised under the country’s $7.0 billion International Monetary Fund (IMF) bailout plan, whi</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 06:45:49 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>