<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 21:15:46 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Blasts injure dozens at Indonesian mosque, student suspected</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/blasts-injure-dozens-at-indonesian-mosque-student-suspected</link><description>Explosions at a mosque in Indonesia's capital Jakarta that injured dozens of people during Friday prayers could have been an attack, officials indicated, with a 17-year-old student identified as the suspected perpetrator.
Police said 55 people were in hospitals with a range of minor to serious inj</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 13:14:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fisherman dies over net casting clash in Sirajganj</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/fisherman-dies-over-net-casting-clash-in-sirajganj</link><description>A fisherman has died after allegedly being beaten by fellow fishermen during a dispute over net casting in Sirajganj.
The incident took place early on Friday in the Gohala River, said Shahjadpur Police chief Md Aslam Ali.
The dead has been identified as Bimal alias Tetul Hawlader, 60.
One of his</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 13:29:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Revolution of 1975 and July uprising stemmed from same context: Asif Mahmud</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/revolution-of-1975-and-july-uprising-stemmed-from-same-context-asif-mahmud</link><description>Youth and Sports Adviser Asif Mahmud Shojib Bhuiyan on Friday said that the Sepoy-People's Revolution of 1975 and the July Uprising of 2024 emerged from the same socio-political context.
"The context of the Sepoy-People's Revolution of 1975 is quite similar to that of the July Uprising of 2024. In</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 14:25:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP suspends three Sitakunda leaders</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-suspends-three-sitakunda-leaders</link><description>BNP has suspended three of its leaders in Sitakunda, Chattogram, over allegations of violating party discipline.
In a press release issued on Friday, signed by party Senior Joint Secretary General Ruhul Kabir Rizvi, the BNP said the action was taken for activities that went against the party&amp;rsquo</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 14:40:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Clashes, arson, vandalism erupt in Faridpur over BNP nomination</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/clashes-arson-vandalism-erupt-in-faridpur-over-bnp-nomination</link><description>Violence has erupted between supporters of two BNP leaders in Boalmari Upazila of Faridpur over the parliamentary polls nomination, leaving at least 20 people, including police, injured.
On Friday afternoon, the clash turned the Boalmari municipality, WAPDA intersection, and surrounding areas into</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 15:41:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Wellness Meets Finance: UCB chairman champions mindful living at Dhaka Flow Fest 2025</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/wellness-meets-finance-ucb-chairman-champions-mindful-living-at-dhaka-flow-fest-2025</link><description>In a city often rushing to meet the next deadline, a rare calm settled over Gulshan’s Shahabuddin Park. The air was alive with music, movement and mindful breathing as Dhaka Flow Fest 2025 returned a celebration that unites yoga, dance, art and conscious living under open skies.
Among the ma</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 16:11:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BRAC Bank inaugurates two new sub-branches in Shariatpur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/brac-bank-inaugurates-two-new-sub-branches-in-shariatpur</link><description>BRAC Bank has officially inaugurated two new sub-branches in Shariatpur District, bringing the total number of sub-branches in the bank's network to 107, according to a press release.
The sub-branches were inaugurated on October 23, 2025, by Md. Muniruzzaman Molla, Deputy Managing Director and Hea</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 16:26:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US snubs UN meeting on its human rights record</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-snubs-un-meeting-on-its-human-rights-record</link><description>A UN meeting to review the United States' human rights record opened without the US on Friday, with rights groups calling the absence a worrying sign of Washington's retreat from global engagement on such issues.
The universal periodic review process is a chance for governments and rights groups t</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 16:41:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Family accuses 'Boro Sajjad' of ordering Sarwar’s shooting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/family-accuses-boro-sajjad-of-ordering-sarwars-shooting</link><description>The father of slain Chattogram BNP activist Sarwar Hossain Babla has alleged that his son was killed on the orders of fugitive gang leader Sajjad Hossain, known locally as “Boro Sajjad”.
Sajjad, who is currently abroad, has been named as the prime suspect in a murder case filed by Sarw</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 17:56:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dreams before Aug 5 unfulfilled even after 15 months: Nur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/dreams-before-aug-5-unfulfilled-even-after-15-months-nur</link><description>Gono Odhikar Parishad President Nurul Haque Nur has said the aspirations people held before Aug 5 last year have not been fulfilled even 15 months later.
Speaking at a youth rally against drugs, terrorism and extortion at the central Shaheed Minar in Narayanganj on Friday evening, he said change c</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 18:11:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Seven ‘drug traders’ charged over murder of DU Chhatra Dal leader Shammo</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/seven-drug-traders-charged-over-murder-of-du-chhatra-dal-leader-shammo</link><description>Detective police have pressed charges against seven suspects, all identified as “drug dealers”, in the murder case of Jatiyatabadi Chhatra Dal leader SM Shahriar Alam Shammo.
Nearly five months after the murder, Inspector Md Akhtar Morshed of the Detective Branch (DB) submitted the cha</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 18:57:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Local goods behind 75.6pc of FY26 Q1 inflation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/local-goods-behind-756pc-of-fy26-q1-inflation</link><description>Bangladesh's inflation profile tilted further towards domestic sources, with home-grown supply constraints and cost pressures increasingly eclipsing imported shocks, according to the Bangladesh Bank analysis on inflation for the first quarter of the fiscal year 2025-26.
Domestically produced goods</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 19:12:21 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>