<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 10:24:08 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Patients suffer as intern doctors continue work stoppage at Osmani Hospital</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/patients-suffer-as-intern-doctors-continue-work-stoppage-at-osmani-hospital</link><description>Patients at Sylhet MAG Osmani Medical College Hospital are facing severe difficulties as intern doctors continue a work stoppage following an attack on a female intern doctor.
Intern doctors at the hospital have been on strike for 24 consecutive hours after failing to reach an agreement with the a</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 07:45:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka University Cultural Society welcomes new 'Oitri' batch</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/dhaka-university-cultural-society-welcomes-new-oitri-batch</link><description>The Dhaka University Cultural Society held its annual reception programme 'Oitri Baran' on Thursday at the TSC Auditorium, welcoming its newest batch of members with an evening of performances that stretched from 2 pm well into the night.
The event brought together students, faculty, and notable c</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 08:00:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BUET Entrepreneurs Network launches BUETEN Summit 2026</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/buet-entrepreneurs-network-launches-bueten-summit-2026</link><description>The BUET Entrepreneurs Network (BUETEN) has announced its flagship event, the BUETEN Summit 2026, to be held on January 23 and 24 at the Bangladesh University of Engineering and Technology (BUET) campus in Dhaka. Organised under the tagline "Connect. Innovate. Lead.", the summit will bring together</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 08:15:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two killed in Tangail road accident</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/two-killed-in-tangail-road-accident-1214</link><description>Two people were killed and two others injured in a road accident at Basail upazila of Tangail district last evening.
The deceased were identified as Milon, 24, son of Mintu Mia of Gosai Joyair area under Tangail Sadar upazila, and Arfan Khan, 75, son of late Moksed Khan of Chakpara area under Basa</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 08:30:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat leaders set to meet CA Yunus on Sunday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-leaders-set-to-meet-ca-yunus-on-sunday</link><description>Jamaat-e-Islami chief Shafiqur Rahman is scheduled to meet Chief Advisor Muhammad Yunus on Sunday.
A five-member delegation led by Shafiqur will hold the meeting with Yunus at the State Guest House Jamuna in the evening, according to a senior official at the Chief Advisor’s Office.
The me</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 07:45:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Six die in Karachi shopping mall fire</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/six-die-in-a-fire-at-shopping-mall-in-pakistans-karachi</link><description>At least six people have been killed in a massive fire that erupted at the Gul Plaza shopping mall in Pakistan’s Karachi, bdnews24.com reported citing Dawn.
The Pakistani newspaper said the operation to put out the blaze is still underway hours after it sparked.
On Sunday morning, South Dep</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 08:00:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Man arrested for ‘killing’ seven-year old daughter in Sherpur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/man-arrested-for-killing-seven-year-old-daughter-in-sherpur</link><description>A father allegedly strangled his daughter to death at Char Basanti Purba Para village of Nakla upazila of Sherpur on Sunday.
The deceased was Morium, 7, daughter of Babu Mia.
His another daughter, Mim Akter, aged three and a half years, was admitted to Sherpur District Hospital with injuries on n</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 08:15:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Police not protectors of any political party: Home adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/police-not-protectors-of-any-political-party-home-adviser</link><description>Home Affairs Adviser Lieutenant General (retd) Md Jahangir Alam Chowdhury on Sunday said the police are not protectors of any political party, as they are state employees funded by taxpayers’ money.
He emphasised that the primary responsibility of the police force is to serve the people and</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 08:30:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Minor boy killed in Jatrabari road crash</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/minor-boy-killed-in-jatrabari-road-crash</link><description>An 11-year-old boy was killed when a truck ran over him in the Jatrabari area of Dhaka on Sunday.
The deceased was identified as Md Zahid, 11, reports UNB.
Inspector Md Faruk, in charge of Dhaka Medical College and Hospital (DMCH) police camp, said the accident occurred around 12:30 am when the t</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 08:45:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Strong demand for cancellation of draft energy–power master plan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/strong-demand-for-cancellation-of-draft-energy-power-master-plan</link><description>Civil society organisations have strongly objected to the interim government’s 25-year “Energy &amp; Power Sector Master Plan (EPSMP): 2026-2050”.
At a press conference held on Sunday at the Dhaka Reporters Unity (DRU) auditorium, speakers demanded the immediate suspension and comple</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 09:00:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt clarifies CA’s support for ‘Yes’ vote in referendum</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-clarifies-cas-support-for-yes-vote-in-referendum</link><description>The interim government today (Sunday) clarified the Chief Adviser's support for the "Yes" vote in the forthcoming referendum is consistent with democratic norms in Bangladesh, outlining six major points in favour of the government's stance.
"Recent commentary has raised concerns that the Interim G</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 09:15:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt releases list of 80 vaccination centres for Hajj pilgrims</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-releases-list-of-80-vaccination-centres-for-hajj-pilgrims</link><description>The Ministry of Religious Affairs has published a list of 80 vaccination centres in the country for Hajj pilgrims to receive the required vaccines.
The ministry issued a notification in this regard, UNB reports. 
As per the Saudi government’s directives, Hajj pilgrims who have passed h</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 09:30:45 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>