<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 09:49:33 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>New York, New Jersey sue Trump administration over tunnel funding halt</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/new-york-new-jersey-sue-trump-administration-over-tunnel-funding-halt</link><description>New York and New Jersey late on Tuesday sued the Trump administration seeking an emergency court order to force the restoration of funding for the massive $16 billion Hudson River tunnel before construction is set to halt on Friday.
US President Donald Trump said in October he had terminated the p</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 06:12:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US says it has returned to Venezuela all $500 million of initial oil sale</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/us-says-it-has-returned-to-venezuela-all-500-million-of-initial-oil-sale</link><description>The United States has now returned to the Venezuelan government all $500 million from the initial sale of oil that was part of a deal reached between Caracas and Washington last month, a US official said on Tuesday.
The last $200 million from the sale has been sent to Venezuela, the official said,</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 06:27:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Election Commission holds coordination meeting with polling officers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/election-commission-holds-coordination-meeting-with-polling-officers</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has brought together central and field-level officials to fine-tune coordination for the national election and referendum.
Chief Election Commissioner AMM Nasir Uddin presided over the meeting at the Nirbachan Bhaban on Wednesday, joined by fellow commissioners, the EC</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 06:15:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pakistan sends helicopters, drones to end desert standoff; 58 dead</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/pakistan-sends-helicopters-drones-to-end-desert-standoff-58-dead</link><description>Pakistan's security forces used drones and helicopters to wrest control of a southwestern town from separatist insurgents after a three-day battle, police said on Wednesday, as the death toll in the weekend's violence rose to 58.
Saturday's wave of coordinated attacks by the separatist Baloch Libe</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 06:30:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Up to 40pc cancer cases preventable: WHO</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/up-to-40pc-cancer-cases-preventable-who</link><description>Up to 40 per cent of cancer cases worldwide are preventable, the World Health Organization (WHO) said Tuesday.
In a joint news release issued from Geneva and Lyon ahead of World Cancer Day, the WHO said the conclusion is based on a new global analysis conducted by the WHO and its International Age</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 06:45:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US says it shot down Iranian drone approaching aircraft carrier</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-says-it-shot-down-iranian-drone-approaching-aircraft-carrier</link><description>A US Navy fighter jet shot down an Iranian drone that was approaching the aircraft carrier USS Abraham Lincoln in the Arabian Sea, US Central Command said Tuesday, threatening to ramp up tensions as the Trump administration warns of possible military action to get Iran to the negotiating table.
Th</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 07:00:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh urges people-centred policies for social justice</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-urges-people-centred-policies-for-social-justice</link><description>Bangladesh has called for renewed global solidarity and people-centred policies to advance social development and social justice, stressing the need for inclusive, compassionate societies with equal opportunities for all.
Addressing the sixty-fourth session of the Commission for Social Development</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 07:15:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>90pc voters willing to participate in national polls: CRF Survey</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/90pc-voters-willing-to-participate-in-national-polls-crf-survey</link><description>About 90 per cent of voters have expressed their willingness to participate in the upcoming 13th national parliamentary election, according to a survey conducted by the Communication and Research Foundation (CRF).

The findings were revealed on Wednesday at the National Press Club during the rele</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 08:30:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC to postpone Sherpur-3 election following Jamaat candidate’s death</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-to-postpone-sherpur-3-election-following-jamaat-candidates-death</link><description>Election in the Sherpur-3 (Sreebardi–Jhenaigati) constituency is set to be postponed following the death of Jamaat-e-Islami–nominated candidate and district Jamaat secretary Nuruzzaman Badal, 51.
Under election laws, voting in a constituency must be suspended if a valid candidate dies.</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 08:45:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US-Iran drone incident raises fresh doubts over planned talks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-iran-drone-incident-raises-fresh-doubts-over-planned-talks</link><description>A tense aerial encounter between the United States and Iran on Tuesday has cast uncertainty over the prospects of upcoming talks between the two rivals.
Iranian media reported that a drone operated by Iran’s armed forces had completed a surveillance mission in international waters, monitorin</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 09:00:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Schoolboy killed in Narsingdi clash</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/schoolboy-killed-in-narsingdi-clash</link><description>A 14-year-old school student was shot dead in a clash between rival groups over establishing dominance in the Saidabad area in Raipura upazila of Narsingdi district on Wednesday.
The deceased was identified as Mustakim Mia, reports UNB.
Police and local sources said rivalry between two local grou</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 09:15:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP to make women self-reliant if voted to power: Tarique</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-to-make-women-self-reliant-if-voted-to-power-tarique</link><description>BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman on Wednesday said women would be made self-reliant if his party is voted to power in the national election.
While addressing a rally at Bell’s Park in Barishal city, he said mothers and daughters would receive primary healthcare services at home, without needing t</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 09:30:46 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>