<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 23:32:30 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Crowne Plaza Dhaka Airport inaugurated</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/crowne-plaza-dhaka-airport-inaugurated</link><description>Crowne Plaza Dhaka Airport has officially opened its doors at Centrepoint, marking a significant milestone in Bangladesh’s hospitality landscape.
The inauguration ceremony was held in the presence of distinguished guests, including advisors and directors of United Group, alongside representa</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 16:45:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Who holds which portfolios in Tarique’s cabinet</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tariques-cabinet-a-strategic-mix-of-trusted-veterans-and-new-faces</link><description>After leading his party to a landslide, Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) chief Tarique Rahman has assembled a 50-member cabinet combining a striking number of new faces alongside seasoned leaders.
The new government, sworn in on Tuesday at the South Plaza of parliament, consists of 25 ministers</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 17:00:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>28 trafficked Bangladeshi children, teens repatriated via Benapole</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/28-trafficked-bangladeshi-children-teens-repatriated-via-benapole</link><description>A total of 28 Bangladeshi children and teenagers trafficked to India were repatriated through the Benapole International Checkpost on Tuesday evening on special travel permits issued by the Indian authorities.
Among the returnees, 17 were children and 11 were teenagers. They were handed over by In</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 16:46:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique visits parents’ graves hours after taking oath</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-visits-parents-graves-hours-after-taking-oath</link><description>A few hours after being sworn in as Prime Minister, Tarique Rahman visited the graves of his parents on Tuesday night.
Tarique, along with his family members, went to the grave premises of his father, Ziaur Rahman and mother, Khaleda Zia, in the capital’s Sher-e-Bangla Nagar area around 8:30</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 17:01:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Global leaders attend Bangladesh new govt’s oath-taking ceremony</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/global-leaders-attend-bangladesh-new-govts-oath-taking-ceremony</link><description>Global  leaders on Tuesday attended the oath-taking ceremony of the new government led by Prime Minister Tarique Rahman, underscoring international interest in Bangladesh’s political transition. 
President of the Maldives Dr Mohamed Muizzu, Bhutanese Prime Minister Tshering Tobgay,</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 17:16:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh begins a new journey</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/bangladesh-begins-a-new-journey</link><description>For the people of Bangladesh the destination is the same now, as it was in 1947 and in 1971 e.g. freedom, democracy, inclusionary development and social harmony. The experience under Pakistan was one of disillusionment over the achievement of hopes and aspirations in respect of the destination adum</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 17:31:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Job loss foreshadows deeper economic strain</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/job-loss-foreshadows-deeper-economic-strain</link><description>For much of the past decade, Bangladesh has been celebrated as a  development model-an economy that expanded rapidly while reducing poverty and improving social indicators. Yet, behind the glow of growth figures, a harsh reality has been unfolding. The latest findings from the Research and Pol</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 17:46:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Modernising trade tax regime</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/modernising-trade-tax-regime</link><description>Bangladesh's trade tax is high and its structure is complex. Though formal customs duties might appear lower, extensive use of para-tariffs (supplementary and regulatory duties) has made the tax structure overly complicated. That has resulted in a large number of (some 50) effective tax rates. But</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 18:01:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique Rahman appointed PM, interim government dissolved</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-rahman-appointed-pm-interim-government-dissolved</link><description>The government has issued a gazette notification appointing BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman as the Prime Minister of Bangladesh, marking the dissolution of the interim government.
The Cabinet Division had earlier issued the relevant notification.
According to the gazette, under Article 56(3) of the C</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 18:16:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>On first working day, PM to pay tribute at Savar Memorial</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/on-first-working-day-pm-to-pay-tribute-at-savar-memorial-first-cabinet-meeting-in-afternoon</link><description>Bangladesh’s newly elected Prime Minister Tarique Rahman will begin his first full day in office on Wednesday by paying homage to the country’s martyrs at the National Martyrs’ Memorial in Savar.
In the afternoon, he will chair the first cabinet meeting of the newly formed govern</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 18:31:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Indian foreign secretary calls on Dr Shafiqur Rahman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/indian-foreign-secretary-calls-on-dr-shafiqur-rahman</link><description>India’s Foreign Secretary Vikram Misri held a courtesy meeting with Bangladesh’s Leader of the Opposition and Ameer of Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami Dr Shafiqur Rahman and discussed issues of mutual interest.
The meeting was held on the sidelines of the swearing-in ceremony of the new gov</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 18:46:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Triumphant Tarique takes oath as 11th PM</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/triumphant-tarique-takes-oath-as-11th-pm</link><description>Zia-family heir Tarique Rahman, who led his party to a sweeping electoral victory, becomes prime minister of Bangladesh to usher in what supporters describe as a new political era.
The swearing-in ceremony of the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) chair and his cabinet members was held Tuesday at</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 19:01:01 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>