<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 08:25:11 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>US, China seek to avoid trade war escalation, salvage Trump-Xi meeting in Malaysia talks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/us-china-seek-to-avoid-trade-war-escalation-salvage-trump-xi-meeting-in-malaysia-talks</link><description>Top economic officials from the US and China will face off in Kuala Lumpur on Saturday to try to avert an escalation of their trade war and ensure that a meeting happens next week between US President Donald Trump and Chinese President Xi Jinping.
The talks on the sidelines of the Association of S</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 05:26:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Thailand's Queen Mother Sirikit, influential style icon, dies at 93</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/thailands-queen-mother-sirikit-influential-style-icon-dies-at-93</link><description>Thailand's Queen Mother Sirikit, who brought glamour and elegance to a postwar revival in the country's monarchy and who, in later years, would occasionally wade into politics, has died aged 93, the Thai Royal Household Bureau said on Saturday.
Sirikit had been out of the public eye since a stroke</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 05:41:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hilsa fishing ban ends: Fishermen in Chandpur set to return to rivers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/hilsa-fishing-ban-ends-fishermen-in-chandpur-set-to-return-to-rivers</link><description>After a 22-day government ban, the Meghna and Padma rivers are set to come alive once again with the sound of boats and nets being cast, as nearly 43,000 fishermen in Chandpur prepare to resume hilsa fishing from Saturday midnight.
 
The annual restriction on catching, selling and tran</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 05:56:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Capturing cosmic beauty with a mobile phone</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/analysis/capturing-cosmic-beauty-with-a-mobile-phone</link><description>Does the night sky ever gaze at us? Does the Milky Way Galaxy ever want to reveal its presence by radiating its light? Late at night, when the city has gone quiet and many people are asleep at the end of a tiring day, a young man patiently waits on a rooftop or in a field, aiming his mobile phone a</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 06:11:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Lessons from Central African Republic</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/analysis/lessons-from-central-african-republic</link><description>The history of human civilization is more, or less, the cronicle of war and conflicts through the ages, inter-state or intra-state. The League of Nations, recognized as the first global organization formed after World War I in 1920, aimed to preserve world peace, stability, promoting global coopera</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 06:26:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Menacing proliferation of three-wheelers in Dhaka City</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/analysis/menacing-proliferation-of-three-wheelers-in-dhaka-city</link><description>The proliferation of auto-rickshaws has reached the tipping point where their earlier version of pedal rickshaws is on the verge of vanishing from the scene. Electricity stored in a battery pack through charging turns a motor into mechanical power to drive the three-wheelers. This is why the vehicl</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 06:41:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Retired officials from 25 BCS cadres demand retrospective promotion, citing discrimination</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/retired-officials-from-25-bcs-cadres-demand-retrospective-promotion-citing-discrimination</link><description>Retired officials from 25 Bangladesh Civil Service (BCS) cadres -- all except the administration cadre -- have demanded promotions and equal benefits, alleging discrimination in government service.
They also called for an ordinance based on key recommendations of the Public Administration Reform C</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 07:11:43 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>