<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 14:40:46 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Narsingdi teen rape-murder: Five arrested, hunt on for prime suspect</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/narsingdi-teen-rape-murder-five-arrested-hunt-on-for-prime-suspect</link><description>Police have arrested five people in connection with the rape and subsequent killing of a teenage girl in Narsingdi, allegedly carried out to conceal the crime.
A case has been filed against nine accused, while the prime suspect remains at large.
Dhaka Range Deputy Inspector General (DIG) Rezaul K</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 11:31:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>East India Company goes bankrupt, shuts down again after 170 years</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/east-india-company-goes-bankrupt-shuts-down-again-after-170-years</link><description>The East India Company, once the powerful British trading firm that ruled large parts of India, has shut down for a second time after its modern incarnation entered liquidation.
The original company, which played a central role in British colonial expansion in India, ceased to exist in the 19th ce</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 12:32:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Suspect Siam ‘confesses’ to murdering Rayerbazar schoolgirl in court</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/suspect-siam-confesses-to-murdering-rayerbazar-schoolgirl-in-court</link><description>The lone suspect in the murder of 14-year-old schoolgirl Shahriar Sharmin Binti in Rayer Bazar has given a “confessional” statement before a Dhaka court, according to police.
Hazaribagh Police Sub-Inspector Md Matiur Rahman, also the investigation officer, produced 19-year-old Siam Hos</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 12:47:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Vegetable prices cool down in Ctg markets</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/relief-for-shoppers-as-ramadan-driven-price-surge-cools-in-chattogram</link><description>Vegetable prices in Chattogram’s kitchen markets have begun to slide after a sharp hike during the first week of Ramadan, bringing much-needed relief to consumers.
A visit to the city's Reazuddin Bazar on Friday showed that most vegetable prices have dropped by Tk 10 to Tk 15 per kg within a</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 13:02:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>OIC leaders back Bangladesh bid for UN General Assembly presidency</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/oic-leaders-back-bangladesh-bid-for-un-general-assembly-presidency</link><description>Senior figures from across the Muslim world have expressed support for Bangladesh’s candidature to preside over the 81st session of the UN General Assembly, as Dhaka’s new government seeks to reposition itself diplomatically following a landslide election victory.
During bilateral meet</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 13:17:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Algerian president congratulates Bangladesh’s PM</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/algerian-president-congratulates-bangladeshs-pm</link><description>President of Algeria Abdelmadjid Tebboune has congratulated Bangladesh’s newly elected Prime Minister Tarique Rahman.
In a goodwill message, President Tebboune warmly commended Prime Minister Rahman on his election win.
He expressed admiration for the Prime Minister's leadership and vision</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 13:32:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Americans doubt Trump’s booming economy claim, Reuters/Ipsos poll finds</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/golden-age-americans-doubt-trumps-claim-of-booming-economy-as-midterms-near-reuters-ipsos-poll-finds</link><description>President Donald Trump says the US economy is booming and that he has fixed inflation. But most Americans, including many in his Republican Party, do not see things that way, according to a Reuters/Ipsos poll.
"This is the golden age of America," Trump said in his State of the Union address on Tue</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 13:18:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ex-SAD leader lands in jail over ‘attempted murder’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/former-sad-leader-riyad-3-others-sent-to-jail-over-attempted-murder</link><description>Abdur Razzak Bin Sulaiman Riyad, a former Students Against Discrimination leader previously accused of extortion, has been sent to jail in a new attempted murder case.
Three other students from Presidency University, Riadul Hawlader, Alif Ahmed Ashik, and Sayem Shikdaer, were also sent to prison a</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 13:33:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pakistan says its air strikes hit 22 Afghan military targets, killing 274</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/pakistan-says-its-air-strikes-hit-22-afghan-military-targets-killing-274</link><description>Pakistani air strikes hit 22 Afghan military targets, Pakistan's military spokesperson said on Friday, after heavy fighting between the South Asian neighbours that began overnight.
At least 12 Pakistani soldiers were killed and 274 Taliban officials and militants were killed since Thursday night,</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 13:48:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Investment drive key to economic uplift: Khosru</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/local-and-foreign-investment-vital-for-jobs-economic-transition-says-finance-minister</link><description>Finance and Planning Minister Amir Khosru Mahmud Chowdhury has stressed the importance of domestic and foreign investment for Bangladesh’s economic recovery.
Speaking on Friday during a visit to a proposed hospital site at Patenga Marine Drive in Chattogram, he said boosting investment is &amp;l</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 14:03:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Iran stored highly enriched uranium at underground site, IAEA report says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/iran-stored-highly-enriched-uranium-at-underground-site-iaea-report-says</link><description>Some of Iran's most highly enriched uranium, close to weapons grade, was stored in an underground area of its nuclear site in Isfahan, the UN nuclear watchdog said in a confidential report sent to member states on Friday and seen by Reuters.
It is the first time the International Atomic Energy Age</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 14:18:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Passengers detained at Dhaka airport with foreign currencies worth over Tk 38 million</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/passengers-detained-at-dhaka-airport-with-foreign-currencies-worth-over-tk-38-million</link><description>Two passengers have been detained at Shahjalal International Airport with foreign currencies worth over Tk 38 million, according to the Customs Intelligence and Investigation Directorate.
On Friday, the agency said in a media statement that the seized currencies from the detainees include Saudi ri</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 14:33:05 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>