<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 16:25:43 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Israel and Hamas sign ceasefire and hostage deal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/israel-and-hamas-sign-ceasefire-and-hostage-deal</link><description>Israel and the Palestinian militant group Hamas signed an agreement on Thursday to cease fire and free Israeli hostages in exchange for Palestinian prisoners, in the first phase of US President Donald Trump's initiative to end the war in Gaza.
Officials on both sides confirmed they had signed the</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 14:01:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCP pushes for ‘Water Lily’, demands removal of other national emblems</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ncp-pushes-for-water-lily-demands-removal-of-other-national-emblems</link><description>The National Citizen Party (NCP) on Thursday reiterated its call to the Election Commission to allocate ‘Water Lily’ as its electoral symbol.
The party also demanded that the Commission remove other national emblems, including the ‘Sheaf of Paddy’ and the ‘Star’</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 14:31:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Musk’s Tesla package pays him billions even if he misses ‘Mars-shot’ goals</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/musks-tesla-package-pays-him-billions-even-if-he-misses-mars-shot-goals</link><description>When Tesla directors offered Elon Musk the biggest executive pay package in corporate history in September, it reassured investors that he would have to achieve the equivalent of “Mars-shot milestones” to earn $878 billion in Tesla stock over 10 years.
The board’s proposal said M</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 14:46:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Third terminal at Dhaka airport to open soon: Commerce Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/third-terminal-at-dhaka-airport-to-open-soon-commerce-adviser</link><description>The Council of Advisers at a meeting on Thursday approved in-principle the drafts of 11 ordinances and three proposals.
Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus presided over the meeting held at his office.
The approved draft ordinances include the National Data Governance Ordinance, 2025, the Pers</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 14:02:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BCCCI Bi-annual election held followed by charge handover to newly elected EC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bccci-bi-annual-election-held-followed-by-charge-handover-to-newly-elected-ec</link><description>The charge-handover and taking over of charge by the newly elected Executive Committee (EC) of Bangladesh China Chamber of Commerce &amp; Industry (BCCCI) was held on Thursday (October 09, 2025) at the BCCCI office in Gulshan, Dhaka, presided over by Mst. Nargis Murshida, Administrator of BCCCI and Joi</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 14:32:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ADB brings together Japan-funded scholarship alumni to advance partnership and knowledge sharing</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/adb-brings-together-japan-funded-scholarship-alumni-to-advance-partnership-and-knowledge-sharing</link><description>Over 150 alumni of scholarships funded by Japan—including those supported by ADB–Japan Scholarship Program (ADB-JSP), Japan Ministry of Education, Culture, Sports, Science and Technology (MEXT), Japan International Cooperation Agency (JICA), International Monetary Fund (IMF), and the Wo</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 14:47:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New ordinance increases bank deposit protection to Tk 200,000</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/new-ordinance-increases-bank-deposit-protection-to-tk-200000</link><description>The government has approved a draft of the “Deposit Protection Ordinance, 2025”, which will increase the deposit guarantee from Tk 100,000 to Tk 200,000 for bank and financial institution depositors.
The ordinance was approved by the Advisory Council, ensuring that if a bank or financi</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 15:02:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New cyber safety ordinance provision clears Digital Security Act defendants</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/new-cyber-safety-ordinance-provision-clears-digital-security-act-defendants</link><description>The government has introduced a new provision in the Cyber Protection Ordinance, effectively dismissing all cases filed under the repealed Digital Security Act.
As a result, all individuals convicted or charged under the law will be granted immunity from the charges, according to the Chief Advisor</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 15:17:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shahidul Alam among flotilla detainees sent to Israeli prison</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/shahidul-alam-among-flotilla-detainees-sent-to-israeli-prison</link><description>Bangladeshi photographer and writer Shahidul Alam and several other activists detained from a Gaza-bound flotilla have been transferred to Ketziot Prison in Israel.
The information was confirmed by the Freedom Flotilla Coalition and Adalah – The Legal Center for Arab Minority Rights in Israe</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 15:32:05 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>