<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 15:24:11 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>EC redraws 4 Pabna, Faridpur seats</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/election-commission-redraws-boundaries-of-four-constituencies-in-pabna-faridpur</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has issued a gazette redefining the boundaries of four parliamentary constituencies in Pabna and Faridpur districts.
The four seats are Pabna-1, Pabna-2, Faridpur-2 and Faridpur-4.
The decision follows an order from the High Court division to revise the boundaries.
A</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 12:41:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DCCI lauds move to set up commercial court</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/dcci-lauds-move-to-set-up-commercial-court</link><description>Dhaka Chamber of Commerce &amp; Industry (DCCI) President Taskeen Ahmed has lauded the government initiative to set up the commercial court, calling it a timely step to strengthen commercial dispute resolution and improve Bangladesh’s pro-business climate.
Taskeen made the comments when he met C</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 12:56:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BB clarifies withdrawal limits for five merging banks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bb-clarifies-withdrawal-limits-for-five-merging-banks</link><description>Bangladesh Bank (BB) on Friday issued a clarification regarding the withdrawal of funds by depositors of five banks currently undergoing a merger process, cautioning the public against misinformation circulating in various media outlets.
“The process to allow depositors of these five banks t</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 13:11:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US says it struck Islamic State militants in northwest Nigeria</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-says-it-struck-islamic-state-militants-in-northwest-nigeria</link><description>The United States carried out a strike against Islamic State militants in northwest Nigeria at the request of Nigeria’s government, President Donald Trump and the U.S. military said on Thursday, claiming the group had been targeting Christians in the region.
“Tonight, at my direction a</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 13:26:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Israeli reservist rams vehicle into Palestinian man praying in West Bank</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/israeli-reservist-rams-vehicle-into-palestinian-man-praying-in-west-bank</link><description>An Israeli reservist soldier rammed his vehicle into a Palestinian man as he prayed on a roadside in the occupied West Bank on Thursday, after earlier firing shots in the area, the Israeli military said.
“Footage was received of an armed individual running over a Palestinian individual,&amp;rdqu</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 12:42:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nigeria averts unilateral US action by cooperating on airstrikes</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/africa/nigeria-averts-unilateral-us-action-by-cooperating-on-airstrikes</link><description>By publicly cooperating with the United States on Christmas Day airstrikes, Nigeria's government may have averted humiliating unilateral military action threatened a month ago by President Donald Trump.
But security experts say it is unclear whether such strikes can do much to hinder Islamist mili</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 12:57:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Sibyoun, Sanjay give sensational information’ in Hadi murder probe</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/sibyoun-sanjay-give-sensational-information-in-hadi-murder-probe</link><description>Investigators in the Sharif Osman bin Hadi murder case have told a Dhaka court that 'sensational' information has been gleaned during interrogation from two suspects arrested in a border area.
Sibyoun Diu and Sanjay Chisim were produced before the court on Friday after completing eight days of gri</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 13:12:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>2,900 incidents not ‘media exaggeration’: India on violence against minorities</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/india-2900-incidents-of-violence-against-minorities-no-way-media-exaggeration-or-political-violence</link><description>India has expressed grave concern over what it called “unremitting hostilities” against minorities in Bangladesh.
India’s foreign ministry spokesperson Randhir Jaiswal made the remark at his weekly media briefing on Friday.
“The unremitting hostilities against the minoriti</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 13:27:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No legal bar for Tarique Rahman to be registered as voter: EC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/no-legal-bar-for-tarique-rahman-to-be-registered-as-voter-ec</link><description>Election Commissioner Abdur Rahmanel Masud on Friday said there is no legal obstacle for BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman to be enlisted as a voter.
Talking to BSS, the election commissioner said the Election Commission has the authority to enlist any individual as a voter at any time under Sect</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 13:42:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BGB recovers 24 electric detonators along Sunamganj border</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/bgb-recovers-24-electric-detonators-along-sunamganj-border</link><description>Members of Border Guard Bangladesh (BGB) recovered 24 powerful electric detonators during a drive along Tahirpur border in Sunamganj district on Friday morning.
A patrol team of Charagaon Border Outpost (BOP) under Sunamganj Battalion conducted the drive near the border pillar 1195/1-S at Maizhati</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 13:57:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gulistan market fire contained</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/gulistan-market-fire-contained</link><description>The fire at the Khadder Bazar Shopping Complex in Dhaka’s Gulistan has been contained after about one and a half hours of effort.
Fire Service Media Officer Anwarul Islam said the flames were brought under control around 7pm on Friday.
Earlier, the Fire Service received reports of a fire in</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 14:12:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Launch loses route permit after Meghna collision</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/adventure-9-launch-route-permit-cancelled-after-fatal-meghna-collision</link><description>Authorities have cancelled the route permit of the MV Adventure-9 launch following a collision between two passenger vessels on the Meghna River in Chandpur that left four people dead.
Barishal Bangladesh Inland Water Transport Authority (BIWTA) Assistant Director Md Solaiman said on Friday evenin</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 14:27:55 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>