<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 12:48:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Soyuz spacecraft blasts off for International Space Station with Russian and American crew</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/soyuz-spacecraft-blasts-off-for-international-space-station-with-russian-and-american-crew</link><description>A Russian Soyuz MS-28 spacecraft blasted off for the International Space Station (ISS) on Thursday with two Russian cosmonauts and one NASA astronaut on board, a live stream of the launch showed.
The Soyuz 2.1a rocket lifted off from the Baikonur Cosmodrome in Kazakhstan at 12:28 pm Moscow time (0</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 10:27:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Arakan Army abducts 12 fishermen on two trawlers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/arakan-army-abducts-12-bangladeshi-fishermen-on-two-trawlers</link><description>Members of Myanmar’s Arakan Army armed insurgent group have captured two trawlers and abducted 12 more fishermen at work in the Bay of Bengal off the coast of Cox’s Bazar’s Teknaf Upazila.
They were abducted while fishing in the sea east of Chheradia on St Martin’s Island o</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 10:42:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh Bank orders pay cuts for Sammilito Islami Bank’s employees</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-bank-orders-pay-cuts-for-sammilito-islami-banks-employees</link><description>Bangladesh Bank has ordered a reduction in the salaries of employees from the five banks that have been merged to form the new ‘Sammilito Islami Bank’ (Combined Islamic Bank).
Sammilito Islami Bank’s Assistant Spokesperson Shahriar Siddiqui on Thursday said, “The decision t</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 10:57:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Beyond our vision, Shilpi's journey gives us hope</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/youth-and-entrepreneurship/beyond-our-vision-shilpis-journey-gives-us-hope</link><description>"Aapu, want to check your weight? Need a pen?" This familiar voice breaks the quiet at Ruqayyah Hall of the University of Dhaka. Some people stop by to buy something, some chat for a bit, and some quietly walk away. 
Behind that simple question is the story of a visually impaired young woman,</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 11:12:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pope Leo arrives in Turkey on closely watched first overseas trip</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/pope-leo-arrives-in-turkey-on-closely-watched-first-overseas-trip</link><description>Pope Leo arrived in Turkey on his first trip outside Italy as leader of the Catholic Church on Thursday and was expected to make appeals for peace in the Middle East and urge unity among long-divided Christian churches.
The first US pope chose mainly Muslim Turkey as his first overseas destination</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 10:28:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fakhrul visits ailing Jamaat leader Dr Taher in hospital</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fakhrul-visits-ailing-jamaat-leader-dr-taher-in-hospital</link><description>BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir on Thursday visited Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami Nayeb-e-Ameer Dr Syed Abdullah Mohammad Taher, who is receiving treatment at a city hospital.
“The BNP Secretary General went to United Hospital around 1pm to meet the ailing Jamaat leader,&amp;rdquo</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 10:58:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dengue Crisis: 7 dead; 567 hospitalised in 24 hours</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dengue-crisis-7-dead-567-hospitalised-in-24-hours</link><description>The dengue situation in Bangladesh continues to deteriorate, with seven more deaths and 567 new hospitalisations recorded across the country in the 24 hours till Thursday morning.
According to the Directorate General of Health Services (DGHS), the latest fatalities bring this year’s death to</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 11:13:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Economy trapped in vicious cycle of high rates, weak growth: Dr Zaidi Sattar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/economy-trapped-in-vicious-cycle-of-high-rates-weak-growth-dr-zaidi-sattar</link><description>Bangladesh’s economy has slipped into a vicious circle of high interest rates, persistent inflation, weak investment and slowing GDP growth, making it increasingly difficult to break out of the cycle, said Dr Zaidi Sattar, Chairman of the Policy Research Institute of Bangladesh (PRI).
Speaki</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 11:28:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Demand for MPO listing: Teachers' sit-in enters 26th day</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/demand-for-mpo-inclusion-teachers-sit-in-on-day-26-finance-ministry-siege-withdrawn</link><description>Teachers have held a sit-in protest for the 26th straight day demanding the inclusion of all recognised non-MPO educational institutions under the government’s monthly pay order (MPO) scheme.
The teachers, who have been continuously stationed outside the National Press Club in Dhaka, had ann</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 11:43:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rohingya crisis returns to global spotlight under interim govt: Shafiqul Alam</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rohingya-crisis-returns-to-global-spotlight-under-interim-govt-shafiqul-alam</link><description>Chief Adviser’s Press Secretary Shafiqul Alam on Thursday said that bringing the Rohingya crisis back onto the international agenda is one of the success stories of the interim government, claiming that the issue had become a “forgotten” matter during the previous regime.
“</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 11:58:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Judge astounded over Hasina’s ‘stunning greed for wealth’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/judge-astounded-over-hasinas-stunning-greed-for-wealth</link><description>A stunned silence swept across the packed courtroom when Judge Mohammad Abdullah Al Mamun paused mid-observation and asked: “Sheikh Hasina is a political leader, a four-time prime minister. Why does she need so much money, so much wealth?”
In a scathing rebuke during the verdict over t</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 12:13:56 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>