<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 15:19:34 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Jamaat’s Shafiqur blasts interim govt over attack on ‘July warriors’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jamaats-shafiqur-blasts-interim-govt-over-attack-on-july-warriors</link><description>Jamaat-e-Islami chief Shafiqur Rahman has condemned the interim government after police allegedly attacked participants of the July Movement, describing the incident as “shameful” and “deeply painful”.
Speaking at a workers’ rally at Mirpur Dhaka on Friday, Shafiqur s</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 13:13:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Three sent to jail in Malibagh jewellery shop heist case</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/three-sent-to-jail-in-malibagh-jewellery-shop-heist-case</link><description>A court in Dhaka on Friday sent three people to jail in a case lodged over the sensational jewellery shop theft at Fortune Shopping Mall in Malibagh in the capital on October 8.
The three accused are Anita Roy, Md Nurul Islam, and Uttam Chandra Sur.
Dhaka Metropolitan Magistrate Mehera Mahbub pas</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 13:28:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Moyeen Khan urges inclusion of ‘July forerunners’ in Charter</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/moyeen-khan-urges-inclusion-of-july-forerunners-in-charter</link><description>BNP Standing Committee Member Dr Abdul Moyeen Khan on Friday stressed the need for including the ‘July forerunners’ in the July Charter to make it more meaningful.
In his reaction to the evolving situation over the signing of the Charter, he said the current situation is “complet</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 13:43:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>​​​​​Will move forward to Feb polls with this tune of unity: Yunus tells politicians</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/will-move-forward-to-feb-polls-with-this-tune-of-unity-prof-yunus-tells-politicians</link><description>Urging political leaders to have talks for a fair and festive election, Chief Adviser Prof Muhammad Yunus on Friday said that the signing of the ‘July National Charter 2025’ symbolises a tune of unity and this unity will guide them towards the upcoming national election.
He expressed o</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 13:25:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>International cricket returns to Bogura after 16 years</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/international-cricket-returns-to-bogura-after-16-years</link><description>The International cricket is set to return to Bogura after almost 16 years when Bangladesh Under-19 team will play two youth ODIs against the Afghanistan counterpart.
Afghanistan youth team is scheduled to arrive in Bangladesh on October 20 to play a five-match youth ODI series, which is seen as t</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 13:40:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladeshi transwoman arrested in Mumbai over human trafficking</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladeshi-transwoman-arrested-in-mumbai-over-human-trafficking</link><description>Mumbai Police have arrested a Bangladeshi transgender woman who had allegedly been living in India for nearly three decades using forged identity documents, reports NDTV.
The suspect, identified as Babu Ayan Khan, alias Jyoti or “Guru Maa”, was arrested on Thursday.
She is accused of</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 14:10:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fire at Sylhet REB control room cuts power to 5 upazilas</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fire-at-sylhet-reb-control-room-cuts-power-to-5-upazilas</link><description>A massive fire broke out at the switching control room of the Rural Electrification Board in Fenchuganj, Sylhet, leaving five surrounding upazilas without power.
The fire started around midnight on Thursday, October 16 at the control room located in the Palbari area of Fenchuganj upazila.
Firefig</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 14:25:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Madagascar coup leader Randrianirina sworn in as president</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/africa/madagascar-coup-leader-randrianirina-sworn-in-as-president</link><description>Madagascar’s coup leader Colonel Michael Randrianirina was sworn in as president on Friday to cheers, blaring trumpets and raised swords, days after taking control of the island nation in the wake of youth-led protests that forced out his predecessor.
Ex-leader Andry Rajoelina, whom lawmaker</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 15:10:24 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>