<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 04:08:31 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Strengthening economic cooperation with Australia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/strengthening-economic-cooperation-with-australia</link><description>Bangladesh and Australia like to describe each other as "old friends", and the phrase is not just diplomatic rhetoric. Australia was among the first countries to recognise Bangladesh after its independence in 1971. More than half a century later, that early political goodwill has matured into a rel</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 20:45:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Negotiable Instruments Act 2025</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/negotiable-instruments-act-2025</link><description>Only days before did the Ministry of Law (MoL) reject the draft of the Artha Rin Adalat Ain (Money Loan Court Act), suggesting amendment to the existing laws instead of getting ready a whole new Act. Now the council of advisers of the interim government has approved a similar but stringent law, the</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 21:00:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Interest income shock halves Jamuna Oil's Q2 profit</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/interest-income-shock-halves-jamuna-oils-q2-profit</link><description>Jamuna Oil Company's profit halved year-on-year to Tk 691 million in the second quarter of FY26 as it failed to realise interest income from deposits in Islamic banks that have been merged to salvage them from a liquidity crisis.
The state-run company holds fixed deposit receipts (FDRs) amounting</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 02:15:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Peninsula Chittagong comes out of the red, aided by cost cuts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/peninsula-chittagong-comes-out-of-the-red-aided-by-cost-cuts</link><description>The Peninsula Chittagong posted a profit of Tk 6.27 million in the second quarter (October-December) of FY26, rebounding from losses in the same quarter a year earlier, mainly due to reduced salary and tax expenses.
The listed hotel recorded less than 3 per cent growth in sales to Tk 111.45 millio</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 02:30:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BFFEA calls for lifting suspension of vannamei post-larvae import approvals</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/bffea-calls-for-lifting-suspension-of-vannamei-post-larvae-import-approvals</link><description>Voicing concerns over the recent suspension of all new and existing approvals for the import of post-larvae for vannamei shrimp farming, the country's shrimp and fish exporters have urged the government to withdraw the decision.
Bangladesh Frozen Food Exporters Association (BFFEA) in a statement t</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 02:14:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Stay on alert to ensure free, fair elections</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/stay-on-alert-to-ensure-free-fair-elections</link><description>Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus on Monday directed the Armed Forces to remain on the highest level of alert to ensure a free, fair, neutral and widely acceptable electoral environment ahead of the referendum and the 13th national parliamentary election scheduled for 12 February.
Speaking at</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 02:29:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Policy, tech-driven reforms yield over 14pc more revenue</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/policy-tech-driven-reforms-yield-over-14pc-more-revenue</link><description>Some rigorous policy, administrative, structural and technology-driven reforms under the
post-uprising interim government of Bangladesh contributed to revenue-earning growth by over 14 per cent.
A report submitted by the National Board of Revenue (NBR) to Chief Adviser Dr Mohammad Yunus reveals a</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 02:44:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat ameer pledges safe society, workplace for women</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-ameer-pledges-safe-society-workplace-for-women</link><description>Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami Ameer Dr Shafiqur Rahman has said his party will ensure a safe society and workplace for women.
He has also rejected the idea of confining women to their houses.
"Women will not be locked inside home. Rather, they will live in a safe society and work in safe workplaces,</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 02:59:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt losing millions in revenue due to misuse of bonded warehouse facilities</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/govt-losing-millions-in-revenue-due-to-misuse-of-bonded-warehouse-facilities</link><description>The government is reportedly losing millions of dollars in revenue each year due to the misuse of bonded-warehouse facilities in the textile sector, industry insiders say.
According to stakeholders, weak monitoring and widespread abuse of the bonded system are not only causing massive revenue loss</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 03:14:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Businesses oppose move to drop requirement</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/businesses-oppose-move-to-drop-requirement</link><description>Business leaders have voiced strong opposition to the commerce ministry's proposal to remove the requirement for chamber-or trade-association membership certificates when issuing or renewing import registration certificates (IRCs), warning that the move could heighten the risk of fraudulent trade a</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 03:29:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Expand purview of universal health coverage</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/expand-purview-of-universal-health-coverage</link><description>Speakers at a dialogue on Monday suggested widening the purview of the universal health coverage (UHC), saying it should include neglected areas, such as mental health, antimicrobial resistance, oral health, occupational health and safety, and emergency care.
There had been a growing concern over</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 03:44:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BJMA, BJSA threaten to shut their mills from Feb 1 unless raw-jute hoarding stopped</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bjma-bjsa-threaten-to-shut-their-mills-from-feb-1-unless-raw-jute-hoarding-stopped</link><description>The country's jute mill owners have threatened to shut their mills across the country from February 1 unless the government takes effective steps against raw-jute hoarding and ensure a steady supply of raw materials.
The Bangladesh Jute Mills Association (BJMA) and Bangladesh Jute Spinners Associa</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 03:59:05 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>