<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 10:28:20 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Two earthquakes shake Sylhet within five minutes</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/two-earthquakes-shake-sylhet-within-five-minutes</link><description>Two mild earthquakes were felt in Sylhet just five minutes apart in the early hours of Wednesday, according to the European-Mediterranean Seismological Centre (EMSC).
India’s National Centre for Seismology (NCS) reported that the first tremor struck at 2:50 am, registering a magnitude of 3.5</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 06:36:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Beacon Pharmaceuticals MD Md Ebadul Karim passes away</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/beacon-pharmaceuticals-md-md-ebadul-karim-passes-away</link><description>Md Ebadul Karim, managing director of Beacon Pharmaceuticals PLC, and director of Kohinoor Chemicals Co. (BD) Ltd, passed away on Thursday.
He breathed his last at 9:00 am while undergoing treatment at a hospital in Dhaka.
Karim was a prominent figure in Bangladesh’s pharmaceutical and cons</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 07:31:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A man filed a July Uprising case over the murder of his brother. Police have now found the victim alive</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/a-man-filed-a-july-uprising-case-over-the-murder-of-his-brother-police-have-now-found-the-victim-alive</link><description>A police investigation into a murder case filed over an incident during the July Uprising has found the alleged victim alive. Law enforcers believe it was part of a conspiracy by the plaintiff – the alleged victim’s brother – that attempted to use the mass uprising as cover.
Now,</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 07:46:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Coca-Cola names a company veteran as its new CEO</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/coca-cola-names-a-company-veteran-as-its-new-ceo</link><description>Coca-Cola said Wednesday that its chief operating officer will become its next CEO in the first quarter of 2026. 
The Atlanta beverage giant said its board elected Henrique Braun as CEO effective March 31. James Quincey, Coke's current chairman and CEO, will transition to executive chairman o</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 08:01:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>RAB official’s wife killed by thieves at home</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/rab-officials-wife-killed-by-thieves-at-home</link><description>A 40-year-old housewife was killed allegedly by a gang of thieves at Shimlapolli in Sarishabari municipality area of Jamalpur district on Thursday.
The deceased was identified as Lipi Begum, wife of Mohor Ali, assistant sub-inspector of RAB-2 in Mohammadpur area of the capital, reports UNB.
Bachh</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 08:16:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>One killed in clash between Chhatra Dal factions in Mirsharai</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/one-killed-in-clash-between-chhatra-dal-factions-in-mirsharai</link><description>A man has been killed in a clash between two factions of the Chhatra Dal, the BNP’s student wing, in Chattogram’s Mirsharai Upazila.
Police and witnesses said the incident unfolded on Wednesday night in the Sadar area of the Baroirhat Municipality.
The victim was identified as 23-ye</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 08:31:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Over 300k expatriates enrolled for postal voting system</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/over-300k-expatriates-enrolled-for-postal-voting-system</link><description>More than 300,000 expatriate Bangladeshis have already registered to take part in the country’s first-ever postal voting initiative, marking a milestone in efforts to enfranchise citizens living abroad.
The Election Commission (EC) reported that a total of 307,577 overseas Bangladeshis had c</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 08:46:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DMTC staff to begin full work stoppage Friday over delay in service rules</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dmtc-staff-to-begin-full-work-stoppage-friday-over-delay-in-service-rules</link><description>Regular officers and employees of Dhaka Mass Transit Company Limited (DMTC) have announced a full work stoppage and suspension of all passenger services from 7am on Friday (December 12), protesting the authorities’ failure to formulate and publish a comprehensive service rule.
Employees said</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 09:01:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>HC rules marriage and divorce registration must be digitalised</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hc-rules-marriage-and-divorce-registration-must-be-digitalised</link><description>The High Court has ruled that marriage and divorce registration has to be digitalised, according to a bdnews24.com report.
The bench of Justice Fahmida Quader and Justice Md Ashif Hasan delivered its verdict on Thursday after the final hearing of a petition over the matter.
Advocate Ishrat Hasa</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 09:16:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Asif leaning towards joining Gono Odhikar Parishad, Mahfuj’s path unclear</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/asif-leaning-towards-joining-gono-odhikar-parishad-mahfujs-path-unclear</link><description>After resigning from his government post, Asif Mahmud Shojib Bhuyain is leaning towards joining the Gono Odhikar Parishad (GOP).
Although he has not shared any official decision on the matter, the GOP has dropped hints, reports bdnews24.com.
However, another student advisor - Mahfuj Alam, who has</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 09:31:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Only one-third of listed companies appoint women independent directors as deadline nears</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/only-one-third-of-listed-companies-appoint-women-independent-directors-as-deadline-nears</link><description>Only 138 out of 360 listed companies have so far appointed women independent directors, despite an extended deadline that expires on December 31, said Bangladesh Securities and Exchange Commission (BSEC) Commissioner Farzana Lalarukh on Thursday.
“After the deadline, we will take action as p</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 09:46:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Youth essential to building safer migration pathways: speakers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/youth-essential-to-building-safer-migration-pathways-speakers</link><description>Youth must be placed at the centre of Bangladesh’s migration governance to build safer and more resilient mobility systems, speakers said at a national dialogue in Dhaka on Thursday.
They noted that young people already constitute a major share of global migrants and that their perspectives</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 10:01:53 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>