<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 12:46:47 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Settle applications of expat voters by Thursday: EC to field officials</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/settle-applications-of-expat-voters-by-thursday-ec-to-field-officials</link><description>The Election Commission has directed its field officials to dispose of applications, filed by expatriate Bangladeshis for registering as voters, by Thursday (Nov 6) ahead of the general election.
All applications submitted by October 31, 2025 must be resolved by November 6, following the completio</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 10:25:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat forms 2-member committee to hold talks with political parties</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-forms-2-member-committee-to-hold-talks-with-political-parties</link><description>Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami has formed a two-member committee to hold discussions with political parties to formulate a framework over the electoral structure, July Charter implementation and a referendum based on consensus.
The political party issued a statement in this regard on Wednesday.
The d</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 09:48:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ACC to sue Joy, Saima, Radwan, and former NBR chair Mosharraf over alleged money laundering</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/acc-to-sue-joy-saima-radwan-and-former-nbr-chair-mosharraf-over-alleged-money-laundering</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) has decided to file a case against eight individuals, including Sajeeb Ahmed Wazed Joy, Saima Wazed, and Radwan Mujib Siddiq, on charges of money laundering, misuse of power, and causing financial losses to the state while implementing political a</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 10:33:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Army to deploy up to 100,000 troops during election: HQ</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/army-to-deploy-up-to-100000-troops-during-election-hq</link><description>The Bangladesh Army will deploy between 90,000 and 100,000 personnel across the country during the upcoming national elections, the highest-ever deployment in the nation’s electoral history.
Brigadier General Dewan Md Monjur Hossain, Director of Military Operations at the Army Headquarters,</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 11:03:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Death toll rises to 11 in fire at Bosnian retirement home</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/death-toll-rises-to-11-in-fire-at-bosnian-retirement-home</link><description>The death toll from a fire at a retirement home in Tuzla in northern Bosnia rose to 11 on Wednesday and about 30 people were injured, police said.
The blaze engulfed the seventh floor of the old nine-storey building at around 1945 GMT on Tuesday, sending flames and smoke pouring out of the top flo</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 11:33:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Probe finds pilot's error in Milestone School aircraft crash</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/probe-body-recommends-shifting-all-baf-initial-trainings-outside-dhaka</link><description>The investigation committee formed over an Air Force training aircraft crash at Milestone School and College found the pilot's operational error and recommended that all Air Force initial training be conducted outside Dhaka.
"The probe body concluded that the tragedy resulted from a pilot's operat</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 12:03:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCP denies discussing seat-sharing or cabinet participation with any party</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ncp-denies-discussing-seat-sharing-or-cabinet-participation-with-any-party</link><description>National Citizens’ Party (NCP) on Wednesday clarified that it has not held any discussions or reached any decisions with any political party regarding seat-sharing or participation in any cabinet.
In a statement, the NCP refuted a report published in a national daily claiming that the party</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 12:18:33 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>