<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 09:17:26 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>LPG cylinder prices should be below Tk 1,000, says energy adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/lpg-cylinder-prices-should-be-below-tk-1000-says-energy-adviser</link><description>Energy Adviser Fouzul Kabir Khan has stressed the need to bring down the price of a 12kg liquefied petroleum gas (LPG) cylinder below Tk 1,000, urging the private sector to boost efficiency and end the practice of profiteering.
Speaking at a policy dialogue on Bangladesh’s LPG sector organis</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 06:27:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Environment human rights defenders’ protection must be ensured: Rizwana</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/environment-human-rights-defenders-protection-must-be-ensured-rizwana</link><description>Environment Adviser Syeda Rizwana Hasan on Saturday stressed the need to ensure the protection of environmental human rights defenders and bring their safety under a legal framework.
"Environmental defenders around the world are facing killings and violence, an issue that the United Nations has hi</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 06:57:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Resolve trade tensions, maintain stability for sustainable global growth: IMF</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/global/resolve-trade-tensions-maintain-stability-for-sustainable-global-growth-imf</link><description>The International Monetary Fund (IMF) has urged countries to resolve trade disputes, maintain financial stability, and implement key reforms to ensure sustainable global economic growth.
In its latest assessment, the IMF said the world economy stands at a crossroads. Despite resilience over the pa</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 06:48:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh sees unseasonal showers as monsoon withdrawal delayed</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-sees-unseasonal-showers-as-monsoon-withdrawal-delayed</link><description>Unseasonal rains have continued across Bangladesh over the past several days, disrupting normal life and prompting questions about the unusual weather pattern.
"The rains are continuing because the monsoon axis is passing over Bangladesh this time. The rainfall could continue until mid-October," M</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 07:33:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DSCC launches clean-up drive at DU, BUET and Dhaka Medical College</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dscc-launches-clean-up-drive-at-du-buet-and-dhaka-medical-college</link><description>The Dhaka South City Corporation (DSCC) will work in tandem with Dhaka University (DU), the Bangladesh University of Engineering and Technology (BUET), and Dhaka Medical College Hospital (DMCH) to maintain cleanliness on their campuses.
Furthermore, no illegal shops will be allowed to operate on t</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 08:03:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Security the biggest challenge in upcoming polls: CEC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/security-the-biggest-challenge-in-upcoming-polls-cec</link><description>Chief Election Commissioner (CEC) AMM Nasir Uddin has highlighted security as the "biggest challenge" in organising Bangladesh’s upcoming 13th parliamentary election as the Election Commission (EC) prepares for what it calls the most transparent polls in the country’s history.
Speaking</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 08:18:11 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>