<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 16:29:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Legal reforms key to strengthening loan recovery: NCC Bank AMD</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/legal-reforms-key-to-strengthening-loan-recovery-ncc-bank-amd</link><description>Emphasising the urgent need for comprehensive legal reforms to strengthen Bangladesh’s banking sector, Additional Managing Director of NCC Bank PLC M. Khurshed Alam has outlined a series of proposals aimed at enhancing loan recovery and improving the effectiveness of the Artha Rin Adalat Act.</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 13:33:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DUCSU, Chhatra Dal leaders trade extortion allegations over campus shops</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/ducsu-chhatra-dal-leaders-trade-extortion-allegations-over-campus-shops</link><description>Dhaka University Central Students’ Union (DUCSU) and Jatiyatabadi Chhatra Dal leaders have traded allegations over extortion involving shops on the Dhaka University campus.
On Saturday night, DUCSU executive member Sarba Mitra Chakma alleged in a Facebook post that Nurul Gani Sagir, VP candi</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 13:48:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NRBC Bank holds BIZCON2026</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/nrbc-bank-holds-bizcon2026</link><description>NRBC Bank PLC successfully hosted its Annual Business Conference, BIZCON2026 — “Leading the Change,” last Saturday at a hotel.
 Mr. Md. Ali Hossain Prodhania, Chairman of the Board, attended as Chief Guest, according to a media release. 
 The conference was chaired by Manag</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 14:03:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Market stable, prices likely to ease further in Ramadan: Commerce adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/market-stable-prices-likely-to-ease-further-in-ramadan-commerce-adviser</link><description>Bangladesh’s market remains stable with no supply crunch, and the prices of essential commodities are expected to decline further during Ramadan, Commerce Adviser Sheikh Bashir Uddin said on Sunday.
Talking to journalists after the 10th meeting of the Taskforce Committee on reviewing prices</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 14:18:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US judge blocks Trump administration's push to end legal status of 8,400 migrants</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/us-judge-blocks-trump-administrations-push-to-end-legal-status-of-8400-migrants</link><description>A federal judge has blocked the Trump administration's push to terminate the legal status of more than 8,400 family members of US citizens and green card holders who moved to the United States from seven Latin American countries.
Boston-based US District Judge Indira Talwani issued a preliminary i</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 14:33:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh’s absence from T20 WC a 'sad moment' for cricket: WCA</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/cricket/bangladeshs-absence-from-t20-wc-a-sad-moment-for-cricket-wca</link><description>The absence of Bangladesh from next month's Twenty20 World Cup is a sad moment for the game and should serve as a call for stakeholders to work towards uniting the sport, not dividing it, the international cricketers' association said on Sunday.
The Tigers were replaced by Scotland in the 20-team</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 14:48:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India will establish world peace under Modi’s leadership: Minister Shekhawat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/india-will-establish-world-peace-under-modis-leadership-minister-shekhawat</link><description>India’s Union Minister for Culture and Tourism Gajendra Singh Shekhawat stated that under the leadership of Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi, India is working to establish peace in the world by following the path of Buddha.
Addressing the Second Global Buddhist Summit held in Bharat Manda</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 14:45:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Noakhali my maternal ancestral home, ensure BNP’s victory’, says Tarique</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/noakhali-my-maternal-ancestral-home-ensure-bnps-victory-says-tarique</link><description>BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman on Sunday urged voters to ensure victory for the party’s ‘Sheaf of Paddy’ candidates in all seats of greater Noakhali, referring to the area as his maternal ancestral home.
“Assalamu Alaikum. How are you all? I have come to Feni after so many yea</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 15:00:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DBM forms human wall to protest inequality</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dbm-forms-human-wall-to-protest-inequality</link><description>The Democratic Budget Movement (DBM) organized a human wall in front of the Jatiya Sangsad Bhaban on Manik Mia Avenue on Sunday afternoon to protest growing economic and social inequality in Bangladesh and globally.
The event aimed to draw policymakers’ attention to the need for fair and inc</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 15:15:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DSE, CSE end week’s first session in red</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/dse-cse-end-weeks-first-session-in-red</link><description>Trading on the country’s bourses ended on a bearish note on Sunday, the first working day of the week, as both the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) and the Chittagong Stock Exchange (CSE) witnessed index falls amid declining turnover and broad-based price erosion.
At the DSE, the benchmark DSEX sh</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 15:30:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jailed BCL leader’s wife, infant son laid to rest in Bagerhat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jailed-bcl-leaders-wife-infant-son-laid-to-rest-in-bagerhat</link><description>A young woman and her nine-month-old son, who died in a tragic case of murder-suicide perpetrated by the mother at their home in Sabekdanga village of Bagerhat Sadar upazila, were laid to rest late Saturday night.
The namaz-e-janaza of Kaniz Surbana Swarnali, 22, and her infant son Nazim Hossain S</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 15:45:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>15 hurt in Lalmonirhat BNP-Jamaat clash</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/15-hurt-in-lalmonirhat-bnp-jamaat-clash</link><description>A violent clash has broken out in Hatibandha Upazila of Lalmonirhat between activists of the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) and Jamaat-e-Islami amid election campaigning.
At least 15 people from both sides were injured in Sunday’s incident, and four to five motorcycles were damaged, spre</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 16:00:55 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>