<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 13:07:16 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Apex Footwear Ltd. successfully concludes Apex Golf Tournament 2026 at Army Golf Club</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/apex-footwear-ltd-successfully-concludes-apex-golf-tournament-2026-at-army-golf-club</link><description>Apex Footwear Limited successfully concluded the much awaited Apex Golf Tournament 2026 at the prestigious Army Golf Club, Dhaka, marking yet another milestone in the company’s commitment to promoting sportsmanship and community engagement. 
Held from January 14 to January 17, 2026, the</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 10:12:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Iranian police say 139 foreigners arrested over unrest in Yazd province</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/iranian-police-say-139-foreigners-arrested-over-unrest-in-yazd-province</link><description>Iranian police said 139 foreign nationals have so far been arrested in the central province of Yazd for their participation in recent protests, the semi-official Tasnim news agency reported on Tuesday, without specifying their nationalities.
Yazd, a predominantly desert province with a relatively</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 10:27:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Spain to ban social media access for children under 16</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/spain-to-ban-social-media-access-for-children-under-16</link><description>Spain will ban access to social media for minors under 16 and platforms will be required to implement age verification systems, Prime Minister Pedro Sanchez said on Tuesday at the World Government Summit in Dubai.
"Our children are exposed to a space they were never meant to navigate alone... We w</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 10:42:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP’s Tarique Rahman heads to Barishal, Faridpur on Wednesday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnps-tarique-rahman-heads-to-barishal-faridpur-on-wednesday</link><description>BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman is headed to Barishal and Faridpur on Wednesday as part of his campaign ahead of the Feb 12 general election.
Mahadi Amin, spokesman for the party's central election management committee, made the announcement at a press briefing at the BNP’s office in Gulshan on</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 10:57:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rizwana Hasan urges action for horn-free streets in Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/rizwana-hasan-urges-action-for-horn-free-streets-in-dhaka</link><description>Bangladesh could have horn-free roads in the future if noise laws are properly enforced, said Syeda Rizwana Hasan, Adviser to the Ministries of Environment, Forest and Climate Change, Information and Broadcasting, and Water Resources.
She made the remark at a public program in Mazar Chattar, Dhaka</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 11:12:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gold Price Shock: Tk 16,330 surge hits Bangladesh overnight</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/gold-price-shock-tk-16330-surge-hits-bangladesh-overnight</link><description>Gold prices in Bangladesh soared again on Tuesday, climbing a total of Tk 16,330 per bhori through two separate hikes announced by the Bangladesh Jewellers Association (BAJUS), pushing the price back above Tk 260,000 per bhori.
In a morning notification, BAJUS said it had raised the price of 22-ca</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 11:27:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CCCL Installs newly elected Executive Committee for 2026</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/cccl-installs-newly-elected-executive-committee-for-2026</link><description>The Installation Ceremony of the newly elected Executive Committee of Cadet College Club Limited (CCCL) for the year 2026 was held on Friday, 30 January 2026, at the Club premises in Purbachal, Dhaka, in a grand and festive setting.
The event was graced by General Waker-Uz-Zaman, SBP, OSP, SGP, ps</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 11:13:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Russia fires 450 drones and 70 missiles at Ukraine, a day before US-brokered talks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/russia-fires-450-drones-and-70-missiles-at-ukraine-a-day-before-us-brokered-talks</link><description>Russia fired around 450 long-range drones and 70 missiles of various types at Ukraine in a major attack overnight, Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelenskyy said Tuesday.
The barrage came as NATO Secretary-General Mark Rutte visited Kyiv in a show of support and a day before Russia and Ukraine were</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 11:28:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCT lease row triggers indefinite strike</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/chittagong-port-workers-launch-indefinite-strike-over-lease-to-foreign-handlers</link><description>Protesters have called a non-stop work stoppage to object to the decision to hand over management of Chittagong Port’s New Mooring Container Terminal (NCT) to UAE-based operator DP World.
On Tuesday afternoon, Ibrahim Khokon, coordinator of the Chittagong Port Protection Struggle Council, sa</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 11:43:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NSU Inaugurates 10th National Career Fair with Over 100 Participating Companies</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/nsu-inaugurates-10th-national-career-fair-with-over-100-participating-companies</link><description>The Career and Placement Centre (CPC) of North South University inaugurated the 10th National Career Fair on Saturday at NSU Plaza, bringing together more than 100 local and multinational organisations in what has become one of Bangladesh's premier platforms for graduate recruitment and industry en</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 11:58:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>21 BGB platoons to secure Bandarban during national election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/21-bgb-platoons-to-secure-bandarban-during-national-election</link><description>Border Guard Bangladesh (BGB) will deploy 21 platoons in Bandarban district to ensure security during the upcoming 13th Jatiya Sangsad election.
The decision was announced at a press briefing on Tuesday morning at Bandarban Government College by BGB Bandarban Sector Commander Col Muhammad Rubayat</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 12:13:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh finalises GCM Action Plan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-finalises-gcm-action-plan</link><description>Bangladesh has finalised its National Action Plan for the Global Compact for Migration (GCM), reaffirming its strong commitment to safe, orderly and regular migration and the protection of migrants’ rights. 
The soft adoption of the GCM National Action Plan (NAP) followed a multi-stakeh</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 12:28:43 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>