<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 15:34:34 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>RAB vows joint raids in Jungle Salimpur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rab-chief-pledges-joint-raids-to-clear-jungle-salimpur-safe-haven-for-criminals-after-nayek-motaleb-murder</link><description>Rapid Action Battalion (RAB) Director General AKM Shahidur Rahman has announced joint operations to clear Jungle Salimpur of “criminals and illegal occupation”, a day after a member of the force was killed there.
Speaking to journalists at the RAB‑7 headquarters in Patenga on Tuesday a</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 12:56:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pubali Bank achieves international PCI-DSS certification</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/pubali-bank-achieves-international-pci-dss-certification</link><description>Pubali Bank PLC has been serving as a symbol of trust, service excellence, and ethical banking in Bangladesh’s financial sector for nearly seven decades. In its continued commitment to customer data protection, ethical banking practices, and adherence to international standards, the bank has</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 13:11:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NRBC Bank observes 6th anniversary of Al-Amin Islamic Banking</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/nrbc-bank-observes-6th-anniversary-of-al-amin-islamic-banking</link><description>NRBC Bank PLC celebrated the 6th anniversary of the launch of its fully Shariah-compliant “Al-Amin Islamic Banking” window.
According to a press release, a special prayer ceremony was held at the bank’s head office to mark the occasion, according to a press release.
The Chairman</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 13:26:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rescue workers clearing Karachi inferno ruins, 57 missing feared dead</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/rescue-workers-clearing-karachi-inferno-ruins-57-missing-feared-dead</link><description>Firefighters were clearing the charred ruins of a Karachi mall on Tuesday as they tried to locate nearly 60 people still missing and feared dead after a fire that burned for nearly two days and killed 27 people.
The Pakistani port city’s largest fire in over a decade began late on Saturday a</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 13:41:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Eastern Bank–Alzheimer Society partnership to develop skilled dementia caregivers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/eastern-bank-alzheimer-society-partnership-to-develop-skilled-dementia-caregivers</link><description>Eastern Bank (EBL), in partnership with the Alzheimer Society of Bangladesh (ASB), has launched a scholarship program to develop skilled dementia caregivers in Bangladesh under its Corporate Social Responsibility (CSR) initiative.
A Memorandum of Understanding (MoU) was signed at EBL’s Head</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 12:58:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DMP to fine up to Tk 10,000 for honking near Dhaka airport from Jan 25</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dmp-to-fine-up-to-tk-10000-for-honking-near-dhaka-airport-from-jan-25</link><description>Dhaka Metropolitan Police (DMP) will start taking action against drivers who honk in restricted areas around Shahjalal International Airport in Dhaka from January 25.
The DMP issued a notice in this regard on Tuesday.
According to the notice, the government declared certain areas around the airpo</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 13:13:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Citizens Bank holds Annual Business Conference 2026</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/citizens-bank-holds-annual-business-conference-2026</link><description>Citizens Bank PLC held its Annual Business Conference 2026 on January 17, 2026, at a resort in Munshiganj, according to a press release.
Mr. Chowdhury Mohammed Hanif Shoeb, Chairman of the bank, graced the conference as the Chief Guest and delivered strategic guidance aligned with the bank’s</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 13:28:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bank Asia Agent Banking marks its 12th anniversary with a milestone of 7.5 million customers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bank-asia-agent-banking-marks-its-12th-anniversary-with-a-milestone-of-75-million-customers</link><description>Bank Asia Agent Banking marked its 12th founding anniversary by celebrating a remarkable milestone—bringing 7.5 million customers into the formal financial system and transforming access to banking services across Bangladesh, according to a press release.
As the pioneer of Agent Banking in t</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 13:43:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Al-Arafah Islami Bank holds training course on leadership development in branch management</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/al-arafah-islami-bank-holds-training-course-on-leadership-development-in-branch-management-1</link><description>A 3-day training course titled “Leadership Development in Branch Management” has started at the bank’s Training Institute at Al-Arafah Islami Bank.
Managing Director and CEO of the bank Mohd Rafat Ullah Khan inaugurated the training workshop as the chief guest on Tuesday, accordi</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 13:58:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat-BNP clash sparks tension in Mirpur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-bnp-activists-scuffle-over-pre-polls-campaigning-triggers-tension-in-mirpur</link><description>Tension has flared in Dhaka’s Mirpur after activists of the Jamaat-e-Islami and BNP were involved in a scuffle over the distribution of campaign leaflets ahead of the official start of electioneering.
The incident took place on Tuesday evening outside the Pirerbagh Al Mubarak Mosque under Mi</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 14:13:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DNCC sets rules to protect tenants’ rights</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dncc-sets-16-rules-for-landlords-rent-hikes-allowed-every-2-years</link><description>The Dhaka North City Corporation has issued 16 instructions for landlords in Dhaka to protect tenants’ rights.
The instructions allow the rents to be hiked only once in every two years.
Tenants will have unrestricted access to their homes and the roof at all times, the instructions said.
L</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 14:28:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Padma Bridge draws Tk 30.0 billion as toll since 2022 opening</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/padma-bridge-draws-tk-300-billion-as-toll-since-2022-opening</link><description>The government has collected so far Tk 30.0 billion as revenue from the users of the Padma Bridge since its June 25, 2022 opening, Bangladesh Bridge Authority (BBA) said in a statement today.
It said the bridge that connected 21 southwestern districts with the rest of the country was increasingly</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 14:43:25 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>