<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 11:19:56 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Reimagining higher education in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/article/reimagining-higher-education-in-bangladesh</link><description>The world is shutting its doors, and the implications for developing countries are profound. Between January and May 2025, USA consulates issued roughly 95,000 F-1 visas, marking the lowest issuance total in three years, whilst the Department of Homeland Security proposed limiting students' length</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 08:10:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Youth Connect empowering a generation to lead change</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/youth-connect-empowering-a-generation-to-lead-change</link><description>Bangladesh stands at a critical juncture. With over one-third of its population aged below 30, the future of the nation will be determined not by policy, but by the ideas, skills, and leadership qualities of the youth. Climate change, increasing inequalities, employability, and the disruptor role o</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 08:25:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP rejects Jamaat’s 'India deal' claim as ‘propaganda’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-rejects-jamaats-india-deal-claim-as-propaganda</link><description>The Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) has rejected allegations by Jamaat-e-Islami that it has reached an agreement with India to return to power, describing the claim as “total propaganda”.
Mahdi Amin, spokesperson for the BNP’s Central Election Steering Committee, clarified t</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 08:40:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Karachi mall inferno came after ignored warnings, delayed response</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/karachi-mall-inferno-came-after-ignored-warnings-delayed-response</link><description>Muhammad Imran did not take the fire seriously at first, thinking it was another small spark at the Karachi mall that would be quickly extinguished by fellow shop owners.
But smoke seeped through ducts and blackened the air in seconds. The lights went out soon after and phone flashlights turned us</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 08:55:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two killed in Kishoreganj road crash</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/two-killed-in-kishoreganj-road-crash-1549</link><description>Two people were killed and at least ten others injured when a pickup van overturned in Ashtagram upazila of the Kishoreganj on Saturday.
The deceased were identified as Hadis Mia, 50, and Nur Alam, 45, both residents of the Mithamoin Ghagra area, reports BSS.
According to police and local sources</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 09:45:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh fails at ICC dispute panel as bid to shift T20 WC matches from India thrown out: PTI</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/bangladesh-fails-at-icc-dispute-panel-as-bid-to-shift-t20-wc-matches-from-india-thrown-out-pti</link><description>Bangladesh’s latest attempt to move its T20 World Cup games from India to Sri Lanka has failed at the ICC Dispute Resolution Committee (DRC), the Press Trust of India reports.
On Jan 21, Bangladesh lost by a 14–2 margin in a vote at the ICC, leaving them with no option but to travel to</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 10:00:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Those seeking votes with Weighing Scale opposed independence,’ Fakhrul says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/those-seeking-votes-with-weighing-scale-opposed-independence-fakhrul-says</link><description>BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir has reminded voters that those campaigning with the "Weighing Scale" symbol opposed the independence of Bangladesh.
Speaking during a mass outreach programme on Saturday in Thakurgaon Sadar Upazila, Fakhrul recalled how people were forced to flee t</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 10:04:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Top gangster ‘Dilip Dada’ ordered Muchabbir's killing: DB</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/swechhasebak-dal-leader-muchabbirs-killing-ordered-by-fugitive-gangster-dilip-dada-db</link><description>Police say the killing of Swechhasebak Dal leader Azizur Rahman Muchabbir was carried out on the instructions of a fugitive underworld figure believed to be living abroad.
Speaking at a media briefing on Saturday, Additional Commissioner Md Shafiqul Islam of Dhaka Metropolitan Police’s Detec</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 10:19:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Suicide bombing at Pakistan wedding kills 7, police say</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/suicide-bombing-at-pakistan-wedding-kills-7-police-say</link><description>The death toll from a suicide bombing at a wedding near the Afghan border rose to seven on Saturday, police said, as Pakistan struggles to deal with a rising wave of militant attacks.
The bombing tore through a building housing members of a peace committee during a wedding ceremony on Friday in no</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 10:34:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Russian air attack on Ukraine knocks out power for millions</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/russian-air-attack-on-ukraine-knocks-out-power-for-millions</link><description>Russia launched another vast attack on Ukraine's energy system in the small hours of Saturday, rocking Kyiv with explosions throughout the night and leaving 1.2 million properties without power countrywide.
Nearly 6,000 buildings in the capital were left without heating on Saturday morning as temp</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 10:49:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Annual Sales Conference 2026 of Square Food &amp; Beverage Ltd held in Cox’s Bazar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/annual-sales-conference-2026-of-square-food-beverage-ltd-held-in-coxs-bazar</link><description>Square Food &amp; Beverage Limited successfully held its Annual Sales Conference 2026 on January 24 (Saturday) at Hotel Sea Palace, Cox’s Bazar.
The conference focused on the company’s sales strategies, market expansion plans and business goals for 2026, alongside discussions on strengthen</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 11:04:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique's ‘plan’: Tackle corruption and crime</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/prioritising-law-and-order-ending-corruption-bnp-chief-tariques-plan-to-fix-bangladesh</link><description>Law and order and the control of corruption are the two priorities BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman wants to put at the centre of his political “plan”.
He outlined this on Saturday afternoon while speaking with the winners of the “Amar Bhabnay Bangladesh”, a national reel-making</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 11:19:56 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>