<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 08:24:34 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>30 killed in Ethiopia scaffolding collapse</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/africa/30-killed-in-ethiopia-scaffolding-collapse</link><description>At least 30 people were killed on Wednesday when a wooden scaffolding collapsed in Ethiopia's Amhara Region, state media reported.
The makeshift structure, set up for the construction of a church in the town of Arerti, collapsed in the early hours of the morning, killing more than 30 worshipers an</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 06:28:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Journalists boycott NCP briefing at airport over alleged harassment</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/journalists-boycott-ncp-briefing-at-airport-over-alleged-harassment</link><description>National Citizen Party (NCP) activists have been accused of harassing journalists at Shahjalal International Airport in Dhaka.
In protest against the incident, reporters subsequently boycotted the party’s press conference. The incident took place around 9:45 am on Thursday outside the airpor</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 06:47:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hilsa fishing ban: Each fisherman to get 30 kgs of rice</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hilsa-fishing-ban-each-fisherman-to-get-30-kgs-of-rice</link><description>The government will distribute 30 kilograms of rice per fisherman family during the fishing ban, beginning from October 4 to 25 this year, according to the Department of Fisheries (DoF).
To support affected fishermen, the government will provide the rice to 620,140 fishing households across 165 up</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 06:54:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Three killed as bus hits roadside shop in Feni</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/three-killed-as-bus-hits-roadside-shop-in-feni</link><description>At least three people, including two women, were killed and 10 others injured when a speeding bus lost control and ploughed into a roadside shop in Daganbhuiyan upazila of Feni district on Thursday.
Two of the deceased were identified as Shamim Ara Begum, 50, wife of Shahidullah from Khushipur are</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 07:24:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Three cases filed over Khagrachhari violence, over 1,000 unnamed suspects accused</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/three-cases-filed-over-khagrachhari-violence-over-1000-unnamed-suspects-accused</link><description>Police have filed three cases over the recent violence in Khagrachhari’s Guimara and Sadar Upazilas, accusing over 1,000 unnamed suspects, reports bdnews24.com.
Police authorities say that two cases, including a murder case, have been filed at Guimara Police Station, while the third case has</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 07:39:34 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>