<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 13:08:33 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Govt fixes Ramadan office timing</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-fixes-ramadan-office-timing</link><description>All offices of the government, semi-government, autonomous and semi-autonomous bodies will function from 9:00 am to 3:30 pm during the upcoming month of holy Ramadan.
The decision was taken at the weekly meeting of the Council of Advisers at the Chief Adviser's Office (CAO) on Thursday, with Chief</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 11:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Babita, Ayub Bachchu, Shafik Rehman to get Ekushey Padak</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/babita-ayub-bachchu-shafik-rehman-to-get-ekushey-padak</link><description>The Ministry of Cultural Affairs has decided to award this year’s Ekushey Padak to nine individuals and a band.
The awardees were selected at a meeting chaired by Cultural Affairs Adviser Mostafa Sarwar Farooki on Thursday.
The names were announced by the Chief Advisor’s Press Secreta</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 11:20:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two options under consideration for oath of new MPs: Asif Nazrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/two-options-under-consideration-for-oath-of-new-mps-asif-nazrul</link><description>Law Adviser Asif Nazrul on Thursday said the government is thinking about two options for who will swear in the newly elected MPs.
Talking to reporters at the Secretariat, he said the oath could either be administered by a person nominated by the President or by the Chief Election Commissioner (CE</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 10:05:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Extra metro trains to run on election day</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/extra-metro-trains-to-run-on-election-day</link><description>Dhaka Mass Transit Company Limited (DMTCL) will operate additional metro rail services on the election day to facilitate voters and ensure smooth movement of passengers.
DMTCL Managing Director Faruk Ahmed said extra trains will be operated on the election day to prevent inconvenience to voters an</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 10:20:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh-India ties faced setbacks during interim govt, recognises Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-india-ties-faced-setbacks-during-interim-govt-recognises-adviser</link><description>Foreign Affairs Adviser Md Touhid Hossain on Thursday acknowledged that the relations between Bangladesh and India had not been ‘smooth’ and faced some ‘setbacks’ during the tenure of the interim government.
He, however, expressed optimism that the next elected government w</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 10:35:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shafiqur's X 'hack' suspect secures bail</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bangabhaban-programmer-sarowar-who-was-held-over-hacking-shafiqurs-x-granted-bail</link><description>Bangabhaban Assistant Programmer Sarowar Alam, who was detained following allegations that he “hacked” the X account of Jamaat-e-Islami chief Shafiqur Rahman, has secured bail.
Dhaka Additional Chief Metropolitan Magistrate Awlad Hossain Mohammad Junaid granted him bail on Thursday.
E</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 10:50:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ekushey Book Fair to begin on Feb 20, reaffirms Bangla Academy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ekushey-book-fair-to-begin-on-feb-20-reaffirms-bangla-academy</link><description>Bangla Academy on Thursday reiterated that the Amar Ekushey Book Fair 2026 will begin on February 20, ruling out the possibility of postponing the country’s largest literary event.
The decision was announced at an emergency press conference organised by the Bangla Academy.
Member Secretary</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 11:05:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Arrest warrants issued for three doctors over child Ayan’s circumcision death</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/arrest-warrants-issued-for-three-doctors-over-child-ayans-circumcision-death</link><description>Police have found evidence of “negligence and medical malpractice” by three doctors in connection with the death of five-year-old Ayan Ahmed, who died after a circumcision procedure at United Medical College Hospital two years ago.
The accused medical professionals are anaesthesia spec</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 11:20:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DCCI calls for immediate normalisation of Ctg port operations</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/dcci-calls-for-immediate-normalisation-of-ctg-port-operations</link><description>Dhaka Chamber of Commerce and Industry (DCCI) on Thursday urged the government to take immediate steps to restore normal operations at Chattogram Port, warning that the prolonged shutdown is severely disrupting trade and could have far-reaching consequences for the national economy.
Describing Cha</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 11:35:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AB Bank signs MoU with Ramada by Windham Cox’s Bazar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ab-bank-signs-mou-with-ramada-by-windham-coxs-bazar</link><description>AB Bank PLC inked a Memorandum of Understanding (MoU) with Ramada by Wyndham Cox’s Bazar, under which AB Bank cardholders will enjoy 50% discount on room rents during the tourist season, 60% discount in off-season, 50%on the Banquet hall, &amp; 10% on the A-La-Cart Menu and 25% on SPA at Ramada b</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 11:50:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Election complaints rise to 344, nearly half against field officers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/election-complaints-rise-to-344-nearly-half-against-field-officers</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has received 344 complaints related to the parliamentary polls and referendum, with almost half directed at field officials.
Md Saiful Islam, director (Operations) of the National Identity Registration Wing and member secretary of the central coordination committee for</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 12:05:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Al-Arafah Islami Bank signs agreement with Nagorik Specialized Hospital</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/al-arafah-islami-bank-signs-agreement-with-nagorik-specialized-hospital</link><description>Al-Arafah Islami Bank PLC, country’s one of the leading Shariah-based banks, has signed a Memorandum of Understanding with Nagorik Specialized Hospital.
Under this agreement, the use of the bank's modern network will increase the ability of the hospital's bill collection and financial manage</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 12:20:11 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>