<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 11:41:20 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Growing business of selling 'pure' products in Ramadan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/food/growing-business-of-selling-pure-products-in-ramadan</link><description>Many things vary from generation to generation, but one thing is becoming exponentially more tiring: the lack of purity in our food. In this life full of hassle, all we can afford is polluted air and adulterated food. 
The urgency of this issue becomes even more profound during Ramadan, a mon</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 09:14:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>PM confers Bangla Academy Literary Award 2025</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/pm-confers-bangla-academy-literary-award-2025</link><description>Prime Minister Tarique Rahman on Thursday presented the Bangla Academy Literary Award 2025 to nine distinguished personalities for their outstanding contributions to Bangla literature.
This year's recipients are Mohan Roy for poetry, Nasima Anis for fiction, Syed Azizul Haque for essays and prose,</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 09:06:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Six critically burnt in Cox’s Bazar gas station explosion moved to Chattogram hospital</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/six-critically-burnt-in-coxs-bazar-gas-station-explosion-moved-to-chattogram-hospital</link><description>Six people injured in a gas filling station explosion in Cox’s Bazar have been admitted to the burn unit of Chattogram Medical College Hospital.
Associate Professor Dr Rafiq Uddin Ahmed of the burn unit told bdnews24.com on Thursday that the victims suffered 20 to 90 percent burns, adding th</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 09:21:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Income tax return submission deadline extended again</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/income-tax-return-submission-deadline-extended-again</link><description>The National Board of Revenue (NBR) has once again extended the deadline for filing income tax returns for individual taxpayers for 2025–2026 tax year until 31 March, 2026.
In an order issued under Section 334 of the Income Tax Act, 2023, the revenue authority said the decision was taken in</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 09:36:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cuba situation escalating, humanitarian needs must be solved: Kremlin</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/kremlin-says-cuba-situation-is-escalating-humanitarian-needs-must-be-solved</link><description>The Kremlin said on Thursday that the situation in Cuba was heating up and called for restraint after a deadly incident with a Florida-registered speedboat off the coast of the Caribbean island.
Cuban forces killed four exiles and wounded six others who sailed into Cuban waters aboard a speedboat</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 09:51:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BGMEA pushes for quick release of Tk 57b RMG incentives</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bgmea-pushes-for-quick-release-of-tk-57b-rmg-incentives</link><description>The Bangladesh Garment Manufacturers and Exporters Association (BGMEA) has urged the government to expedite the disbursement of Tk 57 billion in cash incentives for the ready-made garment (RMG) sector.
The call came during a meeting with Finance Minister Amir Khosru Mahmud Chowdhury at the Secreta</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 10:06:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt reconstitutes upazila law and order committees</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-reconstitutes-upazila-law-and-order-committees</link><description>The Home Ministry on Thursday reconstituted the Upazila Law and Order Committee across the country with expanded mandate of adopting steps required maintain stability within their purviews alongside assessing crime trends and reviewing law and order situation.
The ministry’s political branch</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 10:21:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Governor Mostaqur meets finance minister</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bb-governor-mostaqur-visits-finance-minister-khosru-following-tense-appointment</link><description>Amid the tense backdrop of his appointment, Bangladesh Bank’s new Governor Mostaqur Rahman has made his first visit to the finance minister, following preliminary discussions with senior central bank officials.
He went to Finance Minister Amir Khosru Mahmud Chowdhury’s office at 3:34pm</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 10:30:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladeshi youth-led project wins climate action competition</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladeshi-youth-led-project-wins-climate-action-competition</link><description>A youth-led project from Bangladesh has won a regional climate action competition, with the winners announced during the 13th Asia-Pacific Forum on Sustainable Development held in Bangkok on Wednesday.
The winning team, Eco Sentinels, developed BrineAway, a nature-based water filtration system des</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 10:45:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt clears waiver of up to Tk 10,000 agricultural loans</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-cabinet-clears-waiver-of-up-to-tk-10000-agricultural-loans</link><description>The cabinet has approved a plan to waive agricultural loans of up to Tk 10,000, including accrued interest, in a move aimed at easing pressure on small-scale farmers and strengthening rural resilience.
The decision was taken at the first cabinet meeting chaired by Prime Minister Tarique Rahman at</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 11:00:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>180 vacant sergeant posts to be filled soon: Home Minister</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/180-vacant-sergeant-posts-to-be-filled-soon-home-minister</link><description>Home Minister Salahuddin Ahmed today (Thursday) said that 180 vacant sergeant posts will be filled soon as part of efforts to strengthen law enforcement.
He said the recruitment process would be expedited to ensure the vacancies are filled without delay, enhancing policing efficiency and public sa</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 11:15:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Egg auction shows supply and demand at work</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/egg-auction-shows-supply-and-demand-at-work</link><description>The supply of eggs has exceeded demand for eggs, causing a low price, which has been sustained for months. When egg prices were high, government officers alleged that the egg market was controlled by a syndicate. Low prices have proven this allegation false.
At its sales centre in Ashulia near Dha</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 11:30:39 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>