<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 19:18:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Mutual Trust Bank holds MTB Annual Town Hall 2026</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/mutual-trust-bank-holds-mtb-annual-town-hall-2026</link><description>Mutual Trust Bank PLC (MTB) held its Annual Town Hall 2026 at a local venue in Dhaka under the theme “Trust Rebuilt, Future Redefined.”
According to a press release, the Town Hall focused on reviewing the Bank’s performance, addressing prevailing challenges, and aligning MTBians</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 15:57:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Yemeni government accuses separatists of Aden restrictions</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/yemeni-government-accuses-separatists-of-aden-restrictions</link><description>Yemen’s Saudi-backed government on Sunday accused UAE-backed southern separatists of cutting off the port city of Aden and warned it would “take all necessary measures” after recapturing territory from them in the east on Saturday.
The separatists denied having restricted movemen</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 16:12:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Investors face more geopolitical whiplash from Trump’s Venezuela gamble</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/investors-face-more-geopolitical-whiplash-from-trumps-venezuela-gamble</link><description>Global investors are facing a fresh surge in geopolitical risk after the US capture of Venezuelan President Nicolas Maduro, a move that could unlock the nation’s vast oil reserves and boost risky assets over the longer-term but prompt a flight to safety when trading resumes.
President Donald</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 16:27:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique will become BNP chief shortly: Fakhrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fakhrul-says-tarique-rahman-will-be-made-bnp-chief-in-a-day-or-two</link><description>Tarique Rahman will be appointed the chairman of the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) in “a day or two”, senior leader Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir has said.
Speaking in Sylhet on Sunday, Fakhrul said the position of chairperson Khaleda Zia “must be filled”.
“Right</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 16:30:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Taiyeb questions mobile traders’ opposition to NEIR after attack on BTRC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/taiyeb-questions-mobile-traders-opposition-to-neir-after-attack-on-btrc</link><description>Faiz Ahmad Taiyeb, special assistant to the chief advisor on information technology, has clarified the government’s firm stance on the implementation of the National Equipment Identity Register (NEIR).
He made the remarks on Sunday while visiting the Bangladesh Telecommunication Regulatory C</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 16:45:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Venezuela's interim government backs Maduro after his US capture</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/venezuelas-interim-government-says-it-remains-united-behind-maduro-after-his-us-capture</link><description>A top Venezuelan official declared on Sunday that the country's government would stay unified behind President Nicolas Maduro, whose capture by the US has sparked deep uncertainty about what is next for the oil-rich South American nation.
Maduro is in a New York detention centre awaiting a Monday</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 17:00:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gold prices rise for first time this year in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/gold-prices-rise-for-first-time-this-year-in-bangladesh</link><description>After three consecutive cuts, gold prices in Bangladesh have increased for the first time in 2026, as the Bangladesh Jewellers Association (BAJUS) announced a fresh hike on Sunday.
In a notification issued at night, BAJUS said the price of 22-carat gold has been raised by Tk 2,216 per bhori (11.66</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 17:15:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>LPG crisis artificial, stern action to be taken: Ministry</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/lpg-crisis-artificial-stern-action-to-be-taken-ministry</link><description>After three consecutive cuts, gold prices in Bangladesh have increased for the first time in 2026, as the Bangladesh Jewellers Association (BAJUS) announced a fresh hike on Sunday.
In a notification issued at night, BAJUS said the price of 22-carat gold has been raised by Tk 2,216 per bhori (11.66</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 17:30:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tigress trapped in poachers’ snare in Sundarbans rescued</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tigress-trapped-in-poachers-snare-in-sundarbans-rescued</link><description>A tigress trapped in a snare set by deer poachers in the Sundarbans was rescued by the Forest Department on Sunday afternoon near Boiragi Bari along Sarkir canal in Mongla upazila of Bagerhat district.
The tigress was tranquilised and safely freed from the trap around 3pm, said Divisional Forest O</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 17:47:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Deadline for NBR bifurcation missed, Jan action in wintry chill</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/deadline-for-nbr-bifurcation-missed-jan-action-in-wintry-chill</link><description>December deadline is missed and bid for completing all must-dos for bifurcating the revenue board within January has yet to get into right gear although revenue-sector overhaul is among major uprising-mandated reforms.  
Officials say the final stages of splitting the National Board of R</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 18:02:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Top business leaders meet Tarique Rahman, discuss economy, jobs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/top-business-leaders-meet-tarique-rahman-discuss-economy-jobs</link><description>Top business leaders and industrial entrepreneurs of the country held a meeting with BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman on Sunday night, discussing the current economic situation, investment challenges and rising unemployment.
The meeting was held at the BNP Chairperson’s political office in</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 18:17:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique assures business-friendly decisions for  economic rebound</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/tarique-assures-business-friendly-decisions-for-economic-rebound</link><description>Acting Chairman of BNP Tarique Rahman has assured business leaders that he would implement business-friendly policies if elected to form the government in the next general election.
He made this assurance during a meeting with prominent business leaders and entrepreneurs on Sunday evening at his G</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 18:32:42 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>