<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 13:31:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Navy detains 273 trying to reach Malaysia by sea</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/navy-detains-273-trying-to-reach-malaysia-by-sea</link><description>The Bangladesh Navy has detained 273 people while they were attempting to travel illegally to Malaysia by sea.
The Inter-Services Public Relations (ISPR) disclosed the information in a press statement on Sunday, reports bdnews24.com.
According to the statement, the navy carried out an operation l</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 10:19:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UAE President, PM mourn death of Khaleda Zia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/uae-president-pm-mourn-death-of-khaleda-zia</link><description>The President of the United Arab Emirates, Sheikh Mohamed bin Zayed Al Nahyan, and  Vice President, Prime Minister of the UAE, and Ruler of Dubai, Sheikh Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum, have expressed deep sorrow at the passing of former Prime Minister and BNP Chairperson Khaleda Zia.
Both le</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 10:34:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IFIC Bank promotes 74 officials at various levels in recognition of professional excellence</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ific-bank-promotes-74-officials-at-various-levels-in-recognition-of-professional-excellence</link><description>In recognition of significant contributions to the Bank’s sustainable growth and continued progress, IFIC Bank PLC has promoted 74 officers across various levels.
These promotions were granted as a mark of appreciation for the officers’ professional competence, dedication, and sense of</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 10:49:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two suspects arrested near Tarique Rahman’s Gulshan residence</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/two-suspects-arrested-near-tarique-rahmans-gulshan-residence</link><description>Police and members of the CSF on Sunday detained two men for their suspicious movement near the Gulshan residence of BNP’s Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman.
Officer-in-Charge (OC) of Gulshan Police Station Rakibul Hasan said Md Ruhul Amin, 46, from Matlab South upazila in Chandpur, was seen ta</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 11:04:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mirza Fakhrul visits Sylhet shrine to pay respects to Shahjalal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/mirza-fakhrul-visits-sylhet-shrine-to-pay-respects-to-shahjalal</link><description>Senior BNP leader Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir has visited and paid respect at the shrine of Muslim Sufi saint Shahjalal.
Secretary General Fakhrul flew from Dhaka and reached Sylhet in the evening on Sunday, said Sylhet BNP President Abdul Qaiyum Chowdhury, bdnews24.com reports. 
After the B</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 11:19:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC asks Power Division to provide electricity connections to 325 polling stations</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-asks-power-division-to-provide-electricity-connections-to-325-polling-stations</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has directed the Power Division to take necessary measures to provide electricity connections to 325 polling stations across the country ahead of the national election and the referendum scheduled for February 12 next.
“There is no electricity connection at 325 o</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 11:34:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC to drop deceased voters year-round from voter list</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-to-drop-deceased-voters-year-round-from-voter-list</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has taken an initiative to drop the deceased voters from the electoral rolls around the year instead of a particular time of the voter list updating campaign every year.
The Commission has already formed a committee to ensure the removal of deceased voters from the ele</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 11:49:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US lifts Caribbean airspace curbs after attack on Venezuela</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/us-lifts-caribbean-airspace-curbs-after-attack-on-venezuela</link><description>The United States advised airlines on Saturday that its Caribbean airspace curbs would expire at midnight ET (0500 GMT) and flights could resume as schedules are quickly updated, Transportation Secretary Sean Duffy said.
The comments on X followed the cancelation of hundreds of flights by major ai</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 12:04:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Haor regions to see controlled pesticide use in upcoming Boro season</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/haor-regions-to-see-controlled-pesticide-use-in-upcoming-boro-season</link><description>In a move aimed at safeguarding fisheries, livestock, and biodiversity, the Ministry of Fisheries and Livestock has announced plans to regulate and limit pesticide use in agricultural fields across haor areas during the forthcoming Boro rice season.
The decision was taken at the second mee</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 12:34:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Biman suspends Dhaka–Manchester flights from Feb 1</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/biman-suspends-dhaka-manchester-flights-from-feb-1</link><description>Biman Bangladesh Airlines Limited has announced the suspension of its regular flights on Dhaka–Manchester–Dhaka route from February 1, 2026.
The airline’s board of directors took the decision due to a shortage of aircraft, the upcoming Hajj flights operations, the need for long t</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 12:49:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NBR launches Security Operations Centre to strengthen cyber security</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nbr-launches-security-operations-centre-to-strengthen-cyber-security</link><description>The National Board of Revenue (NBR) on Sunday launched a dedicated Security Operations Centre (SOC) as part of its efforts to strengthen cyber security and protect critical digital infrastructure particularly the ASYCUDA system and other sensitive information assets.
The SOC has been established i</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 13:04:19 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>