<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 04:42:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Revised budget, new one's outline going for CA's perusal today</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/revised-budget-new-ones-outline-going-for-cas-perusal-today</link><description>A pared-down draft revised budget for the current fiscal year and an outline of the next one are being placed before Chief Adviser Muhammad Yunus today to seek his advice and directions, officials say.



An upscale Tk 8.5-trillion budget for next fiscal year is likely to be framed by the inter</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 18:36:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fresh Tk 4.63b project to boost Karnaphuli Tunnel traffic</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fresh-tk-463b-project-to-boost-karnaphuli-tunnel-traffic</link><description>A fresh Tk 4.63-billion project is conceived to construct 21.1 kilometres of connecting roads to ramp up traffic flow through the Karnaphuli Tunnel that operates below its expected capacity for lower-than-anticipated vehicle movement.
Officials say Road Transport and Highways Division (RTHD) has p</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 01:23:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka rejects New Delhi's statement on BD mission attack</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dhaka-rejects-new-delhis-statement-on-bd-mission-attack</link><description>Bangladesh's interim government rebuts India's explanation of an attack on the Bangladesh mission in Delhi and says the host country failed to ensure adequate diplomatic security.
Also, the government raised concerns over reported death threats against the Bangladesh High Commissioner.
Speaking t</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 01:38:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Journalists want BNP, if voted to power, to be truly media-friendly</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/journalists-want-bnp-if-voted-to-power-to-be-truly-media-friendly</link><description>BNP Standing Committee Member Salahuddin Ahmed on Sunday said the recent attacks on the offices of Prothom Alo and The Daily Star were a shame for the nation.
"The attackers burned and destroyed the offices of Prothom Alo and The Daily Star, and the whole world watched it. We cannot simply express</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 01:53:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CEC sits with chiefs of 3 services, law enforcers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cec-sits-with-chiefs-of-3-services-law-enforcers</link><description>Joint-force operations will resume in a bid to keep the law-and-order situation under control ahead of the national elections, Election Commissioner (EC) Brig. Gen. Abul Fazal Md. Sanaullah (Retd.) said on Sunday.
He also said the Election Commission (EC) will not allow any activities that disrupt</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 02:08:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BR still lacks fit execution plan for decade-old policy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/br-still-lacks-fit-execution-plan-for-decade-old-policy</link><description>Bangladesh Railway (BR) has yet to formulate a comprehensive plan to incorporate electric traction in its upcoming development projects, despite a policy-level decision made a decade ago.
While over 70 countries have shifted to electric train services, BR remains limited to a few specialised proje</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 02:23:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Attackers on Prothom Alo, Daily Star identified</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/attackers-on-prothom-alo-daily-star-identified</link><description>Religious Affairs Adviser AFM Khalid Hossain on Sunday said the identities of several individuals involved in the recent arson attacks on Prothom Alo and The Daily Star have been identified and steps are underway to bring them to justice.
Speaking to reporters at the Bangladesh Secretariat, he sai</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 02:38:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NBR chief hints at further extending return submission deadline</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/nbr-chief-hints-at-further-extending-return-submission-deadline</link><description>National Board of Revenue (NBR) Chairman Abdur Rahman Khan has hinted at the possibility of further extension of income-tax return-submission deadline, as many registered taxpayers are yet to file their returns digitally.
Speaking about the possible extension, Mr. Khan mentioned that the NBR would</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 02:53:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BB buys more US dollars to support taka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/bb-buys-more-us-dollars-to-support-taka</link><description>The central bank purchased an additional US$60 million from four banks through an auction on the interbank spot market on Sunday, aiming to keep the exchange rate of the US dollar against the taka stable.
The amount was bought under the multiple price auction method, with a cut-off rate of Tk 122.</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 03:08:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Longer-term T-bill yields edge higher</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/longer-term-t-bill-yields-edge-higher</link><description>Yields on longer-term treasury bills (T-bills) edged up on Sunday as banks remained reluctant to lock in excess liquidity ahead of the year-end closing and the upcoming national election.
The cut-off yield, or interest rate, on the 182-day T-bills rose to 10.65 per cent from 10.57 per cent at the</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 03:23:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Why BSRM remains profitable while GPH Ispat slips into losses amid adversities</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/why-bsrm-remains-profitable-while-gph-ispat-slips-into-losses-amid-adversities</link><description>Economies of scale are helping Bangladesh Steel Re-Rolling Mills (BSRM) make profits during a tough period of sluggish market demand, while GPH Ispat has slipped into the red.
The steel industry navigated one of its toughest phases in FY25 as construction in both the public and private sectors fac</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 03:38:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka bourse dips to one-month low amid rising political tension</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/dhaka-bourse-dips-to-one-month-low-amid-rising-political-tension</link><description>The benchmark index of the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) fell to a one-month low on Sunday as jittery investors continued selling amid growing political concerns.
Market analysts said investor sentiment had already been fragile following the merger of five banks and the move to liquidate nine non-ban</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 03:53:32 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>