<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 11:37:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Some parties deceiving people in the name of consensus: Nahid</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/some-parties-deceiving-people-in-the-name-of-consensus-ncps-nahid</link><description>National Citizen Party (NCP) leader Nahid Islam has accused several political parties of deceiving the public by signing a document under the banner of “national consensus”.
Nahid made the allegation on Friday at the launch of the party’s labour wing, the Jatiya Sramik Shakti, in</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 08:52:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Burnt CEPZ factory lacked 'fire safety certificate', 'breached building code</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/chattogram-epz-blaze-officials-say-factory-lacked-fire-safety-certificate-violated-building-code</link><description>The Fire Service says the factory building gutted in a fire in the Chattogram Export Processing Zone (CEPZ) did not have a fire safety performance certificate.
Fire Service Director (Operations and Maintenance) Lt Col Mohammad Tajul Islam Chowdhury made the remark in response to questions from the</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 09:07:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Stage set for July Charter signing ceremony</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/stage-set-for-july-charter-signing-ceremony-amid-tight-security</link><description>Preparations have been completed at the South Plaza of Bangladesh’s National Parliament for the signing ceremony of the July National Charter.
Chief Advisor Muhammad Yunus will preside over the event, organised by the National Consensus Commission.
Monir Haider, special assistant to the chi</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 09:22:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>510 dengue cases reported in 24 hours</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/510-dengue-cases-reported-in-24-hours</link><description>A total of 510 new dengue cases were reported across the country in the 24 hours till Friday morning, bringing the total number of cases this year to 58,280, according to the Directorate General of Health Services (DGHS).
No new dengue-related deaths were reported during this period, keeping the d</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 09:37:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Last-minute July Charter change in face of protest</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/july-charter-changed-at-last-minute-ahead-of-signing-in-face-of-protest</link><description>The National Consensus Commission has announced changes to the fifth clause of the July Charter just before the signing ceremony.
The “urgent amendment” was made in response to the demands of the July fighters, a press release from the commission said.
The amendment was read out by th</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 09:52:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>July Charter signing ceremony under way</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/july-charter-signing-ceremony-under-way</link><description>The signing ceremony for the July Charter, which sets out commitments to state reform, is under way at the South Plaza of Parliament. Political parties are expected to sign the charter in the presence of Chief Advisor Muhammad Yunus.</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 10:37:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>National Emigration Day of Algeria observed in city</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/national-emigration-day-of-algeria-observed-in-city</link><description>The Embassy of Algeria in Bangladesh on Friday hosted a solemn ceremony to commemorate the 64th anniversary of the massacres of 17 October 1961, under the theme “Cohesion and Commitment.”
This date has been recognised as National Emigration Day in Algeria since 2021, honouring the cour</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 10:52:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shibir sweeps all RU hall elections</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/shibir-sweeps-all-ru-hall-elections</link><description>The Islami Chhatra Shibir-backed “Combined Student Alliance” has secured a landslide victory in the Rajshahi University (RU) Hall Union elections, clinching all vice-president (VP), general secretary (GS), and assistant general secretary (AGS) posts across all 17 residential halls.
Not</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 11:07:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chief adviser, politicians sign July National Charter</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/chief-adviser-politicians-sign-july-national-charter</link><description>Interim government Chief Adviser Muhammad Yunus and leaders of various political parties have signed the July National Charter 2025.
The signing took place at a ceremony at 5pm on Friday.
Earlier, the signing ceremony began at 4:37pm on Friday with the rendition of the national anthem.</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 11:37:47 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>