<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 06:31:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Over 2,600 BJMC staff await eight months' unpaid wages</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/over-2600-bjmc-staff-await-eight-months-unpaid-wages</link><description>The Ministry of Textiles and Jute (MoTJ) has sought Tk 941 million from the Ministry of Finance to clear eight months of unpaid salaries for officers and employees of the Bangladesh Jute Mills Corporation (BJMC).
The request follows months of financial hardship for more than 2,600 workers tasked w</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 02:57:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Political uncertainty drags down foreign cos' income in Jan-Sept</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/political-uncertainty-drags-down-foreign-cos-income-in-jan-sept</link><description>Most multinational companies saw their profits plummet in January-September this year compared to the same period last year, largely due to high finance costs and macroeconomic challenges amid political uncertainty.
Economic activities have remained sluggish following the political changeover last</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 03:12:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fair prices delight jute farmers in Chandpur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/fair-prices-delight-jute-farmers-in-chandpur</link><description>After a few years, farmers of the district wear smiles on their faces as they are getting pretty fair prices of their hard-produced jute at the time of selling it to the big merchants in the weekly marketplaces here.
The demand for jute is on increase across the country as the government is laying</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 03:27:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Family homes, farmlands at risk as erosion worsens in Magura</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/family-homes-farmlands-at-risk-as-erosion-worsens-in-magura</link><description>Severe river erosion has taken devastating turns in Sreepur and Mohammadpur upazilas in Magura, as the fierce currents and surging waves of the Gorai and Madhumati rivers continue to devour vast areas of farmlands and roads.
Despite years of erosion, no effective government action has yet been tak</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 03:42:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Youth held over harassing girl on moving bus in city</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/youth-held-over-harassing-girl-on-moving-bus-in-city</link><description>Members of the Rapid Action Battalion (RAB) have arrested an individual for his alleged involvement in harassing a young girl while travelling on a bus in Mohammadpur area of the capital.
The name of the arrestee is Nizam Uddin (45).
Additional Police Super of RAB -4 KN Roy Nioti said on Saturday</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 03:57:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pry teachers threaten work abstention, sit-in over three-pt demand</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/pry-teachers-threaten-work-abstention-sit-in-over-three-pt-demand</link><description>Assistant teachers at the government primary schools threatened on Saturday to go for nationwide work abstention and sit-in programmes if their long-standing demands of pay grades and promotions were not realised by November 15.
They under the banner of Primary Assistant Teachers Organisation Oiky</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 04:12:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fire at Mexico store kills at least 23</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/fire-at-mexico-store-kills-at-least-23</link><description>A festive holiday weekend turned tragic for families in northwestern Mexico on Saturday when a deadly blaze engulfed a discount store in the city center of Hermosillo, killing at least 23 people and injuring a dozen.
Mexico is celebrating the Day of the Dead this weekend with colourful festivities</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 04:27:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Suspected three 'cattle thieves' lynched in Gaibandha</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/suspected-three-cattle-thieves-lynched-in-gaibandha</link><description>Villagers have beaten three suspected cattle thieves to death in Gobindaganj upazila of Gaibandha district.
The incident occurred at Nasirabad village in Katabari Union early morning on Sunday.
The dead trio could not be identified immediately, reports bdnews24.com.
Gobindaganj Police Station ch</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 04:57:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Body fifth missing child floats up in Jamalpur river</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/body-fifth-missing-child-floats-up-in-jamalpur-river</link><description>The bodies of all five children who went missing after entering the Jhinai River to bathe have now been recovered in Jamalpur's Madarganj Upazila.
Locals found the body of the last remaining missing child from the river on Sunday morning, according to Sub-Inspector Ziaul Haque Zia of the Shyamganj</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 05:27:32 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>