<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 12:44:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Authorities urge calm after fire report near Rooppur nuclear plant</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/authorities-urge-calm-after-fire-report-near-rooppur-nuclear-plant</link><description>Officials from the Rooppur Nuclear Power Plant Project have urged the public not to be misled by misinformation or rumours surrounding a recent fire that broke out near the plant in Pabna.
In a statement issued on Thursday night, Saikat Ahmed, senior scientific information officer for the plant's</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 07:21:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Army warns of legal action over false social media posts on Gazipur arrests</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/army-warns-of-legal-action-over-false-social-media-posts-on-gazipur-arrests</link><description>Bangladesh Army has warned that legal action would be taken against those spreading false or misleading information about the arrests of seven people, including a former Jatiyatabadi Chhatra Dal (JCD) leader of Sreepur upazila in Gazipur district, on social media.
At a press briefing on Friday mor</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 07:15:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fire destroys 15 shops in Lakshmipur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/fire-destroys-15-shops-in-lakshmipur</link><description>Fifteen shops have been destroyed in a fire in Lakshmipur’s Ramgati Upazila.
The blaze broke out in a market in the Alexander Bazar area early on Friday morning, according to Khokon Majudar, station officer of the Ramgati Fire Service.
Locals said the fire originated from an electrical shor</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 07:30:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Conspiracy brewing to shatter democracy again after mass uprising: Fakhrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/conspiracy-brewing-to-shatter-democracy-again-after-mass-uprising-fakhrul</link><description>A conspiracy is being hatched to subvert democracy in Bangladesh again after the July Uprising, says BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir.
He remarked while speaking to the media after laying wreaths at the grave of former president and BNP founder Ziaur Rahman in Dhaka's Sher-e-Bangl</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 07:45:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Attorney general says he can contest polls while in office</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/attorney-general-says-he-can-contest-polls-while-in-office</link><description>Attorney General Md Asaduzzaman has said there is no legal barrier to his participation in the upcoming national elections while holding his current post, arguing that the country's top law officer is not a government employee under the Constitution.
Speaking to reporters at his office on Thursday</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 08:00:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>'Fraudster' held over cheating businessman out of Tk 1.5m</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/fraudster-held-over-cheating-businessman-out-of-tk-15m</link><description>Police have arrested an individual linked with a fraud gang for allegedly swindling a businessman out of Tk 1.5 million.
The name of the arrestee is Md Saddam Hossain (35).
He was arrested by the Cyber Police Centre (CPC) unit of Criminal Investigation Department (CID) from South Keraniganj's Has</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 08:15:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Primary teachers to stage nonstop sit-in from Saturday for pay bump</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/primary-teachers-to-stage-nonstop-sit-in-from-saturday-for-pay-bump</link><description>Assistant teachers of government primary schools are set to launch a fresh protest programme, demanding that their salaries be raised to the 10th grade pay scale and to press for long-pending promotions.
On Saturday, they plan to begin a "continuous" sit-in at Dhaka’s Central Shaheed Minar,</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 08:30:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Honorary consul of Ireland Masud Khan hosts dinner in honour of Irish Ambassador, visiting baroness</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/honorary-consul-of-ireland-masud-khan-hosts-dinner-in-honour-of-irish-ambassador-visiting-baroness</link><description>Honorary consul of Ireland in Bangladesh and Deputy Managing Director of Cosmos Group, Masud Jamil Khan, hosted a farewell dinner in honour of Baroness Nuala O’Loan, a member of the UK House of Lords and the first Police Ombudsman of Northern Ireland, in Bangladesh and Kevin Kelly, Ambassador</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 10:43:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>15 injured in BNP-Gono Odhikar clash in Patuakhali's Galachipa</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/15-injured-in-bnp-gono-odhikar-clash-in-patuakhalis-galachipa</link><description>At least 15 people, including a woman, were injured in a clash between supporters of the BNP and Gono Odhikar Parishad in Galachipa upazila of Patuakhali district on Thursday night.
The incident occurred around 9:00 pm at Dakshin Kupalbera intersection in Charshiba village under Charkazal union, a</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 10:58:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ansar member dismissed over mobile phone theft at Dhaka airport's cargo complex</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ansar-member-dismissed-over-mobile-phone-theft-at-dhaka-airports-cargo-complex</link><description>An Ansar member has been expelled from the force on charges of stealing mobile phones from the cargo complex at Dhaka's Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport.
The expulsion of Zenarul Islam, a uniformed member of the auxiliary force, was announced in a statement issued by the Ansar Headquarters</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 11:13:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India sets up Army base, military station along Bangladesh border</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/india-sets-up-army-base-military-station-along-bangladesh-border</link><description>The Indian Army has operationalised a new military base in West Bengal’s North Dinajpur and is raising a new military station in Assam’s Dhubri to reinforce its capacity along the border with Bangladesh, reports the Deccan Chronicle.
The Hyderabad-based English language daily reported</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 12:06:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh to move towards election through legal basis of July Charter, says Nahid</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bangladesh-to-move-towards-election-through-legal-basis-of-july-charter-says-nahid</link><description>Bangladesh will move towards elections through a legal basis of the July Charter containing state reform initiatives, says National Citizen Party (NCP) Convener Nahid Islam.
He said, “Muhammad Yunus must issue the order of the July Charter from the point of the mass uprising. July Charter sh</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 12:21:35 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>