<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 12:51:37 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Yunus to address the nation on Tuesday evening</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/yunus-to-address-the-nation-on-tuesday-evening</link><description>Chief Advisor Muhammad Yunus is set to address the nation on the occasion of Victory Day.
The speech will be broadcast simultaneously on state-run Bangladesh Television, BTV News and Bangladesh Betar at 6:30pm on Tuesday, the Chief Advisor's Office said.</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 10:15:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CA enjoys Victory Day fly past, parajump</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ca-enjoys-victory-day-fly-past-parajump</link><description>Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus on Tuesday enjoyed Victory Day Fly Past, parajump and band display at the National Parade Ground in the city.
To mark the country’s 54 years of independence, 54 paratroopers from the Bangladesh Army, Navy and Air Force performed a national flag-bearing</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 10:30:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Green becomes IPL's most expensive overseas player</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/australias-green-becomes-ipls-most-expensive-overseas-player-after-277-million-move-to-kolkata</link><description>Australia all-rounder Cameron Green became the most expensive overseas player in the Indian Premier League (IPL), after Kolkata Knight Riders signed him for 252 million Indian rupees ($2.77 million) at the player auction for the 2026 season on Tuesday.
Green, who was initially registered as a bats</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 10:21:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Malaysian PM Anwar names new ministers in cabinet reshuffle</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/malaysian-pm-anwar-names-new-trade-economy-ministers-in-cabinet-reshuffle</link><description>Malaysian Prime Minister Anwar Ibrahim named new trade and economic ministers on Tuesday, reshuffling his cabinet in a bid to stabilise his administration and fill several vacancies arising from resignations and expired senate terms.
The Southeast Asian nation has enjoyed steady economic growth an</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 10:36:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Polish student detained over suspected Christmas market attack plot</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/polish-student-detained-over-suspected-christmas-market-attack-plot</link><description>Polish security services have detained a student suspected of preparing a "mass attack" at a Christmas market, Jacek Dobrzynski, a spokesperson for Poland's special services, said on Tuesday.
Mateusz W, a student at the Catholic University of Lublin, wanted to commit an attack using explosives and</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 10:51:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chhatra Dal boycotts CU Victory Day event over pro-VC’s presence</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/chhatra-dal-boycotts-cu-victory-day-event-over-pro-vcs-presence</link><description>The Chittagong University unit of Jatiotabadi Chhatra Dal has boycotted the Victory Day programme, protesting the presence of pro-Vice-Chancellor Mohammed Shamim Uddin Khan.
The announcement of the boycott came during a discussion organised at the university’s Jarul Tola on Tuesday morning.</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 11:06:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nabanna Festival 2025 held at BRAC University</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/nabanna-festival-2025-held-at-brac-university</link><description>The BRAC University Marketing Association (BUMA) on Monday organised Nabanna Festival 2025 at BRAC University to introduce the next generation to Bengal’s history, traditions and culture.
The festival began at 9:00am on the university campus and concluded in the afternoon with cultural perfo</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 11:21:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Thailand works to repatriate thousands stranded at Cambodia border crossing</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/thailand-works-to-repatriate-thousands-stranded-at-cambodia-border-crossing</link><description>Thailand is working out how to repatriate up to 6,000 citizens unable to return home through a major border crossing in Cambodia closed as fighting along the contested border extended into a second week, authorities said on Tuesday.
The militaries of the Southeast Asian neighbours are clashing at</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 11:36:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shadik Kayem pledges to 'establish justice' on Victory Day</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/ducsu-vp-shadik-kayem-promises-to-establish-justice-on-victory-day</link><description>Dhaka University Central Students’ Union (DUCSU) Vice-President Abu Shadik Kayem has said the "pledge" for this Victory Day is to establish "justice” by holding those who have attempted to make the state "ineffective" since 1971 to account.
Paying tribute to the heroic martyrs at the N</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 11:52:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Faisal's associate to be quizzed for 7 days</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/faisals-associate-to-be-quizzed-for-7-days</link><description>Police have been granted seven days to grill an alleged associate of Faisal Karim Masud, the key suspect in the attempted murder of Inqilab Moncho leader Sharif Osman bin Hadi.
Dhaka Metropolitan Magistrate Hasibuzzaman issued the order on Tuesday in response to the police's 10-day remand petition</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 12:07:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Freedom fighter’s grave torched on Victory Day</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/freedom-fighters-grave-torched-in-shariatpur-on-victory-day</link><description>The grave of a freedom fighter has been set on fire in Shariatpur Sadar Upazila on the morning of Victory Day.
The family of freedom fighter Abdul Mannan Khan said that someone had set fire to the grave in Char Niamatpur village of Angaria Union and fled the scene on Tuesday morning.
Villagers sa</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 12:22:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Praising Ghulam Azam undermines freedom fighters: Abbas</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/where-do-freedom-fighters-stand-if-ghulam-azam-is-hailed-as-nations-best-son-mirza-abbas-asks</link><description>Senior BNP leader Mirza Abbas has questioned the labelling of some Jamaat-e-Islami leaders, convicted of war crimes, as the nation’s best sons.
He wondered where the freedom fighters stand if the likes of Ghulam Azam are hailed in that way.
After paying tribute to the martyrs of Bangladesh&amp;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 12:37:54 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>