<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 04:28:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>ICT releases full verdict on Hasina, Kamal’s death penalty</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ict-releases-full-verdict-on-hasina-kamals-death-penalty</link><description>The International Crimes Tribunal (ICT)-1 on Wednesday released the full text of its 453-page judgment that convicted and sentenced ousted prime minister Sheikh Hasina and former home minister Asaduzzaman Khan Kamal to death for crimes against humanity committed during last year’s July Mass U</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 17:08:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Banks’ NPL balloons to  Tk 6.44t in Sept count</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/banks-npl-balloons-to-tk-644t-in-sept-count</link><description>Banks in Bangladesh gasp under a burden of bad loans as the aggregate volume makes a quantum leap by over Tk 2.24 trillion in just six months to a record high until September.
As per latest-available data until last September, with the fast rise in non-performing loans (NPLs), the outstanding of t</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 17:23:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khaleda Zia’s breathing improves, says BNP</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/khaleda-zias-breathing-improves-says-bnp</link><description>BNP Chairperson Khaleda Zia’s breathing difficulty has eased after an infection in her heart and lungs, the party’s health affairs secretary has said. 
A medical board is providing necessary treatment while she remains in a cabin under intense observation, Dr Rafiqul Islam said, &amp;</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 17:38:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>International liner trade of Bangladesh--partnering with leading terminal operators</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/international-liner-trade-of-bangladesh-partnering-with-leading-terminal-operators</link><description>The recent initiatives of the interim government of Bangladesh in the terminal operations of Chittagong port, awarding two terminals to global operators, as well as the operations of Pangaon inland terminal have raised controversies. Reading the reports and submissions at the apex court and argumen</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 17:53:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Antimicrobial resistance threat looms large</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/antimicrobial-resistance-threat-looms-large</link><description>Antimicrobial Resistance (AMR), a growing global public health threat, is severely affecting the management of infectious diseases. Microorganisms are increasingly developing the ability to resist the killing effects of antimicrobials (AMs), rendering these drugs less effective or even completely u</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 18:08:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Beyond demolition of vulnerable buildings</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/beyond-demolition-of-vulnerable-buildings</link><description>The deployment of eight teams by the Rajdhani Unnayan Kartipakkha (RAJUK) following the Friday's powerful quake and three more tremors the next day to assess the vulnerabilities of buildings in Dhaka is a welcome move. It has identified 300 buildings out of 3,252 already assessed at quake risks. Th</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 18:23:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>45th BCS results released after three years, 1,807 cleared for hiring</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/45th-bcs-results-released-after-three-years-1807-cleared-for-hiring</link><description>The Public Service Commission (PSC) has released the final results of the 45th BCS, nearly three years after the circular was issued, recommending 1,807 candidates for cadre posts.
The PSC published the results at 11pm on Wednesday, said spokesperson SM Matiur Rahman, with details now available on</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 19:23:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Policy gaps hinder Bangladesh’s growth in global toy export market</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/policy-gaps-hinder-bangladeshs-export-growth-in-multi-billion-dollar-global-toy-industry</link><description>Bangladeshi entrepreneurs are facing a series of policy-related challenges that hinder their ability to grab the growing opportunities in the global toy market, though the interim government aims to diversify the country's export basket.
Exporters say they are taking significant risks to explore i</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 02:00:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Electric bus in Dhaka: Rollout hits snag amid approval backlog</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/electric-bus-in-dhaka-rollout-hits-snag-amid-approval-backlog</link><description>The rollout of electric buses under the Bangladesh Clean Air Project (BCAP) is set to be delayed indefinitely, as the required project approvals could not be obtained during the interim government's tenure.
Officials said that although the World Bank (WB) approved US$290 million for the project in</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 02:15:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Businesses call for pre-listing inspections of IPO aspirants to ensure fair valuation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/businesses-call-for-pre-listing-inspections-of-ipo-aspirants-to-ensure-fair-valuation</link><description>Business enterprises have suggested on-the-spot inspections of companies willing to go public to assess whether their financial and operational strength is sufficient to protect shareholders' interests.
The proposal came at a meeting held on Wednesday at the Bangladesh Securities and Exchange Comm</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 02:30:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Death toll rises to 36 in Hong Kong residential block fire</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/death-toll-rises-to-36-in-hong-kong-residential-block-fire</link><description>At least 36 people were killed and 279 were missing on Wednesday after Hong Kong's deadliest fire in three decades ripped through high-rise residential towers sheathed in flammable bamboo scaffolding, authorities said.
More than 10 hours after the fire started in the northern Tai Po district, flam</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 02:45:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>TIB calls for full disclosure of agreements with foreign cos on Laldia, Pangaon terminals</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tib-calls-for-full-disclosure-of-agreements-with-foreign-cos-on-laldia-pangaon-terminals</link><description>Transparency International Bangladesh (TIB) has said that while foreign investment in the development of Chattogram Port may bring positive outcomes for the country, the government must fully disclose all information, conditions, and procedures related to recently signed terminal agreements to ensu</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 03:00:52 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>