<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 06:29:30 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Revised DAP: Realtors in quandary for contractionary complex FAR arithmetic</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/realtors-in-quandary-for-contractionary-complex-far-arithmetic</link><description>Realtors decry house-floor squeeze under the revised the Detailed Area Plan (DAP) arithmetic as they say it makes difficult for them to get optimum achievable FAR in the sprawling capital city.
The newly introduced, more complex calculation method for determining Floor Area Ratio (FAR) could resul</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 02:48:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Stocks slip into red amid flurry of earnings results</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/stocks-slip-into-red-amid-flurry-of-earnings-results</link><description>The benchmark index of the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) slipped into the red this week, reversing a single-week of gains, as risk-averse investors largely stayed on the sidelines amid the ongoing earnings disclosures.
Market analysts noted that investors appeared cautious, adopting a 'wait-and-see'</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 04:08:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BAT Bangladesh posts 23pc drop in Q3 profit on sales slump</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/bat-bangladesh-posts-23pc-drop-in-q3-profit-on-sales-slump</link><description>British American Tobacco (BAT) Bangladesh has posted a 23 per cent year-on-year decline in profits for the third quarter of this year, primarily driven by lower sales and increased operational costs.
The multinational tobacco company reported a profit of Tk 3.05 billion for the July-September peri</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 04:15:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh, Algeria eye major energy deal and direct flights</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladesh-algeria-eye-major-energy-deal-and-direct-flights-1</link><description>Bangladesh and Algeria are moving closer to sealing a major cooperation agreement in the energy sector, a step that could deepen economic ties between the two nations, according to Algerian Ambassador to Bangladesh Dr Abdelouahab Saidani.
In an exclusive interview with The Financial Express, Dr Sa</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 04:30:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fish prices soar; vegetable, egg prices drop last week</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/fish-prices-soar-vegetable-egg-prices-drop-last-week</link><description>Fish prices continued to rise sharply last week, causing frustration among common consumers.
The prices of cultured fishes, such as rui, katla, pabda, and pangas, increased by Tk 30-50 a kg over the past week; while the supply of indigenous species remained limited, traders said.
Cultured rui and</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 05:00:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>RU Syndicate okays Tk 35b dev project proposal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/ru-syndicate-okays-tk-35b-dev-project-proposal</link><description>The Rajshahi University (RU) Syndicate has approved a mega development project proposal worth around Tk 35 billion (3,500 crore) for improving the university's infrastructure and enhancing advanced research facilities.
The approval came at the Syndicate's 543rd meeting, held on Monday with Vice-Ch</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 05:15:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dengue cases, deaths hit record high in October</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dengue-cases-deaths-hit-record-high-in-october</link><description>October has witnessed the highest number of dengue-related deaths and infections this year, amid a worsening situation in and outside of the city.
The country reported no new deaths on Friday, and the total death toll remained at 278 this year. This included a monthly high of 80 deaths in October</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 05:30:28 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>