<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 12:44:49 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Election cannot be held under caretaker govt even if reinstated: Shishir Manir</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/election-cannot-be-held-under-caretaker-govt-even-if-reinstated-shishir-manir</link><description>Advocate Mohammad Shishir Manir stated on Tuesday that it would not be possible to hold the upcoming 13th National Parliamentary Election under a caretaker government, even if such a system were reinstated through a Supreme Court verdict.
"According to the Constitution, a caretaker government must</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 09:35:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Kenyan airline says eight Hungarians, two Germans on plane that crashed</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/kenyan-airline-says-eight-hungarians-two-germans-on-plane-that-crashed</link><description>Kenyan airline Mombasa Air Safari said on Tuesday that eight Hungarians, two Germans and a Kenyan crew member were on one of its aircraft that crashed earlier in the day.
"Sadly, there are no survivors. ... We are profoundly saddened to report that, according to preliminary information, there were</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 09:50:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BB and Mercantile Bank jointly organise closing ceremony of Entrepreneurship Development Program</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bb-and-mercantile-bank-jointly-organise-closing-ceremony-of-entrepreneurship-development-program</link><description>With the finance of Asian Development Bank (ADB), supervision of Bangladesh Bank and initiative of the Ministry of Finance, Mercantile Bank organized the certificate giving and closing ceremony of month-long Entrepreneurship Development Program as part of the ‘Skills for Industry Competitiven</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 10:20:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Saudi AI firm Humain partners with Google, eyes deal with AWS</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/saudi-ai-firm-humain-partners-with-google-eyes-deal-with-aws</link><description>Saudi AI firm Humain's CEO Tareq Amin said on Tuesday the company has a partnership with Google and said there might be an upcoming significant collaboration with Amazon Web Services.
Amin also said the company had met with OpenAI.</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 10:35:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Referendum in Nov, no additional RPO amendments: Jamaat to EC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-seeks-referendum-in-november-no-further-rpo-amendment-at-meeting-with-ec</link><description>Jamaat-e-Islami has called on the Election Commission not to amend the Representation of the People Order (RPO) provision that requires candidates to contest under their own party symbol even when contesting as part of an alliance.
The party also demanded that a national referendum be held next mo</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 10:50:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP rejects Consensus Commission’s call for pre-election referendum</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-rejects-consensus-commissions-call-for-pre-election-referendum</link><description>BNP senior leader Amir Khosru Mahmud Chowdhury on Tuesday said their party does not agree with the Consensus Commission's recommendation to hold a referendum before the national election, saying BNP's position on the issue remains unchanged.
"BNP does not agree with the Consensus Commission's reco</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 11:20:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US should not worry about Bangladesh-China ties: Foreign adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/us-should-not-worry-about-bangladesh-china-ties-foreign-adviser</link><description>Foreign Affairs Adviser Md. Touhid Hossain said that there is no reason for the United States or any third country to be concerned about Bangladesh’s balanced relationship with China.
He said this while asked to comment on the remark of Brent Christensen on Bangladesh’s growing ties wi</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 11:50:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Delhi turns to cloud seeding to spur rain, curb pollution</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/delhi-turns-to-cloud-seeding-to-spur-rain-curb-pollution</link><description>Authorities in the Indian capital territory of Delhi began seeding clouds on Tuesday to induce artificial rain and bring down pollution levels in the city that has been battling poor air for days, Environment Minister Manjinder Singh Sirsa said.
The method seeks to increase precipitation by adding</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 12:05:31 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>