<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 05:30:18 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Swechchhasebak Dal leader Musabbir was murdered over extortion: DMP</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/swechchhasebak-dal-leader-musabbir-was-murdered-over-extortion-dmp</link><description>Dhaka Metropolitan Police (DMP) Additional Commissioner Shafiqul Islam said on Saturday that Swechchhasebak Dal leader Azizur Rahman Musabbir was murdered over extortion and dominance in the capital's Karwan Bazar area.
"The murder was carried out on the instructions of Dilip, alias Binash, centri</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 01:22:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Post-election market recovery unlikely without structural reforms</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/post-election-market-recovery-unlikely-without-structural-reforms</link><description>There is hyped expectation in the secondary market that it will recover after the upcoming national election with the return of political stability, but experts rule this out, saying fundamental change is imperative.
They say the overhaul of the banking sector should continue under the elected gov</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 01:37:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NSU's National Career Fair addresses a market failure employers and graduates both feel</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/article/nsus-national-career-fair-addresses-a-market-failure-employers-and-graduates-both-feel</link><description>Bangladesh produces degree-holders at scale, and employers still struggle to hire job-ready talent. Graduates struggle to land their first credible role. That paradox has a name: mismatch. It comes from information gaps, weak signalling, uneven skills, and hiring processes that reward networks over</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 01:52:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The salary transparency conversation nobody wants to have</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/article/the-salary-transparency-conversation-nobody-wants-to-have</link><description>We discuss everything at work— office politics, weekend plans, relationship drama, even deeply personal health issues. Mention your actual salary, and suddenly everyone's staring at their shoes like you just asked them to explain cryptocurrency to their grandparents. A colleague earns 30 per</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 02:07:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Global deforestation sparks worldwide red alert</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/analysis/global-deforestation-sparks-worldwide-red-alert</link><description>The primary source of natural beauty is trees and forests. Yet due to fires, human exploitation of forests, poverty, and deforestation in the name of development-along with many other factors-the sources of natural beauty are under severe strain. In Bangladesh and across the world, the destruction</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 02:22:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Beyond outrage: How Bangladesh can reform its animal rights regime</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/analysis/beyond-outrage-how-bangladesh-can-reform-its-animal-rights-regime</link><description>On January 16, two cats owned by Zillur Rahman, an inhabitant of Monirampur of Jashore, innocently strolled into the neighbouring house owned by Hira. Hira did not shoo the cats away. Instead, he lured them into a room, closed the doors and windows and proceeded to beat them mercilessly with a stic</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 02:37:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Green coalitions table 12-point recommendation ahead of polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/green-coalitions-table-12-point-recommendation-ahead-of-polls</link><description>Environment rights groups on Saturday placed a 12-point recommendation to the political parties ahead of the February national election, putting special focus on upholding Bangladesh's rights to upstream water, safeguarding the environment and containing pollution.
Bangladesh Environment Movement</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 02:52:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IGP orders police to wear body cameras for transparent polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/igp-orders-police-to-wear-body-cameras-for-transparent-polls</link><description>CHATTOGRAM, Jan 24: Inspector General of Police (IGP) Baharul Alam has directed all police personnel to wear body cameras while on duty to uphold transparency, accountability, and impartiality during the upcoming 13th Jatiya Sangsad (JS) elections.
Addressing a pre-election briefing at the Civic C</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 03:07:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DUJA holds training on investigative journalism</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/duja-holds-training-on-investigative-journalism</link><description>The Dhaka University Journalists' Association (DUJA) organised a training programme on investigative journalism for university-based reporters and distributed its Quarterly Reporters' Awards in recognition of outstanding reporting.
The programme was held on Saturday at the Abdul Matin Chowdhury Vi</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 03:22:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Lions allocates more than $1.0m for 300 dev and humanitarian projects in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/others/lions-allocates-more-than-10m-for-300-dev-and-humanitarian-projects-in-bangladesh</link><description>Lions International has allocated more than US$1.0 million fund for its over 300 development and humanitarian projects across Bangladesh, aiming to bolster the country's socio-economic development.
The information was disclosed by Dr. Manoj Shah, second international vice president of Lions Intern</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 03:37:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US Border Patrol shooting in Minneapolis kills ICU nurse, family says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/us-border-patrol-shooting-in-minneapolis-kills-icu-nurse-family-says</link><description>Alex Jeffrey Pretti, 37, an intensive care nurse at a VA hospital, was shot and killed by a U.S. Border Patrol officer in Minneapolis on Saturday, his family said. Pretti, a U.S. citizen from Illinois, was known for his compassion, love for the outdoors, and concern over immigration policies under</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 03:52:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>10 dead, 80 missing after Indonesia landslide</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/10-dead-80-missing-after-indonesia-landslide</link><description>Indonesian authorities resumed search-and-rescue efforts for 80 people missing after a landslide killed 10 in a residential area of West Java province.
The landslide early on Saturday was triggered by heavy rains starting the day before, which the weather agency warned could continue for a week in</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 04:52:56 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>