<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 06:30:22 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Students prepare for Tech Fusion Fest 2025</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/article/students-prepare-for-tech-fusion-fest-2025</link><description>Excitement builds at the Bangladesh University of Business and Technology (BUBT) as students gear up for Tech Fusion Fest 2025. This highly anticipated technology festival, organised by the BASIS Students' Forum of BUBT Chapter, will take place on November 17, 18, and 19 this year. The entire campu</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 04:31:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Opportunities to save and invest for young people</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/article/opportunities-to-save-and-invest-for-young-people</link><description>Think about this: whilst one person scrolls through social media for an hour, someone their age somewhere else just earned enough returns to buy three months of groceries. The difference isn't luck. It's a matter of where money was positioned last year.
Bangladesh stands at a peculiar crossroads.</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 04:46:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A Bangladeshi physicist at the frontier of quantum science</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/analysis/a-bangladeshi-physicist-at-the-frontier-of-quantum-science</link><description>When Nature, the world’s most prestigious science journal, published a paper by a young Bangladeshi physicist in August 2024, it marked more than an academic milestone. It showed that the frontiers of quantum materials research now extend far beyond elite Western laboratories, encompassing th</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 03:47:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump headlines ASEAN summit, Thailand-Cambodia to sign ceasefire deal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-headlines-asean-summit-thailand-cambodia-to-sign-ceasefire-deal</link><description>US President Donald Trump landed in Malaysia for the ASEAN Summit on Sunday, where he is set to witness an expanded ceasefire deal between Thailand and Cambodia and oversee pivotal trade talks.
Trump's first order of business at the Association of Southeast Asian Nations summit will involve watchi</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 04:02:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Three killed in Pabna road accident</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/three-killed-in-pabna-road-accident345</link><description>Three people, including two school students, were killed and another was injured when a truck overturned onto their van in Sadar upazila of Pabna district on Sunday morning.
The accident occurred in the Bangabari area along Dhaka-Pabna highway, police said.
The deceased are Tasnia and Toha, stude</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 04:17:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Timor-Leste becomes ASEAN's 11th member</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/timor-leste-becomes-aseans-11th-member</link><description>Timor-Leste has been welcomed into the Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN) as the grouping's 11th member, following an official ceremony at the 47th ASEAN Summit in the Malaysian capital on Sunday.
Timor-Leste's President Jose Ramos-Horta and Prime Minister Xanana Gusmao were present at</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 04:32:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Man held after ‘improvised explosive’ blast outside EC offices</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/man-held-after-improvised-explosive-blast-outside-ec-offices</link><description>Police have “chased down” and detained a man after an “improvised explosive”, colloquially known as cocktail bomb, was detonated in front of the Election Commission (EC) headquarters in Agargaon area of Dhaka.
The blast occurred around 11:30 pm on Saturday, according to Ibn</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 04:47:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two killed in US North Carolina shooting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/two-killed-in-us-north-carolina-shooting</link><description>At least two people were killed and several others were critically wounded after a shooting took place Saturday at a large party in the US state of North Carolina, local police said.
A total of 13 people were shot in a rural area outside the southern town of Maxton, Robeson County Sheriff Burnis W</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 05:17:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bank official jailed for acting as proxy in recruitment exam</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bank-official-jailed-for-acting-as-proxy-in-recruitment-exam</link><description>A bank official was caught impersonating a candidate during the Food Department’s Sub-Inspector recruitment exam in Rangpur on Saturday.
He was sentenced to one month in jail by a mobile court, reports UNB.
The convicted man, Golam Rabbani, an officer at Janata Bank’s Rangpur Corporat</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 05:32:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Louvre transfers jewels to Bank of France</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/others/louvre-transfers-jewels-to-bank-of-france</link><description>The Louvre has transferred some of its most precious jewels to the Bank of France, according to French radio RTL, after an audacious daylight heist last week exposed the famed museum's security vulnerability.
The transfer of some precious items from the museum's Apollo gallery, home to the French</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 05:47:34 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>