<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 09:21:40 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Russia's gold reserves hit historic high</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/russias-gold-reserves-hit-historic-high</link><description>Russia's gold reserves exceeded 310 billion US dollars for the first time on Dec. 1, 2025, according to a report released Friday by the Central Bank of Russia.
Marking the fourth consecutive monthly increase, the value of Russia's gold holdings reached a record 310.72 billion dollars, up 3.6 per c</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 06:56:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Lalmonirhat celebrates the day Pakistani troops fled in 1971</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/lalmonirhat-celebrates-the-day-pakistani-troops-fled-in-1971</link><description>Lalmonirhat district is observing Freedom Day on Saturday as the district was freed from Pakistani occupation on this day in 1971.
On this day 54 years ago, Pakistan army troops fled Lalmonirhat amid a coordinated three-pronged assault by Mukti Bahini fighters.
Residents recall that Pakistani for</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 07:11:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jatiya Party leaders Manju, Anisul to launch new 16-party alliance</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jatiya-party-leaders-manju-anisul-to-launch-new-16-party-alliance</link><description>A new multi-party political alliance is set to launch ahead of the 13th national parliamentary election, bringing together the Jatiya Party factions led by Anisul Islam Mahmud and Anwar Hossain Manju, along with several smaller groups.
Ruhul Amin Hawlader, secretary general of the Anisul-led facti</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 07:26:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>193,874 expatriates register for national election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/193874-expatriates-register-for-national-election</link><description>A total of 193,874 Bangladeshi expatriates have so far registered through the 'Postal Vote BD' app to vote in the 13th Jatiya Sangsad Election and the referendum, according to a BSS report. 
According to updated figures released on the Election Commission (EC) website on Saturday morning, of</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 06:27:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khaleda Zia's leadership a national asset: Asif Mahmud</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/khaleda-zias-leadership-a-national-asset-asif-mahmud</link><description>Local Government, Rural Development and Cooperatives Adviser Asif Mahmud Shojib Bhuyain has said that the nation regards the leadership and wisdom of former Prime Minister Begum Khaleda Zia as a valuable asset.
In a post on his verified Facebook page on Thursday, Asif, who also serves as Youth and</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 06:42:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fall of Autocracy Day today</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fall-of-autocracy-day-today</link><description>The nation is observing Fall of Autocracy Day on Saturday marking the fall of autocratic ruler HM Ershad in 1990.
On December 6, 1990, military dictator Ershad stepped down in the face of a mass upsurge and handed power over to a caretaker government ending his nine years of autocratic rule which</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 06:57:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How Netflix won Hollywood's biggest prize, Warner Bros Discovery</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/how-netflix-won-hollywoods-biggest-prize-warner-bros-discovery</link><description>What started as a fact-finding mission for Netflix culminated in one of the biggest media deals in the last decade and one that stands to reshape the global entertainment business landscape, people with direct knowledge of the deal told Reuters.
Netflix announced on Friday it had reached a deal to</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 07:12:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Feni celebrates Liberation Day</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/feni-celebrates-liberation-day</link><description>Feni is observing its Liberation Day on Saturday as freedom fighters defeated the Pakistani occupation force and their local collaborators on this day in 1971.
The valiant sons of the district hoisted the flag of independent Bangladesh on that day, following nine months of a bloody struggle, repor</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 07:27:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US becomes major source of gun violence in Caribbean: report</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/us-becomes-major-source-of-gun-violence-in-caribbean-report</link><description>The United States has become a major source of high-level firearm-related violence plaguing the Caribbean region, according to a recent report jointly released by multiple regional and international organisations.
The region's violence-related activities are on the rise, including the recruitment</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 07:42:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khaleda's condition ‘unchanged’, say doctors</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/khaledas-condition-unchanged-say-doctors</link><description>Doctors treating BNP chief Khaleda Zia say her condition remains “largely unchanged” amid plans to fly the former prime minister to London for advanced treatment.
The 79-year-old has been in Dhaka’s Evercare Hospital since November 23 and remains under close observation in the Cr</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 07:57:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>National election will be major test for law enforcers: Touhid</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/national-election-will-be-major-test-for-law-enforcers-touhid</link><description>Highlighting the role of law enforcers in holding a fair election, Foreign Affairs Adviser Md Touhid Hossain said on Saturday that the upcoming parliamentary polls will be a major test for law enforcement agencies.
"Although there were initial challenges, the police have now organised themselves e</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 08:12:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khaleda's condition remains ‘unchanged’, say doctors</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/khaledas-condition-remains-unchanged-say-doctors</link><description>Doctors treating BNP chief Khaleda Zia say her condition remains “largely unchanged” amid plans to fly the former prime minister to London for advanced treatment.
The 79-year-old has been in Dhaka’s Evercare Hospital since Nov 23 and remains under close observation in the Criti</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 08:27:54 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>