<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 07:21:37 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Turkey says 20 troops killed in Georgia plane crash</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/turkey-says-20-troops-killed-in-georgia-plane-crash</link><description>Turkey's defence ministry said on Wednesday that 20 soldiers were killed in the crash of its military aircraft in Georgia a day earlier, as inspectors continued to seek clues what caused the NATO member's cargo plane to go down.
The C-130 plane took off from Azerbaijan for Turkey and crashed in Ge</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 04:36:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>All 20 personnel on a Turkish military cargo plane that crashed in Georgia died</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/all-20-personnel-on-a-turkish-military-cargo-plane-that-crashed-in-georgia-died</link><description>All 20 personnel on board a military cargo plane that crashed in Georgia were killed, Turkey's defence minister announced on Wednesday.
The C-130 plane had taken off from Azerbaijan and was on its way back to Turkey when it crashed Tuesday in Georgia’s Sighnaghi municipality, close to the Az</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 04:51:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Throat-slit bodies of father and daughter found at home</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/throat-slit-bodies-of-father-and-daughter-found-at-home</link><description>A sleepy night in Haluaghat upazila of Mymensingh turned into a scene of horror and grief on Tuesday when miscreants killed a father and his minor daughter by slitting their throats after entering their house.
The victims-Ratan Mia, 32, and his 7-year-old daughter Nuria Akter, were found dead at t</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 05:06:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Afghanistan economic recovery buckles as nine in 10 families go hungry or into debt, UNDP says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/afghanistan-economic-recovery-buckles-as-nine-in-10-families-go-hungry-or-into-debt-undp-says</link><description>Afghanistan's economic recovery is buckling as nine in 10 households are forced to skip meals, sell belongings or take on debt to survive, the United Nations said on Wednesday, warning that mass returns are exacerbating the country's worst crisis since the Taliban returned to power.
A United Natio</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 05:21:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Temperature drops in Panchagarh as cold intensifies</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/temperature-drops-in-panchagarh-as-cold-intensifies</link><description>Panchagarh, the country’s northwestern border district, is beginning to feel the first real signs of winter, with temperatures continuing to drop over recent days.
Early mornings and late nights in the northern border district are now marked by light fog and chilly winds, signalling the seas</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 05:36:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP, Jamaat block highway over Gazipur-6 seat issue</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-jamaat-block-highway-over-gazipur-6-seat-issue</link><description>Supporters of BNP and others on Wednesday morning blocked the busy Dhaka-Mymensingh highway for around one and a half hours in the Tongi College Gate area, demanding restoration of the Gazipur-6 parliamentary seat.
Hundreds of vehicles remained stuck on both sides of the busy route, causing suffer</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 05:51:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NBR orders transfer of ex-MPs' 31 duty-free cars for govt use</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nbr-orders-transfer-of-ex-mps-31-duty-free-cars-for-govt-use</link><description>The National Board of Revenue (NBR) has issued a special order for the transfer of 31 luxury cars for official use, as those were previously imported under duty-free privileges by members of the now-dissolved 12th National Parliament.
The vehicles will be handed over to the Directorate of Governme</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 06:06:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Swedish envoy in Dhaka on four-day rights mission</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/swedish-envoy-in-dhaka-on-four-day-rights-mission</link><description>Sweden’s Ambassador for Human Rights, Democracy and Rule of Law, Irina Schoulgin-Nyoni, is now on a four-day visit to Bangladesh, focusing on key human rights.
issues, including the rights and empowerment of women and girls, freedom of expression and media freedom, and the role of civil soci</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 06:21:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Police hunt for ‘Awami League activists’ in Dhaka hotels, arrest 44</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/police-hunt-for-awami-league-activists-in-dhaka-hotels-arrest-44</link><description>Police have beefed up security in Dhaka ahead of the banned Awami League’s announced programme on November 13. Law enforcers have conducted overnight raids in different hotels and shared accommodations as Awami League leaders and activists head to the capital for the protest.
On Tuesday, the</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 06:36:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EU delegation chief Miller meets BNP’s Fakhrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/eu-delegation-chief-miller-meets-bnps-fakhrul</link><description>Michael Miller, ambassador and head of the European Union Delegation to Bangladesh, held a courtesy meeting with BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir on Wednesday.
The meeting was held at the BNP chairperson’s office in Dhaka’s Gulshan at 11:00 am today, reports bdnews24.c</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 06:51:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Grameen Bank branch set on fire in Brahmanbaria</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/grameen-bank-branch-set-on-fire-in-brahmanbaria</link><description>Unidentified miscreants set fire to a Grameen Bank branch in Vijaynagar upazila of Brahmanbaria on Wednesday.
The incident occurred around 2:00 am at the bank’s Chandura branch in the upazila.
Bank Manager Md Kalim Uddin said the attackers poured petrol inside the office before setting it o</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 07:06:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Police vehicle burns in Dhaka’s Ramna, microbus catches fire in Uttara</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/police-vehicle-burns-in-dhakas-ramna-microbus-catches-fire-in-uttara</link><description>A police pickup van has caught on fire in front of the Ramna Police Station in Dhaka’s Kakrail while a fire was sparked on a microbus in the capital’s Uttara.
Both incidents occurred due to mechanical problems, according to the police and the Fire Service. No one was hurt in either inc</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 07:21:37 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>