<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 22:16:28 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Narayanganj was a place for godfathers, says Asif Nazrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/narayanganj-was-a-place-for-godfathers-says-asif-nazrul</link><description>Narayanganj was once a place dominated by various types of godfathers, making it difficult to get justice, Law Adviser Dr. Asif Nazrul said on Wednesday.
He made the remarks while inaugurating the “e-Bail Bond: Ease of Access to Justice” programme at the Narayanganj Circuit House, aime</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 15:40:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BEPZA gets new executive chairman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bepza-gets-new-executive-chairman</link><description>Major General Mohammad Moazzem Hossain joined the Bangladesh Export Processing Zones Authority (BEPZA) as its 18th Executive Chairman.
He has joined the Chief Adviser's Office as Executive Chairman of BEPZA, according to a press release.
He succeeds Major General Abul Kalam Mohammad Ziaur Rahman.</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 15:55:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Government plans to cut ‘Savings Tools’ interest rates</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/government-plans-to-cut-savings-tools-interest-rates</link><description>The government is moving to significantly curb its reliance on borrowing through National Savings Certificates (NSCs), opting instead for the lower-cost funds available via Treasury Bills and Bonds (TBBs).
In a budget review file of the Ministry of Finance, the Ministry has recently given this ins</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 16:10:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khaleda to go to Evercare tonight</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/khaleda-to-go-to-evercare-tonight</link><description>BNP Chairperson and former Prime Minister Begum Khaleda Zia will be taken to Evercare Hospital tonight (Wednesday) for a health check-up.
“Madam (Khaleda) will be taken to Evercare Hospital in the evening for health check-ups as advised by her medical board,” said BNP Media Cell member</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 16:25:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP to sign July charter with note of dissents, says Salahuddin</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bnp-to-sign-july-charter-with-note-of-dissents-says-salahuddin</link><description>BNP Standing Committee Member Salahuddin Ahmed on Thursday said the National July Charter will be signed with a “note of dissents” clearly mentioning the issues on which there are differences of opinion.
“We have decided that the National July Charter will be signed with note of</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 16:40:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Let us be better together for building Four Betters</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/let-us-be-better-together-for-building-four-betters</link><description>This year's World Food Day marks 80 years since the founding of the Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations (FAO), whose mandate from the outset has been to ensure humanity's freedom from want.
Today, around 8.2 per cent of people face chronic undernourishment. That compares to rou</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 17:10:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>'Political will must to make South Asian cooperation a success'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/reviews/political-will-must-to-make-south-asian-cooperation-a-success</link><description>Financial Express (FE): You have been a firm believer in regional cooperation in South Asia for a long time. Despite the growing geopolitical tension and rivalry in the region, do you still think that there is a possibility of enhancing the cooperation?
Ishrat Hussain (IH): Yes, I do, and I think</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 17:25:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh economy: a case of incipient stagflation?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/bangladesh-economy-a-case-of-incipient-stagflation</link><description>To state the obvious, an economy at any point of time has three states of being in terms of its gross domestic product (GDP): moving forward, regressing backward and standing still. As is well known, the first is designated as growth, the second is marked by recession and the third defined as stagn</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 17:40:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Protesting teachers and some pertinent questions</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/protesting-teachers-and-some-pertinent-questions</link><description>At a time when students' final exams are just two months away, classes in non-government secondary educational institutions across the country are being badly hampered as thousands of MPO-listed teachers of these intuitions are protesting in Dhaka demanding a hike in their pay and perks. The poor s</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 18:35:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mirpur fire: Illegal chemical depot, yet again, responsible</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/mirpur-fire-illegal-chemical-depot-yet-again-responsible</link><description>Once again a devastating fire originating from an unauthorised chemical warehouse has claimed at least 16 lives. This time the tragedy happened not in the infamous areas of old Dhaka but in Mirpur's Shialbari area. All 16 people died in a garment factory housed in a four-storey building next to the</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 18:50:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nassa's Tk 40b loan being rescheduled</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/nassas-tk-40b-loan-being-rescheduled</link><description>On an avowed purpose of facilitating production and protecting jobs in beleaguered Nassa Group, the defaulter kingpin's loan worth nearly Tk 40 billion out of its accumulated debts is set to be rescheduled.



One of the giant apparel makers in Bangladesh, NASSA's loans have been taken from fiv</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 20:07:16 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>