<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 06:26:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Jute-made home décor offers better option</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/analysis/jute-made-home-decor-offers-better-option</link><description>Often called the "golden fibre", jute has been the most important fibre in the whole world for decades. It's natural golden shine and strength, made it worthy of its name "golden fibre".
The story starts in the rural parts of Bengal. Farmers grow jute with great care. They sell it to what we call</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 04:06:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BANGLADESH: A rising investment destination on its path from LDC to DC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/analysis/bangladesh-a-rising-investment-destination-on-its-path-from-ldc-to-dc</link><description>Bangladesh stands at the threshold of transformation, recognized globally as a story of resilience and dynamic progress. Rising from the ashes of 1971, it has developed a vibrant and diversified economy, led by the world-renowned ready-made garment sector. As Bangladesh prepares to graduate from th</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 04:21:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Man held over bus arson, shooting in Mirpur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/man-held-over-bus-arson-shooting-in-mirpur</link><description>A man has been arrested in connection with setting fire to a passenger bus and opening fire in Dhaka’s Senpara Parbata area on Friday, according to the army.
Suspect Nesar Uddin was arrested from the Rupnagar Eastern Housing area on Saturday following a complaint filed by the owners of the a</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 03:53:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Three killed in separate motorcycle accidents in Gazipur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/three-killed-in-separate-motorcycle-accidents-in-gazipur</link><description>Three people have been killed and two others injured in separate motorcycle accidents in Gazipur.
The crashes took place on the Dhaka-Mymensingh Highway at Rajendrapur and on the Shibbari-Chandna Chowrasta road near the Bangladesh Rice Research Institute on Saturday, according to Mehedi Hasan, chi</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 04:08:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NBR ramps up field-level action against tax evasion</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/nbr-ramps-up-field-level-action-against-tax-evasion</link><description>The National Board of Revenue (NBR) has directed field-level tax regions to strengthen their intelligence and investigation activities to prevent tax evasion and accelerate the recovery of unpaid taxes.
Bangladesh’s top tax collection agency issued a press release regarding the decision on S</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 04:23:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Border Patrol agents shoot armed woman in Chicago as protesters confront immigration personnel</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/border-patrol-agents-shoot-armed-woman-in-chicago-as-protesters-confront-immigration-personnel</link><description>US Border Patrol personnel shot an armed woman in Chicago on Saturday, the Department of Homeland Security said, as scores of protesters faced off against federal immigration agents on the city's southwest side.
No law enforcement officers were seriously injured in the incident in which a group th</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 04:38:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nine years on, Smart NID yet to reach all Bangladeshis</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nine-years-on-smart-nid-yet-to-reach-all-bangladeshis</link><description>Nine years after Bangladesh launched the Smart National Identity Card project, the Election Commission (EC) is still far from delivering cards to all citizens.
When the Smart NID distribution began, the target was to reach every citizen within just over a year. Nearly eight years after that deadli</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 04:53:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The first supermoon of the year is approaching. Here's what to know</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/the-first-supermoon-of-the-year-is-approaching-heres-what-to-know</link><description>The moon will appear slightly larger and brighter Monday night during what's known as a supermoon.
October's supermoon is the first of three this year. It happens when a full moon is closer to Earth in its orbit. That makes the moon look up to 14% bigger and 30% brighter than the faintest moon of</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 05:08:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka’s air continues to be ‘moderate’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dhakas-air-continues-to-be-moderate-1</link><description>Dhaka has ranked 31st on the list of cities with the worst air quality, with an AQI score of 66 at 9:30 am Sunday morning (October 5, 2025).
Dhaka's air was classified as 'moderate,' referring to a light health threat, according to the AQI index. Such air quality has continued for the past few day</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 05:38:32 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>