<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 08:30:18 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Fire breaks out at police station storeroom in Ctg</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fire-breaks-out-at-police-station-storeroom-in-ctg</link><description>A fire broke out at Panchlaish Model Police Station in Chattogram city on Tuesday.
Being informed, two firefighting units rushed to the spot and doused the fire after an hour of frantic effort.
Mohammad Solaiman, officer-in-charge (OC) of the police station, told journalists that the blaze starte</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 06:01:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Stocks up in early trading at DSE, CSE</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/stocks-up-in-early-trading-at-dse-cse</link><description>Indices on both the Dhaka and Chattogram stock exchanges witnessed an upward trend in the first hour of trading on Tuesday, with most companies seeing gains.
At the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE), the benchmark index DSEX rose by 18 points, while the Shariah-based DSES gained 3 points and the bl</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 06:31:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ansar to be deployed for nine days during national polls, says Jahangir</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ansar-to-be-deployed-for-nine-days-during-national-polls-says-jahangir</link><description>Home Adviser Lieutenant General (Retd) Md Jahangir Alam Chowdhury has said that members of the Bangladesh Ansar and Village Defence Party (VDP) will be deployed for nine days during the upcoming general election in February.
"The Ansar force will play a responsible role and help ensure that the el</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 06:46:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Paramount Skydance to cut 1,000 jobs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/paramount-skydance-to-cut-1000-jobs</link><description>Paramount Skydance will begin a major round of layoffs with about 1,000 job cuts on Wednesday, a source familiar with the matter said on Monday.
The job cuts, which follow the $8.4 billion merger between Skydance Media and Paramount Global, would impact roughly 5.0 per cent of Paramount's employee</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 07:01:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rain likely over Khulna, Barishal, Chattogram</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rain-likely-over-khulna-barishal-chattogram</link><description>The Bangladesh Meteorological Department (BMD) forecast rain or thundershowers at a few places over Khulna, Barishal and Chattogram divisions for the next 24 hours, beginning at 9:00 am today.
"Rain or thundershowers is likely to occur at a few places over Khulna, Barishal and Chattogram divisions</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 07:16:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chattogram Port disposes of long-stored hazardous goods in two-day operation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/chattogram-port-disposes-of-long-stored-hazardous-goods-in-two-day-operation</link><description>In a move to ensure port safety and environmental protection, a total of 19 containers of Dangerous Goods (DG) that had been lying unattended for years at Chattogram Port were safely destroyed over the weekend under strict supervision and environmental compliance.
The destruction process, conducte</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 07:46:41 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>