<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 04:34:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Trade should take precedence over BD-India diplomatic ties</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/trade-should-take-precedence-over-bd-india-diplomatic-ties</link><description>Trading is a powerful transactional tool among nations. There are historical evidences of countries continuing trading activities between them even when they are at war. During both the World Wars, for instance, Britain imported crucial chemical dyes from Germany. Even when they were engaged in mil</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 16:30:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Russia jails diplomat for 12 years over passing secrets to US</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/moscow-sentences-russian-diplomat-to-12-years-for-passing-secrets-to-us-intelligence</link><description>A Moscow court sentenced a former Russian diplomat to 12 years in a maximum-security penal colony for selling secrets to US intelligence while on a posting to the United States, the Federal Security Service (FSB) said on Friday.
The FSB, the main successor to the Soviet-era KGB, said that Arseniy</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 17:02:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dense fog halts Daulatdia-Paturia ferries</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dense-fog-halts-ferry-services-on-daulatdia-paturia-route</link><description>Dense fog has forced authorities to suspend ferry services on the Paturia-Daulatdia route.
Bangladesh Inland Water Transport Authority’s Daulatdia office Manager Md Salahuddin said the suspension took effect from 7pm on Friday to prevent accidents.
Dense fog blurred visibility along the riv</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 17:17:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Israel recognises Somaliland as independent state</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/israel-becomes-first-country-to-formally-recognise-somaliland-as-independent-state</link><description>Israel became the first country to formally recognise the self-declared Republic of Somaliland as an independent and sovereign state on Friday -- a decision that could reshape regional dynamics and test Somalia’s longstanding opposition to its secession.
Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu sai</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 17:32:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique pays tribute to fallen 1971 war heroes at National Memorial</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-pays-tribute-to-fallen-1971-war-heroes-at-national-memorial</link><description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman has paid tribute to the fallen heroes of the 1971 Liberation War at the National Memorial in Savar.
His travel to the National Memorial, which started after 5pm from the Zia Udyan, took about five hours to complete.
Tarique laid a wreath on the National Memorial</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 18:03:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Egypt edge S Africa after Salah penalty</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/football/salah-penalty-gives-10-man-egypt-rearguard-1-0-win-over-s-africa</link><description>Mohamed Salah scored a first half penalty as 10-man Egypt defeated South Africa 1-0 in their Africa Cup of Nations Group B clash in Agadir on Friday to become the first team into the knockout stages of the competition.
Egypt have six points from their opening two games and cannot finish outside of</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 18:18:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Banks generous in rural deposit sourcing, miserly in lending</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/banks-generous-in-rural-deposit-sourcing-miserly-in-lending</link><description>Banks are increasingly sourcing deposit from the countryside but their focus on rural Bangladesh keeps fading following tightfisted disbursement of formal credits, widening urban-rural financing gaps, sources say.
At the same time, the number of bank branches in the least-developed but promising a</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 18:33:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka sees mercury drop to 13.5°C</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dhaka-sees-mercury-drop-to-135c</link><description>The capital on Friday experienced a fall in the mercury, while a mild cold wave swept over some parts of the country, according to the Bangladesh Meteorological Department.
As temperatures fell in Dhaka, people thronged shopping malls and makeshift roadside stalls to buy warm clothes.
The elderly</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 01:49:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sub-regional connectivity subdued by highway land hassles, cost swells</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/sub-regional-connectivity-subdued-by-highway-land-hassles-cost-swells</link><description>A Dhaka-Tamabil highway project for sub-regional connectivity remains subdued as nine years got lost in land-acquisition hassles, thus raising the overall cost to Tk 284.016 billion, officials say.
Roads and Highways Department (RHD) couldn't complete acquiring land during this long time and so th</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 02:04:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Veg, onion, potato prices fall further</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/veg-onion-potato-prices-fall-further</link><description>The prices of vegetables, potatoes, and onions declined more over the past week, while those of chicken and eggs saw a small increase.
Most other commodities remained static at their previous highs, according to market sources.
Newly harvested seed onions (murikata) were sold at Tk 60-80 per kg,</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 02:19:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique Rahman's presence triggers euphoria</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-rahmans-presence-triggers-euphoria</link><description>Tarique Rahman, the acting chairman of the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP), has emerged as a galvanising figure in the political arena after his return to the country on Thursday following 17 years in exile, drawing vast jubilant crowds wherever he has made appearances.
From the moment he set f</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 02:34:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Large-scale manufacturing down 0.78pc in Oct</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/large-scale-manufacturing-down-078pc-in-oct</link><description>The large-scale manufacturing (LSM) sector contracted by 0.78 per cent in October year on year due to a sharp slowdown in the garment industry, according to the latest Bangladesh Bureau of Statistics (BBS) data. LSM, which accounts for about 11 per cent of the gross domestic product (GDP), was drag</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 02:49:19 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>