<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 18:35:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Education adviser visits family of Dipu Chandra Das</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/education-adviser-visits-family-of-dipu-chandra-das</link><description>The Office of the Chief Adviser has expressed its profound sorrow over the killing of factory worker Dipu Chandra Das in Mymensingh and extended its deepest condolences to his family.
On behalf of the government, Education Adviser Professor C R Abrar visited the bereaved family in Mymensingh on Tu</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 14:59:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Inqilab Moncho takes ‘Shaheedi oath’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/inqilab-moncho-pledges-martyrdom-demands-trial-for-osman-hadi-within-30-days</link><description>Inqilab Moncho members have taken a “Shaheedi oath”, a solemn pledge for martyrdom, vowing to complete the trial of Sharif Osman bin Hadi’s killing within 30 working days and to rebuild Bangladesh on the basis of justice.
The oath was administered at Shahbagh around 3:30pm on Tue</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 14:45:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt approves drilling of 5 gas wells in Bhola</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-approves-drilling-of-5-gas-wells-in-bhola</link><description>The government on Tuesday approved a proposal to dig five gas wells in Bhola at an estimated cost of Tk 9.07 billion to boost domestic gas production, reduce reliance on imported fuel and strengthen national energy security.
It also endorsed several large-scale power distribution projects aimed at</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 15:00:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Delhi summons Bangladesh envoy amid growing tensions</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/delhi-summons-bangladesh-envoy-amid-growing-tensions</link><description>Amid growing tensions between Dhaka and Delhi, India on Tuesday summoned Bangladesh High Commissioner Riaz Hamidullah.
This development came hours after the Bangladesh Ministry of Foreign Affairs summoned his Indian counterpart Pranay Verma to express Dhaka’s ‘grave concern’ over</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 15:15:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Death toll in South Africa’s latest pub shooting rises to 10</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/africa/death-toll-in-south-africas-latest-pub-shooting-rises-to-10</link><description>The death toll in South Africa ’s latest mass shooting at a pub rose to 10 on Tuesday, while police said they had identified two potential suspects.
Three women and seven men were killed in Sunday’s early-morning assault in the township of Bekkersdal, 46 kilometers (28 miles) west of J</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 15:30:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Vietnam-Bangladesh direct flights likely from 2026</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/vietnam-bangladesh-direct-flights-likely-from-2026</link><description>Vietnamese Ambassador to Bangladesh Nguyen Manh Cuong has said the aviation authorities in Bangladesh and Vietnam are now in the final stage of considering the new Air Services Agreement which will facilitate the establishment of official direct flight connecting Hanoi and Dhaka in 2026.
Once the</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 15:45:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fight over sandbar control claims 5 lives</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/robber-groups-clash-for-control-supremacy-over-sandbar-killing-five-members</link><description>A gunbattle between two “robber gangs” in Noakhali’s Hatia for occupying land and establishing control in a sandbar has left five dead and 10 others injured.
The shootout took place at Jaglar Char on Tuesday morning between two robber gangs, said Abu Taib Md Arif Hossain, an addi</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 16:00:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BGMEA recommends factory closures in Tongi, Gazipur on Tarique’s return day</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bgmea-recommends-factory-closures-in-tongi-gazipur-on-tariques-return-day</link><description>he Bangladesh Garment Manufacturers and Exporters Association (BGMEA), an organisation of traders in the sector, has suggested declaring a holiday for ready-made garment factories in Dhaka’s Tongi and Gazipur on Dec 25, the day BNP leader Tarique Rahman is set to return to the country.
In a</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 16:35:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific awareness still limited in Bangladesh: Dr Firdausi Qadri</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/scientific-awareness-still-limited-in-bangladesh-dr-firdausi-qadri</link><description>Eminent scientist Dr Firdausi Qadri, renowned for her contributions to vaccine innovation, testing and deployment as well as infectious disease research in Bangladesh with ICDDR, B, has said that awareness about science in the country remains limited, although gradual progress is taking place.
She</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 16:50:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cambodia backs Bangladesh's ASEAN dialogue partner bid</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cambodia-backs-bangladeshs-asean-dialogue-partner-bid</link><description>Cambodia has reaffirmed its support for Bangladesh's bid to become an ASEAN Sectoral Dialogue Partner, underlining the importance of sustained engagement with ASEAN during the first-ever Foreign Office Consultations between the two countries.
The assurance was conveyed at the inaugural Foreign Off</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 17:05:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Krishak Dal leader killed in Sylhet road crash</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/krishak-dal-leader-killed-in-sylhet-road-crash</link><description>Iron Mia, 50, convener of the Bishwanath Upazila unit of Bangladesh Jatiotabadi Krishak Dal, was killed in a road accident at Nazirbazar in Dakshin Surma, Sylhet.
The accident occurred at around 6:30 pm on Tuesday.
Irun Mia was a resident of Naogaon village in Bishwanath upazila, reports UNB.
Ac</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 17:52:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt releases electoral song produced for Dhaka division</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-releases-electoral-song-produced-for-dhaka-division</link><description>Ahead of the upcoming parliamentary election and referendum, the Ministry of Cultural Affairs has produced eight songs for the country's eight divisions.
The song produced for the Dhaka division was released today, said the Chief Adviser's Press Wing on Tuesday night, reports BSS.
The song has be</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 18:07:23 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>