<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 02:02:51 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Bombs made overnight at madrasa before blast: police</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/police-say-keraniganj-madrasa-head-prepared-explosives-overnight-before-deadly-blast</link><description>Police have recovered two improvised explosive devices (IEDs), five electric bomb-like devices, and a large quantity of bomb-making materials from the madrasa that was levelled in an explosion in Hasnabad, Keraniganj.
In court, police said the madrasa’s head Sheikh Al Amin had stayed up all</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 15:58:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chill continues under fog as midweek cold snap looms over Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/chill-continues-under-fog-as-midweek-cold-snap-looms-over-bangladesh</link><description>A cold wave is intensifying across Bangladesh as the month of Poush reaches its midpoint.
The sun hides behind a fog-laden sky, and despite a slight temperature rise, the chill remains unrelenting.
The Bangladesh Meteorological Department (BMD) has predicted that this weather pattern will continu</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 16:13:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No approval needed for repair, renovation of polling stations: EC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/no-approval-needed-for-repair-renovation-of-polling-stations-ec</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) on Sunday said its prior approval will not be required for renovation or repair of institutions and establishments to be used as polling stations in the upcoming 13th parliamentary election.
The announcement was made in a statement signed by M Mamun Aur Rashid, Deputy</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 16:28:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Holidays reduced to 64 days in educational institutions in 2026</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/holidays-reduced-to-64-days-in-educational-institutions-in-2026</link><description>The Ministry of Education on Sunday published the holiday list and academic calendar for government and non-government secondary and junior secondary schools for the 2026 academic year, showing a reduction in the number of holidays.
According to the calendar, educational institutions will remain c</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 16:43:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hero Alam joins Aam Janatar Dal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hero-alam-joins-aam-janatar-dal</link><description>Content creator Ashraful Alam, popularly known as Hero Alam, formally joined Aam Janatar Dal on Sunday.
Aam Janatar Dal Member Secretary Tarek Rahman handed over the party membership form to Hero Alam at a programme held in the evening, welcoming him to the party.
Speaking on the occasion, Hero A</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 16:58:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Election: 3,144 nomination papers collected, 166 filed</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/national-election-3144-nomination-papers-collected-166-submitted</link><description>A total of 3144 nomination papers were collected, but only 166 nomination papers were submitted till Sunday, according to the Election Commission’s (EC) Central Coordination Committee, formed ahead of the upcoming national election.
The EC has set the deadline for submission of nomination pa</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 17:13:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sustainable finance for overcoming climate impacts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/sustainable-finance-for-overcoming-climate-impacts</link><description>The International Court of Justice (ICJ) has recently pointed out that climate change is beginning to become an existential threat for humanity.  In this context environmentalist Cecilia Russel has drawn the attention of the world to some observations made recently by the ICJ Judge Yuji Iwasaw</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 17:28:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Saying no to suicide</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/saying-no-to-suicide</link><description>That 40-41people terminate their lives every day, according to recent police data, in this country should send a chill down the spine. The very word 'suicide' has a story behind and that certainly is not very positive. People by nature are more epicurean than ascetic. But then what pushes one to ta</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 17:43:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Has interim govt been up to public's expectation?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/has-interim-govt-been-up-to-publics-expectation</link><description>Syed Fattahul Alim
 
The interim government inherited the virtual wreckage of a state left by the autocracy toppled in the popular upsurge. The financial sector, especially the banks were in a shambles. The ousted autocracy would like to portray a rosy picture of the economy with the help of</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 17:58:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The urban-rural lending divide</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/the-urban-rural-lending-divide</link><description>Bangladesh is predominantly a rural country, with around 68 per cent of its population living in rural areas. A large segment of this population is deprived of formal banking services due to a lack of bank branches in remote areas. Although agent banking has helped improve financial inclusion over</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 18:13:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Manufacturers fret over Tk120b unsold apparel raw material</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/manufacturers-fret-over-tk120b-unsold-apparel-raw-material</link><description>Millers fret over a stockpile of unsold local yarn worth Tk 120 billion amid massive influx of the cheap-rated clothing raw material, allegedly meant to undercut domestic industry, manufacturers say.



The country's primary textile millers, especially spinners, say yarn imports from India in</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 18:28:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gold hits new record in Bangladesh as price rises for 8th straight time</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/gold-hits-new-record-in-bangladesh-as-price-rises-for-8th-straight-time</link><description>Gold prices in Bangladesh have climbed for the eighth consecutive time, with the price of 22-carat gold reaching a new all-time high of Tk 229,431 per bhori (11.664 grams) on Sunday.
Bangladesh Jewellers Association (BAJUS) announced at night that it has increased the price of gold by Tk 1,575 per</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 18:43:21 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>