<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 12:51:29 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Tarique at BNP headquarters after 17 years</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-visits-bnp-headquarters-in-naya-paltan-after-more-than-17-years</link><description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman has visited the party’s central office in Dhaka’s Naya Paltan for the first time in more than a decade and a half, drawing large crowds of party supporters.
Tarique’s motorcade reached the area around 4:05pm on Monday, though it took longer to r</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 10:28:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US Chargé d’Affaires praises CA, reiterates support for Feb polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/us-charge-daffaires-praises-ca-reiterates-support-for-feb-polls</link><description>Ambassador Tracey Ann Jacobson, the Chargé d’Affaires of the United States to Bangladesh, on Monday appreciated the leadership of Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus over the past 17 months and reiterated the support of his country for the February elections in Bangladesh.
Jacobson</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 10:43:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump and Netanyahu are to meet in Florida at a crucial moment for the US-backed Gaza ceasefire</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/trump-and-netanyahu-are-to-meet-in-florida-at-a-crucial-moment-for-the-us-backed-gaza-ceasefire</link><description>President Donald Trump is scheduled to meet with Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu on Monday, as Washington looks to create fresh momentum for a US-brokered ceasefire in Gaza that could be in danger of stalling out before a complicated second phase.
Trump could use the face-to-face at his</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 10:58:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khaleda’s nomination papers for Bogura seat, backup candidate ready</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/khaledas-nomination-papers-for-bogura-seat-backup-candidate-ready</link><description>Nomination papers have been submitted on behalf of former prime minister and BNP chief Khaleda Zia for the Bogura-7 constituency in the upcoming general election.
The BNP also submitted nomination papers for Morshed Milton, the chief of the party's Gabtali Upazila unit, as an alternative candidate</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 11:13:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>COP leadership crucial to elevate Bangladesh’s global standing: Adviser Farida</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cop-leadership-crucial-to-elevate-bangladeshs-global-standing-adviser-farida</link><description>Bangladesh must ensure the participation of the future Prime Minister or the highest number of ministers or advisers at the UN climate summit (COP) to gain due global attention, Fisheries and Livestock Adviser Farida Akhter said on Monday.
“The presence of the Prime Minister (future) or memb</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 11:28:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh sees 26pc rise in foreign loan disbursements in first 5 months of FY26</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/bangladesh-sees-26pc-rise-in-foreign-loan-disbursements-in-first-5-months-of-fy26</link><description>Bangladesh’s foreign loan and grant disbursements have risen by 26 per cent year-on-year in the first five months of the fiscal year 2025-26.
Data released on Monday by the Economic Relations Division (ERD) show that development partners and international lenders disbursed $1.95 billion betw</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 10:58:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique calls for rebuilding country during BNP office visit</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-calls-for-rebuilding-country-during-bnp-office-visit</link><description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman visited the party’s central office on Monday for the first time in 19 years, drawing an enthusiastic response from party leaders and activists, whom he urged to work together to rebuild the country.
Tarique Rahman arrived at the BNP central office at 4:06 p</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 11:13:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mahfuz Alam will not contest in polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/mahfuz-alam-will-not-contest-in-polls</link><description>Former Information Adviser Mahfuz Alam has said he will not contest the upcoming national parliamentary election. He confirmed the decision in an interview with BBC Bangla on Monday (December 29).
Mahfuz Alam said he had made up his mind not to run for office from the outset and that this was the</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 11:28:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nomination submission deadline closes for Bangladesh elections</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nomination-submission-deadline-closes-for-bangladesh-elections</link><description>The submission deadline for nomination papers for Bangladesh’s upcoming national election closed at 5:00 pm on Monday, with most candidates filing their papers on time.
Most of the aspirants submitted their nomination papers today as only 166 nomination papers were filed till Sunday to conte</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 11:43:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Kolkata's iconic trams face final stop as modernization rolls in</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/kolkatas-iconic-trams-face-final-stop-as-modernization-rolls-in</link><description>For more than a century, trams have rumbled past Kolkata's crumbling colonial facades, with their chiming bells contributing to the city's soundtrack as they ferried generations of commuters.
Now, Asia's oldest tram network is on the brink of disappearing as authorities consider pulling the plug o</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 11:58:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Winter bites without cold wave</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/winter-bites-without-cold-wave</link><description>Morning fog has erased the sun from much of Bangladesh, leaving winter to bite deeper than expected. With the gap between day and night temperatures shrinking to near record lows, the cold is being felt more sharply -- even without a cold wave.
The Bangladesh Meteorological Department (BMD) has fo</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 12:13:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bank Asia celebrates 17th anniversary of its Islamic Banking Services</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bank-asia-celebrates-17th-anniversary-of-its-islamic-banking-services</link><description>Bank Asia PLC organised a discussion meeting and Dua Mahfil on the occasion of the 17th anniversary of its Islamic Banking Services on Wednesday (24 December 2025) at Bank Asia Tower, Karwan Bazar, Dhaka.
Former Chairman of the Shariah Supervisory Committee Mufti Shahed Rahmani, former Member Secr</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 12:28:50 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>