<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 12:47:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Ten killed and 40 wounded in heavy Russian attack on Ukraine, officials say</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/ten-killed-and-40-wounded-in-heavy-russian-attack-on-ukraine-officials-say</link><description>Ten people were killed in a heavy overnight Russian missile and drone attack that struck a residential tower block in the western Ukrainian city of Ternopil, Ukrainian officials said on Wednesday.
Another 40 people were wounded in the overnight strikes on Ukraine that targeted energy and transport</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 09:15:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chinese premier makes landmark Zambia trip as West vies for investment foothold</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/africa/chinese-premier-makes-landmark-zambia-trip-as-west-vies-for-investment-foothold</link><description>Zambia will host a Chinese premier on Wednesday for the first time in 28 years as the sub-Saharan state emerges from a financial crisis, with Beijing eager to access commodities and develop a bigger market for its exporters.
China is Zambia's largest official creditor, owed $5.7 billion and keen t</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 09:30:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>30.7pc growth of remittance inflow till Nov 18</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/307pc-growth-of-remittance-inflow-till-nov-18</link><description>Inflow of remittances witnessed a year-on-year growth of 30.7 percent reaching US$1,904 million in the 18 days of November, according to the latest data of Bangladesh Bank (BB) issued today.
Last year, during the same period, the country's remittance inflow was $1,457 million.
 During the Ju</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 09:45:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bengal Islami Life Insurance, BRAC Healthcare sign corporate agreement on health services</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bengal-islami-life-insurance-brac-healthcare-sign-corporate-agreement-on-health-services</link><description>Bengal Islami Life Insurance Limited and BRAC Healthcare Limited have entered into a corporate agreement to enhance health service facilities for the company’s Health Takaful customers.
The signing took place today (Wednesday) at the Bengal Islami Life Insurance Head Office in Motijheel, acc</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 10:00:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BSTI launches unified e-service platform</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bsti-launches-unified-e-service-platform</link><description>The Bangladesh Standards and Testing Institution (BSTI) on Wednesday formally launched its new e-Services Management System aimed at bringing all customer services under a single digital platform.
The system was inaugurated at the BSTI headquarters in Tejgaon.
Secretary (Additional Charge) of the</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 10:15:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US judge to weigh Trump's influence over case against ex-FBI chief Comey</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-judge-to-weigh-trumps-influence-over-case-against-ex-fbi-chief-comey</link><description>Lawyers for former FBI Director James Comey will renew their attempts to get a criminal case against him tossed out on Wednesday, arguing that President Donald Trump's personal animosity improperly motivated the prosecution.
The hearing before U.S. District Judge Michael Nachmanoff in Alexandria,</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 10:30:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UK pay settlements rise to highest in 2025, Brightmine says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/uk-pay-settlements-rise-to-highest-in-2025-brightmine-says</link><description>Median pay settlements granted by British employers in the three months to the end of October rose to their highest so far this year at 3.3%, up from 3.1% in the three months to September.
Brightmine said the move reflected higher public sector pay deals which took effect in August and September.</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 10:45:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Spanish court conditionally releases PM's former ally from jail</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/spanish-court-conditionally-releases-pms-former-ally-from-jail</link><description>Spain's Supreme Court ordered on Wednesday the provisional release from jail of a former senior official within the ruling Socialist Party, citing reduced risk of evidence tampering amid an ongoing corruption investigation.
Santos Cerdan, who had been remanded in custody since June, faces potentia</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 11:00:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UCB to provide small loans at a low interest rate</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ucb-to-provide-small-loans-at-a-low-interest-rate</link><description>United Commercial Bank PLC (UCB) has recently signed an agreement with Bangladesh Bank under the ‘Digital Nano Loan’ refinance scheme.
Under the agreement, UCB will utilize Bangladesh Bank’s refinance facility to disburse Digital Nano Loan at a lower interest rate through a techn</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 11:15:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Air India lobbies to use airspace over China's Xinjiang as financial woes mount</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/air-india-lobbies-to-use-airspace-over-chinas-xinjiang-as-financial-woes-mount</link><description>Air India is lobbying the Indian government to convince China to let it use a sensitive military airspace zone in Xinjiang to shorten routes as the financial toll from a ban on Indian carriers flying over Pakistan mounts, a company document shows.
The unusual request comes just weeks after direct</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 11:30:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BB allows international cards for air ticket purchases</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bb-allows-international-cards-for-air-ticket-purchases</link><description>Bangladesh Bank (BB) has allowed the use of international cards for purchase of air tickets from airlines operating in Bangladesh for travelling abroad.
“To facilitate fair pricing, convenience and market competitiveness, it has been decided that resident Bangladeshi nationals, having visas</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 11:45:42 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>