<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 03:44:39 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Russia destroys large energy facility in Kharkiv, mayor says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/russia-destroys-large-energy-facility-in-kharkiv-mayor-says</link><description>Russian forces have destroyed a large energy facility in Ukraine's second-biggest city Kharkiv, the mayor said on Thursday, the latest target of a winter air campaign by Moscow that has plunged millions of Ukrainians into darkness and cold.
Russia has attacked the power grid and other energy facil</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 17:19:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BPL strike: Cricketers soften stance with new demands</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/bpl-strike-cricketers-soften-stance-with-new-demands</link><description>Players have partially stepped back from their previous hardline demand for the immediate resignation of Bangladesh Cricket Board (BCB) Director M Najmul Islam.
Welcoming the board's decision to remove him as head of the Finance Committee, the cricketers say they will resume playing on Friday if t</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 17:34:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bongo Studios named YouTube’s official MCN in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bongo-studios-named-youtubes-official-mcn-in-bangladesh</link><description>Bongo Studios, a branch of the digital entertainment platform Bongo, has been designated by YouTube as its official Multi-Channel Network (MCN) in Bangladesh.
Bongo announced this in a press release on Thursday, saying the status reflects Bongo Studios’ proven track record in supporting crea</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 18:10:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Much-hyped 'social business' gets institutionalised thru new bank</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/much-hyped-social-business-gets-institutionalised-thru-new-bank</link><description>A much-hyped 'social business' is getting institutionalized through newly introduced microcredit banks meant for empowering grassroots down-and-outs and firing up rural economy across Bangladesh. 

In what officials tout as a landmark move for the country's financial landscape, the Advisory</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 18:25:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>TRANSFORM marks 10 years of collaboration, supports 13 enterprises in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/transform-marks-10-years-of-collaboration-supports-13-enterprises-in-bangladesh</link><description>TRANSFORM, an impact accelerator that supports visionary enterprises across Asia and Africa, marked more than a decade of collaboration on Thursday, according to a press release.
Since its launch in 2015, the initiative has supported 13 enterprises in Bangladesh, reaching 247,313 people, including</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 18:40:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>D.Net appoints co-founder Shah Md Ahsan Habib as governing body chairperson</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/dnet-appoints-co-founder-shah-md-ahsan-habib-as-governing-body-chairperson</link><description>D.Net has appointed Professor Dr Shah Md Ahsan Habib as chairperson of its governing body, effective January 1, 2026, according to a press release.
A co-founder of D.Net, Habib brings experience in academia, policy research, governance and development finance. He is currently a professor (selectio</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 19:45:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP asks EC to form 'fact-checking cell' to curb poll disinformation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bnp-asks-ec-to-form-fact-checking-cell-to-curb-poll-disinformation</link><description>The BNP has urged the Election Commission (EC) to urgently form a “fact-checking cell” to counter what it describes as rampant disinformation on social media during the election season.
At a briefing at the party’s Gulshan office on Thursday evening, Mahdi Amin, spokesperson of t</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 20:00:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Beyond credit: transforming livelihoods</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/beyond-credit-transforming-livelihoods</link><description>Bangladesh's development narrative is often celebrated in macroeconomic statistics. Decades of robust GDP growth, surging exports, and poverty reduction have positioned the country as a global development exemplar. Yet, these numbers conceal the lived reality of millions of Bangladeshis who struggl</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 20:15:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nation bleeding its forests dry</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/nation-bleeding-its-forests-dry</link><description>Bangladesh has earned notoriety in the last decades for the systematic and often irreversible decimation of its wildlife. As a result of mindless killing, habitat loss, and slack enforcement of laws relating to wildlife conservation, dozens of animal species have already been lost and many more hav</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 20:30:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Why children fall victim to road accidents</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/why-children-fall-victim-to-road-accidents</link><description>The Road Safety Foundation (RSF), a private organisation involved with the study of road accidents in the country, reveals that in the just departed year 7,359 people were killed in 7,584 road accidents. More than 20 people met with the unnatural death on an average day in 2025. The RSF puts the nu</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 20:45:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Building a bridge to global e-commerce</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/building-a-bridge-to-global-e-commerce</link><description>There is little room for complacency when assessing Bangladesh's position in the evolving landscape of global digital trade. While some progress has been made in digitising domestic trading processes, the broader adoption of e-commerce across the full spectrum of trade-related activities remains la</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 21:00:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Increased LPG imports to avert supply crunch in Ramadan: BERC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/increased-lpg-imports-to-avert-supply-crunch-in-ramadan-berc</link><description>Bangladesh Energy Regulatory Commission (BERC) Chairman Jalal Ahmed has expressed optimism that increased imports of liquefied petroleum gas (LPG) would help avert any supply crisis of the fuel during the upcoming month of Ramadan.
He has called for urgent cooperation among all stakeholders, inclu</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 02:45:16 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>