<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 06:32:39 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>India's Tata Tech to hire more locals in US</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/indias-tata-tech-to-hire-more-locals-in-us</link><description>Tata Technologies will recruit more local nationals in the United States, its top boss said, as the Indian engineering services provider reacts to US President Donald Trump's wide-ranging immigration crackdown.
The United States plans to charge businesses a steep fee for H1-B visas, used by tech m</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 03:22:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two youths killed in Naogaon road accident</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/two-youths-killed-in-naogaon-road-accident</link><description>Two youths were killed and four others injured in a head-on collision between motorcycles and a truck in Manda upazila of Naogaon district last night.
The deceased were identified as Yamin Ali, 20, son of Emdadul Haque and Tuhin, 20, son of Jahangir Alam, both residents of Ganeshpur village of the</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 03:37:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>WHO leads medical evacuation of 41 critical patients out of Gaza</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/who-leads-medical-evacuation-of-41-critical-patients-out-of-gaza</link><description>The World Health Organization led the medical evacuation of 41 critical patients and 145 companions out of Gaza, Director-General Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus said on Wednesday.
Around 15,000 Gaza patients are awaiting evacuation, Tedros said in an X post.
"We continue to call on countries to show</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 03:52:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump says he canceled meeting with Putin</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-says-he-canceled-meeting-with-putin</link><description>US President Donald Trump said Wednesday that he has canceled his planned meeting with Russian President Vladimir Putin.
"We cancelled the meeting with President Putin," Trump told reporters at the White House. "It just didn't feel right to me."
"It didn't feel like we were going to get to the pl</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 04:07:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Online tax return filing made easier for expatriates</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/online-tax-return-filing-made-easier-for-expatriates</link><description>The National Board of Revenue (NBR) has introduced an option for Bangladeshi taxpayers living abroad to receive One-Time Passwords (OTPs) via email, making online income tax return submission easier and more accessible for expatriates.
In a press release issued today, NBR said that although expatr</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 04:22:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>College student hacked to death in Habiganj</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/college-student-hacked-to-death-in-habiganj</link><description>A college student was hacked to death in broad daylight on Wednesday in Balakipur village of Baniachong upazila of Habiganj district over a family dispute.
The deceased was identified as Sadeq Chowdhury, 18, a first-year commerce student at Sachindra College in Baniachang, reports UNB.
The victim</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 04:52:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Student commits suicide in Dhaka’s Moghbazar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/student-commits-suicide-in-dhakas-moghbazar</link><description>An 18-year-old student committed suicide at his home in Dhaka’s Moghbazar area on Wednesday night.
The deceased was identified as Shahnewaz Jamal (18), a first-year student at Willes Little Flower School and College.
Police said that Shahnewaz was found hanging in his room at their house in</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 05:22:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ex-MP Tahura Ali, mother of actress Shaon, passes away</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ex-mp-tahura-ali-mother-of-actress-shaon-passes-away</link><description>Begum Tahura Ali, a former member of parliament (MP) from a reserved seat for women and director of the Citizen Group, passed away at a hospital in Dhaka early Thursday.
She died at 6:11 am while undergoing treatment at United Hospital in Dhaka, according to a post on Citizen Cables’ Faceboo</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 05:37:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rain, thundershowers likely in Ctg</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rain-thundershowers-likely-in-ctg</link><description>The Bangladesh Meteorological Department (BMD) forecast rain or thundershowers is likely to occur at one or two places over Chattogram division in the next 24 hours, beginning at 9:00 am today (Thursday).
"Rain or thundershowers is likely to occur at one or two places over Chattogram division," ac</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 05:52:28 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>