<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 14:30:20 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>JT International Bangladesh appoints new Managing Director</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/jt-international-bangladesh-appoints-new-managing-director</link><description>JT International Bangladesh Limited has appointed Dr. Oliver Kutz as its new Managing Director, effective February 2026. He will be based in Dhaka.
Oliver brings more than two decades of international experience in the tobacco industry, according to a media release. 
He began his career in 2</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 12:26:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prime Bank CEO Hassan O. Rashid resigns</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/prime-bank-ceo-hassan-o-rashid-resigns</link><description>Hassan O. Rashid, managing director and chief executive officer of Prime Bank, has resigned from his position.
Prime Bank’s board of directors accepted Rashid’s resignation at a meeting on February 10.
The decision was disclosed on Sunday through the website of Dhaka Stock Exchange.</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 12:41:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Azizur Rahman Ripon elected chairman, Sirajul Islam executive director of FERB</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/azizur-rahman-ripon-elected-chairman-sirajul-islam-executive-director-of-ferb</link><description>M. Azizur Rahman Ripon has been elected as Chairman and Serajul Islam Siraj as executive director of the Forum for Energy Reporters Bangladesh (FERB) on Sunday.
The election was held following the biennial general meeting of the FERB at Bijoy Hall of Bidyut Bhaban in the city.
M Azizur Rahman has</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 12:56:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CA greets Muslims marking holy month of Ramadan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ca-greets-muslims-marking-holy-month-of-ramadan</link><description>Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus has extended his heartfelt greetings to the people of the country and to Muslims around the world on the occasion of the holy month of Ramadan.
In a message today, he said the month of Ramadan is a month of self-restraint, sacrifice, compassion, and self-puri</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 12:00:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rupali Insurance Annual Conference 2026 held</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/rupali-insurance-annual-conference-2026-held</link><description>The Annual Conference–2026 of Rupali Insurance Company Limited was held recently at a city convention centre.
The Chairman of Rupali Insurance Company Limited, Mostafa Quamrus Sobhan, Director MQuazi Moniruzzaman, Director, M.  Jinnat Ali Mian, Director Mst. Shafia Sobhan Chowdhury, P.</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 12:15:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>We are lucky people who got the opportunity to serve the nation: CA</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/we-are-lucky-people-who-got-the-opportunity-to-serve-the-nation-ca</link><description>The advisers’ council on Sunday described the recent national poll as a “great success” at its final meeting before stepping down, formally adopting a vote of thanks for what members called a historic and festive election.
The resolution was passed at a meeting chaired by Chief A</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 12:30:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique Rahman at Jamaat Ameer‘s residence</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-rahman-at-jamaat-ameers-residence</link><description>BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman arrived at Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami Ameer Shafiqur Rahman on Sunday evening, just two days before forming the next government following his party’s massive victory in Thursday’s national election.
Tarique reached the Jamaat chief’s residence in Bashu</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 12:45:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Uttara Bank inaugurates new premises of Kalabagan Branch</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/uttara-bank-inaugurates-new-premises-of-kalabagan-branch</link><description>Uttara Bank PLC inaugurated the new premises of Kalabagan Branch in Dhaka through a function on Sunday, according to a press release.
Mr. Md. Abul Hashem, Managing Director &amp; CEO of Uttara Bank PLC, inaugurated the new premises of the branch at Green Landmark Tower, Holding No-129, Mirpur Road, wa</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 13:00:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sudden spike in price of lemons</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/sudden-spike-in-price-of-lemons</link><description>The price of lemons has suddenly skyrocketed at Dhaka’s wet markets, reaching Tk 100-Tk 120 per four pieces in some places.
Traders say poor harvest and limited supplies have driven up prices. But buyers are reluctant to buy such reasoning for a Tk 80-100 jump in price.
Small lemons were se</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 13:15:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two killed, seven injured in Cumilla road crash</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/two-killed-seven-injured-in-cumilla-road-crash</link><description>Two people were killed and seven others were injured when a bus hit an auto-rickshaw and plunged into a roadside ditch on Dhaka-Chattogram highway in Daudkandi upazila of Cumilla district on Sunday.
The deceased were identified as Faruk Hossain, 38, an auto-rickshaw driver of Daudkandi upazila and</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 13:30:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gaza’s Nasser Hospital condemns move by MSF to suspend most services</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/gazas-nasser-hospital-condemns-move-by-msf-to-suspend-most-services</link><description>One of Gaza’s last functioning large hospitals condemned the move by an international organization to pull out of operations over concerns about armed men, claiming on Sunday that the hospital had installed civil police for security. The move comes as at least 10 Palestinians were killed in c</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 13:45:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BCIA expects capital market turnaround under new govt</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bcia-expects-capital-market-turnaround-under-new-govt</link><description>Bangladesh Capital Market Investor Association (BCIA) on Sunday expressed optimism that Bangladesh’s capital market will rebound within the next six months if the newly elected BNP government takes prudent and timely measures.
In a statement congratulating the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (B</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 14:00:55 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>