<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 13:29:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Governor calls for joint efforts to cut high remittance costs from KSA</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/governor-calls-for-joint-efforts-to-cut-high-remittance-costs-from-ksa</link><description>Bangladesh Bank Governor Dr. Ahsan H. Mansur on Tuesday called for coordinated action between the financial sectors of Bangladesh and Saudi Arabia to reduce the high cost of remittances from  KSA.
“The cost of sending remittances from Saudi Arabia is disproportionately high as the expat</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 10:59:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fakhrul issues fresh warning of election conspiracy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/fakhrul-issues-fresh-warning-of-election-conspiracy</link><description>BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir on Tuesday warned afresh that a ‘deep conspiracy’ is underway to divert the upcoming national election from its proper course, urging the country’s teachers to remain alert and cautious.
“I would like to tell you that teache</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 11:14:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trust Bank celebrates achievement of Tk 500.00 billion deposit milestone</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/trust-bank-celebrates-achievement-of-tk-50000-billion-deposit-milestone</link><description>Trust Bank PLC has recently celebrated a significant milestone of reaching Tk 50,000 crore (Tk 500.00 billion) in deposits at a ceremony held at its head office.
The event was graced by the Bank’s Managing Director &amp; CEO, Mr. Ahsan Zaman Chowdhury, along with Deputy Managing Directors, Senio</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 11:44:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Meghna Bank partners with Saudi Arabia–Bangladesh Business Summit 2025</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/meghna-bank-partners-with-saudi-arabia-bangladesh-business-summit-2025</link><description>Meghna Bank has partnered with the Saudi Arabia–Bangladesh Business Summit 2025, organized by the Saudi Arabia–Bangladesh Chamber of Commerce and Industry (SABCCI), as the Silver Sponsor.
The three-day summit is currently being held at Hotel Sheraton, Dhaka, with the aim of strengtheni</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 11:59:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shahjalal Islami Bank unveils Sustainability Report-2024</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/shahjalal-islami-bank-unveils-sustainability-report-2024</link><description>Shahjalal Islami Bank PLC (SJIBPLC) published its “Sustainability Report-2024” and it was formally inaugurated on the 27th September 2025 during the Risk Management Conference in Corporate Head Office of the bank, according to a press release.
With the slogan, ‘Moving Towards Sus</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 12:14:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCC Bank, SICIP arrange Entrepreneurship Training and Loan Disbursement Program in Mymensingh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ncc-bank-sicip-arrange-entrepreneurship-training-and-loan-disbursement-program-in-mymensingh</link><description>A month-long entrepreneurship development training programme in Mymensingh was organised by Bangladesh Bank, in collaboration with NCC Bank PLC, under the Skills for Industry Competitiveness and Innovation Programme (SICIP) implemented by the Finance Division of the Ministry of Finance with funding</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 12:29:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Israel deports 131 Gaza flotilla activists to Jordan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/israel-deports-131-gaza-flotilla-activists-to-jordan</link><description>Jordan's state news agency has said 131 Gaza flotilla activists were deported from Israel to Jordan via the Allenby Bridge crossing, reports bdnews24.com citing Reuters.
On Tuesday, Jordan’s Ministry of Foreign and Expatriates Affairs announced the arrival of a Jordanian citizen and 130 evac</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 12:44:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prime Bank launches SME Debit Card with international remittance facility</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/prime-bank-launches-sme-debit-card-with-international-remittance-facility</link><description>Prime Bank PLC has launched Bangladesh’s first-ever SME Debit Card with International Remittance Facility, enabling small and medium enterprises to make seamless international online payments for business purposes.
According to a press release, the Prime Bank SME Debit Card can also be used</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 13:14:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Modhumoti Bank donates Tk 2 million to 'Inspiration Welfare Society'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/modhumoti-bank-donates-tk-2-million-to-inspiration-welfare-society</link><description>Modhumoti Bank PLC donated Tk 2 million (20 Lac) to “Inspiration Welfare Society” recently under the bank’s CSR program for conducting social welfare programs and educational programs for Special Children across the country.
Mr. Shahnawaj Chowdhury, Managing Director (Current Cha</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 13:29:20 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>