<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 10:39:14 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Man ‘commits suicide’ at Mohammadpur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/man-commits-suicide-at-mohammadpur</link><description>A man allegedly took his own life at his residence in Mohammadpur area of Dhaka on Sunday.
The deceased was identified as Swapan Mia, 25, son of Bazlu Mia of Lalmohon upazila of Bhola district and he used to live with his wife in a rented house at Chandrima Model Town Road of Mohammadpur.
His wif</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 07:13:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chinese 'K Visa' can be a milestone for Bangladeshi students</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/chinese-k-visa-can-be-a-milestone-for-bangladeshi-students</link><description>China has launched a new visa policy named 'K Visa', which is exclusively designed for graduates in specific fields. The fields prioritise the talent souls to contribute to their country, especially in the arenas of technology and innovation.
Initially K visa inspires the students who have graduat</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 07:58:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCP accuses EC of arbitrary decision over denial of ‘Water Lily’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ncp-accuses-ec-of-arbitrary-decision-over-denial-of-water-lily</link><description>National Citizen Party-NCP on Sunday alleged that the Election Commission (EC) is making an 'arbitrary decision' by denying the party its desired electoral symbol 'Water Lily'.
 
"We've seen that the Election Commission is taking an arbitrary decision," said NCP chief organiser for the south</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 08:13:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh announces 3-day waiver of fees for non-scheduled flights after Dhaka airport fire</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-announces-3-day-waiver-of-fees-for-non-scheduled-flights-after-dhaka-airport-fire</link><description>All fees for non-scheduled flights at Dhaka’s Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport have been waived for the next three days following a major fire at the airport’s cargo complex.
Sheikh Bashir Uddin, advisor to the Ministry of Civil Aviation and Tourism, announced on Sunday while spe</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 08:43:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Morocco: The tales of deserts, mountains and the sea</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/others/morocco-the-tales-of-deserts-mountains-and-the-sea</link><description>I fell in love with you watching Casablanca
Back row of the drive-in show in the flickering light
Popcorn and cokes beneath the stars
Became champagne and caviar
Making love on a long hot summer's night
 
I am from the generation who grew up listening to the song Casablanca by Bertie Hig</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 08:58:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gano Forum signs July Charter</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/gano-forum-signs-july-charter</link><description>Gano Forum has signed the July Charter, joining the list of political parties endorsing the political accord initiated by the National Consensus Commission.
Gano Forum’s acting president and valiant freedom fighter Subrata Chowdhury and general secretary Dr Md Mizanur Rahman signed the chart</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 09:28:26 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>