<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 21:17:36 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Mahfuj hopes Notun Kuri winners will bring glory to Bangladesh’s cultural arena</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/entertainment/mahfuj-hopes-notun-kuri-winners-will-bring-glory-to-bangladeshs-cultural-arena</link><description>Information and Broadcasting Adviser Md. Mahfuj Alam on Saturday expressed his hope that the child performers who won the Notun Kuri competition will earn fame in the cultural arena of Bangladesh through hard work.
He said this while addressing the award-giving ceremony for winners of the Notun Ku</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 15:00:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DU students demand ‘exemplary trial’ for teacher accused of sexual assault</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/du-students-demand-exemplary-trial-for-teacher-accused-of-sexual-assault</link><description>Dhaka University students have demanded exemplary punishment for a teacher recently accused of sexually harassing a student.
Students formed a human chain at the Raju Memorial Sculpture at Dhaka University on Saturday, demanding the investigation into chemistry teacher Ershad Halim be completed as</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 15:45:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jahangirnagar University bans all events after 10pm</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/jahangirnagar-university-bans-all-events-after-10pm</link><description>The Jahangirnagar University (JU) has imposed a ban on all events taking place on its campus after 10pm to maintain peace, order, and security.
The directive was announced in an urgent press release signed by the university’s acting registrar Dr. ABM Azizur Rahman on Saturday evening.
The n</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 16:00:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Women’s participation in various sectors increases significantly: Mahfuj</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/womens-participation-in-various-sectors-increases-significantly-mahfuj</link><description>Information and Broadcasting Adviser Md. Mahfuj Alam today (Saturday) said women’s participation in various sectors has increased significantly after the July mass uprising. 
He made these remarks at an event titled “Women in establishing democracy: What we have gained” orga</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 15:46:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Crude bomb explodes near Asian Development Bank in Agargaon</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crude-bomb-explodes-near-asian-development-bank-in-agargaon</link><description>A crude bomb has exploded on the road outside the Asian Development Bank (ADB) building in Agargaon, Dhaka. 
The incident occurred around 8:20pm on Saturday, police said, bdnews24.com reports. 
Sher-e-Bangla Police chief Imaul Haque said no casualties were reported. “We have begun</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 16:01:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Income tax on waived interest raises questions among corporate</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/income-tax-on-waived-interest-raises-questions-among-corporate</link><description>"Where any interest or part thereof is waived by a scheduled bank or a financial institution in favour of a company registered with the RJSC, such waived amount shall be deemed as income of the company and shall be taxable in an assessment year in which such waiver is made," reads Section 67(8) of</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 16:16:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Time to regulate online content creators</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/time-to-regulate-online-content-creators</link><description>Social media offers a unique platform for independent content creators to express themselves freely, experiment with new ideas, and both enlighten and entertain their audiences. This unprecedented freedom of  creating and publishing online content has unleashed countless talents, many of whom</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 16:31:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Setbacks LDCs are up against in global trade</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/setbacks-ldcs-are-up-against-in-global-trade</link><description>For more than a decade, the global community has been working towards the goal of doubling the share of global exports from the Least Developed Countries (LDCs) to two per cent by 2020, up from one per cent a decade ago. There has been the United Nations (UN) Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs') c</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 16:46:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bus catches fire in Gazipur due to engine glitch</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bus-catches-fire-in-gazipur-due-to-engine-glitch</link><description>A passenger bus caught fire on the Dhaka–Mymensingh highway in the Chaydana area of Gazipur city on Saturday evening due to an engine malfunction.
The blaze erupted around 7:30 pm, burning all the seats of the bus. No injuries were reported, as both the driver and passengers were able to eva</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 17:01:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Paying heed to IMF's revenue warning</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/paying-heed-to-imfs-revenue-warning</link><description>The persistent challenge of elevating revenue collection remains the central economic puzzle that Bangladesh has attempted to solve for many years. From enacting a new income tax law in 2023 to expanding and reorganising both the Income Tax wing and the Customs and VAT wing, the government has intr</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 17:16:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gold price drops by Tk 5,447 per bhori at week’s start</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/gold-price-drops-by-tk-5447-per-bhori-at-weeks-start</link><description>After four consecutive hikes, the Bangladesh Jewellers Association (BAJUS) has reduced gold prices by Tk 5,447 per bhori, bringing the new rate for 22-carat gold to Tk 208,272 per bhori.
The revised prices will take effect from Sunday, the association said in a statement on Saturday night, UNB rep</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 18:09:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP to ensure more business-friendly environment if voted to power: Khosru</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-to-ensure-more-business-friendly-environment-if-voted-to-power-khosru</link><description>BNP Standing Committee member Amir Khosru Mahmud Chowdhury has said that if the BNP returns to power, it will take steps to ensure a more business-friendly environment for entrepreneurs across the country.
He made the remarks on Saturday while speaking at the Faridpur Divisional Business Forum mee</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 18:24:50 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>