<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 16:33:51 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>July Charter will ensure religious rights of citizens: Ali Riaz</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/july-charter-will-ensure-religious-rights-of-citizens-ali-riaz</link><description>Chief Adviser’s Special Assistant Professor Ali Riaz on Tuesday said the July National Charter will ensure the religious rights of every citizen and establish a society based on equality, human dignity, and social justice.
 “July National Charter will establish a society based on</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 14:45:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>51.4pc growth of remittance inflow in first 26 days of January</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/514pc-growth-of-remittance-inflow-in-first-26-days-of-january</link><description>Inflow of remittances witnessed a year-on-year growth of 51.4 per cent reaching US$2,708 million in the first 26 days of January, according to the latest data of Bangladesh Bank (BB) issued on Tuesday.
Last year, during the same period, the country's remittance inflow was $1,789 million.
During t</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 15:00:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>National Taskforce submits report on restructuring tax system to CA</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/national-taskforce-submits-report-on-restructuring-tax-system-to-ca</link><description>The National Taskforce on Restructuring the Tax System on Tuesday submitted its report to Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus, outlining specific short-and long-term recommendations aimed at raising Bangladesh’s tax-to-GDP ratio to the desired level.
The report proposed necessary restruct</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 13:45:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Poll atmosphere excellent, debate positive: EC Anwarul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/poll-atmosphere-excellent-debate-positive-ec-anwarul</link><description>Despite reports of clashes between supporters of rival candidates across the country, Election Commissioner Md Anwarul Islam Sarker describes the polling environment as “excellent".
He also views speeches and debates around pledges and manifestos at rallies as “positive”.</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 14:00:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Teen girl stops Tarique’s motorcade, shares her dream of serving people as MP</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/teen-girl-stops-tariques-motorcade-shares-her-dream-of-serving-people-as-mp</link><description>BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman on Tuesday had an emotional encounter with a teenage girl who stopped his motorcade from Mymensingh to Gazipur, telling him she dreams of serving people through politics and becoming an MP one day.
The incident took place in the Seed Store area of Mymensingh’s Bha</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 14:15:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bank staff killed in Dhaka road crash</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/bank-staff-killed-in-dhaka-road-crash</link><description>A 35-year-old man was killed after being crushed between two buses while crossing road in Badda Link Road area of the capital on Tuesday.
The deceased was identified as Abul Kashem Azad, a staff of UCB Bank, Khilkhet branch and son of Abul Kalam Azad of Faridganj upazila in Chandpur district.
He</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 14:30:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BAF, Chinese company sign deal on drone manufacturing, tech transfer</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/baf-chinese-company-sign-deal-on-drone-manufacturing-tech-transfer</link><description>Bangladesh Air Force (BAF) and state-owned China Electronics Technology Group Corporation International (CETC) have signed a deal under a G2G framework on Tuesday to establish an Unmanned Aerial Vehicle (UAV-drone) manufacturing and assembly plant and technology transfer.
The agreement was signed</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 14:45:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Police to maintain neutrality, professionalism in national election: IGP</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/police-to-maintain-neutrality-professionalism-in-national-election-igp</link><description>Inspector General of Police Baharul Alam on Tuesday said police will uphold professionalism, neutrality and a strong sense of responsibility during the national parliamentary election.
He made the remarks while addressing Assistant Superintendent of Police (ASP) probationers at the Hall of Integri</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 15:00:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Education ministry opens transfers for MPO-listed school, college teachers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/education-ministry-opens-transfers-for-mpo-listed-school-college-teachers</link><description>The Ministry of Education has issued a new policy allowing teachers under the Monthly Pay Order (MPO) scheme to transfer between private schools and colleges, introducing a centralised, online system to manage vacancies and applications.
If vacancies exist in the same post, applications will be ac</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 15:15:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NTRCA to hold written, viva exams for heads, deputies at private schools</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/ntrca-to-hold-written-viva-exams-for-heads-deputies-at-private-schools</link><description>The Non‑Government Teachers’ Registration and Certification Authority (NTRCA) will conduct examinations for the appointment of heads and assistant heads in private educational institutions.
According to a notification issued on Tuesday by the Secondary and Higher Education Division of the ed</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 15:30:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>118 joint secretaries promoted to additional secretary posts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/118-joint-secretaries-promoted-to-additional-secretary-posts</link><description>A total of 118 officials of the administration cadre have been promoted to the rank of additional secretary at the final stage of the interim government’s tenure.
The promotions were confirmed in a government notification issued on Tuesday.
According to the notification, the officials were</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 15:45:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US hinted at tariff relief for Bangladeshi goods, says Lutfey Siddiqi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/us-hinted-at-tariff-relief-for-bangladeshi-goods-says-lutfey-siddiqi</link><description>Bangladeshi goods may soon face lower tariffs in the United States, Chief Advisor’s International Affairs Special Envoy Lutfey Siddiqi has said after recent bilateral discussions.
On Tuesday, he said the tariffs are “expected to remain around 20 per cent”.
 “We hope t</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 16:00:47 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>