<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 13:25:16 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Investment, daily life stalled as nation awaits election: Khosru</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/investment-daily-life-stalled-as-nation-awaits-election-khosru</link><description>BNP senior leader Amir Khosru Mahmud Chowdhury on Sunday said investment, business activities and even personal and family decisions across the country have come to a standstill as people are waiting for the national election.
“People now want emancipation form the current situation through</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 10:30:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ex-mayor Selina Hayat Ivy gets bail in 5 cases</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ex-mayor-selina-hayat-ivy-gets-bail-in-5-cases</link><description>The High Court on Sunday granted bail to former mayor of Narayanganj City Corporation (NCC) Selina Hayat Ivy in five separate cases including a murder case.
The HC bench of Justice ASM Abdul Mobin and Justice Md Sagir Hossain passed the order after hearing five separate petitions.
Barrister Sara</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 10:45:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Saudi Arabia executes two people for plotting attacks on places of worship</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/saudi-arabia-executes-two-people-for-plotting-attacks-on-places-of-worship</link><description>Saudi Arabia said on Sunday that it had executed two citizens for joining a terrorist group that planned to carry out attacks on places of worship.
The two men also planned attacks against security facilities and personnel, Saudi state news agency SPA reported, citing a statement from the interior</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 11:00:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DU students told to ‘vacate hall room’ for VP, GS</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dhaka-university-provost-accused-of-ordering-six-students-to-clear-hall-room-for-vp-gs</link><description>A controversy has erupted at Dhaka University’s Sir AF Rahman Hall after six resident students alleged that the hall provost asked them to vacate their room to accommodate the newly elected vice-president and general secretary of the hall union.
According to the students, Prof Quazi Mahfujul</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 11:15:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Syngenta Bangladesh recognized as Innovation Leader of the Year 2025 by FICCI</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/syngenta-bangladesh-recognized-as-innovation-leader-of-the-year-2025-by-ficci</link><description>Syngenta Bangladesh has been recognized as the “Innovation Leader of the Year 2025” by the Foreign Investors’ Chamber of Commerce and Industry (FICCI) under its Sustainability &amp; Innovation Awards, which celebrate excellence in Environmental, Social, and Governance (ESG) practices</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 11:30:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tk 104.8b loan scam: ACC files its biggest case against S Alam Group chairman, 66 others</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/acc-files-its-biggest-case-against-s-alam-group-chairman-66-others-over-tk-1048b-loan-scam</link><description>The Anti‑Corruption Commission (ACC) has filed what it says is its largest ever corruption case, accusing Mohammad Saiful Alam (65), chairman of S Alam Group, and 66 other individuals over a massive loan fraud of Tk 104.8 billion.
The ACC claims loans amounting to Tk 92.84 billion</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 11:05:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Final voter list to be published on Nov 18</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/final-voter-list-to-be-published-on-nov-18</link><description>Election Commission (EC) Senior Secretary Akhtar Ahmed on Sunday said the final voter list will be published and the expatriate voter registration app will be launched on November 18.
“Earlier, we wanted to launch the Expatriate Voter Registration App on November 16. Now instead of November</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 11:20:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IMF delegation meets BNP leaders</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/imf-delegation-meets-with-bnp-leaders-to-discuss-economic-tax-system-reforms</link><description>A delegation from the International Monetary Fund (IMF) has met senior BNP leaders in Dhaka to discuss Bangladesh’s ongoing economic situation and possible reforms in the tax and financial sectors.
The meeting took place at the BNP Chairperson’s Office in Gulshan on Sunday morning.
Th</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 11:35:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Powerful quake hits off Japan’s northern coast, tsunami advisory issued</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/powerful-quake-strikes-off-the-coast-of-japan-tsunami-advisory-lifted-after-3-hours</link><description>A powerful magnitude 6.9 earthquake struck off the coast of Iwate Prefecture in northern Japan on Sunday evening, prompting a tsunami advisory and warnings of possible aftershocks, the Japan Meteorological Agency (JMA) said.
The quake, which occurred at 5:03 p.m. local time at a depth of about 16</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 11:50:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt to decide shareholders’ fate in 5 Shariah banks proposed for merger: Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-to-decide-shareholders-fate-in-5-shariah-banks-proposed-for-merger-adviser</link><description>The government will make the final decision on the status of shareholders of the five Shariah-based banks proposed for merger, said Finance Adviser Dr Salehuddin Ahmed on Sunday.
The Bangladesh Bank governor’s statement is not final as the government will look into the matter, Dr Salehuddin</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 12:05:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Army deployment to remain unchanged: Jahangir</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/army-deployment-to-remain-unchanged-jahangir</link><description>Home Advisor Jahangir Alam Chowdhury has said the government’s plan to withdraw 50 percent of Army personnel deployed with executive magistracy powers from the field will not be implemented.
After a meeting of the core committee on law and order at the Secretariat on Sunday, Jahangir was ask</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 12:20:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Walton cables get approval from Maldives' Utility Regulatory Authority for electrical installations</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/walton-cables-get-approval-from-maldives-utility-regulatory-authority-for-electrical-installations</link><description>Bangladeshi electronics giant Walton has accomplished another milestone in its export business in the latest move of its global presence, since it started exporting locally made power cables to Maldives upon receiving the approval certificate from Male Utility Regulatory Authority.
Walton Cables&amp;r</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 12:35:06 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>