<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 13:52:33 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Govt to procure five cargoes of LNG</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/govt-to-procure-five-cargoes-of-lng</link><description>The government has approved a proposal for procuring five LNG cargoes in 2026 on a G2G basis from Aramco Trading Singapore Pte Ltd to meet the country’s rising energy demand.
The approval came from the 4th meeting of the Advisers Council Committee on Government Purchase this year, held on Tu</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 10:32:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No possibility of postponing or destabilising Feb-12 election: Home Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/no-possibility-of-postponing-or-destabilising-feb-12-election-home-adviser</link><description>Home Affairs Adviser Lt Gen (retd) Jahangir Alam Chowdhury on Tuesday reaffirmed that the February-12 national election will proceed as scheduled, dismissing any speculation about any possible delay, or threats to its stability.
“The terrorists who were active in the past fled the country af</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 10:47:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat chief Shafiqur calls Mustafizur's IPL snub a 'grave insult'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-chief-shafiqur-calls-mustafizurs-ipl-snub-a-grave-insult</link><description>Jamaat-e-Islami Amir Shafiqur Rahman has described the exclusion of Satkhira-born cricketer Mustafizur Rahman from the Indian Premier League (IPL) as a “grave insult”.
“Isn’t it Mustafiz who illuminated the cricketing world, and who has illuminated Bangladesh? And yet this</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 11:02:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCP's Nasiruddin Patwary alleges harassment at college festival, stages protest</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ncps-nasiruddin-patwary-alleges-harassment-at-college-festival-stages-protest</link><description>NCP leader Nasiruddin Patwary, a candidate of the Jamaat-e-Islami-led 10-party alliance in the Dhaka-8 constituency, has staged a sit-in protest after alleging that he was harassed at a college event.
Patwary said he was targeted by members of the Jatiotabadi Chhatra Dal, the student wing of the B</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 11:17:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BB governor for efficiency as key to LDC graduation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/bb-governor-for-efficiency-as-key-to-ldc-graduation</link><description>Bangladesh Bank (BB) Governor Dr. Ahsan H. Mansur today (Tuesday) emphasized that the country’s graduation from Least Developed Country (LDC) status should be viewed not as a mere deadline, but as a drive toward achieving economic efficiency and competitiveness. 
“The policies req</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 11:32:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>5 organizations honored with EBL Climate Change Action Awards 2026</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/5-organizations-honored-with-ebl-climate-change-action-awards-2026</link><description>Eastern Bank PLC. (EBL) hosted the second edition of the EBL Climate Change Action Awards 2026, honoring five organizations for their outstanding, innovative, and impactful initiatives addressing climate change challenges in Bangladesh. The award ceremony was held at the Radisson Blu Water Garden H</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 11:27:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat expresses concern over attacks on its women activists</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-expresses-concern-over-attacks-on-its-women-activists</link><description>Nayeb-e-Ameer of Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami Dr. Syed Abdullah Mohammad Taher today (Tuesday) expressed concern over the recent attacks on its women activists in different parts across the country. "Despite incidents occurring openly in many areas, the Election Commission was playing a "passive</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 11:42:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Police to grill Pabitra Kumar in custody for four days over ‘child abuse’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/police-to-grill-pabitra-kumar-in-custody-for-four-days-over-child-abuse</link><description>Police have been granted approval to question Pabitra Kumar Barua, an administrative officer allegedly involved in the abuse of a child at a school in Dhaka’s Paltan, in their custody for four days.
Dhaka Additional Chief Metropolitan Magistrate Md Sefatullah passed the order after a hearing</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 11:57:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two teens in Teknaf injured by gunfire from Myanmar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/two-teens-in-teknaf-injured-by-gunfire-from-myanmar</link><description>Two teenage fishermen have been injured by gunfire while fishing in the Naf River along the Bangladesh–Myanmar border in Teknaf.
The incident occurred on Tuesday near Whykong Union, according to Sub-Inspector (SI) Khokon Kanti Rudra, chief of the local police outpost.
The injured youths all</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 12:12:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Daffodil International University to hold 13th Convocation Wednesday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/daffodil-international-university-to-hold-13th-convocation-wednesday</link><description>The 13th Convocation of Daffodil International University is going to be held tomorrow, January 28, 2026, at Swadhinata Sommelon Kendro of the university.
Delegated by Mohammad Sahabuddin, President of the People’s Republic of Bangladesh and Chancellor of Daffodil International University, P</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 12:27:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rangpur lynching: Family ‘threatened’ after suspects get bail</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/rangpur-lynching-family-threatened-after-suspects-get-bail</link><description>In Rangpur’s Taragonj Upazila, the family of Ruplal Das and his son-in-law Pradeep Lal -- both beaten to death in a “mob” attack -- has alleged that suspects released on bail are now threatening them to withdraw the murder charges.
The threats and intimidation are aimed at forcin</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 12:42:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CA inaugurates e-Learning Programme in three hill districts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ca-inaugurates-e-learning-programme-in-three-hill-districts</link><description>Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus on Tuesday formally inaugurated the e-Learning Programme in 12 schools across the three hill districts in Chattogram.
He launched the programme virtually from the state guest house Jamuna here this noon and exchanged views with teachers and students of the 12</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 12:57:04 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>