<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 05:22:40 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>State must campaign for ‘Yes’ in referendum: Adviser Nurjahan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/campaigning-for-yes-in-referendum-is-a-state-obligation-adviser-nurjahan</link><description>Health and Family Welfare Adviser Nurjahan Begum on Friday said that campaigning in favor of a ‘Yes’ vote in the upcoming referendum is a collective obligation for the state.
She made the remarks while answering journalists’ questions after a discussion with district- and divisio</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 17:40:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tutor ‘confesses’ to killing student, mother in Keraniganj over ‘NGO loan row’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tutor-confesses-to-killing-student-mother-in-keraniganj-over-ngo-loan-row</link><description>A private tutor arrested in connection with the killing of a woman and her teenage daughter in Keraniganj has “confessed” to her role in the murders, which investigators say stemmed from a dispute over a loan.
The confession was recorded on Friday when Dhaka Senior Judicial Magistrate</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 17:55:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Memorial for ‘resolute’ Khaleda draws calls for unity</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/civic-memorial-remembers-resolute-khaleda-zia-urges-unity-amid-national-strain</link><description>Representatives from across the social and political spectrum have urged the nation to remain united during this period of transition, invoking the late BNP chairperson Khaleda Zia’s “resolute” spirit and her enduring message of peace over vengeance.
The call for solidarity reson</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 18:10:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Japan, Philippines sign new security pacts as regional tensions rise</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/japan-philippines-sign-new-security-pacts-as-regional-tensions-rise</link><description>The Philippines and Japan signed two defence pacts on Thursday, including a deal allowing their forces to exchange supplies and services, with both countries seeking to strengthen security cooperation in response to rising regional tensions.
The Acquisition and Cross-Servicing Agreement, designed</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 18:25:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique supports interim govt's US tariff deal, wants deeper trade ties</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-supports-interim-govts-us-tariff-deal-wants-deeper-trade-ties</link><description>Bangladesh Nationalist party (BNP) Chairman Tarique Rahman seeks to develop wider trade cooperation between Bangladesh and the United States to strengthen the bilateral ties.

The BNP leader has also lent support to the interim government- negotiated tariff agreement with the US Trump administrat</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 18:40:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ICC envoy to visit Dhaka over WC venue row</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/icc-envoy-to-visit-dhaka-as-bangladesh-holds-firm-on-world-cup-venue-stance</link><description>An International Cricket Council (ICC) representative will arrive in Dhaka on Saturday to discuss Bangladesh’s venue concerns for the T20 World Cup, marking a fresh attempt to break the deadlock over where the Tigers will play their games.
Initially, a two-member ICC delegation was expected</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 18:55:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Revenue control pushes Chittagong Port’s profit to 5-year high</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/revenue-control-pushes-chittagong-ports-profit-to-5-year-high</link><description>Chittagong Port has recorded a net profit of Tk 31.43 billion in 2025, the highest in the past five years.
Non-VAT and tax revenues contributed Tk 18.05 billion to the government treasury, also a five-year high.
Port Administration Director Md Omar Faruk said, “Since 2021, revenue has g</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 19:10:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>China hospital chains in Bangladesh, first one to be built in Nilphamari</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/china-hospital-chains-in-bangladesh-first-one-to-be-built-in-nilphamari</link><description>Modern-day China hospital chains in Bangladesh begin with a big venture in the country's far north to cater all low-cost treatments and specialised care at higher expenses, officials say.
Northern Nilphamari district is set to host the country's first high-standard, large-scale 'Bangladesh-China F</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 02:30:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Restoring macroeconomic stability rests on revenue policy upgrade</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/restoring-macroeconomic-stability-rests-on-revenue-policy-upgrade</link><description>A time-bound structural and policy rejig of the revenue system is imperative for restoring and sustaining Bangladesh's macroeconomic stability as insufficient domestic resources upend government plans and generate overall volatility.
To this end, a multi-stakeholder taskforce on revenue reform is</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 02:45:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Meeting with Jamaat chief was part of 'routine engagement,' India says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/meeting-with-jamaat-chief-was-part-of-routine-diplomatic-engagement-india-says</link><description>New Delhi has said the reported meeting between a senior Indian diplomat and Jamaat-e-Islami chief Shafiqur Rahman was part of routine diplomatic engagement, responding nearly two weeks after the issue surfaced in the media.
The Indian Ministry of External Affairs made the comment on Friday, accor</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 03:00:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Why Bangladesh's farmers lose while city consumers pay more</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/why-bangladeshs-farmers-lose-while-city-consumers-pay-more</link><description>For Foishal Rahman, a middle-aged resident of Shantinagar in Dhaka, a simple visit to the local kitchen market has become a source of profound anxiety.
"I grew up in a village where vegetables were practically free during the harvest season. Today, in Dhaka, I am paying nearly four times the price</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 04:00:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Weekly Market Review: Stocks back in red amid selling pressure</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/weekly-market-review-stocks-back-in-red-amid-selling-pressure</link><description>The benchmark equity index ended the week in negative territory, snapping a three-week winning streak as market sentiment turned cautious amid mounting concerns over the ongoing domestic gas crisis and escalating geopolitical tensions.
Analysts pointed out that the market recovery, which had been</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 05:00:46 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>