<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 11:19:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Govt importing rice from India to keep prices stable</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/govt-importing-rice-from-india-to-keep-prices-stable</link><description>The government has decided to import rice from India to keep rice prices stable in the market, said Finance Adviser Salehuddin Ahmed.
He shared the information while talking to reporters after a meeting of the Advisory Council Committee on Government Procurement at the Secretariat on Monday. He sa</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 08:46:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Minor earthquake felt in Saudi Arabia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/minor-earthquake-felt-in-saudi-arabia</link><description>The Saudi Geological Survey (SGS) recorded two earthquakes on Saturday - one in Saudi Arabia and another in Iraq, media reports said.
According to the SGS, its National Seismic Monitoring Network detected a minor quake about 86km northwest of Harrat Al Shaqa, situated between Al-Ais in the Madinah</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 08:19:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Veteran actor Dharmendra passes away</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/entertainment/veteran-actor-dharmendra-passes-away</link><description>Veteran Bollywood actor Dharmendra has passed away at the age of 89.
According to Indian media reports, he died in Mumbai, weeks after being discharged from Breach Candy Hospital following a period of medical treatment.
The legendary actor had been admitted to the hospital earlier this month and</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 08:49:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DU Prof Hafizur Rahman gets bail, no bar to release</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/du-prof-hafizur-rahman-gets-bail-no-bar-to-release</link><description>The High Court on Monday granted ad-interim bail for six months to Dhaka University Professor Hafizur Rahman Karzon in a case filed under the Anti-Terrorism Act.
The HC bench of Justice KM Rasheduzzaman Raja and Justice Rezaul Karim passed the order, UNB reports. 
The DU Professor filed a pe</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 09:04:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt may revise election budget as referendum adds extra costs: Finance Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/govt-may-revise-election-budget-as-referendum-adds-extra-costs-finance-adviser</link><description>Finance Adviser Dr Salehuddin Ahmed on Monday said the government may need to revise the election budget as holding the national election and the referendum on the same day will inevitably raise costs, particularly for security and manpower.
“When we first received their proposal, the refere</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 09:19:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Salman Rahman’s land attached, bank account frozen</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/court-orders-seizure-of-36-bighas-of-land-owned-by-salman-f-rahman-freezes-bank-account</link><description>A Dhaka court has ordered the attachment of 36 bighas of land in Gazipur belonging to Salman F Rahman, the private industry and investment advisor to ousted prime minister Sheikh Hasina.
The court also directed authorities to freeze an IFIC Bank account held in Salman’s name, which investiga</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 09:34:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Court freezes 21 bank accounts of Fazle Noor Taposh, sons</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/court-freezes-21-bank-accounts-of-fazle-noor-taposh-sons</link><description>A Dhaka court on Monday ordered to freeze 21 bank accounts of former Dhaka South City Corporation (DSCC) mayor Barrister Sheikh Fazle Noor Taposh and his two sons, Sheikh Fazle Nawar and Sheikh Fazle Nashwan.
Dhaka Metropolitan Senior Special Judge Md Sabbir Faiz passed the order, allowing a plea</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 09:49:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Walton Micro-Tech’s Nishat Tasnim Shuchi honoured with C-Suite’s ‘CEO of The Year’ award</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/walton-micro-techs-nishat-tasnim-shuchi-honoured-with-c-suites-ceo-of-the-year-award</link><description>The fourth edition of Bangladesh C-Suite Awards-2025 honoured Walton Micro-Tech Corporation's Chief Executive Officer (CEO) Nishat Tasnim Shuchi with ‘CEO of The Year.’
Nishat Tasnim Shuchi is a dynamic young leader who has emerged as a powerful force within Walton Group, according to</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 10:04:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ctg blanket godown fire under control</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ctg-blanket-godown-fire-under-control</link><description>A fire that broke out at a blanket warehouse at Kadamtoli in Chattogram port city has been brought under control.
The fire was brought under control at 3:30 pm, said deputy assistant director Alamgir Hossain of Agrabad Fire Station and Civil Defense.
On information, seven firefighting units rushe</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 10:19:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CA seeks Commonwealth support for upcoming general election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ca-seeks-commonwealth-support-for-upcoming-general-election</link><description>Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus on Monday sought the Commonwealth’s full support for holding the upcoming general election, scheduled for the first half of February next.
“We need your support in our democratic transition as well as in the upcoming general election,” the C</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 10:34:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Malaysian floods affect 11,000 people across seven states</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/malaysian-floods-affect-11000-people-across-seven-states</link><description>More than 11,000 people in seven Malaysian states have been affected by flooding caused by torrential rain, the national disaster agency said on Monday.
Floods are common on the eastern coast of Malaysia during the annual monsoon season from October until March, with thousands of people displaced</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 10:49:43 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>