<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 22:28:11 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>DCs asked to submit data on two key canals of each upazila by Mar 1</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dcs-asked-to-submit-data-on-two-key-canals-of-each-upazila-by-mar-1</link><description>Disaster Management and Relief Ministry has directed all deputy commissioners to submit information on two of most important canals of each upazila by March 1 as part of a nationwide initiative to boost agricultural production and ease waterlogging.
The instruction was issued today through an urge</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 15:30:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NID card services will soon extend to 16-year-olds: EC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nid-card-services-will-soon-extend-to-16-year-olds-ec</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has decided to issue national identity (NID) cards to Bangladeshi citizens aged 16 and above.
A notification issued by the EC’s NID wing on Sunday directed field-level officials to begin registration for those who have reached 16 or 17 years of age.
Under the ne</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 15:45:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Election &amp; rebuilding post-July Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/election-rebuilding-post-july-bangladesh</link><description>The Bangladesh Nationalist party (BNP) has won a landslide majority in the country's election held on February 12, 2026, following an uprising that ended the 15-year rule of Sheikh Hasina in 2024. In the interim period, a transitional government headed by Professor Mohammad Yunus ran the country. T</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 16:00:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pharmaceutical pollution needs to be stopped</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/pharmaceutical-pollution-needs-to-be-stopped</link><description>Technological change in the global supply chain is driving a new era of productivity and creativity with far-reaching implications for global development and security. However, beyond adopting new, non-binding frameworks, all countries must work together to manage new and emerging technologies, bet</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 16:15:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shaping a human-centric future for AI</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/shaping-a-human-centric-future-for-ai</link><description>At a defining moment in human history, the world gathered at the AI Impact Summit 2026 in New Delhi. For us in India, it was a moment of immense pride and joy to welcome Heads of State, Heads of Government, delegates and innovators from across the world.
India brings scale and energy to everything</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 16:30:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Davos 2026 and beyond</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/reviews/davos-2026-and-beyond</link><description>As Davos 2026 concludes, its most important contribution may be what it quietly confirmed: the global economy is no longer organised around convergence, but around managing division. The World Economic Forum (WEF) once again assembled political leaders, central bankers, corporate executives and mul</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 16:45:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Undeterred Trump opts for more aggressive tariffs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/undeterred-trump-opts-for-more-aggressive-tariffs</link><description>With the US Supreme Court (SC) upholding the lower court ruling that the reciprocal tariffs President Trump imposed under the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (IEEPA) is illegal, its fallouts were supposed to be sobering enough to dissipate the turmoil in global trade the tariff policy c</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 17:00:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AI not magic wand for all our problems</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/ai-not-magic-wand-for-all-our-problems</link><description>In recent discussions in the business circles and among the policymakers, the AI-driven solutions have become the watchword. It is as though humanity has found the ultimate magic wand to resolve all problems ranging from healthcare to governance to economic development of a country. This infatuatio</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 17:15:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trade deal with the USA warrants careful review</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/trade-deal-with-the-usa-warrants-careful-review</link><description>The global economy has been on a roller-coaster ride since US President Donald Trump, returning to office for a second term, sought to rewrite the rules of global trade by imposing sweeping tariffs on imports into the United States (US) from most countries. As the US remains the primary export dest</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 17:30:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Child killed as BNP MP’s convoy vehicle hits him in Cox’s Bazar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/child-killed-as-bnp-mps-convoy-vehicle-hits-him-in-coxs-bazar</link><description>An eight‑year‑old boy has been killed after being struck by a vehicle from the motorcade of newly elected BNP lawmaker Alamgir Md Mahfujullah Farid in Cox’s Bazar’s Chakaria.
The incident occurred around 4:30pm on Sunday on the main road near Badarkhali Fazil Madrasa.
The victim, iden</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 18:01:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP HQ lies barren</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bnp-headquarters-looks-deserted-after-party-forms-government</link><description>The Bangladesh Nationalist Party has returned to power after almost two decades, with an unfamiliar scene unfolding at its headquarters.
The once-bustling central office at Naya Paltan is now devoid of leaders and activists, with staff passing idle hours.
Visits at 11am and again at 2:30pm on Sun</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 18:16:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BB cuts down-payment requirement to 1.0pc</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bb-cuts-down-payment-requirement-to-10pc</link><description>Current 2.0-percent mandatory down payment to get default loans regularised has been halved in a latest government measure to stem non-performing loan (NPL) buildup in Bangladesh's banking sector.



Bangladesh Bank (BB) Sunday issued a notification to this effect further easing the loan-resche</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 18:31:07 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>