<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 17:19:20 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Bangladesh Bank reinstates extra increment benefit to attract, retain top talent</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-bank-reinstates-extra-increment-benefit-to-attract-retain-top-talent</link><description>Bangladesh Bank has reinstated the provision of additional increments for officers directly recruited to the 9th and 10th pay grades in a bid to attract and retain highly qualified individuals.
The move, aimed at enhancing the central bank's appeal to brilliant minds, was announced recently throug</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 15:28:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCC to submit comprehensive recommendations soon for implementation of July Charter</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ncc-to-submit-comprehensive-recommendations-soon-for-implementation-of-july-charter</link><description>The National Consensus Commission (NCC) has expressed hope that it will be able to submit specific and comprehensive recommendations to the government very soon for the implementation of the July Charter.
The Commission said on Thursday during a meeting with experts to discuss recommendations on t</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 15:28:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Europe takes aim at Musk's Starlink with new satellite champion</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/europe-takes-aim-at-musks-starlink-with-new-satellite-champion</link><description>A deal to forge Europe’s answer to Elon Musk’s Starlink was reached on Thursday as the continent’s top space firms agreed to combine their satellite manufacturing and services businesses.
Marking the most ambitious tie-up of European aerospace assets since the creation of missile</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 15:43:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BCB president backs Miraz as ODI captain amid criticism</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/bcb-president-backs-miraz-as-odi-captain-amid-criticism</link><description>Bangladesh Cricket Board (BCB) president Aminul Islam Bulbul is keen to be patient with the captaincy of Mehidy Hasan Miraz, saying that the allrounder has the leadership qualities, something which is not yet reflected in the results.
“He is new in this role (captaincy). But he has the leade</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 15:58:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>French court penalizes TotalEnergies for deceptive greenwashing claims</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/french-court-penalizes-totalenergies-for-deceptive-greenwashing-claims</link><description>Oil major TotalEnergies (TTEF.PA) misled consumers in a 2021 ad campaign claiming it could become carbon neutral by 2050, a French civil court found on Thursday, in the first decision applying France's greenwashing law to an energy company.
The court ordered TotalEnergies to remove from its websit</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 16:13:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mapping growth through shadow work</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/mapping-growth-through-shadow-work</link><description>The perception of night has been fundamentally changed ever since the invention of artificial light. The nighttime is not just darkness; it has an economy of its own. It is known as the "nighttime economy" (NTE), a simple term for all the economic activity that happens between 6:00 P.M. and 6:00 A.</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 16:43:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>External debt sustainability in the face of climate change</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/reviews/external-debt-sustainability-in-the-face-of-climate-change</link><description>There are two elements of standard public debt sustainability analysis. The sustainability of external debt and the sustainability of domestic debt. They are inter-related but often have different dimensions. Both are very important. As such, traditional debt sustainability assessment (DSA) conduct</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 16:58:56 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>