<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 09:24:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Indices rise in first hour of trading at DSE, CSE</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/indices-rise-in-first-hour-of-trading-at-dse-cse</link><description>The country's stock markets began the last working day of the week on a positive note, with key indices at both the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) and Chittagong Stock Exchange (CSE) edging up in the first hour of trading on Thursday.
At the DSE, the benchmark DSEX index gained 17 points, while the Sh</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 06:45:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat among eight parties submit memorandum to EC demanding Nov referendum</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-among-eight-parties-submit-memorandum-to-ec-demanding-nov-referendum</link><description>Eight political parties, including Jamaat-e-Islami and Islami Andolan Bangladesh, on Thursday submitted a memorandum to the Election Commission (EC), demanding a referendum in November and implementation of the July National Charter.
 
The parties held a short rally in front of Nirbanchan Bh</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 07:00:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BGB sends 107 Rohingya back to camp</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bgb-sends-107-rohingya-back-to-camp</link><description>Border Guard Bangladesh (BGB) has taken 107 Rohingya, including women and children, who roamed outside their camps into custody and has sent them back to refugee camps in Cox's Bazar' Teknaf.
In a press statement issued in the early hours of Thursday, Lt Col Ashikur Rahman, commander of BGB's Tekn</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 07:30:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fire guts seven shops in Satkhira</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fire-guts-seven-shops-in-satkhira</link><description>At least seven business structures were gutted in a fire at Hazrakati Bazar in Tala upazila of Satkhira district on Thursday.
Officer-in-charge Mainuddin of Tala Police Station said the fire erupted from one of the shops around 3:00 am and engulfed the adjacent others, reports UNB.
Being informed</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 07:45:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Malaysia's labour market reopening to Bangladeshis</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/malaysias-labour-market-reopening-to-bangladeshis</link><description>The Malaysian labour market is opening soon to Bangladeshi expatriates. However, the country – one of the major destinations for Bangladeshi workers -- has also imposed 10 conditions on recruitment agencies.
A press release from Malaysia says recruiting agencies from Bangladesh, India, Nepal</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 07:44:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Afghanistan and Pakistan agree to restart peace talks in Istanbul, sources say</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/afghanistan-and-pakistan-agree-to-restart-peace-talks-in-istanbul-sources-say</link><description>Afghanistan and Pakistan will restart peace talks in Istanbul, three sources familiar with the matter said on Thursday, a day after Islamabad said the discussions had failed.
Two of the sources stated that the nations had agreed to recommence talks at the request of the host nation, Turkey. Nego</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 08:14:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat, seven other parties hold meeting with CEC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-seven-other-parties-hold-meeting-with-cec</link><description>Delegations from eight political parties who came to the Election Commission (EC) to submit a memorandum demanding a referendum in November have met Chief Election Commissioner AMM Nasir Uddin.
EC Secretary Akhtar Ahmed was also present at the meeting, which began at 1pm on Thursday, reports bdn</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 08:44:10 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>