<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 03:11:28 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>8 injured in BNP factional clashes over Munshiganj-3 nomination</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/8-injured-in-bnp-factional-clashes-over-munshiganj-3-nomination</link><description>At least eight people, including a woman, were injured in clashes between two factions of the BNP in Gazaria on Friday evening over the party’s nomination for the Munshiganj-3 constituency. Several vehicles and a private office were vandalised during the violence, prompting authorities to dep</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 16:45:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The digital manufacture of dreams</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/the-digital-manufacture-of-dreams</link><description>Across the developing world, migration has long been a pathway to economic mobility, a strategy for families seeking stability or upward movement. But in recent years, a new force has reshaped how young people think about leaving home. Social media platforms such as TikTok, YouTube and Facebook are</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 17:00:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Lingering curse of autocracy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/lingering-curse-of-autocracy</link><description>Three and a half decades ago, people of Bangladesh ousted the country's first autocratic regime through a mass uprising that reached its climax during the last three months of 1990. The united stance of all the students' organisations, keeping aside their political rivalry for the time being, on Oc</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 16:45:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fake note and the honest man's loss</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/fake-note-and-the-honest-mans-loss</link><description>Counterfeiting is a crime that has existed for millennia, but in contemporary Bangladesh it has evolved into one of the most sophisticated forms of financial deception. Detecting the newest generation of fake notes has become extraordinarily difficult, even bordering on impossible for the untrained</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 17:00:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Managing farm productivity risks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/managing-farm-productivity-risks</link><description>With close to 9.0 million hectares of available cultivable land, which too is shrinking by around 2,500 hectares annually, thanks mainly to urbanisation, feeding some 175 million mouths is a challenge of miraculous proportions. But the farming community of the country has been successfully meeting</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 17:15:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC urges caution against creating confusion over election schedule, voting date</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-urges-caution-against-creating-confusion-over-election-schedule-voting-date</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has urged all concerned not to spread confusion regarding the announcement of the election schedule and polling date for the upcoming national election.
EC Senior Secretary Akhtar Ahmed told the media on Friday evening that no decision has yet been taken on the schedul</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 17:30:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khaleda Zia’s condition unchanged, Zubaida back at hospital</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/khaleda-zias-condition-unchanged-zubaida-back-at-hospital</link><description>BNP Chairperson Khaleda Zia’s health remains unchanged, according to doctors.
Her daughter-in-law Zubaida Rahman again visited her at Evercare Hospital in Dhaka on Friday night after meeting her mother.
BNP Media Cell member Atikur Rahman Rumon said, “[She] visited her mother in Dhanm</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 17:45:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Factor Khaleda’s illness into polls schedule: NCP to EC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ncp-again-pushes-ec-to-factor-khaledas-illness-into-election-timeline</link><description>The National Citizen Party (NCP) has renewed calls for the Election Commission to factor in the critical illness of BNP chief Khaleda Zia when finalising the schedule for the general election slated for February.
At a policy discussion on Friday titled “The Future of Investment in Bangladesh</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 18:00:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Regular liquidity feeding to banks stops, call money market vibrant</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/regular-liquidity-feeding-to-banks-stops-call-money-market-vibrant</link><description>Bangladesh Bank finally discards a major regular liquidity-feeding instrument for primary dealer (PD) banks, eight months after the decision made to tidy the money market under a reform recipe.



As part of the central bank's decision to bring vibrancy in the interbank spot market through le</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 19:18:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tight-fisted govt spending narrows budget deficit, curtails works</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/tight-fisted-govt-spending-narrows-budget-deficit-curtails-works</link><description>A slowdown in public works following the regime-changing political upheavals has narrowed Bangladesh's budget deficit as a blessing in disguise as the interim government couldn't utilise much of the budgetary outlay, official statistics show.
The budget deficit contracted to 3.30 per cent of the G</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 02:28:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Constant product lab tests a must-do to accelerate trade</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/constant-product-lab-tests-a-must-do-to-accelerate-trade</link><description>A government instruction makes it a must-do for key scientific agencies to keep their laboratory-testing services open round the clock, weekends and public holidays no exception, to cut the cost of doing business and accelerate trade facilitation.
Officials say the Ministry of Science and Technolo</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 02:43:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Government, AIIB in talks over $400m budget support credit</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/government-aiib-in-talks-over-400m-budget-support-credit</link><description>The government is discussing with the Asian Infrastructure Investment Bank (AIIB) a $400 million fund in budget support credit to advance policy and institutional reforms, focusing on climate adaptation in the urban and water sectors.
The programme aims to support the government in implementing cr</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 02:58:24 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>