<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 14:25:47 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Prime Bank signs Payroll Banking Agreement with Selise Bangladesh Ltd</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/prime-bank-signs-payroll-banking-agreement-with-selise-bangladesh-ltd</link><description>Prime Bank PLC, one of the leading private commercial banks in Bangladesh renowned for its innovative and customer-centric financial solutions, has recently signed Payroll Banking Agreement with Selise Bangladesh Limited, a leading software development company in Bangladesh, at the Bank’s cor</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 11:25:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Speakers emphasize trauma-informed legal education to combat human trafficking</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/speakers-emphasize-trauma-informed-legal-education-to-combat-human-trafficking</link><description>Speakers on Wednesday emphasized the importance of fostering a victim-centered, trauma-informed, and gender-responsive approach among law students by strengthening their foundational knowledge and practical understanding. This approach aims to reinforce Bangladesh’s legal framework against hu</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 11:40:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>England unhappy with review technology after Carey reprieved in Adelaide Test</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/england-unhappy-with-review-technology-after-carey-reprieved-in-adelaide-test</link><description>England were left fuming after Australia's Alex Carey survived a caught-behind appeal on day one of the third Ashes Test on Wednesday, with the review technology failing to pick up an apparent nick off the century-scorer's bat due to an operator error.
The wicketkeeper, who ended up scoring 106 an</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 11:55:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Modhumoti Bank inaugurates Panchchar Sub-Branch</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/modhumoti-bank-inaugurates-panchchar-sub-branch</link><description>Modhumoti Bank PLC has been continuously expanding its banking footprint through branches, sub-branches, and agent banking points, with a vision to extend its services further and gradually bring underserved communities under the umbrella of financial inclusion.
As part of this ongoing initiative,</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 12:10:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Midland Bank signs MoU with Meena IVF and Fertility Care Ltd</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/midland-bank-signs-mou-with-meena-ivf-and-fertility-care-ltd</link><description>Midland Bank PLC signed a Memorandum of Understanding (MoU) with Meena IVF (In Vitro Fertilization) and Fertility Care Limited. Meena IVF &amp; Fertility Care is a state-of-the-art healthcare facility dedicated to providing advanced fertility treatment along with compassionate, patient-centered care.</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 12:25:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Islami Bank wins first position in Remittance Award</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/islami-bank-wins-first-position-in-remittance-award</link><description>Islami Bank Bangladesh PLC received first position in the Remittance Award 2026 by the Ministry of Expatriates’ Welfare and Overseas Employment.
The bank received this award for collecting the highest remittance in the fiscal year 2024-2025, according to a press release.
Dr. Asif Nazrul, Ad</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 12:40:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt suspends 14 secretariat employees over allowance protests</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-suspends-14-secretariat-employees-over-allowance-protests</link><description>The government has suspended 14 employees from various ministries and divisions following protests at the Bangladesh Secretariat demanding a special allowance.
The action comes after a court accepted the chargesheet in a case filed against the employees.
Different ministries and divisions issued</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 12:55:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UK police plan tougher action against antisemitic chants and protests</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/uk-police-plan-tougher-action-against-antisemitic-chants-and-protests</link><description>British police on Wednesday said they would take tougher action against people who use placards and chants to target the Jewish community, saying recent violent incidents had changed the context around such protests.
The move comes days after 15 people died in a mass shooting at Australia's Bondi</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 13:10:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Full face value refund for damaged notes, as long as 90pc intact: BB</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/full-face-value-refund-for-damaged-notes-as-long-as-90pc-intact-bangladesh-bank</link><description>Bangladesh Bank has issued a new set of guidelines regarding the exchange of damaged, torn, or defective currency notes.
Under the new policy, customers will receive the full face value of a note if more than 90 percent of it is intact.
Any branch of any bank in the country is now mandated to pro</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 13:25:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hadi attack suspect’s look changed: rental owner</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hadi-attack-suspect-had-long-hair-now-its-cropped-short-car-rental-owner-tells-court</link><description>A rent-a-car businessman at the centre of the probe into the attempted killing of Inqilab Moncho Convenor Sharif Osman bin Hadi has told a Dhaka court that the prime suspect looked markedly different now.
On Wednesday, the court sent him on a three-day remand for allegedly helping the gunman flee.</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 13:40:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ekushey Book Fair postponed due to elections, opens Feb 20</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ekushey-book-fair-postponed-due-to-elections-opens-feb-20</link><description>The Amar Ekushey Book Fair has been postponed to Feb 20 due to the national elections and will continue through to Mar 15.
The decision was confirmed at a meeting held at the Bangla Academy on Wednesday, bdnews24.com reports.</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 13:55:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat Ameer Shafiqur Rahman leaves for London</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-ameer-shafiqur-rahman-leaves-for-london</link><description>Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami Ameer Dr Shafiqur Rahman left Dhaka for the United Kingdom on Wednesday to attend a series of scheduled meetings and programmes with a delegation of the British government.
He departed Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport in the morning on a Biman Bangladesh Airlines f</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 14:10:07 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>