<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 05:20:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>AFWA calls for 'transparent probe' into latest Mirpur, Ctg factory fires</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/afwa-calls-for-transparent-probe-into-latest-mirpur-ctg-factory-fires</link><description>Asia Floor Wage Alliance (AFWA) has called for a transparent public investigation into both fires -- Mirpur and Chattogram factories with full disclosure of factory ownership and sourcing brands.
Expressing its solidarity with victims and their families, the AFWA, a global coalition of labor and s</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 01:35:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Summit Power profit nosedives 88pc on plant shutdowns, impairment loss</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/summit-power-profit-nosedives-88pc-on-plant-shutdowns-impairment-loss</link><description>Summit Power reported a whopping 88 per cent year-on-year decline in profit to Tk 0.41 billion in FY25 due to the shutdown of nearly half of its plants and an impairment loss of Tk 1.52 billion shown in its financial statements.
As the government has shifted its power policy towards renewable ener</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 01:50:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>China pledges long-term support for BD's green transition in textile industry</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/china-pledges-long-term-support-for-bds-green-transition-in-textile-industry</link><description>Chinese Ambassador to Bangladesh Yao Wen has said that Bangladesh and China are transitioning into a new phase of development cooperation centred on sustainability, and that Beijing is ready to become a long-term partner in helping Bangladesh adopt greener manufacturing standards across its textile</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 02:20:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Motakabbir Ahmed Relieved, Saif Uddin Appointed as New ATAB Administrator</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/motakabbir-ahmed-relieved-saif-uddin-appointed-as-new-atab-administrator</link><description>The Ministry of Commerce has relieved Deputy Secretary Motakabbir Ahmed from his duties as the Administrator of the Association of Travel Agents of Bangladesh (ATAB). He has been succeeded by the Ministry's Joint Secretary, Dr. Saif Uddin Ahmad.
The Ministry of Commerce's Commerce Organization-2 b</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 02:35:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shipping Secretary Mohammad Yusuf removed</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/shipping-secretary-mohammad-yusuf-removed</link><description>Senior Secretary of the Ministry of Shipping, Mohammad Yusuf, has been removed from his position.
Yusuf, who held the post on a contractual basis, has been reassigned to the Ministry of Public Administration, according to a government notification issued on Thursday.
He was appointed as the senio</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 02:50:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Low-pressure area over Southeast Bay likely to intensify: BMD</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/low-pressure-area-over-southeast-bay-likely-to-intensify-bmd</link><description>A low-pressure area has formed over the Southeast Bay and adjoining regions, and it is likely to intensify, the Bangladesh Meteorological Department (BMD) said in its bulletin on Friday morning.
Rain or thundershowers are expected at one or two places over the Chattogram and Sylhet divisions.
Els</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 04:52:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rare dinosaur mummies help scientists recreate their prehistoric lives</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/rare-dinosaur-mummies-help-scientists-recreate-their-prehistoric-lives</link><description>Researchers have unearthed a spooky pair of dinosaur mummies that seem to have been preserved in an unexpected way.
These dinosaur remains are different from the wrapped mummies of Egypt or natural human mummies that get accidentally preserved in bogs or deserts. Mummified dinosaurs are so old tha</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 05:07:12 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>