<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 16:01:58 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Man to be grilled over ‘raping’ police officer</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/man-to-be-grilled-over-raping-police-officer</link><description>A Dhaka court has ordered a businessman to be questioned for five days in a case filed by a police officer on charges of rape and fraud.
Dhaka Metropolitan Magistrate Mahbub Alam issued the order on Tuesday, and Prosecution Police Sub-Inspector (SI) Tahmina Akhter gave information about the remand</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 13:20:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sarwar Alam reappointed president’s press secretary</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/sarwar-alam-reappointed-presidents-press-secretary</link><description>Retired information cadre officer Md Sarwar Alam has been reappointed as press secretary to President Md Shahabuddin, filling a post that had remained vacant for more than a year.
The public administration ministry issued an order on Tuesday appointing him on a one‑year contractual basis.
In an i</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 13:35:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Standard Islami Bank holds its 423rd board meeting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/standard-islami-bank-holds-its-423rd-board-meeting</link><description>423rd Board Meeting of Standard Islami Bank PLC was held on Tuesday at the bank’s board room at its head office in Dhaka, according to a press release.
Chairman of the Board of Directors Mohammed Abdul Aziz presided over the meeting. It was attended by Vice Chairman Gulzar Ahmed, Directors K</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 13:50:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>PM orders steps to reopen weak, closed factories</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/pm-orders-public-private-partnerships-to-relaunch-weak-closed-industries</link><description>Prime Minister Tarique Rahman has ordered ministries to take steps to reopen dwindling and closed industries in partnership with private entrepreneurs.
Atiqur Rahman Rumon, the prime minister’s assistant press secretary, confirmed the directive on Tuesday.
The move aligns with the BNP&amp;rsquo</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 14:05:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Modhumoti Bank signs deal with RSA Advisory Limited</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/modhumoti-bank-signs-deal-with-rsa-advisory-limited</link><description>Modhumoti Bank PLC signed an Agreement with RSA Advisory Limited on Sunday at the bank’s head office in Gulshan area of Dhaka, according to a press release.
Mr. Md. Shafiul Azam, Managing Director &amp; CEO of Modhumoti Bank and Mr. K Mahmood Sattar, Chairman of RSA Advisory Limited and former M</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 13:21:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka Bank signs agreement with Siddheswari Girls’ College</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/dhaka-bank-signs-agreement-with-siddheswari-girls-college</link><description>Dhaka Bank PLC signed an agreement with Siddheswari Girls’ College (SGC) to collect fees of the college’s student through a secure, technology-driven Tuition Fees Payment Solution, according to a press release.
The agreement was signed by H. M. Mostafizur Rahaman, SEVP &amp; Head of Retail</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 13:36:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Al-Arafah Islami Bank holds training workshop on investment management</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/al-arafah-islami-bank-holds-training-workshop-on-investment-management-1</link><description>A three-day training course titled “Investment Management” has started at the bank’s training institute (AIBTI) at Al-Arafah Islami Bank on Tuesday, according to a press release.
Managing Director and CEO of the bank Mohd. Rafat Ullah Khan inaugurated the training program as the</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 13:51:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Will the president reconcile his words? Shafiqur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/shafiqur-asks-whether-president-will-reconcile-conflicting-accounts-on-hasinas-resignation</link><description>Jamaat-e-Islami chief Shafiqur Rahman has accused President Mohammed Shahabuddin of “withholding key details” about the dramatic events of Aug 5, 2024, and the resignation of Sheikh Hasina as prime minister.
Shafiqur raised questions over “contradictions” in the president&amp;r</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 14:06:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New US tariffs come in at lower 10pc rate</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/new-us-tariffs-come-in-at-lower-10pc-rate</link><description>The United States imposed a new tariff from Tuesday of 10 percent on all goods not covered by exemptions, the US Customs and Border Protection said, the rate first announced by President Donald Trump on Friday rather than the 15 percent he promised a day later.
Reacting to the US Supreme Court rul</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 14:21:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>2 secretaries reshuffled, Sanwar returns to PSC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/2-secretaries-reshuffled-sanwar-returns-to-psc</link><description>The government has reassigned Md Sanwar Jahan Bhuiyan, secretary at the Ministry of Labour and Employment, back to the Public Service Commission (PSC) Secretariat after five months.
In a corresponding move, Abdur Rahman Tarafder, who had been serving as secretary at the PSC Secretariat, was appoin</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 14:36:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BD-Japan defence deal: Decision on implementation after review</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bd-japan-defence-deal-decision-on-implementation-after-review</link><description>Japan has urged Bangladesh’s new government to uphold a defence agreement signed with the previous interim administration, even as Dhaka signalled it would review the deal based on national interest.
The issue was raised on Tuesday during a courtesy call by Japan’s ambassador to Bangla</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 14:51:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangla Academy assures inclusive, safe Amar Ekushey Book Fair</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangla-academy-assures-inclusive-safe-amar-ekushey-book-fair</link><description>Bangla Academy on Tuesday assured that this year’s Amar Ekushey Book Fair will be held in a more organised, inclusive and secure manner from February 26, despite various challenges, with the participation of the highest number of publishers.
Director General Dr Mohammad Azam made the remarks</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 15:06:36 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>