<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 17:34:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>CU Chhatra Dal gives VC 48 hours to quit</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cu-chhatra-dal-demands-resignation-of-vc-pro-vc-in-48-hours-over-nepotistic-appointments</link><description>Chittagong University unit of the Jatiyatabadi Chhatra Dal has demanded the resignation of the vice-chancellor and pro-vice-chancellor, setting a 48-hour deadline over allegations of irregular and nepotistic appointments.
The demand came on Thursday after students staged a six-hour sit-in from 10a</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 13:42:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique Rahman meets CA Yunus at Jamuna</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-rahman-meets-ca-yunus-at-jamuna</link><description>Tarique Rahman has met Chief Advisor Muhammad Yunus in Dhaka, his first family visit to the advisor’s residence since returning to Bangladesh last month.
At 7:28pm on Thursday, the BNP chairman’s flag-bearing car entered the State Guest House Jamuna, accompanied by his wife Zubaida Rah</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 13:57:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Canada’s Carney hails warmer ties with China, Xi’s leadership</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/canadas-carney-hails-warmer-ties-with-china-xis-leadership</link><description>Prime Minister Mark Carney hailed on Thursday Canada’s improving ties with China as well as the leadership of President Xi Jinping, declaring that their nations were charting a new course in cooperation at a time of global division and disorder.
The four-day visit to China was the first by a</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 14:12:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Southeast Bank provides financial assistance to Noakhali Science and Technology University</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/southeast-bank-provides-financial-assistance-to-noakhali-science-and-technology-university</link><description>As part of its Special Corporate Social Responsibility (SCSR), Southeast Bank PLC. has extended special financial support under its “Special CSR Fund” to Noakhali Science and Technology University for conducting agricultural research activities. 
M.A. Kashem, Chairman of Southeast</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 14:27:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump sees Iranian crackdown easing, Tehran denies man to be executed</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-sees-iranian-crackdown-easing-tehran-denies-man-to-be-executed</link><description>U.S. President Donald Trump said he had been told that killings in Iran’s crackdown on protests were easing and that he believed there was no current plan for large-scale executions, adopting a wait‑and‑see posture after earlier threatening intervention.
After Iran’s foreign minister s</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 14:58:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>hosting.com launches operations in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/hostingcom-officially-launches-operations-in-bangladesh</link><description>Global web hosting service provider hosting.com has officially commenced its business operations in Bangladesh.
The formal launch ceremony was held on Wednesday (14 January) at Hotel Sheraton in Dhaka, with Faiz Ahmed Taiyeb, Special Assistant to the Chief Adviser of the Ministry of Posts, Telecom</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 15:13:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>40th FOBANA Convention 2026 set for September 4–6 in Orlando, Florida</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/40th-fobana-convention-2026-set-for-september-4-6-in-orlando-florida</link><description>The 40th FOBANA Convention 2026 is scheduled to take place from September 4 to 6, 2026, at the Holiday Inn Resort, Orlando, Florida, USA. The announcement was made at a press conference held in Dhaka.
Organizers stated that the 40th FOBANA Convention, marking four decades of the Federation of Bang</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 15:28:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh firm on skipping India T20 World Cup</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-rules-out-playing-t20-world-cup-in-india-urges-icc-to-moves-matches-to-sri-lanka</link><description>Bangladesh will not reverse its decision to skip the T20 World Cup in India, youth and sports advisor Asif Nazrul had reiterated.
Speaking at a briefing at the Foreign Service Academy in Dhaka on Thursday, Nazrul said there was “no scope” for Bangladesh to step back from its position.</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 16:15:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BB asks bank officials to register for postal voting via ‘Postal Vote BD’ app</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bb-asks-bank-officials-to-register-for-postal-voting-via-postal-vote-bd-app</link><description>In a move to streamline the voting process for the upcoming 13th National Parliamentary Election and Referendum in 2026, Bangladesh Bank (BB) has issued a formal directive to all scheduled banks regarding the use of the “Postal Vote BD” app.
The central bank’s Banking Regulation</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 16:30:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat-led 11-party alliance announces candidates for 253 seats</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jamaat-led-11-party-alliance-announces-candidates-for-253-seats</link><description>The Jamaat-e-Islami-led 11-party electoral alliance has announced candidates for 253 parliamentary constituencies as part of a seat-sharing arrangement.
The announcement was made at a press conference held after 9pm on Thursday at the Institution of Diploma Engineers in Dhaka.
Speaking on behalf</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 17:04:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Russia destroys large energy facility in Kharkiv, mayor says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/russia-destroys-large-energy-facility-in-kharkiv-mayor-says</link><description>Russian forces have destroyed a large energy facility in Ukraine's second-biggest city Kharkiv, the mayor said on Thursday, the latest target of a winter air campaign by Moscow that has plunged millions of Ukrainians into darkness and cold.
Russia has attacked the power grid and other energy facil</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 17:19:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BPL strike: Cricketers soften stance with new demands</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/bpl-strike-cricketers-soften-stance-with-new-demands</link><description>Players have partially stepped back from their previous hardline demand for the immediate resignation of Bangladesh Cricket Board (BCB) Director M Najmul Islam.
Welcoming the board's decision to remove him as head of the Finance Committee, the cricketers say they will resume playing on Friday if t</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 17:34:53 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>