<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 18:25:50 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>NCP may still sign national consensus charter later: Religious Affairs Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ncp-may-still-sign-national-consensus-charter-later-religious-affairs-adviser</link><description>Religious Affairs Adviser Dr AFM Khalid Hossain on Friday said that the National Citizens’ Party (NCP) could still join the national consensus process even though it did not take part in the certificate signing ceremony.
He made the remarks while speaking to reporters after attending the Bud</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 16:24:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Apple clinches exclusive US media rights for F1 races under five-year deal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/apple-clinches-exclusive-us-media-rights-for-f1-races-under-five-year-deal</link><description>Apple has landed US broadcast rights to Formula 1 in a five-year deal that would help the tech giant bolster its streaming service with one of the country's fastest-growing sports, following the success of its Brad Pitt-starrer "F1: The Movie".
The two sides did not disclose the financial details</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 15:20:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh's journey to vaccine self-sufficiency</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/bangladeshs-journey-to-vaccine-self-sufficiency</link><description>For decades, the robust immunisation programs of Bangladesh, a cornerstone of its public health success, were entirely dependent on imported vaccines.  During the pandemic, this dependency often placed the nation in a vulnerable position, leading to supply shortages and subsequently delaying c</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 15:50:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cheap labour built the industry, can clean energy save it?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/reviews/cheap-labour-built-the-industry-can-clean-energy-save-it</link><description>More often than not, a T-shirt bought from countries like the United States of America (USA) and Australia will have a tag saying, "Made in Bangladesh", reflecting the position Bangladesh's RMG sector holds in the international market. The RMG sector contributes to 81 per cent of the country's expo</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 16:05:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Budding researchers put their merits on display</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/budding-researchers-put-their-merits-on-display</link><description>Tanim Asjad
 
All of them, students from schools, studying between classes seven and ten, and hailing from different parts of the country, gathered in Dhaka to present their research papers or concept notes. Though sound puzzling, their dedication was evident as they expressed various though</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 16:35:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Breaking the silence around ADHD</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/breaking-the-silence-around-adhd</link><description>Dedicating an entire month to a single issue demonstrates the profound seriousness of the cause. It recognises that a single day of lip service is not enough to cut through the noise and a longer effort is needed to make people truly pay attention. This is precisely why October has been designated</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 17:05:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Reining in defiant edible oil companies</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/reining-in-defiant-edible-oil-companies</link><description>Unilaterally announcing a fresh hike in edible oil prices last week, the refining companies have clearly defied the government's position on the issue as the Commerce Adviser on Tuesday last denied having approved any such price hike. This hike in oil prices has taken place exactly three weeks afte</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 17:20:20 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>