<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 16:28:26 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Bangladesh U17s power past Bahrain to make it four wins from four</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/bangladesh-u17s-power-past-bahrain-to-make-it-four-wins-from-four</link><description>Bangladesh have moved a step closer to the AFC U17 Asian Cup finals with a hard-earned 2–1 win over Bahrain, extending their perfect run to four victories from four matches in the qualifiers.
Playing on Friday at the Tongliang Long Stadium in China, Golam Rabbani Choton’s side delivere</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 13:30:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Airfare on Sylhet-Dhaka route revised following public outcry</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/airfare-on-sylhet-dhaka-route-revised-following-public-outcry</link><description>In response to widespread public criticism over high airfares on the Sylhet-Dhaka route, authorities have announced a revised fare structure, officials said on Friday.
According to a statement from the Sylhet Deputy Commissioner’s media cell, the revision aims to improve passenger services w</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 13:45:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Israeli raid in southern Syria leaves 13 dead</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/israeli-raid-in-southern-syria-leaves-13-dead-syrian-state-media-report</link><description>Thirteen people were killed in an Israeli raid in southern Syria on Friday, Syrian state media reported, with Damascus accusing Israel of a "criminal attack" in a village where Israel said its troops came under fire during an operation to arrest militants.
The Israeli military said six soldiers we</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 14:00:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fakhrul urges govt not to pass police, NGO laws hurriedly</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/fakhrul-urges-govt-not-to-pass-police-ngo-laws-hurriedly</link><description>BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir on Friday urged the interim government not to hurriedly pass two major laws, warning that such moves by a non-elected administration can obstruct the country’s democratic process.
In a statement, he said, “We have learned from reliable</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 14:15:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chief Adviser seeks prayers for Khaleda Zia’s recovery</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/chief-adviser-seeks-prayers-for-khaleda-zias-recovery</link><description>Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus has expressed deep concern over the current health condition of former Prime Minister and BNP Chairperson Begum Khaleda Zia and sought prayers from the nation for her quick recovery.
Professor Yunus has been regularly monitoring Khaleda Zia’s health upd</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 14:30:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two killed as bus hits truck on Dhaka-Chattogram highway</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/two-killed-as-bus-hits-truck-on-dhaka-chattogram-highway</link><description>Two people were killed and two others seriously injured Friday afternoon when a passenger bus collided with a truck carrying bricks on the Dhaka-Chattogram Highway in Daudkandi, Cumilla police said.
The accident occurred in the Hugulia area of Daudkandi while a Starline bus traveling toward Chatto</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 14:45:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Belarus leader visits Myanmar ahead of disputed election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/belarus-leader-visits-myanmar-ahead-of-disputed-election</link><description>Belarusian President Alexander Lukashenko arrived in Myanmar on a goodwill visit, state media reported Friday, becoming only the second foreign leader to set foot in the country since the military seized power in 2021.
The trip comes weeks before a national election widely dismissed by critics as</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 15:00:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shift 20pc of transport to rail, waterways to reduce road pressure: Fouzul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/shift-20pc-of-transport-to-rail-waterways-to-reduce-road-pressure-fouzul</link><description>Railways, Road Transport and Bridges Adviser Muhammad Fouzul Kabir Khan on Friday said traffic congestion cannot be solved simply by widening roads and at least 20 percent of passenger and goods transport should be shifted to rail and waterways to ease pressure on highways,.
He made the remarks at</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 15:01:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Attorney general for collective efforts to overcome judicial delays</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/attorney-general-for-collective-efforts-to-overcome-judicial-delays</link><description>Attorney General of Bangladesh Md Asaduzzaman emphasised the need for collective efforts to end the culture of delayed justice, saying that justice is undermined when justice is delayed.
He made the remarks while addressing the Sylhet District Bar Association’s annual dinner as the chief gue</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 15:16:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Detainee beaten to death inside Jamalpur jail</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/detainee-beaten-to-death-inside-jamalpur-jail</link><description>A detainee has been beaten to death inside Jamalpur District Jail.
Jail Superintendent Golam Dastagir said the detainee, 25-year-old Pagla Hazrat, was bludgeoned on the head while asleep early on Thursday.
He died on Friday morning at Dhaka Medical College Hospital.
Hazrat had been remanded in j</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 15:31:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat: Old politics won’t shape new Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-chief-shafiqur-says-new-bangladesh-wont-run-on-old-political-formula</link><description>Jamaat-e-Islami chief Shafiqur Rahman has called for a break from “old, stagnant” politics, saying Bangladesh must now move forward under a new formula.
On Friday, at a public rally in Dhaka’s Bhasantek, he noted that the people of the country “no longer want outdated, corr</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 15:46:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bogura-4 BNP candidate accused of forging undergraduate certificate</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bogura-4-bnp-candidate-accused-of-forging-undergraduate-certificate</link><description>BNP nominated candidate for Bogura-4 (Kahaloo-Nondigram) Md Mosharraf Hossain has been accused of forging an undergraduate certificate.
On Thursday afternoon, following a hearing, a Natore Court judge assigned the Police Bureau of Investigation (PBI) to investigate the case, according to Masud Ran</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 16:01:06 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>