<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 07:16:56 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>RHD facing challenges due to uncontrolled traffic hike</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rhd-facing-challenges-due-to-uncontrolled-traffic-hike</link><description>The Roads and Highways Department (RHD) is facing tremendous challenges in carrying out road development and maintenance work due to what its officials said 'uncontrolled increase in traffic with vehicles of different speeds and spaces'.
The state agency is facing pressure to manage 13 types of ve</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 05:39:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nobel laureate Chen Ning Yang dies at 103, Xinhua says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/nobel-laureate-chen-ning-yang-dies-at-103-xinhua-says</link><description>Chen Ning Yang, one of the world's most renowned physicists and a Nobel Prize winner, died at 103 of illness in Beijing on Oct 18, state news outlet Xinhua said on Saturday.
Born in eastern China's Hefei in Anhui province in 1922, Yang was a Chinese-American physicist who worked on statistical mec</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 04:15:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hamas aims to keep grip on Gaza security, senior official says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/hamas-aims-to-keep-grip-on-gaza-security-and-cant-commit-to-disarm-senior-official-says</link><description>Hamas intends to maintain security control in Gaza during an interim period, a senior Hamas official told Reuters, adding he could not commit to the group disarming - positions that reflect the difficulties facing US plans to secure an end to the war.
Hamas politburo member Mohammed Nazzal also sa</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 04:30:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IMF, World Bank members look at Gaza reconstruction, challenges ahead</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/imf-world-bank-members-look-at-gaza-reconstruction-challenges-ahead</link><description>Top finance officials from around the world this week underscored their willingness to help rebuild the Palestinian enclave of Gaza as the World Bank and United Nations worked to finalise a new cost estimate of $70 billion.
Members of the ministerial-level Development Committee that advises the Wo</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 04:45:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hungary to ensure Putin can enter country for Trump meeting in Budapest</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/hungary-to-ensure-putin-can-enter-country-for-trump-meeting-in-budapest</link><description>Hungary will ensure that Russian President Vladimir Putin can enter the country for a summit with US President Donald Trump planned in Budapest and return home afterwards, Hungary's Foreign Minister Peter Szijjarto said on Friday.
Trump agreed on Thursday to a second summit on the war in Ukraine t</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 05:00:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Samsung Electronics family to sell $1.2b stake amid share rally</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/samsung-electronics-family-to-sell-12b-stake-amid-share-rally</link><description>The mother and two sisters of Samsung Electronics Chairman Jay Y. Lee plan to sell some 1.73 trillion won ($1.22 billion) worth of shares in the South Korean tech firm, the company said in a regulatory filing.
The purpose of the sale of 17.7 million shares, or a 0.3 per cent stake in Samsung Elect</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 05:45:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>One to three low-pressure systems likely over Bay of Bengal this month</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/one-to-three-low-pressure-systems-likely-over-bay-of-bengal-this-month</link><description>One to three low-pressure systems are likely to develop over the Bay of Bengal in October, and one of them may intensify into a depression or a cyclone, according to the long-range weather forecast for October.
The forecast by the Bangladesh Meteorological Department, prepared after analysing regi</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 06:00:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EU hails 'July Charter' as a milestone in Bangladesh's political transition</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/eu-hails-july-charter-as-a-milestone-in-bangladeshs-political-transition</link><description>European Union (EU) Ambassador to Bangladesh Michael Miller has described the signing of the "July Charter" as a significant step toward political consensus and reform in Bangladesh, as the country advances toward national elections slated for early 2026.
"I was delighted to join the signing cerem</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 06:15:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Britain's Prince Andrew gives up title of Duke of York</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/britains-prince-andrew-gives-up-title-of-duke-of-york</link><description>Britain's Prince Andrew said on Friday he would give up using his title of Duke of York following years of criticism about his behaviour and connections to the late US sex offender Jeffrey Epstein.
The reputation of Andrew, the younger brother of King Charles and second son of the late Queen Eliza</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 06:30:16 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>