<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 04:28:36 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Crude bombs explode in front of Adviser Rizwana’s home</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crude-bombs-explode-in-front-of-adviser-rizwanas-home</link><description>Two crude bomb explosions occurred in front of the residence of Syeda Rizwana Hasan, Adviser to the Ministries of Environment, Forest and Climate Change, and Water Resources, in the Central Road area of the capital on Sunday night at around 9 pm. 
No casualties were reported.
Adviser Rizwana conf</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 18:14:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trinamool BNP leader Shamsher Mobin announces retirement from politics</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/trinamool-bnp-leader-shamsher-mobin-announces-retirement-from-politics</link><description>Shamsher Mobin Chowdhury, chairman of the Trinamool BNP, has announced his retirement from politics, reports bdnews24.com.
On Sunday night, he said, “I have fully retired from politics. I am now not involved in anything.”
Asked why he was stepping down, Mobin, who transitioned from di</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 18:29:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ominous shadow of joblessness, poverty</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/ominous-shadow-of-joblessness-poverty</link><description>That all is not well with the state of Bangladesh's economy is corroborated by several recently published local and international studies. Even though the government managed to stabilise the economy to a large extent from the mess it inherited, prolonged political uncertainty appears to be a major</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 19:15:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Automated bond utilisation permission mandatory for export industries</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/automated-bond-utilisation-permission-mandatory-for-export-industries</link><description>Using automated system is made mandatory for issuing utilisation permission (UP) for export-oriented industries from December 1, as allegations of misuse of duty-free facility galore.



The National Board of Revenue (NBR) announced the decision Sunday, after a meeting with leaders of the count</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 19:30:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>'New shipping hub to spur Bangladesh's export growth'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/new-shipping-hub-to-spur-bangladeshs-export-growth</link><description>A new shipping hub in sight at the Laldia Container Terminal (LCT) will help debottleneck Bangladesh's export growth and lower import costs, resulting in a trade boost, says the global chief executive of the foreign lessee.
"It's going to create a port that can go from the current size of about 30</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 01:21:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tribunal delivers verdict against Hasina today</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tribunal-delivers-verdict-against-hasina-today</link><description>Security bulwarks are built around the International Crimes Tribunal-1 in Dhaka which is set to deliver live its verdict today in the first uprising-time crimes-against-humanity case against ousted Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina and two of her top aides.
As tensions brew up amid some acts of violenc</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 01:36:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Child labour up 2.4 percentage points in 6 years: Survey</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/child-labour-up-24-percentage-points-in-6-years-survey</link><description>Bangladesh is witnessing a sharp rise in child labour, with 9.2 per cent of children aged 5-17 now engaged in work, up from 6.8 per cent in 2019, putting an additional 1.2 million children at risk of exploitation, hazardous work, and long-term setbacks, according to the preliminary findings of the</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 01:51:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Axle load limit setup for roads drags on</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/axle-load-limit-setup-for-roads-drags-on</link><description>There is scope for setting axle-load limits for roads and highways during the interim government's term, but no concrete steps have been taken yet, sources say.
If the limits are set, billions of taka spent on checking overload damage can be saved.
The Roads and Highways Department (RHD), respons</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 02:06:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Banks shift to short-term treasury bills</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/banks-shift-to-short-term-treasury-bills</link><description>Yields on treasury bills (T-bills) showed a mixed trend on Sunday as banks chose to invest their excess liquidity in lower-tenure securities rather than higher-tenure ones ahead of the national elections.
The cut-off yield, generally regarded as the interest rate, on the 91-day T-bills fell to 10.</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 02:21:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CVD Investigation On Jute Goods: India extends deadline for Bangladesh's questionnaire responses</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/cvd-investigation-on-jute-goods-india-extends-deadline-for-bangladeshs-questionnaire-responses</link><description>India has extended the deadline for Bangladesh to submit its questionnaire responses in the countervailing duty (CVD) investigation concerning the imports of jute goods from Bangladesh.
The Department of Commerce under the Indian Ministry of Commerce &amp; Industry issued a notification on November 12</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 02:36:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh Submarine Cables' Q1 profit surges on higher core business revenue</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh-submarine-cables-q1-profit-surges-on-higher-core-business-revenue</link><description>Bangladesh Submarine Cables declared a 42.1 per cent year-on-year surge in profits in the first quarter of FY26 to Tk 619.10 million as revenue from its core business increased.
According to the filing on Sunday, the state-owned Bangladeshi telecommunications company reported a rise in earnings pe</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 03:45:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Here's why T-bond yields are rising again</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/heres-why-t-bond-yields-are-rising-again</link><description>Yields on government securities (G-Secs) have again crossed 10 per cent as the government's appetite for fresh funds has increased ahead of the national polls scheduled for February this year.
The rise and fall of yields depend on the government's fund requirement to meet the budgetary shortfall a</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 04:00:52 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>