<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 07:38:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>CV screening realities: What HR actually looks for</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/youth-and-entrepreneurship/cv-screening-realities-what-hr-actually-looks-for</link><description>Your CV sits in a pile of 500 others. A recruiter has 23 hours to screen them all for a single position. That works out to roughly 2.76 minutes per application, though research indicates most spend six to seven seconds on initial scans. In those moments, they operate on a simple binary: highlights</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 04:00:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt moves to clean rivers and canals surrounding Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-moves-to-clean-rivers-and-canals-surrounding-dhaka</link><description>The interim government has taken up an initiative to clean rivers and canals surrounding Dhaka city as the World Bank (WB) is expected to provide US$370 million worth of fund shortly, officials said.
Under the move, eight relevant government agencies would get involved in cleaning the rivers aroun</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 04:15:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rising custodial deaths, mob violence to jeopardise July Uprising spirit</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rising-custodial-deaths-mob-violence-to-jeopardise-july-uprising-spirit</link><description>Speakers at a symposium on Saturday expressed concern that rising custodial deaths and incidents of mob violence during the regime of the interim government are putting the spirit of the July Uprising at risk.
They warned that if mob violence cannot be controlled, the situation may become critical</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 04:30:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prelim round of Chemistry Olympiad held at RU</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/prelim-round-of-chemistry-olympiad-held-at-ru</link><description>As in previous years, the preliminary round of the 15th Bangladesh Chemistry Olympiad 2026 for students of the Rajshahi region was held at Rajshahi University (RU), organised under the initiative of the Bangladesh Chemical Society.
The Department of Chemistry, University of Dhaka, and the Banglade</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 04:45:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hajj visa applications thru Nusak Masar to continue from Feb 8 until Mar 20</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hajj-visa-applications-thru-nusak-masar-to-continue-from-feb-8-until-mar-20</link><description>Bangladeshi intending Hajj 2026 pilgrims could submit their visa applications through Nusak Masar platform from February 8 until March 20 this year.
Nusak Masar is the official Saudi platform for booking Hajj packages, mandatory for international pilgrims to obtain visas.
Pilgrims must register,</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 05:00:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Voters in Gaibandha char areas demand a tangible plan, not lip service, to fight erosion</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/voters-in-gaibandha-char-areas-demand-a-tangible-plan-not-lip-service-to-fight-erosion</link><description>GAIBANDHA, Jan 31: Voters in the char (shoal) areas of Gaibandha district are demanding a tangible and sustainable plan to combat river erosion, turning down any empty promises by the electoral candidates.
Although commitments were made several times by the candidates during the past elections to</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 05:15:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump says Iran negotiating with US</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-says-iran-negotiating-with-us</link><description>US President Donald Trump said on Saturday that Iran is negotiating with the United States.
"The plan is that (Iran is) in talks with us, and we'll see whether anything can be achieved. Otherwise, we'll see what happens," Trump told a Fox News correspondent.
He said, "the last time they negotiate</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 05:30:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tourist travel to Saint Martin closed for 9 months from today</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tourist-travel-to-saint-martin-closed-for-9-months-from-today</link><description>Tourist travel to Saint Martin's Island, the country's only coral island in the Bay of Bengal, has been closed for nine consecutive months from February 1 following the end of the tourism season on January 31.
Although the government allowed tourists to visit the island for three months from Novem</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 05:45:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jailed murder suspect flees using identity of another inmate in Bramanbaria</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/jailed-murder-suspect-flees-using-identity-of-another-inmate-in-bramanbaria</link><description>A suspect in a murder case has allegedly escaped from Brahmanbaria District Jail using the bail papers of another inmate and committing “identity fraud”.
A case has been filed against the absconding suspect and several other inmates, while six prison guards have been temporarily susp</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 06:08:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Posters banned in electioneering, EC tightens rules on banner use</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/posters-banned-in-electioneering-ec-tightens-rules-on-banner-use</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has banned posters in electioneering and also imposed stricter controls on banners as part of its Code of Conduct for the 13th National Parliament Election and the Referendum scheduled for February 12.
The campaign period, which began on January 22, will end at midnigh</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 06:23:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP delegation in meeting with CEC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-delegation-in-meeting-with-cec</link><description>A BNP delegation, led by its Central Election Steering Committee Chairman Nazrul Islam Khan, is now in a meeting with Chief Election Commissioner AMM Nasir Uddin ahead of the national election scheduled for February 12 next.
The meeting started at around 12:00 pm at Nirbachan Bhaban in the city.</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 06:38:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>SC rulings dash election hopes of BNP's Munshi, Gafur as Mobasher stays in the race</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/sc-rulings-dash-election-hopes-of-bnps-munshi-gafur-as-mobasher-stays-in-the-race</link><description>The Supreme Court has rejected appeals by two Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) candidates seeking to contest upcoming parliamentary elections, while allowing another BNP nominee to remain in the race pending a final legal decision.
The rulings were delivered on Sunday by a five-member Appellate</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 06:53:33 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>