<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 14:19:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Historic July Charter signed</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/historic-july-charter-signed</link><description>The Historic July Charter was officially signed on Friday afternoon at the South Plaza of the Jatiya Sangsad Bhaban.
Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus and Vice President of the National Consensus Commission Professor Ali Riaz signed the charter, joined by several other political leaders.
Amo</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 11:55:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Zelensky to seek weapons from Trump in the shadow of a new Putin summit</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/zelensky-to-seek-weapons-from-trump-in-the-shadow-of-a-new-putin-summit</link><description>US President Donald Trump will discuss the possible supply of long-range Tomahawk missiles to Ukraine with President Volodymyr Zelensky on Friday but the surprise announcement of a new US-Russian summit cast doubt over the prospect.
Trump said on Thursday he may meet Russian President Vladimir Put</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 12:25:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two probe bodies formed over CEPZ building fire</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/two-probe-bodies-formed-over-cepz-building-fire</link><description>Two separate probe committees have been formed to investigate the devastating fire that broke out in a seven-storey building inside the Chattogram Export Processing Zone (CEPZ) area.
The fire, which started yesterday afternoon, was finally brought under control this morning after nearly 17 hours o</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 12:40:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>July Charter will be implemented soon: Ali Riaz</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ali-riaz-expresses-optimism-in-july-charters-swift-implementation</link><description>Ali Riaz, the vice-president of the National Consensus Commission, has expressed hope that the July National Charter, formulated through political consensus, will be implemented swiftly.
He said, “We understand that reform will not be achieved overnight, nor can a document alone guarantee su</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 11:58:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AmCham hosts session on Economic and Investment Outlook in Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/amcham-hosts-session-on-economic-and-investment-outlook-in-dhaka</link><description>The American Chamber of Commerce in Bangladesh (AmCham) hosted an engagement session on “AmCham Insights: Economic &amp; Investment Outlook”, on Thursday at the Sheraton in Dhaka.
Dr. Fahmida Khatun, Executive Director, Centre for Policy Dialogue (CPD), and Shah Mohammad Mahboob, Executive</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 12:13:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Salahuddin sees path to democracy through July Charter</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/salahuddin-sees-path-to-democracy-through-july-charter</link><description>BNP Standing Committee Member Salahuddin Ahmed on Friday expressed the hope that Bangladesh will be transformed into a democratic state through the implementation of the July National Charter.
Talking to reporters after attending the July Charter signing ceremony at the South Plaza of the Jatiya S</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 12:28:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>July Charter: Which political parties signed, which did not</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/july-charter-which-political-parties-signed-which-did-not</link><description>A total of 25 political parties have signed the July Charter, according to the Chief Adviser’s Press Wing, while several others have not.
Those who have signed did it at a ceremony at the South Plaza of the Jatiya Sangsad Bhaban in Dhaka city on Friday afternoon.
The parties that signed the</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 12:58:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat’s Shafiqur blasts interim govt over attack on ‘July warriors’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jamaats-shafiqur-blasts-interim-govt-over-attack-on-july-warriors</link><description>Jamaat-e-Islami chief Shafiqur Rahman has condemned the interim government after police allegedly attacked participants of the July Movement, describing the incident as “shameful” and “deeply painful”.
Speaking at a workers’ rally at Mirpur Dhaka on Friday, Shafiqur s</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 13:13:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Three sent to jail in Malibagh jewellery shop heist case</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/three-sent-to-jail-in-malibagh-jewellery-shop-heist-case</link><description>A court in Dhaka on Friday sent three people to jail in a case lodged over the sensational jewellery shop theft at Fortune Shopping Mall in Malibagh in the capital on October 8.
The three accused are Anita Roy, Md Nurul Islam, and Uttam Chandra Sur.
Dhaka Metropolitan Magistrate Mehera Mahbub pas</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 13:28:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Moyeen Khan urges inclusion of ‘July forerunners’ in Charter</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/moyeen-khan-urges-inclusion-of-july-forerunners-in-charter</link><description>BNP Standing Committee Member Dr Abdul Moyeen Khan on Friday stressed the need for including the ‘July forerunners’ in the July Charter to make it more meaningful.
In his reaction to the evolving situation over the signing of the Charter, he said the current situation is “complet</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 13:43:24 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>