<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 08:43:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>RUET holds int'l conf'ce on ECTE on January 29-31</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ruet-holds-intl-confce-on-ecte-on-january-29-31</link><description>RAJSHAHI, Jan 29: The 5th International Conference on Electrical, Computer and Telecommunication Engineering (ICECTE 2026) started at the Rajshahi University of Engineering and Technology (RUET) auditorium on Thursday. The Faculty of Electrical and Computer Engineering (ECE) is organising the confe</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 05:00:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DUCSU protests killing of Sherpur Jamaat leader</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ducsu-protests-killing-of-sherpur-jamaat-leader</link><description>The Dhaka University Central Students' Union (DUCSU) staged a protest march at Dhaka University on Wednesday night, condemning the killing of a Jamaat-e-Islami leader in Sherpur and demanding justice for the ongoing election-related violence across the country.
The protest was organised in respons</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 05:15:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Expansion, diversification drive Olympic Industries' record Q2 profit</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/expansion-diversification-drive-olympic-industries-record-q2-profit</link><description>Olympic Industries secured the highest quarterly profit of Tk 625 million in the second quarter of FY26, driven by higher sales amid capacity expansion and product portfolio diversification.
The branded biscuit manufacturer sustained its growth momentum, supported by newly introduced chocolate and</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 05:30:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UK lawmaker Blackman questions Bangladesh election credibility</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/uk-lawmaker-blackman-questions-bangladesh-election-credibility</link><description>Robert John Blackman CBE MP, a senior British parliamentarian and member of parliament for Harrow East, has expressed concern over recent political developments in Bangladesh, warning that democratic stability and the rule of law could be at risk if elections are not inclusive and credible.
Blackm</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 05:45:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Square Pharma's Q2 profit rises on higher sales, subsidiary income</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/square-pharmas-q2-profit-rises-on-higher-sales-subsidiary-income</link><description>Square Pharmaceuticals posted double-digit year-on-year profit growth to Tk 7.27 billion in the second quarter of FY26, fueled by higher sales and substantial income from subsidiaries.
The 10 per cent year-on-year growth in earnings in the October-December quarter of FY26 pushed up the EPS of the</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 06:00:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Policy shift boosts Submarine Cables' Q2 profit</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/policy-shift-boosts-submarine-cables-q2-profit</link><description>Bangladesh Submarine Cables recorded a remarkable 80 per cent rise in profit to Tk 780.85 million in the second quarter of FY26, as revenue surged by more than 30 per cent compared with the same quarter a year earlier.
According to the company, the strong earnings growth was driven by a policy shi</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 06:15:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh elected Vice Chair of UN Peacebuilding Commission for 2026</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-elected-vice-chair-of-un-peacebuilding-commission-for-2026</link><description>Bangladesh has been elected as the Vice-Chair of the UN Peacebuilding Commission (PBC) for the year 2026.
The election of the five-member bureau of the PBC was held at the UN Headquarters in New York on Thursday, reports UNB. 
The members of the Commission during its first meeting of the 20t</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 06:30:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cooperation between Bangladesh and China must go on, chief adviser says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cooperation-between-bangladesh-and-china-must-go-on-chief-adviser-says</link><description>A delegation of the China-Bangladesh Partnership Forum has met Chief Adviser Muhammad Yunus at the State Guest House Jamuna.
The delegation included senior Chinese academics, investors, and industry leaders from the biomedical, infrastructure, digital, and legal sectors.
Xin-yuan Fu, a leading Ch</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 06:47:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Body of missing poultry farmer recovered in Narsingdi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/body-of-missing-poultry-farmer-recovered-in-narsingdi</link><description>The body of a poultry businessman was recovered from a pond in Nager Bazar area of Belabo upazila on Thursday night, three days after he went missing.
The deceased was identified as Azimul Qader Bhuiya, 45, from Raghab village of Bajnabaup union.
Belabo Police Station’s Inspector (Inv</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 07:02:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat pledges business protection, end to red tape and extortion</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-pledges-business-protection-end-to-red-tape-and-extortion</link><description>Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami has pledged to protect businesses and eliminate bureaucratic red tape and extortion if it comes to power, party Ameer Dr Shafiqur Rahman said at a dialogue with business leaders held ahead of the national election.
The dialogue, titled "Strategic Thoughts for Industry an</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 07:17:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt paves way to compensation for victims of enforced disappearances, torture</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-paves-way-to-compensation-for-victims-of-enforced-disappearances-torture</link><description>The interim government has taken a key step towards allowing compensation and rehabilitation for victims of torture and enforced disappearance by withdrawing a long-standing declaration linked to a United Nations anti-torture treaty.
The decision, approved on Thursday at a meeting of the Advisory</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 07:32:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Navy member dies in Ctg road crash</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/navy-member-killed-as-bus-hits-motorcycle-in-chattograms-patiya</link><description>A member of the Bangladesh Navy has been killed and another injured after a bus hit their motorcycle in Chattogram's Patiya.
The accident happened on Friday at the Patiya bypass on the Chattogram–Cox’s Bazar Highway, according to police.
The dead man was identified as 38-year-old Nazm</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 08:33:10 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>