<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 11:18:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Non-resident Air Attache of Japan calls on Principal Staff Officer  of Armed Forces Division (AFD)</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/non-resident-air-attache-of-japan-calls-on-principal-staff-officer-of-armed-forces-division-afd</link><description>Tomo Aoyama, General Manger, Mitsubishi Electric, Japan &amp; Non-resident Air Attache of Japan Colonel Yasumura Masashi made a courtesy ‘Call On’ the Principal Staff Officer (PSO) of Bangladesh Armed Forces Division (AFD) Lieutenant General S M Kamrul Hassan on Wednesday at Dhaka Cantonmen</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 08:33:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Don’t want ‘questionable officials’ involved in polls: BNP</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dont-want-questionable-officials-involved-in-polls-bnps-moyeen-tells-ec</link><description>The BNP does not want “questionable and controversial officials” in charge of polling duties in the next election, and they have asked the Election Commission to be cautious of the issue, says Abdul Moyeen Khan, a member of the party's National Standing Committee.
He informed reporters</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 08:48:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>China ready to partner with Bangladesh for green growth: Ambassador Yao</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/china-ready-to-partner-with-bangladesh-for-green-growth-ambassador-yao</link><description>Highlighting the importance of green development, Chinese Ambassador to Bangladesh Yao Wen on Thursday said China stands ready to work with all countries, including Bangladesh, to build a more open, inclusive and mutually beneficial global economy, so that the fruits of cooperation can benefit peop</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 09:03:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>6 burnt as man uses petrol to set fire to family</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/6-burnt-as-man-uses-petrol-to-set-fire-to-family</link><description>A man has used petrol to set a fire in Narsingdi Sadar Upazila, leading to burn injuries of six members of his family, including his wife and children.
Three of the victims have been admitted to Dhaka’s National Institute of Burn and Plastic Surgery, with two in critical condition.
Shawon B</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 09:18:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Another low likely to form over Bay of Bengal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/another-low-likely-to-form-over-bay-of-bengal</link><description>The Bangladesh Meteorological Department (BMD) has forecast the formation of another low-pressure area over the southern Bay of Bengal and adjoining regions within the next 24 hours.
According to the BMD, the well-marked low over the southwest Bay and adjoining regions moved west-northwestwards an</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 09:33:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>China trade spat threatens Wisconsin's 'Napa Valley' of ginseng</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/china-trade-spat-threatens-wisconsins-napa-valley-of-ginseng</link><description>The cool woodlands of central Wisconsin boast soils packed with Ice Age mineral deposits that make the area perfect for the cultivation of ginseng, a medicinal root that has been exported to Asia for more than 300 years.
Sliced and used in tea or ground into capsules, ginseng root is touted as an</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 09:48:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump’s shutdown pay plan prioritises security personnel over civilian workers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trumps-shutdown-pay-plan-prioritises-security-personnel-over-civilian-workers</link><description>President Donald Trump has ensured that federal immigration agents, US Border Patrol officers, FBI special agents and active-duty military personnel continue receiving paychecks during the government shutdown, even as hundreds of thousands of civilian federal workers are furloughed or are working w</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 10:18:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>I apologise for any mistakes made, says Jamaat chief Shafiqur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/i-apologise-for-any-mistakes-made-says-jamaat-chief-shafiqur</link><description>Jamaat-e-Islami Ameer Shafiqur Rahman has said the party is offering an unconditional apology not only for its role in 1971, but also for any “mistake” it has made since the Partition of India in 1947, according to bdnews24.com.
He clarified the party’s current political stance d</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 10:33:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fareast Insurance former chairman booked for Tk 2.07b embezzlement</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/fareast-insurance-former-chairman-booked-for-tk-207b-embezzlement</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) had arrested Md Nazrul Islam, former Chairman of Faireast Islami Life Insurance Company Ltd, from the city's Banshal area on Thursday.
The arrest relates to a case of embezzlement totalling Tk 2.07 billion.
According to the ACC, while serving as chairman, Nazr</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 11:03:53 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>