<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 08:34:46 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Zaber &amp; Zubair displays spring-summer '27 collection</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/zaber-zubair-displays-spring-summer-27-collection</link><description>Zaber &amp; Zubair Fabrics Limited, a global leader in sustainable and innovative textile solutions, has started the 17th edition of its signature Fabric Week, showcasing its innovation and product development for the upcoming Spring-Summer 2027 season.
The six-day expo began on Tuesday morning at the</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 05:28:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Winter redefines Dhaka's appetite</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/winter-redefines-dhakas-appetite</link><description>After sunset, the gates of the National Zoo and the Botanical Garden close to visitors. Inside, the paths fall quiet. Outside, the evening begins.
In front of the darkened entrances, carts line the roadside. Charcoal fires glow under aluminum pots, and steam rises into the winter air. People gathe</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 05:43:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No visa fee for foreign election observers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/no-visa-fee-for-foreign-election-observers</link><description>The government has decided to waive visa fees for foreign observers monitoring the 13th national election.
The Ministry of Home Affairs issued a circular on Monday regarding visa on arrival and other visa-related matters for foreign nationals, saying the waiver will be granted based on recommendat</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 05:58:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>What DITF offers to the buyers and sellers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/what-ditf-offers-to-the-buyers-and-sellers</link><description>Mr Sanjoy, 26, claims to be Indian and works as a shoe seller at a shop named 'Indian Footwear' at the Dhaka International Trade Fair (DITF). Although his shop offers various types of shoes, the first thing buyers notice is his persistent attempt to speak Hindi, from bargaining to every small detai</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 06:13:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>At least 2,571 killed in Iran's protests: US-based rights group</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/at-least-2571-killed-in-irans-protests-us-based-rights-group-hrana-says</link><description>The death toll from protests in Iran has reached 2,571 people, the US-based HRANA rights group said on Wednesday, as the Islamic Republic's clerical rulers face the biggest wave of dissent in years.
US President Donald Trump urged Iranians on Tuesday to keep protesting, promising help is on the wa</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 06:28:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>22 killed as crane collapses onto train in Thailand</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/22-killed-as-crane-collapses-onto-train-in-thailand</link><description>At least 22 people have been killed and dozens injured after a construction crane fell on a passenger train in northeastern Thailand on Wednesday.
The accident took place in Nakhon Ratchasima province, north of the capital Bangkok in the morning, officials said.
The death toll is expected to rise</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 06:43:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>2025 was 3rd-warmest year on record: Scientists</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/2025-was-3rd-warmest-year-on-record-scientists</link><description>The planet experienced its third-warmest year on record in 2025, and average temperatures have exceeded 1.5 degrees Celsius of global warming over three years, the longest period since records began, EU scientists said on Wednesday.
The data from the European Union's European Centre for Medium-Ran</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 06:58:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>50th BCS preliminary exam on Jan 30</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/50th-bcs-preliminary-exam-on-jan-30</link><description>The preliminary test for the 50th Bangladesh Civil Service examination is to be held on Friday, Jan 30. The Public Service Commission (PSC) announced that the exam will be held in eight divisional cities from 10 am to noon that day.
The date was announced in a press release on Tuesday.
Although t</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 07:13:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>More than 50 workers fall sick at Tongi RMG factory</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/more-than-50-workers-fall-sick-at-tongi-rmg-factory</link><description>More than 50 workers of Garments Export Village Limited in Tongi fell ill on Wednesday, prompting panic at the factory.
The affected workers, from two factories located in Ma Tower and Alam Tower of the industrial complex, were taken to nearby hospitals after falling sick one after another.
Most</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 07:28:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bancharampur UNO Ferdous Ara passes away</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bancharampur-uno-ferdous-ara-passes-away</link><description>Ferdous Ara, Upazila Nirbahi Officer (UNO) of Bancharampur upazila in Brahmanbaria, died on Wednesday at a hospital in Dhaka.
She breathed her last around 7:00 am, said Additional Deputy Commissioner (General) Ranjan Chandra Dey.
He said Ferdous Ara fell sick on Monday and was admitted to a hospi</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 08:00:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>FIFA World Cup trophy arrives in Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/fifa-world-cup-trophy-arrives-in-dhaka</link><description>The glittering FIFA World Cup trophy arrived in Dhaka on Wednesday morning as part of the FIFA World Cup Trophy Tour.
The trophy, accompanied by Brazilian 2002 FIFA World Cup winner and FIFA ambassador Gilberto da Silva, landed at Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport around 10:00 am.
Tabith Moh</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 08:15:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Elections will be held on Feb 12, CA reaffirms US diplomats</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/elections-will-be-held-on-feb-12-ca-reaffirms-us-diplomats</link><description>Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus has reaffirmed his government’s commitment to hold the general elections and the referendum as scheduled on February 12.
The chief adviser made the remarks when two former senior United States diplomats—Albert Gombis and Morse Tan, both of whom se</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 08:30:42 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>