<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 14:40:54 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Amar Ekushey: Nation to pay tribute to language martyrs at zero hour</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/amar-ekushey-nation-to-pay-tribute-to-language-martyrs-at-zero-hour</link><description>The nation is set to observe ‘Amar Ekushey’, the Language Martyr’s Day and the International Mother Language Day early Saturday, marking the supreme sacrifice of the language heroes for upholding the dignity of the mother tongue, Bangla.
The day will also be observed around the w</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 12:11:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>President for being more mindful in preserving quality, dignity of Bangla</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/president-for-being-more-mindful-in-preserving-quality-dignity-of-bangla</link><description>President Mohammed Shahabuddin urged all the Bangla-speaking people to be ever more mindful in its proper practice and in preserving its quality and dignity.
“Language is the foremost custodian and carrier of a nation’s existence, heritage, and culture . . . As Bangla was earned throug</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 12:26:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat chief to visit Shaheed Minar for the first time</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jamaat-chief-to-visit-shaheed-minar-for-the-first-time</link><description>Jamaat-e-Islami chief and Leader of the Opposition Shafiqur Rahman has announced his plan to visit the Central Shaheed Minar on International Mother Language Day, marking a first for the party chief.
While the party's student front Bangladesh Islami Chhatra Shibir has traditionally held rallies an</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 12:41:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>PM for collective efforts to uphold, protect dignity of languages worldwide</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/pm-for-collective-efforts-to-uphold-protect-dignity-of-languages-worldwide</link><description>Prime Minister Tarique Rahman on Friday called upon all concerned to work collectively to uphold and protect the dignity of languages worldwide.
“Let us preserve the linguistic diversity within our country, safeguard our unique culture and heritage, and ensure the proper use and cultivation</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 11:44:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Food aid in Somalia could halt within weeks due to funding shortages, WFP warns</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/africa/food-aid-in-somalia-could-halt-within-weeks-due-to-funding-shortages-wfp-warns</link><description>The UN World Food Programme said on Friday its life-saving food and nutrition assistance in Somalia could grind to a halt by April unless new funding is secured, putting millions of people at risk of worsening hunger.
An estimated 4.4 million people face crisis-level food insecurity, with nearly o</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 11:59:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Eight feared dead after a bus with Chinese tourists sinks into Russia's Lake Baikal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/eight-feared-dead-after-a-bus-with-chinese-tourists-sinks-into-russias-lake-baikal</link><description>Seven Chinese tourists and a bus driver are feared dead after a tourist bus driving across a frozen stretch of Lake Baikal in Russia's Siberia plunged into the water when the ice broke beneath it, local governor, Igor Kobzev, said on Friday via his channel in Telegram.
One tourist managed to escap</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 12:14:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ex-Biman MD sent to jail in housemaid assault case</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ex-biman-md-sent-to-jail-in-housemaid-assault-case</link><description>A Dhaka court on Friday sent former Managing Director of Biman Bangladesh Airlines, Dr Md Shafiqur Rahman, to jail in a case filed over the alleged assault of his 11-year-old housemaid.
Dhaka Metropolitan Magistrate Alberuni Mir passed the order in the afternoon. Another accused, housemaid Sufia B</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 12:29:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>TIB slates transport minister for toll remarks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tib-rebukes-minister-over-claim-consensual-roadside-collections-are-not-extortion</link><description>Transparency International Bangladesh (TIB) has criticised the transport minister’s description of roadside collections as “compromise-based transactions”, calling it an “attempt to legitimise a serious criminal offence”.
In a statement issued on Friday, the local cha</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 12:44:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Family card’ rollout before Eid: relief minister</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/family-card-scheme-will-launch-before-eid-ul-fitr-says-minister-dulu</link><description>The government will introduce the “family card” programme before Eid ul-Fitr, according to Disaster Management and Relief Minister Asadul Habib Dulu.
The distribution will begin as a pilot project in eight Upazilas, prioritising the poorest households, he said on Friday afternoon in La</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 12:59:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Delhi seeks ‘stronger’ ties with Dhaka: Jaiswal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/india-looks-to-strengthen-multifaceted-relations-with-bangladesh-says-jaiswal</link><description>India has voiced its expectation of strengthening its “multifaceted” relationship with Bangladesh.
At a weekly briefing on Friday, Ministry of External Affairs spokesperson Randhir Jaiswal said Prime Minister Narendra Modi congratulated Bangladesh Prime Minister Tarique Rahman soon aft</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 13:14:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Finance minister pledges ‘revolutionary’ shift in economy, stock market</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/finance-minister-pledges-revolutionary-shift-in-economy-stock-market</link><description>Finance and Planning Minister Amir Khosru Mahmud Chowdhury on Friday pledged sweeping changes to the country’s economy and capital markets, vowing that a 'revolutionary transformation' is on the way.
Talking to reporters at Shah Amanat International Airport as he arrived in Chattogram after</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 13:29:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Police search royal mansion as investigation into king’s brother goes on</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/police-search-royal-mansion-as-investigation-into-kings-brother-goes-on</link><description>British police were searching the former mansion of King Charles’ younger brother Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor on Friday after a photograph of the royal emerging from a police station was splashed on newspapers around the world.
Mountbatten-Windsor was arrested on Thursday, his 66th birthday,</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 13:44:30 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>