<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 06:38:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>BR still lacks fit execution plan for decade-old policy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/br-still-lacks-fit-execution-plan-for-decade-old-policy</link><description>Bangladesh Railway (BR) has yet to formulate a comprehensive plan to incorporate electric traction in its upcoming development projects, despite a policy-level decision made a decade ago.
While over 70 countries have shifted to electric train services, BR remains limited to a few specialised proje</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 02:23:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Attackers on Prothom Alo, Daily Star identified</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/attackers-on-prothom-alo-daily-star-identified</link><description>Religious Affairs Adviser AFM Khalid Hossain on Sunday said the identities of several individuals involved in the recent arson attacks on Prothom Alo and The Daily Star have been identified and steps are underway to bring them to justice.
Speaking to reporters at the Bangladesh Secretariat, he sai</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 02:38:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NBR chief hints at further extending return submission deadline</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/nbr-chief-hints-at-further-extending-return-submission-deadline</link><description>National Board of Revenue (NBR) Chairman Abdur Rahman Khan has hinted at the possibility of further extension of income-tax return-submission deadline, as many registered taxpayers are yet to file their returns digitally.
Speaking about the possible extension, Mr. Khan mentioned that the NBR would</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 02:53:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BB buys more US dollars to support taka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/bb-buys-more-us-dollars-to-support-taka</link><description>The central bank purchased an additional US$60 million from four banks through an auction on the interbank spot market on Sunday, aiming to keep the exchange rate of the US dollar against the taka stable.
The amount was bought under the multiple price auction method, with a cut-off rate of Tk 122.</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 03:08:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Longer-term T-bill yields edge higher</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/longer-term-t-bill-yields-edge-higher</link><description>Yields on longer-term treasury bills (T-bills) edged up on Sunday as banks remained reluctant to lock in excess liquidity ahead of the year-end closing and the upcoming national election.
The cut-off yield, or interest rate, on the 182-day T-bills rose to 10.65 per cent from 10.57 per cent at the</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 03:23:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Why BSRM remains profitable while GPH Ispat slips into losses amid adversities</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/why-bsrm-remains-profitable-while-gph-ispat-slips-into-losses-amid-adversities</link><description>Economies of scale are helping Bangladesh Steel Re-Rolling Mills (BSRM) make profits during a tough period of sluggish market demand, while GPH Ispat has slipped into the red.
The steel industry navigated one of its toughest phases in FY25 as construction in both the public and private sectors fac</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 03:38:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka bourse dips to one-month low amid rising political tension</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/dhaka-bourse-dips-to-one-month-low-amid-rising-political-tension</link><description>The benchmark index of the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) fell to a one-month low on Sunday as jittery investors continued selling amid growing political concerns.
Market analysts said investor sentiment had already been fragile following the merger of five banks and the move to liquidate nine non-ban</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 03:53:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC extends deadline for election observers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ec-extends-deadline-for-election-observers</link><description>The Bangladesh Election Commission (EC) has extended the deadline for submitting applications to deploy local election observers until December 29, ahead of the 13th National Election and referendum.
The decision was taken in response to requests from election observer agencies seeking more time t</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 04:59:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>WASH funding gaps undermine service sustainability</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/wash-funding-gaps-undermine-service-sustainability</link><description>Bangladesh has achieved near-universal coverage of improved water sources in schools and healthcare facilities, but a new national survey reveals deep structural weaknesses that threaten the sustainability of these gains.
Only a small fraction of institutions allocate dedicated funds to maintain w</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 05:14:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt urged to step up public security as violence escalates</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-urged-to-step-up-public-security-as-violence-escalates</link><description>Speakers at a roundtable called on the government to take urgent measures to ensure public safety amid a worsening law and order situation in the capital and across the country.
Referring to the recent shooting of Inqilab Moncho spokesperson Sharif Osman Hadi in broad daylight and other violent in</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 05:29:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DU JCD protests mob violence</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/du-jcd-protests-mob-violence</link><description>Dhaka University (DU) unit of Jatiyatabadi Chhatra Dal (JCD) organised a rally on Sunday, protesting mob violence across the country, including the brutal murder of Dipu Chandra Dash in Mymensingh and the tragic death of 7-year-old Ayesha in a fire in Lakshmipur. The rally began at 12:45 pm from th</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 05:44:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DU Science Unit admission test Dec 27</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/du-science-unit-admission-test-dec-27</link><description>The undergraduate admission test of the Dhaka University's (DU) Science Unit for the 2025-26 session, previously suspended due to the national mourning, will now be held on December 27, from 3:30 PM to 5:00 PM.
A press release, issued by the DU Public Relations Office on Sunday, announced the new</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 05:59:16 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>