<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 16:46:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Three to die for killing woman over dowry in Barguna</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/three-to-die-for-killing-woman-over-dowry-in-barguna</link><description>A Barguna court has sentenced three people to death for murdering a housewife in Pathorghata Upazila over dowry demands.
The verdict was delivered on Tuesday by Judge Begum Lailatul Ferdous of Barguna’s Women and Children Repression Prevention Tribunal, said Public Prosecutor Ronjuara Sipu.</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 13:44:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique urges teachers to back BNP for reform-focused govt</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-urges-teachers-to-back-bnp-for-reform-focused-govt</link><description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman on Tuesday urged teachers to extend their support to BNP in the upcoming national election so that the party can form a government to build a knowledge and merit-based state and implement its plans for national and political reforms.
“To implement all the p</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 13:59:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Next TV, Live TV receive broadcast licenses under interim government</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/next-tv-live-tv-receive-broadcast-licenses-under-interim-government</link><description>For the first time under the interim government, two news-based television stations have been granted broadcasting licenses.
The stations, named Next TV and Live TV, are linked to prominent figures from the National Citizen Party (NCP) and the National Citizens’ Committee, bdnews24.com repor</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 14:29:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BGB detains 24 in Sherpur for attempting ‘illegal’ border crossing into India</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bgb-detains-24-in-sherpur-for-attempting-illegal-border-crossing-into-india</link><description>The Border Guard Bangladesh (BGB) has detained 24 people, allegedly attempting to illegally enter India through the Jhenaigati border in Sherpur.
They were detained around 9:30pm on Monday under the Haldigram Border Outpost, said Lieutenant Colonel Mehedi Hasan, captain of BGB Battalion-39 in Myme</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 14:44:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Abrar Fahad's legacy rebuilt: 'Eight Pillars Against Aggression' inaugurated</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/abrar-fahads-legacy-rebuilt-eight-pillars-against-aggression-inaugurated</link><description>The legacy of BUET student Abrar Fahad was honoured today as the 'Eight Pillars Against Aggression' memorial was rebuilt and inaugurated today (Tuesday) at the Palashi intersection, six years after it was demolished by fascist forces.
The memorial commemorates Abrar Fahad, who was beaten to death</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 14:22:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ACC prosecutes NBR member Belal on charges of ‘illicit wealth’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/acc-prosecutes-nbr-member-belal-on-charges-of-illicit-wealth</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission has filed a case against Mohammad Belal Hossain Chowdhury, a member of the National Board of Revenue, on charges of acquiring assets “beyond known means of income” of around Tk 50 million and "concealing the information".
ACC Director General Akhter Hossa</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 14:52:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pilgrims can register for Hajj 2026 with expired passports: Ministry</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/pilgrims-can-register-for-hajj-2026-with-expired-passports-ministry</link><description>The Ministry of Religious Affairs has announced that pilgrims will be allowed to register for Hajj 2026 using expired passports, in a move aimed at easing the registration process.
The Hajj-1 branch of the ministry issued a letter in this regard on Tuesday.
According to the letter, the decision w</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 15:07:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Salahuddin urges BNP leaders to compete in politics with talent, honesty</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/salahuddin-urges-bnp-leaders-to-compete-in-politics-with-talent-honesty</link><description>BNP Standing Committee Member Salahuddin Ahmed urged the party leaders and workers to compete in the political field with talent, honesty and good leadership.
He made the call at a discussion organized by Chhatra Dal to mark the sixth death anniversary of BUET student Abrar Fahad at the Teacher-St</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 15:22:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Quake of magnitude 6.6 shakes Lae city in Papua New Guinea</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/quake-of-magnitude-66-shakes-lae-city-in-papua-new-guinea</link><description>An earthquake of magnitude 6.6 struck near Papua New Guinea's second largest city Lae on Tuesday, the US Geological Survey said, terrifying mourners in a stadium but with no damage immediately reported.
The epicentre was 26 km (16 miles) from Lae, which has a population of over 76,000, according t</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 15:52:23 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>