<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 04:54:41 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>ECNEC formed with PM Tarique Rahman as Chairperson</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/ecnec-formed-with-pm-tarique-rahman-as-chairperson</link><description>The government has formed the Executive Committee of the National Economic Council (ECNEC) with Prime Minister Tarique Rahman as its chairperson.
The committee was constituted through a gazette notification issued on Tuesday. The notification was signed by Md. Humayun Kabir, Additional Secretary (</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 18:14:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cost of 65 dev projects ramped up by Tk 798.34b</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/cost-of-65-dev-projects-ramped-up-by-tk-79834b</link><description>Costs of 65 projects have been ramped up by Tk 798.34 billion in apparent prodigal reappraisals of the development schemes by the just-gone interim government during its one-and-a-half-year tenure, sources say.



The projects, originally undertaken at a combined cost of Tk 2.24 trillion, were</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 19:16:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh rethinking deal after blanket 10pc US tariffs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladesh-rethinking-deal-after-blanket-10pc-us-tariffs</link><description>Bangladesh begins rethink on the deal signed with the United States as President Donald Trump lately imposed an across-the-board 10-percent tariff on all goods not covered by exemptions.
Reacting to the Supreme Court ruling invalidating his most sweeping duties, the US President announced a new te</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 02:23:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Forex reserves cross $35b ahead of Eid</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/forex-reserves-cross-35b-ahead-of-eid</link><description>Bangladesh's gross foreign- exchange reserves surpassed the $35-billion mark on Tuesday, supported by sustained US dollar purchases by the central bank amid stronger remittance inflows ahead of Eid-ul-Fitr.
Officials said the interventions are aimed at stabilising the dollar-taka exchange rate whi</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 01:55:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP faces uphill task in health sector</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/bnp-faces-uphill-task-in-health-sector</link><description>As the new BNP-led government assumes office and ministers take charge, public health experts say revitalising an almost stagnant health division will be one of its most urgent challenges.
Years of underfunding, weak governance and disrupted services have left the sector struggling to meet growing</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 02:10:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Probe launched into Associated Oxygen's alleged IPO malpractices</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/probe-launched-into-associated-oxygens-alleged-ipo-malpractices</link><description>The market regulator has begun an investigation into Associated Oxygen over alleged irregularities in its initial public offering (IPO) application.
A group led by Kazi Saifur Rahman of NRB Equity Management and controversial ex-NBR official Matiur Rahman had reportedly committed serious fraud, in</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 02:25:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dominage Steel rallies 120pc despite losses, factory shutdown</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/dominage-steel-rallies-120pc-despite-losses-factory-shutdown</link><description>Dominage Steel Building Systems has continued its unabated rally despite having a significantly negative P/E (price-to-earnings) ratio and one of its factory units being shut down.
The company's stock price jumped 120 per cent to Tk 36.70 a share between September 22 last year and February 24 this</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 02:40:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh loses top spot in global shipbreaking</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladesh-loses-top-spot-in-global-shipbreaking-as-imports-of-scrapped-vessels-drop-32pc</link><description>Bangladesh lost its position as the world's top shipbreaking destination in 2025 as imports of scrapped vessels declined by over 32 per cent amid regulatory pressures, economic challenges and stricter international standards.
According to data released by the NGO Shipbreaking Platform (NSP), Bangl</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 02:55:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Haor farmers fear crop loss as work misses deadline</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/haor-farmers-fear-crop-loss-as-work-misses-deadline</link><description>With about 700,000 haor farmers' livelihoods dependent on Boro paddy yield in the Sylhet division, slow progress in developing embankments for crop protection in Sunamganj, Habiganj and Sylhet districts has stirred worries of rain interruption, which would make the works slower. Rainfall will compl</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 03:10:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Garment exporters urge BB governor to release funds from export incentives</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/garment-exporters-urge-bb-governor-to-release-funds-from-export-incentives</link><description>Apparel manufacturers have requested the Bangladesh Bank (BB) governor to release funds from export incentives to facilitate the payment of employee salaries and bonuses ahead of Eid-ul-Fitr.
Leaders of the Bangladesh Garment Manufacturers and Exporters Association (BGMEA) made the request to Dr A</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 03:25:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt moves to revive ‘dead’ stretch of Buriganga through Ati Khal excavation plan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/govt-moves-to-revive-dead-stretch-of-buriganga-through-ati-khal-excavation-plan</link><description>The government has taken an initiative to recover and rejuvenate Ati Khal, a canal locally known as a “dead stretch” of the Buriganga River, in Keraniganj on the outskirts of Dhaka.
The move aims to restore drainage capacity, revive inland navigation and improve the local environment t</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 04:11:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCP calls BNP-linked city corporation administrator appointments ‘abuse of power’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ncp-calls-bnp-linked-city-corporation-administrator-appointments-abuse-of-power</link><description>The National Citizen Party (NCP) has described the appointment of BNP-backed administrators in six city corporations as “an abuse of power”, warning that the move could undermine a level playing field ahead of local government elections.
The party also questioned the government’s</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 04:26:53 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>