<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 08:28:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Dhaka CMM court magistrate suspended over graft allegations</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dhaka-cmm-court-magistrate-suspended-over-graft-allegations</link><description>Dhaka’s Chief Metropolitan Magistrate (CMM) Rezaul Karim Chowdhury has been suspended after the allegations of corruption against him surfaced.
The matter of the suspension came to light on Monday, though the Ministry of Law and Justice issued a notification regarding the action on September</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 04:54:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>76pc women in Bangladesh face intimate partner violence: BBS, UNFPA survey</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/76pc-women-in-bangladesh-face-intimate-partner-violence-bbs-unfpa-survey</link><description>Nearly 76 per cent of women in Bangladesh have experienced violence by an intimate partner at some point in their lives, according to a survey.
The survey titled ‘Bangladesh Bureau of Statistics (BBS) and UNFPA’s latest Violence Against Women (VAW) 2024 survey’ was released on Mo</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 05:09:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Stocks see mixed trend in early trading</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/stocks-see-mixed-trend-in-early-trading-149</link><description>Bangladesh’s two stock exchanges witnessed a mixed trend in the first hour of trading on Monday, with the key index of the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) rising while the Chittagong Stock Exchange (CSE) saw a slight decline.
During the first hour of trading, the DSE’s benchmark index, DSEX</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 05:24:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DBL Ceramics turns tile waste into classroom chalk for underserved schools</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/dbl-ceramics-turns-tile-waste-into-classroom-chalk-for-underserved-schools</link><description>DBL Ceramics, one of Bangladesh’s leading tile manufacturers, has launched the TileChalk initiative, transforming residue sludge from its tile manufacturing process into classroom chalk for underserved schools across Bangladesh, demonstrating how industrial innovation and sustainability can g</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 05:39:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gadget &amp; Gear Officially Unveils New iPhones in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/gadget-gear-officially-unveils-new-iphones-in-bangladesh</link><description>Gadget &amp; Gear, the country's largest multi-branded retail chain ‍and an Apple Authorised Reseller in Bangladesh, unveiled the latest iPhone lineup at Gadget Studio by G&amp;amp;G - the nation's only Apple mono store at bti LANDMARK, Gulshan Avenue, Dhaka.
The launch introduced the iPhone 17, iPhone Ai</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 05:54:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Unidentified body found near DMCH emergency ward</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/unidentified-body-found-near-dmch-emergency-ward</link><description>The body of an unidentified man, aged around 55, was recovered under the stairs of ward No. 101 at the emergency department of Dhaka Medical College and Hospital on Monday morning.
Ayub Ali, ward master of the emergency unit, said the man was found unconscious under the stairs in the morning. He w</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 06:54:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump unsure whether Tony Blair would be accepted on Gaza peace board</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-unsure-whether-tony-blair-would-be-accepted-on-gaza-peace-board</link><description>US President Donald Trump on Sunday questioned whether former UK Prime Minister Tony Blair would serve on a new "Board of Peace" that is intended to oversee the governance of Gaza, amid ongoing criticisms of Blair for his role in the Iraq War.
"I've always liked Tony, but I want to find out that h</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 07:09:53 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>