<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 02:30:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Triumphant Tarique takes oath as 11th PM</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/triumphant-tarique-takes-oath-as-11th-pm</link><description>Zia-family heir Tarique Rahman, who led his party to a sweeping electoral victory, becomes prime minister of Bangladesh to usher in what supporters describe as a new political era.
The swearing-in ceremony of the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) chair and his cabinet members was held Tuesday at</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 19:01:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>PM appoints five advisers with minister status</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/pm-appoints-five-advisers-with-minister-status</link><description>Five advisers to the Prime Minister have been appointed with the ranks of minister, accommodating some BNP seniors among them.
Exercising the powers vested in the Prime Minister of the People's Republic of Bangladesh, newly appointed Prime Minister Tarique Rahman appointed the advisers, shortly</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 23:54:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New finance minister plans cutting business costs, deregulation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/new-finance-minister-plans-cutting-business-costs-deregulation</link><description>Newly-appointed Finance and Planning Minister Amir Khosru Mahmud Chowdhury on Tuesday set out an agenda centred on deregulation and lowering the cost of doing business, saying the measures were essential to restore momentum in the country's fragile economy.
Talking to the Financial Express shortly</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 00:09:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Biz leaders pin hopes on new cabinet for economic recovery</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/biz-leaders-pin-hopes-on-new-cabinet-for-economic-recovery</link><description>Leading trade body leaders have expressed optimism that the newly formed cabinet will take decisive steps to boost economic growth, restore investor confidence, and address long-standing challenges across Bangladesh's industrial and commercial sectors.
They have expressed optimism that the new cab</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 00:24:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Economists, businesses urge new government to review BD-US trade deal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/economists-businesses-urge-new-government-to-review-bd-us-trade-deal</link><description>As an elected government now takes office, a strong plea grows for a review of the trade agreement signed between Bangladesh and the United States during the just-past interim regime.
Economists and businesses suggest the newly elected government to take measures on stakeholder consultation to rev</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 00:39:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No final decision on digital bank licensing, BB clarifies</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/no-final-decision-on-digital-bank-licensing-bb-clarifies</link><description>Bangladesh Bank (BB) has clarified that no final decision has been taken regarding the issuance of digital bank licences, amid reports published in several national dailies.
As part of the government's initiative to expand technology-driven inclusive financial services and build a "Cashless Bangla</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 00:54:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ENVIRONMENT POLLUTION:  BNP govt faces uphill battle</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/environment-pollution-bnp-govt-faces-uphill-battle</link><description>The BNP-led new government has started its journey at a time when every component of the environment, including air and water, is highly polluted, while Dhaka ranks poorly on the global livability indices.
Environmentalists and academics have outlined some challenges, including pollution and poor</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 01:09:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Foreign dignitaries attend Tarique's swearing-in</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/foreign-dignitaries-attend-tariques-swearing-in</link><description>Several foreign dignitaries attended the swearing-in ceremony of Bangladesh's new Prime Minister Tarique Rahman in the capital on Tuesday.
They include UK Parliamentary Under-Secretary of State (Indo-Pacific) and Minister for Equalities Seema Malhotra; Turkish Deputy Minister for Foreign Affairs A</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 01:24:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Experts urge AI-driven sustainable governance to meet SDGs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/experts-urge-ai-driven-sustainable-governance-to-meet-sdgs</link><description>Experts on Tuesday called on the new government to integrate artificial intelligence (AI) into management and policymaking to unlock economic potential and achieve the Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs).
They also advocated circular economy practices and the enactment of laws aligned with the co</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 01:39:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nabil Mustafiz named MD of Sammilito Islami Bank</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/nabil-mustafiz-named-md-of-sammilito-islami-bank</link><description>The government has appointed seasoned banker Nabil Mustafizur Rahman as managing director of the newly formed Sammilito Islami Bank PLC, following the merger of five troubled Islamic banks.
The appointment marks a key step in stabilising the consolidated lender, established under the Bank Resoluti</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 01:54:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>10-year T-bond yields fall again</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/10-year-t-bond-yields-fall-again</link><description>Yields on Bangladesh's 10-year Treasury bonds declined further on Tuesday as banks channelled surplus liquidity into government securities amid subdued private sector credit demand and improved market liquidity.Bangladesh market research
The cut-off yield, generally known as the interest rate, on</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 02:09:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Lock-in on Asiatic Lab shares extended amid price manipulation concerns</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/lock-in-on-asiatic-lab-shares-extended-amid-price-manipulation-concerns</link><description>The securities regulator has extended the lock-in period by at least three years on the shares held by sponsors, directors, and placement holders of Asiatic Laboratories, citing their alleged intention to offload shares after inflating prices through the publication of "unrealistic" price-sensitive</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 02:24:09 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>