<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 16:34:37 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Lawyer moves HC to suspend Bangladesh election until recovery of looted firearms</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/lawyer-moves-hc-to-suspend-bangladesh-election-until-recovery-of-looted-firearms</link><description>A Supreme Court lawyer has filed a public interest petition in the High Court seeking suspension of the national election until thousands of firearms looted during last year’s uprising are recovered.
Lawyer Md Mahmudul Hasan lodged the writ petition on Wednesday, naming the cabinet secretary</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 13:13:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC approves 73 more appeals on 5th day</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-approves-73-more-appeals-on-5th-day</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) on Wednesday approved 73 more appeals on the fifth day against the order of acceptance and cancellation of nomination papers of the Returning Officers in the upcoming 13th national elections.
EC Secretariat Senior Secretary Akhtar Ahmed told reporters this evening that</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 13:28:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BRAC Bank, MetLife Bangladesh reward Bancassurance campaign winners with Bangkok trips</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/brac-bank-metlife-bangladesh-reward-bancassurance-campaign-winners-with-bangkok-trips</link><description>BRAC Bank has recognised the top performers of its bancassurance campaign, ‘Fly Bangkok with Banca’, conducted in strategic partnership with MetLife Bangladesh, according to a press release.
The campaign marked another significant milestone in BRAC Bank’s expanding bancassurance</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 13:43:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BPC seeks LPG import rights</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/energy-advisor-signals-approval-as-bpc-seeks-permission-to-import-lpg</link><description>The Bangladesh Petroleum Corporation (BPC) has formally requested permission from the Energy and Mineral Resources Division to import liquefied petroleum gas (LPG) directly, aiming to tackle a domestic supply crisis and price volatility.
In a letter addressed to the division’s secretary on J</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 13:58:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bank Asia, Bangladesh Bank organise training for SME entrepreneurs in Sylhet</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bank-asia-bangladesh-bank-organise-training-for-sme-entrepreneurs-in-sylhet</link><description>Bank Asia PLC, in association with Bangladesh Bank, has organized a month-long ‘Entrepreneurship Development Program’ for SME entrepreneurs in Sylhet, according to a press release.
The program was inaugurated on 12 January 2026 by the Chief Guest Mr. Khaled Ahmed, Executive Director, B</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 14:13:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>FBCCI organises doa mahfil for seeking eternal peace of Khaleda Zia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/fbcci-organises-doa-mahfil-for-seeking-eternal-peace-of-khaleda-zia</link><description>The Federation of Bangladesh Chambers of Commerce and Industry (FBCCI) on Wednesday organized a doa mahfil for seeking eternal peace of the departed soul of former Prime Minister   Begum Khaleda Zia.
The milad mahfil, which took place at the FBCCI Auditorium following the Asr prayer, was</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 14:28:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UAE rulers grant royal pardons to 440 Bangladeshi prisoners</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/uae-rulers-grant-royal-pardons-to-440-bangladeshi-prisoners</link><description>The rulers of the United Arab Emirates (UAE) have granted royal pardons to 440 Bangladeshi prisoners, said the UAE Embassy in Dhaka on Wednesday.
The royal pardons were granted on the occasion of the 54th UAE National Day (Eid Al Etihad) in 2025, which is observed annually on December 2, commemora</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 14:43:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh receives $1.59b in remittances in first 13 days of Jan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh-receives-159b-in-remittances-in-first-13-days-of-jan</link><description>The upward trend in remittances sent by Bangladesh expatriates has continued in January, with receiving over US $1.59 billion in 13 days of the month.
Bangladesh received $17.85 billion in inward remittances from July to January 13, 2026, in the current fiscal year, FY 2025-26. It was 14.7 billion</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 14:58:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Iran warns of retaliation if Trump strikes, US withdraws some troops from regional bases</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/iran-warns-of-retaliation-if-trump-strikes-us-withdraws-some-troops-from-regional-bases</link><description>The United States is withdrawing some personnel from bases in the Middle East, a US official said on Wednesday, after a senior Iranian official said Tehran had warned neighbours it would hit American bases if Washington strikes.
With Iran's leadership trying to put down the worst domestic unrest t</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 15:13:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC clarifies viral video of postal ballots in Bahrain</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-clarifies-viral-video-of-postal-ballots-in-bahrain</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) on Wednesday clarified a viral video showing a large number of postal ballots delivered to a single address in Bahrain, saying the incident resulted from differences in the country’s postal delivery system and did not involve any irregularities in the voting proce</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 15:28:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC upholds BNP candidate Monirul Haque’s nomination for Cumilla-6</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ec-upholds-bnp-candidate-monirul-haques-nomination-for-cumilla-6</link><description>The Election Commission on Wednesday rejected an appeal challenging the validity of BNP nominated candidate for Cumilla-6 Monirul Haque Chowdhury in the upcoming national election.
Independent candidate and BNP leader Mohammad Amin Ur Rashid for Cumilla-6 filed the petition with the EC, which is t</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 16:15:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Migrants using more distant, riskier departure points to Canaries after Mauritania crackdown, Red Cross finds</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/migrants-using-more-distant-riskier-departure-points-to-canaries-after-mauritania-crackdown-red-cross-finds</link><description>Migrants crossing from West Africa to Spain’s Canaries started using more distant - and potentially more deadly - departure points in 2025 following a crackdown by Mauritania on irregular migration, according to data published by the Red Cross.
The number of small boats arriving in the Canar</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 16:30:47 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>