<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 19:39:56 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>India's Kaur becomes highest-capped woman in international cricket</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/indias-kaur-becomes-highest-capped-woman-in-international-cricket</link><description>Harmanpreet Kaur became the highest-capped player in women’s international cricket when she made her 356th appearance for India in Thursday’s Twenty20 match against Australia, surpassing New Zealand great Suzie Bates.
Indian captain Kaur, 36, has now played six Tests, 161 One-Day</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 16:02:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>King Charles visits London fashion show after brother's arrest</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/king-charles-visits-london-fashion-show-after-brothers-arrest</link><description>Britain's King Charles appeared at a fashion show in London on Thursday just hours after his brother Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor was arrested on suspicion of misconduct in public office.
Charles greeted onlookers with a wave when he arrived at Tolu Coker's London Fashion Week show and was met with</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 16:17:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Asif Nazrul vacates govt residence</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/asif-nazrul-bids-farewell-to-hare-road-residence-in-emotional-facebook-post</link><description>Former law advisor Asif Nazrul has announced that he is leaving his official residence on Hare Road, sharing an emotional message on social media about his attachment to the place.
In a Facebook post on Thursday, he wrote, “Goodbye Hare Road!” while describing the mixed feelings surrou</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 16:32:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>HSC form fill-up fees rise as registration set to begin Mar 1</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/hsc-form-fill-up-fees-rise-as-registration-set-to-begin-mar-1</link><description>The cost of appearing for the Higher Secondary Certificate (HSC) and equivalent examinations has increased this year, with the maximum fee for filling out the form for the exams fixed at Tk 2,995.
A notice issued on Thursday by the Board of Intermediate and Secondary Education, Dhaka informed that</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 16:47:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC orders preservation of voting day CCTV footage</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-orders-returning-officers-to-preserve-election-video-footage-as-future-evidence</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has directed returning officers to preserve video footage of the general election from CCTV-equipped polling stations as future evidence.
In a letter issued on Thursday, the EC Secretariat instructed officials to secure footage recorded on Feb 11, the day before the po</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 17:18:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>44th BCS: PSC recommends 4,136 candidates for non-cadre posts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/44th-bcs-psc-recommends-4136-candidates-for-non-cadre-posts</link><description>The Public Service Commission (PSC) has provisionally nominated 4,136 candidates from the 44th Bangladesh Civil Service examination for non-cadre positions.
In a notification on Thursday, the commission said the nominations were made for vacant posts ranging from 9th to 11th grade.
The selections</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 17:33:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Debapriya urges review of interim govt’s foreign deals</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/debapriya-calls-for-reassessment-of-interim-governments-foreign-agreements</link><description>CPD Distinguished Fellow Debapriya Bhattacharya has urged the government to reconsider foreign agreements signed by the interim administration, saying they must be reassessed alongside the review of Bangladesh’s LDC graduation commitments.
Speaking at a media briefing organised by the Citize</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 17:48:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Remittance inflow crosses $2 billion in just 18 days of February</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/remittance-inflow-crosses-2-billion-in-just-18-days-of-february</link><description>Expatriate Bangladeshis have sent over $2 billion in remittances during the first 18 days of February, as money transfers surged ahead of Ramadan and Eid.
According to data released by Bangladesh Bank on Thursday (Feb 19), if this upward trend continues, total remittances for the month are expecte</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 17:48:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Zero tariffs, new horizons</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/zero-tariffs-new-horizons</link><description>The recently negotiated reciprocal trade agreement between Washington and Dhaka is more than just a tariff adjustment. It is a strategic shift in Bangladesh's economic path. Bangladesh, a country where the ready-made garments (RMG) industry plays a major role in export earnings, employment, and for</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 18:03:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A sleeping giant, halal industry can fetch huge forex</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/a-sleeping-giant-halal-industry-can-fetch-huge-forex</link><description>The halal industry is expanding at a tremendous pace globally. Market analysis suggests that the global halal economy, which includes food, pharmaceuticals, fashion, cosmetics, finance, logistics and tourism, may reach US$9.7 trillion by 2030. Of this, the halal food industry alone may account for</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 18:18:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Import of capital machinery and export diversification are integral</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/import-of-capital-machinery-and-export-diversification-are-integral</link><description>It is premature to conclude that import of capital machinery has peaked up in the first half of the fiscal year 2025-26 riding on the assumption of economic and political stability during this elected government. But the 24 per cent rise in the opening of letters of credit (LCs) year on year during</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 18:33:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Deregulation and reduction of cost of business</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/deregulation-and-reduction-of-cost-of-business</link><description>The statement by the newly appointed finance and planning minister that his immediate priorities are deregulation and lowering the cost of doing business is both timely and pragmatic. Speaking to the media shortly after being sworn in, he underscored that restoring momentum to the country's fragile</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 18:48:24 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>