<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 10:23:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>bKash launches ‘bHive’ to provide students with early corporate exposure</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bkash-launches-bhive-to-provide-students-with-early-corporate-exposure</link><description>Traditionally, students gain professional exposure through internships at the end of their academic life. Breaking away from this conventional approach, bKash has introduced a unique career development initiative titled ‘bHive’, designed to connect students with the corporate environmen</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 07:00:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat’s Abdul Haq loses nomination over loan default; two others cleared in Dhaka-2 race</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jamaats-abdul-haq-loses-nomination-over-loan-default-two-others-cleared-in-dhaka-2-race</link><description>Jamaat-e-Islami nominated candidate Abdul Haq’s nomination paper for Dhaka-2 constituency has been cancelled on grounds of loan default.
The announcement came Saturday from Returning Officer and Dhaka District Commissioner Rezaul Karim during the scrutiny of nomination papers.
Addressing Ha</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 07:30:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Paper and packaging named product of the year as 30th Dhaka International Trade Fair opens</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/paper-and-packaging-named-product-of-the-year-as-30th-dhaka-international-trade-fair-opens</link><description>The 30th Dhaka International Trade Fair (DITF) has opened, with paper and packaging being named as the product of the year as part of efforts to diversify Bangladesh's exports.
The fair, which was delayed by two days following the death of former prime minister Khaleda Zia, was inaugurated by Comm</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 07:45:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat chief Shafiqur cleared in Dhaka-15, CPB’s Rubel disqualified</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jamaat-chief-shafiqur-cleared-in-dhaka-15-cpbs-rubel-disqualified</link><description>Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami chief Md Shafiqur Rahman’s nomination papers for Dhaka-15 constituency have been declared valid by election officials.
BNP’s Shafiqul Islam Khan Milton has also been cleared, while CPB’s Sajedul Huq Rubel’s nomination has been rejected.
The decis</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 08:00:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jatiya Party leader Anisul Islam Mahmud’s nomination rejected in Chattogram-5</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jatiya-party-leader-anisul-islam-mahmuds-nomination-rejected-in-chattogram-5</link><description>The nomination papers of Anisul Islam Mahmud, chairman of a breakaway faction of the Jatiya Party, have been rejected for the Chattogram-5 (Hathazari) parliamentary constituency.
The decision was announced on Saturday by Chattogram Divisional Commissioner and Returning Officer Md Zia Uddin durin</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 08:31:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Venezuela blames explosions on US 'military aggression'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/venezuela-blames-explosions-on-us-military-aggression</link><description>Venezuela said it rejected "military aggression" by the United States after multiple explosions rocked capital Caracas and other areas early on Saturday.
Attacks also took place in the states of Miranda, Aragua and La Guaira, a government statement said, prompting President Nicolas Maduro to decla</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 08:46:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Abdus Sattar made Tarique’s private secretary, Saleh Shibly press secretary</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/abdus-sattar-made-tariques-private-secretary-saleh-shibly-press-secretary</link><description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman has appointed ABM Abdus Sattar, former Secretary of the Bangladesh government, as his private secretary, and AAM Saleh (Saleh Shibly), former General Secretary of Dhaka Reporters' Unity, as his press secretary.
The appointments were announced on Saturday in a pre</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 09:01:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Video messages of Hadi murder prime suspect being examined: DMP Commissioner</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/video-messages-of-hadi-murder-prime-suspect-being-examined-dmp-commissioner</link><description>The police are examining two video messages reportedly released by Faisal Karim, the prime suspect in the Inqilab Moncho spokesperson Osman Hadi murder case.
“We have got the two video messages from Faisal and are currently scrutinising those. No comment on this now. We will speak after veri</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 09:15:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US strikes Venezuela after Trump's threats against Maduro</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-strikes-venezuela-after-trumps-threats-against-maduro</link><description>The US has carried out strikes inside Venezuela, a US official said, as explosions rocked the capital Caracas following months of threats by President Donald Trump against Venezuela's President Nicolas Maduro.
The Venezuelan government said attacks also took place in the states of Miranda, Aragua</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 09:45:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC urges voters to safeguard secrecy of postal ballots</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-urges-voters-to-safeguard-secrecy-of-postal-ballots</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has urged voters to strictly protect the secrecy of postal ballots, cautioning that sharing any information, images, or videos of their vote or ballot on social media constitutes a punishable offence under the law.
In a message issued today (Saturday), the EC stated, "</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 10:00:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique Rahman’s nomination cleared for Dhaka-17 seat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-rahmans-nomination-cleared-for-dhaka-17-seat</link><description>Election officials have declared the nomination papers of BNP leader Tarique Rahman valid for the Dhaka-17 constituency in the upcoming 13th parliamentary election.
The decision was announced on Saturday following the scrutiny of nomination papers at the returning officer’s office in Segunba</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 10:15:47 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>