<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 04:06:54 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Massive fire at Karachi shopping mall kills 3, injures 12</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/massive-fire-at-karachi-shopping-mall-kills-3-injures-12</link><description>A large fire swept through Gul Plaza, a multistory shopping mall in Karachi late Saturday, killing at least three people and injuring around a dozen others, officials said.
Firefighters and rescue teams rushed to the scene shortly after 10 p.m. local time. Most shop owners had already left or were</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 02:08:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Three-wheelers ruin orderly traffic flow on Dhaka roads</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/three-wheelers-ruin-orderly-traffic-flow-on-dhaka-roads</link><description>Unsafe battery-run three-wheelers reign supreme on the roads in Dhaka destroying the traffic order for other formal vehicles, taking opportunity of a lack of regulation, oversight, or intervention by the authorities, observed experts and sufferers.
The locally-modified and manufactured auto-ricksh</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 02:23:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Seven-college students to form 'Adhyadesh Mancha' at Shahbagh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/seven-college-students-to-form-adhyadesh-mancha-at-shahbagh</link><description>Students of seven government colleges in the capital announced on Saturday that they would form "Adhyadesh Mancha" (Ordinance Stage) at Shahbagh on Sunday (January 19) to press for their demand for issuance of the Dhaka Central University Ordinance-2025.
The information was disclosed in a message</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 02:38:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DU authorities lodge case over attack on students</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/du-authorities-lodge-case-over-attack-on-students</link><description>The authorities of Dhaka University (DU) have filed a case with New Market Police Station in connection an attack on DU students in the capital's Science Laboratory area of the capital on January 15.
The information was confirmed in a press release issued by the university's Public Relations Offic</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 02:53:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Temp may remain unchanged</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/temp-may-remain-unchanged</link><description>The overall temperature across the country increased by 1 to 2 degrees Celsius on Saturday and is likely to remain unchanged over the next two days.
According to the Bangladesh Meteorological Department (BMD), dry weather with a temporarily partly cloudy sky is expected to prevail across the count</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 02:15:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>RU 'A' unit admission test held</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/ru-a-unit-admission-test-held</link><description>The admission test for the Arts, Law and Social Science faculties under the 'A' Unit of Rajshahi University (RU) for the 2025-26 academic session was held smoothly on Saturday in two shifts.
The first shift started at 11:00 am, while the second shift began at 3:00 pm at multiple examination centre</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 02:30:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt seeks fast-track ADB budget support of $500 million</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/govt-seeks-fast-track-adb-budget-support-of-500-million</link><description>The government is seeking to fast-track the release of US$500 million in budgetary support from the Asian Development Bank (ADB) to help finance a widening fiscal deficit in the current financial year (FY 2025-26), officials said on Saturday.
The funds are being pursued under an ongoing policy-bas</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 02:45:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bogura potters struggling to stay afloat with scanty income</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/bogura-potters-struggling-to-stay-afloat-with-scanty-income</link><description>The Tk60-80 million pottery industry in Bogura enables the artisans to barley manage to survive, exclusively depending on the production of earthen pots and trays, which mainly covers the demand for the district's famed yoghurt.
Around 2,000 families across Bogura's 12 upazilas depend on the craft</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 03:00:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Children out of school as erosion fury rages on in Gaibandha</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/children-out-of-school-as-erosion-fury-rages-on-in-gaibandha</link><description>Locals of Chargram Jiadanga village in Gaibandha demanded immediate steps to re-establish a primary school as hundreds of children are unable to receive basic education after Brahmaputra River erosion claimed a neighbouring village last month and along with it, its sole primary school.
River erosi</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 03:15:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt moves to overhaul sanctions regime ahead of FATF mutual evaluation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/govt-moves-to-overhaul-sanctions-regime-ahead-of-fatf-mutual-evaluation</link><description>The government has initiated a sweeping overhaul of the national sanctions framework to plug loopholes in the financing of weapons of mass destruction (WMD), sources familiar with the development said.
The move is being seen as a high-priority strategic step to align domestic regulations with the</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 03:30:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BB aims to decrease inflation rate to 5pc approx. in near future</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/bb-aims-to-decrease-inflation-rate-to-5pc-approx-in-near-future</link><description>The central bank aims to gradually decrease the inflation rate to approximately five per cent in the near future from its current level of over eight per cent, Bangladesh Bank (BB) Deputy Governor Dr Md Habibur Rahman said at the divisional-level monetary policy discussion meeting in the BB, Rangpu</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 03:45:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Protecting health demands no money: Expert</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/protecting-health-demands-no-money-expert</link><description>The widespread consumption of bad and junk food-highly processed and often cooked with unhealthy oils-is increasingly posing serious health risks to Bangladesh's population, particularly the younger generation, with experts warning that it is contributing to lifestyle diseases and even premature de</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 04:00:46 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>