<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 17:04:58 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>NCC Bank supports ‘SeaSafe Lifeguard’ initiative at Cox’s Bazar under its CSR</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ncc-bank-supports-seasafe-lifeguard-initiative-at-coxs-bazar-under-its-csr</link><description>As part of its Corporate Social Responsibility (CSR) initiatives, NCC Bank has extended support to the “SeaSafe Lifeguard” program operated by the Centre for Injury Prevention and Research, Bangladesh (CIPRB) at Cox’s Bazar sea beach, aiming to address drowning-related public heal</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 14:20:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Islami Bank holds board meeting on Tuesday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/islami-bank-holds-board-meeting-on-tuesday</link><description>A meeting of the board of directors of Islami Bank Bangladesh PLC was held on Tuesday at the Islami Bank Tower, according to a press release.
Professor Dr M. Zubaidur Rahman, chairman of the bank, presided over the meeting. Mohammad KhurshidWahab, chairman of the executive committee, Md. Abdus Sal</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 14:35:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt dismantles corrupt structure in power, energy sector: Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/govt-dismantles-corrupt-structure-in-power-energy-sector-adviser</link><description>Power, Energy and Mineral Resources Adviser Dr Muhammad Fouzul Kabir Khan on Tuesday said the interim government destroyed the long-standing corruption structure of power and energy sectors.
“We have undertaken legal and institutional reform activities in the sector, leaving a transparent an</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 14:50:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BRAC Bank inaugurates relocated Motijheel Branch in spacious premises</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/brac-bank-inaugurates-relocated-motijheel-branch-in-spacious-premises</link><description>BRAC Bank has relocated its Motijheel Branch to spacious premises with more amenities to provide the best-in-class services and a delightful banking experience to its valued customers, according to a press release.
Tareq Refat Ullah Khan, Managing Director &amp; CEO, BRAC Bank, formally inaugurated th</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 15:05:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Community Bank signs MoU with Project 2morrow for digital onboarding, inclusive financing drive</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/community-bank-signs-mou-with-project-2morrow-for-digital-onboarding-inclusive-financing-drive</link><description>Community Bank Bangladesh PLC has signed a Memorandum of Understanding (MoU) with Project 2morrow Software Ltd to strengthen inclusive financing initiatives and enhance customer onboarding through advanced digital financial systems, according to a press release.
The strategic partnership aims to i</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 15:20:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Officials will face strict action if poll irregularities take place: Home Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/officials-will-face-strict-action-if-poll-irregularities-take-place-home-adviser</link><description>Home Adviser Lt Gen (retd.) Md. Jahangir Alam Chowdhury has warned that strict action will be taken against election officials and law enforcement personnel if any irregularities occur at polling stations during the 13th national election, including ballot box snatching or fake voting.
He issued t</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 14:51:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EU, Japanese election observation missions meet Prof Yunus</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/eu-japanese-election-observation-missions-meet-prof-yunus</link><description>The EU Election Observer Mission (EU-EOM) paid a courtesy call on Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus at the State Guest House Jamuna on Tuesday.
The Japanese Election Observation Mission also paid a courtesy call on the Chief Adviser separately, said the Chief Adviser’s press wing.
The</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 15:06:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>452nd board meeting of Al-Arafah Islami Bank held</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/452nd-board-meeting-of-al-arafah-islami-bank-held</link><description>452nd Board meeting of Al-Arafah Islami Bank PLC was held on Tuesday at the Banks’ head office, according to a press release.
Chairman of the Board of Directors Khwaja Shahriar presided over the meeting. The overall business performance of the Bank was reviewed and several policy decisions w</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 15:21:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Top U.S. immigration officials testify before lawmakers following killings in Minnesota</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/top-us-immigration-officials-testify-before-lawmakers-following-killings-in-minnesota</link><description>Top U.S. immigration officials are testifying before a congressional committee on Tuesday in the first such hearing since two U.S. citizens were killed in Minnesota and amid mounting opposition to President Donald Trump’s crackdown.
The officials - the highest ranking at three agencies overs</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 15:36:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique Rahman to cast vote at Gulshan Model High School and College</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-rahman-to-cast-vote-at-gulshan-model-high-school-and-college</link><description>The campaign and public outreach for the 13th National Parliamentary Election, scheduled for February 12, have ended. Now, it is time for voters to cast their ballots.
BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman will cast his vote at the Gulshan Model High School and College center, located on Road 86, Block 1/D</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 15:51:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EU lawmakers approve fast-track deportations of rejected asylum seekers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/eu-lawmakers-approve-fast-track-deportations-of-rejected-asylum-seekers</link><description>European lawmakers approved changes to the European Union asylum system on Tuesday, paving the way for fast-track deportations of rejected asylum seekers, underlining the rise in anti-immigration politics over the past decade.
The text, which requires final formal approval from the 27 EU member go</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 16:06:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Interim government reveals advisors’ asset details before election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/interim-government-reveals-advisors-asset-details-before-election</link><description>The interim government has disclosed the details of assets owned by its advisors and their spouses.
The Cabinet Division published a notice on Tuesday outlining records from June 2024 to June 2025.
These disclosures also account for their outstanding liabilities.
Commerce Advisor Sheikh Bashir U</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 16:21:41 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>