<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 17:28:50 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>UNDP, Canada partner to strengthen Bangladesh’s electoral process</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/undp-canada-partner-to-strengthen-bangladeshs-electoral-process</link><description>The United Nations Development Programme (UNDP) and the High Commission for Canada in Bangladesh, on Sunday, signed a Memorandum of Understanding at the Bangladesh Election Commission to support free, fair and inclusive elections through the Bangladesh Advancement for Credible, Inclusive and Transp</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 13:03:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Thailand PM’s party takes early lead in three-way election race</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/thailand-pms-party-takes-early-lead-in-three-way-election-race</link><description>Thai Prime Minister Anutin Charnvirakul’s Bhumjaithai Party took an early lead in Sunday’s general election, though the three-way battle is unlikely to give any single party a clear majority, potentially prolonging the spectre of political instability.
Anutin set the stage for the snap</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 13:18:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prime Bank holds ‘Empowering Youth’ session at KUET under PrimeAcademia initiative</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/prime-bank-holds-empowering-youth-session-at-kuet-under-primeacademia-initiative</link><description>Prime Bank PLC, in collaboration with Khulna University of Engineering &amp; Technology (KUET) and the KUET Business &amp; Entrepreneurship Club (KEBC), organised an “Empowering Youth” session at the KUET campus under its flagship initiative, PrimeAcademia.
PrimeAcademia is a customised servic</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 13:48:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>MTB board approves plan to raise Tk 3.46 billion in Tier-I Capital</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/mtb-board-approves-plan-to-raise-tk-346-billion-in-tier-i-capital</link><description>The Board of Directors of Mutual Trust Bank PLC (MTB) has approved a proposal to raise Tier-I Capital amounting to Tk 3.46 billoin (BDT 3,460 million) to further strengthen the bank’s core capital base.
According to a press release, the decision was taken at the 330th meeting of the board, h</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 14:03:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamuna Bank signs MoU with Microcredit Regulatory Authority</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/jamuna-bank-signs-mou-with-microcredit-regulatory-authority</link><description>Jamuna Bank PLC has signed a Memorandum of Understanding (MoU) with the Microcredit Regulatory Authority (MRA) of Bangladesh to enhance institutional cooperation and modern banking services, according to a press release.
Mr. A. K. M. Atiqur Rahman, Deputy Managing Director &amp; Chief Information Offi</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 14:18:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Community Bank signs MoU with Biztrade Ventures to strengthen SME 360° Business Solutions</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/community-bank-signs-mou-with-biztrade-ventures-to-strengthen-sme-360-business-solutions</link><description>Community Bank Bangladesh PLC has signed a Memorandum of Understanding (MoU) with Biztrade Ventures Limited to strengthen SME 360° Business solutions across the country, according to a press release.
Under the agreement, Biztrade Ventures Limited will act as a strategic advisory business partn</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 14:33:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>321 publishers ‘won’t join’ if Book Fair is held in February</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/321-publishing-houses-will-not-participate-if-ekushey-book-fair-is-held-in-february</link><description>As many as 321 publishers have said they will not participate in the Amar Ekushey Book Fair, citing concerns over “potential lack of readers, humanitarian disasters, and financial risks”.
In a joint statement, they expressed that due to the post-2026 national election climate and the m</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 14:48:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BRAC Bank hosts BRAC Kumon Book Fair for co-workers’ children</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/brac-bank-hosts-brac-kumon-book-fair-for-co-workers-children</link><description>BRAC Bank hosted a two-day “BRAC Kumon Book Fair” at its Head Office to support the intellectual growth of its co-workers’ children and encourage consistent study habits, according to a press release.
The event was inaugurated by Tareq Refat Ullah Khan, Managing Director and CEO</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 15:03:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dozens of journalists honoured with South Asian Hero Award 2026</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/others/dozens-of-journalists-honoured-with-south-asian-hero-award-2026</link><description>The SAARC Foundation established in Sri Lanka has honoured various individuals from Nepal, India, Bangladesh and Sri Lanka who have contributed to democracy, human rights and freedom of the press and expression with the South Asian Hero Award 2026.
They were honoured during a special program organ</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 15:18:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chattogram-bound cargo ship sinks near Thailand’s Phuket, crew rescued</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/chattogram-bound-cargo-ship-sinks-near-thailands-phuket-crew-rescued</link><description>MV SEALLOYD ARC, a Chittagong Port-bound Panama-flagged vessel carrying cargo from Malaysia, has sunk off the coast of Thailand’s Phuket.
The vessel sank on Saturday afternoon.
All 16 Bangladeshi crew members aboard were rescued.
According to the ship’s Bangladeshi agent Alvi Lines B</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 15:33:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Voters secretly decided whom they’ll vote: Nahid</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/voters-secretly-decided-whom-theyll-vote-nahid</link><description>National Citizen Party (NCP) Convener Nahid Islam said on Sunday that the people of Bangladesh have already decided in secret whom they will vote for and are set to carry out that ‘great act’ on Thursday.
In a televised address on Bangladesh Television in the evening, Nahid, also a can</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 15:48:20 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>