<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 22:22:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Chinese researchers establish new model to predict human organ aging</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/chinese-researchers-establish-new-model-to-predict-human-organ-aging</link><description>A team of Chinese researchers has recently developed a model to predict the aging of 13 human organs, including the brain, enabling precise assessment of organ aging levels, the China Science Daily reported on Monday.
Previous research focused mainly on the common features of overall aging or expl</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 16:15:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hamas confirms death of spokesman of its military wing</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/hamas-confirms-death-of-spokesman-of-its-military-wing</link><description>Hamas' armed wing, the Al-Qassam Brigades, announced on Monday that its military spokesperson Abu Obeida had been killed during the Israeli offensive on the Gaza Strip.
The announcement was made by a newly-appointed spokesperson, who assumed the same nom de guerre, Abu Obeida, during a televised p</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 16:30:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Joint effort needed for quality telecom services: Taiyeb</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/joint-effort-needed-for-quality-telecom-services-taiyeb</link><description>Chief Adviser's Special Assistant for the Ministry of Posts, Telecommunications and Information Technology Faiz Ahmad Taiyeb on Monday urged the concerned authorities to work together to ensure uninterrupted and improved telecommunication services.
He made the call while inspecting the Third Subma</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 16:45:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>2,582 candidates submitted nomination papers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/2582-candidates-submitted-nomination-papers</link><description>A total of 2,582 candidates have submitted nomination papers to contest from the country’s 300 constituencies in the 13th general election slated for February 12, 2026.
As many as 3,407 aspirants collected nomination papers, but 2,582 ones filed nomination papers, according to the statistics</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 17:00:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A new dawn for democratic media</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/a-new-dawn-for-democratic-media</link><description>The print media in Bangladesh is going through one of the most critical periods in its history. Advertisements shrinking in number, production costs rising, and readership dwindling have pushed newspapers, especially ones that carry serious and public interest-based content, to the point of extinct</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 16:31:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A market run by non-market forces</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/a-market-run-by-non-market-forces</link><description>A former lead economist of the World Bank (WB)'s Dhaka office, Dr Zahid Hussain recently said what Bangladesh economy is experiencing at the moment is a form of stagflation. Stagflation in developed economies like in the UK is characterized by high inflation, low growth and rising unemployment. The</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 16:46:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Textile sector needs urgent support</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/textile-sector-needs-urgent-support</link><description>The country's textile sector, the backbone of export economy and the foundation on which the garment industry stands, is facing an existential crisis. Nowhere is this more evident than in the country's spinning mills, where mounting losses, policy inertia and external pressures are pushing an entir</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 17:01:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Why agro-processing remains timid</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/why-agro-processing-remains-timid</link><description>If agro-processing is value-addition to farm outputs such as crops, livestock, fish, timber etc., Bangladesh has a long way to go before it economically transforms the raw versions of produce into products. The country has to its credit surplus production of certain vegetables and fruits but most v</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 17:16:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Man held with ‘toy pistol’ at Inqilab Moncho rally</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/man-detained-at-inqilab-moncho-rally-for-carrying-firearm-later-found-to-be-toy-pistol</link><description>Police have detained a youth at the Inqilab Moncho’s rally in Shahbagh, initially reported by some protesters on social media as an “armed individual”.
The incident occurred around 8pm, but by 9pm, Ramna Division Deputy Commissioner Masud Alam clarified that the detainee, identif</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 17:31:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Death rates in hybrids ‘three times higher’ than petrol cars, data shows</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/death-rates-in-hybrids-three-times-higher-than-petrol-cars-data-shows</link><description>UK newspapers have reported, citing official data, that motorists in hybrid cars are three times more likely to die than those in petrol cars.
Analysing figures from the Department of Transport, the newspapers said 122 people died in collisions involving hybrid vehicles and 777 in petrol car crash</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 17:46:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khaleda Zia’s condition turns extremely critical, say physicians</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/khaleda-zias-condition-turns-extremely-critical-say-physicians</link><description>The health condition of BNP Chairperson and former Prime Minister Begum Khaleda Zia, who is being treated in the Critical Care Unit (CCU) of Evercare Hospital, has worsened and become extremely critical, members of her medical board said on Monday night.
“Khaleda Zia’s condition is ext</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 18:01:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Remittances hit $2.93 billion in 28 days of December</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/remittances-hit-293-billion-in-28-days-of-december</link><description>The upward trend in remittances sent by expatriate Bangladeshis has continued in December, with receiving over US $ 2.93 billion in 28 days of the month.
Bangladesh received $15.97 billion inward remittance so far in the current fiscal year FY 2025-26.
According to the latest update from Banglade</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 19:18:02 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>