<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 04:25:47 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Police arrest eight men of AL, affiliates in city</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/police-arrest-eight-men-of-al-affiliates-in-city</link><description>Police have arrested eight individuals linked to banned Awami League (AL) and its affiliates in raids at various locations in the capital.
The arrestees are: organising secretary of banned Bangladesh Chhatra League (BCL) of Alipur Union unit of Dagonbhuiyan upazila of Feni district Ekram Hossain (</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 01:34:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BGMEA, BKMEA to set up temporary warehouse at HSIA</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bgmea-bkmea-to-set-up-temporary-warehouse-at-hsia</link><description>Two trade bodies --BGMEA and BKMEA -will jointly set up a temporary warehouse at the Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport for facilitating their overseas trade as the latest devastating fire at its cargo village disrupted the export-import activities.
The decision was taken following a meeting o</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 01:49:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Writ seeks HC order to probe authorities' ‘negligence’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/writ-seeks-hc-order-to-probe-authorities-negligence</link><description>A writ petition has been filed seeking a High Court (HC) order to form an independent probe body to investigate authorities' failure and inaction in maintaining the Dhaka Metro Rail, which led to the death of a pedestrian at city' Farmgate on Sunday.
Abul Kalam Azam, the pedestrian, was hit by a b</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 02:04:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ACC approves case against ex-PM’s press secy Naimul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/acc-approves-case-against-ex-pms-press-secy-naimul</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) has approved a case against former press secretary to the ousted PM Md Naimul Islam Khan for failing to submit his wealth statement within the stipulated time as required by law.
He was appointed as the press secretary to the Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina in Jul</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 02:19:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fine for smoking, expulsion for drug use</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fine-for-smoking-expulsion-for-drug-use</link><description>The authorities of Dhaka University's (DU) Shaheed Sergeant Zahurul Huq Hall have announced that students caught smoking openly on the hall premises would be fined, while those found using or possessing drugs would face expulsion from the hall.
Announcing the measures, a notice was issued on Monda</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 02:34:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ishwardi Silk Seedbed now stands decrepit</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/ishwardi-silk-seedbed-now-stands-decrepit</link><description>Where earlier there used to be a hustle and bustle of cutting mulberry leaves, rearing silkworms, making cocoons and making silk thread from them throughout the year.
However, the evolution of time has created a spooky atmosphere in that seedbed today. Due to the closure of activities for a long t</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 02:49:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Farmers demand solution as irrigation pump lies inoperative in Gaibandha's Saghata</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/farmers-demand-solution-as-irrigation-pump-lies-inoperative-in-gaibandhas-saghata</link><description>Farmers of the Abdullah village in Gaibandha's Saghata Upazila demanded a solution as an irrigation pump designated for at least a hundred bighas of land have been remaining out of order for about two years.
Growers say that due to the inoperability of the pump, they have to bear extra costs to us</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 03:19:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BD's future growth hinges on export diversification, says expert</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bds-future-growth-hinges-on-export-diversification-says-expert</link><description>Bangladesh's next phase of development will depend on how quickly the country can navigate the evolving global trade landscape. Failure to diversify and technology-enable its export sector could push the country into the middle-income trap.
Dr Masrur Reaz, Chairman and CEO of Policy Exchange Bangl</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 03:34:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Row brews over continuation of RMG workers' wage hike</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/row-brews-over-continuation-of-rmg-workers-wage-hike</link><description>Garment owners and labour leaders have locked horns over whether the enhanced annual wage increment for workers in the country's readymade garment (RMG) sector will continue beyond 2025.
According to labour leaders, workers are entitled to a 9.0-per-cent annual increment, which includes an additio</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 03:49:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Man dies as two Jubo Dal factions clash in Ctg</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/man-dies-as-two-jubo-dal-factions-clash-in-ctg</link><description>A man has been killed in Chattogram city’s Bakalia area following a clash between two factions of the Jubo Dal, a BNP affiliate.
The incident occurred on Syed Shah Road late on Monday night and locals say there was heavy gunfire during the violence.
The victim, a 22-year-old identified by a</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 04:04:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Amazon plans to cut 30,000 corporate jobs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/amazon-plans-to-cut-30000-corporate-jobs</link><description>Amazon is planning to cut as many as 30,000 corporate jobs beginning on Tuesday, as the company pares expenses and compensates for overhiring during the peak demand of the pandemic, according to three people familiar with the matter.
The figure represents a small percentage of Amazon's 1.55 millio</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 04:19:53 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>