<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 07:41:20 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>'YES' VOTE IN REFERENDUM: Student unions to hold mass gatherings in cities</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/yes-vote-in-referendum-student-unions-to-hold-mass-gatherings-in-cities</link><description>The central student unions of the Dhaka University, Jahangirnagar University, Rajshahi University, Chittagong University and Jagannath University have jointly announced a series of mass gatherings in the divisional cities in support of "Yes" vote in the upcoming referendum.
The announcement was ma</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 04:37:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US govt won't take sides in BD election: Envoy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/us-govt-wont-take-sides-in-bd-election-envoy</link><description>United States (US) Ambassador in Dhaka Brent T. Christensen on Wednesday said the US government would not take any sides in the next parliamentary election, and the country is ready to work with the next political government here.
"The United States government does not take sides in Bangladesh's e</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 04:52:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>JUCSU unveils 4-month report on student welfare initiatives</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jucsu-unveils-4-month-report-on-student-welfare-initiatives</link><description>The Jahangirnagar University Central Students' Union (JUCSU) on Wednesday unveiled a four-month activity report, outlining a wide range of initiatives taken by the union for students' welfare since it assumed office.
The report was made public at a press conference held in front of the JUCSU build</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 05:07:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jatrabari police recover hanging body of constable</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jatrabari-police-recover-hanging-body-of-constable</link><description>Police recovered the body of a constable hanging from a rope tied to the ventilator of a toilet at Jatrabari Police Outpost in the capital on Wednesday.
The deceased, Shafikul Islam (42) - hailing from Chandpur, might have committed suicide.
Jatrabari Police Station Officer-in-Charge (OC) Mohamma</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 05:22:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Iran dismisses Trump’s threats, vows swift response to any US attack</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/iran-dismisses-trumps-threats-vows-swift-response-to-any-us-attack</link><description>Iran has firmly rejected renewed military threats from US President Donald Trump, warning that its armed forces are fully prepared to respond immediately and forcefully to any American attack.
Iranian Foreign Minister Abbas Araghchi said on Wednesday that the country’s military was on high a</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 05:37:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fans pay tribute as Arijit Singh announces retirement from playback singing</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/fans-pay-tribute-as-arijit-singh-announces-retirement-from-playback-singing</link><description>Heartbroken fans of renowned Indian singer Arijit Singh have been paying tribute to him after he announced he would no longer take on new playback assignments, marking the end of a defining chapter in contemporary Bollywood music.
Some described his voice as "the sound of our heartbreaks and celeb</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 05:52:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Misinformation sparks confusion about Saint Martin’s, authorities clarify</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/misinformation-sparks-confusion-about-saint-martins-authorities-clarify</link><description>Widespread misinformation surrounding Saint Martin’s, Bangladesh’s only coral island, has triggered public confusion, with officials dismissing claims that the island is being handed over to a foreign power or converted into a military base.
For months, misleading posts, videos and pol</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 06:07:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Amazon confirms 16,000 job cuts after internal email sent in error</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/amazon-confirms-16000-job-cuts-after-internal-email-sent-in-error</link><description>US tech giant Amazon has confirmed it will lay off about 16,000 employees, hours after an internal email detailing the cuts was mistakenly sent to staff.
The email, seen by the BBC, was circulated late Tuesday and referred to job losses affecting employees in the United States, Canada and Costa Ri</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 06:22:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Banking sector reforms to restore confidence, stability</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/banking-sector-reforms-to-restore-confidence-stability-1</link><description>The banking sector of Bangladesh has been under intense strain after years of weak governance, political interference, and regulatory failure. Doctored financial statements and large-scale loan defaults have eroded public confidence and threatened overall economic stability. The central bank, under</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 06:37:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Starmer seeks fresh start with China, economic wins</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/starmer-seeks-fresh-start-with-china-economic-wins</link><description>British Prime Minister Keir Starmer told Chinese President Xi Jinping on Thursday that he wanted to build a "sophisticated relationship" aiming to boost growth and security, signalling a breakthrough in ties after years of acrimony.
On the most important day of his four-day visit to China, the fir</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 06:52:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Plane crashes in Colombia, killing all 15 on board</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/plane-crashes-in-colombia-killing-all-15-on-board</link><description>A passenger plane has crashed in northern Colombia, killing all 15 people on board, the country's state-run airline Satena confirmed.
In a statement, it said its aircraft - a Beechcraft 1900 - "suffered a fatal accident", but gave no further details. The wreckage has now been located in a mountain</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 07:07:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>TIME magazine calls Tarique Rahman “clear front runner” in upcoming polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/time-magazine-calls-tarique-rahman-clear-front-runner-in-upcoming-polls</link><description>The US-based TIME magazine in its latest issue published today called BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman the “clear front runner” in the upcoming February 12 elections as it carried an analysis ahead of the polls.
“Rahman is the clear front runner in Feb. 12 elections, which were called</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 07:22:02 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>