<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 17:21:52 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Election 2026: EC clarifies what would disqualify MP aspirants</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/election-2026-ec-clarifies-what-would-disqualify-mp-aspirants</link><description>The Election Commission has clarified the provisions related to qualifications and disqualification for an MP aspirant ahead of the upcoming national election scheduled to be held on February 12 next.
The commission, in the election circular-1 issued following the announcement of election schedule</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 14:34:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DUCSU sets 24-hour deadline for arrest of Hadi’s assailants</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ducsu-sets-24-hour-deadline-for-arrest-of-hadis-assailants</link><description>Dhaka University Central Students’ Union (DUCSU) leaders have given the government 24 hours to arrest the attackers of Sharif Osman bin Hadi.
The convenor of Inquilab Mancha and a potential independent candidate for Dhaka-8 remains in critical condition after being shot.
The leaders threate</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 14:49:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Metro rail services resume</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/metro-rail-services-resume</link><description>Metro rail services resumed on Friday night following a five-hour suspension due to a strike called by officers and employees of Dhaka Mass Transit Company Limited (DMTCL).
The DMTCL gave the information after the resumption of the service from Uttara North station at 8:15 pm, according to local n</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 15:04:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hadi shifted to Evercare Hospital after surgery</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hadi-shifted-to-evercare-hospital-after-surgery</link><description>Sharif Osman Hadi, the independent candidate for Dhaka-8 and spokesperson of Inqilab Mancha who was wounded in a gun attack, has been moved from Dhaka Medical College Hospital (DMCH) to Evercare Hospital.
About Osman Hadi’s latest physical condition, Dhaka Medical College Hospital Director B</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 15:19:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCP expresses deep concern over attack on Hadi, calls for arrest of perpetrators</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ncp-expresses-deep-concern-over-attack-on-hadi-calls-for-arrest-of-perpetrators</link><description>The National Citizens Party (NCP) has condemned and expressed deep concern over the shooting attack on Sharif Osman Hadi, an independent candidate for Dhaka-8 and spokesperson of Inquilab Mancha, in Bijoynagar on Thursday.
In a statement issued Friday evening, NCP Joint Member-Secretary and Media</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 14:44:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ctg appoints 42 magistrates to enforce election rules</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/42-magistrates-appointed-in-chattogram-to-enforce-election-code-of-conduct</link><description>A total of 42 magistrates have been appointed across Chattogram city and its Upazilas to operate mobile courts aimed at ensuring compliance with the electoral code of conduct.
Chattogram Deputy Commissioner Zahidul Islam Mian issued the order on Friday, confirming their appointment.
Chattogram Ad</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 14:59:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique terms attack on Hadi a conspiracy against democracy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-terms-attack-on-hadi-a-conspiracy-against-democracy</link><description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman on Friday described the shooting of Dhaka-8 independent candidate Sharif Osman Hadi as a “conspiracy against democracy.”
“Today’s attack on Sharif Osman Bin Hadi is not an isolated incident. Similar incidents have happened before. A few da</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 15:14:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bus catches fire on Badda Link Road</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bus-catches-fire-on-badda-link-road</link><description>A bus has caught on fire in Dhaka’s Badda Link Road.
According to the Fire Service, the blaze broke out on a Dewan Paribahan bus around 7:45pm on Friday.
A video of the incident is circulating on social media, showing the vehicle engulfed in flames before it suddenly begins to roll forward</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 15:29:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DMP intensifies drive to arrest attackers of Hadi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dmp-intensifies-drive-to-arrest-attackers-of-hadi</link><description>Dhaka Metropolitan Police (DMP) has launched an extensive drive to arrest the assailants who shot Inqilab Mancha spokesperson Osman Hadi in the capital’s Bijoynagar area on Friday afternoon.
According to police, a group of motorcycle-borne attackers opened fire on Hadi around 2:25pm in the B</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 15:44:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique Rahman to return to country on December 25</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-rahman-to-return-to-country-on-december-25</link><description>BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir has said Tarique Rahman, the acting chairman of the party, will return to the country from the United Kingdom on December 25.
The BNP leader gave the information at a press conference after a meeting of the party’s highest policy-making body,</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 15:59:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Climate Justice Assembly to be held in Dhaka on Dec 13-14</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/climate-justice-assembly-to-be-held-in-dhaka-on-dec-13-14</link><description>Organisers of the Climate Justice Assembly, scheduled for Dec 13-14, briefed reporters at a press conference at the National Press Club in Dhaka.
They talked about the main modalities of the two-day event and answered questions from journalists.
Among those who spoke were Md Shamsuddoha, chief ex</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 16:14:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scores of migrants cross into Poland through hidden Belarus border tunnel</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/scores-of-migrants-cross-into-poland-through-hidden-belarus-border-tunnel</link><description>More than 180 migrants crossed into Poland through a tunnel hidden in a forest on the border with Belarus, frontier guards said on Friday.
Around 130 of them were detained in Poland after the passage was discovered on Thursday, but the rest were still on the run, the Polish Border Guard said in a</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 16:29:10 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>