<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 16:06:47 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>India sticks to e-cigarette ban in snub for Philip Morris</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/india-sticks-to-e-cigarette-ban-in-snub-for-philip-morris</link><description>India has ruled out relaxation of a ban on e-cigarettes that would have allowed heat-not-burn tobacco products, dealing a blow to a lengthy private lobbying campaign by Philip Morris International for New Delhi to permit such devices.
India banned e-cigarettes, including heated tobacco products, i</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 12:29:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat Ameer alleges vandalisation of polling booths in Dhaka-15</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-ameer-alleges-vandalisation-of-polling-booths-in-dhaka-15</link><description>Jamaat Ameer Dr Shafiqur Rahman on Wednesday alleged that 13 polling booths were vandalised in his Dhaka-15 constituency.
In a Facebook post around 5 pm, the Jamaat chief strongly condemned and protested the incident, UNB reports. 
“Those who still want to stop us through terror and in</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 12:44:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dipu’s family rejects compensation, demands justice</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/no-wealth-can-repay-his-life-dipus-family-rejects-compensation-demands-justice</link><description>The family of Dipu Chandra Das, who was beaten to death before his body was set on fire in Mymensingh’s Bhaluka by a mob who alleged he insulted Islam, has reiterated the demand for justice.
The murder occurred on Dec 18 last year.
The family reacted after the government announced a compens</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 12:59:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two killed as bus overturns in Faridpur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/two-killed-as-bus-overturns-in-faridpur</link><description>Two people were killed and 10 others injured when a bus overturned on the Dhaka-Khulna highway in Bhanga upazila of Faridpur district on Wednesday.
One of the deceased was identified as Shariful Islam, supervisor of a bus while the identity of another could not be known immediately.
The accident</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 13:14:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cash-for-votes claims fly in Lakshmipur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/bnp-jamaat-trade-cash-for-votes-allegations-before-polling-in-lakhsmipur</link><description>On the eve of the parliamentary election, allegations have surfaced in Lakshmipur that money was distributed to buy votes on behalf of candidates from the Bangladesh Nationalist Party and Jamaat-e-Islami.
In Lakshmipur-3, rival complaints were lodged by the camps of “Weighing Scale” an</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 13:29:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>330 Ansars relieved for unauthorised election duty</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/330-ansars-relieved-for-unauthorised-election-duty</link><description>The Bangladesh Ansar and VDP on Wednesday removed 330 members from election duties over allegations that a team leader in Hatirjheel assigned them roles illegally in exchange for money.
A day before the parliamentary election and referendum, the force announced that anyone found involved in corrup</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 13:44:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CEC urges all to vote, accept results</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cec-nasir-uddin-calls-on-all-citizens-to-vote-respect-outcome-of-election</link><description>On the eve of the parliamentary election, Chief Election Commissioner AMM Nasir Uddin has addressed the nation, calling on citizens to go to polling centres fearlessly and exercise their right to vote.
He also urged everyone to accept the results of the democratic process, whatever they may be.
W</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 13:59:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat activist held with cash in Shariatpur; jailed for 2 years</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-activist-held-with-cash-in-shariatpur-jailed-for-2-years</link><description>A Jamaat activist was arrested with over Tk 7 lakh during a joint force operation in Naria upazila of Shariatpur on Wednesday.
The arrestee is Golam Mustafa, an assistant teacher of Shaheed Samad High School in Japsa Union and a resident of the Rajnagar area, UNB reports. 
He was sentenced t</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 14:14:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IRI delegation meets Jamaat Ameer</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/iri-delegation-meets-jamaat-ameer</link><description>An election observation delegation from the US-based International Republican Institute (IRI), currently in Bangladesh, on Wednesday paid a courtesy call on Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami Ameer to exchange views on the upcoming election.
The 19-member delegation is led by former US Congressman David D</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 14:29:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Miscreants fire blanks at BNP activist’s house in Raozan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/miscreants-fire-blanks-at-bnp-activists-house-in-raozan</link><description>Armed miscreants opened fire on the house of an expatriate BNP activist in Raozan of Chattogram around noon on Wednesday (February 11), a day before Bangladesh’s polls.
The incident took place at the house of Rustom Ali in Shamsherpara village under Kodolpur Union. Rustom Ali, a BNP activist</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 14:44:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat complains to EC about attacks, intimidation on election eve</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-complains-to-ec-about-attacks-intimidation-on-election-eve</link><description>Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islam on Wednesday lodged a series of complaints with the Election Commission, alleging attacks, intimidation of its leaders and activists and vandalism of party offices across the country in an attempt to undermine the election-friendly environment ahead of Thursday’s ele</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 14:59:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Australia begin T20 World Cup with 67-run win over Ireland</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/australia-begin-t20-world-cup-with-67-run-win-over-ireland</link><description>Australia launched their Twenty20 World Cup campaign with a commanding 67-run victory over Ireland in Colombo on Wednesday, powered by four-wicket hauls from Nathan Ellis and Adam Zampa.
Australia shrugged off the last-minute pullout of captain Mitchell Marsh to post 182-6 in 20 overs, after stand</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 15:14:23 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>