<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 14:34:26 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Italian role in Trump's 'Board of Peace' seems problematic, minister says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/italian-role-in-trumps-board-of-peace-seems-problematic-minister-says</link><description>Italian Economy Minister Giancarlo Giorgetti said on Wednesday it appeared problematic for his country to join the so-called Board of Peace promoted by US President Donald Trump to govern Gaza.
Speaking at an event in Rome to present the Winter Olympics Italy is hosting next month, Giorgetti said</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 11:41:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Agent banking breaks social barriers, brings women into financial system</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/agent-banking-breaks-social-barriers-brings-women-into-financial-system</link><description>Such financial inclusion is playing a pivotal role in providing adequate financial services, especially for rural women, small business entrepreneurs, beneficiaries of remitters, writes JUBAIR HASAN about virtues of banking hybridization
 
Villagers used to depend on usurers and thereafter o</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 11:56:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>'Agent banking highly cost-efficient, but interconnected challenges are many'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/agent-banking-highly-cost-efficient-but-interconnected-challenges-are-many</link><description>M. Nazeem A. Choudhury, Deputy Managing Director, Prime Bank PLC during an interview with The Financial Express recently gave his views on agent banking and performance of the Prime Bank with regard to this grassroots banking that uniquely helps financial inclusion.
Excerpts of the interview follo</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 12:11:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>'For Midland Bank, agent banking a cornerstone of its financial inclusion strategy'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/for-midland-bank-agent-banking-a-cornerstone-of-its-financial-inclusion-strategy</link><description>Midland Bank recognizes the transformative potential of agent banking as a cost-effective and inclusive solution for providing financial services to the underserved and under developed areas of the country, said Md. Ahsan-uz Zaman, Managing Director and Chief Executive Officer of the bank in an int</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 12:26:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Teachers demand UAP staff reinstated</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/teachers-network-calls-for-return-of-dismissed-faculty-amid-blasphemy-row</link><description>The University Teachers’ Network has demanded the reinstatement of two teachers who were dismissed by the University of Asia Pacific authorities following student protests over allegations of “blasphemy”.
The platform of public and private university teachers raised the demand on</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 12:41:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh’s vehicle imports surge ahead of election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladeshs-vehicle-imports-surge-ahead-of-election-port-revenue-gets-a-boost</link><description>Vehicle imports through Bangladesh’s main seaport have jumped sharply ahead of the national election through Chattogram port, giving a significant boost to government revenue.
More than 7,000 vehicles were cleared through the port over the past six months, generating over Tk 12 billion in cu</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 12:56:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>69,000 pass written test for recruitment of primary teachers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/69000-pass-written-test-for-recruitment-of-primary-teachers</link><description>The Directorate of Primary Education has published the results of the written examination for recruitment of teachers in government primary schools across 61 districts, with 69,265 candidates declared successful.
The results were announced at 7:30 pm on Wednesday.
The exam was held on Jan 9 at 1,</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 13:11:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ninth National Pay Commission submits report to CA</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ninth-national-pay-commission-submits-report-to-ca</link><description>The Ninth National Pay Commission on Wednesday submitted its report to Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus at the State Guest House Jamuna.
The 23-member commission, led by its Chairman Zakir Ahmed Khan, presented the report this afternoon, three weeks ahead of its deadline, said the Chief Advi</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 13:26:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sonali Bank SMT holds meeting with Board of Directors</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/sonali-bank-smt-holds-meeting-with-board-of-directors</link><description>The 18th review meeting between the Board of Directors and Senior Management Team (SMT) of Sonali Bank PLC was held at the Bank’s head office conference room on Wednesday, according to a press release.
Board of Directors Chairman, Mohammad Muslim Chowdhury presided over the meeting while ban</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 13:41:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Defamation case filed against Amir Hamza in Jashore</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/defamation-case-filed-against-amir-hamza-in-jashore</link><description>A defamation case has been filed in Jashore against Jamaat-e-Islami–nominated Kushtia-3 candidate Mufti Amir Hamza for allegedly making derogatory remarks about the late Arafat Rahman Koko, younger son of former Prime Minister Begum Khaleda Zia.
Mehedi Hasan Zillu, a member of the convening</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 13:56:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>MTB launches its own hosted order management system ‘MTB Lenden’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/mtb-launches-its-own-hosted-order-management-system-mtb-lenden</link><description>Mutual Trust Bank PLC (MTB) has officially inaugurated the go-live of its own hosted Order Management System (OMS), branded as ‘MTB Lenden’, marking a significant milestone in the Bank’s digital and capital market services, according to a press release.
The inauguration was atten</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 14:11:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt appoints new administrator of Ctg Chamber</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/govt-appoints-new-administrator-of-ctg-chamber</link><description>Additional Divisional Commissioner (Gen) of Chattogram Motaher Hossain has been appointed as the new administrator of The Chattogram Chamber of Commerce and Industry, a press release of the chamber said.
Motaher Hossain’s will replace Administrator Mohammad Nurullah Noori until the completio</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 14:26:44 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>