<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 16:55:30 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Senegal to get bonuses, land for Africa Cup of Nations win</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/senegal-to-get-bonuses-land-for-africa-cup-of-nations-win</link><description>Senegal’s President Bassirou Diomaye Faye has offered bonuses of more than $130,000 as well as plots of coastal land to each member of the country’s soccer team following their victory in Sunday’s Africa Cup of Nations final against Morocco.
He spoke at a ceremony in the capital</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 13:45:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Policy dialogue on prevention of trade-based money laundering held in Chattogram</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/policy-dialogue-on-prevention-of-trade-based-money-laundering-held-in-chattogram</link><description>The Bangladesh Financial Intelligence Unit (BFIU), in collaboration with the and Association of Anti Money Laundering Compliance Officers of Banks in Bangladesh (AACOBB), organised a high-level Policy Dialogue on the Prevention of Trade-Based Money Laundering (TBML) at Chittagong Club Ltd recently.</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 14:00:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bengal Commercial Bank holds Annual Business Conference 2026</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bengal-commercial-bank-holds-annual-business-conference-2026</link><description>Bengal Commercial Bank PLC held its “Annual Business Conference 2026” with a motto of ‘Building Tomorrow’s Bank Today’.
According to a press release, the two-day conference was held on 17 and 18 January 2026 at a hotel in Cox’s Bazar.
The conference was inaugur</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 14:15:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP expels 59 leaders for standing in election defying party line</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-expels-59-leaders-for-standing-in-election-defying-party-line</link><description>The Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) has expelled 59 leaders for running for parliament independently in defiance of party mandates.
The move was announced Wednesday night in a media statement.
Previously, 11 members faced expulsion for similar defiance, but the bans on two were revoked after t</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 14:30:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pakistan to join Trump’s ‘Board of Peace’ on Gaza, says foreign office</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/pakistan-to-join-trumps-board-of-peace-on-gaza-says-foreign-office</link><description>Pakistan will join US President Donald Trump’s “Board of Peace” to help achieve lasting peace in Gaza, its foreign ministry said on Wednesday.
Pakistan hoped “concrete steps will be taken towards the implementation of a permanent ceasefire” as well as to boost aid and</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 14:45:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump says he wants immediate negotiations to purchase Greenland</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-says-he-wants-immediate-negotiations-to-purchase-greenland</link><description>US President Donald Trump on Wednesday called for immediate negotiations toward a deal to acquire Greenland, adding that he would not use force in his campaign for the northern island.
“I’m seeking immediate negotiations to once again to discuss the acquisition of Greenland by the Unit</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 15:00:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ICC rejects Bangladesh demand to shift T20 World Cup matches outside India</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/cricket/icc-rejects-bangladesh-demand-to-shift-t20-world-cup-matches-outside-india</link><description>The International Cricket Council on Wednesday rejected Bangladesh's demand to shift their matches at next month's Twenty20 World Cup outside India, dismissing any security threat to the team following political tensions between the South Asian neighbours.
Uncertainty loomed over the global showpi</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 15:15:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Police recover and return 105 lost mobile phones to owners in Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/police-recover-and-return-105-lost-mobile-phones-to-owners-in-dhaka</link><description>Police have recovered 105 mobile phones lost at different times and returned them to their rightful owners in the capital.
The recovered phones were handed over by Paltan Model Police Station of the Dhaka Metropolitan Police (DMP).
DMP’s Deputy Commissioner (Media) Talebur Rahman said polic</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 15:30:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Candidates allocated symbols, campaign begins on Thursday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/candidates-allocated-symbols-campaign-begins-on-thursday</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has completed the allocation of symbols for 1,973 candidates contesting 298 constituencies across the country for the upcoming 13th national parliamentary election.
With the symbol allocation completed, candidates will be able to start their campaigns from Thursday, EC</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 15:46:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US looks forward to working with all Bangladeshi political parties: Ambassador</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/us-looks-forward-to-working-with-all-bangladeshi-political-parties-ambassador</link><description>Expressing optimism over the future of the two countries, US Ambassador to Bangladesh Brent T. Christensen on Wednesday said his country does not take any side and it is the 'sovereign decision' of the people of Bangladesh whom they want.
“We don't take any side," he said during his first in</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 16:01:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Eight UNOs transferred with EC consent</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/eight-unos-transferred-with-ec-consent</link><description>The government has transferred Upazila Nirbahi Officers (UNOs) of eight upazilas with the consent of the Election Commission.
The Ministry of Public Administration issued a notification in this regard on Tuesday.
As per the order, Israt Jahan, UNO of Patharghata in Barguna, has been transferred t</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 16:16:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fraternal clash between BNP activists in Mymensingh leaves 10 injured</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/fraternal-clash-between-bnp-activists-in-mymensingh-leaves-10-injured</link><description>At least 10 people were injured in a clash between the supporter groups of two BNP leaders in Mymensingh-10 (Gafargaon) constituency on Wednesday evening.
The clash occurred in front of Islamia School in Gafargaon after election symbols were allocated for the constituency. Supporters of Akhtaruzza</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 16:31:01 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>