<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 04:40:51 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Language Movement veteran Ahmed Rafiq dies</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ahmed-rafiq-iconic-language-movement-activist-dies-at-96</link><description>Veteran Language Movement activist and researcher Ahmed Rafiq has died in Dhaka at the age of 96.
He breathed his last at 10:12pm on Thursday at Dhaka’s BIRDEM Hospital after doctors removed his ventilation support, cultural activist Dipanto Rayhan, who was present at the hospital, told bdne</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 17:22:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>34km tailback on Dhaka-Sylhet Highway</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/34km-traffic-gridlock-on-dhaka-sylhet-highway-for-two-days</link><description>Traffic on the Dhaka-Sylhet highway has been at a standstill for two consecutive days, leaving passengers stranded across a 34km stretch from Ashuganj roundabout in Brahmanbaria to Madhabpur in Habiganj.
The congestion, which began around 2am on Wednesday, continued through Thursday evening.
High</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 17:53:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fuel-import reliance rendering BD susceptible to external shocks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/fuel-import-reliance-rendering-bd-susceptible-to-external-shocks</link><description>Years of electricity-generation expansion falls short of catering Bangladesh's demand and its reliance on imported fossil fuels leaves the country susceptible to global price shocks and supply shortages, experts alert.
A new report by the International Institute of Energy Economics and Financial A</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 18:23:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh looks for new financiers as Indian LoC projects stall</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh-looks-for-new-financiers-as-indian-loc-projects-stall</link><description>Bangladesh had to forsake Indian line of credit (LoC) support for three major infrastructure projects after months of noncooperation from the lender and contractors after the regime change through July 2024 uprising.
Dhaka is now looking for alternative funding sources to keep the delayed schemes</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 02:35:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BIDA wavers over permitting tobacco sector investment</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bida-wavers-over-permitting-tobacco-sector-investment</link><description>A proposed export-oriented joint venture in tobacco sector has put Bangladesh Investment Development Authority (BIDA) in wavering over investment permission because of restrictions from the top court and health ministry.
Officials say the issue came to the spotlight after a proposal was placed to</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 03:16:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Drone sightings disrupt Munich airport, halt flights and impact thousands</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/drone-sightings-disrupt-munich-airport-halt-flights-and-impact-thousands</link><description>Germany's Munich airport said early on Friday that drone sightings on Thursday evening had forced air traffic control to suspend operations, leading to the cancellation of 17 flights and disrupting travel for nearly 3,000 passengers.
Another 15 arriving flights were diverted to Stuttgart, Nurember</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 03:31:47 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>