<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 04:23:18 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Towards an austerity-driven revised FY26 budget</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/towards-an-austerity-driven-revised-fy26-budget</link><description>As far as a new fiscal year's budget is concerned, it was a tradition that its size would be bigger than that of the previous fiscal year. But the interim government seems to have departed from that norm by reducing the size of FY26's budget compared with the FY25's reflecting a move towards fiscal</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 20:53:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Major dev partners follow 'wait and watch' policy amid political transition</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/major-dev-partners-follow-wait-and-watch-policy-amid-political-transition</link><description>At least five key development partners of Bangladesh fid not make any foreign- aid commitment in the first quarter of this fiscal year, as they seem waiting for the next elected government, insiders said Friday, as post-uprising transition is underway.



In addition, Bangladesh's largest devel</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 21:08:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Green, sustainable financing down in Q2 of 2025</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/green-sustainable-financing-down-in-q2-of-2025</link><description>Bangladesh's banks and finance companies (FCs) witnessed a notable slowdown in both green-and sustainable-finance disbursements during the April-June 2025 period, reflecting weaker momentum in environment-friendly and socially responsible lending compared to the previous quarter.
According to the</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 01:48:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>220MW Sonagazi solar plant to get Tk 2.46b cost cut ahead of approval</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/220mw-sonagazi-solar-plant-to-get-tk-246b-cost-cut-ahead-of-approval</link><description>The cost of the proposed 220-megawatt solar photovoltaic (PV) power plant in Sonagazi, Feni, is set to be reduced by Tk 2.46 billion before final approval, following recommendations from a recent meeting of the Project Evaluation Committee (PEC) of the Planning Commission, officials said.
The Powe</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 02:03:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Diplomatic channels move to settle HSIA 3rd terminal payment impasse</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/diplomatic-channels-move-to-settle-hsia-3rd-terminal-payment-impasse</link><description>Diplomatic efforts are underway to resolve a financial dispute between the contractor of Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport's (HSIA) third terminal and the Civil Aviation Authority of Bangladesh (CAAB), after the issue drew the attention of both the South Korean and Japanese embassies in Dhaka.</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 02:33:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Revised DAP: Realtors in quandary for contractionary complex FAR arithmetic</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/realtors-in-quandary-for-contractionary-complex-far-arithmetic</link><description>Realtors decry house-floor squeeze under the revised the Detailed Area Plan (DAP) arithmetic as they say it makes difficult for them to get optimum achievable FAR in the sprawling capital city.
The newly introduced, more complex calculation method for determining Floor Area Ratio (FAR) could resul</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 02:48:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Stocks slip into red amid flurry of earnings results</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/stocks-slip-into-red-amid-flurry-of-earnings-results</link><description>The benchmark index of the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) slipped into the red this week, reversing a single-week of gains, as risk-averse investors largely stayed on the sidelines amid the ongoing earnings disclosures.
Market analysts noted that investors appeared cautious, adopting a 'wait-and-see'</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 04:08:17 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>