<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 10:38:41 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Fascist, their cohorts behind conspiracy to unsettle CHT: Home adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fascist-their-cohorts-behind-conspiracy-to-unsettle-cht-destroy-communal-harmony-home-adviser</link><description>Adviser to the Ministry of Home Affairs Lt Gen (Retd) Md Jahangir Alam Chowdhury on Sunday said that fascist elements and their cohorts are behind the conspiracy to create unrest in the Chittagong Hill Tracts (CHT) region and to ruin communal harmony by adding a beard to the face of ‘Oshur&amp;rs</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 08:41:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Petition filed to detain NSU student Apurbo in jail</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/petition-filed-to-detain-nsu-student-apurbo-in-jail</link><description>Police have petitioned to have North South University (NSU) student Apurbo Pal detained in jail over allegations of “insulting the Quran”.
Sub-Inspector Chand Mia of Vatara Police Station, the investigating officer in the case, filed the petition in court on Sunday, reports bdnews24.co</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 09:11:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UK Trade Envoy visits Bangladesh; long-term economic growth, trade on agenda</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/uk-trade-envoy-visits-bangladesh-long-term-economic-growth-trade-on-agenda</link><description>British Trade Envoy to Bangladesh Baroness Winterton of Doncaster DBE has arrived in Dhaka on a five-day official visit aimed at deepening the longstanding trade and investment relationship between the UK and Bangladesh.
The Trade Envoy's mission will reinforce the UK's commitment to supporting Ba</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 08:13:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Swiss ambassador meets Jamaat-e-Islami chief Shafiqur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/swiss-ambassador-meets-jamaat-e-islami-chief-shafiqur</link><description>Switzerland’s Ambassador to Bangladesh, Reto Renggli, has held talks with Jamaat-e-Islami chief Shafiqur Rahman in Dhaka.
The meeting took place at the Jamaat leader’s office in Bashundhara around 9am on Sunday, the party said in a statement.
The diplomat was accompanied by Counsellor</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 08:28:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No evidence of sexual harassment found in Khagrachhari girl’s report: Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/no-evidence-of-sexual-harassment-found-in-khagrachhari-girls-report-adviser</link><description>No evidence of sexual harassment has been found in the medical report over the alleged rape of an indigenous girl in Khagrachhari district, said Home Affairs Adviser Lt Gen (retd) Md Jahangir Alam Chowdhury on Sunday.
He made the statement following a meeting of the law and order core committee at</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 08:43:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BCB election to go ahead as Supreme Court chamber upholds stay order</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/bcb-election-to-go-ahead-as-supreme-court-chamber-upholds-stay-order</link><description>The Bangladesh Cricket Board (BCB) election, scheduled for Monday (October 06), will proceed as planned after the Supreme Court’s chamber judge upheld a High Court order suspending the effect of a letter issued by BCB President Aminul Islam on September 18 regarding councillor nominations.
O</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 09:13:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>8 AL leaders, activists arrested in Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/8-al-leaders-activists-arrested-in-dhaka</link><description>Detectives of Dhaka Metropolitan Police (DMP) arrested eight leaders and activists of Awami League from different areas in the capital on Sunday.
The arrestees were Enamul Kabir Emon, 51, member of Central committee of AL, Emdadul Haque, office secretary of Dhaka South Metropolitan unit AL, Moshar</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 09:58:11 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>