<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 14:41:16 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>YouTube to pay $24.5 million to settle Trump account suspension suit</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/youtube-to-pay-245-million-to-settle-trump-account-suspension-suit</link><description>Alphabet-owned YouTube has agreed to pay $24.5 million to settle a lawsuit that U.S. President Donald Trump brought against the company over the suspension of his account following the January 2021 U.S. Capitol riots, a court filing showed on Monday.
The deal makes Google the last of the three big</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 11:23:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prof Yunus at UNGA: Press Secretary outlines 6 key achievements</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/prof-yunus-at-unga-press-secretary-outlines-6-key-achievements</link><description>Chief Adviser’s Press Secretary Shafiqul Alam on Friday listed six major achievements during Chief Adviser Prof Muhammad Yunus’ recent UNGA tour, including his government’s democratic commitment and vision for a collaborative future.
Prof Yunus led Bangladesh’s high-level d</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 11:38:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Elon Musk becomes world’s first half-trillionaire</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/elon-musk-becomes-worlds-first-half-trillionaire</link><description>Elon Musk on Wednesday became the first person to surpass $500 billion in net worth, powered by a rebound in Tesla's share price this year and swelling valuations of his other tech ventures.
The milestone comes just under a year after Musk's net worth crossed $400 billion and underscores his lead</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 11:53:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Israel intercepts last Gaza flotilla boat, begins deportations</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/israel-intercepts-last-gaza-flotilla-boat-begins-deportations</link><description>The Israeli military intercepted the last boat in an aid flotilla attempting to reach blockaded Gaza on Friday, a day after stopping most of the vessels and detaining some 450 activists including Swedish campaigner Greta Thunberg.
The organisers of the Global Sumud Flotilla said the Marinette was</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 12:23:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Indian Army chief threatens to ‘wipe Pakistan off Map’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/indian-army-chief-threatens-to-wipe-pakistan-off-map</link><description>India’s Army chief Gen Upendra Dwivedi has issued a sharp warning to Pakistan, accusing the country of fuelling terrorism and threatening its existence on the map unless it ends state-backed militancy.
Speaking at an Army post in Rajasthan’s Anupgarh on Friday, Gen Dwivedi said Indian</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 12:42:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Turag boat capsize: Child’s body recovered</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/childs-body-recovered-from-turag-river-after-boat-capsize-another-still-missing</link><description>Rescuers have recovered the body of a child after a boat capsized in the Turag River at Kaliakair in Gazipur, leaving another child still missing.
A diving team from Tongi Fire Station pulled out the body along with the sunken boat around 11am on Friday, said Md Alauddin, deputy assistant director</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 12:57:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Islami Bank regains control of its Facebook page</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/islami-bank-regains-control-of-its-facebook-page</link><description>The Islami Bank Bangladesh PLC regained control of its official Facebook page on Friday afternoon, nearly 10 hours after it was hacked.
Local news portals said the page was hacked around 5:42 am, and the authorities of the bank regained the control around 4:00 pm on Friday.
Nazrul Islam, head of</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 13:12:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>22-day hilsa fishing ban to begin Friday midnight</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/22-day-hilsa-fishing-ban-to-begin-friday-midnight</link><description>A 22-day ban on hilsa fishing will come into effect across the country’s rivers and marine waters from Friday midnight with a view to protecting the species during its peak breeding season.
Fisheries and Livestock Adviser Farida Akhter outlined the ban at a press conference on Monday at the</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 13:42:21 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>