<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 17:19:26 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Fully extinguishing Keraniganj building fire may take yet another day</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fully-extinguishing-keraniganj-building-fire-may-take-yet-another-day</link><description>Firefighters have contained the blaze in a multi-storey building in Keraniganj after more than 11 and a half hours, though full extinguishment is expected to take at least another day.
Fire Service teams succeeded in taming the blaze at 5:03pm on Saturday following efforts by 20 units, but removin</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 15:00:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC directs police to tighten security at all election offices after recent attacks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-directs-police-to-tighten-security-at-all-election-offices-after-recent-attacks</link><description>In the wake of recent attacks targeting candidates and election facilities, the Election Commission (EC) has instructed police to beef up security at election offices nationwide, including those of the chief election commissioner, commissioners, the EC secretary, and returning officers.
The direct</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 15:16:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CA to witness flypast, paratrooping at Tejgaon Parade Ground on Victory Day</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ca-to-witness-flypast-paratrooping-at-tejgaon-parade-ground-on-victory-day</link><description>Chief Adviser (CA) Professor Dr Muhammad Yunus will witness the flypast and paratrooping of Bangladesh Army, Navy and Air Forces at Tejgaon Parade Ground as part of celebrating the Great Victory Day on December 16.
A release of the Inter Services Public Relations (ISPR) Directorate stated this on</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 15:31:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Aid is built for yesterday’s crises: Communities are building what comes next</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/aid-is-built-for-yesterdays-crises-communities-are-building-what-comes-next</link><description>The humanitarian sector is running out of road. I write this from the Regional Humanitarian Partnership Meeting 2025, where actors from across the Global South are confronting a truth it is no longer possible to ignore: the world has entered an age of overlapping, fast-moving crises that our system</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 15:46:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nation to observe Martyred Intellectuals Day on Sunday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nation-to-observe-martyred-intellectuals-day-on-sunday</link><description>The nation is set to observe the Martyred Intellectuals Day on Sunday to commemorate the intellectuals killed systematically by Pakistan occupation forces and their local collaborators at the fag-end of the Liberation War in 1971.
On this day in 1971, the country’s renowned academicians, doc</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 16:01:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Roots of Hadi's would-be assassins to be uprooted: Attorney General</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/roots-of-hadis-would-be-assassins-to-be-uprooted-attorney-general</link><description>Attorney General Md Asaduzzaman on Saturday warned that the roots of those responsible for attacking Inqilab Mancha spokesperson Sharif Osman Hadi would be uprooted, no matter how strong they are.
He said Sharif Osman Hadi is a hero of the July mass uprising and is currently undergoing treatment a</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 15:49:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BGB on alert in Chuadanga, Meherpur after attempted assassination of Hadi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bgb-on-alert-in-chuadanga-meherpur-after-attempted-assassination-of-hadi</link><description>The Border Guard Bangladesh (BGB) has imposed maximum alert along all borders of Chuadanga and Meherpur districts following the attempted assassination of Sharif Osman Hadi, spokesperson of Inquilab Mancha and a potential independent candidate for Dhaka-8.
Security has been stepped up to prevent t</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 16:04:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>War and peace: the role of merchants of death</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/war-and-peace-the-role-of-merchants-of-death</link><description>War is as old as human beings life on earth. The main cause of war between territorial entities has been land and occasionally water. The first remains the pre-eminent reason why wars - local, regional or global - have taken place throughout human history. Land is at the heart of the recent devasta</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 16:19:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Time for piloting CDBC in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/reviews/time-for-piloting-cdbc-in-bangladesh</link><description>In the era of massive technological diffusion, digital transformation, and aggressive cashless transactions, Bangladesh has been in a strong position. Online banking, digital banking and mobile banking through mobile apps are growing faster than ever before. Bangladesh is also relentless in its dig</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 16:34:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Attack on Hadi and a complacent home adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/attack-on-hadi-and-a-complacent-home-adviser</link><description>The shooting of Sharif Osman Hadi on Friday afternoon in the city's Paltan area has left the entire nation shell-shocked. He is reportedly in a critical condition now and fighting for his life at Evercare Hospital. Hadi, an independent MP candidate from the Dhaka-8 constituency, has been in the van</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 16:49:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>From Bengal-partition to Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/from-bengal-partition-to-bangladesh</link><description>Day after tomorrow, on Tuesday to be precise, Bangladesh will observe the 55th Victory Day, commemorating the final victory over the Pakistani occupation army in the nine-month bloody war of independence in 1971. On December 16, 1971, Bangladesh emerged as a sovereign country on the world map. The</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 17:04:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Healing the banks through Truth Commission</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/healing-the-banks-through-truth-commission</link><description>Nations emerging from prolonged misrule often find that their financial system has been hollowed out far more deeply than meets the eye, eroded by years of politically motivated lending, normalisation of misconduct and weak regulation. Bangladesh today faces precisely such a reckoning, with non-per</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 17:19:25 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>