<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 08:32:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>ICB fund injection drives DSE back above 5,000 after 3 weeks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/icb-fund-injection-drives-dse-back-above-5000-after-3-weeks</link><description>The benchmark equity index of the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) crossed the 5,000-mark threshold after three weeks on Monday, largely supported by the Investment Corporation of Bangladesh (ICB).
The state-run investment bank began injecting funds into the market this week after receiving Tk 10 billio</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 05:26:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Australian far-right senator wears burqa to parliament, sparking outrage</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/australian-far-right-senator-wears-burqa-to-parliament-sparking-outrage</link><description>Australian far-right Senator Pauline Hanson wore a burqa to Parliament on Monday as a political prop in her push to ban the Muslim garment in public, sparking accusations of racism from Muslim senators over the stunt.
Hanson wore the burqa shortly after she was denied permission to introduce a bil</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 05:41:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>French poll shows far-right leader Bardella winning presidential election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/french-poll-shows-far-right-leader-bardella-winning-presidential-election</link><description>French pollster Odoxa predicted for the first time that 30-year-old far-right leader Jordan Bardella would win the next presidential election, scheduled in 2027, no matter who his opponents would be.
The current president of far-right National Rally (RN) party, and heir to long-time leader Marine</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 05:29:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>'Return' to China not an option for Taiwan's people, premier says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/return-to-china-not-an-option-for-taiwans-people-premier-says-responding-to-xi</link><description>Taiwan Premier Cho Jung-tai said on Tuesday that a "return" to China is not an option for the island's 23 million people, after Chinese President Xi Jinping pressed his country's sovereignty claims in a call with U.S. President Donald Trump.
Xi told Trump on Monday that Taiwan's "return to China"</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 05:44:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Well-marked low over Bay likely to intensify: Met office</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/well-marked-low-over-bay-likely-to-intensify-met-office</link><description>The well-marked low over South Andaman Sea and adjoining area persisted over the same region and is likely to move west-northwestwards and intensify further, according to Bangladesh Meteorological Department (BMD).
 
Besides, another low-pressure area has formed over southwest Bay and</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 05:59:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Thousands mourn Hezbollah commander killed in Israeli airstrike</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/thousands-mourn-hezbollah-commander-killed-in-israeli-airstrike</link><description>Thousands of people on Monday attended the funeral organized by the militant Hezbollah group for its top military commander, a day after he was killed in an Israeli airstrike on a southern suburb of Beirut.
 
Hezbollah supporters walked by Haytham Tabtabai’s coffin, draped in the group</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 06:14:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Unregulated poultry farms push Feni into a growing environmental crisis</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/unregulated-poultry-farms-push-feni-into-a-growing-environmental-crisis</link><description>Unplanned, unregulated and unapproved poultry farms across Feni district are triggering severe environmental pollution, disrupting local biodiversity and putting thousands of residents at risk, according to locals and officials.
 
Residents have filed repeated complaints with government offi</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 06:29:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump begins process of labeling Muslim Brotherhood chapters as terrorist</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/trump-begins-process-of-labeling-muslim-brotherhood-chapters-as-terrorist</link><description>US President Donald Trump on Monday began the process of designating certain Muslim Brotherhood chapters as foreign terrorist organisations and specially designated global terrorists, a move that would bring sanctions against one of the Arab world's oldest and most influential Islamist movements.</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 06:44:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Australian Senate suspends far-right leader over 'disrespectful' burqa stunt</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/australian-senate-suspends-far-right-leader-over-disrespectful-burqa-stunt</link><description>Australia's Senate on Tuesday suspended far-right Senator Pauline Hanson for seven sitting days after she wore a burqa to Parliament as a political prop in her campaign to ban the Muslim garment in public, triggering condemnation from lawmakers.
Hanson wore the burqa in the upper house on Monday a</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 06:59:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ageing populations a 'ticking time bomb' for GDP growth, says EBRD</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/global/ageing-populations-a-ticking-time-bomb-for-gdp-growth-says-ebrd</link><description>Countries must act now to keep slowing population growth from wreaking havoc on their long-term economic prospects, the European Bank for Reconstruction and Development said in a semi-annual report on Tuesday.
The report said ageing populations have already begun to hinder economic growth in some</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 07:14:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Don’t hire politically linked election observers: CEC Nasir</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dont-hire-politically-linked-election-observers-cec-nasir</link><description>Chief Election Commissioner (CEC) AMM Nasir Uddin on Tuesday called on local election observation organisations not to appoint any person involved in politics or any party as they are field-level observers to ensure their neutral role in the upcoming national election.
“Please make sure that</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 07:29:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Metro Rail cards can now be recharged online</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/metro-rail-cards-can-now-be-recharged-online</link><description>From now on, passengers using the Dhaka Metro Rail can recharge their travel passes online.
The service was inaugurated at the capital's Agargaon Metro Station on Tuesday morning.
As a result, the Rapid Pass or MRT Pass can be recharged from home or through mobile phones anywhere without waiting</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 07:44:14 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>