<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 09:34:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>City getting back to normal after polls fever</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/city-getting-back-to-normal-after-polls-fever</link><description>The life in the capital started getting back to normal after much expected national elections and referendum held on Thursday.
The shopping malls and markets at different areas reopened on Friday, with the vehicular movement on the city streets and roads high on the day compared to Thursday (Feb 1</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 05:50:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CA congratulates Tarique on landslide victory</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ca-congratulates-tarique-on-landslide-victory</link><description>Chief Adviser of the Interim Government Professor Muhammad Yunus has extended warm congratulations to Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) Chairman Tarique Rahman on securing an overwhelming majority in the 13th Jatiya Sangsad election. 
In a congratulatory message, the Chief Adviser said, "I c</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 06:05:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bhutanese PM congratulates Tarique Rahman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/bhutanese-pm-congratulates-tarique-rahman</link><description>Prime Minister of Bhutan Tshering Tobgay today congratulated Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) Chairman Tarique Rahman on his party's massive victory in the general elections.
"Warmest congratulations to Mr. Tarique Rahman and the BNP on winning the Bangladesh General Elections," the Bhutanese Pr</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 06:20:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US military preparing for potentially weeks-long Iran operations</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/us-military-preparing-for-potentially-weeks-long-iran-operations</link><description>The US military is preparing for the possibility of sustained, weeks-long operations against Iran if President Donald Trump orders an attack, two US officials told Reuters, in what could become a far more serious conflict than previously seen between the countries.
The disclosure by the officials,</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 06:46:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>MPs will be sworn in by Feb 17, says press secretary</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/mps-will-be-sworn-in-by-feb-17-says-press-secretary</link><description>The swearing-in of elected members of parliament will take place by February 16 or at the latest by February 17, according to the Chief Adviser’s Press Secretary Shafiqul Alam.
Speaking to reporters at the Foreign Service Academy in Dhaka on Saturday, he said the oath-taking process will be</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 07:01:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US Secretary of State congratulates Tarique</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/us-secretary-of-state-congratulates-tarique</link><description>US Secretary of State Marco Rubio has congratulated the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) Chairman Tarique Rahman on his party's electoral victory and expressed Washington's interest in working with the new government.
"Congratulations to the Bangladesh Nationalist Party and its leader, Tarique R</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 07:16:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh election credible and competitive: EU Chief Observer Ivars Ijabs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-election-credible-and-competitive-eu-chief-observer-ivars-ijabs</link><description>Chief Observer of the European Union Election Observation Mission (EU EOM) to Bangladesh Ivars Ijabs on Saturday described the national election as ‘credible, hugely and genuinely competitive and pluralistic’ but observed that there were lack of proper women's representation.
Regarding</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 07:31:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hotel Sarina celebrates Valentine’s Day with Curated Dining and Stay Experiences for Couples</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/hotel-sarina-celebrates-valentines-day-with-curated-dining-and-stay-experiences-for-couples</link><description>This Valentine’s Day, Hotel Sarina Dhaka is spreading love from every corner by presenting a range of thoughtfully curated dining and stay experiences designed exclusively for couples. With diverse cuisines, romantic ambiances, and multiple experiences under one roof, the hotel aims to make V</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 07:46:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Awami League open to talks with Tarique, says Joy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/awami-league-open-to-talks-with-tarique-says-joy</link><description>As Tarique Rahman prepares to lead a BNP government with a two-thirds majority, Sajeeb Wazed Joy says the Awami League would be willing to engage with him despite branding the Feb 12 election a “complete sham”.
In an interview with British broadcaster ITV, the son of deposed prime mi</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 08:01:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Basanta Utsab blooms with hope for 'open cultural windows'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/basanta-utsab-blooms-with-hope-for-open-cultural-windows</link><description>The Basanta Utsab has drawn a packed crowd to the lobby of the Liberation War Museum in Dhaka's Agargaon, with barely any room to move as spring revellers turn out in large numbers.
Most attendees have come dressed in shades of yellow, some with friends, others with parents and family members, whi</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 08:16:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>What perks do Bangladesh MPs enjoy?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/what-perks-do-bangladesh-mps-enjoy</link><description>As the process of forming the 13th Jatiya Sangsad gets underway following the national election, public attention has once again turned to the state privileges enjoyed by members of parliament (MPs).
The Election Commission (EC) has published the two gazette notifications of the 297 newly elected</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 08:31:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ali Riaz calls for implementing reforms following referendum verdict</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/prof-ali-riaz-calls-for-implementing-reforms-following-referendum-verdict</link><description>Chief Adviser’s Special Assistant Professor Ali Riaz on Sunday urged political parties to implement the reforms in line with the referendum verdict, noting that the overwhelming ‘Yes’ vote reflects a clear public mandate for change.
“The citizens of Bangladesh gave, in a cl</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 09:34:27 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>