<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 04:42:46 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Singer Noble's marriage 'no shield' from rape trial</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/entertainment/singer-nobles-prison-marriage-to-complainant-cannot-erase-rape-charges-police-say</link><description>Marriage cannot absolve singer Mainul Ahsan Noble of rape charges, Demra Police Inspector Murad Hossain has said.
Murad, the investigating officer, submitted a charge sheet against the musician on Nov 29, accusing him of raping the complainant, filming the assaults and physically abusing her while</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 18:27:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC bars early election campaigning</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/election-commission-orders-halt-to-early-campaigning-for-february-polls</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has ordered an immediate halt to early campaigning for the parliamentary elections.
It also instructed authorities to ensure compliance with the election code of conduct at religious, social and national programmes.
The EC issued the directive to all returning officer</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 18:42:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Levying fees on state guarantees against risk-laden loans likely</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/levying-fees-on-state-guarantees-against-risk-laden-loans-likely</link><description>A government move gets underway for revising the fee structure for state guarantees against both foreign and domestic loans to introduce a risk-based pricing mechanism to reduce fiscal exposure and strengthen financial discipline in borrowing institutions.



Officials say the move is intended</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 19:43:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh Railway planning 2 new projects of Tk 333.08b</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-railway-planning-2-new-projects-of-tk-33308b</link><description>Bangladesh Railway (BR) plans to take on 19 new projects, including two on the Dhaka-Chattogram corridor involving Tk 333.08 billion, to improve the train-movement capacity of its eastern and western zones.
It has already spent over Tk 100 billion on developing double lines on the 321km Dhaka-Ch</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 01:26:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>RMG labour unrest likely before polls: Intelligence report</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rmg-labour-unrest-likely-before-polls-intelligence-report</link><description>An intelligence agency has warned of a high possibility of widespread labour unrest and instability in the readymade garment (RMG) sector, the country's largest export industry and employer of around four million workers, ahead of the national elections.
The National Security Intelligence (NSI)</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 01:41:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Judiciary seen as accomplice in misrule</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/judiciary-seen-as-accomplice-in-misrule</link><description>Chief Justice (CJ) Dr Syed Refaat Ahmed on Sunday said that during certain political periods, the judiciary was perceived as an undeclared accomplice to unconstitutional exercises of power, misrule, and state hypocrisy.
"In Bangladesh's progress, many distinguished judges have earned deep respect</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 01:56:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Thailand looks to sign free trade deal with Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/thailand-looks-to-sign-free-trade-deal-with-bangladesh</link><description>Thailand has expressed strong interest in opening negotiations on a bilateral free-trade agreement with Bangladesh, a move that could significantly expand trade and encourage Thai investment, as Dhaka intensifies efforts to deepen economic and diplomatic engagement with South-east Asia.
The newly-</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 02:11:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ACC approves case against S Alam Group, Zaman Syndicate</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/acc-approves-case-against-s-alam-group-zaman-syndicate</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) on Sunday approved filing a case against the "Zaman Syndicate," linked to Nabil Group, and officials of S Alam Group, over a Tk 10.08-billion-loan fraud and money laundering at Islami Bank Bangladesh PLC's Pabna branch.
According to the ACC, Md Aminul Islam, ma</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 02:26:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>T-bill yields rise ahead of year-end closing</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/t-bill-yields-rise-ahead-of-year-end-closing</link><description>Yields on treasury bills (T-bills), particularly long-term ones, rose on Sunday as banks appeared reluctant to park excess liquidity in government securities ahead of the year-end closing.
The cut-off yield on 91-day T-bills remained unchanged at 10.55 per cent, while the yield on 182-day T-bills</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 02:41:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Large-caps drive volatility in struggling stock market</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/large-caps-drive-volatility-in-struggling-stock-market</link><description>The wobbling equity market has experienced heightened volatility over the past three weeks, driven primarily by significant price erosion among market leaders, including Grameenphone.
A combination of factors, including a decline in foreign portfolio investments, concerns over the viability of s</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 02:56:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>First Security Islami Bank reveals true financial health</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/first-security-islami-bank-reveals-true-financial-health</link><description>First Security Islami Bank has shocked its stakeholders by revealing a staggering loss of Tk 575.8 billion for the first nine months of 2025, significantly increasing the losses previously reported for the same period.
This revision follows a directive from Bangladesh Bank, which has raised concer</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 03:41:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BD’s capital market missing from global investment discourse</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/bds-capital-market-missing-from-global-investment-discourse</link><description>Bangladesh remains largely absent from global and regional discussions on capital markets and investment, former Bangladesh Bank governor Dr Mohammed Farashuddin said on Saturday.
He noted that stock markets in cities such as Karachi, Lahore, Mumbai, Bangkok and Colombo -- and even Bhutan -- are r</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 03:56:54 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>