<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 08:28:35 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Rain, thundershowers likely over Rangpur, Rajshahi, Mymensingh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rain-thundershowers-likely-over-rangpur-rajshahi-mymensingh42</link><description>Bangladesh Meteorological Department (BMD) forecast rain or thundershowers at many places over Rangpur, Rajshahi and Mymensingh divisions in the next 24 hours beginning from 9:00 am today.
“Light to moderate rain or thundershowers is likely to occur at most places over Rangpur, Rajshahi and</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 05:47:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IUB's Ive Sithi Chambugong to represent Bangladesh at Int'l Gold Event in Nigeria</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/iubs-ive-sithi-chambugong-to-represent-bangladesh-at-intl-gold-event-in-nigeria</link><description>Ive Sithi Chambugong, an undergraduate student of Biochemistry and Biotechnology at Independent University, Bangladesh (IUB), will represent Bangladesh at the International Gold Event (IGE) and Forum 2025 in Lagos, Nigeria, from November 16-22, 2025. She is a DEA Gold Award Holder and the first ele</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 06:02:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh braces for surge in elderly population</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-braces-for-surge-in-elderly-population</link><description>Bangladesh is facing a rapidly aging population, with a new study projecting the 60+ age group will grow from 13 percent in 2020 to over 30 percent by 2050.
These findings were released at an event in Dhaka Tuesday as part of launching Bangladesh's first-ever Country Diagnostic Study (CDS) on Long</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 06:17:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique calls for childcare plan to empower women</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-calls-for-childcare-plan-to-empower-women</link><description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman has called for building Bangladesh in a way where every working mother and every female student has the freedom to thrive, instead of being forced to leave work or education due to a lack of adequate childcare.
In a post on his verified Facebook page on Thursday,</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 06:32:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Indices rise in first hour of trading at DSE, CSE</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/indices-rise-in-first-hour-of-trading-at-dse-cse</link><description>The country's stock markets began the last working day of the week on a positive note, with key indices at both the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) and Chittagong Stock Exchange (CSE) edging up in the first hour of trading on Thursday.
At the DSE, the benchmark DSEX index gained 17 points, while the Sh</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 06:45:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat among eight parties submit memorandum to EC demanding Nov referendum</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-among-eight-parties-submit-memorandum-to-ec-demanding-nov-referendum</link><description>Eight political parties, including Jamaat-e-Islami and Islami Andolan Bangladesh, on Thursday submitted a memorandum to the Election Commission (EC), demanding a referendum in November and implementation of the July National Charter.
 
The parties held a short rally in front of Nirbanchan Bh</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 07:00:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BGB sends 107 Rohingya back to camp</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bgb-sends-107-rohingya-back-to-camp</link><description>Border Guard Bangladesh (BGB) has taken 107 Rohingya, including women and children, who roamed outside their camps into custody and has sent them back to refugee camps in Cox's Bazar' Teknaf.
In a press statement issued in the early hours of Thursday, Lt Col Ashikur Rahman, commander of BGB's Tekn</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 07:30:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fire guts seven shops in Satkhira</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fire-guts-seven-shops-in-satkhira</link><description>At least seven business structures were gutted in a fire at Hazrakati Bazar in Tala upazila of Satkhira district on Thursday.
Officer-in-charge Mainuddin of Tala Police Station said the fire erupted from one of the shops around 3:00 am and engulfed the adjacent others, reports UNB.
Being informed</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 07:45:37 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>