<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 06:47:43 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Learning a lesson of cosmopolitanism in the capital</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/analysis/learning-a-lesson-of-cosmopolitanism-in-the-capital</link><description>Is Bangladesh a nation of forgers? When such denigration comes from none other than the head of the government, one who is a recipient of the highest award on offer in the world, people cannot but look askance. In fact, any generalised perception of any race, people or nation is faulty. But this ki</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 04:11:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fortune Shoes stock price manipulation: FID seeks list of ICB employees involved</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/fortune-shoes-stock-price-manipulation-fid-seeks-list-of-icb-employees-involved</link><description>The Financial Institutions Division (FID) has asked the Bangladesh Securities and Exchange Commission (BSEC) to provide a list of Investment Corporation of Bangladesh (ICB) employees allegedly involved in the manipulation of stock price of Fortune Shoes Ltd.
This move follows an investigation repo</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 04:26:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ctg port operations resume as strike suspended</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ctg-port-operations-resume-as-strike-suspended</link><description>CHATTOGRAM, Feb 06: After a six-day halt, the operational activities at the Chittagong Port resumed on Friday as the workers suspended their strike for two days.
As a result, the loading and unloading of goods and containers from ships at the jetties and the outer anchorage, as well as the transpo</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 04:42:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Poultry, fish, lemon, cucumber prices rise well ahead of Ramadan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/poultry-fish-lemon-cucumber-prices-rise-well-ahead-of-ramadan</link><description>Poultry, fish, lemon and cucumber prices witnessed a hike in the market last week, enhancing woes of the commoners.
Broiler chicken prices increased to Tk 180-190 a kg, marking Tk 10 a kg hike. Sonali (Pakistani) chicken prices also rose to Tk 320-350 per kg, from Tk 280-300 a week ago.
Egg price</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 04:57:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Illegal arms, drugs seized in city: Five held</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/illegal-arms-drugs-seized-in-city-five-held</link><description>A large cache of illegal arms, ammunition, narcotics and cash has been recovered in joint operations conducted by the army in the capital's North Badda and Dhalpur areas.
The Inter-Services Public Relations (ISPR) disclosed the information in a press release issued on Friday, saying that five peop</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 05:12:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ISU and Asia e University Malaysia sign MoU to expand higher study opportunities</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/isu-and-asia-e-university-malaysia-sign-mou-to-expand-higher-study-opportunities</link><description>International Standard University (ISU) and Asia e University (AeU) Malaysia have signed a Memorandum of Understanding (MoU) aimed at expanding higher study opportunities, strengthening academic collaboration, and promoting joint research initiatives.
The MoU signing ceremony and a discussion sess</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 05:27:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Toyota changes CEO</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/toyota-changes-ceo</link><description>Toyota Motor's surprise CEO switch comes as global automakers confront a tumultuous industry landscape - one that the Japanese automaker has been navigating more adeptly than most.
The world's No. 1 carmaker by sales said on Friday that it is moving away from CEO Koji Sato after a three-year stint</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 05:13:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Crowds gather in Thakurgaon ahead of Tarique Rahman rally</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/crowds-gather-in-thakurgaon-ahead-of-tarique-rahman-rally</link><description>Supporters of the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) have begun gathering in Thakurgaon ahead of party chief Tarique Rahman's election rally.
In his first visit to the district in over two decades, Tarique is expected to arrive at the Government Boys’ High School ground around 11:30 am on Sa</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 05:28:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prisoner dies at Kushtia District Jail</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/prisoner-dies-at-kushtia-district-jail</link><description>A convicted prisoner died at Kushtia District Jail early Saturday.
The deceased was identified as Bidyut Ali, 27, son of Chaddu Ali of Bheramara upazila.
Kushtia Jail Super Shariful Alam said Bidyut was sent to jail about two months ago after being convicted in a drug-related case.
Initially, it</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 05:43:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India rejects any allegations of involvement in Pakistan bombing</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/india-rejects-any-allegations-of-involvement-in-pakistan-bombing</link><description>India said it rejected "any and every" allegation of involvement in a bombing at a mosque in Islamabad on Friday, that killed at least 31 people, saying such claims were baseless and pointless.
"The bombing at an Islamabad mosque earlier today is condemnable and India condoles the loss of life it</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 05:58:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Amazon shares fall as it joins Big Tech AI spending spree</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/global/amazon-shares-fall-as-it-joins-big-tech-ai-spending-spree</link><description>Amazon has announced plans to invest $200 billion (£147.7b) in artificial intelligence (AI) and infrastructure, becoming the latest US tech giant to set out a sharp rise in spending.
It dwarfs the $125bn Amazon spent on AI last year, and appeared to rattle investors. Shares were down nearly</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 06:13:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gold price in Bangladesh crosses Tk 260,000 per bhori again</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/gold-price-in-bangladesh-crosses-tk-260000-per-bhori-again</link><description>Gold prices in Bangladesh surged once again on Saturday, with the price of 22-carat gold crossing the Tk 260,000 mark per bhori, according to the Bangladesh Jewellers Association (BAJUS).
 
In a notification issued in the morning, BAJUS announced an increase of Tk 7,640 per bhori, setting th</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 06:28:54 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>