<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 11:19:52 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>KUET student suspended for stabbing fellow student</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/kuet-student-suspended-for-stabbing-fellow-student</link><description>Khulna University of Engineering and Technology (KUET) authorities have suspended a student for stabbing a fellow student over a dispute regarding street painting and stall locations for the first-year admission test.
The accused, Kazi Sadiq Mahmud, is a student of the Civil Engineering Department</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 07:22:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>39 more Bangladeshis deported from US</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/39-more-bangladeshis-deported-from-us</link><description>The United States has repatriated another group of Bangladeshi nationals, with 39 people arriving in Dhaka early Friday.
The returnees landed at Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport (HSIA) around 5:30 am on a special US military flight.
Airport authorities facilitated their arrival, while BRAC</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 08:01:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Grandmother, granddaughter killed in Chandpur road crash</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/grandmother-granddaughter-killed-in-chandpur-road-crash</link><description>A grandmother and her six-year-old granddaughter were killed when a speeding passenger bus crashed into them on the Chandpur–Cumilla regional road in Hajiganj upazila of Chandpur district on Thursday night.
The deceased were identified as Nazma Begum, and granddaughter Marzia Begum, resident</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 08:16:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>WFP provides emergency food aid fire-hit families in Korail slum</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/wfp-provides-emergency-food-aid-fire-hit-families-in-korail-slum</link><description>The United Nations World Food Programme (WFP) on Friday provided emergency food assistance to families affected by the devastating fire that swept through the Karail slum on Tuesday.
The WFP, in collaboration with the Department of Disaster Management (DDM), Dhaka North City Corporation, and partn</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 08:31:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Expatriate postal ballot registratios reach 70,660</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/expatriate-postal-ballot-registratios-reach-70660</link><description>A total of 70,660 expatriate Bangladeshis have so far registered for the country’s first-ever postal voting system, enabling them to cast their ballots in the upcoming 13th Jatiya Sangsad election and the referendum.
Updated figures on the Election Commission (EC) website show that 70,660 ex</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 09:28:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CID files Tk 16.1b money laundering case against Nafeez Sarafat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cid-files-tk-161b-money-laundering-case-against-nafeez-sarafat</link><description>The Criminal Investigation Department (CID) has filed a case accusing former Padma Bank chairman Chowdhury Nafeez Sarafat, members of his family, and an associate of laundering more than Tk 16.13 billion.
The case was lodged at Gulshan Police Station on Thursday under the Money Laundering Preventi</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 09:43:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Foreign firms challenge liquor policy of India's Maharashtra in court</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/foreign-firms-challenge-liquor-policy-of-indias-maharashtra-in-court</link><description>Diageo and Pernod Ricard’s Indian lobbying group has sued Maharashtra state over a sharp tax hike on their affordable brands and for excluding the companies from a new lower tax category reserved for some local firms.
Maharashtra accounts for 7% of India’s premium liquor consumption an</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 09:56:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bicyclist stabbed to death in Ctg</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bicyclist-stabbed-to-death-in-ctg</link><description>A bicyclist was stabbed to death by muggers in Lal Dighi area of the port city of Chattogram early Friday, said police.
The incident occurred near Zilla Parisahd Market, just a hundred yards off Kotwali Police Station around 2:30am.
The deceased was identified as Ismail Hossain, 33, a resident fr</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 10:11:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khaleda in 'critical condition': BNP;s Fakhrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/khaleda-in-critical-condition-says-bnp-mirza-fakhrul</link><description>BNP Chairperson Khaleda Zia is in a “critical condition,” Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir has told the media.
His remarks came following a special prayer session after the Jummah prayers on Friday at Paltan Central Jame Mosque.
He said, “You know that our leader Be</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 10:26:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>'Stop kowtowing to political parties': Fakhrul to journalists</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bnps-mirza-fakhrul-urges-journalists-to-steer-clear-of-partisanship</link><description>Senior BNP leader Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir has urged journalists to break free from the clutches of political parties, warning that partisanship has blighted the country’s media landscape.
Speaking at the biennial conference of the Bangladesh Federal Union of Journalists (BFUJ) at the Nat</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 10:41:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Genome study reveals milestone in history of cat domestication</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/genome-study-reveals-milestone-in-history-of-cat-domestication</link><description>Whether they are a Siamese, Persian, Maine Coon, or Domestic Shorthair, there are hundreds of millions of cats living with people around the world. But despite their popularity as pets, the history of cat domestication has remained difficult for scientists to decipher.
A new genome study is provid</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 10:56:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>At crowded Ukrainian cemetery, mourners yearn for war to end</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/at-crowded-ukrainian-cemetery-mourners-yearn-for-war-to-end</link><description>After losing her son to Russia's war in Ukraine, Olya Kachmaryk hopes a new US-backed peace plan can finally end the fighting - even if it could mean giving up land he fought for as a soldier.
"The more they (the Russians) come this way, the more they'll want," said Kachmaryk, 50, visiting his gra</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 11:11:20 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>