<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 12:39:35 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Gazans return to wrecked homes as Israeli forces pull back</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/gazans-stream-towards-wrecked-homes-as-israeli-forces-pull-back-under-ceasefire</link><description>Thousands of displaced Palestinians streamed back towards their abandoned homes on Friday after a ceasefire between Israel and Hamas went into effect and Israeli troops began pulling back from parts of Gaza.
A massive column of displaced Gazans filed north through the dust towards Gaza City, the e</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 09:43:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Japan's ruling coalition splits, throwing Takaichi's PM bid into doubt</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/japans-ruling-coalition-splits-throwing-takaichis-pm-bid-into-doubt</link><description>Sanae Takaichi's bid to become Japan's first female prime minister was thrown into doubt on Friday when her ruling party's junior coalition partner quit.
The Liberal Democratic Party, which has ruled Japan for almost all of the postwar era, selected hardline conservative Takaichi as its new</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 11:13:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Young researchers’ conference on Saturday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/young-researchers-conference-on-saturday</link><description>In a bid to explore the innovative potential and nurture the creativity of school students, ‘10th Chintar Chash Young Researcher Conference, 2025’ will take place on Saturday (October 11) at the Teacher-Student Centre (TSC), in the University of Dhaka (DU).
Dr Niaz Ahmed Khan, vice-cha</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 10:28:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump proposes barring Chinese airlines from flying over Russia on US routes</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-proposes-barring-chinese-airlines-from-flying-over-russia-on-us-routes</link><description>The Trump administration on Thursday proposed banning Chinese airlines from flying over Russia on routes to and from the United States, saying the reduced flight time this practice enables puts American carriers at a disadvantage.
The proposal is another escalation of the trade war between the wor</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 10:43:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP nomination hopefuls frustrated as party delays green signal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-nomination-hopefuls-frustrated-as-party-delays-green-signal</link><description>While candidates of their main rival party have already begun reaching out to voters, BNP nomination seekers across the country remain in limbo, awaiting the party high command's green signal, a delay that has left many grassroots leaders and activists increasingly frustrated.
Talking to UNB, seve</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 10:58:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Celebrating nutrition: BAU distributes 2,500 eggs in World Egg Day</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/celebrating-nutrition-bau-distributes-2500-eggs-in-world-egg-day</link><description>The Faculty of Veterinary Science of Bangladesh Agricultural University (BAU), celebrated World Egg Day 2025 in a festive atmosphere on Friday, recognising three outstanding contributors to the country’s egg production and poultry industry.
The honorees are Dr. Mohammad Kamruzzaman Masud, Ch</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 11:13:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Educationist Syed Manzoorul Islam is no more</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/educationist-syed-manzoorul-islam-is-no-more</link><description>Renowned educationist, fiction writer and essayist Syed Manzoorul Islam has passed away.
He breathed his last around 5pm on Friday while undergoing treatment at LabAid Hospital in the capital, Prothom Alo reports, citing Mazharul Islam, Chief Executive of Anyaprokash.
Syed Manzoorul Islam was an</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 11:28:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DU Fine Arts dean says ‘Sarat Utsob’ was postponed, not cancelled</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/du-fine-arts-dean-says-sarat-utsob-was-postponed-not-cancelled</link><description>Dhaka University's Faculty of Fine Arts Dean Azharul Islam has said reports of the “Sarat Utsob”, organised by Satyen Sen Shilpi Group to mark the arrival of autumn, being cancelled due to "objections" from some quarters are wide of the mark.
The festival has merely been postponed, rat</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 11:58:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Malaysia plans to spend $111 billion in 2026, boost tax collection</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/malaysia-plans-to-spend-111-billion-in-2026-boost-tax-collection</link><description>Malaysia said on Friday it plans to boost tax collection and strengthen social protection systems next year, as it looks to bolster government revenue amid external uncertainties.
Speaking in parliament, Prime Minister Anwar Ibrahim announced a budget of 470 billion ringgit ($111.40 billion) for 2</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 12:13:38 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>