<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 05:39:43 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Commercial engagements with Bangladesh to expand: Maldives President</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/commercial-engagements-with-bangladesh-to-expand-maldives-president</link><description>Bangladesh and the Maldives have reaffirmed their commitment to further strengthening the existing excellent bilateral relations and enhancing cooperation between the two friendly countries.
Dr Md Nazmul Islam, the newly appointed High Commissioner of Bangladesh to the Republic of Maldives, presen</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 04:22:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rome calls on US to reconsider extra tariff on pasta imports</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/rome-calls-on-us-to-reconsider-extra-tariff-on-pasta-imports</link><description>Rome is working closely with the European Commission to press the United States to reconsider an additional anti-dumping tariff on pasta imports which would effectively double their price, the Italian foreign ministry said.
The decision to impose an extra duty of 91.74 per cent is the result of pr</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 04:09:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>France names new government amid political turmoil</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/france-names-new-government-amid-political-turmoil</link><description>President Emmanuel Macron's office on Sunday unveiled a new cabinet to be led by Prime Minister Sebastien Lecornu, whose most pressing - and most perilous - task will be to win support for a 2026 budget in a fragmented and fractious parliament.
Following is the list of ministers and their posts.</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 04:39:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>To return home ‘soon’, Tarique Rahman tells BBC Bangla</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/to-return-home-soon-tarique-rahman-tells-bbc-bangla</link><description>BNP’s Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman has said he intends to return to Bangladesh “soon,” marking his first on-camera interview with the media in two decades. In an exclusive conversation with BBC Bangla, he discussed his possible return, the party’s strategy for the upcoming</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 05:09:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>'Moderate' air quality persists in Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/moderate-air-quality-persists-in-dhaka</link><description>Dhaka has ranked 33rd on the list of cities with the worst air quality with an AQI score of 66 at 9:20 am on Monday (October 6, 2025).
Dhaka's air was classified as 'moderate,' referring to a light health threat, according to the AQI index. Such air quality continued for the past few days as Dhaka</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 05:24:43 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>