<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 07:18:43 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Riding Dinajpur Commuter thru northern vista</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/analysis/riding-dinajpur-commuter-thru-northern-vista</link><description>It is a damp September morning. The early morning rain has left the long platforms of the Lalmonirhat railway station wet. The chirping of birds is heard from time to time amid the babble of passengers waiting under the blue sheds.
I walk along the bluish-yellow carriages of Dinajpur Commuter, whi</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 04:12:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>International Space Station marks 25 years of nonstop human presence in orbit</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/international-space-station-marks-25-years-of-nonstop-human-presence-in-orbit</link><description>It’s an unprecedented space streak: 25 years of people living off-planet without even a moment’s pause.
The International Space Station marks a quarter-century of continuous occupancy this weekend, boasting a guest list of nearly 300 — mostly professional astronauts but also</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 04:27:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BTRC to deactivate extra SIMs beyond limit from Saturday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/btrc-to-deactivate-extra-sims-beyond-limit-from-saturday</link><description>Mobile operators will begin from Saturday deactivating additional SIM cards registered under a single national ID (NID) if the number exceeds 10, as per a directive from the Bangladesh Telecommunication Regulatory Commission (BTRC).
In a recent notice, the regulator said that any excess SIMs will</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 04:42:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tanzania's Hassan declared landslide winner in election marred by violence</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/tanzanias-hassan-declared-landslide-winner-in-election-marred-by-violence</link><description>Tanzania's electoral commission declared on Saturday that President Samia Suluhu Hassan had won, with nearly 98 per cent of the votes, an election that set off violent protests across the country this week.
The result hands Hassan, who took power in 2021 after the death in office of her predecesso</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 04:57:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Three Bangladeshi-Americans set to take office as mayor and councilmen in US city</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/three-bangladeshi-americans-set-to-take-office-as-mayor-and-councilmen-in-us-city</link><description>Bangladeshi-origin US citizen Mahabubul Alam Tayub is set to become the mayor of Millbourne city in the state of Pennsylvania, running unopposed.
Two other Bangladeshi Americans are also set to be elected council members unopposed in the city.
The results will be officially announced after Novemb</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 05:12:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Low pressure area likely to form over east-central Bay</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/low-pressure-area-likely-to-form-over-east-central-bay</link><description>A low-pressure area is likely to form over east-central Bay and the adjoining area during the next 48 hours, commencing 9:00 am on Saturday, according to the Bangladesh Meteorological Department (BMD).
“Light to moderate rain or thunder showers is likely to occur at many places over Rangpur,</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 05:27:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Cattle lifter’ lynched in Gaibandha</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cattle-lifter-lynched-in-gaibandha</link><description>A suspected cattle lifter was killed, reportedly in a lynch-mob attack in Sundarganj upazila of Gaibandha district on Saturday.
The deceased was identified as Abdus Salam of Ramdakua village in the upazila, reports UNB.
Abdur Hakim Azad, officer-in-charge of Sundarganj Police station, said Abdus</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 05:57:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Recovering Encroached Land: New act allows administrative fix outside court</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/recovering-encroached-land-new-act-allows-administrative-fix-outside-court</link><description>The government has taken an initiative to recover encroached land and help the real owner get it back through an administrative process.
A high official at the Ministry of Land says according to the Land Crime Prevention and Remedy Act 2023, if a real owner's land is encroached by others, it can b</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 06:27:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fire breaks out at Petronas Tower 3 in Kuala Lumpur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/fire-breaks-out-at-petronas-tower-3-in-kuala-lumpur</link><description>A fire broke out at Petronas Tower 3 in Kuala Lumpur city of Malaysia, on Saturday
Malaysian news outlets reported that the fire involved a restaurant in one of the building’s upper floors, with images and videos uploaded online showing thick smoke billowing from the top of the building.
Ma</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 06:42:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>8-month ban on Jatka fishing begins</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/8-month-ban-on-jatka-fishing-begins</link><description>An eight-month nationwide ban on catching juvenile Hilsa (Jatka) began on Saturday and will remain in effect until June 30, 2026, aiming to boost Hilsa production and ensure sustainable conservation.
Supervised by the Ministry of Fisheries and Livestock and implemented by the Department of Fisheri</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 06:57:43 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>