<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 11:20:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Ageing populations a 'ticking time bomb' for GDP growth, says EBRD</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/global/ageing-populations-a-ticking-time-bomb-for-gdp-growth-says-ebrd</link><description>Countries must act now to keep slowing population growth from wreaking havoc on their long-term economic prospects, the European Bank for Reconstruction and Development said in a semi-annual report on Tuesday.
The report said ageing populations have already begun to hinder economic growth in some</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 07:14:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Don’t hire politically linked election observers: CEC Nasir</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dont-hire-politically-linked-election-observers-cec-nasir</link><description>Chief Election Commissioner (CEC) AMM Nasir Uddin on Tuesday called on local election observation organisations not to appoint any person involved in politics or any party as they are field-level observers to ensure their neutral role in the upcoming national election.
“Please make sure that</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 07:29:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Metro Rail cards can now be recharged online</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/metro-rail-cards-can-now-be-recharged-online</link><description>From now on, passengers using the Dhaka Metro Rail can recharge their travel passes online.
The service was inaugurated at the capital's Agargaon Metro Station on Tuesday morning.
As a result, the Rapid Pass or MRT Pass can be recharged from home or through mobile phones anywhere without waiting</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 07:44:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mother, two children found dead in suspected murder-suicide in Bogura</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/mother-two-children-found-dead-in-suspected-murder-suicide-in-bogura</link><description>A mother and her two children have been found dead in an apparent case of murder-suicide in Bogura's Shajahanpur Upazila.
Law enforcers believe the woman slit the throats of her children before dying by suicide, says Shafiqul Islam, chief of Shajahanpur Police Station.
The incident occurred on Tu</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 08:31:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Earthquake: 23 highly vulnerable buildings to be demolished in Sylhet</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/earthquake-23-highly-vulnerable-buildings-to-be-demolished-in-sylhet</link><description>Sylhet district administration has decided to demolish 23 buildings identified as highly vulnerable to earthquakes, beginning next week.
The decision was made at a meeting on earthquake preparedness and response held at Nagar Bhaban on Monday afternoon, UNB reports.
Divisional Commissioner and Sy</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 08:46:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Superintendents of police picked by lottery in all 64 districts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/superintendents-of-police-picked-by-lottery-in-all-64-districts</link><description>Superintendents of police (SPs) have been selected for all 64 districts through a lottery ahead of the upcoming parliamentary elections next year.
The lottery was held at the State Guest House Jamuna, the official residence of Chief Advisor Muhammad Yunus, on Monday, according to several police</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 09:32:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Plot graft: Verdict in case against British MP Tulip on Dec 1</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/plot-graft-verdict-in-case-against-british-mp-tulip-on-dec-1</link><description>A Dhaka court has fixed Dec 1 to deliver its verdict in an Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) case against ousted prime minister Sheikh Hasina, her sister Sheikh Rehana, Rehana's daughter and British MP Tulip Siddiq, and 17 others on charges of fraud in allocating plots under the Purbachal New Town P</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 09:47:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Stronger registration law essential to protecting women’s rights: Speakers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/stronger-registration-law-essential-to-protecting-womens-rights-speakers</link><description>Speakers at a webinar on Tuesday said a strong birth and death registration law is particularly important for safeguarding women’s fundamental rights, including access to education, healthcare, social protection and justice.
The webinar titled “Stronger Registration Laws to Protect Wom</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 09:48:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DMP files 1,590 cases against traffic rules violators</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dmp-files-1590-cases-against-traffic-rules-violators</link><description>Traffic Division of Dhaka Metropolitan Police (DMP) filed a total of 1,590 cases against motor vehicles and drivers for violating traffic rules in the capital over the past day.
The DMP has been conducting drives against traffic rule violations in the city to bring the traffic management system un</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 10:03:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>365,472 financial units excluded from Economic Census count: Survey</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/365472-financial-units-excluded-from-economic-census-count-survey</link><description>A total of 365,472 financial units were excluded from the count of the Economic Census, according to a survey. 
The Economic Census, conducted in 2024, had recorded over 11.88 million financial establishments, but a later Post Enumeration Check (PEC) revealed that the national Net Coverage Er</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 10:18:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two to die in Cumilla murder case</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/two-to-die-in-cumilla-murder-case</link><description>A court on Tuesday sentenced two people to death and five others to life term imprisonment in a murder case in Chauddagram upazila of the district in 2013.
Judge of Additional Sessions Judge's Court-3 Sabrina Nargis delivered the verdict on Tuesday afternoon. 
The death-row convicts are Zia</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 10:33:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt finalizes SPs for 64 districts through lottery</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-finalizes-sps-for-64-districts-through-lottery</link><description>The interim government has finalized the appointments of Superintendents of Police (SPs) for all 64 districts through a lottery system ahead of the upcoming 13th national parliament elections.
The lottery was conducted on Monday at the residence of the Chief Adviser, Jamuna, in the presence of Act</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 10:48:47 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>