<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 16:25:18 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Jamaat Ameer expects next polls to create new history</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-ameer-expects-next-polls-to-create-new-history</link><description>Jamaat-e-Islami Ameer Dr. Shafiqur Rahman today (Saturday said the upcoming national election is expected to create a new history in Bangladesh, but warned any attempt to tamper the polls would face a “resolute response”.
“Any attempt to manipulate votes or occupy polling centres</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 12:44:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt writes to EC on same-day election, referendum</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/government-writes-to-ec-ordering-simultaneous-election-referendum</link><description>The interim government has formally written to the Election Commission (EC) to hold the parliamentary polls and a referendum on the same day.
EC Secretary Akhtar Ahmed confirmed the development on Saturday.
The decision follows political disagreements over the legal basis of the July Charter and</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 12:59:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Taijul leads Bangladesh’s charge to complete series sweep against Ireland</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/cricket/taijul-leads-bangladeshs-charge-to-complete-series-sweep-against-ireland</link><description>Bangladesh are four wickets away from a series sweep over Ireland on the fourth day of the Dhaka Test, with Taijul Islam dominating the attack and surpassing Shakib Al Hasan as the nation’s highest Test wicket-taker.
Ireland were 176 for 6 while chasing 509 at stumps at the Sher-e-Bangla Cri</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 13:14:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Unresolved human trafficking cases remain concerning in Bangladesh in H1 2025</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/unresolved-human-trafficking-cases-remain-concerning-in-bangladesh-in-h1-2025</link><description>The number of unresolved human- trafficking cases remained at a concerning level in Bangladesh in the first half of 2025, as ongoing investigations and court proceedings continue to delay justice for victims. While data shows a steady increase in the resolution of human trafficking cases, with seve</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 13:29:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Brazil's ex-president Bolsonaro detained by police ahead of vigil</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/brazils-ex-president-bolsonaro-detained-by-police-ahead-of-vigil</link><description>Former Brazilian president Jair Bolsonaro was taken into federal police custody on Saturday before a planned supporters' vigil near his home, ending months of house arrest as he appeals a Supreme Court conviction for plotting a coup.
Bolsonaro's attorney Celso Vilardi confirmed the detention but d</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 13:44:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fresh tremor shakes quake-cracked building, triggering worker protest in Narayanganj</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fresh-tremor-shakes-quake-cracked-building-triggering-worker-protest-in-narayanganj</link><description>Workers of a readymade garment factory in Narayanganj’s Rupganj have demonstrated after being forced to work inside the building that had been cracked in places by the earthquake that struck Bangladesh on Friday.
The demonstrators vandalised five vehicles. Over 50 workers were injured when t</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 13:59:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>6 DU students hurt amid tremor panic</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/six-students-injured-at-dhaka-university-after-fresh-quake-triggers-panic</link><description>A 3.7-magnitude tremor has left six Dhaka University students injured after they panicked and tried to rush out of their residential halls.
On Saturday, three students were hurt at Shamsun Nahar Hall, while Bangladesh-Kuwait Maitree, Begum Rokeya, and Surja Sen halls each reported one injury.
Fiv</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 14:14:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Labourers call Ctg Port blockade to protest leasing of terminals to foreign companies</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/labourers-call-ctg-port-blockade-to-protest-leasing-of-terminals-to-foreign-companies</link><description>The Sramik-Karmachari Oikya Parishad (SKOP) has announced a blockade of Chattogram Port demanding the suspension of plans to lease the New Mooring Container Terminal and the Laldiar Char terminal to foreign companies.
The decision was made public on Saturday during SKOP’s divisional conventi</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 14:29:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>60 women entrepreneurs in Jamalpur and Mymensingh complete BRAC Bank’s ‘Amrai TARA’ training</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/60-women-entrepreneurs-in-jamalpur-and-mymensingh-complete-brac-banks-amrai-tara-training</link><description>BRAC Bank, in collaboration with the Bangladesh Open-Source Network (BdOSN), has successfully organised two three-day training programmes under its flagship women entrepreneur initiative, ‘Amrai TARA’, in Jamalpur and Mymensingh.
Held from October 20–22, 2025, in Jamalpur and Oct</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 14:44:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EXIM Bank’s Business Development Meeting for Chattogram Region held</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/exim-banks-business-development-meeting-for-chattogram-region-held</link><description>EXIM Bank holds Business Development Meeting for Chattogram Region today (22 November, 2025) at the bank’s regional office Chattogram.
Administrator of EXIM Bank and Executive Director of Bangladesh Bank Md. Sawkatul Alam was present as Chief Guest while Additional Managing Director of the B</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 14:59:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two quakes shake Dhaka, Narsingdi in a second</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/two-quakes-shake-dhaka-narsingdi-in-a-second</link><description>Bangladesh has been shaken twice within seconds, with epicentres at Dhaka’s Badda and Narsingdi, according to the Meteorological Department’s Seismology Monitoring Centre.
Residents felt the tremors at 6:06:04pm and 6:06:05pm on Saturday, rattling Dhaka and nearby districts.
Rubaiyat</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 15:14:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UCB customers can get insurance services from any of its branches</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ucb-customers-can-get-insurance-services-from-any-of-its-branches</link><description>United Commercial Bank PLC (UCB) has officially launched its bancassurance services, enabling customers to access insurance directly through the bank.
According to a press release, customers can now obtain both life and general insurance services from any UCB branch across the country.
On the eve</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 15:29:56 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>