<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 09:31:56 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Ship operations on Cox's Bazar-St. Martin route begin</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/ship-operations-on-coxs-bazar-st-martin-route-begin</link><description>After a nine-month closure, the Cox's Bazar-St. Martin's route has resumed its tourist traffic from December 1. On the first day of the season, Monday, MV Bar Aulia, MV Karnaphuli and Keary Sindabad set off for St Martin's from the Nuniarachara BIWTA jetty at 7 am.
 
Additional passenger con</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 07:30:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sammilito Islami Bank gets its first chairman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/sammilito-islami-bank-gets-its-first-chairman</link><description>Former senior secretary Dr Mohammad Ayub Mia has been appointed chairman of the newly-formed Sammilito Islami Bank PLC, which was created by merging five financially weak banks in the country.
Bangladesh Bank gave the approval of his appointment on Sunday, reports UNB.
The central bank said the S</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 07:45:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rice drives nearly half of October food inflation, GED reports</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/rice-drives-nearly-half-of-october-food-inflation-ged-reports</link><description>Rice accounted for about 47 per cent of total food inflation in October, while vegetables had a strong negative impact because of seasonal abundance, according to the Economic Update and Outlook for November 2025 prepared by the General Economics Division (GED).
Protein items — including bee</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 08:00:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CA expresses condolences over ‘Cyclone Ditwah’ casualties in Sri Lanka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ca-expresses-condolences-over-cyclone-ditwah-casualties-in-sri-lanka</link><description>Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus has expressed deep condolences to Sri Lankan President Anura Kumara Dissanayake following the tragic loss of lives and widespread devastation caused by ‘Cyclone Ditwah’, one of the worst weather-related disasters to hit the island nation in recent</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 07:27:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mother, daughter die as speedboat sinks off Saint Martin’s Coast</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/mother-daughter-die-as-speedboat-sinks-off-saint-martins-coast</link><description>A mother and her young daughter died after a passenger speedboat sank on its way from Saint Martin’s Island to Teknaf on Monday afternoon.
The accident occurred around 11:00 am near the Gholarchar area, north of Saint Martin’s Island.
The deceased were identified as Mariam Akter and h</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 07:42:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Falling Tree Coverage: Dhaka faces environmental crisis</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/falling-tree-coverage-dhaka-faces-environmental-crisis</link><description>In Dhaka, a single tree must support the oxygen needs of around 28 people - far below what is needed for a healthy, livable environment.
Across the country, forests are shrinking, with 0.25 million acres of forest land illegally grabbed and overall coverage falling by 0.1 million acres since 2015.</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 07:57:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Metro rail yet to confirm how youth climbed onto train roof</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/metro-rail-yet-to-confirm-how-youth-climbed-onto-train-roof</link><description>Dhaka Mass Transit Company Limited (DMTCL) is yet to determine how the young man, who was found on the rooftop of an MRT-6 train, managed to get up there, officials said on Monday.
Faruque Ahmed, managing director of DMTCL, said CCTV footage from various stations showed the youth at Agargaon and K</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 08:12:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Doctors doing all they can for Khaleda Zia’s recovery: Fakhrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/doctors-doing-all-they-can-for-khaleda-zias-recovery-fakhrul</link><description>Doctors in Bangladesh and abroad are working in tandem to oversee the treatment of BNP chief Khaleda Zia, says senior party leader Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir.
The BNP secretary general remarked in response to a question from the media at an event marking Dr Reza Kibria's joining the BNP at the pa</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 08:27:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khaleda put on ventilation: Azam Khan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/khaleda-put-on-ventilation-azam-khan</link><description>BNP Chairperson and former prime minister Khaleda Zia has been placed on ventilation on Sunday night as her health has taken another critical turn.
"Begum Zia's condition has turned critical again. She has been on ventilation support since last night," BNP Vice-Chairman Advocate Ahmed Azam Khan to</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 08:42:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fire guts 50 homes in Chattogram slum</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/fire-guts-50-homes-in-chattogram-slum</link><description>A fire has swept through a slum in Chattogram’s Bayezid Bostami area, destroying around 50 houses.
The blaze broke out around 9:50 am on Monday near the railway line behind a factory operated by industrial group KDS.
The area is home to factory workers and various other low-income families,</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 08:57:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tulip calls Bangladeshi prison sentence 'flawed and farcical'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tulip-calls-bangladeshi-prison-sentence-flawed-and-farcical</link><description>British lawmaker Tulip Siddiq said a Bangladeshi court process, which has sentenced her in absentia to two years in prison, was "flawed and farcical" and said the verdict should be treated with contempt.
"This whole process has been flawed and farcical from the beginning to the end. The outcome of</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 09:12:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Annual exams postponed in most government schools amid teachers’ strike</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/annual-exams-postponed-in-most-government-schools-amid-teachers-strike</link><description>Annual examinations in most government schools have been disrupted as teachers at public secondary and primary institutions continue their work stoppage, despite warnings from the government.
Teachers at 721 government secondary schools began boycotting exams on Monday, suspending annual tests tha</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 09:27:45 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>