<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 01:50:22 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>AKIJ Resource launches smart lifestyle brand ‘Enovar’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/akij-resource-launches-smart-lifestyle-brand-enovar</link><description>AKIJ Resource has launched its new brand Enovar, offering smart and modern lifestyle products to make daily life easier and more efficient.
The launch event, held at the United Convention Centre in Dhaka, marked the company’s move into the home appliance and consumer technology market. Enova</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 16:30:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP withdraws expulsion orders against 40 Sylhet city leaders</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-withdraws-expulsion-orders-against-40-sylhet-city-leaders</link><description>BNP has withdrawn the expulsion orders against its 40 leaders from different wards under the Sylhet City Corporation.
In a press release issued on Sunday and signed by party Senior Joint Secretary General Ruhul Kabir Rizvi, it was said that the decision was taken following applications submitted b</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 16:45:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Primary teachers suspend work stoppage</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/primary-teachers-suspend-work-stoppage</link><description>Assistant teachers from the government primary schools, who are demanding 10th-grade pay among three demands, have suspended their work stoppage, according to bdnews24.com.
Following a meeting with government representatives at the Secretariat, Shamsuddin Masud, convenor of the “Primary Teac</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 17:00:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt appoints new DCs in 14 more districts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-appoints-new-dcs-in-14-more-districts</link><description>The government has appointed new Deputy Commissioners (DCs) in 14 more districts.
The Ministry of Public Administration issued a notification to this effect on Sunday evening.
The new postings include Brahmanbaria, Jhenaidah, Narail, Jamalpur, Meherpur, Kishoreganj, Jhalokathi, Gopalganj, Chuadan</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 16:45:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DMTC cancels all staff leave amid safety concerns</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dmtc-cancels-all-staff-leave-amid-safety-concerns</link><description>The Dhaka Mass Transit Company Limited (DMTCL), which builds and operates the metro rail, has cancelled all leave for its officials and employees until further notice, following recent accidents and heightened safety concerns.
The order, signed by DMTCL Director (Administration) A K M Khairul on S</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 17:00:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tourism and SDGs: Bangladesh boasts ample potential to score</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/tourism-and-sdgs-bangladesh-boasts-ample-potential-to-score</link><description>Tourism is the single-largest economic sector in today's world. About one-tenth of global gross domestic product (GDP) and employment opportunities come from this economic sector. More than 50 countries depend mainly on this sector for their economic development. Many countries emphasize tourism as</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 17:15:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No music &amp; sports teachers for primary schools!</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/no-music-sports-teachers-for-primary-schools</link><description>The planned appointment of music and sports teachers to government primary schools has been cancelled. This decision has invited protests from different cultural organisations, educators, child rights activists and students of a number of universities. Apparently, the interim government has backed</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 17:30:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Development damaging Nature, defying law</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/development-damaging-nature-defying-law</link><description>Already ranked ninth globally for climate disaster risk, according to the World Risk Index 2023, Bangladesh, so far, seems to have resigned itself to its fate. Worse, it has been doing everything to make matters worse often in the name of development work. So, one is not surprised when, according a</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 17:45:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Domestic factors undermining price stability</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/domestic-factors-undermining-price-stability</link><description>The latest Bangladesh Bank analysis of inflation may explain why a stable exchange rate has largely failed to translate into lower consumer prices and why a tight monetary policy has so far failed to bring inflation rate down to the desired level. The central bank's analysis reveals that the countr</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 18:00:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC finalises 22-point security plan for 13th national election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-finalises-22-point-security-plan-for-13th-national-election</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has finalised a 22-point security plan ahead of the 13th National Parliamentary Election to ensure a safe, peaceful and orderly voting process.
Law enforcement agencies will be deployed under a red, yellow, and green zoning system, based on security risk levels, accord</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 18:50:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pakistan approves bill to expand army chief’s powers amid broad constitutional changes</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/pakistan-approves-bill-to-expand-army-chiefs-powers-amid-broad-constitutional-changes</link><description>Pakistan’s parliament has taken a significant step towards expanding the constitutional powers of its military leadership, as the standing committees on law and justice of both houses approved the draft of a bill for the 27th Constitutional Amendment, reports bdnews24.com, citing Dawn.
Senat</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 19:05:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Revenue board opposes blanket scrapping of tax incentives</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/revenue-board-opposes-blanket-scrapping-of-tax-incentives</link><description>A willy-nilly government action undoing time-bound tax-breaks falters as investors lodge multiple objections and take the matter up with court on alleged breach of commitment.



Tax officials say the abrupt phasing out of these exemptions - the first of its kind - follows the International Mon</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 20:06:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>