<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 21:19:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nation to observe Martyred Intellectuals Day on Sunday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nation-to-observe-martyred-intellectuals-day-on-sunday</link><description>The nation is set to observe the Martyred Intellectuals Day on Sunday to commemorate the intellectuals killed systematically by Pakistan occupation forces and their local collaborators at the fag-end of the Liberation War in 1971.
On this day in 1971, the country’s renowned academicians, doc</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 16:01:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Roots of Hadi's would-be assassins to be uprooted: Attorney General</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/roots-of-hadis-would-be-assassins-to-be-uprooted-attorney-general</link><description>Attorney General Md Asaduzzaman on Saturday warned that the roots of those responsible for attacking Inqilab Mancha spokesperson Sharif Osman Hadi would be uprooted, no matter how strong they are.
He said Sharif Osman Hadi is a hero of the July mass uprising and is currently undergoing treatment a</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 15:49:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BGB on alert in Chuadanga, Meherpur after attempted assassination of Hadi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bgb-on-alert-in-chuadanga-meherpur-after-attempted-assassination-of-hadi</link><description>The Border Guard Bangladesh (BGB) has imposed maximum alert along all borders of Chuadanga and Meherpur districts following the attempted assassination of Sharif Osman Hadi, spokesperson of Inquilab Mancha and a potential independent candidate for Dhaka-8.
Security has been stepped up to prevent t</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 16:04:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>War and peace: the role of merchants of death</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/war-and-peace-the-role-of-merchants-of-death</link><description>War is as old as human beings life on earth. The main cause of war between territorial entities has been land and occasionally water. The first remains the pre-eminent reason why wars - local, regional or global - have taken place throughout human history. Land is at the heart of the recent devasta</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 16:19:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Time for piloting CDBC in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/reviews/time-for-piloting-cdbc-in-bangladesh</link><description>In the era of massive technological diffusion, digital transformation, and aggressive cashless transactions, Bangladesh has been in a strong position. Online banking, digital banking and mobile banking through mobile apps are growing faster than ever before. Bangladesh is also relentless in its dig</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 16:34:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Attack on Hadi and a complacent home adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/attack-on-hadi-and-a-complacent-home-adviser</link><description>The shooting of Sharif Osman Hadi on Friday afternoon in the city's Paltan area has left the entire nation shell-shocked. He is reportedly in a critical condition now and fighting for his life at Evercare Hospital. Hadi, an independent MP candidate from the Dhaka-8 constituency, has been in the van</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 16:49:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>From Bengal-partition to Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/from-bengal-partition-to-bangladesh</link><description>Day after tomorrow, on Tuesday to be precise, Bangladesh will observe the 55th Victory Day, commemorating the final victory over the Pakistani occupation army in the nine-month bloody war of independence in 1971. On December 16, 1971, Bangladesh emerged as a sovereign country on the world map. The</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 17:04:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Healing the banks through Truth Commission</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/healing-the-banks-through-truth-commission</link><description>Nations emerging from prolonged misrule often find that their financial system has been hollowed out far more deeply than meets the eye, eroded by years of politically motivated lending, normalisation of misconduct and weak regulation. Bangladesh today faces precisely such a reckoning, with non-per</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 17:19:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>6 Bangladeshi peacekeepers killed in Sudan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/assault-on-un-base-in-abyei-claims-six-bangladeshi-lives-injures-eight-others</link><description>Six Bangladeshi peacekeepers have been killed and eight others injured in an attack on a United Nations base in Abyei, Sudan, the Inter-Services Public Relations (ISPR) has confirmed.
The assault occurred amid ongoing clashes in the region, the military’s media wing said in a statement issue</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 18:41:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Salah returns for Liverpool amid uncertainty over Merseyside future</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/salah-returns-for-liverpool-amid-uncertainty-over-merseyside-future</link><description>Liverpool forward Mohamed Salah made his return for the Merseyside club to loud applause and a standing ovation at Anfield during Saturday's Premier League clash with Brighton &amp; Hove Albion.
The Egyptian, whose future at the club has been in doubt since his scathing criticism a week earlier, was n</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 18:56:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hadi remains in critical condition with injury to brain stem, hospital says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hadi-remains-in-critical-condition-with-injury-to-brain-stem-ventilator-support-continues</link><description>Inquilab Mancha spokesperson Sharif Osman Hadi, who was shot in the capital’s Bijoynagar area on Friday, remains in critical condition while undergoing treatment at Evercare Hospital in Dhaka, hospital authorities said on Saturday.
Doctors said the bullet caused severe damage to Hadi’s</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 19:11:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>RMG export to US beats BD’s competitors</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/rmg-export-to-us-beats-bds-competitors</link><description>Bangladesh's apparel export to the United States, its single-largest market, circumvents tariff tempests and records a double-digit growth of18.64 per cent, the highest among major competitors, in the first nine months of 2025.
According to US official count, the exports grew both in terms of va</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 19:26:53 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>