<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 05:21:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Ensuring  structural integrity of city buildings</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/ensuring-structural-integrity-of-city-buildings</link><description>The writing has long been on the wall that a powerful earthquake is quite likely any time. Friday's 5.7-magnitude tremor, with its epicentre in Narsingdi, sent a powerful jolt through Dhaka and surrounding areas. Many described the frightening shock as unprecedented in their memory, as buildings sw</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 17:46:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Restoring stability in the banking sector</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/restoring-stability-in-the-banking-sector</link><description>The financial sector in Bangladesh is at a crossroads now amid the interim government's hectic efforts towards widespread redressal of irregularities, which has been long overdue. The task is challenging, and there is no quick fix for the problems created, deliberately or otherwise, by the previous</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 18:01:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Now IMED finds Savar leather park faultlines</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/now-imed-finds-savar-leather-park-faultlines</link><description>A government watchdog has dug out an epitome of operational, environmental, and governance "failures" in a vital project that continue to undermine Bangladesh's leather sector and its global competitiveness, thereby causing the country to miss millions in foreign exchange.



On such a discover</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 18:16:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Police should act to combat violent crime</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/police-should-act-to-combat-violent-crime</link><description>Miscreants gunned down a political worker reportedly belonging to the youth wing of the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP), named Golam Kibria, on Monday (November 17) evening from Pallabi area in the city, unchallenged either by the watching public or any law-enforcer.  Evidently, this</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 18:31:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mashrur Arefin named ‘CEO of the Year 2025’ at Bangladesh C-Suite Awards</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/mashrur-arefin-named-ceo-of-the-year-2025-at-bangladesh-c-suite-awards</link><description>Mashrur Arefin, managing director and CEO of City Bank, has been named ‘CEO of the Year—2025’ in the Financial Institutions category at the 4th Bangladesh C-Suite Awards.
The honour recognises his exceptional leadership and more than 30 years of contributions to Bangladesh’</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 21:40:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>4 quakes in 2 days; experts urge long-term preparedness</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/4-quakes-in-2-days-experts-urge-long-term-preparedness</link><description>The Meteorological Department reported that two earthquakes struck Dhaka on Saturday evening, both originating in the Badda area.
Tariful Nawaz Kabir, a meteorologist at the department, said the first quake occurred at 6:06:04pm with a magnitude of 3.7, immediately followed one second later by a 4</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 03:20:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Judiciary urged to stick to principle and safeguard Constitution</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/judiciary-urged-to-stick-to-principle-and-safeguard-constitution</link><description>Chief Justice Dr Syed Refaat Ahmed has urged that the judiciary remain firmly rooted in principle to safeguard the integrity of the Constitution.
Addressing the opening session of this year's Bay of Bengal Conversation organised by the Centre for Governance Studies (CGS) on Saturday, he warned tha</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 03:35:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BD-Bhutan accords on two major fronts signed during PM Tobgay tour</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bd-bhutan-accords-on-two-major-fronts-signed-during-pm-tobgay-tour</link><description>Bangladesh and Bhutan Saturday took fresh steps to deepen bilateral cooperation as the two countries signed accords on health collaboration and cross-border digital connectivity meant to integrate the eastern Himalayas and the Bay of Bengal.
The couple of agreements, marking the official visit of</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 03:50:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CCTF seeks increased allocation to expand climate-risk activities</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cctf-seeks-increased-allocation-to-expand-climate-risk-activities</link><description>The Ministry of Environment, Forest, and Climate Change (MoEFCC) has sought an additional allocation for the climate change trust fund, aiming to sustain and expand climate-risk mitigation activities for the 2025-2026 fiscal year (FY).
The Bangladesh Climate Change Trust Fund (BCCTF), a state body</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 04:07:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP hints at major ICT policy overhaul if elected</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bnp-hints-at-major-ict-policy-overhaul-if-elected</link><description>A senior BNP leader has said that a future democratically elected government would revisit all major decisions taken in Bangladesh's ICT and telecom sectors, arguing that public interest, national security and investor protection must guide future reforms.
Speaking at a seminar in Dhaka on Saturda</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 04:22:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Weak enforcement, market distortions weaken tobacco tax system</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/weak-enforcement-market-distortions-weaken-tobacco-tax-system</link><description>Experts on Saturday said Bangladesh's tobacco tax system is failing to curb consumption not because taxes are low on paper, but because enforcement gaps, market distortions and an outdated multi-tiered structure continue to undermine policy effectiveness.
Speaking at a national dialogue titled "Re</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 04:37:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nurses protest abolition of Midwifery Directorate</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nurses-protest-abolition-of-midwifery-directorate</link><description>Nurses of different hospitals across the country staged a demonstration on Saturday protesting against the move to abolish the Nursing and Midwifery Directorate and demanding formation of a National Nursing Commission.
The demonstration began around 10.00am, with thousand of nurses gathering in fr</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 04:52:05 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>