<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 13:21:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Former Awami League MP BM Mozammel Haque arrested</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/former-awami-league-mp-bm-mozammel-haque-arrested</link><description>Police have arrested former Shariatpur-3 lawmaker and Awami League Central Executive Committee Organising Secretary BM Mozammel Haque.
He was arrested from Dhaka’s Niketon, according to a statement released by Dhaka Metropolitan Police on Sunday afternoon.
The statement did not reveal when</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 09:50:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gaza flotilla activists say they faced abuse, humiliation while in Israeli custody</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/gaza-flotilla-activists-say-they-faced-abuse-humiliation-while-in-israeli-custody</link><description>Activists detained while attempting to reach Gaza by sea have accused Israeli authorities of abuse and humiliation during their detention, following the interception of the Global Sumud Flotilla.
Israeli forces detained around 450 people when they stopped the 42-boat flotilla between Wednesday and</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 10:20:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Merchandise exports record 4.61pc decline in September</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/merchandise-exports-record-461pc-decline-in-september</link><description>The country's merchandise exports recorded a 4.61 per cent decline in September 2025 year-on-year to fetch US$3.62 billion, mainly because of negative growth of the largest foreign currency earner--readymade garments.Bangladesh fetched US$3.80 billion in September 2024, according to Export Promotio</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 10:35:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dengue claims nine more lives, second highest daily toll this year</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/dengue-claims-nine-more-lives-second-highest-daily-toll-this-year</link><description>The relentless scourge of dengue continues to tighten its grip on Bangladesh, claiming nine more lives in the 24 hours till Sunday morning, the second highest daily toll recorded this year.
With these latest fatalities, the death count from the mosquito-borne disease has climbed to 212 in 2025, ac</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 10:50:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US soybean farmers brace for losses as Trump plans new aid amid China boycott</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/us-soybean-farmers-brace-for-losses-as-trump-plans-new-aid-amid-china-boycott</link><description>President Donald Trump is preparing a major aid package to help American soybean farmers struggling under China’s ongoing boycott of US beans, even as he continues efforts to secure a trade deal with Beijing.
US soybean growers, who once relied on China as their biggest customer, fear that t</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 11:20:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Court orders seizure of Saifuzzaman's Ctg flats, assets</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/court-orders-seizure-of-6-flats-other-assets-belonging-to-ex-minister-saifuzzaman-in-ctg</link><description>A Dhaka court has ordered the seizure of six flats in Chattogram worth Tk 74.26 million belonging to former land minister Saifuzzaman Chowdhury as part of an ongoing investigation into money laundering allegations.
The order was issued on Sunday by Dhaka Metropolitan Senior Special Judge Sabbir Fo</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 11:35:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>MPO teachers reject rent allowance increase, plan protest</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/mpo-teachers-reject-rent-allowance-increase-plan-protest</link><description>The government has increased the house rent allowance for MPO-listed teachers by Tk 500, but they have rejected the move, announcing a protest instead.
The Finance Division issued a notification increasing the allowance from Tk 1,000 to Tk 1,500 on Sunday, bdnews24.com reports. 
Rejecting th</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 12:05:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No more single-use plastic at Secretariat: Rizwana</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/secretariat-to-be-fully-plastic-free-from-the-new-year-says-rizwana</link><description>The government aims to make the Bangladesh Secretariat completely free of single-use plastic by Jan 1, Environment Advisor Syeda Rizwana Hasan has said.
Speaking to reporters at the Secretariat on Sunday, Rizwana said the initiative to phase out single-use plastic from government offices has begun</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 12:20:21 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>