<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 17:19:47 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Travel ban on 9 foreigners over ‘embezzlement’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/travel-ban-imposed-on-9-foreigners-over-embezzling-tk-275b</link><description>A Dhaka court has barred nine foreign nationals, including five founding directors of Ring Shine Textiles Limited, from leaving the country over allegations of embezzling Tk 2.75 billion.
They allegedly submitted falsified documents to list the Dhaka EPZ-based company on the capital market.
Dhaka</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 15:10:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh’s remittance crosses $10b in FY’s first four months</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladeshs-remittance-crosses-10b-in-fys-first-four-months</link><description>The remittance inflow to Bangladesh has surpassed $10 billion in the first four months (July–October) of the 2025-26 fiscal year.
According to information provided on Thursday by Bangladesh Bank’s Assistant Spokesperson Shahriar Siddiqui, the remittance inflow exceeded $10 billion with</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 15:25:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BATBC’s profit drops 46pc in Jan-Sept due to lower sales, higher costs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/batbcs-profit-drops-46pc-in-jan-sept-due-to-lower-sales-higher-costs</link><description>British American Tobacco (BAT) Bangladesh’s profit dropped nearly 46 per cent year-on-year to Tk 7.20 billion in nine months through September this year, owing to lower sales and higher costs.
The multinational tobacco manufacturer said sales volume declined, while higher excise duty and add</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 14:28:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Water Lily’, newly added symbol ‘Water Lily Bud’ not same: EC Secretary</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/water-lily-newly-added-symbol-water-lily-bud-not-same-ec-secretary</link><description>Election Commission (EC) Senior Secretary Akhtar Ahmed on Thursday clarified that there is a difference between the ‘Water Lily’ symbol sought by the National Citizen Party (NCP) and the newly incorporated ‘Water Lily Bud’ (Shapla Koli) in the revised list of 119 electoral s</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 14:58:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>More than 1m taxpayers submit returns online: NBR</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/more-than-1m-taxpayers-submit-returns-online-nbr</link><description>More than 1.0 million individual taxpayers have submitted their income tax returns online so far in the current tax year, marking a significant milestone in Bangladesh’s ongoing digital transformation of tax administration, according to the National Board of Revenue (NBR).
The online e-retur</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 15:13:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Man killed in Chandpur road crash</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/man-killed-in-chandpur-road-crash</link><description>A motorcycle rider was killed and another injured in a road accident at Madanergaon village in Faridganj upazila of Chandpur district on Thursday.
The deceased was Junaid Badsha Talukder, 45, son of Maulana Idris Talukder of Manikraj village of the upazila, reports BSS.
The accident took place ar</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 15:28:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DMP files 1,583 cases against traffic rules violations</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dmp-files-1583-cases-against-traffic-rules-violations</link><description>As part of the ongoing campaign to bring traffic system under control, Dhaka Metropolitan Police's (DMP) Traffic Division has filed a total of 1,583 cases against vehicles, owners and its drivers for violating traffic rules.
Deputy Commissioner (Media and Public Relations Division) of Dhaka Metrop</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 15:43:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CA to decide on implementation of Consensus Commission’s recommendations, referendum: Asif Nazrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ca-to-decide-on-implementation-of-consensus-commissions-recommendations-referendum-asif-nazrul</link><description>Law Adviser Professor Dr Asif Nazrul on Thursday said that Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus will take the final decision regarding the implementation of the National Consensus Commission’s recommendations and referendum.
“Two proposals of the Consensus Commission were discussed i</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 16:13:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cox’s Bazar gets its first plastic recycling plant to reuse waste</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/coxs-bazar-gets-its-first-plastic-recycling-plant-to-reuse-waste</link><description>The first municipal plastic recycling plant in Cox’s Bazar was officially inaugurated recently, aiming to transform single-use plastic waste into valuable resources.
The initiative, established in Mithaichori of Ramu Upazila, was hailed by guests as a milestone for sustainable waste manageme</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 16:28:28 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>