<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 17:36:13 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Rickshaw driver sent kidnapped child home after abducting him: RAB</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/rickshaw-driver-sent-kidnapped-child-home-after-abducting-him-rab</link><description>A 3-year-old boy abducted outside Mugda Hospital in Dhaka was sent to his ancestral home in Gaibandha by the rickshaw driver who kidnapped him, the Rapid Action Battalion (RAB) has said.
Following reports of the abduction, the driver, identified as 41-year-old Chan Mia, was arrested at Wireless Ga</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 13:37:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCP vows ‘reform-oriented’ roadmap</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ncp-unveils-36-point-manifesto-pledging-state-reform-justice-for-july-atrocities</link><description>The National Citizen Party (NCP) has announced a 36-point election manifesto aimed at constructing a “realistic and reform-oriented roadmap” before the February elections.
According to the party, the manifesto builds upon its vision of “governance, principled policies, and reform</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 13:52:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP’s Sirajganj-3 candidate Ainul Haque hospitalized</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnps-sirajganj-3-candidate-ainul-haque-hospitalized</link><description>BNP candidate for the Sirajganj-3 (Raiganj–Tarash) constituency, Ainul Haque, has been hospitalised in Dhaka for heart treatment.
He underwent surgery at Evercare Hospital in the capital on Thursday, during which two stents were placed in his heart, said Khandaker Selim Jahangir, former pres</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 14:15:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Iran prepared for 'fair' talks with US, Araqchi says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/iran-prepared-for-fair-talks-with-us-but-not-on-defence-capabilities-araqchi-says</link><description>Iran is prepared for the resumption of talks with the United States, but they should be fair and not include Iran's defence capabilities, Iran's chief diplomat said on Friday, as regional powers work to prevent military conflict between the two foes.
US President Donald Trump said on Thursday he p</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 14:30:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hasnat pledges crackdown on extortionists, drug dealers in Debidwar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/hasnat-pledges-crackdown-on-extortionists-drug-dealers-in-debidwar</link><description>Hasnat Abdullah, the chief organizer of the National Citizens' Party (NCP) Southern Region and the 11-party alliance nominee for the Cumilla-4 (Debidwar) constituency, on Friday declared that he would hound the extortionists, drug dealers, and loan defaulters if gets elected in the forthcoming parl</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 14:45:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EU says no post-Brexit energy deal without UK payments</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/eu-says-no-post-brexit-energy-deal-without-uk-payments</link><description>European Union countries will demand that Britain contributes financially to poorer EU member states' development as part of any deal to re-link the two sides' energy markets, according to EU documents and diplomats.
As part of efforts to reset relations following Britain's exit from the EU, the t</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 15:00:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Asif Mahmud says he handed over govt-allotted residence before scheduled time</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/asif-mahmud-says-he-handed-over-govt-allotted-residence-before-scheduled-time</link><description>Former adviser to the interim government Asif Mahmud Shojib Bhuyain has rejected reports on keeping government-allotted residence occupied despite resignation as an adviser.
Describing the reports as false, fabricated and intentional, the former adviser on Friday said he handed over the residence,</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 15:35:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fire in Banani doused after an hour</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fire-in-banani-doused-after-an-hour</link><description>A fire that broke out in a residential building in the capital’s Banani Chairmanbari has been brought under control after almost an hour of efforts.
The Fire Service received the report of the blaze around 7pm on Friday.
Fire Service spokesperson Anwarul Islam said the fire was brought unde</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 15:50:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Those who persecuted Hindus in 71 are back in elections’, says Salahuddin</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/those-who-persecuted-hindus-in-71-are-back-in-elections-says-salahuddin</link><description>BNP Standing Committee member Salahuddin Ahmed on Friday said that those who persecuted the country’s Hindu community during the 1971 Liberation War have returned in a new form to contest elections, raising concerns about the safety of all citizens in Bangladesh.
Speaking at an interaction m</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 16:05:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rohinya survivors hope ICJ find Myanmar liable for genocide</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/rohingya-survivors-expect-uns-highest-court-to-find-myanmar-committed-genocide</link><description>Rohingya survivors of the 2017 military crackdown in Myanmar expect the International Court of Justice, the United Nations' highest court, to rule the country committed genocide against them, they said on Friday.
A judgment is expected in three-to-six months' time following three weeks of hearings</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 16:37:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique questions Jamaat’s five-year alliance with BNP</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-asks-why-jamaat-was-in-alliance-for-five-years-if-bnp-was-bad</link><description>Tarique Rahman has publicly challenged Jamaat-e-Islami over its past alliance with the BNP, asking why the party remained in coalition for five years if it now portrays the BNP as “bad”.
Speaking at a campaign rally at Rangpur’s Collectorate Eidgah Ground on Friday night, the BNP</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 16:52:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCT foreign deal destabilising country: BaSaD’s Masud</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/government-destabilising-country-with-nct-foreign-deal-before-election-says-basads-masud-rana</link><description>The Socialist Party of Bangladesh’s (BaSaD-Marxist) Central Coordinator Masud Rana has said the government is destabilising the country ahead of the parliamentary polls by signing a contract to appoint foreign operators at the New Mooring Container Terminal (NCT) of Chattogram.
He alleged th</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 17:07:30 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>