<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 22:18:47 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Two hacked to death over ‘land dispute’ in Narsingdi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/two-hacked-to-death-over-land-dispute-in-narsingdi</link><description>Two men have been killed in a machete attack over a land dispute in Narsingdi’s Raipura, police say.
The incident took place in the remote Char Subuddhi on Saturday, said Raipura Police Station chief Adil Mahmud.
He said that they had received information about the double murder, reports bd</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 16:01:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mobile court fines six noisy vehicles in Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/mobile-court-fines-six-noisy-vehicles-in-dhaka</link><description>The Department of Environment (DoE) has conducted a mobile court at Kakrail area of Dhaka to control noise pollution.
During the mobile court operation, a total of six vehicles were fined Tk 23,000 for violating Rule 8(1) of the Noise Pollution (Control) Rules, 2006, by generating excessive noise</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 16:16:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Worker killed by falling tree in Bagerhat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/worker-killed-by-falling-tree-in-bagerhat</link><description>A worker died after being crushed by a tree in Sarankhola upazila of Bagerhat on Saturday.
The deceased was identified as Sultan Hawladar, 60, a laborer and son of Anis Hawladar of Khuriyakhali village in Southkhali Union, reports UNB.
Md. Shahidullah, officer-in-charge of Sarankhola Police Stati</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 16:31:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Yunus meets chiefs of Army, Navy, Air Force</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/yunus-meets-chiefs-of-army-navy-air-force</link><description>Chief Advisor Muhammad Yunus has met with the chiefs of the Bangladesh Army, Navy, and Air Force to discuss preparations for the next national elections and the maintenance of law and order during the vote.
The meeting took place at the State Guest House Jamuna at 7pm on Saturday, the Chief Adviso</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 17:01:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Father, daughter killed in Sylhet road accident</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/father-daughter-killed-in-sylhet-road-accident</link><description>A man and his daughter were killed and four others injured in a head-on collision between a bus and a private car in Osmaninagar upazila of Sylhet on Saturday.
The deceased were identified Harun Mia and his 10-year-old daughter Anisha Begum, residents of Khadimpur village in Osmani Nagar, reports</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 17:31:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Japanese  cos bid for business in  diverse BD sectors</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/japanese-cos-bid-for-business-in-diverse-bd-sectors</link><description>Japanese companies bid big to  do business with Bangladesh in diverse sectors to seize emergent prospects, with many seeking information daily about the country's latest investment climate.
Affordable labour, local and global marketing prospects amid rising domestic consumer clientele act as</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 17:46:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>American markets: dependency yes, but free ride no</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/american-markets-dependency-yes-but-free-ride-no</link><description>Critics of the United States (US) trade policy often argue that America is deeply protectionist. Tariffs on steel, aluminum, and Chinese imports, subsidies for farmers, and new industrial supports like the CHIPS and Science Act are frequently cited as proof that Washington talks free trade but prac</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 18:29:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Putting an end to food wastage</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/putting-an-end-to-food-wastage</link><description>In recent years, Bangladesh has been under a rising threat of food insecurity. This concern is not merely a matter of public perception; several international rankings that measure poverty and food security, such as the Global Food Security Index, Global Hunger Index, and Multidimensional Poverty I</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 18:44:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh's struggle to make trade sustainable</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/bangladeshs-struggle-to-make-trade-sustainable</link><description>Can the trade and environmental policies interact? If yes, what will be its influence on climate change, biodiversity loss, pollution, and global trade flows? The questions are not new, and the answer to the first question is a resounding 'yes': it is both possible and necessary to interact with tr</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 18:59:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bridging the startup funding gap</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/bridging-the-startup-funding-gap</link><description>An enabling environment for young businesses is vital to any economy seeking sustainable growth. When entrepreneurs are given access to capital and institutional backing, they can turn ideas into initiatives that generate jobs and innovation. As such, the forthcoming public company for start-up inv</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 19:14:46 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>