<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 23:27:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Investing in children’s talents ensures bright future for nation: Minister Amin Ur Rashid</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/investing-in-childrens-talents-ensures-bright-future-for-nation-minister-amin-ur-rashid</link><description>Fisheries and Livestock Minister Mohammad Amin Ur Rashid has said that today’s children are the future of the nation and proper development of their talents will help build a worthy generation.
“If we can develop them properly, the country will have a capable and enlightened generation</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 16:11:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh to seek US trade deal status after Trump tariffs scrapped</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladesh-to-seek-us-trade-deal-status-after-trump-tariffs-scrapped</link><description>The government plans to send a letter to Washington seeking clarity on the implications of its trade deal after the US Supreme Court struck down President Donald Trump’s retaliatory tariffs.
Commerce Secretary Mahbubur Rahman told bdnews24.com the letter may be issued by Monday.
During his</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 16:47:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>22 fishermen held for entering Sundarbans illegally</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/22-fishermen-held-for-entering-sundarbans-illegally</link><description>The Forest Department has detained 22 fishermen for illegally entering the Mandarbaria area of the western Sundarbans.
The detainees are residents of different areas of Patuakhali and Bagerhat districts.
Satkhira Range Assistant Conservator of Forests Mashiur Rahman said the fishermen entered the</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 17:02:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Inqilab, azadi not words that belong in Bangla: Iqbal Hasan Tuku</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/inqilab-azadi-not-words-that-belong-in-bangla-iqbal-hasan-tuku</link><description>Power, Energy and Mineral Resources Minister Iqbal Hasan Mahmud Tuku has said that the Bengali language has no connection with the words ‘Inqilab’ and ‘Azadi’.
“If the people of Bangladesh truly embrace Bangla as their mother tongue, slogans like ‘Inqilab Zindab</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 17:17:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Asymmetrical reciprocity is Bangladesh's strategic gamble in the new US trade order</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/asymmetrical-reciprocity-is-bangladeshs-strategic-gamble-in-the-new-us-trade-order</link><description>Bangladesh was not alone in reaching a trade agreement with the United States (US) under what can only be described as asymmetrical reciprocity. The governing principle of the US-Bangladesh Reciprocal Trade Agreement is clear: access to the world's largest single-country market is a privilege-earne</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 17:40:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Festivals and unfair trading practice</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/festivals-and-unfair-trading-practice</link><description>The onset of Ramadan has triggered a wave of consumer-friendly market initiatives across many Muslim-majority countries, where governments and businesses alike seek to ease the financial burden on households during the holy month. According to a Khaleej Times report, retailers in the United Arab Em</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 17:55:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No scope to undermine July mass uprising</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/no-scope-to-undermine-july-mass-uprising</link><description>Dispelling speculations and predictions, the Yunus-led interim government accomplished its core mission by upholding the national elections and the referendum. The elections took place on February 12, and the interim government peacefully handed over power to the elected government within a week. T</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 18:10:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New BNP govt's climate challenges</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/new-bnp-govts-climate-challenges</link><description>Bangladesh is one of the 10 most climate vulnerable nations in the world. And the prime mover of the climate vulnerability is human action. In fact, human-induced climate change is intensifying the phenomenon of extreme heat across the country. In Dhaka, rising temperatures aggravate air pollution,</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 18:25:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>50 killed, many abducted in armed attack in Nigeria</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/africa/50-killed-many-abducted-in-armed-attack-in-nigeria</link><description>At least 50 people were killed and a significant number of others abducted after a group of armed men launched a brutal attack on a village in Nigeria's northwestern state of Zamfara, a local lawmaker said.
The raid on Tungan Dutse village, located in the Bukkuyum Local Government Area, reportedly</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 18:40:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Indian Assistant HC meets Commerce Minister Muktadir in Sylhet</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/indian-assistant-hc-meets-commerce-minister-muktadir-in-sylhet</link><description>Indian Assistant High Commissioner to Bangladesh Aniruddha Das today paid a courtesy call on Commerce, Industries and Jute and Textiles Minister Khandaker Abdul Muktadir at Sylhet Circuit House here.
During the meeting, they discussed various issues of mutual interest between the two countries, es</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 18:55:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump says he will raise US global tariff rate from 10 to 15 percent</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/trump-says-he-will-raise-us-global-tariff-rate-from-10-to-15-percent</link><description>President Donald Trump said on Saturday he will raise temporary tariffs on almost all US imports from 10 percent to 15 percent, the maximum level allowed under the law, after the US Supreme Court struck down his previous tariff programme as invalid.
Trump had immediately announced a 10 percent acr</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 19:10:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BD-US reciprocal tariff deal’s status unclear</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bd-us-reciprocal-tariff-deals-status-unclear</link><description>A landmark ruling by the US Supreme Court torpedoing Trump tariffs effectively upsets Bangladesh's trade arrangements with the United States, prompting calls for a cautious reassessment of the recently signed bilateral deal.



The media-highlighted "blow" to President Donald Trump's tariff reg</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 19:25:02 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>