<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 04:25:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Should every fire take us by surprise?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/should-every-fire-take-us-by-surprise</link><description>Probe committees by separate government bodies, namely, the Civil Aviation ministry, the Internal Resources Division of the finance ministry and Biman Bangladesh Airlines, have, reportedly, been formed to investigate Saturday (October 18)'s fire incident at the import cargo section called, the carg</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 17:42:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sabotage or gross negligence?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/sabotage-or-gross-negligence</link><description>When the cargo complex of Dhaka's Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport (HSIA) went up in flames last Saturday afternoon, the skies above Bangladesh's busiest gateway turned into a symbol of something far larger than a single accident. The orange glow rising over the capital was not just fire -- i</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 17:57:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>From blazes to infernos</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/from-blazes-to-infernos</link><description>First, the fire originating from a chemical warehouse at Shialbari, Mirpur on Tuesday last gulped 16 lives in an adjacent four-storey apparel factory to which it spread. Then on Thursday a fire gutted Adams Caps and Textile Ltd housed in a seven-storey building in the Chittagong Export Processing Z</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 18:12:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Statistics bureau be made an independent body</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/statistics-bureau-be-made-an-independent-body</link><description>A government taskforce has recommended transforming the Bangladesh Bureau of Statistics (BBS) into an independent statutory body to reduce bureaucratic control by the Statistical and Informatics Division (SID).



On Monday, the taskforce, led by Dr Hossain Zillur Rahman, executive chairman of</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 18:27:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Several FTAs up for early signing to facilitate trade</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/several-ftas-up-for-early-signing-to-facilitate-trade</link><description>Negotiations for inking free-trade agreements (FTAs) with a number of countries are ripe, officials say, while deal-feasibility studies with scores of others get underway.
The ministry is planning to begin feasibility study soon aiming to sign FTA with Turkey and Nigeria, among others, they added.</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 02:19:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DBH Finance's Q3 profit edges down due to higher expenses, provisioning</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/dbh-finances-q3-profit-edges-down-due-to-higher-expenses-provisioning</link><description>DBH Finance has reported nearly a 3 per cent year-on-year decline in profit to Tk 324 million for the third quarter (Q3) through September, mainly due to higher provisioning amid a spike in interest expenses on deposits and borrowings.
The leading non-bank financial institution (NBFI), which focus</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 02:34:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Crown Cement's FY25 profit dips 33pc as expenses offset revenue gains</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/crown-cements-fy25-profit-dips-33pc-as-expenses-offset-revenue-gains</link><description>Crown Cement has reported a 33 per cent year-on-year drop in profit to Tk 0.67 billion for FY25, despite a rise in revenue.
In a disclosure on Monday, the company attributed the decline in profit to higher marketing expenses, additional depreciation from a newly inaugurated plant, and increased fi</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 02:49:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Target $2.5b export to SADC bloc</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/target-25b-export-to-sadc-bloc</link><description>Bangladesh moves to discover trade treasure troves across Africa with an imminent exploration mission and trade summit under a comprehensive plan for export-market diversification into potential destinations yet untapped.
Sources say direct shipping connectivity with prime ports on the continent p</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 03:04:29 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>