<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 02:32:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nazrul urges voters to guard polling centres in shifts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/nazrul-urges-voters-to-guard-polling-centres-in-shifts</link><description>BNP Standing Committee Member and Chairman of the party’s Central Election steering Committee Nazrul Islam Khan on Wednesday urged party leaders, activists and voters to guard polling centres in shifts to ensure a free and fair election.
He made the call at an emergency press conference held</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 22:00:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two election officials detained for 'dining at Jamaat leader’s house' in Lakshmipur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/two-election-officials-detained-for-dining-at-jamaat-leaders-house-in-lakshmipur</link><description>Two election officials were detained in Lakshmipur on Wednesday night after they allegedly left their polling centre and went to have dinner at the residence of a local Jamaat leader.
The incident took place at Nolthogi Madinatul Ulum Islamia Madrasa polling centre under the Lakshmipur-3 (Sadar) c</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 22:15:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Brother of Kurigram-2 NCP candidate attacked</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/brother-of-kurigram-2-ncp-candidate-attacked</link><description>The National Citizen Party (NCP) on Wednesday alleged that the brother of its Kurigram-2 candidate Atiq Mujahid was attacked.
In a Facebook post, the party claimed that Ashiq, brother of the NCP-nominated candidate, was attacked by Chhatra Dal President Amimul, Shaon, Sohel and around 35 BNP activ</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 22:30:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shahidul Alam expresses frustration over EC’s role</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/shahidul-alam-expresses-frustration-over-ecs-role</link><description>Renowned photographer and human rights activist Shahidul Alam has expressed frustration over the Election Commission’s role in preventing irregularities surrounding Thursday’s national election.
In a Facebook post in the early hours of Thursday, he wrote that the posts he had been shar</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 23:17:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mohila Dal leader found dead in Feni</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/mohila-dal-leader-found-dead-in-feni</link><description>Police recovered the hanging body of a Jatiotabadi Mohila Dal leader from her rented house in Feni town on Wednesday evening.
The body of Roksana Akhter Lipi, 31, was recovered around 6:30pm from a locked room on the second floor of a six-storey building named Khalek Mansion on Mokchedur Rahman Ro</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 23:32:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Anee clarifies about Tk 1.5m found in his vehicle</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/anee-clarifies-about-tk-15m-found-in-his-vehicle</link><description>BNP Joint Secretary General and Lakshmipur-3 (Sadar) constituency candidate Shahiduddin Chowdhury Anee has clarified the circumstances surrounding Tk1.5 million that was found in his vehicle in Laxmipur on Wednesday evening.
In a video shared on his verified Facebook account, Anee said the Tk 15 m</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 00:34:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Three fake observers detained in Sylhet</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/three-fake-observers-detained-in-sylhet</link><description>Three people were detained in Sylhet on Wednesday night after they allegedly entered a polling centre posing as election observers.
The incident took place at Shahjalal Jameya Islamia School and College centre around 10 pm.
According to locals, the three individuals entered the centre wearing obs</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 00:22:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Eight injured in BNP-Jamaat clash in Bagerhat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/eight-injured-in-bnp-jamaat-clash-in-bagerhat</link><description>At least eight people were injured in a clash between activists of BNP and Jamaat-e-Islami in Bagerhat’s Sadar upazila on Wednesday night.
The incident took place in the Baruipara area around 10 pm.
Both parties traded blame over the cause of the clash.
Jamaat leaders alleged that activist</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 00:37:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>15 dead after ferry capsizes in Sudan’s Nile River</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/africa/15-dead-after-ferry-capsizes-in-sudans-nile-river</link><description>A passenger ferry capsized on the Nile River in Sudan on Wednesday, leaving at least 15 people dead, a medical group said.
The ferry, with at least 27 people on board, including women and children, sank in the Shendi district in northern Nile River province, said the Sudan Doctors Network, a media</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 00:52:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP, Jamaat trade blame as money seized in different areas</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-jamaat-trade-blame-as-money-seized-in-different-areas</link><description>At least three Jamaat leaders have been detained from Thakurgaon, Cumilla and Shariatpur districts on allegations of carrying huge sums of money the day before parliamentary election.
The Islamic party headquarters dismissed the allegations as smear campaigns to malign its vote prospect.
Police s</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 01:07:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>JS polls: National Helpline 333 activated</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/js-polls-national-helpline-333-activated</link><description>A special information service has been launched through the a2i National Helpline 333 to provide voters with accurate and reliable information during the election.
Citizens can dial the toll-free number from any mobile operator and press 9 to access election-related assistance.
The service provid</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 01:22:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh cannot sign trade deals with nonmarket countries without US consent</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladesh-cannot-sign-trade-deals-with-nonmarket-countries-without-us-consent</link><description>Bangladesh's reciprocal trade-tariff deal with the United States is bound with strings that bar it from signing any free-trade deal or preferential economic deal with "non-market" countries, including China and Russia, without US consent.
The US has officially listed 12 countries as non-market: Ch</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 01:37:10 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>