<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 09:30:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Oil rises over 1.0pc as Trump's Venezuela blockade stokes uncertainty</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/oil-rises-over-10pc-as-trumps-venezuela-blockade-stokes-uncertainty</link><description>Oil prices rose more than 1% on Wednesday after U.S. President Donald Trump ordered "a total and complete" blockade of all sanctioned oil tankers entering and leaving Venezuela, raising fresh geopolitical tensions at a time of concerns over demand.
Brent crude futures were up 79 cents, or 1.3%, at</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 06:17:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Indian visa application centre in Dhaka to close at 2pm Wednesday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/indian-visa-application-centre-in-dhaka-to-close-at-2pm-wednesday</link><description>In view of the ongoing security situation, the Indian Visa Application Centre in Dhaka will close at 2:00 pm on Wednesday.
"In view of the ongoing security situation, we wish to bring to your kind notice that IVAC JFP Dhaka will be closed at 2:00 pm today," said a notification issued by the IVAC i</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 06:32:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hadi attack: RAB arrests suspect’s parents</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hadi-attack-rab-arrests-suspects-parents</link><description>Members of the Rapid Action Battalion (RAB) have arrested the parents of prime suspect Faisal Karim Masud, and another suspect in connection with the attempted murder of Dhaka-8 aspiring independent candidate Sharif Osman Hadi in Puratan Paltan area.
With the latest arrests, the total number of de</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 06:47:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Voter numbers rise but number of polling centres drop in Chattogram for upcoming election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/voter-numbers-rise-but-number-of-polling-centres-drop-in-chattogram-for-upcoming-election</link><description>The number of voters in Chattogram has increased ahead of the 13th parliamentary election, but the number of polling centres in the city and surrounding areas has fallen compared with the previous election.
According to the latest voter list published by the Election Commission on Sunday, Chattogr</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 07:02:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India fences almost 80pc with Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/india-fences-almost-80pc-with-bangladesh</link><description>India has fenced almost 80 per cent of its border with Bangladesh, according to the Ministry of Home Affairs (MHA).
According to data provided by the Ministry of Home Affairs, India has physically fenced nearly 79 per cent of the length of the India-Bangladesh border, and over 93 per cent of the I</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 07:17:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique calls himself ‘half-Sylheti’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-calls-himself-half-sylheti</link><description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman has described himself as “half-Sylheti” while speaking at a discussion meeting on Great Victory Day at the City Pavilion in London.
“Many of you here are not just from Sylhet, but from other districts as well. Yet most of you are Sylhetis,&amp;rdquo</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 07:32:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC urges TV channels to avoid 'insults, personal attacks' in talk shows</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-urges-tv-channels-to-avoid-insults-personal-attacks-in-talk-shows</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has asked television channels to refrain from airing insults, derogatory remarks or personal attacks in talk shows and election-related discussions ahead of the 13th national election and referendum due in February next year.
In a letter sent on Wednesday to the secret</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 07:47:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fire breaks out at plastic warehouse in Lalbagh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fire-breaks-out-at-plastic-warehouse-in-lalbagh</link><description>A fire broke out at a plastic warehouse in the Islambagh area of Lalbagh in Old Dhaka on Wednesday afternoon.
Four units of the Fire Service rushed to the scene to control the blaze. Firefighting operations were underway at the time of reporting.
The cause of the fire could not be determined imme</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 08:02:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India summons Bangladesh high commissioner</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/india-summons-bangladesh-high-commissioner</link><description>Bangladesh’s high commissioner to New Delhi, M. Riaz Hamidullah, has been summoned by India’s Ministry of External Affairs.
He was called in at the ministry on Wednesday afternoon to issue a formal diplomatic protest over recent threats to the Indian High Commission in Dhaka and inflam</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 08:17:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tejgaon College students protest in Farmgate over death of peer Sakibul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tejgaon-college-students-protest-in-farmgate-over-death-of-peer-sakibul</link><description>Students of Dhaka’s Tejgaon College have launched a protest to demand the swift arrest of those accused in the death of Sakibul Hasan Rana, who died after being injured during a clash at a college hostel.
They have been staging a demonstration outside the college campus in Farmgate since ear</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 08:32:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Forged documents block Bangladesh’s overseas job prospects: Yunus</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/forged-documents-block-bangladeshs-overseas-job-prospects-yunus</link><description>Highlighting the importance of safer, fairer and skilled migration, Chief Adviser Prof Muhammad Yunus on Wednesday said the submission of fake documents has emerged as a major barrier to sending people abroad, despite the huge opportunities offered by destination countries for Bangladeshis.
&amp;ldquo</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 08:47:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fire breaks out at plastic warehouse in Old Dhaka's Islambagh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fire-breaks-out-at-plastic-warehouse-in-old-dhakas-islambagh</link><description>A fire has broken out at a plastic warehouse in Old Dhaka’s Islambagh.
The Fire Service said it received reports of the fire at Chairman Ghat around 1:30pm on Wednesday and initially sent six units to the scene. Three more units were later dispatched as firefighters worked to bring the fire</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 09:02:14 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>