<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 11:42:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Bogura-6, Sherpur-3 by-polls likely on April 9</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bogura-6-sherpur-3-by-polls-likely-on-april-9</link><description>By-elections to two parliamentary constituencies – Bogura-6 and Sherpur-3 -- are likely to be held on April 09 next.
The Election Commission is considering April 9 as the tentative date to hold by-elections in the two constituencies, an EC official said on Tuesday.
He said the schedule for</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 08:41:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>President to pay tribute to BDR martyrs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/president-to-pay-tribute-to-bdr-martyrs</link><description>President Mohammed Shahabuddin will pay tribute to martyred BDR (Now BGB) members at Banani military graveyard on Wednesday.
The President will place a wreath at 10:00 am, marking the National Martyred Army Day, said a notification issued by the Protocol Wing of the President’s Office on Mon</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 08:56:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ministers visit victims of Ctg, Cumilla fire incidents</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ministers-visit-victims-of-ctg-cumilla-fire-incidents</link><description>Health Minister Sardar Md Sakhawat Husain and Disaster Management and Relief Minister Asadul Habib Dulu visited the National Burn and Plastic Surgery Institute on Tuesday morning to see victims of Chattogram and Cumilla fire incidents.
The ministers arrived at the institute in the morning where it</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 08:44:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>After AL’s fall, there were attempts at ‘counter-revolution’: President</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/after-als-fall-there-were-attempts-at-counter-revolution-president</link><description>President Md Shahabuddin has said there were attempts to stage a “counter-revolution” in the immediate aftermath of the July-August 2024 mass uprising that ended the Awami League’s decade-and-a-half rule.
He also said he was subjected to intense pressure from different quarters t</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 08:59:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>PM chairs meeting on 'Family Card' at Secretariat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/pm-chairs-meeting-on-family-card-at-secretariat</link><description>A meeting on the 'Family Card' was held on Tuesday with Prime Minister Tarique Rahman in the chair.
The meeting was held in the conference room of the Cabinet Division in the Bangladesh Secretariat, reports BSS. 
Prime Minister's Additional Press Secretary Atikur Rahman Ruman confirmed the</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 09:14:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh govt orders strict adherence to office hours for public servants</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-govt-orders-strict-adherence-to-office-hours-for-public-servants</link><description>The Cabinet Division has directed all officials and employees of government, semi-government and autonomous institutions to strictly follow prescribed office hours in a move to strengthen good governance.
In a letter sent to senior secretaries and secretaries of all ministries and divisions, as we</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 09:29:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DSE slips despite rise in DS30; CSE edges up on selective gains</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/dse-slips-despite-rise-in-ds30-cse-edges-up-on-selective-gains</link><description>Stocks witnessed mixed performance on Tuesday as key indices fell on the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) while the Chittagong Stock Exchange (CSE) closed marginally higher.
At the DSE, the benchmark DSEX shed 10 points, while the Shariah-based DSES declined by 5 points. However, the blue-chip DS30 inde</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 09:44:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ali Hossain Fakir becomes new chief of Bangladesh Police</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ali-hossain-fakir-becomes-new-chief-of-bangladesh-police</link><description>Additional Inspector General Ali Hossain Fakir has been named the new inspector general of police (IGP) amid an administrative shake-up after the new government took office.
The Ministry of Home Affairs announced the decision in an order issued on Tuesday, bdnews24.com reports. 
Ali had been</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 09:59:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Family Card to be launched in 14 upazilas on March 10</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/family-card-to-be-launched-in-14-upazilas-on-march-10</link><description>The government will initially introduce the ‘Family Card’ programme in 14 upazilas on March 10 to support marginal and low-income families.
Prime Minister Tarique Rahman will inaugurate the programme, said his Additional Press Secretary Atikur Rahman Rumon.
Under the initiative, he sa</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 10:14:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Strict legal action against corruption in tribunal: Chief Prosecutor</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/strict-legal-action-against-corruption-in-tribunal-chief-prosecutor</link><description>Md Aminul Islam, the newly-appointed Chief Prosecutor of the International Crimes Tribunal (ICT), on Tuesday said strict legal action will be taken if anyone associated with the tribunal is found involved in corruption.
He made the remarks while responding to questions from journalists at his offi</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 10:29:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>MP Arman meets governor over potential foreign investment in Nagad</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/mp-arman-meets-governor-over-potential-foreign-investment-in-nagad</link><description>Barrister Mir Ahmad Bin Quasem Arman, a Jamaat MP, met Bangladesh Bank Governor Ahsan H. Mansur on Tuesday at his office to discuss a potential foreign investment in the mobile financial service (MFS) provider, Nagad.
The meeting was held as Bangladesh Bank sought to restructure Nagad after admini</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 10:44:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EBL, POJF launch Sundarbans mangrove restoration initiative</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ebl-pojf-launch-sundarbans-mangrove-restoration-initiative</link><description>Eastern Bank PLC (EBL) has partnered with Prokriti O Jibon Foundation (POJF) to support the Mangrove Restoration for Climate Resilience Project (MRCP) in the Sundarbans coastal belt, including Satkhira and nearby areas.
The initiative will focus on large-scale mangrove restoration, community engag</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 10:59:49 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>