<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 14:18:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Peru Congress ousts president, successor vows ‘war on crime’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/peru-congress-ousts-president-successor-vows-war-on-crime</link><description>Peru's lawmakers swore in Congress chief Jose Jeri as the country's new president less than an hour after unanimously voting to remove President Dina Boluarte, as anger mounted over rising crime and accusations of corruption.
One of the world's least popular leaders was ousted shortly after midnig</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 12:00:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ex-chief of Bangladesh Navy Sarwar Jahan Nizam dies</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ex-chief-of-bangladesh-navy-sarwar-jahan-nizam-dies</link><description>Former Chief of Naval Staff Vice Admiral (Retd) Sarwar Jahan Nizam died at 9.15 am on Friday at Combined Military Hospital (CMH) in Dhaka.
He was 73. Members of the Bangladesh Navy, including the current chief of naval staff, have expressed deep sorrow over his death, an Inter-Services Public Rela</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 12:45:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat demands inclusion of PR proposal in referendum</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-demands-inclusion-of-pr-proposal-in-referendum</link><description>The Jamaat-e-Islami has demanded that the proposal for elections under a system of proportional representation (PR) be included in the referendum on the July Charter.
Secretary General Mia Golam Porwar made the call during a brief speech on Friday at the south gate of Baitul Mukarram National Mosq</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 13:00:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India to reopen embassy in Kabul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/india-upgrades-ties-with-afghanistans-taliban-says-it-will-reopen-kabul-embassy</link><description>India on Friday upgraded ties with Afghanistan's Taliban administration, giving a boost to the diplomatically isolated group, by announcing it would reopen its embassy in Kabul that was shut after the Taliban seized power in 2021.
The Afghan Taliban administration will also send diplomats to New D</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 13:15:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Eggs should be added to school feeding programme, says Adviser Farida</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/eggs-should-be-added-to-school-feeding-programme-says-adviser-farida</link><description>Farida Akhter, adviser to the Ministry of Fisheries and Livestock, on Friday said that eggs should be included in school feeding programmes.
She mentioned that students are currently being given milk, and eggs should also be added to that menu.
She made the comment at a discussion meeting held at</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 13:00:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>309 more Bangladeshis repatriated from Libya</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/309-more-bangladeshis-repatriated-from-libya</link><description>A total of 309 Bangladeshi nationals who had been staying irregularly in Tripoli and surrounding areas of Libya were repatriated to Bangladesh on Friday through a coordinated effort of the Government of Bangladesh and the International Organization for Migration (IOM).
The repatriation was arrange</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 13:15:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Seven burnt in gas balloon explosion in Rajshahi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/seven-burnt-in-gas-balloon-explosion-in-rajshahi</link><description>Seven passengers of a battery-run rickshaw have suffered burns in a gas balloon explosion in Rajshahi’s Godagari Upazila, with five of them in critical condition.
The explosion occurred around 11:30am on Friday in the Kalipur area, said Godagari Police chief Moazzem Hossain.
Five of the inj</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 13:30:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>icddr,b, Washington University develop complementary food for children</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/icddrb-washington-university-develop-complementary-food-for-children</link><description>TIME has named a gut-restoring complementary food for undernourished children developed by icddr,b and Washington University to TIME’s Best Inventions of 2025.
The complementary developed through a long-standing collaboration between the International Centre for Diarrhoeal Disease Research,</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 14:00:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Details of the Gaza ceasefire agreement</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/details-of-the-gaza-ceasefire-agreement</link><description>Israel's government approved the Gaza ceasefire and hostage release deal early on Friday, setting the clock ticking on the first phase of an agreement that aims to end the two-year-old war.
The agreement covers only an initial stage, including handing over hostages held in Gaza in exchange for Pal</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 14:15:15 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>