<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 23:27:59 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>UK withdraws staff from Iran temporarily</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/uk-withdraws-staff-from-iran-temporarily</link><description>Britain said on Friday it had temporarily withdrawn its staff from Iran citing the security situation in the region.
US President Donald Trump briefly laid out his case for a possible attack on Iran in his State of the Union speech on Tuesday, underlining that while he preferred a diplomatic solut</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 16:53:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DSCC warns contractors over extra waste charges</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/waste-collectors-charging-above-tk-100-will-face-action-says-dscc-administrator</link><description>Dhaka South City Corporation (DSCC) Administrator Abdus Salam has warned that contractors will face consequences if they charge more than Tk 100 for collecting household waste.
At an Iftar event on Friday, he said any contractor found demanding more than the fixed amount would have their primary c</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 17:08:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Family blame loan shark for man’s death</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/family-allege-murder-over-loan-interest-as-man-found-hanging-in-madaripur</link><description>The family of a man whose body was found hanging from a tree near his house in Madaripur has alleged he was murdered after he failed to pay loan interest.
Relatives and local residents held a human chain and protest in Shibchar Upazila on Friday, demanding a fair investigation and the arrest of th</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 17:23:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt bans fishing in Padma-Meghna for 2 months to protect jatka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-bans-fishing-in-padma-meghna-for-2-months-to-protect-jatka</link><description>The government has imposed a two-month ban on catching all types of fish, including hilsa, in the Padma River and Meghna River from Saturday midnight to boost hilsa production and conserve jatka.
The restriction will remain in force from March 1 to April 30, during which fishing, sale, transport a</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 17:38:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Preparation underway to compensate small investors in 5 merged banks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/preparation-underway-to-compensate-small-investors-in-5-merged-banks</link><description>Government authorities prepare to compensate the small investors in the five distressed private banks merged into Sammilito Islami Bank late last year, officials say.



Instructed by the high-ups of the new government, the Financial Institutions Division (FID) is now calculating how much money</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 20:01:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Zubaida Rahman envisions women at the heart of development</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/zubaida-rahman-envisions-women-at-the-heart-of-development</link><description>Zubaida Rahman has emphasised placing women at the center of family and national development to ensure self-reliance and social justice.
She made the remarks while speaking at an Iftar event for underprivileged women and children in Gulshan on Friday.
The vice-president of the Ziaur Rahman Founda</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 20:16:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Natore police sub-inspector shot in leg as child fiddles with pistol</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/natore-police-sub-inspector-shot-in-leg-as-child-fiddles-with-pistol</link><description>A police sub-inspector has been injured after a bullet fired from his service pistol hit him while his young son was playing with the firearm in Natore.
On Friday evening, the incident took place at the police lines in Borhorishpur, Natore Police Superintendent Muhammad Abdul Wahab said.
Sub-Insp</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 20:31:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Developing local currency bond market</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/developing-local-currency-bond-market</link><description>The bond market serves as a critical lifeline for developing countries worldwide to channel funds for government expenditures and providing capital for businesses. However, Bangladesh's bond market remains very small, underdeveloped, and inactive compared to its regional peers. Bangladesh's bond ma</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 20:46:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Strengthening bank-financed projects to safeguard economic growth</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/reviews/strengthening-bank-financed-projects-to-safeguard-economic-growth</link><description>Business projects remain vital pillars of industrial expansion, employment generation, and national economic progress, where bank finance plays a pivotal role. By channelling public deposits into productive investments, banks contribute to the country's development trajectory in a variety of ways.</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 21:01:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Who are distorting Bangla language?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/who-are-distorting-bangla-language</link><description>During the month of language, a debate resurfaced over the distortion of Bangla through the use of Arabic, Persian, and Urdu words and jargon. Some people alleged a deliberate move to replace common Bangla words with non-Bengali ones, claiming an intent to undermine the essence of the language. Man</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 21:16:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Where do workers stand in AI age?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/where-do-workers-stand-in-ai-age</link><description>The debate over artificial intelligence and the future of the job market has often swung between anxiety and excitement. Much of the excitement has come from the promise of a more efficient world where machines can produce code, analyse data and handle routine tasks with remarkable speed. At the sa</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 21:31:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cleaning up the power sector mess</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/cleaning-up-the-power-sector-mess</link><description>A lack of long-term power and energy policy, penchant for quick fix and governance issues are responsible for leaving the country's power forever crisis-prone.  So, when Power, Energy and Mineral Resources Minister Iqbal Hassan Mahmood observes that power deals signed during the previous Awami</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 21:46:50 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>