<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 07:21:11 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Two killed in underground explosion at Australian silver mine</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/two-killed-in-underground-explosion-at-australian-silver-mine</link><description>Two workers were killed and another injured in an explosion at the recently reopened Polymetals Resources-owned Endeavor silver, zinc and lead mine in Australia on Tuesday, forcing the temporary suspension of operations.
Emergency services were called to the remote mining town of Cobar in the stat</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 04:37:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Here's what happens to your body when clocks 'fall back' an hour</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/heres-what-happens-to-your-body-when-clocks-fall-back-an-hour</link><description>Plan on a glorious extra hour of sleep as most of America “falls back” into standard time. But make sure to get outside for some morning sun, too — it’ll help your body clock reset faster.
Daylight saving time ends at 2 a.m. local time Sunday, which means you should set you</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 05:07:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cyclone ‘Montha’ over Bay likely to intensify, cross Andhra coast by evening</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cyclone-montha-over-bay-likely-to-intensify-cross-andhra-coast-by-evening</link><description>The cyclonic storm ‘Montha’ over the Westcentral Bay and adjoining Southwest Bay of Bengal is likely to move north-northwestwards and intensify further into a severe cyclonic storm.
 
It is expected to cross the Andhra Pradesh coast of India by Tuesday evening or night, said a sp</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 05:22:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Marico Bangladesh declares 500pc interim cash dividend</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/marico-bangladesh-declares-500pc-interim-cash-dividend</link><description>Marico Bangladesh has declared a 500 per cent interim cash dividend based on audited financial statements for the six-month period ended September 30 this year.
The company’s earnings per share (EPS) stood at Tk 110.52 for April to September this year, from Tk 101.31 in the same period of th</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 05:04:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Train hits truck in Chattogram; one dead</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/train-hits-truck-in-chattogram-one-dead</link><description>A man was killed when a goods-laden train hit a truck at the Sagorika level crossing in Chattogram port city early Tuesday.
 
The deceased was identified as Md Samsuddin, 38, the assistant of the truck driver.
 
Quoting witnesses, Shahidul Islam, officer-in-charge of Chattogram Railwa</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 05:19:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Three madrasha girls remain missing for 48 days</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/three-madrasha-girls-remain-missing-for-48-days</link><description>Three madrasa girls have been missing for one and a half months in Thakurgaon, leaving their families in deep distress.
The missing girls are Jui, 15, daughter of Shahjalal from Muraripur village in Birganj upazila of Dinajpur; Jannatul Ferdous Tamanna, 16, daughter of Jahangir Alam of Ganakpoyen</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 06:04:21 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>