<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 16:29:17 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>CRAB mourns passing of founding director Matiul Islam</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/crab-mourns-passing-of-founding-director-matiul-islam</link><description>Credit Rating Agency of Bangladesh Limited (CRAB) has expressed deep sorrow over the demise of its founding director, Md. Matiul Islam, according to a press release.
He was a visionary leader who played a pivotal role in shaping Bangladesh’s financial landscape.
His guidance was instrumenta</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 13:12:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>National grid to get extra 5mmcfd gas from Kailashtila next week</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/national-grid-to-get-extra-5mmcfd-gas-from-kailashtila-next-week</link><description>The country’s national gas grid is set to start receiving an additional around 5.0 million cubic feet per day (mmcfd) of natural gas from the onshore Kailashtila gas field starting next week.
This additional gas resource was found following a workover of Kailashtila-1 well by state-run Bangl</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 13:27:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Australia launches joint campaign to combat visa fraud</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/australia-launches-joint-campaign-to-combat-visa-fraud</link><description>Australia has joined its international partners in a coordinated campaign to raise awareness about visa scams as part of International Fraud Awareness Week, warning that fraudulent agents are increasingly targeting would-be migrants across South Asia, said a spokesman of the Australian High Commiss</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 13:42:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UNGA adopts resolution for renewed action on Rohingya crisis</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/unga-adopts-resolution-for-renewed-action-on-rohingya-crisis</link><description>The UN General Assembly’s Third Committee has adopted by consensus a resolution urging renewed international efforts to resolve the protracted Rohingya crisis and ensure the safe return of Rohingya refugees to Myanmar, said a foreign ministry spokesman on Thursday.
The measure, jointly table</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 13:57:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BD calls for collective cybersecurity at Colombo Security Conclave</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bd-calls-for-collective-cybersecurity-at-colombo-security-conclave</link><description>Bangladesh has urged member states of the Colombo Security Conclave (CSC) to accelerate collective action on cyberthreats, misinformation and regional security, warning that individual national measures are no longer sufficient to counter rapidly evolving digital risks.
Addressing the seventh meet</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 14:12:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Techtextil and Texprocess 2026 to kick off in Frankfurt on Apr 21</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/techtextil-and-texprocess-2026-to-kick-off-in-frankfurt-on-apr-21</link><description>The Techtextil and Texprocess 2026, one of the leading technical textiles and machinery exhibitions, will kick off on April 21 next year in Frankfurt, Germany, creating opportunities for value-added garment producers, including those from Bangladesh.
With changes in global demand toward specialise</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 14:27:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NBR’s revenue shortfall widens in October</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/nbrs-revenue-shortfall-widens-in-october</link><description>The National Board of Revenue (NBR) recorded a sharp fall in customs duty collection in October, posting a 27.17 percent deficit against its monthly target, according to official data released on Thursday.
The NBR had set a collection target of Tk 43.67 billion (Tk 4,367.17 crore) in customs duty</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 14:42:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt aiming to complete Aman procurement before election: Food Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-aiming-to-complete-aman-procurement-before-election-food-adviser</link><description>The government aims to complete the bulk of its seasonal procurement of Aman rice well ahead of the national election scheduled for mid-February, Food Adviser Ali Imam Majumdar said on Thursday.
He made the remarks following the official inauguration of the Aman rice collection drive.
Speaking to</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 14:57:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ADP implementation YoY rises slightly in first 4 months of FY26</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/adp-implementation-yoy-rises-slightly-in-first-4-months-of-fy26</link><description>The implementation rate of the Annual Development Programme (ADP) in the first four months (July–October) of the current fiscal year (FY26) has increased slightly to 8.33 percent compared to 7.90 percent registered in the same period last year.
According to data released by the Implementatio</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 15:12:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh Navy warship sails for Sri Lanka to join International Fleet Review</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-navy-warship-sails-for-sri-lanka-to-join-international-fleet-review</link><description>Bangladesh Navy warship BNS Prottoy left for the Indian Ocean island of Sri Lanka on Thursday to take part in an International Fleet Review (IFR), being held as part of the Sri Lankan Navy’s 75th anniversary.
The international maritime gathering will be held in Colombo from November 27 to 30</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 15:27:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bomb attack on DUCSU member’s home</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/attempted-arson-bomb-attack-at-ducsu-member-rafias-mymensingh-residence</link><description>Assailants have thrown a crude bomb at DUCSU member Umma Uswatun Rafia’s house in Mymensingh, while pouring flammable materials in an attempt to set the residence on fire.
Her family is reportedly in a state of panic following the attack.
The incident took place around 2:45am on Wednesday a</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 15:42:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Yunnan business delegation urges more Bangladesh consulates in China</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/yunnan-business-delegation-urges-more-bangladesh-consulates-in-china-chinese-mission-in-chattogram</link><description>A visiting business delegation from China’s Yunnan province has called on the Bangladesh government to open more consulates in key Chinese regions and recommended that China set up a consulate in Chattogram to deepen and facilitate trade and investment ties.
The proposals came at a discussio</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 15:57:44 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>