<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 02:28:16 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>British High Commissioner meets Army Chief</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/british-high-commissioner-meets-army-chief</link><description>British High Commissioner to Bangladesh Sarah Cooke has met Chief of Army Staff General Waker‑uz‑Zaman to explore ways to deepen defence ties.
She also reaffirmed the UK’s long‑standing encouragement of free, fair, credible and peaceful elections in Bangladesh, said the High Commission on Mo</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 16:56:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Biman MD, his wife, sent to jail for torturing domestic help</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/biman-md-his-wife-sent-to-jail-for-torturing-domestic-help</link><description>A Dhaka court on Monday sent Managing Director (MD) of Biman Bangladesh Airlines Shafiqur Rahman, his wife and two others to jail in a case filed over torturing domestic help.
Dhaka Metropolitan Magistrate Mohammad Ehsanul Islam passed the order when sub-inspector of Uttara West Police Station, Ro</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 17:11:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Arrest warrant issued for singer Noble, family</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/entertainment/court-orders-arrest-of-singer-noble-four-others-over-embezzlement</link><description>A Dhaka court has issued an arrest warrant against singer Mainul Ahsan Noble, his mother, wife, and two others in a case that accuses them of embezzling Tk 1.3 million.
Dhaka Metropolitan Magistrate Raju Ahmed passed the order on Monday after a report by the Police Bureau of Investigation (PBI).</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 17:26:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Another 15 Chittagong Port officials transferred amid NCT protests</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/another-15-chittagong-port-officials-transferred-amid-nct-protests</link><description>Authorities have transferred 15 more Chittagong Port officials involved in protests against lease of the New Mooring Container Terminal (NCT) to foreign handlers, a move denounced as “harassment”.
The Ministry of Shipping announced the reshuffle on Monday, citing “official necess</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 17:41:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Iran, US to hold nuclear talks Friday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/iran-us-to-hold-nuclear-talks-on-friday-some-regional-countries-to-participate-say-sources</link><description>Iran and the United States will resume nuclear talks on Friday in Turkey, Iranian and US officials told Reuters on Monday, while a regional diplomat said representatives from countries such as Saudi Arabia and Egypt would participate.
US Special Envoy Steve Witkoff and Iranian Foreign Minister Abb</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 17:56:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Uprising’s expectations remain unmet in last 18 months: TIB</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/uprisings-expectations-remain-unmet-in-last-18-months-tib</link><description>Transparency International Bangladesh (TIB) on Monday noted that despite an announcement to establish the practice of disclosing the asset statements of members of the Council of Advisers and government employees, they failed to set a positive example.
According to the TIB report, the growth and i</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 18:11:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>GP declares 105pc final cash dividend for 2025</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/gp-declares-105pc-final-cash-dividend-for-2025</link><description>Grameenphone (GP), the country’s largest mobile phone operator, has recommended a 105 per cent final cash dividend (total 215 per cent) for the year ended December 31, 2025.
The total dividend represents 98.16 per cent of profit after tax for 2025, including a 110 per cent interim cash divid</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 18:26:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Silence as social order</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/silence-as-social-order</link><description>Domestic violence in Bangladesh is routinely framed as a private tragedy, an unfortunate but inevitable aspect of family life. Yet the latest report, 'Violence Against Women Survey 2024' by the Bangladesh Bureau of Statistics (BBS), confronts us with a far more disturbing reality. According to the</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 18:41:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>What's in store for post-poll govt?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/whats-in-store-for-post-poll-govt</link><description>Following a consultation with Bangladesh at the end of January 2026, the global multilateral lender IMF in a press release made a rather cautious forecast about the economy under the post-election government. The IMF was somewhat positive about GDP's growth prospect amidst the recent economic slowd</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 18:56:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>In quest of peaceful electioneering</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/in-quest-of-peaceful-electioneering</link><description>For the first time in nearly two decades, the people of Bangladesh are being offered a genuine opportunity to exercise their right to vote under a non-partisan interim government. The election scheduled for 12 February is more than a routine democratic exercise. It is a moment freighted with histor</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 19:11:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh's exports on negative growth trajectory for months</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladeshs-exports-on-negative-growth-trajectory-for-months</link><description>Bangladesh's merchandise-export earnings during the first seven months of the current fiscal year stayed on a negative growth trajectory as main earner garment shipments to major EU countries and other destinations contracted.
Germany and France are among the major destinations in the European Uni</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 19:26:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Restoration of rivers and canals</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/restoration-of-rivers-and-canals</link><description>As part of river and canal restoration in and around the capital city, a programme is on the move with the World Bank (WB) committing a loan to the tune of $370 million. A report carried in this newspaper on Sunday claims that the fund may be approved by the WB Board within this month. The interim</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 19:41:44 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>