<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 09:24:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Bangladesh seeks urgent international actions for Rohingya repatriation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-seeks-urgent-international-actions-for-rohingya-repatriation</link><description>Bangladesh has called for urgent international action for the return of the Rohingyas, as it was no longer possible for Bangladesh to bear the burden of hosting 1.3 million Rohingyas.The UN General Assembly’s third committee has adopted by consensus the resolution on Rohingya Muslims calling</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 06:30:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP to ensure all future investments follow economic benchmarks, says Khosru</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bnp-to-ensure-all-future-investments-follow-economic-benchmarks-says-khosru</link><description>Every future investment will be made in strict adherence to economic standards to ensure that taxpayers’ money is used for public welfare, BNP Standing Committee Member Amir Khasru Mahmud Chowdhury said on Thursday.
Khosru said that investments must be carefully evaluated, speaking at an eve</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 06:45:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump approves 28-point plan for Russia-Ukraine peace</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-approves-28-point-plan-for-russia-ukraine-peace</link><description>US President Donald Trump has approved a 28-point plan for peace between Russia and Ukraine that US officials developed in consultation with Russian and Ukrainian officials, NBC News reported on Wednesday.
Trump's special envoy, Steve Witkoff, Vice President JD Vance, Secretary of State Marco Rubi</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 07:00:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Police recover a student's dead body in Gaibandha</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/police-recover-a-students-dead-body-in-gaibandha</link><description>Fulchhari Thana police recovered the hanging body of a college student from the family toilet at Kanchipara village of Kanchipara union in Fulchhari upazila of Gaibandha district on Wednesday.
The victim has been identified as Riyad Miah, 23, son of Rahmat Ali, of the village. He is also an interm</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 07:15:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Iran denies starting nuclear talks with US</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/iran-denies-starting-nuclear-talks-with-us</link><description>Iran's Foreign Ministry spokesman Esmaeil Baghaei on Wednesday rejected a recent claim by the US president that Tehran and Washington were holding nuclear talks.
He made the remarks in an address to reporters in Tehran, one day after US President Donald Trump said the United States was talking to</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 07:30:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Three executive magistrates dismissed during training</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/three-executive-magistrates-dismissed-during-training</link><description>The government has dismissed three assistant commissioners (executive magistrates) while they were undergoing foundation training.
A notification, signed by Ehsanul Haque, Senior Secretary to the Ministry of Public Administration, was issued in this regard on Wednesday, reports UNB.
Those dismiss</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 07:45:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Joy confident India will reject Bangladesh’s request to extradite Hasina</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/joy-confident-india-will-reject-bangladeshs-request-to-extradite-hasina</link><description>Sajeeb Wazed Joy, the son and former ICT advisor to ousted prime minister Sheikh Hasina, says India is not likely to accept the Bangladesh government’s request to extradite her to face a death sentence over crimes against humanity.
"India has always been a good friend, and in the crisis, Ind</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 08:00:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pakistan army kills 23 militants near Afghan border</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/pakistan-army-kills-23-militants-near-afghan-border</link><description>Pakistani security forces raided two Pakistani Taliban hideouts in the country’s northwest near the Afghan border, triggering intense shootouts that left 23 militants dead, the military said Thursday.
There were no details on any casualties among the military. The raids took place on Wednesd</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 08:00:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>SMP launches GenieA app to streamline citizen services</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/smp-launches-geniea-app-to-streamline-citizen-services</link><description>Sylhet Metropolitan Police (SMP) has launched the GenieA app to make police services more accessible, enabling citizens to request help and report incidents with a single click.
SMP Commissioner Abdul Kuddus Chowdhury introduced the app which was first piloted on October 16 at Moglabazar Police St</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 08:15:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DMP launches modern cyber support centre</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dmp-launches-modern-cyber-support-centre</link><description>Detective Branch (DB) of Dhaka Metropolitan Police (DMP) on Thursday unveiled a state-of-the-art cyber support centre, setting a new benchmark in the fight against cybercrime and strengthening measures to safeguard public security.
DMP Commissioner S M Sazzat Ali formally opened the centre as chie</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 08:30:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US clears $93m sale of Javelin anti-tank system, Excalibur projectiles to India</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-clears-93m-sale-of-javelin-anti-tank-system-excalibur-projectiles-to-india</link><description>The US State Department has approved the sale of Javelin anti-tank missile system and Excalibur guided artillery munitions worth $93 million to India, the US Defense Security Cooperation Agency (DSCA) said on Wednesday.
The purchase of US defence equipment is India's first under Washington's forei</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 08:45:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Journalists to enjoy greater freedom after election: Khosru</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/journalists-to-enjoy-greater-freedom-after-election-khosru</link><description>BNP standing committee member Amir Khosru Mahmud Chowdhury has said that journalists will be able to practice freer and more independent journalism if BNP forms the next government, reaffirming that the party has always stood for media freedom.
“Ziaur Rahman broke the idea of Baksal’s</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 09:00:46 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>