<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 18:32:46 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Israeli fire kills three people in Gaza, tension rises</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/israeli-fire-kills-three-people-in-gaza-tension-rises</link><description>Israeli fire killed at least three Palestinians in two separate incidents across the enclave, local health authorities said, as tension rises over continued violence.
Medics said one Palestinian was killed in the Tuffah neighbourhood in Gaza City, in an area under Palestinian control, while two ot</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 16:07:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh sees $1.12b in remittances in first 10 days of January</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh-sees-112b-in-remittances-in-first-10-days-of-january</link><description>The remittance from Bangladeshi expatriates continued its upward momentum in January, with the country receiving more than US$1.12 billion in the first 10 days of the month.
Bangladesh received $17.39 billion in inward remittances from July to January 10, 2026, in the current fiscal year, FY 2025-</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 16:22:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt cuts Tk 120b from top development projects over slow progress</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/govt-cuts-tk-120b-from-top-development-projects-over-slow-progress</link><description>The interim government is slashing allocations for several major development projects in the Revised Annual Development Programme (RADP), cutting over Tk 120 billion from eight of the top 10 priority projects due to slow progress and fiscal constraints.
According to planning ministry sources, allo</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 16:37:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cut default rate to 25pc by March: governor</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh-central-bank-chief-asks-banks-to-cut-default-loans-to-25-per-cent-by-march</link><description>Bangladesh Bank Governor Ahsan H Mansur has directed commercial banks to reduce their non-performing loan (NPL) ratio to 25 percent by March, using a combination of restructuring, rescheduling, write-offs, and intensified recovery efforts.
The directive came during a meeting on Sunday with top exe</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 16:52:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ICT grants first bail in July Uprising case</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ict-grants-first-bail-in-july-uprising-crimes-against-humanity-case</link><description>The International Crimes Tribunal (ICT) on Sunday granted bail to an accused for the first time in a case involving crimes against humanity committed during the July uprising last year.
The accused, Humayun Kabir Patwary, served as president of the Lakshmipur Sadar Upazila Awami League and chairma</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 16:15:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hajj flights set to begin from April 18: Ministry</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hajj-flights-set-to-begin-from-april-18-ministry</link><description>The Hajj flights from Bangladesh to Saudi Arabia will start from April 18, said the Religious Affairs Ministry.
All Hajj agencies and airlines will have to strictly follow the directives of the Saudi government and the Hajj Package and Guidelines 2026, it said.
The ministry sent letters to the Ha</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 16:30:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Noticeable transformation in the financial horizon</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/noticeable-transformation-in-the-financial-horizon</link><description>The last few days have seen positive development on the country's financial horizon. Remittances hit a record in 2025, helping shore up reserves. According to Bangladesh Bank data, Bangladeshis abroad sent home a record US$32.8 billion in 2025. Economists have observed that more expatriates are now</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 16:45:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Security concerns before election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/security-concerns-before-election</link><description>The 13th national election is barely a month away. Now, is the atmosphere congenial to holding a general election? If maintenance of law and order is a prerequisite for holding a free, fair and peaceful poll, a unanimous verdict would be in the negative. Killings by shooting, beating, hacking and s</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 17:00:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Modernising data  protection laws</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/modernising-data-protection-laws</link><description>Data are what a piece of information is made of. So, it is important that data on any subject are well-preserved and protected; and the information they generate is also well-preserved and protected. In this Digital Age, which started from the mid-20th century and is ongoing, protection of data is</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 17:15:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Protecting local industries</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/protecting-local-industries</link><description>For a developing country like Bangladesh, the importance of pursuing an import substitution strategy cannot be overstated. Import substitution is not merely about reducing dependence on foreign goods; it is a strategic pathway to building a robust industrial base, generating employment, saving fore</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 17:30:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Help struggling businesses with policy  concessions promptly, slash NPLs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/help-struggling-businesses-with-policy-concessions-promptly-slash-npls</link><description>Bankers are now given until next March to downsize the classified-loan buildups in the banking sector below 25 per cent through prompt delivery of government policy concessions for struggling businesses.
The central bank made the directive to top executives in the country's all commercial</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 17:45:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Best Opportunity of My Life’: Moyeen Khan on working with Khaleda Zia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/best-opportunity-of-my-life-moyeen-khan-on-working-with-khaleda-zia</link><description>BNP senior leader and former minister Dr Abdul Moyeen Khan has said that serving in the cabinet of former prime minister Begum Khaleda Zia was the most significant and rewarding opportunity of his life.
“A dignified and just prime minister like the late Begum Khaleda Zia may not come to Bang</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 18:00:42 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>