<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 12:45:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Border standoff flares over BSF Joypurhat re-fencing bid</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tension-grips-joypurhat-border-after-bgb-halts-bsf-re-fencing-attempt</link><description>Tension has returned to the Joypurhat border after Bangladesh border troopers stopped an attempt by India’s Border Security Force (BSF) to re-fence a sensitive stretch of the frontier, raising fresh concerns among residents of the area.
The incident unfolded on Saturday at Ghonapara along th</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 09:51:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCP, LDP join Jamaat-led alliance</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ncp-ldp-join-jamaat-led-alliance</link><description>Two more political parties have joined an alliance of eight like-minded parties led by Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami, Jamaat Amir Dr Shafiqur Rahman said on Sunday.
He said the newly added parties are the Liberal Democratic Party (LDP) and the National Citizen Party (NCP).
Dr Shafiqur made the annou</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 10:06:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Online Editors Alliance president Hasan Sharif, secretary Mizan Sohel</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/online-editors-alliance-president-hasan-sharif-secretary-mizan-sohel</link><description>A new executive committee of the Online Editors Alliance (OEA), an organisation of heads of online and digital departments of leading media outlets in the country, was formed for the 2026 term during its annual general meeting (AGM) on Saturday.
The AGM was held at Waterfall Restaurant and Convent</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 10:21:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jara, Tajnuva invited to Aam Jonotar Dal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/aam-jonotar-dal-opens-door-to-former-ncp-leaders-jara-tajnuva-after-resignations</link><description>Aam Jonotar Dal’s General Secretary Tarek Rahman has invited former National Citizen Party (NCP) leaders Tasnim Jara and Tajnuva Jabeen to join his party.
He made the call in a Facebook post at 2:10pm on Sunday.
“For those who are leaving NCP because of Jamaat, the doors of the Aam Jo</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 10:36:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ukraine's DTEK says power restored to 1 million Kyiv-area households</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/ukraines-dtek-says-power-restored-to-1-million-kyiv-area-households</link><description>Ukraine's leading private energy provider said on Sunday that it had restored power to more than a million households in and around Kyiv a day after a Russian air attack had forced emergency outages.
A combined missile and drone attack early on Saturday had killed two people and knocked out power</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 10:51:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh expresses concern over minority killings in India</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-expresses-concern-over-minority-killings-in-india</link><description>Bangladesh has expressed deep concern over recent incidents of minority killings and violence in India. Dhaka has called for fair investigations into these incidents and for bringing the guilty to justice.
SM Mahbubul Alam, spokesperson of the Foreign Ministry, expressed this concern on Sunday (De</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 11:06:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Amazon halts plans for drone delivery in Italy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/amazon-halts-plans-for-drone-delivery-in-italy</link><description>Amazon (AMZN.O) said on Sunday it has decided not to pursue plans to deliver goods by drone in Italy, saying that while it had made good progress with aerospace regulators, broader business regulatory issues did not support the project.
The Italian civil aviation ENAC called the decision unexpecte</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 11:21:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Central African Republic votes, Russia ally Touadera seeks third term</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/central-african-republic-votes-russia-ally-touadera-seeks-third-term</link><description>Central African Republic President Faustin-Archange Touadera is seeking a third term on Sunday as the chronically unstable country holds national elections, touting security gains made with the help of Russian mercenaries and Rwandan soldiers.
The 68-year-old mathematician oversaw a constitutional</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 11:36:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tepid early turnout in Myanmar election as junta touts stability</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/tepid-early-turnout-in-myanmar-election-as-junta-touts-stability</link><description>Under the shadow of civil war and questions over the poll's credibility, voters in Myanmar cast their ballots in apparently low numbers in a general election on Sunday, the first since a military coup toppled the last civilian government in 2021.
The junta, having crushed pro-democracy protests af</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 11:51:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Inqilab Moncho‘s blockade triggers massive traffic jam on Dhaka-M’singh highway</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/inqilab-monchos-blockade-triggers-massive-traffic-jam-on-dhaka-msingh-highway</link><description>A massive traffic jam was created on the Dhaka-Mymensingh highway on Sunday following a blockade enforced by Inqilab Moncho, demanding the swift arrest and trial of those responsible for the killing of martyr Sharif Osman bin Hadi.
A group of protesters blocked the highway in front of Uttara&amp;rsquo</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 12:06:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CA orders tighter cybersecurity for polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/yunus-orders-tighter-cybersecurity-for-polls-digital-services-ahead-of-election</link><description>Chief Advisor Muhammad Yunus has instructed the National Cyber Security Agency to intensify efforts to counter all forms of cybercrime ahead of the February elections.
Yunus gave the order on Sunday at a meeting of the National Cyber Security Council, according to the Chief Advisor’s Office</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 12:21:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AI reshapes storytelling from script to screen in China</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/ai-reshapes-storytelling-from-script-to-screen-in-china</link><description>Artificial intelligence is rapidly transforming China’s film and television industry, playing an expanding role in storytelling from script development to on-screen production.
At Hengdian World Studios in east China’s Zhejiang Province — often dubbed “China’s Hollywo</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 12:36:45 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>