<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 15:25:40 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Shimanto Bank inks MoU with Force Support Wing of Border Guard Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/shimanto-bank-inks-mou-with-force-support-wing-of-border-guard-bangladesh</link><description>Shimanto Bank has recently signed a Memorandum of Understanding (MoU) with the Force Support Wing of Border Guard Bangladesh at Pilkhana, Dhaka, according to a press release.
As part of this agreement, BGB members who use their Shimanto Bank Credit Cards for monthly purchases at the BGB Exclusive</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 12:21:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Electrical short circuit triggered cargo village fire at Dhaka airport, probe finds</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/electrical-short-circuit-triggered-cargo-village-fire-at-dhaka-airport-probe-finds</link><description>A devastating fire that tore through the cargo village of Dhaka’s Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport last month was caused by an electrical short circuit, an official investigation has concluded.
The report which exposing years of neglect, dangerous storage practices and the absence of b</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 12:36:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prime Bank launches Bangladesh’s first AI-powered digital LC platform ‘Prime Banijjo’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/prime-bank-launches-bangladeshs-first-ai-powered-digital-lc-platform-prime-banijjo</link><description>Prime Bank PLC has recently launched Prime Banijjo, the country’s first AI-powered digital LC management platform, marking a major milestone in Bangladesh’s trade digitisation journey, according to a press release.
The launch event featured an interactive experience session where corpo</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 12:51:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cox’s Bazar NGOs left out of UNHCR’s 2026–29 ‘Rohingya Response’ partnership</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/coxs-bazar-ngos-left-out-of-unhcrs-2026-29-rohingya-response-partnership</link><description>Local NGOs in Cox’s Bazar, who have long worked on Rohingya issues, said on Tuesday that UNHCR has stopped all partnerships with Cox’s Bazar–based NGOs.
Instead, UNHCR has given the partnerships to international NGOs and organisations based outside the district.
They said this g</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 13:06:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pragati Insurance settles its first non-life car insurance claim under Bancassurance partnership of Midland Bank</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/pragati-insurance-settles-its-first-non-life-car-insurance-claim-under-bancassurance-partnership-of-midland-bank</link><description>Pragati Insurance Limited, the Bancassurance partner of Midland Bank PLC, has successfully settled its first non-life motor car insurance claim.
To mark the occasion, a brief ceremony was organised at the bank’s Gulshan branch. During the event, a cheque was handed over to the customer, Mr.</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 13:21:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mahtab Osmani joins Bank Asia as deputy managing director</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/mahtab-osmani-joins-bank-asia-as-deputy-managing-director</link><description>Mr. Mahtab Osmani has joined Bank Asia PLC. as Deputy Managing Director &amp; Head of Corporate Business, International Banking, and Export Finance, effective 25 November 2025.
Mr. Osmani brings 24 years of distinguished experience from Standard Chartered Bank, where he progressed from an analyst role</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 13:36:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Allow expats to register with only passports: BNP to EC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/allow-expats-to-register-with-only-passports-bnp-to-ec</link><description>BNP on Tuesday urged the Election Commission to extend the registration time for out of country voting (OCV) and include the eligible expatriates who do not have national identity (NID) cards but hold valid Bangladeshi passports in the voter lists ahead of the upcoming national election.
“Ma</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 13:51:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fire breaks out at Korail Basti, 16 fire units working</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fire-breaks-out-at-korail-basti-16-fire-units-working</link><description>A fire broke out at Korail Basti, a slum in Tejgaon area of the capital on Tuesday evening.
Talha Bin Jashim, duty officer at the Fire Service and Civil Defence (FSCD) headquarters media cell, said the fire originated from one of the shanties of the slum around 5:22pm.
Responding to an emergency</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 13:52:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump’s battle with the BBC could threaten its global reach</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trumps-battle-with-the-bbc-could-threaten-its-global-reach</link><description>When the BBC launched an expansion into the US in June, its head of news promised “trust at a time of dramatic global uncertainty”.
Five months on, President Donald Trump is threatening a $5 billion lawsuit, governments long hostile to independent news are vowing to make life difficult</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 14:07:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Janata Bank calls auction for Beximco factories</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/janata-bank-calls-auction-for-beximco-factories</link><description>Janata Bank PLC has issued an auction notice to sell off the factories, land, and head office of Bangladesh Export Import Company (Beximco) Limited in an effort to recover over Tk 13.22 billion in defaulted loans, even as the government pursues an international leasing arrangement to revive the tro</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 14:22:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Protests outside Shahbagh Police Station after clashes</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/protesters-stage-sit-in-after-clashes-with-police-over-deferring-47th-bcs-exam</link><description>An hour of clashes between police and job seekers demanding a postponement of the 47th BCS written exam have brought traffic at Shahbagh to a standstill, while protesters staged sit-in outside the police station.
Clashes erupted on Tuesday afternoon when the demonstrators broke through police barr</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 14:37:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh to face England, West Indies in T20 World Cup</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/cricket/bangladesh-to-face-england-west-indies-in-t20-world-cup</link><description>Bangladesh have been drawn alongside England, West Indies, Nepal and Italy in Group C of the 2026 Men’s T20 World Cup, scheduled for February and March next year.
India face their archrivals Pakistan in Group A.
The tournament, co-hosted by India and Sri Lanka, will be held from Feb 7 to Ma</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 14:52:52 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>