<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 17:36:57 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>UK PM Starmer to visit India on 8-9 October, says Indian foreign ministry</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/uk-pm-starmer-to-visit-india-on-8-9-october-says-indian-foreign-ministry</link><description>British Prime Minister Keir Starmer will make his first official visit to India on 8-9 October, India's Ministry of External Affairs said in a statement on Saturday.
Britain and India signed a free trade agreement in July during a visit by Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi, sealing a deal to cut</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 15:13:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC dialogue with media persons on Monday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-dialogue-with-media-persons-on-monday</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) will hold a dialogue with journalists on Monday ahead of the upcoming 13th National Parliamentary Election.
The dialogue will take place at the conference room of the EC Secretariat in Agargaon, Dhaka, said Ashadul Haque, Assistant Director (Public Relations) of EC.
E</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 15:28:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>British lawmakers call for action over human rights ‘decline’ in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/british-lawmakers-call-for-action-over-human-rights-decline-in-bangladesh</link><description>A group of British lawmakers has voiced concern over what they describe as a “deteriorating” human rights situation in Bangladesh, urging the UK government, alongside the United Nations and the “wider international community”, to take a firm stance on the issue.
They also c</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 15:11:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gold price hits record high again, nears Tk 2 lakh per bhori</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/gold-price-hits-record-high-again-nears-tk-2-lakh-per-bhori</link><description>The Bangladesh Jewellers Association (BAJUS) has increased the price of gold by Tk 2,192 per bhori, setting the new rate of 22-carat gold at Tk 1,97,576 per bhori, the highest in the country’s history.
The new price will come into effect from Sunday, according to a BAJUS press release issued</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 15:26:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BFUJ demands implementation of 9th wage board, formation of 10th, and other reforms</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bfuj-demands-implementation-of-9th-wage-board-formation-of-10th-and-other-reforms</link><description>The Bangladesh Federal Union of Journalists (BFUJ) has demanded immediate implementation of the 9th Wage Board and the formation of the 10th, along with eight other pressing demands aimed at improving the professional rights, welfare, and security of journalists across the country.The demands were</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 15:41:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UP Chairman Alfu Mia, suspect linked to ‘Sada Pathor loot’, arrested</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/up-chairman-alfu-mia-suspect-linked-to-sada-pathor-loot-arrested</link><description>Kazi Abdul Wadud Alfu Mia, the chairman of Telikhal Union and a prominent figure in the local Awami League, has been arrested over alleged connections with the illegal sand and stone theft from Sada Pathor in Sylhet’s Companiganj.
He was arrested near the Agricultural Bank in the town on Sat</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 16:11:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh seeks further reduction in US tariffs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-seeks-further-reduction-in-us-tariffs</link><description>National Security Adviser and High Representative for the Rohingya issue Dr Khalilur Rahman has requested Assistant US Trade Representative Brendan Lynch to consider further reduction in tariffs as the trade gap becomes narrower between the two countries.
Dr Rahman made the request at a meeting wi</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 16:26:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh closely monitoring safety of Shahidul Alam: CA</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-closely-monitoring-safety-of-shahidul-alam-ca</link><description>Bangladesh is closely monitoring the status and safety of those participating in the historic flotilla for Gaza, especially world-renowned photographer and human rights activist Shahidul Alam, Chief Adviser Prof Muhammad Yunus said in a statement today (Saturday). 
“Shahidul has approac</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 16:56:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A saga of wastage and despair</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/a-saga-of-wastage-and-despair</link><description>The news appeared in newspapers rather quietly - and it did not attract much public attention either. May be, it was not an exciting issue or it did not represent a loud emergency. But in the absolute analysis, it reflects an impending danger. In Bangladesh, about nine lakh young people with univer</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 17:11:34 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>