<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 10:27:29 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Killing of 8 puppies: Ishwardi govt officer's wife arrested</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/killing-of-8-puppies-ishwardi-govt-officers-wife-arrested</link><description>Police have arrested a government officer's wife suspected of killing eight puppies that were stuffed into a sack and drowned in a pond in Pabna’s Ishwardi Upazila.
Nishi Rahman, 38, was detained on Tuesday in connection with a case filed by livestock officials under the Animal Welfare Act,</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 07:04:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>28th anniversary of CHT accord celebrated</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/28th-anniversary-of-cht-accord-celebrated</link><description>The 28th anniversary of the historic Chittagong Hill Tracts (CHT) Peace Accord was observed on Tuesday with a renewed call for harmony, cooperation, and inclusive development in the hill region.
The Ministry of Chittagong Hill Tracts Affairs marked the occasion by organising a seminar titled &amp;ldqu</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 07:04:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cloth on overhead cable halts Metro Rail for 16 minutes</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cloth-on-overhead-cable-halts-metro-rail-for-16-minutes</link><description>Metro rail services were suspended for 16 minutes on Wednesday after a piece of cloth got entangled in the overhead electric cable between Uttara North and Uttara South stations.
According to Dhaka Mass Transit Company Limited (DMTCL), train movement came to a halt at 12:22 pm when the cloth fell</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 07:19:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Miscreants hack woman to death at her house</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/miscreants-hack-woman-to-death-at-her-house</link><description>A woman was killed, and her niece was injured in an attack by miscreants at their house in Joypurhat Sadar upazila early Wednesday.  
The deceased was identified as Nurunnahar Begum, 47, a resident of Chirla village under Chak Barkat union of the upazila, and her injured niece is Khatija Khat</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 07:34:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Eden College students block road over 5-point demand</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/eden-college-students-block-road-over-5-point-demand</link><description>Students of Dhaka's Eden Mohila College have taken to the streets to press home a five-point demand that includes greater autonomy for the institution.
The protesters descended on the road in front of the college around 11:00 am on Wednesday, chanting slogans to emphasise their demands, reports bd</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 07:49:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Over 156,000 Bangladeshi expats register to vote so far</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/over-156000-bangladeshi-expats-register-to-vote-so-far</link><description>More than 156,000 expatriate Bangladeshi voters from different countries have so far registered through the mobile app ‘Postal Vote Bd’ since November 19 to vote in the upcoming national election and the referendum, both to be held on a single day in early February 2026.
The Election C</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 08:04:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Child diarrhoea on rise, patients outnumber DMCH beds</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/child-diarrhoea-on-rise-patients-outnumber-dmch-beds</link><description>With the advent of winter, noted physician Abdul Kadir urged the parents to remain in high alert about seasonal diarrhoea.
He advised avoiding outside food to protect their children from diarrhoea during the winter as the prevalence of various viruses and bacteria increases during this season, rep</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 08:12:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rebuilding trust through technology: The future of Islamic digital banking</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/rebuilding-trust-through-technology-the-future-of-islamic-digital-banking</link><description>Islamic banking in Bangladesh is entering a new phase of transformation shaped by evolving customer expectations, rapid technological progress and an increasingly digital financial landscape. As the market expands and customers seek more accessible, transparent and value-driven financial solutions,</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 08:27:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Global growth to slow to 2.6pc in 2025: UN report</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/global/global-growth-to-slow-to-26pc-in-2025-un-report</link><description>Global growth will slow to 2.6 per cent in 2025, down from 2.9 per cent in 2024, due to growing pressure from financial volatility and geopolitical uncertainty facing global trade and investment, the United Nations Trade and Development (UNCTAD) said in a report released on Tuesday.
The UNCTAD's T</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 08:42:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Youth dies after being hit by train in Khulna</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/youth-dies-after-being-hit-by-train-in-khulna</link><description>A young man was killed on Wednesday after being run over by a train in the Daulatpur rail gate area of Khulna city.
Police said the victim, identified as Touhidur Rahman, 25, was crossing the railway line when a Khulna-bound passenger train from Chilahati hit him, killing him on the spot.
Azad Ra</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 08:57:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Helicopters to land near Evercare under SSF protocol</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/helicopters-to-land-near-evercare-under-ssf-protocol</link><description>The government has said that Army and Air Force helicopters will conduct test landings and takeoffs at two open fields near Dhaka’s Evercare Hospital, where former prime minister Khaleda Zia is currently undergoing treatment.
The members of the public have been asked not to be confused by th</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 09:12:54 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>