<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 15:18:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>80pc of strokes preventable through lifestyle modification: Experts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/80pc-of-strokes-preventable-through-lifestyle-modification-experts</link><description>Nearly 80 per cent of strokes are preventable through lifestyle modifications and controlling high blood pressure, quitting smoking, avoiding unhealthy diets and staying physically active, said experts.
The experts said this at the International Stroke Conference 2025 held on Sunday at Bangladesh</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 12:05:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>At least two dead as Super Typhoon Fung-wong nears landfall in the Philippines</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/at-least-two-dead-as-super-typhoon-fung-wong-nears-landfall-in-the-philippines</link><description>At least two people died in the Philippines as Super Typhoon Fung-wong lashed central and eastern parts of the country, with heavy rains and strong winds cutting power in large areas of the Bicol region ahead of its expected landfall in northern Luzon.
More than a million people have evacuated vul</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 12:20:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>71 Madrasah teachers, 2 faculty members become British Council-trained teacher educators for English</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/71-madrasah-teachers-2-faculty-members-become-british-council-trained-teacher-educators-for-english</link><description>The British Council, in collaboration with the Bangladesh Madrasah Teachers’ Training Institute (BMTTI) and Technical and Madrasah Education Division (TMED), has completed an intensive six-day residential Training of Trainers (ToT) programme.
Delivered over 28 sessions by nine top English La</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 12:35:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Asif Mahmud plans to stand in February election as an independent</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/asif-mahmud-plans-to-stand-in-february-election-as-an-independent</link><description>Local Government Advisor Asif Mahmud Shojib Bhuyain has said he intends to contest in the next parliamentary polls as an independent candidate.
On Sunday afternoon, he said, though he has not yet decided from where he will stand, he hopes, “It will be from Dhaka, God willing,” accordin</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 12:50:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Four school students drown in Meherpur lake</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/four-school-students-drown-in-meherpur-lake</link><description>Four school students have died while picking water lilies from a lake in Meherpur Sadar.
Meherpur Sadar Upazila administrator (UNO) Khairul Islam said, “The accident occurred around 5:15 pm on Sunday at Mominpur Beel.”</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 13:05:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>6 more die of dengue; 1,195 hospitalised in 24 hours</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/6-more-die-of-dengue-1195-hospitalised-in-24-hours</link><description>The dengue situation in Bangladesh continues to worsen, with six more deaths and 1,195 new hospitalisations recorded across the country in the 24 hours till Sunday morning.
According to the Directorate General of Health Services (DGHS), the latest figures bring this year’s total death toll f</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 13:20:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Expand Bangladesh-South Korea cooperation: Seminar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/expand-bangladesh-south-korea-cooperation-seminar</link><description>Speakers at a seminar on Sunday highlighted the importance of expanding cooperation between Bangladesh and South Korea in advanced manufacturing and infrastructure projects in a changing global environment.
They talked about roads, ports and power sector projects, strengthening collaboration in di</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 13:35:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka slams Rajnath Singh’s remarks on Prof Yunus as ‘incorrect, not respectful’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dhaka-slams-rajnath-singhs-remarks-on-prof-yunus-as-incorrect-not-respectful</link><description>Bangladesh on Sunday described the recent comments made by Indian Defence Minister Rajnath Singh on Chief Adviser Dr Muhammad Yunus as ‘incorrect’ and ‘not respectful of propriety and diplomatic nicety’ and stressed that Bangladesh remains committed to a mutually beneficial</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 13:39:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CID approves charge sheets against Beximco for laundering TK 12 billion</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cid-approves-charge-sheets-against-beximco-for-laundering-tk-12-billion</link><description>The Criminal Investigation Department (CID) of Police has approved the submission of charge sheets in 17 money-laundering cases filed against Beximco Group Vice Chairman Salman F. Rahman, Chairman A.S.F. Rahman, and several others, over allegations of laundering nearly USD 97 million (approximately</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 13:54:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>25 held in Dhaka over ‘plan to release 100,000 balloons with AL slogans’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/25-held-in-dhaka-over-plan-to-release-100000-balloons-with-al-slogans</link><description>Dhaka Metropolitan Police’s Detective Branch (DB) have arrested 25 leaders and activists of Awami League and its affiliated bodies in separate drives in the capital over 24 hours till 8 am on Sunday for their alleged plan  to release 100,000 balloons with Awami League slogans.
They had</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 14:09:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tariff weaponisation poses grave threat to Bangladesh, experts warn</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tariff-weaponisation-poses-grave-threat-to-bangladesh-experts-warn</link><description>Bangladesh faces an increasingly precarious trade environment as global tariff regimes grow more volatile and geopolitics reshapes global supply chains, economists and policy analysts warned at a seminar in Dhaka on Sunday.
Speaking at the event, titled “Navigating Geopolitical Dynamics: Tow</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 14:24:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Plot graft’: 22 people testify against Hasina, Rehana, Tulip</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/plot-graft-22-people-testify-against-hasina-rehana-tulip</link><description>A Dhaka court has recorded testimonies of 22 witnesses in three separate cases by the Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) against deposed prime minister Sheikh Hasina and members of her family over forgery allegations in the allocation of plots in the Purbachal New Town Project.
Her sister Sheikh Reh</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 14:39:02 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>