<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 03:15:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Ensuring justice for small investors</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/ensuring-justice-for-small-investors</link><description>A sudden swing from officially reported positive asset values to a declaration of deeply negative net worth is no routine accounting adjustment. Yet the speed with which this emerged during the merger of the five troubled Islamic banks has raised serious concerns about the credibility of financial</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 18:45:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>RSC to expand activities beyond safety issues amid industry disagreement</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/rsc-to-expand-activities-beyond-safety-issues-amid-industry-disagreement</link><description>The RMG Sustainability Council (RSC) is set to expand its activities beyond safety-related issues as it plans to address concerns mainly involving workers’ rights, including wages, trade unions, and collective bargaining, amid disagreement from industry leaders.
Industry insiders said the RS</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 19:00:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Commission recommends onion import to tame prices</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/commission-recommends-onion-import-to-tame-prices</link><description>The Bangladesh Trade and Tariff Commission (BTTC) has recommended allowing onion imports to control the rising prices in the local market.
Given the increase in onion prices, import permission should be granted immediately, the commission noted.
According to the BTTC, onion prices typically rise</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 00:00:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New ICT projects look foredoomed like forerunners</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/new-ict-projects-look-foredoomed-like-forerunners</link><description>Three new ICT-sector development projects involving Tk 46.33 billion have been proposed all of which are lookalikes of previous ones allegedly doomed to failure in set goals for corruption, misuse of public funds.
Officials at the Planning Commission hold such view about the projects designed by I</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 00:15:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No referendum provision in Bangladesh's Constitution , says Amir Khasru</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/no-referendum-provision-in-bangladeshs-constitution-says-amir-khasru</link><description>BNP Standing Committee Member Amir Khasru Mahmud Chowdhury said on Saturday that Bangladesh's current Constitution did not allow a national referendum.
"If a referendum is to be held, it can only be done after obtaining the people's mandate, coming to parliament, and passing it there," he commente</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 00:30:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Project preparation delays cost country a huge sum</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/project-preparation-delays-cost-country-a-huge-sum</link><description>World Bank's loan confirmation without project preparation creates a hiatus making Bangladesh pay interest and other fees before fund utilisation begins, officials say about the financial waste.
The mismatch has caused a financial gap of about US$1.5 billion between the active loans and the WB's</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 00:45:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AI holds huge promise, but BD must act fast</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/ai-holds-huge-promise-but-bd-must-act-fast</link><description>Amid growing fears of job losses and disruption, experts believe artificial intelligence (AI) could unlock vast new economic opportunities for Bangladesh if managed wisely.
While concerns persist over automation and its impact on employment, they argue that the country's focus should now shift tow</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 01:00:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Include anti-discrimination pledges in upcoming poll manifestos</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/include-anti-discrimination-pledges-in-upcoming-poll-manifestos</link><description>Economist Dr Debapriya Bhattacharya has urged all political parties to include firm anti-discrimination commitments in their forthcoming election manifestos and called for the enactment of a comprehensive anti-discrimination law.
"Without legal protection, fair justice, free and credible elections</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 01:15:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Internet banking transactions surge 47.5pc in Aug</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/internet-banking-transactions-surge-475pc-in-aug</link><description>Internet banking transactions in Bangladesh posted a robust growth of about 47.5 per cent year-on-year in August 2025, reaching Tk 1.12 trillion from Tk 759.39 billion in the same month of 2024, according to the latest data from the Bangladesh Bank (BB).
Although the August figure was slightly l</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 01:30:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UN chief urges faster shift to renewables to avoid climate disaster</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/un-chief-urges-faster-shift-to-renewables-to-avoid-climate-disaster</link><description>United Nations Secretary-General António Guterres has warned that the global energy landscape is changing at lightning speed, with renewable energy leading the way.
Speaking at the Energy Transition Roundtable during the Belém Climate Summit on November 7, he said last year 90 per</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 01:45:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>PROPOSED TELECOM LICENSING POLICY:  Stakeholders fear foreign dominance, rise in internet prices</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/proposed-telecom-licensing-policy-stakeholders-fear-foreign-dominance-rise-in-internet-prices</link><description>Speakers at a discussion on Saturday warned that the proposed telecom licensing policy could undermine domestic entrepreneurs, restore foreign dominance, and sharply raise internet prices.
They urged the government to review the draft guidelines, currently being prepared by the Bangladesh Teleco</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 02:00:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Experts push for discounted shares for general investors</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/experts-push-for-discounted-shares-for-general-investors</link><description>As the central bank moves forward with the merger of five troubled Islamic banks, general shareholders of these listed banks should either be offered shares of the merged entity or allowed to subscribe to its shares at a discounted price.
This view has been voiced by market experts as well as of</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 02:15:19 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>