<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 06:37:28 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Uncertainty in politics undermines economic rebound</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/uncertainty-in-politics-undermines-economic-rebound</link><description>A mixed economic picture comes clear in the yearbook 2025 with Bangladesh having witnessed its external accounts fairly strengthened while stubborn inflation, weak private investment and deep-rooted stress in banking continuing to weigh on growth prospects.
The year opened on a firmer footing exte</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 03:15:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CCC, army to jointly build int’l-standard hospital in Ctg</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ccc-army-to-jointly-build-intl-standard-hospital-in-ctg</link><description>Chattogram City Corporation (CCC) and the Bangladesh Army will jointly build an "international-standard" hospital in the port city, aiming to provide quality healthcare at affordable costs to the general public.
The announcement came on Tuesday at the seventh general meeting of the committee forme</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 03:30:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Market likely to rebound in 2026 with clouds clearing over politics, economy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/market-likely-to-rebound-in-2026-with-clouds-clearing-over-politics-economy</link><description>Bangladesh's capital market is expected to see a year of resurgence in 2026 from its current rock-bottom level, aided by political stability and macroeconomic recovery following the parliamentary election scheduled for February 12.
The year 2025 proved challenging for the country's capital market,</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 04:32:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Three die in Dhaka road accidents</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/three-die-in-dhaka-road-accidents</link><description>Three people have been killed in separate road accidents in Dhaka.
Two of them died when an autorickshaw and a motorcycle collided head-on near the Mouchak Flyover, while a policeman was killed when a covered van rammed his motorcycle on the Khilgaon Flyover, bdnews24.com reports.
The Mouchak acc</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 04:47:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Four killed as sand-laden truck overturns at Rajshahi village market</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/four-killed-as-sand-laden-truck-overturns-at-rajshahi-village-market</link><description>Four people were killed and another was injured when a sand-laden truck lost control and overturned at a village market in Puthia upazila of Rajshahi on Thursday morning.
The accident occurred at Jhalmalia Bazar while banana trading was underway. The identities of the victims could not be known im</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 04:02:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gold price falls by Tk 2,741 per bhori</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/gold-price-falls-by-tk-2741-per-bhori</link><description>Bangladesh Jewellers Association (BAJUS) has decided to further reduce the price of gold on the country's market.
This time, the price of 22-carat gold per bhori (11.664 grams) has been reduced by 2,741 taka, setting it at 224,182 taka, the organisation said. The new price will take effect from to</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 04:17:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>SHIPPING AGENTS' ASSOC POLLS: Appellate Division orders status quo</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/shipping-agents-assoc-polls-appellate-division-orders-status-quo</link><description>CHATTOGRAM Dec 31: The Appellate Division of the Supreme Court has ordered all parties to maintain the status quo over the Bangladesh Shipping Agents Association (BSAA) election for the 2025-27 term, following legal challenges over alleged violations of a High Court directive.
The order was issued</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 04:32:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tourists throng Cox's Bazar to mark new year's eve</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/tourists-throng-coxs-bazar-to-mark-new-years-eve</link><description>COX'S BAZAR, Dec 31: Hundreds of thousands of tourists have thronged Cox's Bazar to mark new year's eve, eager to witness the year's final sunset from the beach and welcome 2026.
Throughout December, the world's longest natural sea beach remained vibrant with visitors from across the country amid</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 04:47:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Thousands suffer on Manikganj's dilapidated road</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/thousands-suffer-on-manikganjs-dilapidated-road</link><description>MANIKGANJ, Dec 31: Thousands of local residents have been suffering immensely as a vital rural road in Singair Upazila of Manikganj is in poor condition.
Although over a year and a half has passed since the deadline to complete the road renovation project was over, works remain virtually inactive.</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 05:02:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>More condolences pour in for Khaleda Zia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/more-condolences-pour-in-for-khaleda-zia</link><description>Different organisations and individuals continued to express condolences over the death of former Premier Begum Khaleda Zia, who breathed her last on Tuesday and was buried with state honour on Wednesday.
They highlighted Begum Zia's lifelong struggle for sustaining the country's democracy and her</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 05:17:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>RU female student’s hanging body recovered from hostel</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/ru-female-students-hanging-body-recovered-from-hostel</link><description>Police recovered the hanging body of a female student of Rajshahi University (RU) from a student hostel in the Binodpur area of Rajshahi city on Wednesday afternoon.
The deceased was identified as Lamisa Nawrin Pushpita, a first-year student of the Department of Islamic History and Culture. She ha</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 05:32:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique thanks CA, all others for support during Khaleda’s janaza</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-thanks-ca-all-others-for-support-during-khaledas-janaza</link><description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman on Thursday expressed his heartfelt gratitude to the Chief Adviser and advisers of the interim government, members of the armed forces, law-enforcement agencies, government officials and media professionals for their role in ensuring a dignified and orderly farewe</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 05:47:52 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>