<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 13:47:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Yunus returns to Yunus Centre after 18 months</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/yunus-returns-to-yunus-centre-after-18-months-1</link><description>Muhammad Yunus has returned to the Yunus Centre after 18 months following his stint as chief advisor to the interim government.
In a Facebook post on Sunday, the Yunus Centre said he was received by long-time colleagues when he arrived at its office at Telecom Bhaban in Mirpur in the morning.
He</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 10:48:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ICT opens trial of 11 over Taim killing during July Uprising</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ict-opens-trial-of-11-over-taim-killing-during-july-uprising</link><description>The International Crimes Tribunal (ICT) has ordered the trial of 11 people on charges of crimes against humanity over the killing of Imam Hasan Taim, the son of a policeman, during the July 2024 mass uprising in Dhaka's Jatrabari.
The order was issued on Sunday by a three-member bench of ICT-2 hea</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 11:03:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pakistan says it has launched border strikes in Afghanistan. The Red Crescent reports 18 killed</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/pakistan-says-it-has-launched-border-strikes-in-afghanistan-the-red-crescent-reports-18-killed</link><description>Islamabad said it carried out strikes along the border with Afghanistan early Sunday, targeting what it called hideouts of Pakistani militants it blamed for recent attacks inside Pakistan. The Afghan Red Crescent Society said more than a dozen people were killed.
Pakistan didn't specify the locati</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 11:18:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Parliament sits Mar 12, speaker vote first order</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/parliament-to-convene-mar-12-with-speaker-deputy-speaker-elections-topping-agenda</link><description>The first session of the 13th Parliament will convene on Mar 12, when lawmakers will also elect the speaker and deputy speaker to formally set the legislative machinery in motion.
On Sunday, Home Minister Salahuddin Ahmed disclosed the date while at the Secretariat after a meeting chaired by Prime</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 11:33:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh Bank extends loan rescheduling deadline for raw jute exporters</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh-bank-extends-loan-rescheduling-deadline-for-raw-jute-exporters</link><description>Bangladesh Bank on Sunday extended the deadline for raw jute exporters to apply for loan rescheduling, aiming to support businesses facing liquidity challenges and help regularise defaulted loans.
According to a circular issued by the Banking Regulation and Policy Department (BRPD) of the central</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 11:48:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>By-polls to Bogura-6, polls to Sherpur-3 likely before Apr 14: EC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/by-polls-to-bogura-6-polls-to-sherpur-3-likely-before-apr-14-ec</link><description>Election Commissioner (EC) Abdur Rahmanel Machud on Sunday said by-elections to Bogura-6 constituency and polls to Sherpur-3 constituency are likely to be held before April 14 next.
He said the Commission is trying to take all preparations so that the by-elections and election could be held before</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 12:03:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India seeks stronger people-centric ties with Bangladesh: Envoy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/india-seeks-stronger-people-centric-ties-with-bangladesh-envoy</link><description>Indian High Commissioner to Bangladesh Pranay Verma on Sunday said they look forward to working together with Bangladesh in a forward-looking manner to strengthen people-centric cooperation in all domains.
"So, I think, of course, people-to-people exchanges are a very important part of our bilater</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 11:51:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No foreign force should harm Dhaka–Beijing ties: envoy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/chinese-ambassador-says-no-foreign-force-should-undermine-china-bangladesh-relations</link><description>China has warned that no external power should be allowed to damage its growing relationship with Bangladesh, as Beijing signalled strong support for the new government led by Prime Minister Tarique Rahman.
Speaking to reporters after a meeting with senior officials, the Chinese ambassador said Ch</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 12:06:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Habiganj BNP leader held for 'verbally abusing' police officer</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/habiganj-bnp-leader-in-custody-after-going-viral-for-insulting-police-officer</link><description>Police have detained a BNP leader in Habiganj after an audio clip surfaced where he was reportedly heard using abusive language toward a police officer.
Ferdous Chowdhury Tushar, president of the Bahubal Upazila unit of the BNP, was picked up from his residence around 12pm on Sunday, confirmed Hab</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 12:21:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CAB protests obstruction of consumer watchdog drive</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cab-protests-obstruction-of-consumer-watchdog-drive</link><description>The Consumers Association of Bangladesh (CAB) staged a human chain on Sunday to protest what it called the obstruction of a government market monitoring drive and demanded strict action against those responsible.
The demonstration took place in front of the Jatiya Press Club in the capital.
Speak</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 12:36:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Supreme Court limits Trump tariff powers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/tariff-ruling-limits-trumps-leverage-but-wont-end-uncertainty-for-trade-partners</link><description>The US Supreme Court's decision to strike down a large swath of President Donald Trump's tariffs has weakened his ability to threaten and impose tariffs at a moment's notice, but it won't end gnawing uncertainty for trade partners or companies.
Trump responded within hours to the ruling on Friday,</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 12:51:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump says he is sending a hospital ship to Greenland</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-says-he-is-sending-a-hospital-ship-to-greenland</link><description>US President Donald Trump on Saturday said he was working with Louisiana Governor Jeff Landry to send a hospital boat to Greenland, a Danish territory that Trump has said he wants to acquire.
Trump announced the plan on social media moments before hosting a dinner for Republican governors at the W</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 13:06:35 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>