<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 12:46:51 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Govt extends tenure of probe panel’s over attack on Nur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-extends-tenure-of-probe-panels-over-attack-on-nur</link><description>The government has extended the period of the panel, formed to investigate the attack on Gano Odhikar Parishad President and former DUCSU Vice President Nurul Haque Nur, by over one month.
According to a notification issued by the Cabinet Division on Tuesday, the tenure of the three-member investi</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 09:40:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Food flows into Gaza still far below targets, World Food Programme says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/food-flows-into-gaza-still-far-below-targets-world-food-programme-says</link><description>The UN World Food Programme said on Tuesday that supplies into Gaza were ramping up after the US-brokered ceasefire but were still far short of its daily target of 2,000 tonnes because only two crossings are open, and none to the famine-hit north of the enclave.
Around 750 metric tonnes of food ar</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 10:10:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dengue death toll crosses 250-mark</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dengue-death-toll-crosses-250-mark</link><description>Four more deaths were reported from dengue in 24 hours till Tuesday morning, raising the number of fatalities from the mosquito-borne disease in Bangladesh to 251 this year.
During the period, 814 more patients were hospitalised with viral fever, raising the total infected cases to 56,257 this yea</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 10:40:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamal Bhuyan becomes brand ambassador of EcoFlow</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/jamal-bhuyan-becomes-brand-ambassador-of-ecoflow</link><description>Global No. 1 portable power solution brand “EcoFlow” has officially commenced its journey in Bangladesh recently.
ACI Motors has signed an agreement with this leading technology company to become its exclusive distributor in the country. Industry insiders regard this partnership as a s</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 10:55:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Only one agreement under Indian LoC cancelled: Touhid Hossain</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/only-one-agreement-under-indian-loc-cancelled-touhid-hossain</link><description>Foreign Affairs Adviser Md Touhid Hossain on Tuesday affirmed that only one agreement under the Indian Line of Credit (LoC) with India was cancelled, disagreeing with his Cabinet colleague Adviser Asif Mahmud what he shared from his verified Facebook account.
Talking to reporters at the Ministry o</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 11:10:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>German delegation ends BD visit</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/german-delegation-ends-bd-visit</link><description>A delegation of leadership representatives from various areas in Germany, including government, private sector, civil society and academia, organised by the Bundesakademie für Sicherheitspolitik (BAKS, Federal Academy for Security Policy) ended their visit to Bangladesh on Tuesday.
The five-d</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 11:25:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt to upgrade Pabna Mental Hospital</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/govt-to-upgrade-pabna-mental-hospital</link><description>The government has approved a Tk 13.65 billion project to transform Pabna Mental Hospital into an international-standard mental health institute and hospital.
The approval came at an Executive Committee of the National Economic Council (ECNEC) meeting held on Tuesday, led by Chief Advisor and ECNE</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 11:40:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Probe report in Salman Shah murder case on Dec 7</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/probe-report-in-salman-shah-murder-case-on-dec-7</link><description>A Dhaka court on Tuesday set December 7 for submitting probe report in a case lodged against 11 over the murder of Bangla movie star Salman Shah in 1996.
Dhaka Metropolitan Magistrate Saifuzzaman passed the order, accepting first information report of the case.
Earlier in the day, Salman Shah&amp;rsq</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 11:55:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Banking sector faces capital shortfall of Tk 1.55 trillion</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/banking-sector-faces-capital-shortfall-of-tk-155-trillion</link><description>The financial health of Bangladesh’s banking sector has worsened sharply, with troubled banks facing a combined capital shortfall exceeding Tk 1.55 trillion in the June quarter.
This alarming figure marks a sharp increase from the Tk 1.1026 trillion (Tk 110,260 crore) deficit recorded in the</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 12:25:53 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>