<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 19:17:13 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>ESCAP and the next frontier of Asia-Pacific development</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/reviews/escap-and-the-next-frontier-of-asia-pacific-development</link><description>The United Nations Economic and Social Commission for Asia and the Pacific (ESCAP) is one of the five Regional Commissions under the jurisdiction of the UN Economic and Social Council. It was established in order to increase economic activity in Asia and the Far East, as well as to foster economic</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 16:25:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Butterfly fair more than an exhibition</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/butterfly-fair-more-than-an-exhibition</link><description>Most people view butterfly, a unique creation in the living world, as an aesthetic treat to the eye or a source of entertainment. But whoever could think of a butterfly fair instead of a show of the most decorated wingy creature! And that too an annual affair! 
Yes, the Jahanrirnagar Universi</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 15:45:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The headwinds export sector faces</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/the-headwinds-export-sector-faces</link><description>Bangladesh's export sector has of late been facing headwinds mainly from the dual impact of the fall in demand in the international market and the reciprocal tariff imposed by  the USA. According to the Export Promotion Bureau (EPB), last November Bangladesh exported merchandise worth US$3.89</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 16:00:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Intriguing case of decline in internet subscription</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/intriguing-case-of-decline-in-internet-subscription</link><description>The digital era, characterised by unprecedented connectivity, has reshaped communication, commerce, education and daily life. As more and more services go online, internet access is no longer a matter of convenience but a basic necessity. In fact, its importance is so widely recognised that the Uni</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 16:15:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AB Party’s Fuaad faces angry crowd in electoral constituency</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ab-partys-fuaad-faces-angry-crowd-in-electoral-constituency</link><description>Amar Bangladesh (AB) Party’s General Secretary Asaduzzaman Fuaad has faced public backlash during a visit to his electoral constituency in Babuganj.
Atikur Rahman Al Amin, convenor of the Babuganj Upazila unit of Jatiyatabadi Chhatra Dal, said the incident occurred on Sunday around 1pm, foll</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 16:30:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New OCs appointed to 12 Rajshahi city police stations</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/new-ocs-appointed-to-12-rajshahi-city-police-stations</link><description>New officers-in-charge (OCs) have been appointed to 12 police stations under the Rajshahi Metropolitan Police ahead of the parliamentary election.
The transfer came into effect on Sunday via an office order signed by RMP Commissioner Md Zillur Rahman.
The new station chiefs will take charge immed</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 16:45:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DCU: Students hold night sit-in</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/students-hold-night-protest-outside-shikkha-bhaban-over-dhaka-central-university-ordinance</link><description>Students demanding the issuance of the proposed Dhaka Central University ordinance have continued their sit-in outside the Directorate of Secondary and Higher Education building on Abdul Gani Road.
They continued their campaigning over the conversion of seven colleges into a university on Sunday n</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 17:00:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Remittance inflow exceeds $632 million in first six days of December</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/remittance-inflow-exceeds-632-million-in-first-six-days-of-december</link><description>The upward trend in remittances sent by expatriate Bangladeshis has continued into December, with the country receiving approximately US $632 million in the first six days of the month.
According to the latest update from Bangladesh Bank (BB), the $632 million remittance figure for December 1-6 is</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 17:15:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Air ambulance for Khaleda cleared to land on Tuesday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/air-ambulance-hired-for-khaleda-zias-london-trip-cleared-to-land-in-dhaka-on-tuesday</link><description>The air ambulance chartered to fly BNP Chairperson Khaleda Zia to London for medical treatment has received clearance to land in Dhaka on Tuesday morning.
A senior officer of the Civil Aviation Authority of Bangladesh (CAAB) confirmed on Sunday that Bangladesh had approved the request submitted on</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 17:30:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt allows onion import from India as prices surge</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/govt-allows-onion-import-from-india-as-prices-surge</link><description>The government has approved the import of 1,500 tonnes of onions from India to tame soaring prices in the local market.
The Department of Agricultural Extension (DAE), under the Ministry of Agriculture, cleared the imports on Sunday, local media report. 
A total of 50 import permits (IPs) ha</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 18:00:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Onion imports resume through Hili port</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/onion-imports-resume-through-hili-land-port-after-3-months</link><description>Onion imports from India have resumed through the Hili Land Port in Dinajpur after three months of suspension.
On the first day, 30 tonnes of onions, imported by a company named Rocky Traders, entered the Hili port.
An onion-laden truck from India entered the port at 4pm on Sunday.
Atik Hasan Ru</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 18:15:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bankers given until end of Dec to downsize bloated NPLs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bankers-given-until-end-of-dec-to-downsize-bloated-npls</link><description>Commercial banks in Bangladesh are now given a cutoff time until end of this month to significantly downsize mounting non-performing loans to clean up their year-end balance sheets.



Spelling out this direction at a meeting with bankers Sunday, the central bank high-ups suggested top executiv</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 18:30:45 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>