<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 07:20:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>CUCSU election a ‘rehearsal’ for national polls, VC says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/cucsu-election-a-rehearsal-for-national-polls-vc-says</link><description>Chittagong University Vice Chancellor Muhammad Yeahia Akhter has said the long-awaited CUCSU election will be a “rehearsal” for creating a “favourable” environment during the parliamentary elections in February.
“Voting has begun after completing all the preparations,</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 04:35:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pakistan reports new clash with Afghan forces along border</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/pakistan-reports-new-clash-with-afghan-forces-along-border</link><description>Clashes erupted Tuesday between Pakistani and Afghan forces in a remote northwestern border region, with state-run media in Pakistan accusing Afghan troops of opening “unprovoked fire” that was repulsed.
Pakistani forces responded, damaging Afghan tanks and military posts, according to</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 04:50:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>D'Angelo, trailblazing neo-soul singer, dies at 51, family says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/entertainment/dangelo-trailblazing-neo-soul-singer-dies-at-51-family-says</link><description>Grammy-winning R&amp;amp;B artist D’Angelo, a pioneer of neo-soul music, died at the age of 51 on Tuesday "after a prolonged and courageous battle with cancer," his family said in a statement.
"We are saddened that he can only leave dear memories with his family, but we are eternally grateful for th</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 05:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shibir, Chhatra Dal complain of outsiders entering campus during CUCSU election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/shibir-chhatra-dal-complain-of-outsiders-entering-campus-during-cucsu-election</link><description>After an hour and a half of voting in the Chittagong University Central Students' Union (CUCSU) elections, the Islami Chhatra Shibir and the Jatiyatabadi Chhatra Dal have complained about “outsiders” entering the campus.
Neither side, however, accused any specific student organisation</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 05:20:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>12 new offices introduced in NBR’s customs and VAT unit</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/12-new-offices-introduced-in-nbrs-customs-and-vat-unit</link><description>The National Board of Revenue (NBR) has been administratively reformed, restructured and expanded its Customs and VAT unit, creating 12 new commissionarates, Customs Houses and specialised units.
The Internal Resources Division (IRD) issued an order in this regard on Tuesday, the NBR said in a pre</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 05:35:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sri Lanka to issue domestic dollar bonds to boost foreign exchange liquidity</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/global/sri-lanka-to-issue-domestic-dollar-bonds-to-boost-foreign-exchange-liquidity</link><description>The Sri Lankan Cabinet of Ministers has approved a proposal to issue domestic dollar-denominated bonds as a debt instrument, a government spokesman said on Tuesday.
Cabinet spokesman Nalinda Jayatissa stated that the decision was made as foreign exchange inflows into the country have increased, th</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 05:50:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IMF, Pakistan reach staff-level deal on $1.2 billion payout</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/global/imf-pakistan-reach-staff-level-deal-on-12-billion-payout</link><description>The International Monetary Fund said on Tuesday it has reached a staff-level agreement with Pakistan on its loan programme, which would allow the country to access $1.2 billion after approval from the fund's board.
The IMF will provide Pakistan $1 billion under its Extended Fund Facility and $200</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 06:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Assad government secretly moved mass grave to cover up killings, Reuters investigation finds</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/africa/assad-government-secretly-moved-mass-grave-to-cover-up-killings-reuters-investigation-finds</link><description>The Assad government carried out a two-year clandestine operation to truck thousands of bodies from one of Syria’s largest known mass graves to a secret location more than an hour away in the remote desert, a Reuters investigation has found.
The conspiracy by President Bashar al-Assad’</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 06:35:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India to resume postal services to US from Oct 15</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/india-to-resume-postal-services-to-us-from-oct-15</link><description>India's postal department has announced the resumption of all postal services to the United States from October 15.
The federal ministry of communications on Tuesday said the postal department has established a compliant mechanism for Delivery Duty Paid processing after extensive system developmen</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 06:50:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BUET chemical expert team visits Mirpur fire site</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/buet-chemical-expert-team-visits-mirpur-fire-site</link><description>A chemical expert team of the Bangladesh University of Engineering and Technology (BUET) led by a BUET teacher Yeasir Arafat on Wednesday visited the fire site at Mirpur.  During the visit, they collected samples from the spot, media officer of the Fire Service and Civil Defence (FSCD) Ta</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 07:20:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>