<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 01:52:38 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Capitalism without wings: why capital markets matter</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/capitalism-without-wings-why-capital-markets-matter</link><description>Capitalism is often described as a system powered by private ownership, competitive markets, and the relentless search for profit. Beneath these familiar pillars lies a deeper engine that makes modern capitalism possible: the capital market, especially the stock market. It is where long-term saving</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 17:14:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>In memoriam of a warrior woman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/reviews/in-memoriam-of-a-warrior-woman</link><description>The curtain dropped on a different warrior four years ago. Freedom fighter, writer, and activist Begum Mushtari Shafi passed away at 84. While many knew her as ‘Shaheed Jaya’ (the wife of Shaheed), this title does not fully capture her lifelong efforts for upholding the spirit of Bangla</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 17:29:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Toxic ink on the plate</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/toxic-ink-on-the-plate</link><description>The scene is familiar to anyone living in or visiting Bangladesh. At street corners, outside schools, bus stands, and train terminals, vendors dish out puri, jhalmuri, fried crispy snacks and sweets packaged in newspaper sheets. Bakeries, confectionery shops, and roadside tea stalls also use newspa</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 17:44:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka's elevation as a megacity is no cause for celebration</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/dhakas-elevation-as-a-megacity-is-no-cause-for-celebration</link><description>Dhaka has emerged as the 2nd largest megacity in the world in terms of population. The United Nations World Urbanisation Prospects 2025 report finds Jakarta to secure the top position with 42 million people. Taking urban sprawl into consideration, the UN applies a new gauge to measure the world's m</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 17:59:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shahbagh blocked over Osman Hadi’s death</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/shahbagh-blocked-over-osman-hadis-death</link><description>Traffic came to a standstill at Shahbagh on Thursday night as leaders and activists of Inqilab Moncho, along with Dhaka University students, began gathering around 10:30 pm to mourn the death of Sharif Osman bin Hadi.
Osman Hadi, the fiery face of the July Uprising, convenor of Inqilab Moncho and</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 18:14:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh to mourn Hadi on Saturday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/yunus-declares-state-mourning-on-saturday-over-hadis-death</link><description>The interim government has declared state mourning on Saturday over Inqilab Moncho Convenor Sharif Osman bin Hadi’s death, who was shot in the head by assailants.
In a televised address to the nation on Thursday, Chief Advisor Muhammad Yunus said the state will bear all responsibilities for</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 18:29:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Do not act rashly: Yunus urges restraint after Osman Hadi’s death</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/do-not-act-rashly-yunus-urges-restraint-after-osman-hadis-death</link><description>Chief Advisor Muhammad Yunus has urged citizens to remain patient and exercise restraint following the death of Sharif Osman bin Hadi, convenor of the Inqilab Moncho.
He made the remarks in an address to the nation on Thursday night, shortly after news of Hadi’s death arrived from Singapore,</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 18:44:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Development projects for DSCC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/development-projects-for-dscc</link><description>The news that a substantial fund has been proposed for more than a dozen development projects under the Dhaka South City Corporation (DSCC) offers a rare moment of cautious optimism. For years, many wards under the DSCC have existed with minimal urban facilities, bearing the consequences of prolong</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 18:59:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Arson attack on Prothom Alo building in Karwan Bazar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/arson-attack-on-prothom-alo-building-in-karwan-bazar</link><description>An attack was carried out at the Prothom Alo newspaper office building in Karwan Bazar on Thursday after midnight, during which arson was reported, sources said.
At one stage of the incident, unruly people set fire to parts of the building, prompting an immediate response from the Fire Service and</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 19:14:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mob incited by Elias sets fire to Daily Star office in Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/mob-incited-by-elias-sets-fire-to-daily-star-office-in-dhaka</link><description>An unruly mob incited by ex-journalist Elias Hossain on Thursday attacked the office building of The Daily Star, Bangladesh’s leading English-language daily, and later set it on fire, creating panic in the area in the aftermath of the death of Sharigf Osman Hadi, a frontliner in the July Upri</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 21:17:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Daily Star journalists rescued after 4 hours</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/at-least-25-journalists-of-daily-star-rescued-after-more-than-4-hours</link><description>At least 25 journalists of The Daily Star have been rescued from their office more than four hours after a mob swooped on the newspaper office in Dhaka’s Kawran Bazar.
The angry crowd descended on the English-language daily's office around 12am on Friday.
The first attack came on Bengali-la</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 23:18:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh's second oil refinery in sight: Project ready with Tk 355b domestic financing</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladeshs-second-oil-refinery-in-sight-project-ready-with-tk-355b-domestic-financing</link><description>Bangladesh's second oil refinery is now in sight as a project with an estimated cost Tk 355 billion in domestic financing awaits ECNEC seal at its next meeting, officials say.



With this decisive initiative by the interim government a prolonged wait for nearly 17 years, after the feasibilit</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 01:20:34 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>