<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 18:32:17 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>JCD vows to confront conspiracies under Tarique Rahman’s leadership</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jcd-vows-to-confront-conspiracies-under-tarique-rahmans-leadership</link><description>Bangladesh Jatiyatabadi Chhatra Dal (JCD) President Rakibul Islam Rakib on Saturday said the organisation would firmly confront all ongoing conspiracies against the country under the leadership of BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman.
He made the remarks after paying tribute and offering prayers at</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 15:22:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ordinance toughens penalties for travel agency violations</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ordinance-toughens-penalties-for-travel-agency-violations</link><description>The government has promulgated an ordinance strengthening the regulatory framework for travel agencies, introducing up to one year’s imprisonment and fine up to TK 1.0 million for violations to ensure fair ticket pricing and protect passengers.
Issued by order of the President, the ordinance</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 15:43:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>131 candidates cleared for 15 Dhaka city constituencies</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/131-candidates-cleared-for-15-dhaka-city-constituencies</link><description>The scrutiny of nominations for the 15 constituencies in Dhaka city has found 131 candidates valid to contest in the parliamentary polls scheduled to be held on Feb 12.
The Election Commission has cancelled 62 nomination papers and suspended one.
The scrutiny was done at the returning officer&amp;rsq</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 15:58:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Salahuddin warns against exploiting religion for votes</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/salahuddin-warns-against-exploiting-religion-for-votes</link><description>BNP Standing Committee Member Salahuddin Ahmed has said that religion should neither be exploited for worldly gains, nor should people be misled with promises of heaven in exchange for votes.
“It is a major responsibility of Alem-Olama to take a clear stand against those who spread confusion</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 16:13:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP leader shot dead in Jashore in motorcycle drive-by attack</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-leader-shot-dead-in-jashore-in-motorcycle-drive-by-attack</link><description>Assailants have gunned down a BNP leader in Jashore Sadar Upazila, sending shockwaves through the local political community.
The incident occurred at around 6:50pm in Shankarpur on Saturday, outside the office of former municipal councillor Shahed Hossain Nayan, according to Inspector (Operations)</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 16:28:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mustafizur axe from IPL sparks controversy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/cricket/mustafizurs-kkr-release-draws-criticism-from-indian-congress-leader-world-cup-winner</link><description>The decision to drop Bangladesh fast bowler Mustafizur Rahman from the 2026 Indian Premier League (IPL) has drawn sharp criticism from former Indian state minister for external affairs and current Congress MP Shashi Tharoor
Tharoor questioned the Board of Control for Cricket in India’s (BCCI</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 16:46:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump ends Maduro’s heavy-handed rule in Venezuela</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/nicolas-maduros-heavy-handed-rule-in-venezuela-is-finally-ended-by-trump</link><description>Nicolas Maduro ruled Venezuela with a heavy hand for more than 12 years, presiding over deep economic and social crises and resisting pressure from domestic opponents and foreign governments for political change.
His rule abruptly ended on Saturday when President Donald Trump announced US forces h</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 17:01:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Latin America reacts after US capture of Maduro</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/condemnation-and-applause-in-latin-america-after-us-seizes-venezuelas-maduro</link><description>Former Chattogram North District BNP convenor Golam Akbar Khondakar has asserted that the recent wave of killings in Raozan stems from extortion, encroachment, and disputes over the sand trade rather than political rivalry.
Speaking after the scrutiny of nomination papers at the Chattogram deputy</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 17:16:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Raozan killings caused by crime, not politics: Golam Akbar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/killings-in-raozan-linked-to-extortion-and-sand-trade-not-politics-says-golam-akbar</link><description>Former Chattogram North District BNP convenor Golam Akbar Khondakar has asserted that the recent wave of killings in Raozan stems from extortion, encroachment, and disputes over the sand trade rather than political rivalry.
Speaking after the scrutiny of nomination papers at the Chattogram deputy</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 17:31:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh gets cautious as  global rice price spikes</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladesh-gets-cautious-as-global-rice-price-spikes</link><description>Global rice-price spike in recent months has nudged  major rice-consuming countries like Bangladesh into bracing with preparation to fend off any external shocks to food security.
According to the FAO Rice Price Update (January 2026), the FAO All Rice Price Index rose 4.3 per cent month on mo</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 18:02:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hindu-Buddhist-Christian Unity Council leaders meet Tarique, mourn Khaleda’s death</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hindu-buddhist-christian-unity-council-leaders-meet-tarique-mourn-khaledas-death</link><description>Leaders of the Bangladesh Hindu Buddhist Christian Unity Council met BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman on Saturday night and expressed condolences over the death of former Prime Minister and BNP Chairperson Begum Khaleda Zia.
The meeting was held at the BNP Chairperson’s Gulshan office, sai</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 18:17:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>About willful defaulters in amortising bank loan dues</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/about-willful-defaulters-in-amortising-bank-loan-dues</link><description>Subjecting willful loan defaulters to rigorous actions for loan recovery is fully justifiable from bankers' viewpoint. The central  bank   issued  a circular ( BRPD  circular no.:6 dated  12.03.2024) instructing all scheduled  banks   to  identify  willf</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 18:32:17 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>