<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 10:26:34 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Govt moves to repatriate fugitive police officers abroad</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-moves-to-repatriate-fugitive-police-officers-abroad</link><description>Home Adviser Lieutenant General (Retd) Md Jahangir Alam Chowdhury on Tuesday said the government is trying its best to bring back the fugitive police officers abroad after the 2024 July Uprising.
"We're trying our best to repatriate the police officers who went into hiding abroad," he said respond</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 07:14:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fakhrul asks BNP leaders left out of candidate list to stay loyal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/fakhrul-asks-bnp-leaders-left-out-of-candidate-list-to-stay-loyal</link><description>A day after announcing BNP's list of 237 potential candidates for the upcoming national election, BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir on Tuesday urged party leaders who were not nominated to have faith that the party will give them due responsibility and respect.
In a post on his ver</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 08:14:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh, Japan hold human resources seminar in Tokyo, 13 MoUs signed</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-japan-hold-human-resources-seminar-in-tokyo-13-mous-signed</link><description>A seminar on human resources between Bangladesh and Japan was held in Tokyo on Monday, where 13 memorandums of understanding (MoUs) and agreements were signed between Bangladeshi manpower sending agencies and Japanese recruitment firms.
Bangladesh Embassy in Tokyo arranged the seminar titled "A hi</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 08:29:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Revolutionary Workers Party slates RPO amendment 'without discussion'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/revolutionary-workers-party-slates-rpo-amendment-without-discussion</link><description>The Revolutionary Workers Party has voiced dissatisfaction over the amendment to the Representation of the People Order (RPO), arguing that changes to it were made without consulting political parties.
Conveying its stance to the media after a meeting with the chief election commissioner (CEC) on</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 08:59:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Türkiye delegation meets Foreign Adviser, pledges support for Rohingyas</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/turkiye-delegation-meets-foreign-adviser-pledges-support-for-rohingyas</link><description>Bangladesh and Turkiye have expressed their keenness in strengthening bilateral cooperation between the two countries in trade, investment and humanitarian areas especially for Rohingyas.
A five-member Turkish Parliamentary delegation, led by the Chairperson of Bangladesh-Turkiye Parliamentary Fri</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 09:29:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Weapons allegedly stolen from vault at Dhaka airport's burnt cargo complex</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/weapons-allegedly-stolen-from-vault-at-dhaka-airports-burnt-cargo-complex</link><description>Seven firearms have allegedly gone missing from the strongroom of the burnt cargo complex at Dhaka's Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport.
Biman Bangladesh filed a general diary (GD) with the Airport Police Station on Oct 28 over the theft of the weapons after a break-in at the vault, but no cas</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 09:44:14 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>