<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 10:27:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>India fences almost 80pc with Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/india-fences-almost-80pc-with-bangladesh</link><description>India has fenced almost 80 per cent of its border with Bangladesh, according to the Ministry of Home Affairs (MHA).
According to data provided by the Ministry of Home Affairs, India has physically fenced nearly 79 per cent of the length of the India-Bangladesh border, and over 93 per cent of the I</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 07:17:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique calls himself ‘half-Sylheti’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-calls-himself-half-sylheti</link><description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman has described himself as “half-Sylheti” while speaking at a discussion meeting on Great Victory Day at the City Pavilion in London.
“Many of you here are not just from Sylhet, but from other districts as well. Yet most of you are Sylhetis,&amp;rdquo</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 07:32:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC urges TV channels to avoid 'insults, personal attacks' in talk shows</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-urges-tv-channels-to-avoid-insults-personal-attacks-in-talk-shows</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has asked television channels to refrain from airing insults, derogatory remarks or personal attacks in talk shows and election-related discussions ahead of the 13th national election and referendum due in February next year.
In a letter sent on Wednesday to the secret</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 07:47:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fire breaks out at plastic warehouse in Lalbagh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fire-breaks-out-at-plastic-warehouse-in-lalbagh</link><description>A fire broke out at a plastic warehouse in the Islambagh area of Lalbagh in Old Dhaka on Wednesday afternoon.
Four units of the Fire Service rushed to the scene to control the blaze. Firefighting operations were underway at the time of reporting.
The cause of the fire could not be determined imme</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 08:02:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India summons Bangladesh high commissioner</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/india-summons-bangladesh-high-commissioner</link><description>Bangladesh’s high commissioner to New Delhi, M. Riaz Hamidullah, has been summoned by India’s Ministry of External Affairs.
He was called in at the ministry on Wednesday afternoon to issue a formal diplomatic protest over recent threats to the Indian High Commission in Dhaka and inflam</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 08:17:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tejgaon College students protest in Farmgate over death of peer Sakibul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tejgaon-college-students-protest-in-farmgate-over-death-of-peer-sakibul</link><description>Students of Dhaka’s Tejgaon College have launched a protest to demand the swift arrest of those accused in the death of Sakibul Hasan Rana, who died after being injured during a clash at a college hostel.
They have been staging a demonstration outside the college campus in Farmgate since ear</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 08:32:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Forged documents block Bangladesh’s overseas job prospects: Yunus</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/forged-documents-block-bangladeshs-overseas-job-prospects-yunus</link><description>Highlighting the importance of safer, fairer and skilled migration, Chief Adviser Prof Muhammad Yunus on Wednesday said the submission of fake documents has emerged as a major barrier to sending people abroad, despite the huge opportunities offered by destination countries for Bangladeshis.
&amp;ldquo</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 08:47:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fire breaks out at plastic warehouse in Old Dhaka's Islambagh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fire-breaks-out-at-plastic-warehouse-in-old-dhakas-islambagh</link><description>A fire has broken out at a plastic warehouse in Old Dhaka’s Islambagh.
The Fire Service said it received reports of the fire at Chairman Ghat around 1:30pm on Wednesday and initially sent six units to the scene. Three more units were later dispatched as firefighters worked to bring the fire</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 09:02:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pabna BNP leader shot dead</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/pabna-bnp-leader-shot-dead</link><description>A BNP leader has been shot dead in Ishwardi upazila of Pabna.
The incident took place around 10 am on Wednesday in the Kamalpur area of Lakshmikunda Union, said Ishwardi Police Station chief (OC) Md Mominuzzaman.
The victim, 65-year-old Biru Molla, was the convenor of the Lakshmikunda Union unit</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 09:18:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Walton's founding chairman SM Nazrul Islam’s 8th death anniversary today</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/waltons-founding-chairman-sm-nazrul-islams-8th-death-anniversary-today</link><description>Today marks the 8th death anniversary of SM Nazrul Islam, the founding chairman of Walton Group and a pioneer of Bangladesh’s electronics manufacturing industry.
On the occasion, Milad Mahfil and special prayers are being held on Wednesday at Walton’s headquarters, corporate office, se</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 09:33:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt to modernise fire safety, power systems at Bangladesh Secretariat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-to-modernise-fire-safety-power-systems-at-bangladesh-secretariat</link><description>Nearly a year after a devastating fire ripped through the Bangladesh Secretariat, destroying vital documents, the government has decided to undertake a major modernisation project to strengthen fire safety and ensure an uninterrupted power supply at the Secretariat and other key government installa</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 09:48:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DMP intensifies security check posts across Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dmp-intensifies-security-check-posts-across-dhaka</link><description>The Dhaka Metropolitan Police (DMP) has intensified its check post system at various key points across the capital to maintain law and order. 
The enhanced security measures came into effect from 4:00 pm today (Wednesday), BSS reports. 
"We have enhanced the security arrangement with se</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 10:03:37 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>