<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 12:51:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Tarique Rahman holds exchange of views with Dhaka-17 BNP leaders</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-rahman-holds-exchange-of-views-with-dhaka-17-bnp-leaders</link><description>Ahead of the upcoming 13th National Parliamentary Election, Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman held an exchange of views meeting with the leaders of the Dhaka-17 constituency.
The meeting took place on Tuesday at the BNP Chairperson's office in Gulshan.The meeting wa</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 09:44:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt okays procurement of 40,000 mt fertiliser from Saudi Arabia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/govt-okays-procurement-of-40000-mt-fertiliser-from-saudi-arabia</link><description>The government on Tuesday approved a proposal for procuring some 40,000 metric tonnes of bulk granular fertiliser from Saudi Arabia for the current fiscal year (FY26) to meet the growing demand.
The approval came from this year’s 1st meeting of the Advisers Council Committee on Government Pu</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 09:59:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No safety inspections at site of Swiss bar fire since 2019, mayor says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/no-safety-inspections-at-site-of-swiss-bar-fire-since-2019-mayor-says</link><description>No safety inspections were carried out since 2019 at the Swiss bar that burst into flames at New Year, killing 40 people, the mayor of the town of Crans-Montana said on Tuesday.
“We are profoundly sorry. We did not have an indication that the checks had not been done,” Crans-Montana Ma</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 10:14:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prime Bank signs Payroll Banking agreement with National Life Insurance</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/prime-bank-signs-payroll-banking-agreement-with-national-life-insurance</link><description>Prime Bank PLC has recently entered into a Payroll Banking agreement with National Life Insurance PLC, a trusted provider of multifarious life insurance solutions in Bangladesh, to offer comprehensive Payroll Banking services.
The signing ceremony took place at the bank’s corporate office in</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 10:29:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt okays import of lentil, edible oil to stabilise Ramadan market</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/govt-okays-import-of-lentil-edible-oil-to-stabilise-ramadan-market</link><description>The Advisers Council Committee on Government Purchase on Tuesday approved separate proposals to procure lentil and edible oil to help stabilise the market for essential commodities ahead of the Holy Month of Ramadan.
The decision came from a meeting the Advisers Council Committee on Government Pur</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 10:44:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Frustration as some students arrive too late to vote in JnUCSU election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/frustration-as-some-students-arrive-too-late-to-vote-in-jnucsu-election</link><description>Several students at Jagannath University have said they were unable to cast their ballots in the central students’ union election after polling closed on Tuesday afternoon.
Voting in the Jagannath University Central Students’ Union (JnUCSU) election began at 9 am on Tuesday at 178 boot</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 10:59:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ex-DNCC ward councillor Bappi ordered Hadi killing: DB chief</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ex-dncc-ward-councillor-bappi-ordered-hadi-killing-db-chief</link><description>Former Dhaka North City Corporation ward councillor and Jubo League leader Taizul Islam Chowdhury Bappi ordered the killing of Inqilab Moncho spokesperson Sharif Osman Hadi, said Detective Branch (DB) chief Mohammad Shafiqul Islam on Tuesday.
He revealed the information at a press briefing at the</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 11:14:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BB buys $223.50m through dollar auction</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bb-buys-22350m-through-dollar-auction</link><description>Bangladesh Bank (BB) on Tuesday purchased US$223.50 million from 14 commercial banks through multiple auction methods as part of its ongoing strategy to curb the depreciation of the US dollar against the taka and revitalise the remittance and export sectors.
According to central bank data, it boug</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 11:29:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Experts concerned over depletion of marine fisheries stocks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/experts-concerned-over-depletion-of-marine-fisheries-stocks</link><description>Bangladesh’s deep-sea ecosystem is under mounting pressure from overfishing, aggressive industrial practices and plastic pollution, according to new findings presented to the country’s chief adviser on Tuesday, prompting calls for urgent research-driven policy intervention.
The warning</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 11:44:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCP accuses EC officials of bias ahead of election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ncp-accuses-ec-officials-of-bias-ahead-of-election</link><description>National Citizen Party (NCP) on Tuesday warned that democracy is at risk, accusing senior government officials, including intelligence chiefs, of openly favoring a party ahead of the national election.
“We’ve seen various government officials and chiefs of different intelligence agenci</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 11:59:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC vows transparent, impartial conduct of polls: EC Sanaullah</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-vows-transparent-impartial-conduct-of-polls-ec-sanaullah</link><description>Election Commissioner Brigadier General (Retd.) Abul Fazal Md. Sanaullah on Tuesday said there is no concern regarding the upcoming national elections scheduled for February 12, assuring that the Election Commission (EC) will discharge its duties with transparency, impartiality and firmness.
He sa</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 12:14:51 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>