<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 06:02:49 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Dominage Steel rallies 120pc despite losses, factory shutdown</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/dominage-steel-rallies-120pc-despite-losses-factory-shutdown</link><description>Dominage Steel Building Systems has continued its unabated rally despite having a significantly negative P/E (price-to-earnings) ratio and one of its factory units being shut down.
The company's stock price jumped 120 per cent to Tk 36.70 a share between September 22 last year and February 24 this</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 02:40:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh loses top spot in global shipbreaking</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladesh-loses-top-spot-in-global-shipbreaking-as-imports-of-scrapped-vessels-drop-32pc</link><description>Bangladesh lost its position as the world's top shipbreaking destination in 2025 as imports of scrapped vessels declined by over 32 per cent amid regulatory pressures, economic challenges and stricter international standards.
According to data released by the NGO Shipbreaking Platform (NSP), Bangl</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 02:55:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Haor farmers fear crop loss as work misses deadline</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/haor-farmers-fear-crop-loss-as-work-misses-deadline</link><description>With about 700,000 haor farmers' livelihoods dependent on Boro paddy yield in the Sylhet division, slow progress in developing embankments for crop protection in Sunamganj, Habiganj and Sylhet districts has stirred worries of rain interruption, which would make the works slower. Rainfall will compl</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 03:10:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Garment exporters urge BB governor to release funds from export incentives</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/garment-exporters-urge-bb-governor-to-release-funds-from-export-incentives</link><description>Apparel manufacturers have requested the Bangladesh Bank (BB) governor to release funds from export incentives to facilitate the payment of employee salaries and bonuses ahead of Eid-ul-Fitr.
Leaders of the Bangladesh Garment Manufacturers and Exporters Association (BGMEA) made the request to Dr A</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 03:25:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt moves to revive ‘dead’ stretch of Buriganga through Ati Khal excavation plan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/govt-moves-to-revive-dead-stretch-of-buriganga-through-ati-khal-excavation-plan</link><description>The government has taken an initiative to recover and rejuvenate Ati Khal, a canal locally known as a “dead stretch” of the Buriganga River, in Keraniganj on the outskirts of Dhaka.
The move aims to restore drainage capacity, revive inland navigation and improve the local environment t</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 04:11:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCP calls BNP-linked city corporation administrator appointments ‘abuse of power’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ncp-calls-bnp-linked-city-corporation-administrator-appointments-abuse-of-power</link><description>The National Citizen Party (NCP) has described the appointment of BNP-backed administrators in six city corporations as “an abuse of power”, warning that the move could undermine a level playing field ahead of local government elections.
The party also questioned the government’s</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 04:26:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UK to enforce travel permit requirement on foreign visitors</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/uk-to-enforce-travel-permit-requirement-on-foreign-visitors</link><description>Starting on Wednesday, visitors to Britain from 85 countries must obtain an electronic permit in advance of their trip or they will be barred from travelling, the UK interior ministry said.
The Electronic Travel Authorisation (ETA) scheme requires all visitors who do not need a visa to enter Brita</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 04:12:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Agent banking network shrinks following Agrani Bank’s exit</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/agent-banking-network-shrinks-following-agrani-banks-exit</link><description>Bangladesh's agent banking network contracted in terms of agents and outlets in the October-December quarter of 2025, mainly due to the closure of all agent banking activities of Agrani Bank PLC.
However, deposits, loans and transaction values continued to record healthy growth, according to the l</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 04:27:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>S Arabia bans poultry and egg imports from Bangladesh, 39 other countries</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/saudi-arabia-bans-poultry-and-egg-imports-from-bangladesh-39-other-countries</link><description>Saudi Arabia has prohibited the import of poultry and table eggs from Bangladesh and 39 other countries as part of precautionary steps to safeguard public health and ensure food safety in its domestic market.
The Saudi Food and Drug Authority (SFDA) also applied partial restrictions on specific re</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 04:42:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nagad privatisation depends on new govt,  says BB governor</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/nagad-privatisation-depends-on-new-govt-says-bb-governor</link><description>Privatising Nagad, the provider of mobile financial services (MFS) under the postal department, largely depends on the decision and policy of the new government, Bangladesh Bank Governor Dr Ahsan H Mansur has told the local coordinator of potential overseas investors.
Once the policy is finalised,</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 04:57:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Verdict on ex-Jubo League leader Samrat’s graft case Wednesday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/verdict-on-ex-jubo-league-leader-samrats-graft-case-on-wednesday</link><description>A Dhaka court will deliver its verdict in a corruption case against ex-Jubo League leader Ismail Hossain Chowdhury Samrat over the illegal accumulation of wealth on Wednesday, February 25.
Dhaka Sixth Special Judge Zakaria Hossain will announce the verdict.
After hearing arguments, the case was s</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 05:12:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh committed to democratic principles, envoy tells British Parliament</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-committed-to-democratic-principles-envoy-tells-british-parliament</link><description>Bangladesh High Commissioner to the United Kingdom Abida Islam has described the recent national parliamentary election as a defining milestone in the country's democratic journey, reaffirming the government's commitment to democracy, rule of law and human rights.
Speaking at a panel discussion ti</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 05:27:51 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>