<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 05:28:37 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>DUCSU launches campaign to mobilise public support for 'Yes' vote</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ducsu-launches-campaign-to-mobilise-public-support-for-yes-vote</link><description>The Dhaka University Central Students' Union (DUCSU) has announced a month-long nationwide campaign to draw public support for a 'Yes' vote in the upcoming national referendum, describing it as a crucial step toward implementing reforms of the state structure.
The programme was unveiled at a press</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 01:32:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Move to put a cap on significant shareholding faces stiff opposition</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/move-to-put-a-cap-on-significant-shareholding-faces-stiff-opposition</link><description>A move to put a limit on shareholding in bank companies by individuals, family members, and entities is facing strong opposition from the stakeholders, officials say.
The central bank in a draft for amending the bank company act has proposed that individuals, family members, and entities directly</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 01:47:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DMP directs field-level officers to intensify intelligence gathering</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dmp-directs-field-level-officers-to-intensify-intelligence-gathering</link><description>The Dhaka Metropolitan Police (DMP) has directed field-level officers to step up intelligence gathering and take preventive measures against those suspected of trying to create disorder during the upcoming 13th national election and referendum "before any incident happens".
The directive was given</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 02:02:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>RUET congratulates its VC Abdur Razzak</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/ruet-congratulates-its-vc-abdur-razzak</link><description>The authority of Rajshahi University of Engineering and Technology (RUET) has extended heartfelt congratulations to Vice-Chancellor (VC) Professor Dr. S. M. Abdur Razzak on his appointment as the President of the Bangladesh University Council (BUC).
In a recent meeting of the BUC, an organisation</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 02:17:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mango farmers cheerful for early blossoms; but downbeat for cold</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/mango-farmers-cheerful-for-early-blossoms-but-downbeat-for-cold</link><description>Mango growers in Rajshahi are optimistic as early blossoms have begun appearing in orchards even before the end of winter, raising hopes for a good harvest this season.
However, persistent cold weather combined with dense fog has also triggered concern over possible disease outbreaks that could th</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 02:32:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Economic growth may slow to 4.6pc this FY</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/economic-growth-may-slow-to-46pc-this-fy</link><description>Bangladesh economy may expand at a rate of 4.6 per cent in the current fiscal year in a further 0.3-percentage-point fall from the level predicted in June 2025, says the World Bank in an update.
With this downgrading, the global development financier cut the country's economic-growth forecast for</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 02:47:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Q1 budget surplus jumps on revenue surge</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/q1-budget-surplus-jumps-on-revenue-surge</link><description>The government posted a sharply higher budget surplus for the first quarter of this fiscal year ending September last as revenue growth surpassed government spending during the period.
This is a rare fiscal breathing space to take actions to stimulate the growth momentum and fight the inflationary</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 03:45:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Merged banks' depositors to get no profit for 2024, 2025</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/merged-banks-depositors-to-get-no-profit-for-2024-2025</link><description>Depositors of five banks undergoing merger will not receive any profit on their deposits for 2024 and 2025, as the central bank has directed the banks to recalculate deposit balances under the approved resolution scheme.
The banks-First Security Islami Bank, Social Islami Bank, Union Bank, Global</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 04:00:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>After flood, Boro season unfolds in Sunamganj</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/after-flood-boro-season-unfolds-in-sunamganj</link><description>As the vast haor waters slowly recede, life in Sunamganj's low-lying wetlands is once again defined by urgency, mud and relentless labour by farmers.
Across the district, farmers have plunged into the Boro cultivation season, racing against a narrow planting window that will determine their liveli</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 04:15:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka's air quality remains ‘very unhealthy’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dhakas-air-quality-remains-very-unhealthy</link><description>Dhaka, the densely populated capital of Bangladesh, ranked first among the world's most polluted cities on Thursday morning, recording an Air Quality Index (AQI) of 271 at 9:13 am.
Today, the city's air was classified as 'very unhealthy', indicating a serious health threat, according to the AQI re</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 04:30:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump says Zelensky, not Putin, is holding up a Ukraine peace deal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-says-zelensky-not-putin-is-holding-up-a-ukraine-peace-deal</link><description>US President Donald Trump told Reuters that Ukraine - not Russia - is holding up a potential peace deal, a rhetoric that stands in marked contrast to that of European allies, who have consistently argued Moscow has little interest in ending its war in Ukraine.
In an exclusive interview in the Oval</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 04:45:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump questions Reza Pahlavi's ability to garner support in Iran</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-questions-reza-pahlavis-ability-to-garner-support-in-iran</link><description>US President Donald Trump said on Wednesday that Iranian opposition figure Reza Pahlavi "seems very nice" but expressed uncertainty over whether Pahlavi would be able to muster support within Iran to eventually take over.
In an exclusive Reuters interview in the Oval Office, Trump said there is a</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 05:00:54 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>