<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 16:24:58 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Ukraine secures US LNG imports from Greece to cover winter needs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/ukraine-secures-us-lng-imports-from-greece-to-cover-winter-needs</link><description>Ukraine has secured imports of US liquefied natural gas (LNG) from Greece to cover its winter needs from December through to March next year, Greek and Ukrainian officials said on Sunday during a visit to Athens by President Volodymyr Zelensky.
Ukraine will import gas via a pipeline that runs acro</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 13:17:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BAJF launches 25-day programme on its 25th anniversary</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bajf-launches-25-day-programme-on-its-25th-anniversary</link><description>The Bangladesh Agricultural Journalists’ Forum (BAJF) on Sunday announced a 25-day programme to mark its 25th anniversary, featuring a three-day international agriculture and food conference this month.
The announcement came at a press briefing on the day, held at the Cotton Development Boar</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 13:32:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Modhumoti Bank holds ‘AML &amp; CFT Conference 2025’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/modhumoti-bank-holds-aml-cft-conference-2025</link><description>Modhumoti Bank PLC. organized “Anti-Money Laundering and Combating the Financing of Terrorism Conference 2025” on Saturday at the International Conference Center, Police Staff College, Mirpur, Dhaka.
Mr. Md. Mofizur Rahman Khan Chowdhury, Executive Director &amp; Head (CC) of Bangladesh Fi</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 13:47:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Committee formation in MPO institutions suspended for 3 months</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/committee-formation-in-mpo-institutions-suspended-for-3-months</link><description>The Ministry of Education has suspended the formation of managing committees in MPO-listed educational institutions for three months.
The suspension was announced through a letter issued on Saturday, signed by Syed A. Z Morshed Ali, Deputy Secretary of the Secondary and Higher Education Division.</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 14:02:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mohammad Samir Uddin, CFA joins Midland Bank Asset Management Company as CEO</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/mohammad-samir-uddin-cfa-joins-midland-bank-asset-management-company-as-ceo</link><description>Mohammad Samir Uddin, CFA has joined as the Chief Executive Officer of Midland Bank Asset Management Company Limited (MDBAMC), a wholly owned subsidiary of Midland Bank PLC, according to a press release.
With over 14 years of professional experience in the Bangladesh capital market and banking sec</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 14:17:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nation on alert as ICT set to deliver verdict in Hasina’s case</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nation-on-alert-as-ict-set-to-deliver-verdict-in-hasinas-case</link><description>Security has been tightened across the country, particularly in and around the International Crimes Tribunal (ICT) in Dhaka, ahead of Monday’s verdict in a high-profile case of crimes against humanity.
The tribunal is set to deliver its judgement on cases against former Prime Minister Sheikh</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 14:32:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Islami Bank tops in deposits and remittances</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/islami-bank-tops-in-deposits-and-remittances</link><description>Islami Bank Bangladesh PLC has secured the top position in the banking sector by collecting new deposits of about Tk 18,000 crore this year, crossing the milestone of Tk 1,80,000 crore in deposits, according to a press release.
The bank achieved this success due to return of good governance and cu</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 14:47:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IFIC Bank hosts ‘Festival of Youth 2025’ in Barishal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ific-bank-hosts-festival-of-youth-2025-in-barishal</link><description>With the aim of providing the youth with basic knowledge of banking, cultivating a habit of saving and offering insights into financial management, IFIC Bank has organized a special workshop on financial literacy in Barishal under the guidance of Bangladesh Bank, as part of the "Festival of Youth 2</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 15:02:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Israeli forces open fire on UN peacekeepers in Lebanon, no injuries reported</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/israeli-forces-open-fire-on-un-peacekeepers-in-lebanon-no-injuries-reported</link><description>Israeli military forces opened fire on United Nations peacekeepers in southern Lebanon on Sunday, in an incident the UN peacekeeping mission described as a serious violation.
None of the UN forces were reported wounded.
Israeli soldiers had opened fire on two suspects in the El Hamames area near</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 15:17:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Global Islami Bank administrator holds meeting with Gulshan Corporate Branch customers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/global-islami-bank-administrator-holds-meeting-with-gulshan-corporate-branch-customers</link><description>Global Islami Bank Administrator Md. Moksuduzzaman visited Gulshan Corporate Branch today, Sunday, according to a press release.
During this time, he exchanged views with the customers on different issues. He informed everyone about the action plan taken by Bangladesh Bank to protect the interests</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 15:32:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BRAC Bank partners Mhadi Support Services to extend digital lending programme ‘Shafollo’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/brac-bank-partners-mhadi-support-services-to-extend-digital-lending-programme-shafollo</link><description>BRAC Bank has entered into a partnership with Mhadi Support Services Limited to extend digital lending facilities to the organisation’s support staffers through the bank’s digital lending platform, Shubidha App, according to a press release.
Through this initiative, BRAC Bank will enab</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 15:47:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New police commissioner for Gazipur Met Police; new SPs in 6 districts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/new-police-commissioner-for-gazipur-met-police-new-sps-in-6-districts</link><description>The government made some important new postings on the police, including a new commissioner for one of the largest and most critical police forces in the country - the Gazipur Metropolitan Police (GMP).
It also posted six new superintendents of police (SPs) in as many key districts across the coun</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 16:02:32 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>