<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 17:19:56 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Russia uses missile in Ukraine that led Trump to quit nuclear treaty, Kyiv says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/russia-uses-missile-in-ukraine-that-led-trump-to-quit-nuclear-treaty-kyiv-says</link><description>Russia has in recent months attacked Ukraine with a cruise missile whose secret development prompted Donald Trump to abandon a nuclear arms control pact with Moscow in his first term as U.S. president, Ukraine’s foreign minister said.
Andrii Sybiha’s comments are the first confirmation</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 15:14:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Woman ‘commits suicide’ under loan pressure in Demra</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/woman-commits-suicide-under-loan-pressure-in-demra</link><description>A 50-year-old woman allegedly took her own life in Demra, Dhaka, after facing pressure and humiliation from lenders, on Friday.
The incident occurred around noon on Friday at a rented house in Demra.
She was taken unconscious to Dhaka Medical College Hospital, where the duty doctor at the emergen</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 15:29:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US lawmakers want response after Sudan ‘horrors’ by paramilitaries</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-lawmakers-want-response-after-sudan-horrors-by-paramilitaries</link><description>Republican and Democratic US senators called for a strong response from President Donald Trump’s administration after the paramilitary Rapid Support Forces seized new territory in Sudan, reportedly attacking civilians.
Republican Senator Jim Risch of Idaho, chairman of the Senate Foreign Rel</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 15:59:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Three children drown, two missing in Jamalpur river</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/three-children-drown-two-missing-in-jamalpur-river</link><description>Three children have died and two others remain missing after they went bathing in the Jhinai River at Madarganj Upazila in Jamalpur.
The incident occurred on Friday afternoon, said Madarganj Police chief Md Saifullah Saif.
The dead were identified as Polly Akhter, 12, and her brother Abu Hasan, 8</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 15:26:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AL leader stabbed to death in Sylhet</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/al-leader-stabbed-to-death-in-sylhet</link><description>Police in Sylhet have recovered the bloodied body of Awami League leader Abdur Razzak from the staircase section of his house roof.
The incident occurred on Friday morning between 6:30 am and 9:00 am in Telirai village of Mollar Gaon Union, South Surma, according to Sylhet Metropolitan Police Depu</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 15:56:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Man killed over trivial matter in Mymensingh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/man-killed-over-trivial-matter-in-mymensingh</link><description>A 35 year-old man was stabbed to death allegedly by his rival over a trivial matter in Dhobaura upazila of Mymensingh district on Friday.
The victim was identified as Ershad Ali, son of late Hossen Ali of Paschim Sohagipara village under Dakshin Maizpara union of the upazila, reports UNB.
Police,</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 16:11:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Missing Sylhet farmer found dead in haor</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/missing-sylhet-farmer-found-dead-in-haor</link><description>The body of a missing farmer, Hanif Mia, was recovered from a haor in Sylhet’s Companyganj upazila one day after he went missing.
Hanif Mia, the son of Montaz Ali, was from Chanpur Keyaghat village of Purba Islampur Union. His body was retrieved from Rauti Beel at around 8:00 am on Friday, r</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 16:26:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Train communication on Dhaka-Mymensingh resumes after 4 hours</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/train-communication-on-dhaka-mymensingh-resumes-after-4-hours</link><description>The train communication between Dhaka and Mymensingh resumed after suspending it for four hours following derailment of Mohonganj express near Joydebpur junction at 2:00 pm Friday.
A rear compartment of Mymensingh bound Mohonganj express left from Dhaka derailed when it reached Joydebpur junction</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 16:41:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Vote to be held before Feb 15, says press secretary</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/vote-to-be-held-before-feb-15-says-press-secretary</link><description>Chief Adviser’s press secretary Shafiqul Alam has firmly said that the election will be held before February 15, regardless of any decision on the referendum issue.
“The Chief Adviser will decide on the referendum. Whatever the decision, there is no power to delay the election,”</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 16:56:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BIWTA electrician beaten to death in Jatrabari</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/biwta-electrician-beaten-to-death-in-jatrabari</link><description>A man working as an electrician for the Bangladesh Inland Water Transport Authority (BIWTA) was reportedly beaten to death in Dhaka’s Jatrabari area on suspicion of theft.
The deceased, Anwar Hossain Babu, 43, was taken to and attacked at a garage where bus repairs are conducted in the Counc</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 17:11:39 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>