<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 11:36:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Pentagon asked to probe SpaceX for potential Chinese ownership</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/pentagon-asked-to-probe-spacex-for-potential-chinese-ownership</link><description>Two Democratic US senators urged the Pentagon on Thursday to conduct an immediate review of SpaceX amid allegations that Chinese investors have secretly acquired stakes in the closely held rocket maker, citing potential national security risks, according to a letter seen by Reuters.
Senators Eliza</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 07:06:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gold price drops by Tk7,640 per bhori in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/gold-price-drops-by-tk7640-per-bhori-in-bangladesh</link><description>Gold prices in Bangladesh have been reduced by Tk7,640 per bhori on Friday, following a fresh price revision announced by the Bangladesh Jewellers Association (BAJUS).
The association explained that the decision was taken in view of an overall assessment of the market situation, particularly a fal</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 07:21:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tension near Jamuna as protesters demand 9th pay scale</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tension-near-jamuna-as-protesters-demand-9th-pay-scale</link><description>Tension flared up near Jamuna, the official residence of the Chief Adviser, on Friday as protesters staged demonstrations demanding the immediate implementation of the 9th national pay scale.
Mohammad Moniruzzaman, officer-in-charge (OC) of Shahbagh Police Station, said a protest procession of gov</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 08:22:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>JS polls, referendum preparations complete: Anwarul Islam</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/js-polls-referendum-preparations-complete-anwarul-islam</link><description>Election Commissioner Md Anwarul Islam Sarker has said that all preparations of the Election Commission (EC) for the 13th Jatiya Sangsad (JS) Elections and Referendum, scheduled for February 12, have been completed. 
"Now there is no preparation left except for the voters to go to the polling</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 07:51:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Police use batons, sound grenades on govt workers protesting in front of Jamuna</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/police-use-batons-sound-grenades-on-govt-workers-protesting-in-front-of-jamuna</link><description>Police have fired tear gas and sound grenades at government employees who were protesting in front of the State Guest House Jamuna, the official residence of the Chief Advisor, to demand the publication and implementation of the 9th pay scale gazette in light of the National Pay Commission’s</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 08:37:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Effigies of Adviser Sakhawat, BIDA’s Ashik, among others burnt at DU</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/effigies-of-adviser-sakhawat-bidas-ashik-among-others-burnt-at-du</link><description>Effigies of several individuals were burned at Dhaka University on Thursday in protest against the government’s move to lease the New Mooring Container Terminal (NCT) of Chattogram Port to foreign entities, branding them as 'economic hitmen'.
The demonstration was held in the afternoon at th</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 08:52:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mild cold wave grips four districts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/mild-cold-wave-grips-four-districts</link><description>A mild cold wave is sweeping over the Moulvibazar, Panchagarh, Rajshahi and Pabna districts, the Bangladesh Meteorological Department says.
Meteorologist Shahnaz Sultana told bdnews24.com on Friday afternoon that the cold wave may continue in the four districts on Saturday, with little temperature</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 09:52:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP declares 51-point manifesto to build ‘welfare-oriented, prosperous Bangladesh’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-declares-51-point-manifesto-to-build-welfare-oriented-prosperous-bangladesh</link><description>BNP chief Tarique Rahman is announcing the party’s 51-point election manifesto, prioritising nine issues with the promise of “building a welfare-oriented and prosperous Bangladesh”.
The party chairman presented the manifesto at the Pan Pacific Sonargaon Hotel in Dhaka on Friday a</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 09:56:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>JUCSU Vice President Jitu joins Chhatra Dal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jucsu-vice-president-jitu-joins-chhatra-dal</link><description>Abdur Rashid Jitu, vice president of the Jahangirnagar University Central Students Union, has joined the BNP. Alongside him, several other student representatives have also joined the BNP’s student affiliate, the Jatiotabadi Chhatra Dal.
They officially joined at an event at the BNP’s</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 10:11:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh, Japan sign historic EPA</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladesh-japan-sign-historic-epa</link><description>Bangladesh and Japan on Thursday signed a historic Economic Partnership Agreement (EPA), marking a major milestone in their bilateral ties and giving duty free access to 7,379 Bangladeshi products to the Japanese market.
This is the first time Bangladesh has signed an Economic Partnership Agreemen</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 10:26:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hazlewood injury adds to Australia’s T20 World Cup woes</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/hazlewood-injury-adds-to-australias-t20-world-cup-woes</link><description>Australia’s T20 World Cup campaign has suffered a severe blow just five days before their opening match, with pace bowler Josh Hazlewood officially ruled out of the tournament due to injury.
The news comes as a double blow for the 2021 champions, who had already lost Test and ODI captain Pat</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 10:41:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Vote manipulators to face consequences like fascists: Nahid</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/vote-manipulators-to-face-consequences-like-fascists-nahid</link><description>National Citizen Party (NCP) Convener Nahid Islam on Friday warned that anyone attempting to steal votes or commit election fraud will face consequences similar to those faced by fascists.
Speaking at an election rally in Savar for Dilshana Parul, the 11-party alliance candidate for Dhaka-19, Nahi</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 10:56:48 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>