<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 14:43:04 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>BRAC Bank hosts workshop on seamless trade and payment solutions for shipping agents in Chattogram</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/brac-bank-hosts-workshop-on-seamless-trade-and-payment-solutions-for-shipping-agents-in-chattogram</link><description>BRAC Bank, in collaboration with the Bangladesh Shipping Agents Association (BSAA), organised a workshop in Chattogram to promote seamless trade and payment solutions for the shipping industry.
Titled “Seamless Trade &amp; Payment Solutions: Regulatory Compliance and Central Bank Reporting for S</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 13:14:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>President of International Federation for Human Rights meets Prof Yunus</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/president-of-international-federation-for-human-rights-meets-prof-yunus</link><description>Alice Mogwe, President of the International Federation for Human Rights (FIDH), met with Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus on Monday at the Guest House Jamuna on Monday.
The two leaders held a wide-ranging discussion on the human rights situation in Bangladesh and across the globe, reports UN</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 13:29:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shahjalal Islami Bank’s 'Centralized Trade Services Division, Gulshan Hub, Dhaka' shifted to new address</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/shahjalal-islami-banks-centralized-trade-services-division-gulshan-hub-dhaka-shifted-to-new-address</link><description>In order to provide better services to the customers, Shahjalal Islami Bank PLC's "Centralized Trade Services Division (CTSD), Gulshan Hub, Dhaka" has started banking activities at a new address (Devotech Technology Park Limited, Holding No.-11, Road No.-113/A, Gulshan, Dhaka) from 5 October 2025 i</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 12:28:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Inflation rises to 8.36pc in September</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/inflation-surges-to-836pc-in-september-reversing-augusts-decline</link><description>After a dip in August, inflation rate has surged again, to 8.36 percent, in September.
The latest Bangladesh Bureau of Statistics (BBS) figures show a 0.07 percentage point rise in inflation, compared with 8.29 percent in August. In September last year, inflation stood at 9.92 percent.
The inflat</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 12:43:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt yet to appoint secretary to Public Administration Ministry</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-yet-to-appoint-secretary-to-public-administration-ministry</link><description>The post of Secretary at the Ministry of Public Administration has remained vacant for two weeks as the government delays the appointment of a new official due to various reasons, including political lobbying, the search for a qualified candidate, and concerns over avoiding controversy.
Sources at</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 13:13:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh, Saudi Arabia sign deal on manpower recruitment</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-saudi-arabia-sign-landmark-deal-on-manpower-recruitment</link><description>Bangladesh and Saudi Arabia today (Monday) signed a landmark agreement in Riyadh on the recruitment of general workers, the first of its kind between the two countries in their 50-year history of diplomatic relations.
Bangladesh Expatriates Welfare and Overseas Employment Adviser Dr. Asif Nazrul a</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 13:28:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bulbul, Fahim elected BCB directors</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/bulbul-fahim-elected-bcb-directors</link><description>Aminul Islam Bulbul and Nazmul Abedeen Fahim got elected to the board of directors’ election of the Bangladesh Cricket Board (BCB) held at the Pan Pacific Sonargaon Dhaka on Monday.
Bulbul and Fahim were elected from Dhaka Division in Category-1 (Districts and Divisions) after obtaining 15 v</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 13:58:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Death toll from Indonesian school collapse rises to 65, search continues</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/death-toll-from-indonesian-school-collapse-rises-to-65-search-continues</link><description>The death toll from the collapse of a school in Indonesia last week has climbed to 65, authorities said on Monday, while rescuers continued to search for survivors under the rubble, seven days after the disaster.
Concrete walls and floors caved in on hundreds of mostly teenage boys at the Al Khozi</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 14:13:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fertiliser factories seek tariff relief and gas supply to avert import dependence</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/fertiliser-factories-seek-tariff-relief-and-gas-supply-to-avert-import-dependence</link><description>Fertiliser production costs in state-run factories would be 32.60 per cent lower than the import costs if the gas price is doubled to Tk 30 per cubic meter and annual production reaches around 2.0 million tonnes, as the state-run Bangladesh Chemical Industries Corporation (BCIC) claimed Monday.</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 14:28:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BB buys another US$104mn to stabilise dollar market</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bb-buys-another-us104mn-to-stabilise-dollar-market</link><description>The Bangladesh Bank (BB) has purchased an additional US$104 million from commercial banks through an auction to maintain stability in the foreign exchange market, raising the country’s foreign exchange reserves to $26.62 billion.
The central bank bought the dollars at a rate of Tk 121.80 fro</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 14:43:04 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>