<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 18:33:58 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>ICC confirms it removes Bangladesh from T20 World Cup</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/cricket/icc-confirms-it-removes-bangladesh-from-t20-world-cup</link><description>The International Cricket Council (ICC) confirmed that Bangladesh have been removed from next month’s T20 World Cup after refusing to play their scheduled matches in India over security concerns, with Scotland called up as their replacement.
In a formal statement, the ICC said that, based on</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 15:00:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IGP orders police to be patient, neutral during election duties</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/igp-orders-police-to-be-patient-neutral-during-election-duties</link><description>Inspector General of Police (IGP) Baharul Alam on Saturday directed all police members to perform their duties with utmost vigilance, patience and neutrality during the upcoming 13th National Parliamentary Election.
He also instructed police personnel to ensure the use of body-worn cameras while o</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 15:15:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh, India reaffirm depth of ties; stress people-centred cooperation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-india-reaffirm-depth-of-ties-stress-people-centred-cooperation</link><description>Bangladesh and India used the occasion of the 77th anniversary of India’s Republic Day to publicly reaffirm the depth of their bilateral relationship, highlighting shared history, expanding energy and connectivity links, and the importance of addressing challenges through sustained dialogue.</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 15:30:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>One box for every 400 postal ballots: EC circular says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/one-box-for-every-400-postal-ballots-ec-circular-says</link><description>Election Commission (EC) has issued a special circular outlining the procedures to be followed after the receipt of the postal ballots by the Returning Officer (RO).
The circular contains detailed guideline on the preservation and counting of postal ballots of the forthcoming 13th national parliam</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 15:55:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Lions International allocates 300 development, humanitarian projects</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/lions-international-allocates-300-development-humanitarian-projects</link><description>Lions International has allocated over 300 development and humanitarian projects across Bangladesh, each valued at more than US$1.0 million, aimed at bolstering the country's socio-economic landscape.
The information was disclosed by Dr. Manoj Shah, Second International Vice President of Lions Int</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 16:10:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCP launches election theme song</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ncp-launches-election-theme-song</link><description>National Citizen Party (NCP) unveiled its election theme song at Shahbagh on Saturday, with party spokesperson Asif Mahmud Shojib Bhuyain leading the ceremony.
Speaking at the event, Asif Mahmud said, “We chose Shahbagh because it is where our political journey began and grew. That is why we</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 16:25:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shaping political socialisation in BD</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/shaping-political-socialisation-in-bd</link><description>Political preferences, loyalties, and behaviours do not emerge spontaneously in Bangladesh. They are cultivated over the years through subtle and persistent influence of social institutions and interpersonal relationships. This process, widely studied as political socialisation, encompasses how ind</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 16:40:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Growing visa restrictions: A wake-up call for Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/growing-visa-restrictions-a-wake-up-call-for-bangladesh</link><description>The United States has temporarily suspended immigrant visas for applicants from Bangladesh and 74 other countries. Effective from January 21, the restriction has been imposed citing concerns that a large number of immigrants from these countries rely on government benefits instead of entering the w</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 16:55:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Election time inflation in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/election-time-inflation-in-bangladesh</link><description>National elections critically influence economic growth and inflation across countries. Studies have examined patterns such as declining growth and rising inflation in election years. As Bangladesh prepares for the 13th parliamentary election on February 12, along with the referendum on the July Ch</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 17:10:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Stepping up banking reform efforts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/stepping-up-banking-reform-efforts</link><description>Bangladesh Bank has long been expected to act as a strong regulator without being given the legal space to do so. The latest move to amend the Bangladesh Bank Order and the Bank Company Act is an attempt to reverse that pattern by redefining who holds authority over banks and on what terms. Few now</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 17:25:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US-brokered peace talks break off without deal after overnight Russian bombardment of Ukraine</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-brokered-peace-talks-break-off-without-deal-after-overnight-russian-bombardment-of-ukraine</link><description>Ukraine and Russia ended a second day of U.S.-brokered talks in Abu Dhabi on Saturday without a deal but with future meetings mooted after overnight Russian airstrikes that knocked out power for over a million Ukrainians amid subzero winter cold.
Statements after the conclusion of the talks did no</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 17:40:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP leader shot in Keraniganj dies at DMCH</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-leader-shot-in-keraniganj-dies-at-dmch</link><description>A union-level BNP leader in Dhaka’s Keraniganj upazila, who was shot by miscreants on Thursday night, died at a hospital on Saturday afternoon.
Hasan Molla, general secretary of Hazratpur union BNP, succumbed to his injuries at around 4pm while undergoing treatment at Dhaka Medical College H</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 17:55:27 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>