<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 13:44:37 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Prime Bank partners with Wecon Properties Ltd to offer special benefits for home loan customers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/prime-bank-partners-with-wecon-properties-ltd-to-offer-special-benefits-for-home-loan-customers</link><description>Prime Bank PLC has recently signed a strategic partnership agreement with one of the country’s leading real estate companies, Wecon Properties Ltd. 
The agreement was formally signed at a ceremony held at the bank’s Head Office in Gulshan, according to a media release. 
Under thi</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 09:56:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump says considering limited strike on Iran</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-says-considering-limited-strike-on-iran</link><description>U.S. President Donald Trump said Friday that he is considering a limited military strike to pressure Iran to make a deal.
"I guess I can say I am considering that," Trump told reporters at the White House.
The Wall Street Journal reported Thursday that Trump is weighing "an initial limited milita</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 10:27:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>3 dead in helicopter crash in Russia's Amur Oblast</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/3-dead-in-helicopter-crash-in-russias-amur-oblast</link><description>All three people on board a helicopter that went missing on Thursday have been confirmed dead, the Ministry of Emergency Situations of Russia for the Amur Oblast said on Saturday.
The helicopter vanished from radar on Thursday evening after taking off from a logging site in the Romnensky municipal</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 10:42:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Child abuse’: Ex-Biman MD’s wife gives statement</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/former-biman-mds-wife-gives-statement-over-domestic-child-worker-abuse</link><description>The wife of former Biman Bangladesh Airlines managing director and chief executive officer Shafiqur Rahman has given a statement before a Dhaka court in a case over the alleged abuse of a minor domestic worker.
After completing seven days of remand, Bithi was produced before the court on Saturday</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 10:57:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt to give honorariums to khatibs, imams, muezzins before Eid</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-to-give-honorariums-to-khatibs-imams-muezzins-before-eid</link><description>The government will begin providing honorariums to khatibs, imams and muezzins in some areas before the upcoming Eid as part of implementing an election pledge.
The decision was taken at a meeting chaired by Prime Minister Tarique Rahman at the Prime Minister’s Office (PMO) on Saturday.
Tal</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 11:30:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CNG-truck collision leaves 5 dead in Kushtia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/cng-truck-collision-leaves-5-dead-in-kushtia</link><description>At least five people, including three women, were killed when a CNG-powered auto-rickshaw collided head-on with a gas cylinder-laden truck on the bypass road in Kushtia on Saturday afternoon.
The identities of the victims could not be immediately ascertained.
The accident occurred around 2:05 pm,</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 11:45:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chairman of Russian Federation congratulates Tarique</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/chairman-of-russian-federation-congratulates-tarique</link><description>The Chairman of the Government of the Russian Federation Mikhail Mishustin has congratulated Tarique Rahman upon his appointment to the post of the Prime Minister of the People’s Republic of Bangladesh.
The head of the Russian government expressed confidence that constructive joint efforts a</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 12:00:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>FA won’t take action against Man Utd owner Ratcliffe over immigration remarks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/fa-wont-take-action-against-man-utd-owner-ratcliffe-over-immigration-remarks</link><description>Manchester United owner Jim Ratcliffe will face no disciplinary action for saying Britain had been “colonised” by immigrants, the Football Association said on Saturday.
British billionaire Ratcliffe last week apologised for his choice of language but said it was important to raise the</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 12:01:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Banana trunks found inside guide wall construction in Madaripur!</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/banana-trunks-found-inside-guide-wall-construction-in-madaripur</link><description>A road construction project meant to improve connectivity in Madaripur has drawn sharp criticism after residents uncovered banana trunks placed inside the foundation of a guide wall.
The incident occurred at the Charkakair intersection in the Shiruail Union under a project by the Local Government</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 12:16:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Narsingdi retired teacher's tendons severed in land feud, mob torches attackers' home</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/narsingdi-retired-teachers-tendons-severed-in-land-feud-mob-torches-attackers-home</link><description>A retired schoolteacher has been critically injured after his leg tendons were allegedly severed in an attack over a land dispute in Narsingdi’s Shibpur Upazila. Angry residents, incited by rumours of his death, later vandalised and set fire to the accused neighbour’s house.
The incide</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 12:31:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique Rahman exchanges greetings with PMO officials</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-rahman-exchanges-greetings-with-pmo-officials</link><description>Prime Minister Tarique Rahman on Saturday exchanged greetings with the officials and employees of Prime Minister’s Office (PMO) at Tejgaon.
PM’s Additional Press Secretary Atiqur Rahman Rumon said, the Prime Minister exchanged greetings with the officials and employees and inquired abo</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 12:46:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ensuring media freedom my responsibility: Swapon</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/information-minister-swapon-pledges-to-guarantee-independent-media</link><description>Calling a free press essential for democracy, Information and Broadcasting Minister Zahir Uddin Swapon says he sees himself as a “guardian of the media”, responsible for ensuring journalists can work independently and without intimidation.
He made the remarks at a discussion marking th</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 13:01:29 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>