<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 11:21:57 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Zubaida to arrive in Dhaka as plans advance to fly Khaleda to London</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/zubaida-to-arrive-in-dhaka-as-plans-advance-to-fly-khaleda-to-london</link><description>Dr Zubaida Rahman, wife of BNP acting chairman Tarique Rahman, is set to arrive in Dhaka from London as preparations progress to take BNP Chairperson and former Prime Minister Khaleda Zia abroad for advanced treatment.
Senior BNP sources confirmed that Zubaida is expected to accompany Khaleda to L</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 09:30:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>RU suspends 3 teachers, punishes 5 students</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/ru-suspends-3-teachers-punishes-5-students</link><description>Rajshahi University (RU) authorities suspended three of its teachers and took disciplinary action against five students.
The decisions were taken at the 544th meeting of the RU syndicate, held on December 2, with Vice-Chancellor Prof Saleh Hassan Naqib presiding, BSS reports citing a RU press rele</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 10:00:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC to meet with president on Dec 10 ahead of schedule announcement</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-to-meet-with-president-on-dec-10-ahead-of-schedule-announcement</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) led by AMM Nasir Uddin is set to meet with the president on Dec 10 before announcing the schedule for the upcoming parliamentary election and the referendum.
Sharing the decision with bdnews24.com on Thursday, an election commissioner said: "The election schedule may b</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 10:15:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Merchandise export earnings in November decline by 5.54pc</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/merchandise-export-earnings-in-november-decline-by-554pc</link><description>The country’s merchandise export earnings in November 2025 declined by 5.54 per cent, mainly due to the poor performance of the readymade garment sector during the month.
Bangladesh earned US$3.89 billion in November 2025, down from US$4.11 billion in the same month of 2024, according to dat</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 09:31:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Referendum to lay foundation of ‘new Bangladesh’, CA tells SPs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/referendum-to-lay-foundation-of-new-bangladesh-ca-tells-sps</link><description>Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus has urged newly appointed Superintendents of Police (SPs) from 64 districts to view the upcoming national election as a historic responsibility and to work toward ensuring a credible, peaceful and inclusive vote.
Addressing the SPs at his Tejgaon office on Th</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 09:46:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP announces 36 more possible candidates for national election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-announces-36-more-possible-candidates-for-national-election</link><description>BNP on Thursday announced 36 more candidates, including four for Dhaka, to contest the upcoming national election.
BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir revealed the names of the candidates at the party Chairperson’s Gulshan office in the afternoon, UNB reports. 
“The</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 10:16:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh seeks ‘new canvas’ in relations with India, says High Commissioner Hamidullah</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-seeks-new-canvas-in-relations-with-india-says-high-commissioner-hamidullah</link><description>Bangladeshi High Commissioner to India Riaz Hamidullah says Dhaka is trying to “articulate a new canvas” regarding the relationship with its next-door neighbour, the Times of India reports.
"The effort is to articulate a new canvas where we can look at as a shared future,” he w</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 10:31:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>In JD Vance case, US Supreme Court may again chip away campaign finance limits</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/in-jd-vance-case-us-supreme-court-may-again-chip-away-campaign-finance-limits</link><description>The US Supreme Court for decades has chipped away at campaign finance laws, deciding they suppress political speech in violation of constitutional protections. A case involving US Vice President JD Vance being argued next week gives the court and its conservative majority a chance to amplify this t</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 10:46:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Did the US military commit a war crime in boat attack off Venezuela?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/did-the-us-military-commit-a-war-crime-in-boat-attack-off-venezuela</link><description>Members of Congress have said they will investigate whether the US military broke the law by allegedly killing two survivors of a strike on a suspected drug trafficking vessel in the Caribbean. The White House has defended the strike as lawful.
Below is a look at the potential legal violations in</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 11:01:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt set to implement Tk 40.62 billion project to strengthen reproductive health</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/govt-set-to-implement-tk-4062-billion-project-to-strengthen-reproductive-health</link><description>The government is set to strengthen reproductive health and family planning services across the country with the introduction of a major new initiative titled "Climate Responsive Reproductive Health and Population Services Improvement and System Strengthening Project for Result." 
The project</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 11:16:42 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>