<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 06:30:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nobel Prize in chemistry goes to discovery that could trap C02 and bring water to deserts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/nobel-prize-in-chemistry-goes-to-discovery-that-could-trap-c02-and-bring-water-to-deserts</link><description>Three scientists won the Nobel Prize in chemistry Wednesday for their development of new molecular structures that can trap vast quantities of gas inside, laying the groundwork to potentially suck greenhouse gases out of the atmosphere or harvest moisture from desert environments.
The chairperson</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 02:55:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Malaysia foreign minister heads to Myanmar for talks with junta on election, peace plan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/malaysia-foreign-minister-heads-to-myanmar-for-talks-with-junta-on-election-peace-plan</link><description>Malaysia's foreign minister will visit Myanmar on Thursday for talks with the ruling junta on its upcoming election and will push for progress on a stalled peace process, Malaysia's government said.
Mohamad Hasan will make a one-day visit to the capital Naypyitaw in Malaysia's capacity as chair of</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 03:10:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>China tightens rare earth export controls, targets defence, semiconductor users</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/china-tightens-rare-earth-export-controls-targets-defence-semiconductor-users</link><description>China tightened its rare earth export controls on Thursday, expanding restrictions on processing technology, barring unauthorised overseas cooperation and spelling out its intention to limit exports to overseas defence and semiconductor users.
The announcement from the Ministry of Commerce clarifi</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 03:25:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>France's Macron will appoint new prime minister in next 48 hours</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/frances-macron-will-appoint-new-prime-minister-in-next-48-hours</link><description>French President Emmanuel Macron will appoint a new prime minister in the next 48 hours, his office said on Wednesday, adding that a majority of lawmakers were against holding a snap parliamentary election amid France's worst crisis in decades.
Sebastien Lecornu, France's fifth prime minister in t</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 03:40:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>World leaders react to agreement on first phase of Trump's Gaza deal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/world-leaders-react-to-agreement-on-first-phase-of-trumps-gaza-deal</link><description>US President Donald Trump said on Wednesday that Israel and Hamas had reached a long-sought deal for a Gaza ceasefire and hostage release under his plan for ending the two-year-old war in the Palestinian enclave.
Following are reactions from leaders to the development:
BRITISH PRIME MINISTER KEIR</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 03:55:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EU climate agency reports world's third-warmest September</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/eu-climate-agency-reports-worlds-third-warmest-september</link><description>The world has just experienced its third warmest September on record, with land and sea surface temperatures remaining persistently high, the EU's climate monitoring network reported on Thursday.
The Copernicus Climate Change Service (C3S) said that the global average surface temperature in Septem</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 04:10:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khaleda offers prayers at Zia’s grave</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/khaleda-offers-prayers-at-zias-grave</link><description>BNP Chairperson Khaleda Zia on Wednesday night visited the grave of her late husband and BNP founder Ziaur Rahman at Sher-e-Bangla Nagar in the capital.
She went to Zia’s grave and offered prayers there around 11:00 pm, UNB reported citing BNP Media Cell member Sayrul Kabir Khan.
The BNP ch</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 04:25:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Light to moderate rain likely in parts of country</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/light-to-moderate-rain-likely-in-parts-of-country-146890</link><description>The Bangladesh Meteorological Department (BMD) forecast light to moderate rain or thundershowers accompanied by temporary gusty wind is likely to occur at many places across the country over the next 24 hours, beginning at 9:00 am today.
"Light to moderate rain or thunder showers accompanied by te</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 04:55:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ronaldo becomes football's first billionaire</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/ronaldo-becomes-footballs-first-billionaire</link><description>Cristiano Ronaldo has become the first footballer to reach billionaire status, according to the latest Bloomberg Billionaires Index, which has valued the Portugal great's net worth at an estimated $1.4 billion.
The 40-year-old striker's financial ascent comes after he signed a new contract with Sa</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 05:25:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bus passengers beat up 5 ‘Oggyan Party’ suspects in Dhaka’s FDC intersection</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bus-passengers-beat-up-5-oggyan-party-suspects-in-dhakas-fdc-intersection</link><description>Five suspected members of a gang called the “Oggyan Party” or “Malam Party” – known for robbing victims after rendering them unconscious - have been beaten up by bus passengers and handed over to police in Dhaka’s FDC intersection.
A passenger, identified as 45-</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 05:40:44 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>