<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 16:27:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>BRAC Bank wins Remittance Award from expatriates’ welfare ministry</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/brac-bank-wins-remittance-award-from-expatriates-welfare-ministry</link><description>The Ministry of Expatriates’ Welfare &amp; Overseas Employment has awarded BRAC Bank the prestigious Remittance Award for the second consecutive year.
According to a press release, this recognition from the government of Bangladesh demonstrates BRAC Bank's strong commitment to bolstering the eco</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 13:38:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Islami Bank holds meeting of board of directors</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/islami-bank-holds-meeting-of-board-of-directors</link><description>A meeting of the board of directors of Islami Bank Bangladesh PLC was held on Sunday at Islami Bank Tower, according to a press release.
Professor Dr. M. Zubaidur Rahman, chairman of the bank, presided over the meeting. Mohammad Khurshid Wahab, chairman of the executive committee, Md. Abdus Salam,</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 13:53:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Modhumoti Bank signs MoU with World Famous Tours and Travels</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/modhumoti-bank-signs-mou-with-world-famous-tours-and-travels</link><description>Modhumoti Bank PLC signed an MoU with World Famous Tours &amp; Travels (WFTT) on Tuesday at the Bank’s Head Office, Gulshan, Dhaka.
Mr. Arab Fazlur Rahman, Deputy Managing Director &amp; Chief Business Officer of Modhumoti Bank, and Mr. Shohan Mahmud, CEO and Founder of World Famous Tours &amp; Travels,</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 14:08:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>MTB distributes loans to participants of SICIP at Jashore</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/mtb-distributes-loans-to-participants-of-sicip-at-jashore</link><description>Mutual Trust Bank PLC (MTB) has distributed loan sanction letters to selected participants of the Skills for Industry Competitiveness and Innovation Program (SICIP) at the concluding ceremony of a month-long capacity-building workshop held in Jashore, according to a press release.
Nawshad Mustafa,</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 14:23:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh Polls: Nomination paper submission closes Monday; 99pc yet to file</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-polls-nomination-paper-submission-closes-monday-99pc-yet-to-file</link><description>With the deadline for submitting nomination papers for the upcoming national election falling on Monday, nearly 99 percent of aspirants who collected the forms have yet to file them as they are waiting for the last day.
“A total of 2,780 nomination papers were collected to contest the electi</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 14:38:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique signs nomination papers for Dhaka-17, Bogura-6 polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-signs-nomination-papers-for-dhaka-17-bogura-6-polls</link><description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman on Sunday signed his nomination papers to contest the 13th national parliamentary election from Dhaka-17 and Bogura-6 constituencies with the party’s electoral symbol, the Sheaf of Paddy.
Tarique signed the nomination papers in the evening at the BNP C</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 14:10:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NRB Global Convention 2025 to be held on Tuesday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nrb-global-convention-2025-to-be-held-on-tuesday</link><description>A day-long NRB Global Convention 2025 will be held on Tuesday to highlight the contributions of NRBs in various sectors, celebrate their impact on Bangladesh’s growth and strengthen ties between Bangladesh and its international partners.
Non-resident Bangladeshis (NRBs) from about 25 countri</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 14:25:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Many textile mills about to shut down due to faulty policy: BTMA</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/many-textile-mills-about-to-shut-down-due-to-faulty-policy-btma</link><description>The Bangladesh Textile Mills Association (BTMA) on Sunday warned that many textile mills are about to shut down due to faulty policy and economic meltdown.
The BTMA issued the warning from a press conference held at the Gulshan Club in Dhaka on Sunday. Speaking at the event, BTMA’s present a</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 14:40:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCP allied with Jamaat to cross electoral bridge: Nahid</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ncp-allied-with-jamaat-to-cross-electoral-bridge-nahid</link><description>National Citizen Party (NCP) Convenor Nahid Islam has formally announced an “electoral understanding” with Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami as the country approaches the parliamentary elections.
Speaking at a media briefing at their Bangla Motor office in Dhaka on Sunday night, Nahid said th</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 14:55:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khaelda files nomination for Dinajpur-3</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/former-pm-khaleda-zia-submits-nomination-papers-from-dinajpur-3</link><description>BNP Chairperson Khaleda Zia’s nomination papers have been submitted for the Dinajpur-3 constituency in the parliamentary polls.
Local BNP leaders and activists submitted the nomination papers on behalf of the former prime minister at 4pm on Sunday.
BNP’s central leader Syed Jahangir A</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 15:10:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Providing dependents’ income tax info in nomination form optional: EC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/providing-dependents-income-tax-info-in-nomination-form-optional-ec</link><description>Hours after a demand for clarification from BNP, the Election Commission on Sunday said providing the income tax information of an aspirant's spouse, children and dependents in the nomination form would be considered as optional.
The EC issued the clarification in a letter sent to 69 returning off</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 15:25:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>China welcomes Thailand-Cambodia truce ahead of trilateral talks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/china-welcomes-thailand-cambodia-truce-ahead-of-trilateral-talks</link><description>China on Sunday congratulated Cambodia on reaching a ceasefire with Thailand after weeks of deadly border fighting, as officials from the three countries prepared to open a two-day meeting in southwestern China.
Thailand and Cambodia on Saturday ended weeks of fierce border clashes that killed at</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 15:40:40 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>