<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 15:28:52 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>UK's Starmer says deployment of troops to Ukraine would be voted by parliament</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/uks-starmer-says-deployment-of-troops-to-ukraine-would-be-voted-by-parliament</link><description>British Prime Minister Keir Starmer said on Wednesday that any deployment of UK forces under a declaration signed with France and Ukraine would be subject to a parliamentary vote.
Starmer, French President Emmanuel Macron and Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelenskiy signed on Tuesday a declaration</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 12:45:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UNDP Bangladesh launches SDG Socialisers Season 2</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/undp-bangladesh-launches-sdg-socialisers-season-2</link><description>The United Nations Development Programme (UNDP) Bangladesh has launched Season 2 of SDG Socialisers, bringing together a new group of content creators who will use their creativity and influence to generate conversations and inspire action on the Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs).
The initiativ</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 13:00:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>'Profitable state-owned enterprises to be floated on capital market'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/profitable-state-owned-enterprises-to-be-floated-on-capital-market-finance-ministry</link><description>The government has agreed in principle to bring profitable state-owned enterprises, including multinational companies with government shareholding to the capital market, aiming to deepen the stock market and restore investor confidence.
Several profitable state-owned companies will be listed throu</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 13:15:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh Bank &amp; NCC Bank sign agreement to Implement BDT 5b Start-up refinance fund</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladesh-bank-ncc-bank-sign-agreement-to-implement-bdt-5b-start-up-refinance-fund</link><description>With the objective of expanding financing in the start-up sector, NCC Bank has signed a participating agreement with Bangladesh Bank.
Under this agreement, NCC Bank will be able to disburse loans to eligible start-up entrepreneurs using refinance funds received from Bangladesh Bank, according to a</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 13:30:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh’s overseas labour migration up 12pc in 2025: RMMRU</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladeshs-overseas-labour-migration-up-12pc-in-2025-rmmru</link><description>Overseas migration of Bangladeshi workers rose by 12 percent in 2025 compared to the previous year, reflecting a continued outbound labour trend amid domestic economic pressures, according to a report released on Wednesday by the Refugee and Migratory Movements Research Unit (RMMRU).
The report, t</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 13:45:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chinese ambassador meets Tarique Rahman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/chinese-ambassador-meets-tarique-rahman</link><description>Chinese Ambassador to Bangladesh Yao Wen on Wednesday held a courtesy meeting with BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman.
The ambassador handed over a bouquet to Tarique Rahman and conveyed his greetings during the meeting held at the BNP Chairperson's political office in Ghulshan this afternoon.
BN</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 14:00:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jashore district primary education officer held by ACC with Tk 120,000 bribe</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jashore-district-primary-education-officer-held-by-acc-with-tk-120000-bribe</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) on Wednesday arrested the District Primary Education Officer of Jashore, Md Ashraful Alam, red-handed while receiving a bribe of Tk 120,000.
The arrest followed a written complaint filed by Md Nurunnabi, alleging that the accused demanded bribes by unlawfully w</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 13:45:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CA describes DNA test of unclaimed bodies of July uprising major step toward justice</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ca-describes-dna-test-of-unclaimed-bodies-of-july-uprising-major-step-toward-justice</link><description>Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus today said that the initiative of collecting DNA samples to confirm identities of those, who were buried as unclaimed individuals during the July Uprising (2024), is a significant progress toward justice for families of those people.
“This effort to unc</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 14:00:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US seizing Venezuela-linked, Russian-flagged oil tanker after weeks-long pursuit</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-seizing-venezuela-linked-russian-flagged-oil-tanker-after-weeks-long-pursuit</link><description>The US was attempting on Wednesday to seize a Russian-flagged oil tanker being shadowed by a Russian submarine, after a more than two-week-long pursuit across the Atlantic as part of a US "blockade" of Venezuelan oil exports, two US officials told Reuters.
This appeared to be the first time in rec</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 14:15:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BRAC Bank introduces scholarship support for employees' children with disabilities</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/brac-bank-introduces-scholarship-support-for-employees-children-with-disabilities</link><description>BRAC Bank has introduced a scholarship programme to support the education of employees' children with disabilities, reinforcing its commitment to inclusion, dignity, and equal opportunity.
Under the scholarship programme, BRAC Bank will provide monthly financial assistance for each eligible child.</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 14:30:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CID arrests accused in Liza Akhter murder case after 17 months</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cid-arrests-accused-in-liza-akhter-murder-case-after-17-months</link><description>The Criminal Investigation Department (CID) has arrested an accused in the murder case of Liza Akhter, who was shot dead during the Anti-Discrimination Student Movement in the capital’s Shantinagar area.
The arrest was made after one year and five months of the incident. The arrestee is Maht</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 14:45:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>National election: 295 appeals filed against nomination decisions</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/national-election-295-appeals-filed-against-nomination-decisions</link><description>A total of 131 appeals have been filed with the Election Commission (EC) on the third day against the order of the Returning Officer to accept and cancel nomination papers in the upcoming 13th National Parliament election.
A total of 295 appeals have been filed till the last three days, EC officia</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 15:00:52 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>