<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 13:33:37 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Promoting ocean literacy in Bangladesh: No further vacillations should be entertained</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/promoting-ocean-literacy-in-bangladesh-no-further-vacillations-should-be-entertained</link><description>Humans depend on the ocean, whether we live near or far from it. But to what extent are citizens aware of the state of the oceans and their environmental, economic, political, medical and cultural importance?
The essence of ocean literacy is to know and understand the ocean’s influence on us</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 10:15:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CA seeks support from armed forces to hold peaceful, festive polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ca-seeks-support-from-armed-forces-to-hold-peaceful-festive-polls</link><description>Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus on Wednesday sought support from the armed forces, police and other law enforcement agencies to hold the upcoming national elections in a peaceful and festive manner in the first half of February next.
 “So now is the time for the election. We are</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 10:30:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamuna Bank organises financial literacy program</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/jamuna-bank-organises-financial-literacy-program</link><description>Recently, Jamuna Bank PLC organized Financial Literacy Program for the students Naohata Girls High School, a renowned educational institution under Paba Upazilla in Rajshahi district, as part of its Financial Literacy.
Executive Vice President &amp; Head of Banking Operation Division of Jamuna Bank PL</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 10:45:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DSE in talks with govt agencies to protect investors of merged banks: Chairman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/dse-in-talks-with-govt-agencies-to-protect-investors-of-merged-banks-chairman</link><description>The Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) is maintaining active communication with the Bangladesh Bank, the Ministry of Finance, the Financial Institutions Division and other government agencies to prevent losses for investors of the five recently merged Shariah-based banks, DSE Chairman Mominul Islam said on</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 11:00:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mercantile Bank holds AML Awareness Program</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/mercantile-bank-holds-aml-awareness-program</link><description>Mercantile Bank PLC organized Anti Money Laundering Awareness Program at its Head Office in the city today (November 19, 2025).
A. K. M. Golam Mahmud, Director of BFIU, spoke as the Chief Guest at the event, according to a media release. 
Chairman of Mercantile Bank’s Board of Director</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 11:15:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC seeks ordinance before setting referendum procedure</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-seeks-ordinance-before-setting-referendum-procedure</link><description>Although the interim government has announced that a referendum will be held on the day of the parliamentary election, the Election Commission (EC) says it must wait for an ordinance before determining its course of action.
Chief Election Commissioner (CEC) AMM Nasir Uddin made the remark on Wedne</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 11:30:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UNFPA welcomes preliminary MICS findings of BBS</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/unfpa-welcomes-preliminary-mics-findings-of-bbs</link><description>The United Nations Population Fund (UNFPA) has welcomed the release of the preliminary findings of the 2025 Multiple Indicator Cluster Survey (MICS), conducted by the Bangladesh Bureau of Statistics (BBS) with technical support from UNICEF.
The survey, which covers 172 indicators, including 27 lin</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 11:45:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Witnesses recount messages over Jobayed’s murder</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jobayeds-student-alerted-someone-killed-him-over-messenger-jnu-student-testifies</link><description>Two individuals have testified in the murder case of Jagannath University (JnU) student Jobayed Hossain: Saikat Hossain, a JnU student and junior to Jobayed on campus, and Wahidur Rahman, a physician at Salauddin Specialised Hospital and the uncle of Jobayed’s student.
On Wednesday, Saikat t</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 12:00:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Spain to investigate Meta, alleges Android privacy breaches</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/spain-to-investigate-meta-alleges-android-privacy-breaches</link><description>Spain's parliament will investigate Meta (META.O), opens new tab for possible privacy violations of its Facebook and Instagram users, Spanish Prime Minister Pedro Sanchez said on Wednesday.
"In Spain, the law is above any algorithm or any large technology platform. And anyone who violates ou</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 12:15:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCC Bank launches online “A-Chalan” service for customers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ncc-bank-launches-online-a-chalan-service-for-customers</link><description>NCC Bank has launched a new digital service, enabling customers to pay 206 types of government fees—including passport fees, income tax, VAT, customs duties, and surcharges—using the online A-Chalan platform, under its transaction banking and cash management.
From now on, customers can</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 12:30:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC lacks ability to enforce electoral code of conduct, says NCP</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ec-lacks-ability-to-enforce-electoral-code-of-conduct-says-ncp</link><description>The National Citizen Party (NCP) has expressed strong support for the Election Commission after the Representation of the People Order (RPO) was amended to require coalition candidates to contest under their own party symbols.
The party says the Commission must remain firm in its stance despite pr</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 12:45:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Three arrested with firearms and bullets in Ctg</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/three-arrested-with-firearms-and-bullets-in-ctg</link><description>Three individuals were arrested in Noapara for possession of weapons and ammunition. 
The arrests were made during a raid in the Chowdhuryhat area of Noapara union in Raozan upazila, BSS reports. 
Additional Superintendent of Police Md. Russell provided details of the operation at a pre</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 13:00:46 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>