<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 11:19:13 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Foreign operator of Pangaon terminal up with halved usage-cost plan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/foreign-operator-of-pangaon-terminal-up-with-halved-usage-cost-plan</link><description>Derelict-like Pangaon Inland Container Terminal (PICT) is poised for renascence as its Switzerland-based foreign operator formally begins operating the trade facility today with plans to halve the box-transportation costs.
Sources say the company, Medlog SA, comes up with this and ancillary offers</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 08:30:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>$1b Package For ERL Unit-2: IsDB technical mission likely in late January</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/1b-package-for-erl-unit-2-isdb-technical-mission-likely-in-late-january</link><description>The Islamic Development Bank (IsDB) is likely to send a technical mission to Bangladesh in late January as it may lend a record high of $1.0 billion for setting up an oil refinery, officials say.
The delegation aims to finalise the terms of the financing package for the long-delayed Eastern Refine</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 08:45:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mamunul Haque responds to EC show-cause over alleged code breach</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/mamunul-haque-responds-to-ec-show-cause-over-alleged-code-breach</link><description>Bangladesh Khelafat Majlis candidate Mamunul Haque has submitted a reply to a show-cause notice from the Election Commission (EC), rejecting allegations of violating the electoral code of conduct in the Dhaka-13 constituency.
He denied breaching the rules by distributing leaflets in favour of the</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 09:00:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Free, fearless media vital to Bangladesh democracy: Journalists</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/free-fearless-media-vital-to-bangladesh-democracy-journalists</link><description>Editors, journalists and media leaders from across the country on Saturday underscored the vital role of a free, independent, active and fearless media in sustaining democracy, warning that any attempt to silence media organisations ultimately threatens the rights of society as a whole.
“The</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 09:15:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Teknaf residents accuse armed group of planting landmines in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/teknaf-residents-accuse-armed-group-of-planting-landmines-in-bangladesh</link><description>Landmine explosions have become a grim reality along the Bangladesh-Rakhine border, leaving civilians wounded and heightening fears amid the ongoing civil war in Myanmar.
For the first time, however, a landmine blast inside Bangladesh severely injured a resident in Teknaf’s Whykong, causing</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 09:30:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Iran eyes 'permanent split' from global internet, say digital rights activists</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/iran-eyes-permanent-split-from-global-internet-say-digital-rights-activists</link><description>Iran has planned a “permanent break” from the global internet, allowing only individuals vetted by the regime to connect online, according to digital rights activists.
Bdnews24.com, citing The Guardian, reported that a confidential plan is underway to make international internet access</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 09:16:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique urges vigilance, says BNP shows restraint despite EC controversy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-urges-vigilance-says-bnp-shows-restraint-despite-ec-controversy</link><description>Urging all to remain vigilant against any attempts to obstruct the path of democratic transition, BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman on Saturday said his party still intends to show restraint despite what he described as the Election Commission's recent controversial roles and positions.
Speaking at a vi</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 09:31:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Taiwan says Chinese drone made 'provocative' flight over South China Sea island</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/taiwan-says-chinese-drone-made-provocative-flight-over-south-china-sea-island</link><description>A Chinese reconnaissance drone briefly flew over the Taiwan-controlled Pratas Islands at the top end of the South China Sea on Saturday, in what Taiwan's defence ministry called a "provocative and irresponsible" move.
Democratically governed Taiwan, which China claims as its own territory, reports</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 09:46:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>U-19 World Cup: Bangladesh-India captains avoid handshakes at toss</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/u-19-world-cup-bangladesh-india-captains-avoid-handshakes-at-toss</link><description>The diplomatic tension between Dhaka and New Delhi has spilled onto the cricket field, as the captains of the Bangladesh and India Under-19 teams refused to shake hands during the toss at the ICC U-19 World Cup on Saturday in Zimbabwe.
In a scene reminiscent of recent India-Pakistan encounters, Ba</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 10:01:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh reaffirms commitment to rules-based global order: Touhid</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-reaffirms-commitment-to-rules-based-global-order-touhid</link><description>Foreign Affairs Adviser Md Touhid Hossain, on Saturday, reaffirmed Bangladesh’s commitment to a rules-based international order and collective global action, emphasising dialogue and cooperation to address shared economic challenges.
“As a responsible neighbour and an active member of</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 10:16:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hindu Mohajote leader Gobinda regains candidacy in Gopalganj-3</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/hindu-mohajote-leader-gobinda-regains-candidacy-in-gopalganj-3</link><description>Gobinda Chandra Pramanik, secretary general of the Bangladesh Jatiya Hindu Mohajote, has had his nomination reinstated for the Gopalganj-3 constituency after filing an appeal with the Election Commission (EC).
On Friday, following a hearing on his appeal, the EC declared the independent candidate&amp;</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 10:31:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khamenei calls Trump criminal for causing casualties, damage, slander on Iranians</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/khamenei-calls-trump-criminal-for-causing-casualties-damage-slander-on-iranians</link><description>Iran's supreme leader Ali Khamenei said on Saturday that Iran considers US President Donald Trump a "criminal" for inflicting casualties, damage, and slander on the Iranian people during the protests.
"The latest anti-Iran sedition was different in that the US President personally became involved,</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 10:46:44 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>