<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 04:28:33 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Bond yields climb as banks hold back</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bond-yields-climb-as-banks-hold-back</link><description>Yields on two types of long-term treasury bonds rose sharply on Tuesday, as banks showed reluctance to invest their surplus funds in government securities in an effort to manage their portfolios more efficiently.
According to auction results, the cut-off yield, effectively the interest rate, on</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 01:27:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Marico posts record quarterly revenue on strong Parachute sales</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/marico-posts-record-quarterly-revenue-on-strong-parachute-sales</link><description>Marico has secured double-digit revenue growth year-on-year to Tk 5 billion in the second quarter through September this year, the highest quarterly revenue since its listing on the secondary market.
The growth, achieved in an adverse macroeconomic situation, was driven by the company's flagship</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 01:57:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Land sales boost Eastern Housing's Q1 profit by 27pc</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/land-sales-boost-eastern-housings-q1-profit-by-27pc</link><description>Eastern Housing declared a 27 per cent rise in profit to Tk 201.79 million for the first quarter through September of FY26 as revenue from land sales experienced a boost and finance income grew modestly.
The company witnessed higher growth in land sales compared to its apartment business in Q1 o</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 02:12:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Runner Automobiles returns to profit in FY25 on strong three-wheeler sales</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/runner-automobiles-returns-to-profit-in-fy25-on-strong-three-wheeler-sales</link><description>Runner Automobiles returned to profit in FY25, driven by robust sales growth, particularly in the three-wheeler segment, after enduring losses for two consecutive years.
The country's pioneering motorcycle manufacturer reported a consolidated profit of Tk 102 million in FY25 against a loss of Tk</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 02:27:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IPDC Finance profit jumps 74pc in Jan-Sept on higher investment income</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/ipdc-finance-profit-jumps-74pc-in-jan-sept-on-higher-investment-income</link><description>IPDC Finance showed a strong financial recovery in the first nine months of 2025, with profit soaring 73.8 per cent year-on-year to Tk 262 million.



The growth was driven by higher investment returns, steady lending income, and cost discipline amid economic headwinds, according to a press r</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 02:25:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt extends aromatic rice export deadline by one month</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/govt-extends-aromatic-rice-export-deadline-by-one-month</link><description>The government has extended the deadline for exporting aromatic rice to international markets by one month, sources said. The Ministry of Commerce (MoC) issued an order on Monday formalising the extension.



Earlier, the ministry had permitted the export of 18,150 tonnes of aromatic rice on</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 02:40:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Journey Outdoors becomes 50th company to invest in BEPZA Economic Zone</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/journey-outdoors-becomes-50th-company-to-invest-in-bepza-economic-zone</link><description>Journey Outdoors Bangladesh Co. Ltd., a company backed by investors from Singapore and China, has become the 50th company to sign a lease agreement with the Bangladesh Export Processing Zones Authority (BEPZA) in order to establish a high-end garment and outdoor products manufacturing industry in</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 02:55:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Focus on economic stability, spurring investment to sustain BD's growth</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/focus-on-economic-stability-spurring-investment-to-sustain-bds-growth</link><description>The two-day Economic Reform Summit 2025 has made a set of recommendations including ensuring macroeconomin stability, reviving investment and creating jobs.



For doing so, the summit stressed the need for overhaul of financial governance, trade policy, skills development and SME transformat</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 03:10:20 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>