<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 01:25:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Lalmonirhat at flood risk as Teesta flows above danger level</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/lalmonirhat-at-flood-risk-as-teesta-flows-above-danger-level</link><description>Relentless rainfall and upstream runoff have sent the waters of the Teesta River surging above the danger level, putting the low-lying areas on the left bank of the river, including Lalmonirhat, at risk of flooding.
Around 3pm on Sunday, the water flow recorded at Dalia Point of Teesta Barrage was</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 16:59:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique vows green, sustainable Bangladesh on World Habitat Day</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/tarique-vows-green-sustainable-bangladesh-on-world-habitat-day</link><description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman has pledged to build a greener and more sustainable Bangladesh, stressing the importance of protecting both the environment and planned urbanization.
In a post on his verified Facebook page marking World Habitat Day on Sunda, he said, “I pledge that BNP gov</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 17:14:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Misfiring Barcelona suffer 4-1 loss at Sevilla</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/misfiring-barcelona-suffer-4-1-loss-at-sevilla</link><description>Sevilla thrashed Barcelona 4-1 on Sunday, ending the champions' unbeaten start in LaLiga and denying them an opportunity to return to the top of the table.
Sevilla took the lead in the 13th minute, after Isaac Romero went down while jostling for the ball with Ronald Araujo near Barcelona's six-yar</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 16:39:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hundreds of trekkers on Tibetan side of Mount Everest rescued</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/hundreds-of-trekkers-on-tibetan-side-of-mount-everest-rescued</link><description>Hundreds of trekkers stranded by a blizzard near the eastern face of Mount Everest in Tibet had been guided to safety by rescuers, Chinese state media reported on Sunday, as unusually heavy precipitation including rain pummelled the Himalayas.
As of Sunday, 350 trekkers had reached the small towns</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 16:54:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump's Gaza plan: a Hobson's choice for Hamas?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/analysis/trumps-gaza-plan-a-hobsons-choice-for-hamas</link><description>The most crucial issues relate to withdrawal of IDF from Gaza, the surrender of arms by Hamas, establishment of ISF and agreement by all parties on a time-bound pathway to an independent state of Palestine. All these have to happen at the same time, in signed documents and on the ground in Gaza
&amp;n</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 17:09:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Grouping of climate conventions towards a holistic approach</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/grouping-of-climate-conventions-towards-a-holistic-approach</link><description>Analysts from different parts of the world have been monitoring very closely the impact of climate variability and the need for international governance of environmental challenges. Stacey Azores has used her participatory experience in UN climate negotiations and reflected on the various dimension</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 17:24:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fishing bans fail to arrest decline in hilsha population</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/fishing-bans-fail-to-arrest-decline-in-hilsha-population</link><description>The breeding season ban of 22 days on catching of hilsha has become effective from October 4 last. This yearly legal restriction was introduced in 2008 for 11 days covering a pre- and post-full-moon period. But a study found that hilsha is used to spawning during the new moon or dark moon too. This</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 17:39:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Urgency of diversifying country's exports</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/urgency-of-diversifying-countrys-exports</link><description>Following a formal request from the interim government, the UN is going to carry out an independent review of the state of the country's economy prior to its graduation from LDC status scheduled for November 2026.  The government's request came in response to the country's top business and tra</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 17:54:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Why no urgency to contain dengue?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/why-no-urgency-to-contain-dengue</link><description>Frequent spells of rainfall over the last couple of months have created ideal breeding conditions for mosquitoes. While all three genera of mosquitoes---aedes, anopheles and culex---have proliferated due to the favourable conditions, the most dreaded one is aedes that causes dengue and chikungunya.</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 18:09:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>World Bank to back $8.5b 'Blue Network' megaproject</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/world-bank-to-back-85b-blue-network-megaproject</link><description>The World Bank has agreed to lend US$600 million in the first go to support the interim government's flagship 'Blue Network Programme' that seeks to restore to life and protect all rivers, canals and drainage channels in and around Dhaka.
Officials say the initiative aims to create an integrated</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 18:24:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Saif, Saifuddin star in T20 sweep of Afghans</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/saif-and-saifuddin-propel-bangladesh-to-clean-sweep-of-afghanistan-t20-series</link><description>Bangladesh completed a 3-0 sweep of Afghanistan in the T20 series in a 6-wicket rout in the third game, with Saif Hassan blasting a swashbuckling 64* after Saifuddin returned a confining 3-15 in Sharjah.
Opting to bowl first on Sunday, Bangladesh bowlers never allowed Afghan batters to break free</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 20:37:52 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>