<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 01:56:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Doctors hold off removing bullet from injured Teknaf child’s head</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/doctors-at-dhaka-neurosciences-institute-say-9-year-old-huzaifas-head-bullet-cannot-be-removed-now</link><description>Doctors at the National Institute of Neurosciences in Dhaka have said they cannot yet remove the bullet lodged in the head of 9-year-old Huzaifa Afnan, who was shot near the Teknaf border.
Joint Director Badrul Alam told bdnews24.com on Wednesday night that Huzaifa’s condition has not deteri</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 16:04:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Drone manufacturing deal with China: ‘We will not jeopardise other relations’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/drone-manufacturing-deal-with-china-we-will-not-jeopardise-other-relations</link><description>Bangladesh will not take any step in defence procurement that could damage its relations with other countries, Foreign Advisor Touhid Hossain has said.
He made the remarks on Wednesday in response to queries over a Tk 6.08 billion agreement with the Chinese government to establish a military drone</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 16:19:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gold price hits record Tk 234,680 per bhori in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/gold-price-hits-record-tk-234680-per-bhori-in-bangladesh</link><description>Gold prices in Bangladesh have climbed to an all-time high, with the Bangladesh Jewellers Association (BAJUS) fixing the price of 22-carat gold (11.664 grams) at Tk 234,680 per bhori after raising it by Tk 2,625.
In a statement issued on Wednesday night (January 14, 2026), BAJUS said the new price</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 16:34:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>APBN seize 680g gold from Umrah trip leader at Dhaka airport</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/apbn-seize-680g-gold-from-umrah-trip-leader-at-dhaka-airport</link><description>Airport Armed Police Battalion (APBN) at Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport on Tuesday detained a man with 680 grams of gold, Tk 77,550, and foreign currency 16,125 Saudi riyals.
The suspect, identified as Gias Uddin, 46, was stopped around 11:15 am near Canopy Area 2 after his movements appea</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 16:49:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Finnish observers joining EU’s Election Observation Mission</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/finnish-observers-joining-eus-election-observation-mission</link><description>Bangladesh on Wednesday lauded Finland and the European Union for deploying a large EU Election Observation Mission (EOM) for the upcoming national elections
Bangladesh also sought sought Finland’s support for its post-LDC transition and GSP+ aspirations.
Non-resident Ambassador of Finland</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 17:04:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US to suspend visas for Bangladesh, 74 others</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/us-to-halt-visa-processing-for-bangladesh-pakistan-and-73-other-nations</link><description>The Trump administration is suspending all visa processing for applicants from 75 countries, including Bangladesh and Pakistan.
A US State Department spokesperson shared the development with Reuters on Wednesday.
The spokesperson did not elaborate on the plan, first reported by Fox News, which ci</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 17:19:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Seat-sharing: Islami Andolan cites ‘mistrust’ over Jamaat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/seat-sharing-rift-in-11-party-alliance-what-islami-andolan-says-over-mistrust-in-jamaats-role</link><description>The 11-party alliance led by Jamaat-e-Islami, formed to consolidate the Islamist vote into a "single box", has hit a deadlock over seat-sharing negotiations.
Despite consecutive days of meetings, a consensus remains elusive.
Jamaat had initially planned to hold a media briefing on Wednesday follo</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 17:34:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Contractionary monetary policy under critical scrutiny as inflation bites</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/contractionary-monetary-policy-under-critical-scrutiny-as-inflation-bites</link><description>Businesses feel unease and inflation frowns while some liquidity-squeezing moves have been in place for months.



The central bank, however, claims its contractionary monetary policy still looks accommodative in current context.
Officials and money-market analysts say the monetary policy is c</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 17:49:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Export potential of Bangladesh's handicraft sector</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/export-potential-of-bangladeshs-handicraft-sector</link><description>Export diversification remains a critical development objective for Bangladesh as the country seeks to reduce its heavy reliance on readymade garments (RMG). Within this context, the handicraft sector presents a viable alternative export avenue due to its strong backward linkages with rural employm</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 18:04:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>HC verdict on safe water: What next?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/hc-verdict-on-safe-water-what-next</link><description>The recent High Court verdict recognising access to safe drinking water free of cost as a fundamental right is a welcome and timely juridical intervention. By declaring that "access to safe drinking water free of charge is a fundamental right of every citizen as per Article 32 of the Constitution,"</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 18:19:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BPL in Jeopardy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bpl-in-jeopardy-players-threaten-total-strike-if-a-board-director-doesnt-step-down-by-thursday-1-pm</link><description>The crisis within Bangladesh cricket has reached a boiling point as the country’s cricketers have issued a stern ultimatum— if Bangladesh Cricket Board (BCB) Director M Nazmul Islam does not resign by 1:00 PM on Thursday, players will boycott all forms of cricket immediately.
The annou</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 18:34:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How RADP will impact development work</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/how-radp-will-impact-development-work</link><description>Downsizing the annual development programme (ADP) halfway in a fiscal year has been a routine practice in this country. This year is no exception to the rule. The original development budget of Tk 2.30 trillion in the current fiscal year has been pared down to Tk 2.0 trillion. Compared with the imm</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 18:49:40 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>