<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 05:38:28 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Entire world supports Bangladesh’s democratic transition: Mirza Fakhrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/entire-world-supports-bangladeshs-democratic-transition-mirza-fakhrul</link><description>BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir on Friday night said the whole world is supporting Bangladesh’s process of democratic transition through the next national election.“The entire world supports our democratic transition. Especially the democratic world is fully behind it,</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 04:06:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khagrachhari blockade withdrawn after days of unrest</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/khagrachhari-blockade-withdrawn-after-days-of-unrest</link><description>The Jumma Chhatra-Janata has called off a blockade that had been enforced for four days in Khagrachhari following unrest triggered by the alleged rape of a Marma teenager.
The decision was announced on Saturday in a statement issued by the group’s media cell.
According to the statement, the</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 04:21:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>George Clooney says Trump should create incentives, not tariffs, for movie industry</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/george-clooney-says-trump-should-create-incentives-not-tariffs-for-movie-industry</link><description>Movie star George Clooney said on Friday that US President Donald Trump's threat to impose a 100 per cent tariff on all films produced overseas was the wrong solution for a real issue.
Clooney spoke before the annual Albies awards ceremony in London, a program that he and his wife Amal created to</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 04:36:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BCB announces ODI squad for Afghanistan series</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/cricket/bcb-announces-odi-squad-for-afghanistan-series</link><description>The Bangladesh Cricket Board (BCB) has announced the squad for the upcoming three-match ODI series against Afghanistan to be held in Abu Dhabi later this month. The 16-member squad remains largely unchanged from the team that featured in the ODI series against Sri Lanka earlier this year, with</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 04:08:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scores of Bollywood AI videos vanish from YouTube after Reuters story</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/scores-of-bollywood-ai-videos-vanish-from-youtube-after-reuters-story</link><description>Hundreds of AI-generated Bollywood videos with 16 million views have been deleted from Google's YouTube after Reuters reported they were similar to those at the centre of a legal challenge filed by a celebrity couple to protect their rights.
Bollywood stars Abhishek Bachchan and his wife Aishwarya</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 04:23:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UK police say officers accidentally shot victim who died in synagogue attack</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/uk-police-say-officers-accidentally-shot-victim-who-died-in-synagogue-attack</link><description>British police said on Friday they accidentally shot a victim who died in the attack on a synagogue in Manchester, as well as one of the survivors, as they attempted to stop an attacker who appeared to be wearing an explosive belt.
In Thursday's attack two men, Adrian Daulby, 53, and Melvin Cravit</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 04:38:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prices of essentials jump in Khulna kitchen markets amid rains</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/prices-of-essentials-jump-in-khulna-kitchen-markets-amid-rains</link><description>Prices of daily essentials have increased unusually in Khulna kitchen markets due to a supply shortage and incessant rain, leaving low- and middle-income people struggling.
Visiting different city markets on Friday, it was found that vegetables are not available for less than Tk 60 per kg while th</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 04:53:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Former leader of banned BCL, two others held with Yaba in Savar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/former-leader-of-banned-bcl-two-others-held-with-yaba-in-savar</link><description>Police in a drive arrested three people including a former leader of the banned Bangladesh Chhatra League (BCL) along with 22 Yaba pills from Bhabanipur in Savar early Saturday.
The arrestees were Mazedul Islam alias Molla Hridoy, 27, former deputy social welfare affairs secretary of Savar Governm</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 05:08:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prices of essentials jump in Khulna kitchen markets amid rains</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/prices-of-essentials-jump-in-khulna-kitchen-markets-amid-rains-1</link><description>Prices of daily essentials have increased unusually in Khulna kitchen markets due to a supply shortage and incessant rain, leaving low- and middle-income people struggling.
Visiting different city markets on Friday, it was found that vegetables are not available for less than Tk 60 per kg while th</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 05:38:28 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>