<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 06:37:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Tarique shares feelings on his homecoming</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-shares-feelings-on-his-homecoming</link><description>Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman on Thursday shared his feelings in a Facebook post on how he was keen to return to his motherland-Bangladesh.
"After a long 6,314 days (I am) in the sky of Bangladesh!" he wrote these few works in his verified Facebook account, post</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 05:29:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>35pc drivers have high blood pressure, diabetes</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/35pc-drivers-have-high-blood-pressure-diabetes</link><description>Road safety continues to be a pressing issue in the country due to the poor state of drivers' health, with recent health camp data revealing that the majority of them have visual impairment, diabetes, and hypertension.
Dhaka Transport Coordination Authority (DTCA) collected the health data of ar</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 04:00:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>FE planning editor Kibria among 30 awarded Golden Silk Road BD Media Award</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fe-planning-editor-kibria-among-30-awarded-golden-silk-road-bd-media-award</link><description>Some 30 journalists from different print and electronic media outlets received the Golden Silk Road Bangladesh Media Award.
The award-giving ceremony took place at Shilpakala Academy in Dhaka on Wednesday evening. Chinese Ambassador to Bangladesh Yao Wen delivered the ceremonial address at the eve</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 04:15:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cox's Bazar bustling with massive tourist flow</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/coxs-bazar-bustling-with-massive-tourist-flow</link><description>COX'S BAZAR, Dec 24: Ahead of the upcoming Christmas on December 25 and the New Year's Eve celebrations, a massive influx of tourists has been witnessed in Cox's Bazar, home to the world's longest natural sea beach.
With the onset of winter, consecutive holidays and favourable weather conditions,</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 04:30:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Follow DAP, promote green buildings for safer Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/follow-dap-promote-green-buildings-for-safer-dhaka</link><description>Regulators on Wednesday urged the country's real estate developers to strictly comply with all relevant rules and regulations, particularly the latest Detailed Area Plan (DAP), to ensure better living conditions in the capital.
They also called for environment-friendly construction and adequate ro</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 04:45:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scheduled banks to remain open on Saturday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/scheduled-banks-to-remain-open-on-saturday</link><description>All scheduled banks across the country will remain open on Saturday following a directive from Bangladesh Bank (BB) to facilitate election-related financial transactions ahead of the 13th national parliamentary election.
In a circular issued on Wednesday to all banks, the central bank said the dec</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 05:00:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sarjis welcomes Tarique's return with call for unity</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/sarjis-welcomes-tariques-return-with-call-for-unity</link><description>NCP leader Sarjis Alam has welcomed Tarique's return to Bangladesh, saying he hopes political forces will work “together” to rebuild the country.In a Facebook post on Thursday, Sarjis said Tarique was returning at a critical juncture for Bangladesh's political landscape as the country g</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 05:15:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Red bus with ‘Bangladesh first’ slogan ready at Dhaka airport for Tarique</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/red-bus-with-bangladesh-first-slogan-ready-at-dhaka-airport-for-tarique</link><description>A red bus bearing the slogan ‘Bangladesh First’ has been kept ready in front of the VIP terminal of Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport ahead of BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman’s onward journey.
Party sources said Tarique Rahman will travel on the bus to the stage set up on</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 05:30:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman arrived in Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-rahman-lands-in-dhaka</link><description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman arrived at Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport in the city on Thursday morning at around 11:40 am.
Earlier, the Bangladesh Biman flight carrying Tarique Rahman from London landed him at Sylhet airport, then another landed him in Dhaka airport.
BNP leaders and</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 05:45:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Unforgettable event awaits in country's history, says Salahuddin</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/unforgettable-event-awaits-in-countrys-history-says-salahuddin</link><description>BNP Standing Committee member Salahuddin Ahmed has said an unforgettable event is going to take place in the country's 55-year history with the return of Tarique Rahman.
He said BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman's return to the country is a historic and outstanding moment in the Bangladesh's demo</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 06:00:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique to contest election from Bogura-6</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-to-contest-election-from-bogura-6</link><description>The BNP has announced that its Acting Chairman, Tarique, will contest the 13th national election from the Bogura-6 (Sadar) constituency, a seat previously held by his mother, former prime minister Khaleda Zia.
After returning to Bangladesh, Tarique is expected to complete voter registration, pavin</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 06:15:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique's schedule for the first three days back home</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tariques-schedule-for-the-first-three-days-back-home</link><description>Thursday
The flight carrying BNP leader Tarique Rahman landed at Dhaka's Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport at 11:11 am.
From the airport, he will travel to the 300 Feet Road in Purbachal, where a reception has been organised, reports bdnews24.com.
After the reception, he will go to Evercare</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 06:30:45 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>