<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 14:40:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Annual Business Conference 2026 of Midland Bank held</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/annual-business-conference-2026-of-midland-bank-held</link><description>Annual Business Conference 2026 of Branch, Sub-Branch, Agent Banking, Islami Banking, Retail Sales, Institutional Banking, SME, NRB, Cards and Treasury Business of Midland Bank PLC was held on 6th February 2026.
Independent Director of the Bank Mr. Riaz Ahmed Choudhury, attended the conference as</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 10:58:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP cancels final Dhaka election rally scheduled for Feb 8</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-cancels-final-dhaka-election-rally-scheduled-for-feb-8</link><description>BNP has cancelled its final election rally scheduled to be held in Dhaka on February 8 (on Sunday).
Instead of holding the rally, BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman will deliver election speeches at different locations across Dhaka North and South on February 8 and 9, BNP Senior Joint Secretary General R</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 11:13:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Inqilab Moncho activists clash with police</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/inqilab-moncho-activists-clash-with-police-while-marching-to-jamuna</link><description>Leaders and activists of Inqilab Moncho have clashed with police while attempting to march towards the official residence of the chief advisor to demand justice for the killing of Sharif Osman bin Hadi.
The confrontation took place on Friday afternoon when police stopped the march at the intersect</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 11:28:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Suicide bomber kills 31 in Shi’ite mosque in Pakistan’s capital, officials say</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/suicide-bomber-kills-31-in-shiite-mosque-in-pakistans-capital-officials-say</link><description>A suicide bomber killed at least 31 people and wounded almost 170 others during Friday prayers in a Shi’ite Muslim mosque in Pakistan’s capital Islamabad, police and government officials said.
Images from the site showed bloodied bodies lying on the carpeted mosque floor surrounded by</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 11:43:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No one to be allowed to loot banks, warns Jamaat Ameer</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/no-one-to-be-allowed-to-loot-banks-warns-jamaat-ameer</link><description>Jamaat-e-Islami Ameer Dr Shafiqur Rahman on Friday warned that no one would be allowed to loot banks in Bangladesh in the future if the 11-party alliance comes to power.
“Those who have stolen the country’s money and smuggled it abroad—if Allah Almighty gives us the opportunity t</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 11:58:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>TikTok hit with charges of breaching EU online content rules</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/tiktok-hit-with-charges-of-breaching-eu-online-content-rules</link><description>Social media app TikTok was charged by EU tech regulators on Friday with breaching EU online content rules through its addictive features and was told that it may have to change the design of its app or risk a fine of as much as 6 percent of owner ByteDance's global turnover.
The European Commissi</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 12:13:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Inqilab Moncho blocks Shahbagh after police clash</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/inqilab-moncho-activists-occupy-shahbagh-after-clashes-with-police-during-protest-march</link><description>Inqilab Moncho activists have blocked Dhaka’s Shahbagh intersection after clashing with police.
Around 5:15pm on Friday, they marched from the Raju Sculpture on the Dhaka University campus and staged a sit-in at the intersection.
Around 4pm, clashes erupted when the group set out towards th</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 12:28:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Six govt employees hurt in police action over ninth pay scale march</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/six-govt-employees-hurt-in-police-action-over-ninth-pay-scale-march</link><description>At least six government employees were injured on Friday when police attacked a march demanding the gazette of the ninth pay scale.
The incident occurred around 12:00 pm near Shahbagh Mor in the capital.
The injured were later taken to Dhaka Medical College Hospital emergency department around 12</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 12:43:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>1,490 recruited as 44th BCS appointments finalised</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/1490-recruited-as-44th-bcs-appointments-finalised</link><description>The public administration ministry has appointed 1,490 candidates to different cadres under the 44th Bangladesh Civil Service (BCS).
This recruitment comes seven months after the Public Service Commission (PSC) initially shared its recommendations.
The ministry’s new recruitment branch issu</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 12:58:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No firearms, bullets used to disperse gathering near Jamuna: DMP</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/no-firearms-bullets-used-to-disperse-gathering-near-jamuna-dmp</link><description>Dhaka Metropolitan Police (DMP) on Friday said no firearms or bullets were used to disperse an illegal gathering near the state guesthouse Jamuna, the official residence of the Chief Adviser and its surroundings.
“Despite a ban on meetings, processions, mass gatherings or demonstrations in t</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 13:28:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Security beefed up outside Prothom Alo, Daily Star</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/security-beefed-up-outside-prothom-alo-daily-star</link><description>Extra police personnel have been deployed outside the offices of two national dailies: Prothom Alo and The Daily Star, following clashes between police and Inqilab Moncho activists that triggered tension in Dhaka’s Shahbagh and Banglamotor.
Tejgaon Zone Assistant Commissioner of Police Akkas</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 13:43:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No guns fired on Inqilab Moncho protest: CAO</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/interim-government-says-no-guns-fired-at-inqilab-moncho-activists</link><description>The interim government has said law-enforcers did not fire any live rounds in their attempt to control the protests by Inqilab Moncho activists outside State Guest House Jamuna.
The Chief Advisor’s Office (CAO) made the claim in a statement issued on Thursday afternoon after clashes and seve</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 13:58:52 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>