<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 23:25:38 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>4 NCT workers transferred after strike at Ctg port</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/4-nct-workers-transferred-after-strike-at-ctg-port</link><description>Following a work stoppage at the Chittagong Port, four employees who led protests against the leasing of the New Mooring Container Terminal (NCT) to foreign operators have been transferred to the Pangaon Inland Container Terminal in Dhaka’s Keraniganj.
An office order on Saturday instructed</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 16:44:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique outlines industrial plans in Tangail</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bnp-chief-tarique-pledges-barrage-factories-and-revival-of-jute-industry-in-tangail</link><description>BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman has outlined plans for constructing a barrage on the Jamuna River, establishing juice processing plants, and setting up different factories, alongside initiatives to revive the jute industry in Tangail.
Speaking at the last rally of his three-day tour to the north on Sa</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 16:59:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pakistan thrash Australia by 90 runs to win T20 series after 7 years</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/cricket/pakistan-thrash-australia-by-90-runs-to-win-t20-series-after-7-years</link><description>Pakistan secured a historic T20I series triumph against Australia, defeating the hosts by 90 runs in the second match on Saturday.
This came as Pakistan’s first T20 series win against the Aussies in seven years, dating back to the Sarfaraz Ahmed-led victory in the UAE in October 2018.
The m</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 17:14:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>RAB recovers five looted grenades from Dhaka’s Demra</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rab-recovers-five-looted-grenades-from-dhakas-demra</link><description>Rapid Action Battalion (RAB) on early Saturday recovered five grenades, looted from a police station, from an abandoned location in the capital's Demra.
Acting on a tip-off, a team from RAB-10’s Jatrabari camp conducted an operation around 3:15am, said RAB-10 Assistant Director (Media) Tapas</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 17:29:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>2 arrested in Jhenaidah for allegedly selling madrasa student</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/2-arrested-in-jhenaidah-for-allegedly-selling-madrasa-student</link><description>Police arrested two people in Jhenaidah’s Harinakundu upazila on allegations of abducting a madrasa student and selling him to a hijra community in Bhola district.
The arrestees are Sumon, son of Shariful Islam of Mandartala village, and his wife Shyamoli Khatun.
According to police sources</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 17:44:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt cuts fuel prices by Tk 2 per litre for February</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/govt-cuts-fuel-prices-by-tk-2-per-litre-for-february</link><description>The government has announced a Tk 2 per litre reduction in the prices of diesel, octane, petrol, and kerosene for February 2026, aiming to provide fuel at a relatively affordable price to consumers.
Under the revised rates, diesel will now sell at Tk 100 per litre, down from Tk 102; octane at Tk 1</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 17:59:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sink or swim</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/sink-or-swim</link><description>Bangladesh has a troubled relationship with corruption. Since independence, it has been an enduring feature of public life-shaping institutions, distorting economic outcomes, and steadily eroding public trust. While corruption has long been widespread, systematic evidence from both domestic and int</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 18:14:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The changing global economic order</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/reviews/the-changing-global-economic-order</link><description>The global economic order is undergoing a massive long-term shift away from free trade towards a more fragmented or more precisely a patchwork structure. This new emerging global economic system is largely influenced by rising protectionism, geo-political tensions and structural risks.
The post WW</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 18:29:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The silent crisis of drug abuse</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/the-silent-crisis-of-drug-abuse</link><description>There has been little success in the drive against drugs, even in relative terms. By all indications, the menace is expanding, assuming newer forms and greater intensity with the influx of new substances. The findings of the latest nationwide survey conducted by Bangladesh Medical University (BMU)</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 18:44:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Lenders stare at Tk 6.46b loss after bank merger</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/lenders-stare-at-tk-646b-loss-after-bank-merger</link><description>At least five financial institutions risk losing assets following the recent bank merger, as shares held as collateral for loans they disbursed have been valued at zero.
IFIC Bank, Dutch-Bangla Bank, Shahjalal Islami Bank, Southeast Bank and National Housing Finance together face losses exceeding</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 18:59:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>GDP growth in  election years</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/gdp-growth-in-election-years</link><description>The current fiscal year is an election year, with polls scheduled for February 12. A key question is how the economy will respond to the election in terms of Gross Domestic Product (GDP) growth. As the economy has entered the Political Business Cycle (PBC), the impact of this cycle on growth needs</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 19:14:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Designing tax reform that works</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/designing-tax-reform-that-works</link><description>Tax policy in Bangladesh has long been driven by what is easiest to collect rather than what is fair or efficient. High trade taxes and transaction-based levies have filled revenue gaps left by weak income assessment and limited information. This has created a system where compliance is often more</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 19:29:25 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>