<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 14:42:59 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Israeli forces advance ahead of Trump-Netanyahu Gaza war talks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/israeli-forces-advance-ahead-of-trump-netanyahu-gaza-war-talks</link><description>Israeli tanks thrust closer to the heart of Gaza City on Monday in the hours before Donald Trump was due to host Benjamin Netanyahu at the White House, where the US president has promised "SOMETHING SPECIAL" in his latest bid to end the war.
After nearly two years of failed diplomacy, Washington p</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 12:36:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DSE rebounds as turnover rises; CSE also ends higher</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/dse-rebounds-as-turnover-rises-cse-also-ends-higher</link><description>The Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) bounced back on Monday after the previous session’s decline, with its key index, overall turnover and prices of most listed shares closing higher.
At the end of the day’s trading, the benchmark DSEX index gained 9 points.
The Shariah-based DSES and the b</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 11:32:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCP’s Masud apologises after controversial comments on Khagrachhari ‘rape’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ncps-masud-apologises-after-controversial-comments-on-khagrachhari-rape</link><description>Abdul Hannan Masud, senior joint chief coordinator of the National Citizen Party, has apologised for his comments regarding the alleged gang-rape of a Marma schoolgirl in Khagrachhari.
In a Facebook post on Monday, he admitted his mistake and expressed regret over his statement, acknowledging that</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 11:47:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trust Bank opens Gulshan North Branch</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/trust-bank-opens-gulshan-north-branch</link><description>Trust Bank PLC has inaugurated its new Gulshan North Branch at Doreen Tower, Gulshan-2, Dhaka, further expanding its network to provide modern and technology-driven banking solutions.
The branch was inaugurated by Major General Md. Hakimuzzaman, SGP, ndc, awfc, psc, Vice Chairman of the bank and A</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 12:17:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sonali Bank signs tri-party MoU on collection of court fees, charges</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/sonali-bank-signs-tri-party-mou-on-collection-of-court-fees-charges</link><description>Sonali Bank PLC signed a tri-party Memorandum of Understanding (MoU) along with the Law and Justice Division and the Bangladesh Supreme Court to collect all types of fees and charges, including court fees for submitting an e-bail bond through the Sonali Payment Gateway.
The MoU signing ceremony wa</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 12:32:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Early marriage, teenage pregnancy rampant among female RMG workers: Study</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/early-marriage-teenage-pregnancy-rampant-among-female-rmg-workers-study-reveals</link><description>Two out of every three female garment workers were married before reaching 18 years of age, and nearly 65 per cent of them had their first pregnancy before turning 18, said an icddr,b study on Monday.
Furthermore, about one-third of the participants reported at least one unintended pregnancy, whil</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 12:47:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>89th meeting of Shari’ah Supervisory Committee of Shahjalal Islami Bank held</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/89th-meeting-of-shariah-supervisory-committee-of-shahjalal-islami-bank-held</link><description>The 89th meeting of Shari'ah Supervisory Committee of Shahjalal Islami Bank PLC (SJIBPLC) was held on 24th September 2025 at the Board meeting room of Corporate Head Office of the bank, according to a press release.
The Chairman of Shari'ah Supervisory Committee of Shahjalal Islami Bank PLC Hazrat</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 13:02:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Inflow of remittances reaches $2.47 billion so far this month</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/inflow-of-remittances-reaches-247-billion-so-far-this-month</link><description>The inflow of remittances witnessed a significant year-on-year growth of 16.7 per cent through the first 28 days of September.
According to the latest data issued by the Bangladesh Bank (BB) on Monday, the total inflow of remittances reached $2.47 billion during this period.
This represents a not</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 13:32:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Modhumoti Bank holds workshop on prevention of trade-based, credit-backed money laundering</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/modhumoti-bank-holds-workshop-on-prevention-of-trade-based-credit-backed-money-laundering</link><description>Modhumoti Bank PLC successfully organised a workshop on “Prevention of Trade-Based Money Laundering (TBML) &amp; Credit-Backed Money Laundering (CBML)” on Saturday at the bank’s Learning &amp; Development Centre (Explore) in Pragati Sarani.
The event was graced by the presence of Mr. Md.</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 13:47:51 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>