<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 10:25:56 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>South Africa beat India by 408 runs to sweep series</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/south-africa-beat-india-by-408-runs-to-sweep-series</link><description>South Africa beat India by 408 runs in the second test in Guwahati to complete a 2-0 series sweep on Wednesday.
Chasing an improbable target of 549, India were all out for 140 on the final day of the contest.
Ravindra Jadeja (54) topped the score for the hosts, who once again struggled against th</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 07:41:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Low pressure over Southwest Bay of Bengal intensifies into well-marked low</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/low-pressure-over-southwest-bay-of-bengal-intensifies-into-well-marked-low</link><description>The low-pressure area over the southwest Bay of Bengal and adjoining Sri Lanka coast intensified into a well-marked low over the same area at 6:00 am on Wednesday, according to the Bangladesh Meteorological Department (BMD).
It is likely to move north-northwesterly direction and intensify further,</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 07:56:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Vast trove of medieval Jewish records opened up by AI</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/vast-trove-of-medieval-jewish-records-opened-up-by-ai</link><description>Researchers in Israel are hoping to make new discoveries about Jewish history by loading a digital database of manuscripts stretching back a thousand years into a new transcription tool that uses artificial intelligence.
The Cairo Geniza, the biggest collection of medieval Jewish documents in the</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 08:11:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Navy College student shines in Notun Kuri-2025</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/others/navy-college-student-shines-in-notun-kuri-2025</link><description>Navy College’s seventh-grade student Somriddhi Suchona Swarg has secured the second position in the ‘Kha’ category of the storytelling segment in the final round of BTv-organised Notun Kuri-2025, the country’s largest talent hunt competition for children and teenagers.
The</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 08:26:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Classified loans reach all-time high at Tk 6.44 trillion in September</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/classified-loans-reach-all-time-high-at-tk-644-trillion-in-september</link><description>The classified loans in the country’s banking sector hit an all-time high at Tk 6.44 trillion in September 2025, accounting for 35.73 per cent of the entire loans worth Tk 18.04 trillion disbursed by all scheduled banks.
The volume of non-performing loans (NPLs) rose to Tk 6.44 trillion as o</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 08:41:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt appoints SPs for 64 districts through lottery</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-appoints-sps-for-64-districts-through-lottery</link><description>The interim government today issued an order regarding the appointments of Superintendents of Police (SPs) for all 64 districts
The appointment was finalized through a lottery system ahead of the upcoming 13th national parliament elections on Monday at the residence of the Chief Adviser, Jamuna, r</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 08:56:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gravity Shift: Is Google's new 'Antigravity' IDE 'Cursor-killer'?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/gravity-shift-is-googles-new-antigravity-ide-cursor-killer</link><description>If you've spent any time on "Tech Twitter" over the last six months, you know the drill: Cursor is the vibe-coding king. The AI-native editor has eaten VS Code's lunch, becoming the go-to for everyone from indie hackers to enterprise architects. We've settled comfortably into the era of 'Vibe Codin</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 09:11:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tk 10b loan granted to ICB to revitalise stock market</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/tk-10b-loan-granted-to-icb-to-revitalise-stock-market</link><description>The government has provided a loan of Tk 10 billion to the Investment Corporation of Bangladesh (ICB), a state-owned investment institution, to overcome its liquidity crisis and increase its investment capacity in the stock market.
ICB Chairman Abu Ahmed told bdnews24.com on Wednesday that the loa</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 09:12:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Backtracking on Airbus purchases will impact Bangladesh’s trade relations with Europe’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/backtracking-on-airbus-purchases-will-impact-bangladeshs-trade-relations-with-europe-says-german-ambassador</link><description>Germany’s Ambassador to Bangladesh Rüdiger Lotz has warned that Dhaka’s trade relations with Europe could be strained if it rows back on its commitment to purchase aircraft from Airbus.
He also hinted that the Airbus decision could impact the EU’s decision on allowing Bangla</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 09:27:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rizvi slams Hasina over reported gold recovery from bank vaults</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/rizvi-slams-hasina-over-reported-gold-recovery-from-bank-vaults</link><description>BNP Senior Joint Secretary General Ruhul Kabir Rizvi on Wednesday criticised deposed Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina, saying the reported recovery of a large quantity of gold ornaments from bank vaults registered under her name exposed how big a ‘thief’ she was.
“I saw in the newspa</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 09:42:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Wahiduddin for coordinated efforts for livestock sector growth</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/wahiduddin-for-coordinated-efforts-for-livestock-sector-growth</link><description>Planning Adviser Wahiduddin Mahmud today (Wednesday) underscored the need for technical support and coordinated initiatives to accelerate the development of the country’s livestock sector.
Speaking at the opening of the National Livestock Week 2025 as the chief guest, he said that researcher</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 09:57:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BGMEA expresses deep shock over fire at Korail slum</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bgmea-expresses-deep-shock-over-fire-at-korail-slum</link><description>The Bangladesh Garment Manufacturers and Exporters Association (BGMEA) has expressed deep shock over the fire incident at the Korail slum in the capital, which destroyed numerous homes and left many families homeless.
The BGMEA conveyed heartfelt sympathy to all the affected families and wished a</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 10:12:37 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>