<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 17:04:17 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Russia fully blocks WhatsApp, talks up state-backed alternative</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/russia-fully-blocks-whatsapp-talks-up-state-backed-alternative</link><description>US messenger app WhatsApp, owned by Meta Platforms, has been completely blocked in Russia for failing to comply with local law, the Kremlin said on Thursday, suggesting Russians turn to a state-backed “national messenger” instead.
“Due to Meta’s unwillingness to comply with</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 14:11:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>North Korea’s Kim positioning daughter as successor</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/north-koreas-kim-positioning-daughter-as-successor</link><description>North Korean leader Kim Jong Un appears to be taking steps to consolidate his daughter's position as successor, and there are signs she is providing input on policy matters, South Korean lawmakers said on Thursday, citing a spy agency briefing.
South Korea's National Intelligence Agency (NIS) will</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 14:26:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Child drowns as mother goes to vote in Chuadanga</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/child-drowns-as-mother-goes-to-vote-in-chuadanga</link><description>A child has drowned in Chuadanga’s Alamdanga Upazila as his mother was at the polling centre to cast her ballot.
The incident occurred around 10:30am in Kharad village in the Upazila, said Alamdanga Police chief Bani Israel.
The child -– three-year-old Hasan -– was the son of vi</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 14:41:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh Polls: Vote counting underway; early results show who’re leading</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-polls-vote-counting-underway-early-results-show-whore-leading</link><description>Preliminary results from 12 out of 185 polling stations in Thakurgaon-1 (Sadar) constituency show BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir leading.
He has secured 12536 votes so far. His nearest rival, Jamaat’s candidate Delwar Hossain, has received 9,359 votes.
Counting is underwa</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 14:56:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP leader held in Barishal over alleged attack on AB Party’s Barrister Fuad</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/bnp-leader-held-in-barishal-over-alleged-attack-on-ab-partys-barrister-fuad</link><description>Joint forces on Thursday detained a BNP leader from Babuganj upazila in Barishal-3 constituency over his alleged involvement in an attack on AB Party leader Barrister Asaduzzaman Fuad last year.
The detainee, Rajon Sikder, is the general secretary of Rahmatpur union BNP. He was picked up around 3p</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 15:15:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP’s Asaduzzaman unofficially wins Jhenaidah-1 by huge margin</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bnps-asaduzzaman-unofficially-wins-jhenaidah-1-by-huge-margin</link><description>BNP-backed candidate and former Attorney General Md Asaduzzaman was unofficially declared elected from the Jhenaidah-1 constituency in the 13th national election.
According to unofficial results, Asaduzzaman secured 171,598 votes, while his nearest rival Jamaat-nominated candidate Matiur Rahman re</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 15:30:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCP’s Patwary flags ‘tally manipulation’ at six Dhaka-8 centres</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ncps-patwary-flags-tally-manipulation-at-six-dhaka-8-centres</link><description>National Citizen Party (NCP) candidate for Dhaka-8 Nasiruddin Patwary has approached the Dhaka divisional returning officer, alleging that vote counts were manipulated at six polling centres in the constituency.
Around 7:45pm on Thursday, he went ot Returning Officer Sharaf Uddin Ahmed Chowdhury t</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 15:45:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC thanks all for peaceful polls, urges special Friday prayer</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-thanks-all-for-peaceful-polls-urges-special-friday-prayer</link><description>The Election Commission on Thursday expressed its gratitude to political parties, candidates, law enforcement personnel, government and private officials on election duty, observers, media workers, voters and the people of Bangladesh for their overall cooperation in making the referendum and the 13</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 16:00:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP candidates take early lead in Manikganj-1, 2 and 3</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/bnp-candidates-take-early-lead-in-manikganj-1-2-and-3</link><description>BNP candidates are leading in all three parliamentary constituencies of Manikganj district, according to unofficial results received from a number of polling centres.
In Manikganj-1, results from 48 out of 179 centres show SA Jinnah Kabir of BNP (Sheaf of Paddy) securing 43,779 votes.
His nearest</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 16:15:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP leads in Sylhet-1 by 32,766 votes; narrow margin in Sylhet-6</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bnp-leads-in-sylhet-1-by-32766-votes-narrow-margin-in-sylhet-6</link><description>BNP candidate Khandakar Abdul Muktadir has taken a commanding lead in Sylhet-1 constituency while a close contest is underway in Sylhet-6.
In Sylhet-1, results from 106 out of 215 polling centres show BNP-nominated candidate Khandakar Muktadir securing 95,276 votes, according to unofficial results</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 16:30:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>For the first time in 35 years, no one killed in electoral violence on polling day</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/for-the-first-time-in-35-years-no-one-killed-in-electoral-violence-on-polling-day</link><description>In a welcome occurrence, not a single person was killed in election-related violence on polling day of the 13th Jatiya Sangshad election, that fell on Thursday. This is the first time since 1991 that polling day of a parliamentary or general election has passed without fatalities due to electoral v</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 16:45:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat will accept results if vote trend holds: Shafiqur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jamaat-will-accept-results-if-counting-reflects-voting-trend-says-shafiqur-rahman</link><description>Jamaat-e-Islami will accept the voting results if they reflect the current trend of votes receoved by the party, says its Ameer Shafiqur Rahman.
Speaking at a press conference in the Dhaka‑15 seat on Thursday evening, he noted that preliminary results were emerging but cautioned against premature</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 17:00:55 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>