<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 07:30:20 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Rescue efforts under way after Philippine ferry sinks, leaving 18 dead</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/rescue-efforts-under-way-after-philippine-ferry-sinks-leaving-18-dead</link><description>Search and rescue operations continued on Tuesday for 10 people still missing after a passenger boat capsized off a southern Philippine province, with the death toll rising slightly to 18, the Philippine Coast Guard said.
Captain Noemie Cayabyab, a spokesperson at the PCG, said the total number of</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 03:59:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Israel recovers last hostage body from Gaza</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/israel-recovers-last-hostage-body-from-gaza</link><description>Israel has recovered the remains of the last remaining hostage held in Gaza, the military said on Monday, fulfilling a key condition of the initial phase of US President Donald Trump's plan to end the war in the Palestinian territory.
The remains of police officer Ran Gvili - held in Gaza for more</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 04:14:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC starts postal ballot distribution in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-starts-postal-ballot-distribution-in-bangladesh</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) says the distribution of postal ballots nationwide has officially begun.
Speaking at the Nirbachan Bhaban on Monday, EC Secretary Akhtar Ahmed said ballots are being dispatched to the registered addresses of those who have signed up for postal voting.
This facility is</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 04:29:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump says he is raising tariffs on South Korean imports after trade deal delays</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/trump-says-he-is-raising-tariffs-on-south-korean-imports-after-trade-deal-delays</link><description>President Donald Trump said on Monday he was raising tariffs on US imports of South Korean autos and other goods, blaming the legislature of an ally and a major trading partner for dragging its feet on enacting a deal agreed last year.
For South Korea, the decision, which officials in Seoul said c</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 04:44:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NATO chief wishes 'good luck' to those who think Europe can defend itself without US help</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/nato-chief-wishes-good-luck-to-those-who-think-europe-can-defend-itself-without-us-help</link><description>NATO Secretary-General Mark Rutte insisted Monday that Europe is incapable of defending itself without U.S. military support and would have to more than double current military spending targets to be able to do so.
"If anyone thinks here … that the European Union or Europe as a whole can de</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 04:59:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>30 killed in US from effects of winter storm</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/30-killed-in-us-from-effects-of-winter-storm</link><description>Many in the U.S. faced another night of below-freezing temperatures and no electricity after a colossal winter storm heaped more snow Monday on the Northeast and kept parts of the South coated in ice. At least 30 deaths were reported in states afflicted with severe cold.
Deep snow — over a f</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 06:00:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India's prime minister says it has reached a free trade with the EU</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/indias-prime-minister-says-it-has-reached-a-free-trade-with-the-eu</link><description>Prime Minister Narendra Modi said Tuesday that India and the European Union have reached a free trade agreement to deepen their economic and strategic ties.
The accord, which touches a whopping 2 billion people, was concluded after nearly two decades of negotiations. It was dubbed the "mother of a</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 06:15:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>More than 21,000 expatriate postal ballots reach Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/more-than-21000-expatriate-postal-ballots-reach-bangladesh</link><description>More than 21,000 postal ballots cast by Bangladeshi voters overseas have reached the country ahead of the 13th parliamentary election.
By 10:30am on Tuesday, 21,508 postal ballots had been returned, according to Salim Ahmad Khan, team leader of the Election Commission’s OCV-SDI project.
He</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 06:30:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ekushey Book Fair to open on Feb 20 as government cuts stall fees</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ekushey-book-fair-to-open-on-feb-20-as-government-cuts-stall-fees</link><description>The annual Amar Ekushey Book Fair will begin on Feb 20 after the 13th parliamentary election, with stall rents reduced by 25 percent, the Ministry of Cultural Affairs has announced.
In a statement, the ministry said that the decision was taken following requests from publishers participating in th</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 06:45:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladeshi workers ‘lured to Russia’ for jobs forced to fight in Ukraine war</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladeshi-workers-lured-to-russia-for-jobs-forced-to-fight-in-ukraine-war</link><description>A labour recruiter reportedly persuaded Maksudur Rahman to leave the tropical warmth of his hometown in Bangladesh and travel thousands of miles to frigid Russia for a job as a janitor.
Within weeks, he found himself on the front lines of Russia’s war in Ukraine.
An Associated Press investi</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 07:00:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Three members of fake currency gang arrested in Gazipur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/three-members-of-fake-currency-gang-arrested-in-gazipur</link><description>Rapid Action Battalion (RAB) personnel arrested three people after raiding an illegal counterfeit currency factory in Gazipur on Monday.
Acting on a tip-off, the RAB personnel raided a rented house in the Bonomala area of Tongi, where the factory had reportedly been operating for an extended perio</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 07:15:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Stocks jump as key indices post strong gains</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/stocks-jump-as-key-indices-post-strong-gains</link><description>Trading at both the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) and the Chittagong Stock Exchange (CSE) remained upbeat on Tuesday, as key indices posted strong gains amid a rise in the majority of listed securities.
In the first half of the session, the benchmark DSE Broad Index (DSEX) jumped 64 points.
The Shar</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 07:30:19 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>