<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 06:37:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Post-IPO expansion failure drags Lub-rref deeper into losses</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/post-ipo-expansion-failure-drags-lub-rref-deeper-into-losses</link><description>Lub-rref (Bangladesh) has sunk deeper into the red within five years of listing, as its post-IPO expansion plan went haywire.
The lubricant producer reported a loss of Tk 662 million for the year ended June this year, up from a loss of Tk 107 million a year earlier.
The poor financial performance</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 04:28:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump confirms conversation with Maduro</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-confirms-conversation-with-venezuelas-maduro</link><description>US President Donald Trump confirmed on Sunday that he had spoken with Venezuelan President Nicolas Maduro, but did not provide details on what the two leaders discussed.
"I don't want to comment on it. The answer is yes," Trump said when asked if he had spoken with Maduro. He was speaking to repor</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 04:43:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Judgment in plot scam case against Hasina, Rehana, Tulip today</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/judgment-in-plot-scam-case-against-hasina-rehana-tulip-today</link><description>A Dhaka court is set to pronounce its judgment today in a case against 17 people, including ousted prime minister Sheikh Hasina, her sister Sheikh Rehana and niece Tulip Siddique, over irregularities in the allocation of a 10-katha plot in the RAJUK Purbachal New Town Project.
The court is schedul</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 04:58:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Month of Victory begins</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/month-of-victory-begins</link><description>December, the month of Victory when Bangladesh was born as an independent country in 1971 after the surrender of Pakistani occupation forces following a nine-month war, began on Monday.
Different sociocultural, political, and professional bodies and institutions will celebrate the month through di</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 03:58:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mobile phone traders observe shutdown over NEIR reforms</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/mobile-phone-traders-observe-shutdown-over-neir-reforms</link><description>Mobile phone traders across Bangladesh staged a day-long shutdown and formed a human chain in Dhaka on Sunday, pressing for sweeping reforms to the National Equipment Identity Register (NEIR), a fair and consistent tax structure, and an end to what they describe as a growing monopolistic grip on th</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 04:13:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>November death toll hits single-month high of 99</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/november-death-toll-hits-single-month-high-of-99</link><description>The total fatalities due to mosquito-borne dengue disease hit a single-month high of 99 in November with five new deaths reported on Sunday, according to the Director General of Health Services (DGHS).
On the other hand, some 636 new dengue patients were also hospitalised across the county during</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 04:28:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Locals block Ctg-Cox's Bazar Highway</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/locals-block-ctg-coxs-bazar-highway</link><description>Agitated locals blocked the Chattogram-Cox's Bazar Highway at several points on Sunday demanding the development of the two-lane 136-km long highway into a six-lane expressway.
As part of a pre-announced programme, the blockade started around 9 AM in Lohagara and Keranihat of Satkania in the Chatt</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 04:43:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Security beefed up ahead of verdict in Hasina plot scam case</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/security-beefed-up-ahead-of-verdict-in-hasina-plot-scam-case</link><description>Law enforcement agencies have taken heightened security measures in the capital ahead of today's (Monday) verdict in a case against 17 people, including ousted prime minister Sheikh Hasina, her sister Sheikh Rehana and niece Tulip Siddique, over irregularities in the allocation of a 10-katha plot i</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 04:58:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BIWTA to set up country's 54th river port in Bogura</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/biwta-to-set-up-countrys-54th-river-port-in-bogura</link><description>The Bangladesh Inland Water Transport Authority (BIWTA) is set to establish the country's 54th river port in Bogura very soon, aiming to expand transportation of goods, mostly agricultural produces, between northern Bangladesh and Dhaka through river ways.
To this goal, a feasibility study has alr</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 05:13:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>TCB seeks procurement provider VAT exemption for all suppliers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/tcb-seeks-procurement-provider-vat-exemption-for-all-suppliers</link><description>The state-run Trading Corporation of Bangladesh (TCB) has requested an exemption from the procurement provider VAT for all suppliers of edible oil and sugar in local tenders, sources say.
It recently made the request to the commerce ministry, urging the latter to take steps in this regard.
The mo</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 05:28:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Banglalink unveils its new identity to power digital future</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/banglalink-unveils-its-new-identity-to-power-digital-future</link><description>Banglalink, the country's leading digital operator, has unveiled a bold brand refresh that marks its transformation into a modern, customer-centric, and technology-driven company.
This milestone reflects Banglalink's commitment to accelerating the nation's digital progress while advancing its pare</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 05:43:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UK military committed war crimes in Afghanistan, ex-officer says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/ex-officer-tells-inquiry-uk-military-committed-war-crimes-in-afghanistan</link><description>A former senior British officer has told a public inquiry that British special forces in Afghanistan appeared to commit war crimes by executing suspects and despite widespread knowledge in the chain of command nothing was done.
Britain's defence ministry (MoD) ordered the inquiry after a BBC TV do</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 05:58:51 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>