<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 15:29:58 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Country's first govt freelancer ID management software launched</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/countrys-first-govt-freelancer-id-management-software-launched</link><description>The country's first government freelancer ID management software has been officially inaugurated as an effort to build a transparent, secure and harassment-free verification system for freelancers.
Chief Adviser's Special Assistant on Posts, Telecommunications and Information Technology, Faiz Ahma</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 12:02:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UN rights office says hundreds killed in Iran protests</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/un-rights-office-says-hundreds-killed-in-iran-protests</link><description>The UN human rights chief said on Tuesday that he was "horrified" by mounting violence by Iran's security forces against peaceful protesters, with the UN citing its own sources as saying that hundreds have been killed so far.
The Islamic Republic's clerical authorities are facing the biggest demon</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 12:17:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BB tightens sustainable finance reporting to curb greenwashing</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bb-tightens-sustainable-finance-reporting-to-curb-greenwashing</link><description>In a move to bolster transparency and ensure the integrity of environmental initiatives within the financial sector, Bangladesh Bank (BB) has issued new directives to refine the reporting framework for sustainable finance.
The central bank’s Sustainable Finance Department (SFD) on Tuesday re</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 12:32:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP to democratise economy if it comes to power: Amir Khasru</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-to-democratise-economy-if-it-comes-to-power-amir-khasru</link><description>Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) will democratise the economy if it comes to power, as the people remain deprived if the economy is kept under group-centric patronage, said BNP leader Amir Khasru Mahmud Chowdhury.
He said this at a dialogue titled National Election 2026 and Citizen Expectations,</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 12:47:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC clears way for 53 more candidates to contest Feb-12 election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-clears-way-for-53-more-candidates-to-contest-feb-12-election</link><description>The Election Commission on Tuesday allowed 53 previously rejected aspirants to contest the February-12 national election after hearings, while two Jamaat candidates for Dhaka-2 and Cumilla-3 were declared invalid.
But the EC as the Electoral Appeal Tribunal turned down the appeal petitions of 15 o</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 13:02:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Zaber &amp; Zubair hosts 17th Fabric Week featuring Spring–Summer ’27 collection</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/zaber-zubair-hosts-17th-fabric-week-featuring-spring-summer-27-collection</link><description>Zaber &amp; Zubair Fabrics Limited, a global leader in sustainable and innovative textile solutions, has started the six-day-long 17th edition of its signature Fabric Week, showcasing its innovation and product development for the upcoming Spring–Summer 2027 season.
The expo began on Tuesday mor</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 13:17:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pubali Bank achieves record-breaking financial performance in 2025</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/pubali-bank-achieves-record-breaking-financial-performance-in-2025</link><description>Pubali Bank PLC opened a new era in the country’s banking sector by achieving record-breaking financial performance in 2025, according to a press release.
Driven by sustainable growth strategies, robust risk management and a strong customer-centric approach, the bank recorded operating profi</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 13:32:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP alleges bias in postal ballot arrangement</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bnp-says-deliberate-ordering-of-postal-ballot-symbols-gives-some-parties-unfair-advantage</link><description>The Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) has alleged that the postal ballot papers prepared for overseas voters deliberately placed certain party symbols first, giving some groups an unfair advantage.
BNP’s representative team raised the issue at an Election Commission meeting, claiming the ar</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 13:47:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh’s economy grows by 4.50pc in Q1 of FY26</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladeshs-economy-grows-by-450pc-in-q1-of-fy26</link><description>Bangladesh’s economy grew by 4.50 percent in the first quarter (July-September) of the current fiscal year (FY26) driven by moderate performances by the agriculture, industry and services sectors.
According to the latest data by the Bangladesh Bureau of Statistics (BBS), the GDP growth rate</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 14:02:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BRAC Bank distributes over 62,000 winter clothes across Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/brac-bank-distributes-over-62000-winter-clothes-across-bangladesh</link><description>BRAC Bank has distributed more than 62,000 winter clothes nationwide to support marginalised communities affected by extreme cold, according to a press release.
As part of the initiative, the bank provided 13,000 blankets through the Chief Advisor’s Welfare Fund and the Chattogram City Corpo</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 14:17:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ancient Roman home opens to the public - with remote guided tours</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/ancient-roman-home-opens-to-the-public-with-remote-guided-tours</link><description>An ancient Roman home more than 2,000 years old has opened to the public, but its spectacular mosaics, frescoes and stucco decorations will be accessible only via remote and web-streamed guided tours.
The "House of the Griffins", named after animal decorations in one of its rooms, was an aristocra</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 14:32:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Al-Arafah Islami Bank inaugurates workshop on general banking management</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/al-arafah-islami-bank-inaugurates-workshop-on-general-banking-management</link><description>A 3-day training workshop titled 'General Banking Management' at Al-Arafah Islami Bank has begun at the bank's training institute, according to a press release.
Managing Director and CEO Mohd Rafat Ullah Khan inaugurated the Workshop as the chief guest on Tuesday, January 13, 2026.
Speaking as th</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 14:47:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>