<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 17:19:44 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Secondary level students to get all textbooks by January 15: NCTB</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/secondary-level-students-to-get-all-textbooks-by-january-15-nctb</link><description>The National Curriculum and Textbook Board (NCTB) has expressed optimism to ensure distributing the rest of all the books for the secondary students by January 15.
After completing the distribution of hundred percent textbooks of the pre-primary and primary level students, the NCTB has fixed the t</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 14:37:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCP leader held over Dinajpur ‘extortion’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/ncp-leader-held-over-dinajpur-extortion</link><description>Police have arrested NCP leader Tafsir Hasan in an extortion case in Bochaganj Upazila in Dinajpur.
According to Anwar Hossain, additional police superintendent of the district, Tafsir and his associate Monjurul Islam were detained around Saturday midnight.
Both were sent to jail on Sunday aftern</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 14:52:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Political motives were behind enforced disappearances, says Commission in final report</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/political-motives-were-behind-enforced-disappearances-says-commission-in-final-report</link><description>The Commission of Inquiry on Enforced Disappearances today (Sunday) submitted its final report to Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus, stating that enforced disappearances in Bangladesh were largely politically motivated and carried out with involvement from the highest levels of the immediate p</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 15:07:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Enforced Disappearances Commission says ex-PM Hasina ordered many cases</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/enforced-disappearances-commission-says-ex-pm-hasina-ordered-many-cases</link><description>The Commission of Inquiry on Enforced Disappearances on Sunday submitted its final report to Chief Adviser Prof Muhammad Yunus, claiming that former Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina herself had issued direct orders in many cases of enforced disappearances.
Members of the Commission said the disappeara</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 14:27:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCP in talks with resigned leaders, no final decision on seat sharing yet: Akhtar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ncp-in-talks-with-resigned-leaders-no-final-decision-on-seat-sharing-yet-akhtar</link><description>National Citizen Party (NCP) Member Secretary Akhtar Hossain on Sunday said the party is holding discussions with leaders who have resigned, noting that their resignations have not yet been formally accepted.
"The resignations have hurt the party. Those concerned have submitted resignation letters</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 14:42:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Uttara Bank inaugurates its 49th sub-branch in Hajiganj</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/uttara-bank-inaugurates-its-49th-sub-branch-in-hajiganj</link><description>Uttara Bank PLC has inaugurated its 49th sub-branch, named ‘Hajiganj Sub-Branch’, at Hajiganj Bazar Road in Chandpur.
According to a press release, Deputy Managing Director of Uttara Bank PLC, Mr. Khandaker Ali Samnoon, inaugurated the branch at an event on Sunday.
Md. Rabiul Hasan, G</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 14:57:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Southeast Bank hands over ‘BETON CARD’ insurance claim cheque</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/southeast-bank-hands-over-beton-card-insurance-claim-cheque</link><description>Southeast Bank PLC has handed over an insurance claim cheque to the family of a deceased employee of Shrabony Knitwear Ltd. under the Group Insurance Coverage of the bank’s “BETON CARD” program.
According to a press release, the insurance benefit is provided in partnership with N</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 15:12:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prime Bank secures $20m term loan from Invest In Visions to fuel MSME growth</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/prime-bank-secures-20m-term-loan-from-invest-in-visions-to-fuel-msme-growth</link><description>Prime Bank PLC, a leading private commercial bank in Bangladesh, has successfully signed a Term Loan Agreement for USD 20 million with Invest In Visions Microfinance Fund, a respected German-based impact investor, according to a press release.
In this regard, a signing ceremony took place recently</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 15:27:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rights groups say at least 16 dead in Iran during week of protests</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/rights-groups-say-at-least-16-dead-in-iran-during-week-of-protests</link><description>At least 16 people have been killed during a week of unrest in Iran, rights groups said on Sunday, as protests over soaring inflation spread across the country, sparking violent clashes between demonstrators and security forces.
Deaths and arrests have been reported through the week both by state</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 15:42:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mutual Trust Bank holds MTB Annual Town Hall 2026</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/mutual-trust-bank-holds-mtb-annual-town-hall-2026</link><description>Mutual Trust Bank PLC (MTB) held its Annual Town Hall 2026 at a local venue in Dhaka under the theme “Trust Rebuilt, Future Redefined.”
According to a press release, the Town Hall focused on reviewing the Bank’s performance, addressing prevailing challenges, and aligning MTBians</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 15:57:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Yemeni government accuses separatists of Aden restrictions</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/yemeni-government-accuses-separatists-of-aden-restrictions</link><description>Yemen’s Saudi-backed government on Sunday accused UAE-backed southern separatists of cutting off the port city of Aden and warned it would “take all necessary measures” after recapturing territory from them in the east on Saturday.
The separatists denied having restricted movemen</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 16:12:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Investors face more geopolitical whiplash from Trump’s Venezuela gamble</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/investors-face-more-geopolitical-whiplash-from-trumps-venezuela-gamble</link><description>Global investors are facing a fresh surge in geopolitical risk after the US capture of Venezuelan President Nicolas Maduro, a move that could unlock the nation’s vast oil reserves and boost risky assets over the longer-term but prompt a flight to safety when trading resumes.
President Donald</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 16:27:42 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>