<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 12:44:39 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Rashed Khan leaves Gono Odhikar Parishad to join BNP</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/rashed-khan-leaves-gono-odhikar-parishad-to-join-bnp</link><description>Rashed Khan, the general secretary of Gono Odhikar Parishad, has left the party and officially joined the BNP.
He joined the BNP by presenting a bouquet to BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir at the chairperson’s office at Dhaka’s Gulshan on Saturday, reports bdnews24.com</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 10:00:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shrine vandalised overnight in Thakurgaon</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/shrine-vandalised-overnight-in-thakurgaon</link><description>A shrine in Thakurgaon town has reportedly been vandalised under the cover of darkness, prompting tensions among local residents and devotees.
The shrine, known as the Hazrat Baba Shah Satyapir Mazar, was damaged at some point on Friday night in the Satyapir Bridge area of the town, according to T</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 09:45:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique offers fateha at graves of Pilkhana martyrs, father-in-law</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-offers-fateha-at-graves-of-pilkhana-martyrs-father-in-law</link><description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman on Saturday visited the graves of the slain army officers of the 2009 Pilkhana tragedy at the Banani Military Graveyard in the capital.
He offered fateha and paid homage to the military officers who were killed during the 2009 BDR mutiny at Pilkhana in Dhaka.
Ta</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 10:00:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Move underway to ensure 20pc power subsidy for fisheries: Adviser Farida</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/move-underway-to-ensure-20pc-power-subsidy-for-fisheries-adviser-farida</link><description>The government is working to extend a 20 per cent electricity subsidy to the fisheries sector, similar to the incentive currently enjoyed by agriculture, Fisheries and Livestock Adviser Farida Akhter said on Saturday.
"The fisheries sector does not yet receive subsidised electricity like agricultu</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 10:15:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Army chief says Switzerland can't defend itself from full-scale attack</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/army-chief-says-switzerland-cant-defend-itself-from-full-scale-attack</link><description>Switzerland cannot defend itself against a full-scale attack and must boost military spending given rising risks from Russia, the head of its armed forces said.
The country is prepared for attacks by "non-state actors" on critical infrastructure and for cyber attacks, but its military still faces</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 10:30:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>What lies ahead for Ukraine's contested Zaporizhzhia nuclear power plant?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/what-lies-ahead-for-ukraines-contested-zaporizhzhia-nuclear-power-plant</link><description>The Zaporizhzhia nuclear power plant, Europe's largest, is one of the main sticking points in US President Donald Trump's peace plan to end the nearly four-year war between Russia and Ukraine.
The issue is one of 20 points laid out by Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelenskiy in a framework peace pr</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 10:45:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Explosion at Keraniganj madrasa injures four</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/explosion-at-keraniganj-madrasa-injures-four</link><description>An explosion ripped through a madrasa in the Hasnabad area of South Keraniganj, Dhaka, on Friday morning, injuring four people, including a woman and two children, police said.
The blast occurred around 10:30 am at a single-storey building of Ummal Qura International Madrasa, blowing off the walls</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 11:00:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>England survive Melbourne mayhem to claim drought-breaking win</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/england-survive-melbourne-mayhem-to-claim-drought-breaking-win</link><description>England celebrated their first test win in Australia in 15 years on Saturday as they chased down 175 runs for a four-wicket Ashes victory completed in two manic days at the Melbourne Cricket Ground.
Though the hosts had already locked away the urn after three straight victories in Perth, Brisbane</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 11:00:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Winter storm bears down on US Northeast, disrupting airline travel</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/winter-storm-bears-down-on-us-northeast-disrupting-airline-travel</link><description>A winter storm packing a frosty mix of snow and ice bore down on the US Northeast early on Saturday, disrupting post-holiday weekend airline traffic and prompting officials in New York and New Jersey to issue weather emergency declarations.
The National Weather Service posted ice storm and winter</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 11:15:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Premier Bank holds Annual Risk Conference 2025</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/premier-bank-holds-annual-risk-conference-2025</link><description>Premier Bank PLC recently held its Annual Risk Conference 2025 at its Head Office in Dhaka. The conference, organised under the theme “Proactive Risk Management for Sustainable Growth”, was attended by members of the Board of Directors, senior management and other senior officials of th</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 11:30:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Yemen's Saudi-led coalition warns STC against moves in Hadramout</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/yemens-saudi-led-coalition-warns-stc-against-moves-in-hadramout</link><description>Yemen's Saudi-led coalition said any military moves by the main southern separatist group STC in the eastern province of Hadramout that undermined de-escalation efforts would be countered to protect civilians, the Saudi state news agency reported on Saturday.
The statement from coalition spokesper</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 11:45:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt vows credible elections, warns against sabotage: Adilur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-vows-credible-elections-warns-against-sabotage-adilur</link><description>Adviser of LGRD and Cooperatives and Housing and Public Works Adilur Rahman Khan, on Saturday, said that the government is making all-out efforts to ensure citizens' safety and will take strict measures against any attempt to disrupt the upcoming election. 
"Fascist forces may try to hinder t</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 12:00:53 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>