<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 13:51:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Extra public holiday on Feb 11 to facilitate voting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/extra-public-holiday-on-feb-11-to-facilitate-voting</link><description>The Council of Advisers on Thursday approved a proposal to declare February 11 a public holiday, in addition to the public holiday on the voting day on February 12, to help voters participate and ensure law and order management in an effective manner.
The approval was given at the Council’s</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 10:11:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka Central University Ordinance cleared</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/advisory-council-approves-dhaka-central-university-ordinance</link><description>The Advisory Council has greenlighted the Dhaka Central University Ordinance, which will bring seven government colleges under a single academic framework.
The matter has been confirmed by Shafiqul Alam, press secretary to the chief adviser.
“The main objective of this ordinance is to impro</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 10:26:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Army chief assures full cooperation for election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/army-chief-waker-uz-zaman-promises-full-cooperation-for-free-fair-peaceful-election</link><description>Bangladesh Army chief General Waker-Uz-Zaman has said the armed forces will provide all-out support to ensure a free, fair, and peaceful election.
He made the remarks at a discussion on the February general election at the Chattogram Circuit House on Thursday afternoon.
An announcement about the</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 10:41:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NATO chief says allies must step up Arctic security in Greenland deal with Trump</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/nato-chief-says-allies-must-step-up-arctic-security-in-greenland-deal-with-trump</link><description>NATO Secretary General Mark Rutte said on Thursday NATO allies will need to step up their presence in the Arctic under a framework deal with U.S. President Donald Trump after he backed off tariff threats and ruled out taking Greenland by force.
Rutte told Reuters in an interview on the sidelines o</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 10:56:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UCB employees will get special discounts at Scholastica for their children</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ucb-employees-will-get-special-discounts-at-scholastica-for-their-children</link><description>United Commercial Bank PLC (UCB) has entered into a Memorandum of Understanding (MoU) with Scholastica, one of the country’s leading educational institutions, to create enhanced educational opportunities for the children of UCB employees.
The MoU signing ceremony was held on Thursday at UCB</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 11:11:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ICC chief slams 'spoon-feeding' of weak banks, demands end to bailout culture</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/icc-chief-slams-spoon-feeding-of-weak-banks-demands-end-to-bailout-culture</link><description>Mahbubur Rahman, President of the International Chamber of Commerce (ICC) Bangladesh, has strongly criticised the practice of providing artificial life support to failing banks, warning that such measures will not resolve the banking sector crisis.
Speaking at a discussion on 'Banking Sector R</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 11:26:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EBL &amp; icddr,b renew partnership for National Biohazardous Waste Reform</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ebl-icddrb-renew-partnership-for-national-biohazardous-waste-reform</link><description>Eastern Bank PLC (EBL) and icddr,b have renewed their partnership for the third consecutive year, reaffirming their joint commitment to improving public health and environmental sustainability in Bangladesh.
A cheque handover ceremony under the existing MoU was held on Thursday at EBL’s head</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 11:41:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BRAC Bank launches Visa Multicurrency SME Business Debit &amp; Credit Cards</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/brac-bank-launches-visa-multicurrency-sme-business-debit-credit-cards</link><description>BRAC Bank has recently introduced Visa Multicurrency SME Business Debit and Credit Cards to enable small and medium enterprise (SME) customers to perform authorised B2B local and foreign currency transactions, supporting smoother business operations.
The cards were launched at a ceremony held on W</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 11:56:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>2,496 graduates receive degrees at IUB’s 26th convocation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/2496-graduates-receive-degrees-at-iubs-26th-convocation</link><description>Independent University, Bangladesh (IUB) held its 26th Convocation at the International Convention City Bashundhara on Wednesday, with a total of 2,496 students receiving degrees from undergraduate and postgraduate programmes.
Of the graduates, 2,140 completed undergraduate programmes while 356 ea</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 12:11:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Biased admin forced me out of constituency on day one of campaign: Rumeen</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/biased-admin-forced-me-out-of-constituency-on-day-one-of-campaign-rumeen</link><description>Independent candidate of Brahmanbaria-2 and expelled BNP leader Rumeen Farhana alleged on Thursday that she was forced to come to Dhaka on the first day of the electioneering, accusing the administration and police of bias.
“Today I have come to the Election Commission with my written explan</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 12:26:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>MTB introduces ‘CEO Connect’ to strengthen direct engagement with employees</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/mtb-introduces-ceo-connect-to-strengthen-direct-engagement-with-employees</link><description>Mutual Trust Bank PLC (MTB) has introduced a new internal engagement initiative titled ‘CEO Connect’, marking a significant milestone in the bank’s journey to strengthen open dialogue and closer leadership engagement.
According to a press release, the initiative aims to provide s</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 12:41:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique slams political tactic of ‘heaven-for-vote’ targeting women</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-slams-political-tactic-of-heaven-for-vote-targeting-women</link><description>BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman on Thursday accused a political party of trying to mislead people, especially women, by selling ‘tickets-to-heaven’ in exchange for votes.
“There is a political party whose role we saw 50 years ago. They are now going to the homes of innocent mothers a</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 12:56:28 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>