<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 18:34:14 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Somalia says it killed 29 al-Shabaab militants with international support</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/somalia-says-it-killed-29-al-shabaab-militants-with-international-support</link><description>Somalia’s armed forces have eliminated 29 al-Shabaab militants in the town of Jabad Godane in southeastern Somalia, in coordination with international partners, the Defence Ministry said in a statement on Thursday.
Al-Shabaab has waged an insurgency in Somalia since 2007 in a bid to topple t</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 15:45:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Yemen’s Aden airport shuts as Saudi-UAE rift deepens</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/yemens-aden-airport-shuts-as-saudi-uae-rift-deepens</link><description>Air traffic at Yemen’s Aden international airport was halted on Thursday as tensions persisted between Saudi Arabia and the United Arab Emirates, two Gulf powers whose rivalry is reshaping war-torn Yemen.
The Saudi-backed, internationally recognised Yemeni government ordered new restrictions</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 16:00:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jaishankar’s visit should not be read through political lens: Touhid</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jaishankars-visit-should-not-be-read-through-political-lens-touhid</link><description>Foreign Affairs Adviser Md Touhid Hossain suggested not to interpret Indian External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar’s brief visit to Dhaka through an inter-state or political lens, saying it should be seen primarily as a gesture of courtesy.
He made the remarks on Thursday while speaking to j</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 16:30:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Latifur Rahman’s remarks on AL in Chapainawabganj were personal: Jamaat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/latifur-rahmans-remarks-on-al-in-chapainawabganj-were-personal-jamaat</link><description>Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami on Thursday said that remarks made by Professor Latifur Rahman regarding the Awami League at a courtyard meeting in Chapainawabganj were entirely his personal views and do not reflect the party’s position.
The clarification came in a statement issued by Jamaat&amp;rsqu</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 16:45:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat chief Shafiqur says not everyone gets a farewell like Khaleda’s</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jamaat-chief-shafiqur-says-not-everyone-gets-a-farewell-like-khaledas</link><description>Jamaat-e-Islami chief Shafiqur Rahman has said the outpouring of emotion and respect for former prime minister and BNP chairperson Khaleda Zia was not a farewell that “everyone is fortunate” to receive.
Speaking at the BNP chairperson’s Gulshan office on Thursday evening, he urge</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 17:00:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New Year party at Swiss ski resort turned into a disaster zone</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/new-year-party-at-swiss-ski-resort-turned-into-a-disaster-zone</link><description>As he approached Le Constellation bar to celebrate the New Year in a snowy Swiss ski resort bright with Christmas lights, Dominic Dubois saw flames engulfing the building.
"You could see the orange, the orange, yellow, red," Dubois told Reuters, describing chaotic scenes as bystanders and emergenc</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 16:30:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Merged banks: Depositors begin withdrawing funds</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/after-months-of-freeze-depositors-begin-withdrawing-funds-from-merged-banks</link><description>Depositors of five private Shariah-based banks, which were recently merged to form the Sammilito Islami Bank, have begun withdrawing their savings.
Depositors gaining access to their funds on Thursday marks a cautious return of liquidity after a prolonged period of financial distress.
For months,</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 16:45:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A year of growth for Chattogram Port</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/chattogram-port-sails-to-record-year-as-ship-arrivals-cargo-revenue-post-broad-based-growth</link><description>Chattogram Port has recorded gains across all key indicators over the past year, with higher volumes of containers and bulk cargo handled and a sharp rise in ship arrivals, underscoring the premier sea port’s growing role in the trade-led economy.
According to port authority data, container</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 17:00:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Consumptionscape in Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/consumptionscape-in-dhaka</link><description>Walking through the streets of Gulshan, Banani, or Dhanmondi in Dhaka, it is easy to imagine that the city has joined the ranks of global metropolises. Sleek shopping malls, international brands, trendy cafes, and luxury boutiques give the impression of a cosmopolitan urban life. Shoppers with desi</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 17:15:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No escape from Dhaka's air pollution!</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/no-escape-from-dhakas-air-pollution</link><description>While celebration of the year 2026 began earlier in some countries like New Zealand and Australia, Dhaka began its journey into the New Year with the dubious tag of one of the most polluted cities in the world. Breathing outdoors now poses serious health risks due to the high levels of toxic partic</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 17:30:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Welcome year 2026</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/welcome-year-2026</link><description>An eventful year marked by tumultuous national developments and international conflicts raising at times the spectre of a World War III has just passed. The world has already welcomed the New Year with open arms in the hope that the looming threat of global trade suffering commercial convulsions du</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 17:45:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Areas of non-existent workplace safety</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/areas-of-non-existent-workplace-safety</link><description>Workplace safety has long been a matter of serious concern but recent developments suggest that the situation has further deteriorated. Accidents and deaths arising from hazardous working conditions and compounded by persistent negligence in enforcing safety standards have cast a long shadow over t</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 18:00:56 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>