<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 08:33:11 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Reinforce legal framework against human trafficking, speakers suggest at a city seminar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/reinforce-legal-framework-against-human-trafficking-speakers-suggest-at-a-city-seminar</link><description>Speakers on Wednesday emphasised the importance of fostering a victim-centred, trauma-informed, and gender-responsive approach among law students by strengthening their foundational knowledge and practical understanding.
They said this approach aimed to reinforce Bangladesh's legal framework again</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 05:48:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>RU holds 12th convocation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/ru-holds-12th-convocation</link><description>Rajshahi University (RU) held its 12th convocation on Wednesday, after uncertainty in the last five years. The ceremony took place at the central stadium amid a festive atmosphere across the campus.
From early morning, the university premises buzzed with excitement as graduates reunited with frien</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 06:03:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Indian visa centre in Dhaka now open</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/indian-visa-centre-in-dhaka-now-open</link><description>After assessing the security situation on Thursday morning, Indian Visa Application Centre (IVAC) in Dhaka is now operational and functioning as normal.
"We do understand the difficulties faced by applicants," said an official. 
Based on evolving security situation, there will be a reassessm</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 06:18:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Another Bangladeshi peacekeeper injured in Sudan drone attack</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/another-bangladeshi-peacekeeper-injured-in-sudan-drone-attack</link><description>Another Bangladeshi peacekeeper has been injured in a drone attack by separatist forces in Sudan, raising the total number of wounded Bangladesh Army personnel serving in the UN mission to nine.
According to a media release from the Inter-Services Public Relations (ISPR), eight Bangladeshi peaceke</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 06:33:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCP activist Jannat Ara Rumi found dead in Hazaribagh hostel</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ncp-activist-jannat-ara-rumi-found-dead-in-hazaribagh-hostel</link><description>Police have recovered the hanging body of a young woman, identified as Jannat Ara Rumi (30), from a female hostel in the Hazaribagh area of Dhaka
She was involved in politics with the National Citizen Party (NCP), though it has not yet been confirmed whether she held any official post in the party</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 06:48:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DSE, CSE down in early trading</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/dse-cse-down-in-early-trading</link><description>Trading at both the Dhaka and Chattogram stock exchanges began on a negative note on Thursday, with key indices falling in the first hour amid declines in most company prices.
The benchmark DSEX at the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) shed 17 points.
The Shariah-based DSES fell by 5 points, while the b</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 07:03:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>46 Bangladeshis arrested in Malaysia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/46-bangladeshis-arrested-in-malaysia</link><description>Malaysia’s Immigration Department on Wednesday detained 46 Bangladeshi nationals, aged between 18 and 43, in a major operation at an iron factory at Nilai city of Negeri Sembilan state.
During the operation, authorities checked the documents of 117 foreign nationals. Of them, 46 Bangladeshis</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 06:48:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>483 die, 1,317 injured in road accidents in November</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/483-die-1317-injured-in-road-accidents-in-november</link><description>As many as 483 people, including 64 women and 71 children, were killed and 1,317 others injured in 534 road accidents across the country in November, according to a report of the Road Safety Foundation (RSF).
Like October, Dhaka division recorded the highest number of accidents at 141, resulting i</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 07:03:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Apex Footwear holds Annual Sales Conference, honours top performers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/apex-footwear-holds-annual-sales-conference-honours-top-performers</link><description>Apex Footwear Limited on Tuesday held its Annual Sales Conference at the Samajik Convention Center in Ashulia, Dhaka, bringing together around 1,500 employees from across the country for a day-long programme.
The conference opened with a tribute to the company's late Founder Chairman, Syed Manzur</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 07:18:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rajshahi farmer killed by excavator</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rajshahi-farmer-killed-by-excavator</link><description>A group of locals in Rajshahi’s Mohonpur Upazila have allegedly killed a farmer by running him over with an excavator as he blocked them from digging a pond illegally.
The deceased, 25-year-old Zubayer Ali, was the son of Rafiz Uddin from Boro Palsha village.
The incident occurred in Boro P</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 07:33:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DSE launches Help Desk to improve investor information services</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/dse-launches-help-desk-to-improve-investor-information-services</link><description>The Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) launched an Information Help Desk on Thursday, aiming to make capital market-related information more accessible and effective for investors and other stakeholders.
The help desk was formally inaugurated by DSE Managing Director (acting) Mohammad Asadur Rahman at the</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 07:48:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Grameen Bank office in Feni set on fire</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/grameen-bank-office-in-feni-set-on-fire</link><description>Miscreants set fire to the Shorshadi Bazar branch of Grameen Bank in Feni Sadar early Thursday, damaging motorcycles and furniture inside the bank premises.
According to bank officials, the attackers poured petrol from outside the main gate and set the building on fire late at night. Three motorcy</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 08:03:36 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>