<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 12:41:34 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nine new anthrax cases detected as outbreak spreads in Rangpur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nine-new-anthrax-cases-detected-as-outbreak-spreads-in-rangpur</link><description>Health officials have confirmed nine new human cases of anthrax in Rangpur as the outbreak spread beyond Pirgachha to Mithapukur and Kaunia Upazilas.
The Institute of Epidemiology, Disease Control and Research (IEDCR) said eight people in Pirgachha and one in Mithapukur tested positive after sampl</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 09:53:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khagrachhari unrest: Shops reopen, traffic resumes, but Section 144 still enforced in key areas</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/khagrachhari-unrest-shops-reopen-traffic-resumes-but-section-144-still-enforced-in-key-areas</link><description>The Khagrachhari has seen a return to normalcy at large after the ongoing road blockade was suspended by the Jumma Chhatra Janata, following assurances of fulfilling eight demands, and in respect of the ongoing Durga Puja celebrations.
However, Section 144 continues to be enforced in the district</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 10:23:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India raises wheat purchase price by 6.6 per cent to boost output</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/india-raises-wheat-purchase-price-by-66-per-cent-to-boost-output</link><description>India has raised the price at which it will buy new-season wheat from domestic farmers by 160 rupees ($1.80) or 6.6 percent to encourage growers to expand acreage and boost supplies in the world's second-biggest producer of the grain.
The revised purchase price of 2,585 rupees ($29.15) per 100 kg</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 10:38:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gulshan-Banani Sarvajanin Puja Foundation celebrates 18th Sharadiya Durga Utsab 2025</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/gulshan-banani-sarvajanin-puja-foundation-celebrates-18th-sharadiya-durga-utsab-2025</link><description>The Gulshan-Banani Sarvajanin Puja Foundation (GBSPF) has announced the celebration of its 18th Annual Sharadiya Durga Utsab, from September 28 (Sashthi) to October 2, 2025 (Bijoya Dashami).
This year’s festival promises to be one of the most vibrant in the foundation’s history, blendi</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 11:08:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India says highly unlikely that UN peace forces will be deployed in Ukraine, Gaza</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/india-says-highly-unlikely-that-un-peace-forces-will-be-deployed-in-ukraine-gaza</link><description>​​​​​It is highly unlikely that UN peacekeeping forces will be deployed in Ukraine or Gaza given the composition of the United Nations Security Council, a senior Indian defence ministry official said on Wednesday.
The official, Vishwesh Negi, was speaking at a press conference of the conclave of a</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 11:23:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BRAC Bank secures approval for Bangladesh’s first social bond</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/brac-bank-secures-approval-for-bangladeshs-first-social-bond</link><description>BRAC Bank has secured approval from the Bangladesh Securities and Exchange Commission and Bangladesh Bank to issue the country’s first-ever Social Subordinated Bond, valued at BDT 1,000 crore, according to a press release.
The landmark issuance of the ‘BRAC Bank Social Subordinated Bon</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 11:53:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>16 candidates drop out of BCB polls amid claims of ‘naked govt interference’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/cricket/16-candidates-drop-out-of-bcb-polls-amid-claims-of-naked-govt-interference</link><description>Many candidates vying for director posts in the Bangladesh Cricket Board (BCB) elections are set to be elected unopposed. Out of 50 people who filed nomination papers, 16 have withdrawn their candidacies. Out of 30 in the club category, 13 have pulled out of the race.
One of them, Israfil Khosru,</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 12:08:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Islami Bank publishes results of competency assessment test for officials</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/islami-bank-publishes-results-of-competency-assessment-test-for-officials</link><description>The results of the special competency assessment test for officials of Islami Bank Bangladesh PLC were published on Tuesday, according to a press release.
Eighty-eight per cent of the candidates passed this examination, which was administered by the Institute of Business Administration (IBA) of th</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 12:38:07 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>