<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 11:20:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Advisers Council approves four ordinances</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/advisers-council-approves-four-ordinances</link><description>The government on Thursday approved the drafts of four ordinances.
The Council of Advisers gave the final and in-principle approval to the drafts of the ordinances at its weekly meeting at the Chief Adviser’s Office in the city.
Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus chaired the meeting.
T</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 08:27:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Turkey says Lebanon-Cyprus maritime deal violates Turkish Cypriots' rights, is unacceptable</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/turkey-says-lebanon-cyprus-maritime-deal-violates-turkish-cypriots-rights-is-unacceptable</link><description>A maritime demarcation deal signed between Lebanon and Cyprus violates the rights of Turkish Cypriots on the island and is therefore unacceptable, Turkey said on Thursday.
Lebanon and Cyprus on Wednesday signed the long-awaited deal, which aims to pave the way for potential exploration of offshore</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 08:42:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt secondary teachers threaten shutdown, exam boycott</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-secondary-teachers-threaten-shutdown-boycott-of-exams-to-push-for-demands</link><description>Teachers of government secondary schools have gathered at the premises of Shikkha Bhaban, the headquarters of the Directorate of Secondary and Higher Education (DSHE), on Abdul Gani Road in Dhaka to conduct a protest.
They are pressing for four demands, including elevating their pay scale from Gra</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 08:57:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pakistan ex-PM Khan's party demands meeting amid health worries</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/pakistan-ex-pm-khans-party-demands-meeting-amid-health-worries</link><description>The party of Pakistan's jailed former Prime Minister Imran Khan demanded a meeting with him on Thursday, saying it was worried about his health as he has been barred from seeing his family and lawyers for over three weeks.
Khan has been in jail since August 2023, serving a 14-year sentence on corr</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 09:12:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Train hits, kills 11 in China's worst rail accident in over a decade</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/train-hits-kills-11-in-chinas-worst-rail-accident-in-over-a-decade</link><description>A train ran into a group of railway workers in the southwestern Chinese city of Kunming on Thursday, killing 11 and injuring two, officials there said, the country’s deadliest rail accident in more than a decade.
The train, which was testing earthquake detection equipment, hit workers on a c</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 09:27:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>'Like an ocean': Malaysians recall race against rising waters after major flood</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/like-an-ocean-malaysians-recall-race-against-rising-waters-after-major-flood</link><description>Gon Qasim and her husband were about to flee their home in Malaysia's northern Perlis state last weekend when rising floodwaters cut off road access, leaving them stranded in the middle of a field.
The elderly couple were eventually rescued by one of their children living nearby and taken to an ev</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 09:42:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>3.6 magnitude quake jolts Dhaka, other parts of Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/36-magnitude-quake-jolts-dhaka-other-parts-of-bangladesh</link><description>An earthquake measuring 3.6 on the Richter scale was felt in Dhaka and various other parts of the country on Thursday.
There were no immediate reports of casualties or damage. 
The tremor was felt at 4:15 pm today, according to the European-Mediterranean Seismological Centre (EMSC).
This is</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 09:57:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Venezuela revokes flight rights for six airlines amid escalating US tensions</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/venezuela-revokes-flight-rights-for-six-airlines-amid-escalating-us-tensions</link><description>Venezuela has revoked operating rights for six major international airlines which suspended flights to the country following a warning from the US Federal Aviation Administration.
The civil aviation authority revoked permits for Iberia, TAP, Avianca, Latam Colombia, Turkish Airlines and Gol, which</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 10:12:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Soyuz spacecraft blasts off for International Space Station with Russian and American crew</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/soyuz-spacecraft-blasts-off-for-international-space-station-with-russian-and-american-crew</link><description>A Russian Soyuz MS-28 spacecraft blasted off for the International Space Station (ISS) on Thursday with two Russian cosmonauts and one NASA astronaut on board, a live stream of the launch showed.
The Soyuz 2.1a rocket lifted off from the Baikonur Cosmodrome in Kazakhstan at 12:28 pm Moscow time (0</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 10:27:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Arakan Army abducts 12 fishermen on two trawlers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/arakan-army-abducts-12-bangladeshi-fishermen-on-two-trawlers</link><description>Members of Myanmar’s Arakan Army armed insurgent group have captured two trawlers and abducted 12 more fishermen at work in the Bay of Bengal off the coast of Cox’s Bazar’s Teknaf Upazila.
They were abducted while fishing in the sea east of Chheradia on St Martin’s Island o</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 10:42:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh Bank orders pay cuts for Sammilito Islami Bank’s employees</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-bank-orders-pay-cuts-for-sammilito-islami-banks-employees</link><description>Bangladesh Bank has ordered a reduction in the salaries of employees from the five banks that have been merged to form the new ‘Sammilito Islami Bank’ (Combined Islamic Bank).
Sammilito Islami Bank’s Assistant Spokesperson Shahriar Siddiqui on Thursday said, “The decision t</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 10:57:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Beyond our vision, Shilpi's journey gives us hope</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/youth-and-entrepreneurship/beyond-our-vision-shilpis-journey-gives-us-hope</link><description>"Aapu, want to check your weight? Need a pen?" This familiar voice breaks the quiet at Ruqayyah Hall of the University of Dhaka. Some people stop by to buy something, some chat for a bit, and some quietly walk away. 
Behind that simple question is the story of a visually impaired young woman,</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 11:12:05 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>