<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 04:41:44 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>MTB joins global carbon accounting initiative to boost climate transparency</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/mtb-joins-global-carbon-accounting-initiative-to-boost-climate-transparency</link><description>Mutual Trust Bank PLC (MTB) has joined the Partnership for Carbon Accounting Financials as a signatory, reinforcing its commitment to transparency, consistency and accountability in climate-related measurement and reporting.
The bank said the move reflects its intention to align with globally reco</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 01:15:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Most stakeholders look indifferent to campaign</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/most-stakeholders-look-indifferent-to-campaign</link><description>Despite necessity, the issue of campaign on referendum to bring structural reform remains neglected by most of the stakeholders, especially political parties, speakers observed at an event on Thursday.
They also said unless necessary reforms are accomplished the country will continue to face the s</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 01:30:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Civic mourning for Khaleda today</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/civic-mourning-for-khaleda-today</link><description>A civic mourning programme will be held today at the south plaza of the national parliament building to commemorate BNP chairperson and three-time prime minister Khaleda Zia.
Newly appointed BNP chairman Tarique Rahman is expected to attend the programme, organisers said Thursday.
The commemorati</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 01:45:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Claims of Bismillah removal, erasure of Liberation War from charter baseless: Ali Riaz</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/claims-of-bismillah-removal-erasure-of-liberation-war-from-charter-baseless-ali-riaz</link><description>Prof Ali Riaz, special assistant to the Chief Adviser, said claims that Bismillah has been removed from the July National Charter or that the history of the 1971 Liberation War is being erased are unfounded and misleading.
"There is no mention anywhere in the charter about dropping Bismillah or nu</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 02:00:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CPD's Debapriya doubts interim govt's capacity for fair polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cpds-debapriya-doubts-interim-govts-capacity-for-fair-polls</link><description>Distinguished Fellow at the Centre for Policy Dialogue (CPD) Dr Debapriya Bhattacharya on Thursday expressed his doubt about whether the interim government could hold the February elections in a fair manner.
Furthermore, he said, the bureaucracy, which was the main obstacle to the reform agenda, w</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 02:15:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC declares 60 more candidates valid</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ec-declares-60-more-candidates-valid</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) approved 60 more appeals on Thursday, the sixth day of hearings against the Returning Officer's decisions on nomination papers.
A total of 104 appeals were heard during the day.
Of these, 60 appeals against the cancellation of nomination papers were approved, while 29</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 02:30:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Meghna River Master Plan faces many implementation challenges</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/meghna-river-master-plan-faces-many-implementation-challenges</link><description>The Meghna River has ever been an important riverine route for goods transportation as well as an effective option for safe water supply; yet implementation of the master plan for its protection is yet to start due to a good number of challenges.
The Meghna River Master Plan was approved by the Ch</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 02:45:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DU Prof Maksudur Rahman quits National Pay Commission</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/du-prof-maksudur-rahman-quits-national-pay-commission</link><description>Professor Md. Maksudur Rahman Sarkar, chairman of the Department of Accounting at Dhaka University (DU), has resigned from his position as a member of the National Pay Commission-2025, citing the commission's failure to give due importance to the proposals concerning public universities.
He announ</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 03:00:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gopalganj fisherfolk battling to survive</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/gopalganj-fisherfolk-battling-to-survive</link><description>The traditional fishermen community in Gopalganj district is in a tight spot for various challenges, especially waning sources of fish and lack of conservation and trade facilities.
Around 22,000 members of the fishermen community covering five upazilas of the district have been living amid financ</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 03:15:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BPL returns on Friday after day of uncertainty</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/bpl-returns-on-friday-after-day-of-uncertainty</link><description>After a day of uncertainty and tension, Bangladesh cricket received a late-night sigh of relief: the Bangladesh Premier League is set to resume.
BPL Governing Council Secretary Iftekhar Rahman announced at a press briefing that matches will restart on Friday.
He was joined by Cricketers’ We</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 03:30:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mother-daughter found slain in coaching centre</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/mother-daughter-found-slain-in-coaching-centre</link><description>Police recovered the bodies of a mother and her daughter from a room in a coaching centre at Muslimbagh, Keraniganj, on Thursday.
The deceased were identified as Rokeya Negem, 32, and her 14-year-old daughter Fatema, an eighth-grade student, reports UNB.
Keraniganj Model Police Station Officer-in</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 03:45:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Holy Shab-e-Meraj today</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/holy-shab-e-meraj-today</link><description>The holy Shab-e-Meraj will be observed across the country tonight with due respect and religious fervour.
The Muslims every year on the 26th night of the Arabic month of Rajab observe the Shab-e-Meraj. On this night, Prophet Hazrat Muhammad (PBUH) had embarked on a special journey to meet the Almi</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 04:00:47 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>