<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 14:22:36 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>EC lacks ability to enforce electoral code of conduct, says NCP</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ec-lacks-ability-to-enforce-electoral-code-of-conduct-says-ncp</link><description>The National Citizen Party (NCP) has expressed strong support for the Election Commission after the Representation of the People Order (RPO) was amended to require coalition candidates to contest under their own party symbols.
The party says the Commission must remain firm in its stance despite pr</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 12:45:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Three arrested with firearms and bullets in Ctg</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/three-arrested-with-firearms-and-bullets-in-ctg</link><description>Three individuals were arrested in Noapara for possession of weapons and ammunition. 
The arrests were made during a raid in the Chowdhuryhat area of Noapara union in Raozan upazila, BSS reports. 
Additional Superintendent of Police Md. Russell provided details of the operation at a pre</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 13:00:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ex-Islami Bank chairman Obayed sent to prison</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/agrani-bank-fraud-former-islami-bank-chairman-obayed-ullah-sent-to-prison</link><description>Former Islami Bank chairman Obayed Ullah Al Masud has been sent to prison after being arrested in a Tk 1.89 billion loan fraud case linked to Agrani Bank.
Dhaka Metropolitan Senior Special Judge Sabbir Faiz issued the order on Wednesday after a petition from the Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC).</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 11:45:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Akij Resource launches career portal 'nextjobz'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/akij-resource-launches-career-portal-nextjobz</link><description>Bangladesh’s leading business conglomerate AKIJ Resource on Wednesday launched career portal 'nextjobz' (nextjobz.com.bd).
Sheikh Jasim Uddin, managing director of AKIJ Resource, inaugurated the portal at a function held at AKIJ House in Dhaka’s Tejgaon, according to a press release.</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 12:00:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ACC probes Rose Garden acquisition for ‘Tk 3.32b loss’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/acc-investigates-alleged-tk-332b-state-loss-in-2018-rose-garden-acquisition</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) has launched an inquiry into the purchase of Rose Garden on Hrishikesh Das Road in Old Dhaka, alleging a loss of nearly Tk 3.32 billion to the state.
The historic building is where the Awami League, which later led the Liberation War, began its political journe</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 12:15:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Large financial dealings’ linked to Pallabi murder</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/large-financial-dealings-linked-to-pallabi-murder</link><description>The murder of Pallabi Jubo Dal leader Golam Kibria involved not only political rivalry and a struggle for dominance, but also “large financial transactions”, the Rapid Action Battalion (RAB) has said.
Lieutenant Colonel Mahbub Alam, commander of RAB-4, provided the information on Wedne</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 12:30:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Government unveils tribute documentary marking Humayun Ahmed’s birth anniversary</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/entertainment/government-unveils-tribute-documentary-marking-humayun-ahmeds-birth-anniversary</link><description>The interim government has released a documentary paying tribute to celebrated writer Humayun Ahmed on the occasion of his birth anniversary, observed on Nov 13.
State-run news agency Bangladesh Sangbad Sangstha (BSS), citing the Chief Advisor’s Press Wing, reported that the Ministry of Cult</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 12:45:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>French Ambassador meets Jamaat Ameer</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/french-ambassador-meets-jamaat-ameer</link><description>The newly appointed Ambassador of France to Bangladesh, Jean-Marc Sere-Charlet, paid a courtesy call on Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami Ameer Dr. Shafiqur Rahman at his Bashundhara office this afternoon.
The meeting was held in a warm and cordial atmosphere. The Ambassador was accompanied by French Emb</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 13:00:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shahjalal Islami Bank awards scholarships to 300 poor meritorious students</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/shahjalal-islami-bank-awards-scholarships-to-300-poor-meritorious-students</link><description>Shahjalal Islami Bank PLC has provided scholarships to 300 poor and meritorious students who have passed HSC and equivalent examinations from different parts of the country, according to a press release.
They are currently studying in the first year of their degree in various public universities,</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 13:15:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khalilur Rahman discusses bilateral issues in meeting with Ajit Doval</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/khalilur-rahman-discusses-bilateral-issues-in-meeting-with-ajit-doval</link><description>Amid Dhaka’s renewed call for former Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina’s extradition, National Security Adviser (NSA) and High Representative for the Rohingya Issue Dr Khalilur Rahman on Wednesday met National Security Adviser of India Ajit Doval in New Delhi.
“They discussed work of</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 13:30:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dengue: 6 die, 788 hospitalised</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dengue-6-die-788-hospitalised</link><description>Six more people have died of dengue fever in Bangladesh, while 788 new patients have been admitted to hospitals with the disease in the past 24 hours.
The total number of hospitalisations from the Aedes mosquito-borne illness this year has reached 87,712, with 17,450 patients admitted in November</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 13:45:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>National footballers made every Bangladeshi proud: Prof Yunus</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/national-footballers-made-every-bangladeshi-proud-prof-yunus</link><description>Chief Adviser Prof Muhammad Yunus has congratulated the Bangladesh national football team on their impressive 1-0 win over India in the AFC Asian Cup qualifiers, noting that the victory has made every Bangladeshi proud.
“This victory has made every Bangladeshi proud of. This is not just a vi</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 14:00:52 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>