<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 16:29:44 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Kosovo’s ‘political earthquake’ election sees Kurti resurgent</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/kosovos-political-earthquake-election-sees-kurti-resurgent</link><description>An emphatic election victory for Kosovo’s Prime Minister Albin Kurti marks a resurgence for the nationalist leader, ending a political deadlock in Europe’s youngest state and potentially determining its domestic and international agenda for years.
The win strengthens Kurti’s mand</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 13:59:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nomination papers submitted peacefully ahead of Bangladesh election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nomination-papers-submitted-peacefully-ahead-of-bangladesh-election</link><description>Candidates across the country submitted their nomination papers on Monday before the 5:00 pm deadline in a calm and orderly atmosphere for the upcoming national election billed for February 12.
Most aspirants submitted their nomination papers on the final day. A total of 3,144 nomination papers we</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 14:14:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Taxpayers must notify by Jan 15 if unable to file e-return</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/taxpayers-must-notify-by-jan-15-if-unable-to-file-e-return</link><description>Taxpayers struggling with online income tax returns have until Jan 15 to request permission for alternate filing from their tax offices.
The National Board of Revenue (NBR) issued an order on Monday setting the deadline for applications from taxpayers unable to submit e-returns.
Earlier, the onli</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 14:29:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No compromise on question of justice: Hasnat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/no-compromise-on-question-of-justice-hasnat</link><description>There will be no compromise on the issue of justice (Insaaf), said Hasnat Abdullah, chief organiser of the southern region of the National Citizen Party (NCP), on Monday.
“We will work to establish a just Bangladesh,” he said while talking to reporters after filing his nomination paper</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 14:44:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Crude bomb attack on BNP protest triggers turmoil in Bhola</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/crude-bomb-attack-on-bnp-protest-triggers-turmoil-in-bhola</link><description>Bhola town has descended into chaos after crude bombs were hurled at a protest of the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) demanding justice for its slain student leader Rezwan Amin Sifat.
Police fired blank shots to bring the situation under control after the Bangladesh Jatiya Party (BJP) office at</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 14:59:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nahid Islam files nomination papers for Dhaka-11 constituency</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/nahid-islam-files-nomination-papers-for-dhaka-11-constituency</link><description>National Citizen Party (NCP) Convenor Nahid Islam has submitted his nomination papers to run from Dhaka-11 constituency in the parliamentary polls.
Dhaka-11 comprises Rampura, Badda, Bhatara and parts of Hatirjheel.
The nomination papers were submitted to the Office of the Divisional Commissioner</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 14:29:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>5 Dhaka seats attract 44 nominations</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/44-candidates-file-nomination-papers-in-five-dhaka-seats</link><description>A total of 44 candidates have submitted nomination papers for five constituencies in Dhaka ahead of the parliamentary elections.
Dhaka District Administrator and Returning Officer Md Rezaul Karim released the figures after the Monday deadline.
Speaking at a press briefing, he said: “Eight c</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 14:44:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shut down University Teachers’ Network: RUCSU GS</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rucsu-gs-ammar-calls-for-university-teachers-network-to-be-shut-down</link><description>Rajshahi University Central Student Union General Secretary Salahuddin Ammar has called for the University Teachers’ Network to be shut down.
He made this call in response to a statement made by the platform on Sunday titled “Stop the unauthorised activities of student representatives</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 14:59:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Stocks extend losses for second day at DSE</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/stocks-extend-losses-for-second-day-at-dse</link><description>Bangladesh’s stock market continued its downward trend for the second consecutive session on Monday, with key indices falling at the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) and losses also recorded at the Chittagong Stock Exchange (CSE).
At the DSE, the benchmark DSEX index shed 7 points, while the Shari</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 15:14:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>JnUCSU election on Tuesday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/jnucsu-election-on-tuesday</link><description>The Jagannath University Central Students’ Union (JnUCSU) and Hall Students’ Union elections will be held on Tuesday.
Voting will start at 9:00 am and continue until 3:00 pm without any break.
A total of 16,500 students are expected to exercise their voting rights at 178 booths across</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 15:29:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>39 candidates file nominations in Gopalganj</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/39-candidates-file-nominations-in-gopalganj</link><description>A total of 39 candidates submitted nomination papers for three parliamentary seats in Gopalganj till Monday, the final day for filing nominations for the 13th national election.
Despite a cold wave, the offices of the district commissioner and returning officer, as well as the election office, saw</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 15:44:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Health protection scheme launched for urban sanitation workers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/health-protection-scheme-launched-for-urban-sanitation-workers</link><description>The Dhaka North City Corporation (DNCC), in collaboration with SAJIDA Foundation and Harpic, on Sunday launched Shasthya Nirapotta Scheme (SNS), a health insurance policy, for its sanitation workers, aiming to improve their access to healthcare services.
Under the scheme, sanitation workers will b</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 15:59:48 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>