<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 20:37:38 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>The people hold the power now</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/the-people-hold-the-power-now</link><description>On the same day voters choose their representatives in the upcoming national parliamentary elections, a crucial and arguably more consequential vote on constitutional reforms will also take place. This referendum could well prove to be a turning point for democracy. Yet while the election dominates</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 17:26:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dealing with emerging EU, USA trade issues</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/dealing-with-emerging-eu-usa-trade-issues</link><description>A Free Trade Agreement (FTA) signed between the European Union (EU) and India a week back and the reduction of US reciprocal tariff on India from 50 per cent to only 18 per cent have evidently heightened concerns in Bangladesh about safeguarding its trade preferences in the two major export markets</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 17:41:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BGB deployed in 8 upazilas of Khagrachhari for election security</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bgb-deployed-in-8-upazilas-of-khagrachhari-for-election-security</link><description>Border Guard Bangladesh (BGB) has been deployed in eight of the nine upazilas of Khagrachhari district to ensure election security ahead of the upcoming 13th national parliamentary polls.
The information was disclosed on Friday during a press briefing at the Panchhari Logang Zone office ground by</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 17:56:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique pledges to prioritise 'sovereignty, citizens’ welfare' while fostering global partnerships</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-pledges-to-prioritise-sovereignty-citizens-welfare-while-fostering-global-partnerships</link><description>BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman has promised to conduct foreign policy prioritising the “interests of the country and its people” if his party wins the parliamentary elections and forms a government after two decades.
He emphasised that Bangladesh’s independence and sovereignty will</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 18:11:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat leaders visit injured Inquilab Mancha supporters at DMCH</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jamaat-leaders-visit-injured-inquilab-mancha-supporters-at-dmch</link><description>Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami Assistant Secretary General Advocate Ahsanul Mahboob Zubair visited the injured protesters of Inquilab Mancha including its member secretary Abdullah Al Jaber at Dhaka Medical College hospital.
During their visit, Advocate Zubair, also chief of Jamaat media and publicity</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 18:26:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Inqilab Moncho reoccupies Shahbagh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/inqilab-moncho-protesters-return-to-shahbagh-blockade-after-dispersal</link><description>Inqilab Moncho activists have returned to block Shahbagh intersection after being dispersed earlier and engaging in prolonged chases with police.
On Friday after 9pm, the protesters moved back onto the key Dhaka road after police withdrew from the area, ending nearly one and a half hours of back a</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 18:41:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DUCSU calls off rally on Inqilab Moncho request</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ducsu-suspends-mass-gathering-after-request-from-inqilab-moncho</link><description>The Dhaka University Central Students' Union (DUCSU) has suspended its scheduled "mass gathering" following a direct request from Inqilab Moncho as clashes with police continue to rock the capital.
DUCSU General Secretary SM Farhad announced the decision during a press conference outside the DUCSU</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 18:56:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Conjoined twins born in Chandpur, referred to DMCH</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/conjoined-twins-born-in-chandpur-referred-to-dmch</link><description>A woman gave birth to conjoined twins in Chandpur on Thursday night. The newborn is currently admitted to Crescent Hospital in Chandpur town.
The mother, Sumi Akter, gave birth to the child via cesarean section. Her husband, Masud Gazi, is a daily wage laborer. The family resides in Purbo Borali v</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 19:11:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Security, voter participation, level playing field: EU's 3 areas of focus in election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/security-voter-participation-level-playing-field-eus-3-areas-of-focus-in-election</link><description>The European Union (EU) said it will focus on three key areas while observing Bangladesh’s upcoming 13th parliamentary election.
EU election observation mission chief and European Parliament member Ivars Ijabs told journalists at a roundtable meeting at Sylhet District Press Club on Friday t</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 19:26:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>White House deletes racist Trump post depicting Obamas as apes</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/white-house-deletes-racist-trump-post-depicting-obamas-as-apes</link><description>A video shared on Donald Trump's social media account that depicted Democratic former President Barack Obama and first lady Michelle Obama as apes was deleted on Friday, following criticism that the US president's post evoked racist imagery long used to dehumanise people of African descent.
"A Whi</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 19:41:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BD, Japan sign full-fledged deal on economic partnership</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bd-japan-sign-full-fledged-deal-on-economic-partnership</link><description>Bangladesh and Japan Friday signed a landmark Economic Partnership Agreement (EPA) that ushers in a new era of bilateral trade and investment cooperation and marks Dhaka's first such comprehensive pact with any country.



Under the agreement, Japan will grant 100-percent duty-free access to 7,</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 19:56:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP pledges economic, political democratisation if voted to power</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-pledges-economic-political-democratisation-if-voted-to-power</link><description>Economic and political democratisation free from oligarchs, higher foreign direct investment (FDI), financial-sector reforms, capital-market development and trade liberalisation are central to BNP vision for rebuilding a "fragile economy".



Chairman of the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) T</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 20:11:25 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>