<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 12:54:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Election violence: 15 injured in BNP-Jamaat clash in Bhola</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/election-violence-15-injured-in-bnp-jamaat-clash-in-bhola</link><description>At least 15 people have been injured in a clash between supporters of the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) and Jamaat-e-Islami during election campaigning in Bhola's Borhanuddin Upazila.
The violence broke out on Saturday morning in Tobgi Union's Mulaipattan village, according to Borhanuddin Pol</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 10:01:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Six int'l organisations to deploy 63 observers for Bangladesh elections</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/six-intl-organisations-to-deploy-63-observers-for-bangladesh-elections</link><description>Six international organisations, including the Organisation of Islamic Cooperation (OIC), have agreed to deploy at least 63 observers for Bangladesh’s 13th general election and the referendum on the July National Charter, both scheduled for February.
They will join observer missions from the</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 09:35:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No Islamic basis for Jamaat vote claim: Fakhrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/claim-that-voting-for-jamaat-will-lead-to-heaven-has-no-basis-in-islam-fakhrul</link><description>BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir has urged voters not to support those who use religion in politics.
Fakhrul, who is contesting the Thakurgaon-1 constituency in the upcoming parliamentary election, made the comment while attending an election rally at Akcha Union in Sadar Upazila</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 09:50:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Thousands flee northwest Pakistan after mosques warn of possible military action</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/thousands-flee-northwest-pakistan-after-mosques-warn-of-possible-military-action</link><description>Tens of thousands of people have fled a remote mountainous region in northwestern Pakistan in recent weeks, residents said, after warnings broadcast from mosques urged families to evacuate ahead of a possible military action against Islamist militants.
Residents of the Tirah Valley, in the Pakista</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 10:05:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Israeli strikes kill 12 in Gaza, health ministry says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/israeli-strikes-kill-12-in-gaza-health-ministry-says</link><description>Israeli airstrikes in Gaza killed at least 12 people, the Palestinian health ministry said, with children reported to be among the fatalities in the latest violence rattling a tenuous ceasefire.
One airstrike hit an apartment in Gaza City killing three children and two women, according to a family</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 10:20:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BGB asked to avoid lethal weapons during election duty</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bgb-asked-to-avoid-lethal-weapons-during-election-duty</link><description>Bangladesh’s Border Guard (BGB) has been instructed not to use lethal weapons while performing security duties during the country’s national election and referendum, senior officials have said.
More than 37,000 BGB members will be deployed across the country to help maintain law and or</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 10:35:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tangail prepares to welcome BNP chief Tarique Rahman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tangail-prepares-to-welcome-bnp-chief-tarique-rahman</link><description>BNP leaders and activists in Tangail are ready to welcome the party’s chief Tarique Rahman, who is en route to the district to deliver his first-ever speech at an election rally.
On Saturday, the party’s leaders and activists, as well as people from across the district and its adjacent</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 10:50:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka Trade Fair wraps up with Tk 4.0 billion in sales</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/dhaka-trade-fair-wraps-up-with-tk-40-billion-in-sales</link><description>The Dhaka International Trade Fair, the country’s flagship trade showcase, closed after a month on Saturday with sales of nearly Tk 4.0 billion, underscoring steady domestic demand despite pressure from inflation and a slowing economy, according to the Export Promotion Bureau.
At the closing</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 11:05:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP to ensure fee institutional internet, if voted to power: Mahdi Amin</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-to-ensure-fee-institutional-internet-if-voted-to-power-mahdi-amin</link><description>Adviser to the BNP Chairman and the party's Election Steering Committee Spokesperson Dr Mahdi Amin today (Saturday) said that if the party comes to power, free institutional internet facilities will be ensured for all. 
He said, "BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman has announced plans to gradually pr</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 11:20:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cuba declares "international emergency" in response to US executive order</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/cuba-declares-international-emergency-in-response-to-us-executive-order</link><description>Cuban Foreign Minister Bruno Rodriguez Parrilla said Friday that Cuba has declared an "international emergency" in response to a recent executive order of tariff threats issued by US President Donald Trump.
Rodriguez said in a post on X that the Cuban people, with the solidarity of the internation</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 11:35:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Power gel, detonators seized from abandoned Sylhet school</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rab-recovers-power-gel-detonators-from-deserted-primary-school-building-in-sylhet</link><description>The Rapid Action Battalion (RAB) has recovered 25 power gel sticks and 27 electric detonators from an abandoned school building in Sylhet’s Kanaighat Upazila, materials the force described as being used to make “high-grade explosives”.
The items were recovered on Friday night fro</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 11:50:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique pledges to export handloom goods worldwide if elected</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-pledges-to-export-handloom-goods-worldwide-if-elected</link><description>BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman has pledged to take Bangladesh’s handloom products to global markets, saying his party would launch export initiatives for the sector if it forms the government.
Speaking at an election rally at the Bangladesh Small and Cottage Industries Corporation (BSCIC) Indus</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 12:05:42 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>