<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 11:21:57 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>No uncertainty over national election, reaffirms CEC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/no-uncertainty-over-national-election-reaffirms-cec</link><description>Chief Election Commissioner AMM Nasir Uddin on Monday reaffirmed that there is no uncertainty over the upcoming national election as it will be held in free, fair and competitive manners on time, reports UNB.
 
"InshaAllah, rest assured-- we will rightly see a fair, nice and competitive elec</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 08:33:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh needs strong diplomatic engagement to delay LDC graduation, says RAPID chief</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/bangladesh-needs-strong-diplomatic-engagement-to-delay-ldc-graduation-says-rapid-chief</link><description>Bangladesh needs strong diplomatic engagement to delay its graduation from the Least Developed Country (LDC) category, as the country is likely to face multiple post-graduation challenges without adequate preparation, said Dr Mohammad Abdur Razzaque, chairman of the Research and Policy Integration</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 08:48:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bullet-hit Hadi airlifted to Singapore</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bullet-hit-hadi-airlifted-to-singapore</link><description>The air ambulance, equipped with all emergency facilities for a critical patient, departed Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport carrying bullet-hit Dhaka-8 aspiring independent candidate Sharif Osman Hadi to Singapore for advanced treatment on Monday.
The ambulance, operated by Aspro Aviation, t</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 09:03:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt to procure one cargo LNG</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/govt-to-procure-one-cargo-lng</link><description>The Advisory Council Committee on Government Purchase has recommended the procurement of one cargo of liquefied natural gas (LNG) from the international spot market to meet the country’s growing energy demand.
The decision was taken in a meeting of the committee at the Cabinet Division Confe</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 09:04:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two killed in road crashes in Jhalakathi, Pirojpur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/two-killed-in-road-crashes-in-jhalakathi-pirojpur</link><description>Two people have been killed in separate road accidents in Jhalakathi and Pirojpur districts.
In Jhalakathi, a woman was killed, and her husband was injured when a trolley hit their motorbike in the Lakshman Kathi area in Nalchiti upazila of the district on Monday.
The deceased was identified as L</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 09:19:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Traffic diversions in Dhaka for Victory Day celebrations</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/traffic-diversions-in-dhaka-for-victory-day-celebrations</link><description>Traffic diversions will be enforced at Gabtoli and Bypile points on the Dhaka-Ashulia and Dhaka-Aricha highways on the occasion of the Great Victory Day.
According to the Superintendent of Police, Dhaka, the diversions will remain in effect from 3:00 am to 9:00 am on December 16, BSS reports.&amp;nbsp</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 09:34:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Midland Bank Family provides financial assistance of Tk 10 Lac to Bengal Institute</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/midland-bank-family-provides-financial-assistance-of-tk-10-lac-to-bengal-institute</link><description>Midland Bank Family provided financial assistance of Tk 10.00 Lac to Bengal Institute for the comprehensive publication on the work and life of Architect Muzharul Islam.
The bank provided Tk 5.00 lac financial assistance from its Islami Banking Fund under its Corporate Social Responsibilities (CSR</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 09:49:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Anis Alamgir arrested in anti-state conspiracy case</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/anis-alamgir-arrested-in-anti-state-conspiracy-case-actress-shaon-accused</link><description>Journalist Anis Alamgir, actress Meher Afroz Shaon, and four others have been named in a case filed at Uttara West Police Station, accusing them of conspiring to destabilise the state and inciting a banned organisation. Anis has also been shown arrested in the case.
Shahriar Ali, deputy police com</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 10:04:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Safe, quality shrimp production must be prioritised: Adviser Farida</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/safe-quality-shrimp-production-must-be-prioritised-adviser-farida</link><description>Fisheries and Livestock Adviser Farida Akhter on Monday stressed the need for ensuring safe and high-quality shrimp production alongside increasing output.
Speaking at a dialogue session with leaseholders and farmers at a 48-acre demonstration shrimp farm in Rampur Mouza, Badarkhali Union, Chakari</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 10:19:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Student protesters leave Shahbagh after 3 hours</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/student-protesters-leave-shahbagh-after-three-hours</link><description>The Jatiya Chhatra Shakti, the student wing of National Citizen Party (NCP), has suspended the blockade at the Shahbagh intersection in Dhaka demanding the resignation of the home affairs advisor following the shooting of Inqilab Moncho Convenor Osman Sharif Hadi.
After blocking the Shahbagh inter</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 10:34:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>German regulator orders oversight, limits on online bank N26</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/german-regulator-orders-oversight-limits-on-online-bank-n26</link><description>Germany's financial regulator BaFin on Monday announced stricter oversight of Berlin-based online bank N26, including limits on new business in the Netherlands and the instalment of a special monitor, after finding lapses in compliance by the lender.
The measures mark the second time since 2021 th</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 10:49:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US demands EU exempt its gas from methane emissions law</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/us-demands-eu-exempt-its-gas-from-methane-emissions-law-document-shows</link><description>The United States has demanded that the European Union exempt its oil and gas from obligations under the bloc's methane emissions law on fuel imports until 2035, a US government document seen by Reuters showed.
Starting this year, the EU requires importers of oil and gas to Europe to monitor and r</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 11:04:51 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>