<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 05:27:32 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Primary school teacher recruitment exam to be held on Jan 9</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/primary-school-teacher-recruitment-exam-to-be-held-on-jan-9</link><description>The postponed written exam for assistant teacher recruitment in government primary schools will be held on Jan 9.
The Directorate of Primary Education (DPE) said on Tuesday that the exam will be held at the same time on the new date at the designated venue.
The recruitment exam was scheduled to b</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 17:45:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pakistan’s Speaker to attend Khaleda Zia’s funeral</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/pakistans-speaker-to-attend-khaleda-zias-funeral</link><description>Sardar Ayaz Sadiq, Speaker of Pakistan’s National Assembly, will represent Pakistan at the funeral of former Prime Minister and BNP Chairperson Begum Khaleda Zia on Wednesday.
The announcement was confirmed by Pakistan’s Deputy Prime Minister Ishaq Dar through his verified X account.</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 18:00:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>51 parties to contest in polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/51-parties-to-contest-in-polls</link><description>In the general election, 2,090 candidates from 51 political parties have submitted nomination papers, while 478 seek to run as independent candidates.
Among these parties, the BNP has the highest number of candidates in 300 seats, with 331 nominations submitted.
The Jamaat-e-Islami has fielded th</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 18:15:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>JU announces results of ‘A’ unit admission test</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/ju-announces-results-of-a-unit-admission-test</link><description>Jahangirnagar University (JU) has published the results of the 2025–26 academic year admission test for the first-year undergraduate (honours) batch-55 ‘A’ unit, which includes the Faculty of Mathematical and Physical Sciences and the Institute of Information Technology.
The resu</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 18:30:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nation bereft of a great guardian when most needed: CA</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nation-bereft-of-a-great-guardian-when-most-needed-ca</link><description>The head of interim government, Prof Muhammad Yunus, expressed profound sorrow at the death of BNP chairperson Begum Khaleda Zia, a three-time former Prime Minister and symbol of democratic movement, when her guardianship was most needed.



He urges everyone to stay "vigilant so no one can att</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 19:46:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A life of resolve and resistance</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/a-life-of-resolve-and-resistance</link><description>We have lost one of the towering figures of Bangladesh's political history -- Begum Khaleda Zia. The first female prime minister of the country, she slipped into eternal silence on Tuesday in Dhaka at the age of 79 after battling a prolonged illness. With her demise, an era characterised by uncompr</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 02:15:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Democratic, economic reset under Khaleda Zia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/democratic-economic-reset-under-khaleda-zia</link><description>When Bangladesh returned to democracy in 1991 after nearly a decade of authoritarian rule, the moment carried both relief and expectation.
At the centre of that transition stood Begum Khaleda Zia, who not only became the country's first female prime minister and the second woman head of government</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 02:30:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Central bank buys another $89m from banks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/central-bank-buys-another-89m-from-banks</link><description>The Bangladesh Bank purchased $89 million more through auction from seven banks in the interbank spot market on Tuesday, aiming to keep the exchange rate of the US dollar against the local currency stable.
The purchase was made under the Multiple Price Auction method, and the cutoff rate was Tk 12</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 02:45:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DU observing 3-day mourning over Khaleda Zia's demise</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/du-observing-3-day-mourning-over-khaleda-zias-demise</link><description>Dhaka University has declared a three-day period of mourning in honour of former Prime Minister and BNP Chairperson Begum Khaleda Zia who passed away at 6am on Tuesday.
The mourning will be observed from Tuesday (30 December) to Thursday (1 January).
During this period, all classes and examinatio</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 03:00:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NRBs urged to shift from remittance to investment</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/nrbs-urged-to-shift-from-remittance-to-investment</link><description>Foreign Affairs Adviser Mohammad Touhid Hossain has urged non-resident Bangladeshis (NRBs) to move beyond their traditional role as remittance senders and play a more direct part in investment, employment generation and skills development.
This shift is essential for Bangladesh's long-term economi</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 03:15:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sammilito Islami Bank to decide fate of subsidiaries after merger</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/sammilito-islami-bank-to-decide-fate-of-subsidiaries-after-merger</link><description>Sammilito Islami Bank, which emerged from the merger of five Islamic banks, will decide whether to close the banks' subsidiaries or keep their businesses running, according to the central bank.
The decision will be based on a feasibility study, sources at the Bangladesh Bank (BB) said.
"The subsi</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 04:15:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>27 BGB platoons deployed in Dhaka around Khaleda Zia’s janaza, burial</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/27-bgb-platoons-deployed-in-dhaka-around-khaleda-zias-janaza-burial</link><description>Twenty seven platoons of Border Guard Bangladesh (BGB) have been deployed at key points of Dhaka to ensure tight security around the janaza and burial of BNP Chairperson and former Prime Minister Begum Khaleda Zia.
Md Shariful Islam, public relations officer of the BGB headquarters, said the deplo</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 04:30:48 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>