<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 08:35:16 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Plot graft: Rehana, Tulip get jail terms alongside Hasina</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/plot-graft-rehana-british-mp-tulip-get-jail-terms-alongside-hasina</link><description>A Dhaka court has delivered its verdict in another corruption case against ousted prime minister Sheikh Hasina and her family members over the allocation of plots in the Purbachal New Town project.
Alongside Hasina, the court has also found her sister Sheikh Rehana and Rehana’s daughter, Bri</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 05:44:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka College students block Science Lab intersection</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dhaka-college-students-block-science-lab-intersection</link><description>A group of Dhaka College students have blocked the Science Laboratory intersection to press for the repeal of the Dhaka Central University ordinance.
New Market Police Station chief AKM Mahfuzul Haque said the demonstration began around 10:30 am on Monday when higher secondary students of the coll</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 05:59:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BTCL gets approval for virtual network operator</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/btcl-gets-approval-for-virtual-network-operator</link><description>Bangladesh Telecommunications Company Limited (BTCL) has received approval to operate experimentally as a Mobile Virtual Network Operator (MVNO) in the country.
Faiz Ahmad Taiyeb, chief advisor's special assistant on ICT, shared the development in a Facebook post on Sunday, reports bdnews24.com.</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 06:14:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Reza Kibria joins BNP</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/reza-kibria-joins-bnp</link><description>Reza Kibria, an economist and founder-convener of the political platform Gono Odhikar Parishad, has formally joined the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP).
He announced his joining on Monday at the political office of BNP Chairperson Khaleda Zia in Gulshan.
BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Isl</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 06:29:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Medical technologists, pharmacists threaten nationwide shutdown</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/medical-technologists-pharmacists-threaten-nationwide-shutdown</link><description>Medical technologists and pharmacists across Bangladesh have threatened a nationwide shutdown of healthcare services if their salaries are not upgraded to the 10th grade of the national pay scale -- a demand they say has remained unmet for more than three decades.
To press home their demand, profe</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 06:44:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nepal announces $200,000 in financial aid to flood-hit Sri Lanka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/nepal-announces-200000-in-financial-aid-to-flood-hit-sri-lanka</link><description>The Nepali government has announced financial aid of 200,000 US dollars for Sri Lanka to support relief and recovery efforts for people badly affected by recent floods.
Heavy rainfall and flooding triggered by Cyclone Ditwah in the past few days have resulted in the deaths of at least 334 people,</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 06:59:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Garment scraps gutted in Gazipur fire</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/garment-scraps-gutted-in-gazipur-fire-145654</link><description>A fire gutted a large quantity of jhut (garment scraps) at a warehouse in Konabari area of Gazipur on Monday.
According to the Fire Service and local sources, the fire broke out around 5:30 am at the jhut warehouse owned by Palash Mia in Amragh Purbapara area of Konabari.
Locals initially tried t</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 06:45:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Indonesia floods death toll rises to 442</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/indonesia-floods-death-toll-rises-to-442</link><description>The death toll from recent floods and landslides across three provinces on Indonesia's Sumatra Island has risen to 442, the National Disaster Management Agency (BNPB) said on Sunday.
BNPB Chief Suharyanto said at a press briefing that North Sumatra recorded the highest number of casualties. "The n</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 07:00:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Share market slips in early trading at DSE, CSE</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/share-market-slips-in-early-trading-at-dse-cse</link><description>The Dhaka Stock Exchange and the Chittagong Stock Exchange began the first trading hour on Monday with a downward trend, as the share prices of most listed companies declined.
At the DSE, the benchmark DSEX index fell by 29 points, while the Shariah-based DSES dropped 5 points and the blue-chip DS</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 07:15:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ship operations on Cox's Bazar-St. Martin route begin</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/ship-operations-on-coxs-bazar-st-martin-route-begin</link><description>After a nine-month closure, the Cox's Bazar-St. Martin's route has resumed its tourist traffic from December 1. On the first day of the season, Monday, MV Bar Aulia, MV Karnaphuli and Keary Sindabad set off for St Martin's from the Nuniarachara BIWTA jetty at 7 am.
 
Additional passenger con</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 07:30:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sammilito Islami Bank gets its first chairman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/sammilito-islami-bank-gets-its-first-chairman</link><description>Former senior secretary Dr Mohammad Ayub Mia has been appointed chairman of the newly-formed Sammilito Islami Bank PLC, which was created by merging five financially weak banks in the country.
Bangladesh Bank gave the approval of his appointment on Sunday, reports UNB.
The central bank said the S</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 07:45:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rice drives nearly half of October food inflation, GED reports</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/rice-drives-nearly-half-of-october-food-inflation-ged-reports</link><description>Rice accounted for about 47 per cent of total food inflation in October, while vegetables had a strong negative impact because of seasonal abundance, according to the Economic Update and Outlook for November 2025 prepared by the General Economics Division (GED).
Protein items — including bee</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 08:00:54 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>