<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 03:44:40 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>BPL in Jeopardy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bpl-in-jeopardy-players-threaten-total-strike-if-a-board-director-doesnt-step-down-by-thursday-1-pm</link><description>The crisis within Bangladesh cricket has reached a boiling point as the country’s cricketers have issued a stern ultimatum— if Bangladesh Cricket Board (BCB) Director M Nazmul Islam does not resign by 1:00 PM on Thursday, players will boycott all forms of cricket immediately.
The annou</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 18:34:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How RADP will impact development work</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/how-radp-will-impact-development-work</link><description>Downsizing the annual development programme (ADP) halfway in a fiscal year has been a routine practice in this country. This year is no exception to the rule. The original development budget of Tk 2.30 trillion in the current fiscal year has been pared down to Tk 2.0 trillion. Compared with the imm</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 18:49:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BSEC restores IPO lottery system to ensure transparency</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/bsec-restores-ipo-lottery-system-to-ensure-transparency</link><description>The securities regulator has reinstated the process of allotting IPO (initial public offering) shares through a lottery system, reversing a previous shift to a pro-rata allocation method.
This decision is part of the revised Bangladesh Securities and Exchange Commission (Public Offer of Equity Sec</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 00:32:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Steps underway to bring discipline in gold, jewellery sector: NBR chairman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/steps-underway-to-bring-discipline-in-gold-jewellery-sector-nbr-chairman</link><description>The National Board of Revenue (NBR) is working to bring about discipline in the country's gold and jewellery sector, long plagued by smuggling, weak compliance and regulatory loopholes, NBR Chairman Abdur Rahman Khan has said.
Most of the gold enters Bangladesh through illegal channels, he said, a</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 00:47:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>73 more aspirants get back candidacies</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/73-more-aspirants-get-back-candidacies</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) on Wednesday approved candidacies of 73 more aspirants on the fifth day of hearings on appeals filed against returning officers' decisions over the scrutiny of nomination papers for the 13th national parliamentary election.
The verdicts were delivered during hearings h</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 01:02:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Strengthen BSC fleet to bolster footprint on global shipping</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/strengthen-bsc-fleet-to-bolster-footprint-on-global-shipping</link><description>Strengthen Bangladesh Shipping Corporation to bolster its footprint on global shipping routes and protect the country's maritime interests, the Chief Adviser instructs as BSC begins booking higher profits.
Professor Muhammad Yunus gave the direction Wednesday while receiving payments from the corp</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 01:17:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DUCSU launches campaign to mobilise public support for 'Yes' vote</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ducsu-launches-campaign-to-mobilise-public-support-for-yes-vote</link><description>The Dhaka University Central Students' Union (DUCSU) has announced a month-long nationwide campaign to draw public support for a 'Yes' vote in the upcoming national referendum, describing it as a crucial step toward implementing reforms of the state structure.
The programme was unveiled at a press</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 01:32:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Move to put a cap on significant shareholding faces stiff opposition</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/move-to-put-a-cap-on-significant-shareholding-faces-stiff-opposition</link><description>A move to put a limit on shareholding in bank companies by individuals, family members, and entities is facing strong opposition from the stakeholders, officials say.
The central bank in a draft for amending the bank company act has proposed that individuals, family members, and entities directly</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 01:47:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DMP directs field-level officers to intensify intelligence gathering</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dmp-directs-field-level-officers-to-intensify-intelligence-gathering</link><description>The Dhaka Metropolitan Police (DMP) has directed field-level officers to step up intelligence gathering and take preventive measures against those suspected of trying to create disorder during the upcoming 13th national election and referendum "before any incident happens".
The directive was given</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 02:02:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>RUET congratulates its VC Abdur Razzak</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/ruet-congratulates-its-vc-abdur-razzak</link><description>The authority of Rajshahi University of Engineering and Technology (RUET) has extended heartfelt congratulations to Vice-Chancellor (VC) Professor Dr. S. M. Abdur Razzak on his appointment as the President of the Bangladesh University Council (BUC).
In a recent meeting of the BUC, an organisation</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 02:17:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mango farmers cheerful for early blossoms; but downbeat for cold</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/mango-farmers-cheerful-for-early-blossoms-but-downbeat-for-cold</link><description>Mango growers in Rajshahi are optimistic as early blossoms have begun appearing in orchards even before the end of winter, raising hopes for a good harvest this season.
However, persistent cold weather combined with dense fog has also triggered concern over possible disease outbreaks that could th</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 02:32:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Economic growth may slow to 4.6pc this FY</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/economic-growth-may-slow-to-46pc-this-fy</link><description>Bangladesh economy may expand at a rate of 4.6 per cent in the current fiscal year in a further 0.3-percentage-point fall from the level predicted in June 2025, says the World Bank in an update.
With this downgrading, the global development financier cut the country's economic-growth forecast for</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 02:47:32 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>