<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 07:20:17 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>JU renames four halls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/ju-renames-four-halls</link><description>The Jahangirnagar University (JU) authority officially renamed four residential halls, previously linked to Sheikh Hasina and her family members. The decision was finalised at a Syndicate meeting on Friday, confirmed Acting Registrar A B M Azizur Rahman.
According to the decision, Sheikh Mujibur R</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 03:41:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CU student found dead</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cu-student-found-dead</link><description>Police recovered the hanging body of a Chittagong University (CU) student from a house in the Khulshi area of Chattogram on Thursday night.
The victim was identified as Omar Faruk Sumon, a student of the Arabic Department of CU.
Police sources said Sumon's body was found hanging from a ceiling-fa</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 03:56:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BTB asks customs not to allow any tea import consignment</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/btb-asks-customs-not-to-allow-any-tea-import-consignment</link><description>The Bangladesh Tea Board (BTB) has requested the customs authorities not to allow any tea import consignments without prior approval from the regulator, sources said
The move comes amid growing concerns over the influx of foreign tea brands into local super shops despite having no official permiss</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 04:11:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>National SME Products Fair kicks off in city tomorrow</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/national-sme-products-fair-kicks-off-in-city-tomorrow</link><description>The 12th National SME Products Fair, the largest event of 100 per cent domestic products, will kick off tomorrow (Sunday) in the city's Bangladesh-China Friendship Conference Centre.
The SME Foundation under the Ministry of Industries is organising the fair.
SME Foundation Chairperson Md Mushfiqu</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 04:26:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ctg port extends suspension of four-fold penal rent on imported FCL containers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ctg-port-extends-suspension-of-four-fold-penal-rent-on-imported-fcl-containers</link><description>CHATTOGRAM, Dec 05: The Chittagong Port Authority (CPA) has again extended the suspension of its four-fold penal rent on imported full container load (FCL) units at both Chittagong Port and Dhaka's Kamalapur ICD, aiming to ease pressure on traders and keep cargo movement steady through the year-end</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 04:41:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Freight forwarding in economic policy: Overlooked but indispensable</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/analysis/freight-forwarding-in-economic-policy-overlooked-but-indispensable</link><description>Freight Forwarders are considered as the architects of international trade logistics. They organise and coordinate the carriage of goods from origin to destination through the maze of customs regulations, multimodal transport systems, and intricate supply chains. In today's world of globalisation,</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 04:56:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Garba Labiyat: Two days in hospitality of rural CHT life</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/analysis/garba-labiyat-two-days-in-hospitality-of-rural-cht-life</link><description>It's a refreshing, busy, and truly once-in-a-lifetime experience, at least for now. I have just returned from Rangamati backwoods. Even after reaching Dhaka, the flashbacks are constantly running through my mind. I feel an urge to write them down, to put these thoughts into words, in hope that ever</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 05:11:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Muggers stab man to death on Gazipur flyover</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/muggers-stab-man-to-death-on-gazipur-flyover</link><description>A man was stabbed to death, allegedly by muggers, in the Tongi area of Gazipur early Saturday.
The deceased was identified as Siddiqur Rahman, an employee of a power company in Keraniganj, reports UNB.
Monohar Ali, sub-inspector of Tongi Pashim Police Station, said a group of muggers waylaid Sidd</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 05:26:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Panchagarh records season's lowest temperature</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/panchagarh-records-seasons-lowest-temperature</link><description>Bangladesh’s northernmost district of Panchagarh has recorded the season’s lowest temperature, with intensifying cold and dense fog disrupting daily activities, particularly for low-income residents.
The Tetulia meteorological observatory recorded the temperature at 10.5 degrees Celsiu</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 05:41:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Young girl dies in Habiganj road accident</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/young-girl-dies-in-habiganj-road-accident</link><description>A 20-year-old girl died when a truck knocked her down on the bypass road in Sadar upazila of Habiganj district on Friday night.
The deceased was identified as Sujina Akter, daughter of Manik Mia of Najirpur village in the upazila, reports UNB.
The accident occurred around 8:00 pm at the Poddarbar</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 05:56:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Syed Mizanur Rahman appointed Managing Director of Meghna Bank</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/syed-mizanur-rahman-appointed-managing-director-of-meghna-bank</link><description>Mr. Syed Mizanur Rahman, a seasoned professional with almost three decades of experience in the financial services sector, has been appointed as the Managing Director of Meghna Bank PLC, effective from December 4, 2025.     
Prior to this appointment, Mr Rahman was serving AB Bank a</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 06:11:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Meeting over marriage turns violent, one dead</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/meeting-over-marriage-turns-violent-one-dead</link><description>A 36-year-old man was stabbed to death, and two others were injured in an attack, allegedly by his neighbour, during a meeting over marriage in Farhadabad in Hathazari upazila of Chattogram on Friday night.
The deceased was identified as Rabiul Islam alias Babu, son of Zahur of Musa of the village</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 06:26:09 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>