<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 20:34:34 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Biman resumes direct Dhaka-Karachi flight</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/after-years-of-hiatus-biman-resumes-flight-services-between-dhaka-and-karachi</link><description>Bangladesh has resumed direct flights from Dhaka to Karachi after a long pause.
On Thursday at 8:15pm, a Biman Bangladesh Airlines Boeing 737 took off from Shahjalal International Airport carrying 138 passengers.
Advisor Sheikh Bashir Uddin and Pakistan’s High Commissioner to Dhaka Imran Ha</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 16:07:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Afghanistan launches $100 million food security programme as crisis deepens</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/afghanistan-launches-100-million-food-security-programme-as-crisis-deepens</link><description>Afghanistan will roll out a $100 million food security project, the United Nations said on Thursday, as it contends with a worsening hunger crisis driven by mass deportations of Afghans from neighbouring states, foreign aid cuts and economic crisis.
Afghanistan's humanitarian situation is deterior</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 16:22:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Women cannot head Jamaat: Shafiqur tells Al Jazeera</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jamaat-chief-rules-out-women-leading-party-as-cultural-reality-in-al-jazeera-interview</link><description>Jamaat‑e‑Islami chief Shafiqur Rahman has said no woman can ever lead his party because, in his words, Allah did not create women “in that way” and it is “unchangeable”.
He claimed that no party has nominated a “substantial number” of female candidates in the pa</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 16:37:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Home Adviser asks officials to uphold integrity, professionalism in election duties</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/home-adviser-asks-officials-to-uphold-integrity-professionalism-in-election-duties</link><description>Home Affairs Adviser Lt Gen Md Jahangir Alam Chowdhury (retd) on Thursday asked election officials and members of law enforcement agencies to discharge their duties with utmost integrity, efficiency and professionalism.
“Government officials are not members of any political party. They are s</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 16:52:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pitfalls of Trumpian tariffs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/pitfalls-of-trumpian-tariffs</link><description>Aimed at pulling up the cost of foreign products, protecting domestic industries, and raising revenue, tariffs are taxes or duties imposed by a government on imported commodities. These are used as an important tool in inter-governmental economic policy-making, as they influence foreign trade, affe</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 17:07:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Doctors we produce, patients we lose</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/doctors-we-produce-patients-we-lose</link><description>Bangladeshi citizens spend an estimated US$5.0 billion every year on medical treatment abroad, primarily in India and Thailand, a staggering outflow of foreign currency. Many middle-class families travel to India and affluent families fly to Thailand and Singapore to receive healthcare with China e</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 17:22:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>People use polythene knowing full well it is harmful</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/people-use-polythene-knowing-full-well-it-is-harmful</link><description>In a country as small as Bangladesh with an area of 147,570 square kilometres and a population size of 180 million, 8th largest in the world, the per capita use of nine kilogram plastic unfolds a terribly tragic vista the country is heading for. An update of this 2020 estimate is most likely to pai</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 17:37:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Making the LPG market cartel-free</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/making-the-lpg-market-cartel-free</link><description>The ongoing liquefied petroleum gas (LPG) crisis in the country appears to be less of a problem of supply and more of a consequence of weak regulatory oversight, which has allowed market distortion through cartelisation. Despite imports exceeding domestic consumption needs during the July-December</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 17:52:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nisho, Putul win top honours at National Film Awards</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/entertainment/national-film-awards-2023-nisho-putul-win-top-actor-awards-saatao-bags-best-film</link><description>Afran Nisho has been named Best Actor at this year’s National Film Awards, while Aynun Nahar Putul has won Best Actress. “Saatao” has been awarded the honour of Best Film.
The Ministry of Information and Broadcasting announced the National Film Awards for 2023 on Thursday night,</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 18:22:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>One group fled after snatching voting rights, another plotting again: Tarique</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/one-group-fled-after-snatching-voting-rights-another-plotting-again-tarique</link><description>BNP Chairperson Tarique Rahman on Thursday said one group had stripped people of their voting rights and fled the country while another group had remained out of sight for years but is now conspiring again.
“Everyone must remain alert to ensure ballot boxes are protected and empty boxes cann</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 18:37:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Freed Chhatra League leader Saddam accuses Bagerhat jailer of Tk 500,000 bribe demand</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/freed-chhatra-league-leader-saddam-accuses-bagerhat-jailer-of-tk-500000-bribe-demand</link><description>Jewel Hasan Saddam, a leader of the now-banned Bangladesh Chhatra League who was released on bail from Jashore Central Jail, has accused the Bagerhat district jailer of demanding Tk 500,000.
Saddam made the allegation on Wednesday evening after returning to his home in Sabekdanga, Bagerhat Sadar,</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 18:52:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Merged Islamic banks' clients getting maximum 9.5pc profit</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/merged-islamic-banks-clients-getting-maximum-95pc-profit</link><description>Depositors in the five Islamic banks merged into the newly formed Sammilito Islami Bank will receive profits at market rates of up to 9.5 per cent, says the regulator.



But depositors in nine non-bank financial institutions (NBFIs) up for liquidation would receive only their principal amounts</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 19:54:58 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>