<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 05:22:34 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>VAT On Metro Rail Tickets: Passengers to get exemption for another six months</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/vat-on-metro-rail-tickets-passengers-to-get-exemption-for-another-six-months</link><description>The government has decided to extend the Vat exemption facility for Metrorail passengers by six months more, until June 30. 2026.
The facility is scheduled to expire on December 31, 2025.
Finance adviser Dr Salehuddin Ahmed recently approved the proposal on exemption of 15 per cent Vat on prices</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 03:38:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt to extend 20pc power bill rebate facility to fish, livestock, poultry farms</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/govt-to-extend-20pc-power-bill-rebate-facility-to-fish-livestock-poultry-farms</link><description>The government is set to extend the 20 per cent power bill rebate facility to the owners of marginal fish farms, hatcheries, and livestock and poultry farms.
This important inclusion in the rebate beneficiary list, spearheaded by the Ministry of Fisheries and Livestock (MoFL), aims to drastically</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 03:53:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Regulatory lapses haunt nine NBFIs as liquidation looms</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/regulatory-lapses-haunt-nine-nbfis-as-liquidation-looms</link><description>The nine non-bank financial institutions (NBFIs) now heading for liquidation under a Bangladesh Bank initiative were in good financial health even a decade ago.
Their condition has gradually eroded over the years due to irregularities, loan scams and mismanagement under the watch of regulatory bod</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 02:40:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Real turnaround requires honesty, commitment</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/real-turnaround-requires-honesty-commitment</link><description>A real turnaround of the struggling commercial banks in Bangladesh requires honesty and commitment, and there are no shortcuts, City Bank Chairman Hossain Khaled says in an interview with The Financial Express.
Sharing the experience of how City became one of the leading banks from a problematic o</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 02:55:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Certain group spreading propaganda about Bangladesh abroad: Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/certain-group-spreading-propaganda-about-bangladesh-abroad-adviser</link><description>Terming the country's business environment 'quite good', Commerce Adviser Sheikh Bashir Uddin has said a certain group is spreading propaganda about Bangladesh abroad.
"A group is spreading negative propaganda about Bangladesh abroad, including security risks, which is affecting the export sector,</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 03:10:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>RENEWABLE ENERGY: Experts call for urgent reforms to procurement framework</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/renewable-energy-experts-call-for-urgent-reforms-to-procurement-framework</link><description>Experts have called for urgent reforms to Bangladesh's renewable energy procurement framework after a new study by the Centre for Policy Dialogue (CPD) revealed that many of the recently advertised solar power tenders received little to no participation.
The study, presented on Monday at a dialogu</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 03:25:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Twelve parties sign Child Rights Manifesto with ten commitments</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/twelve-parties-sign-child-rights-manifesto-with-ten-commitments</link><description>Political parties have united to sign a Child Rights Manifesto (CRM), responding to the powerful voices of children and young people, who have demanded a future where their rights are better respected and protected.
Ahead of the upcoming national election, 12 political parties signed the manifesto</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 03:40:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>White House defends US attack on boat from Venezuela as lawful</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/white-house-defends-us-attack-on-boat-from-venezuela-as-lawful</link><description>The White House on Monday defended a US admiral's decision to conduct multiple strikes on an alleged Venezuelan drug-smuggling vessel in September, saying he had Defense Secretary Pete Hegseth's authorisation, even as critics questioned the legality of a strike on survivors.
The Washington Post ha</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 03:55:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique will return ‘soon’, says Salahuddin</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-will-return-soon-says-salahuddin</link><description>Tarique Rahman will return to Bangladesh soon, BNP leader Salahuddin Ahmed has said.
The member of the party's Standing Committee made this comment in response to reporters' questions following an emergency meeting at the chairperson's Gulshan office on Monday night.
The BNP leader, however, did</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 04:10:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Plying of cruise ships resumes on Cox's Bazar-St Martin waterway</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/plying-of-cruise-ships-resumes-on-coxs-bazar-st-martin-waterway</link><description>COX'S BAZAR, Dec 01: After a nine-month closure, movement of vessels transporting tourists resumed on the Cox's Bazar-Saint Martin's route on Monday (December 1).
Cruise ships MV Bar Aulia, MV Karnaphuli and Keary Sindabad set off for Saint Martin's Island from the Nuniarachara BIWTA jetty in Cox'</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 04:25:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump rejected Maduro requests on call, options narrow for Venezuela leader</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-rejected-maduro-requests-on-call-options-narrow-for-venezuela-leader-sources-say</link><description>Venezuela's President Nicolas Maduro is running out of options to step down and leave his country under US-guaranteed safe passage, following a short call with US President Donald Trump last month where Trump refused a series of requests from the Venezuelan leader, according to four sources briefed</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 04:40:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Throat-slit body of man recovered in Chuadanga</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/throat-slit-body-of-man-recovered-in-chuadanga</link><description>A 25-year-old young man was found dead with his throat slit at Belgachi in the Chuadanga municipality area on Tuesday. 
The deceased was identified as Sohel, son of Asabul Haque of Bakcharpara area of the village, reports UNB.
Md Shahidur Rahman, officer-in-charge of Sadar Police Station, sa</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 04:55:25 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>