<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 08:32:54 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Khaleda’s  janaza likely on Wednesday, burial beside Ziaur Rahman: Salahuddin</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/khaledas-janaza-likely-on-wednesday-burial-beside-ziaur-rahman-salahuddin</link><description>BNP Chairperson and former Prime Minister Khaleda Zia is likely to be laid to rest beside her husband late President Ziaur Rahman at Zia Udyan in the capital’s Sher-e-Bangla Nagar.
BNP Standing Committee member Salahuddin Ahmed shared the information with the media on Tuesday.
He said Khale</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 04:54:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hasina mourns death of archrival Khaleda</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/a-profound-loss-hasina-mourns-death-of-archrival-khaleda</link><description>Ousted prime minister Sheikh Hasina has expressed condolences following the death of BNP chief Khaleda Zia, her archrival who dominated Bangladesh’s politics alongside her for decades.
In a condolence message posted on the Awami League's X account on Tuesday, Hasina described Khaleda as a si</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 05:09:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt announces 3-day state mourning, general holiday on Wednesday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-announces-3-day-state-mourning-general-holiday-on-wednesday-over-khaleda-zias-death</link><description>The government has announced a three-day state mourning and general holiday on Wednesday following the death of BNP Chairperson and former Prime Minister Khaleda Zia.
Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus announced the decision in a televised address to the nation on Tuesday, UNB reports.
"I hum</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 05:24:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Political tension hits much-preferred multinational stocks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/political-tension-hits-much-preferred-multinational-stocks</link><description>Listed foreign companies passed another tough year, with their stocks suffering further erosion in market value due to investors' apathy in making fresh investments.
A major reason is the exodus of foreign investors from Bangladesh's secondary market.
Overseas investors mostly prefer multinationa</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 05:39:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Al-Haj Textile Mills posts remarkable recovery in delayed FY24 results</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/al-haj-textile-mills-posts-remarkable-recovery-in-delayed-fy24-results</link><description>Listed yarn manufacturer Al-Haj Textile Mills reported a miraculous comeback in its more than one-year-late declaration of FY24 results, showing a profit of Tk 224.55 million after a significant loss in the first nine months of the year.
The time to announce even FY25 results has already passed by</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 05:54:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Workplace deaths jump in Bangladesh as safety conditions continue to deteriorate</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/workplace-deaths-jump-in-bangladesh-as-safety-conditions-continue-to-deteriorate</link><description>Workplace safety in Bangladesh worsened sharply in 2025, with at least 1,190 workers killed and 222 injured in job-related accidents across the country, according to a new report released on Tuesday.
The death toll marks a significant rise from 2024, when 905 workers were killed and 218 injured. T</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 06:09:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat chief Shafiqur expresses condolences over Khaleda Zia's death</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jamaat-chief-shafiqur-expresses-condolences-over-khaleda-zias-death</link><description>Jamaat-e-Islami chief Shafiqur Rahman, whose party was once a key ally of the BNP, has expressed condolences over the death of former prime minister Khaleda Zia.
In a message posted on Facebook, he prayed that Khaleda would be accepted as a “guest of paradise” and asked for strength an</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 06:24:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>SUPREME COURT SECRETARIAT: Lack of manpower, infrastructure hinders operations</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/supreme-court-secretariat-lack-of-manpower-infrastructure-hinders-operations</link><description>The activities of the newly-established Supreme Court (SC) Secretariat remain almost stagnant due to inadequate manpower and infrastructure.
Consequently, the Supreme Court continues to rely heavily on the Ministry of Law, Justice and Parliamentary Affairs for almost all of its secretarial functio</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 06:39:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Traders' human chain protesting extortion attacked at Karwan Bazar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/traders-human-chain-protesting-extortion-attacked-at-karwan-bazar</link><description>A group of miscreants carried out an attack on a human chain, formed by traders in the capital's Karwan Bazar area, protesting extortion on Monday.
Tejgaon Police Station Inspector Abdul Hannan said the incident took place around 11:15 am in front of the Kitchen Market.
The incident later led to</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 06:54:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP standing committee sits in emergency meeting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-standing-committee-sits-in-emergency-meeting</link><description>The BNP Standing Committee sat in an emergency meeting on Tuesday to decide the party’s next course of action following the death of its chairperson Begum Khaleda Zia.
The meeting began around 12:40 pm at the chairperson’s Gulshan office with BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman in</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 07:09:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Exporters seek exclusion of certain yarn types from duty-free facility</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/exporters-seek-exclusion-of-certain-yarn-types-from-duty-free-facility</link><description>In a bid to safeguard local spinning mills, apparel exporters and spinners have agreed on a proposal to exclude certain types of yarn from the duty-free bonded-warehouse facility and will soon request the government to take necessary action in this regard, industry insiders said.
The move comes in</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 07:24:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Graduation may hit country's apparel exports hard: Study</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/graduation-may-hit-countrys-apparel-exports-hard-study</link><description>LDC graduation poses a significant threat, with Bangladeshi exporters likely to bear a large share of tariff costs, as they may need to absorb 40 per cent of post-graduation tariffs to remain competitive in the European Union, according to a recent study.
After Bangladesh's graduation from the LDC</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 07:39:45 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>