<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 08:31:05 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>New rules formulated to control noise pollution</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/new-rules-formulated-to-control-noise-pollution</link><description>The government has formulated the Noise Pollution (Control) Rules 2025, removing limitations of the previous rules, bringing clarity to some key regulatory issues, and expanding enforcement authority.
Previously, only magistrates were empowered to take actions against noise pollution, making it di</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 04:22:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Korail Slum fire doused nearly 16 hours of efforts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/korail-slum-fire-doused-nearly-16-hours-of-efforts</link><description>Firefighters finally extinguished the devastating fire that broke out at Karail Slum in the Tejgaon area of Dhaka after nearly 16 hours of efforts on Wednesday morning.
Shahjahan Sikder, duty assistant director (media cell) at the Fire Service and Civil Defence (FSCD) headquarters, said they were</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 04:37:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cuba accuses US of seeking violent overthrow of Venezuelan government</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/cuba-accuses-us-of-seeking-violent-overthrow-of-venezuelan-government</link><description>Cuba on Tuesday accused the US of seeking a violent overthrow of the Venezuelan government, calling the increased presence of US military forces in the region an "exaggerated and aggressive" threat.
The US overthrowing Venezuelan President Nicolas Maduro's government would be extremely dangerous a</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 04:52:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bolsonaro starts serving 27-year sentence for Brazil coup plot</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/brazils-former-president-bolsonaro-starts-serving-27-year-sentence-for-coup-plot</link><description>Brazil's Supreme Court on Tuesday ordered former far-right President Jair Bolsonaro to begin a 27-year prison sentence for a coup plot against his successor, a climax to years of political turmoil and legal battles over his contentious legacy in Brazilian democracy.
The top court formally conclude</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 05:07:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Alphabet races toward $4 trillion valuation as AI-fuelled gains accelerate</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/alphabet-races-toward-4-trillion-valuation-as-ai-fuelled-gains-accelerate</link><description>Alphabet closed in on a $4 trillion valuation on Monday, set to become only the fourth company to enter the exclusive club, as the Google parent rides an artificial intelligence-driven rally.
Shares of the company rose more than 5% to hit a record high of $315.9, giving it a market capitalisation</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 05:22:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Taiwan plans extra $40 billion in defence spending to counter China</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/taiwan-plans-extra-40-billion-in-defence-spending-to-counter-china</link><description>Taiwan will introduce a $40-billion supplementary defence budget to underscore its determination to defend itself in the face of a rising threat from China, President Lai Ching-te said on Wednesday.
China, which views democratically-governed Taiwan as its own territory, has ramped up military and</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 05:37:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US budget deficit hits $284b in October</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/us-budget-deficit-hits-284b-in-october</link><description>The US government posted a higher $284 billion deficit for October in a report delayed and impacted by the recent federal government shutdown and reflecting record tariff revenues offset by a shift of some November benefit payments into last month's data, the Treasury Department said on Tuesday.
T</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 05:52:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>One spouse is enough, Vatican tells world's Catholics</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/others/one-spouse-is-enough-vatican-tells-worlds-catholics</link><description>Happily ever after doesn't require any complicated maths, the Vatican said on Tuesday -- for Catholics, one spouse is enough.
In a new decree approved by Pope Leo, the Vatican's top doctrinal office told the world's 1.4 billion Catholics they should seek to marry one spouse for life and should not</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 06:07:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>With 36.6m residents, Dhaka now world's second-largest city: UN report</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/with-366m-residents-dhaka-now-worlds-second-largest-city-un-report</link><description>A new United Nations report has found that Indonesia’s capital Jakarta is the world’s largest city with 41.9 million people living there, followed by Dhaka in Bangladesh, which is home to 36.6 million, Al Jazeera reports.
A low-lying coastal city located in the west of the densely popu</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 07:26:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fire at BMU under control</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/fire-at-bmu-under-control</link><description>A fire that broke out at Bangladesh Medical University (BMU) at Shahbagh intersection of Dhaka, was brought under control within a short time on Wednesday morning.
Rashed Bin Khalid, duty officer (media cell) at Fire Service and Civil Defence (FSCD) headquarters, said the fire erupted on the fourt</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 07:41:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Everything will be fine before the voting day: CEC on law and order</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/everything-will-be-fine-before-the-voting-day-cec-on-law-and-order</link><description>Chief Election Commissioner (CEC) AMM Nasir Uddin on Wednesday said the law and order situation will continue to improve and everything will be in order before the voting day.
“It will improve gradually. As the polling day approaches, you will see everything will fall in line. Everything wil</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 07:56:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>64 districts get SPs through lottery: Home adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/64-districts-get-sps-through-lottery-home-adviser</link><description>The government has appointed Superintendents of Police (SPs) for 64 districts across the country through a lottery system ahead of the national election slated for the first half of February next year.
According to a gazette notification signed by Md Mahbubur Rahman, deputy secretary at the Minist</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 08:11:35 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>