<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 16:28:57 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Rajshahi judge’s son died from excessive bleeding: Doctor</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/excessive-bleeding-caused-rajshahi-judges-sons-death-says-doctor</link><description>Tawsif Rahman Sumon, son of Rajshahi Metropolitan Sessions Judge Abdur Rahman, has died from excessive bleeding caused by multiple stab wounds, according to the forensic team.
On Friday morning, a two-member team led by the head of the Forensic Department at Rajshahi Medical College informed repor</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 13:43:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BECPS recognises four DU Psychologists for completing MS, MPhil degrees</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/becps-recognises-four-du-psychologists-for-completing-ms-mphil-degrees</link><description>The Bangladesh Educational and Counselling Psychology Society (BECPS) has officially recognised four psychologists as full-fledged professional psychologists for completing their MS and MPhil degrees in Educational Psychology and Counselling Psychology.
The recognition was announced at the society</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 13:58:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka University professor sent to jail over ‘sexual harassment’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/dhaka-university-professor-sent-to-jail-over-sexual-harassment</link><description>A Dhaka court has ordered authorities to send Dhaka University (DU) Chemistry Professor Ershad Halim to jail in a sexual harassment case initiated by a student.
Halim was arrested late on Thursday night at his Shewrapara residence by Mirpur Model Police.
On Friday, the investigating officer Sub-I</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 14:13:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>School feeding programme begins Saturday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/school-feeding-programme-begins-saturday</link><description>School feeding programme is going to lunch on Saturday in some selected government primary schools across the country, aiming to increase the attendance rate, maintain attention and improve nutrition of the students.
Primary and Mass Education Adviser Professor Dr Bidhan Ranjan Roy Podder is expec</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 14:28:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>35 crude bombs seized in Dhaka’s Geneva Camp</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/35-crude-bombs-seized-in-dhakas-geneva-camp</link><description>Police have recovered 35 crude bombs and bomb-making equipment from the Geneva Camp in Dhaka’s Mohammadpur.
The operation was carried out in the afternoon, the Dhaka Metropolitan Police (DMP) Public Relations Department said in a statement
A police officer involved in the raid said the bomb</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 14:43:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Young climate activists rally in Dhaka ahead of COP30</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/young-climate-activists-rally-in-dhaka-ahead-of-cop30</link><description>More than 500 young climate activists from 13 youth organisations joined a demonstration in front of the National Press Club in Dhaka on Friday in solidarity with ActionAid Bangladesh, demanding a greener, fairer, and more equitable world.
With an aim to amplify the call for justice-centred climat</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 14:58:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bodies of two missing youths recovered after trawler sinks in N’ganj</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bodies-of-two-missing-youths-recovered-after-trawler-sinks-in-nganj</link><description>The bodies of two men, who went missing after a cement-loaded trawler sank in the Meghna River in Sonargaon upazila of Narayanganj district, have been recovered.
The deceased were identified as Roni Sardar, son of Ali Sardar of Bisarat village in Barishal’s Bandar upazila, and Shubho, son of</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 15:13:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Russia plans to make up to 120,000 glide bombs this year, Ukrainian intelligence says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/russia-plans-to-make-up-to-120000-glide-bombs-this-year-ukrainian-intelligence-says</link><description>Russia plans to manufacture up to 120,000 of its cheap and devastating glide bombs this year, a senior Ukrainian intelligence official said, including 500 of a new, longer-range version which can reach more towns and cities.
Russia has ramped up arms production massively since the full-scale invas</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 15:28:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tens of thousands of displaced people missing in Sudan’s Darfur, UN says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/africa/tens-of-thousands-of-displaced-people-missing-in-sudans-darfur-un-says</link><description>Tens of thousands of people who have fled the Sudanese city of al-Fashir are unaccounted for, the UNrefugee agency said on Friday, raising concerns for their safety after reports of rape, killings and other abuses from escapees.
Famine-stricken al-Fashir was the final stronghold of the Sudanese ar</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 15:43:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fish hospital opens in Khulna to treat diseased fish</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/fish-hospital-opens-in-khulna-to-treat-diseased-fish</link><description>Usually people visit hospitals when sick, now fish in Khulna can also receive medical care. A specialised fish hospital, ‘Fish Square Fisheries Hospital,’ was inaugurated in Dumuria of Khulna on Friday afternoon, to provide treatment and advice for fish diseases and aquaculture issues.</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 15:58:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>2 Chinese nationals taken into custody over ‘unauthorised travel’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/2-chinese-nationals-taken-into-custody-over-unauthorised-travel</link><description>Police in Khagrachhari’s Ramgarh have taken two Chinese nationals into custody, saying they travelled to the hill district “without permission”.
Police seized laptops and several other electronic devices from the duo—Jiang Chengtong and Teng Tonggui.
Ramgarh Police Chief M</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 16:13:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DUCSU announces Bengali New Year celebration in Agrahayan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ducsu-strays-from-boishakh-announces-bengali-new-year-celebrations-in-agrahayan</link><description>The Dhaka University Central Students’ Union (DUCSU) has announced that it will celebrate Bengali New Year at the start of Agrahayan rather than on the traditional first day of Boishakh.
The newly elected DUCSU leadership intends to organise the event on Sunday, the first day of the Bengali</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 16:28:57 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>