<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 17:32:38 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Russia withdrawing troops from airport in northeast Syria, sources say</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/russia-withdrawing-troops-from-airport-in-northeast-syria-sources-say</link><description>Russia is withdrawing forces from an airport in northeastern Syria, moving to end its military presence in a corner of the country where the Damascus government is trying to seize control from Kurdish forces, five Syrian sources said.
Russia has stationed forces at Qamishli airport in the northeas</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 13:52:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BRAC Bank top-performing bank in GSEC trading for 4th consecutive years</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/brac-bank-top-performing-bank-in-gsec-trading-for-4th-consecutive-years</link><description>BRAC Bank has once again secured its position as the top-performing bank in secondary market trading of Government Securities (GSEC) for the fourth consecutive year, as per the latest yearly report on GSEC published by Bangladesh Bank.
In FY 2024-25, BRAC Bank expanded its market share to 17.03 pe</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 14:07:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BB chief for stronger enforcement to restore confidence in bond market</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/bb-chief-for-stronger-enforcement-to-restore-confidence-in-bond-market</link><description>Bangladesh Bank (BB) Governor Dr Ahsan H Mansur today (Monday) laid emphasis on stricter regulation and stronger enforcement to restore confidence of investors for the development of Bangladesh's corporate bond market.
“Weak enforcement of rules has significantly eroded investor confidence i</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 14:22:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat alleges harassment of its female campaigners</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-alleges-harassment-of-its-female-campaigners</link><description>Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islam on Monday lodged several complaints with the Election Commission, alleging that its women activists and school teachers enlisted under the Monthly Pay Order (MPO) are facing harassment while campaigning for the party ahead of the upcoming national election scheduled for Fe</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 14:37:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Community Bank signs MoU with National Pension Authority for Universal Pension Scheme Digital Contribution Collection</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/community-bank-signs-mou-with-national-pension-authority-for-universal-pension-scheme-digital-contribution-collection</link><description>A Memorandum of Understanding (MoU) has been signed between Community Bank Bangladesh PLC. and the National Pension Authority to facilitate the collection of monthly installments for the universal pension schemes—Probas, Pragati, Surakkha, and Samata.
The MoU was signed on behalf of their re</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 14:52:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Stocks rebound at DSE despite broad price declines</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/stocks-rebound-at-dse-despite-broad-price-declines</link><description>Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) rebounded on Monday after an early slump, with key indices closing higher, although prices of most listed companies ended the session lower.
The benchmark DSEX index gained 8 points by the end of trading. The Shariah-based DSES advanced 4 points, while the blue-chip DS30</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 15:07:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt moves to merge BIDA, BEZA, BEPZA, MIDA</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/govt-moves-to-merge-bida-beza-bepza-mida</link><description>The interim government on Monday decided to merge all investment promotion agencies (IPAs) in Bangladesh in a move aimed at simplifying procedures and making the country more investor-friendly.
The decision was taken at a meeting of the IPA Governing Board, chaired by Chief Adviser Prof Muhammad Y</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 15:22:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rent of Ekushey Book Fair reduced by 25pc</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rent-of-ekushey-book-fair-reduced-by-25pc</link><description>Cultural Affairs Adviser Mostofa Sarwar Farooki has asked the authorities concerned to reduce the rent of this year's Amar Ekushey Book Fair stall by 25 per cent.
The adviser gave the directive in response to requests from publishers, the adviser said in a Facebook post.
“Following appeals</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 15:37:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Italy visa application submissions suspended worldwide from February 11 to 18</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/italy-visa-application-submissions-suspended-worldwide-from-february-11-to-18</link><description>The Embassy of Italy in Dhaka on Monday announced a temporary worldwide suspension of visa application submissions in mid-February due to scheduled technical maintenance of the Italian visa processing system.
In an advisory, the embassy said that no visa applications of any category will be accept</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 15:52:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ACC summons Summit Group chairman for questioning over ‘illicit wealth’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/acc-summons-summit-group-chairman-for-questioning-over-illicit-wealth</link><description>Summit Group Chairman Muhammed Aziz Khan has been summoned by the Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) for questioning over allegations of acquiring wealth beyond means and money laundering.
He has been asked to appear on Thursday to provide statements, according to the graft watchdog.
The commission</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 16:07:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pre-orders open for Mizanur Rahman Sohel’s ‘Content Creator’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/others/pre-orders-open-for-mizanur-rahman-sohels-content-creator</link><description>Pre-orders have officially opened for Content Creator, the latest book by renowned writer and journalist Mizanur Rahman Sohel, aimed at individuals aspiring to build a successful career as content creators on digital platforms.
The book is now available for pre-order at a special discounted price</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 16:22:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Animal, poultry feed industry to get 20pc power rebate</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/animal-poultry-feed-industry-to-get-20pc-power-rebate</link><description>The interim government is going to offer a 20 per cent rebate on electricity bills to reduce production costs in four sectors, including animal and poultry feed manufacturing.
The decision was announced in a media statement issued by the Ministry of Fisheries and Livestock on Monday.
The statemen</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 16:37:46 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>