<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 05:53:17 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>BD-US reciprocal tariff deal’s status unclear</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bd-us-reciprocal-tariff-deals-status-unclear</link><description>A landmark ruling by the US Supreme Court torpedoing Trump tariffs effectively upsets Bangladesh's trade arrangements with the United States, prompting calls for a cautious reassessment of the recently signed bilateral deal.



The media-highlighted "blow" to President Donald Trump's tariff reg</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 19:25:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump raises new global tariff from 10pc to 15pc</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/global/trump-raises-new-global-tariff-from-10pc-to-15pc</link><description>U.S. President Donald Trump said Saturday he will raise the new global tariff to 15 percent, one day after he announced a 10 percent worldwide duty following a heavy blow from the Supreme Court.
"I, as President of the United States of America, will be, effective immediately, raising the 10% World</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 01:46:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nation observes Amar Ekushey with solemnity</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nation-observes-amar-ekushey-with-solemnity</link><description>The nation on Saturday observed Amar Ekushey and International Mother Language Day with solemnity and quiet pride, marking the 74th anniversary of the historic 1952 Language Movement that laid the foundation of Bangladesh's linguistic and cultural identity.
The day's observances began just after m</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 02:01:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>150 mmcfd gas supply disruption likely</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/150-mmcfd-gas-supply-disruption-likely</link><description>A key floating liquefied natural gas (LNG) terminal operated by US-based Excelerate Energy will suspend regasified fuel supply for 48 hours from February 23 to February 25 to carry out urgent maintenance after a technical fault developed in one of its core systems.
The shutdown of the floating sto</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 02:16:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Industry sees big 6.97pc growth in Q1 FY26</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/industry-sees-big-697pc-growth-in-q1-fy26</link><description>Bangladesh's industrial sector saw a strong recovery in the first quarter of FY26, driven by robust growth in construction, mining, and manufacturing activities.
According to the latest Bangladesh Bank (BB) data, industrial growth rose to 6.97 per cent in Q1 of FY26, a significant improvement from</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 02:31:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Past missteps haunt BSEC as fresh lobbying begins for top posts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/past-missteps-haunt-bsec-as-fresh-lobbying-begins-for-top-posts</link><description>Strong lobbying has begun for the top positions at the securities regulator after the newly elected government assumed office last week.
Market experts insist that the right leadership is imperative for the capital market to recover from decades-old wounds inflicted by fraud and self-serving polic</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 02:46:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Reimagining Bangladesh's education for Generation Alpha</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/article/reimagining-bangladeshs-education-for-generation-alpha</link><description>According to UNESCO (2023), 92 per cent of Bangladesh's Generation Alpha - born in 2010 and after - is the country's biggest and most technologically savvy group. Despite having enormous economic potential, children are taught using a mass-production, industrial-era educational system that views st</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 03:50:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh must rebuild its public universities now</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/article/bangladesh-must-rebuild-its-public-universities-now</link><description>For decades, Bangladesh has invested heavily in human capital. Public funds sustain millions of students through primary, secondary, and higher secondary education. Families allocate significant income to examinations and university preparation. Public universities are subsidised so that merit, rat</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 04:05:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Customs seize phones, cigarettes worth Tk 1m from Dubai returnee at Chattogram airport</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/customs-seize-phones-cigarettes-worth-tk-1m-from-dubai-returnee-at-chattogram-airport</link><description>Customs officials at Shah Amanat International Airport in Chattogram have seized 15 mobile phones and a large quantity of foreign cigarettes from a passenger arriving from Dubai.
The seizure was made around 10am on Saturday after the baggage of passenger Mohammad Hossain Zahed Habib was searched b</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 04:20:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mobile services may face brief disruption during NEIR test on Sunday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/mobile-services-may-face-brief-disruption-during-neir-test-on-sunday</link><description>Mobile phone connections may be temporarily disrupted during a trial run of the National Equipment Identity Register (NEIR) system.
The test will be conducted from 10am to 12pm on Sunday as part of preparations to fully implement the system from March, the Association of Mobile Telecom Operators o</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 04:35:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pakistan says it carried out cross-border strikes in Afghanistan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/pakistan-says-it-carried-out-cross-border-strikes-in-afghanistan</link><description>Pakistan said it carried out cross-border strikes on militant targets inside Afghanistan after blaming a series of recent suicide bombings - including attacks during the holy month of Ramadan - on fighters it said were operating from Afghan territory.
The strikes mark a sharp escalation in tension</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 04:50:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Social media can be addictive even for adults, but there are ways to cut back</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/others/social-media-can-be-addictive-even-for-adults-but-there-are-ways-to-cut-back</link><description>Social media addiction has been compared to casinos, opioids and cigarettes.
While there's some debate among experts about the line between overuse and addiction, and whether social media can cause the latter, there is no doubt that many people feel like they can't escape the pull of Instagram, Ti</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 05:53:17 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>