<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 06:31:49 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Ten-storey building at Bijoynagar catches fire</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ten-storey-building-at-bijoynagar-catches-fire</link><description>An incident of fire happened on Saturday at the ninth floor of a ten-storey building in the capital's Bijoynagar area.
However, there was no report of casualties.
Fire Service and Civil Defense control room official Rozina Akhter told the FE that they had received the information of fire at aroun</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 03:09:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UN panel demands immediate release of Shahriar Kabir from 'arbitrary' detention</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/un-panel-demands-immediate-release-of-shahriar-kabir-from-arbitrary-detention</link><description>The United Nations’ Working Group on Arbitrary Detention has found the detention of Bangladeshi filmmaker, writer, and human rights defender Shahriar Kabir “arbitrary and unlawful”
In its detailed opinion submitted on Saturday, the Working Group found that Kabir’s arrest, r</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 03:24:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bitter gourd cultivation expands in Manikganj; yet yield prospects low</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/bitter-gourd-cultivation-expands-in-manikganj-yet-yield-prospects-low</link><description>Bitter gourd cultivation has been increasing every year in Manikganj Sadar upazila.
Farmers are opting to cultivate the crop on a large scale, hoping for good yield with relatively lower production costs. But this year, natural disasters have dampened those hopes. Repeated rainfall, reduced yields</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 03:39:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hundreds of thousands suffer in Cox's Bazar, Sylhet due to slow progress</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/hundreds-of-thousands-suffer-in-coxs-bazar-sylhet-due-to-slow-progress</link><description>Slow progress in two government bridge construction projects has left hundreds of thousands of people to face serious inconveniences for years in Cox's Bazar and Sylhet.
Our correspondent from Cox's Bazar reports, hundreds of thousands of people have been facing much hardship as the works for cons</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 03:54:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh shifts fiscal gears as bank debt falls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/bangladesh-shifts-fiscal-gears-as-bank-debt-falls</link><description>The interim government has reversed years of aggressive bank borrowing, opting instead to repay outstanding loans in a move economists said could unlock fresh credit for the private sector and cool inflationary pressures.
The policy shift marks a clear departure from the previous administration, w</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 04:09:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DU declares closure for 15 days; students asked to leave halls by this evening</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/du-declares-closure-for-15-days-students-asked-to-leave-halls-by-this-evening</link><description>Dhaka University has been declared closed for 15 days due to an emergency situation following a recent earthquake. 
As per the announcement, students have been instructed to leave their residential halls by 5:00 pm of Sunday. The directive was issued in a notice sent on Saturday night by Acti</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 04:24:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>When low confidence overshadows skill</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/article/when-low-confidence-overshadows-skill</link><description>She made a perfect presentation-well-prepared slides, solid facts, proper research and innovative ideas. Still, when she got to the stage, her self-doubt kicked in. "What if I missed something?"-she thought. Her voice trembled; despite having well-researched solutions, she forgot to present them. T</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 04:39:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Why part-time jobs for students matter</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/article/why-part-time-jobs-for-students-matter</link><description>Bangladesh is facing a youth puzzle it has not fully solved. Nearly one-third of the population is between 15 and 29, making it one of the youngest countries in the region. We often call this a big advantage, yet many young people still struggle to find jobs and the jump from school to work takes f</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 04:54:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How AI dependency is eroding critical thinking of youths</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/article/how-ai-dependency-is-eroding-critical-thinking-of-youths</link><description>Since late 2023, the way young people interact with the internet has changed drastically. The shift has moved from seeking information to demanding instant answers. LLM-based AI applications like ChatGPT, Claude, DeepSeek, and Gemini have transformed user behaviou—today's youths no longer wan</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 05:09:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Barriers and opportunities: The role of sustainable private universities in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/analysis/barriers-and-opportunities-the-role-of-sustainable-private-universities-in-bangladesh</link><description>Private universities have become pivotal in expanding access to higher education in Bangladesh, particularly in response to rising demand and the limited capacity of public institutions. This paper examines the barriers and opportunities influencing the transformation of private universities toward</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 05:24:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Midnight clash erupts between two groups at Alia Madrasa in Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/midnight-clash-erupts-between-two-groups-at-alia-madrasa-in-dhaka</link><description>Two factions of students have clashed at the Government-Madrasah-e-Alia in Old Dhaka’s Bakshibazar in several stages.
Several students have reportedly been injured in the incident, which started around midnight on Saturday, according to Sub-Inspector Ashraful Islam of the Chawkbazar Police S</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 05:39:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hilsa prices soar further</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hilsa-prices-soar-further</link><description>Hilsa, the pride of Bangladesh’s rivers and the heart of its culinary culture, has once again slipped beyond the reach of ordinary consumers as prices surged dramatically at the century-old Mir Kadim wholesale fish market in Munshiganj.
Within just 48 hours, hilsa prices have jumped by up to</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 05:54:01 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>