<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 03:12:28 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Youth beaten to death in Rangpur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/youth-beaten-to-death-in-rangpur</link><description>A young man was beaten to death on late Wednesday night two days after being taken away on suspicion of motorcycle theft in Mithapukur upazila of Rangpur.
The victim collapsed and died shortly after being returned to his family, reports UNB.
Police recovered the body Thursday afternoon and sent i</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 17:17:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>State of mental health in South Asia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/state-of-mental-health-in-south-asia</link><description>The World Mental Health Day, observed annually on October 10, is a reminder of the importance of good mental health and the need to prioritise and invest in good mental health.
Worldwide, over one billion people, i.e. around one in eight persons, live with a mental health disorder. Anxiety and dep</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 17:32:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Makkah for mankind</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/makkah-for-mankind</link><description>There are good reasons why Allah almighty let Prophet Ibrahim (pbuh) to construct the Holy Kaaba – the House of Allah in Makkah. Prophet Ibrahim was born well before other three important Prophets – Musa, I’sa and Muhammad (peace be upon them all), and is highly revered by the fol</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 17:47:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>When human life is considered cheap</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/when-human-life-is-considered-cheap</link><description>Human lives seem to have lost their sanctity in our society. Incidents that happen every day here remind us how cheap we consider lives of our own and others. The recent death of a man caused by a falling bearing pad from the metro rail in Dhaka, mirrors this grim reality. Otherwise, how could a mu</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 18:17:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No room for independent media commission!</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/no-room-for-independent-media-commission</link><description>Old habits die hard. Reportedly, the information ministry essentially run by bureaucrats are once again up to the task of foiling the independence of media stipulated in the draft report submitted to the chief adviser. The reported striking off the independent media commission, the most important i</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 18:32:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Reviewing the draft labour law</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/reviewing-the-draft-labour-law</link><description>The recent approval of the draft Bangladesh Labour Act (Amendment) Ordinance 2025 by the interim government has drawn strong reactions from the representatives of the country's largest industry association, the Bangladesh Garment Manufacturers and Exporters Association (BGMEA). Labour law reforms,</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 18:47:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Public company coming up for start-up funding</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/public-company-coming-up-for-start-up-funding</link><description>An equity-backed public limited company comes up shortly with a Tk 20-billion authorised capital for startup financing to facilitate promising economic ventures in the country, sources say.



With eight shareholders, the company is being initially formed with the contribution from 52 commerc</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 19:02:15 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>