<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 05:58:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>BNP MPs begin arriving at parliament for swearing-in</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bnp-mps-begin-arriving-at-parliament-for-swearing-in</link><description>Newly elected BNP lawmakers have begun arriving at the parliament complex ahead of their swearing-in ceremony.
Vehicles carrying the MPs started entering the complex from 9:00 am on Sunday. The oath ceremony is scheduled for 10:00 am, where Chief Election Commissioner AMM Nasir Uddin will administ</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 04:30:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>RMG buyers eye GSP Plus as next growth driver</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/rmg-buyers-eye-gsp-plus-as-next-growth-driver</link><description>Global readymade garment (RMG) buyers have largely welcomed Bangladesh's 13th parliamentary election, viewing the smooth transition of power as a positive signal for business continuity, while setting their sights on securing preferential market access as the country approaches graduation from the</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 03:00:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>TCB seeks procurement provider VAT exemption for suppliers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/tcb-seeks-procurement-provider-vat-exemption-for-suppliers</link><description>The Trading Corporation of Bangladesh (TCB) has requested an exemption from procurement provider (withholding) VAT on locally procured goods supplied under its government-subsidised programmes, sources said.
In an official letter dated February 10, 2026, TCB stated that it distributes essential co</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 03:15:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Supreme Court stays Ramadan school closure</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/supreme-court-stays-ramadan-school-closure</link><description>The Appellate Division of the Supreme Court of Bangladesh on Monday stayed a High Court order directing the government to keep all secondary schools across the country closed throughout the holy month of Ramadan.
Justice Farah Mahbub, Chamber Judge of the Appellate Division, passed the order after</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 03:30:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DMTCL earns one-fourth of average revenue on election day</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dmtcl-earns-one-fourth-of-average-revenue-on-election-day</link><description>Dhaka Mass Transit Company Limited (DMTCL) earned about one-fourth of its average daily revenue by keeping metro services operational on the 13th national election day.
According to data, DMTCL received over 100,000 riders on February 12 against an average of over 400,000 riders. However, the ride</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 03:45:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>OATH-TAKING CEREMONY: Traffic remains limited in JS area today</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/oath-taking-ceremony-traffic-remains-limited-in-js-area-today</link><description>Dhaka Metropolitan Police (DMP) said traffic would remain restricted on Manik Mia Avenue and Lake Road in the capital today (Tuesday) for the oath-taking ceremony of the newly-elected members of parliament (MPs) and the newly-formed cabinet.
DMP deputy commissioner (media and public relations) Muh</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 04:00:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP MPs won’t take oath as members of Constitution Reform Council</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bnp-mps-wont-take-oath-as-members-of-constitution-reform-council</link><description>Newly elected BNP MPs have been sworn in as members of the 13th national parliament but have declined to take oath as members of the Constitution Reform Council.
The decision was announced on Tuesday morning at the parliament oath room before the swearing-in ceremony by BNP Standing Committee memb</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 04:15:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt cuts VAT on LPG to stabilise price</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/govt-cuts-vat-on-lpg-to-stabilise-price</link><description>The government has reduced value Added Tax(VAT) on LPG in a move aimed at stabilising the market and keeping the essential fuel within consumers’ purchasing power.
In a press release issued on Monday night, the National Board of Revenue (NBR) said it had issued two separate notifications on</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 04:30:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Oath ceremony snarls Dhaka traffic</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/oath-ceremony-snarls-dhaka-traffic</link><description>Traffic congestion spread across parts of Dhaka on Tuesday morning as heightened security measures were put in place for the swearing-in of newly elected members of parliament.
Police and Border Guard Bangladesh (BGB) personnel stepped up patrols and imposed strict traffic controls, leading to con</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 04:45:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP MPs-elect take oath as members of parliament</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bnp-mps-elect-take-oath-as-members-of-parliament</link><description>BNP MPs-elect have taken oath as only members of the 13th parliament, not as members of the Constitution Reform Council on Tuesday morning.
Chief Election Commissioner AMM Nasir Uddin administered the oath at 10:43am in line with the Constitution as the posts of Speaker and Deputy Speaker of</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 05:00:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nepal FM Sharma arrives in Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nepal-fm-sharma-arrives-in-dhaka</link><description>Nepal's Foreign Minister Bala Nanda Sharma arrived in Dhaka to attend the oath-taking ceremony of the newly elected Government of Bangladesh led by BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman on Tuesday.
Secretary of the Ministry of Foreign Affairs of Bangladesh Dr Md Nazrul Islam and Nepal Ambassador to Banglade</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 05:15:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Oath ceremony snarls Dhaka traffic as security tightened around parliament</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/oath-ceremony-snarls-dhaka-traffic-as-security-tightened-around-parliament</link><description>Traffic congestion spread across parts of Dhaka on Tuesday morning as heightened security measures were put in place for the swearing-in of newly elected members of parliament.
Police and Border Guard Bangladesh (BGB) personnel stepped up patrols and imposed strict traffic controls, leading to con</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 05:30:48 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>