<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 07:25:22 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Experts urge govt to execute anti-torture commitments</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/experts-urge-govt-to-execute-anti-torture-commitments</link><description>Human rights experts, government officials, and international partners have called for swift and substantive implementation of Bangladesh's new obligations under the Optional Protocol to the Convention against Torture (OPCAT), opining that its ratification must now be translated into real accountab</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 04:15:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Australia begins enforcing world-first teen social media ban</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/australia-begins-enforcing-world-first-teen-social-media-ban</link><description>Australia on Wednesday became the first country to ban social media for children under 16, blocking access in a move welcomed by many parents and child advocates but criticised by major technology companies and free-speech advocates.
Starting at midnight (1300 GMT on Tuesday), 10 of the largest pl</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 04:30:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US trade deal with Indonesia at risk of collapse, US official says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/us-trade-deal-with-indonesia-at-risk-of-collapse-us-official-says</link><description>A US trade agreement reached with Indonesia in July is at risk of collapsing because Jakarta has backtracked on several commitments it made as part of the deal, a US official said on Tuesday.
"They're reneging on what we agreed to in July," said the official, who spoke on condition of anonymity, g</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 04:45:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cambodia vows fierce fight against Thailand in their escalating border conflict</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/cambodia-vows-fierce-fight-against-thailand-in-their-escalating-border-conflict</link><description>Cambodia’s Senate President Hun Sen vowed a fierce fight against Thailand as a second day of widespread renewed combat between the nations Tuesday drove tens of thousands of people to flee border areas.
The fighting following a skirmish Sunday that injured two Thai soldiers and derailed a ce</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 05:00:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CU Chhatra Dal leader dies after road accident</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cu-chhatra-dal-leader-dies-after-road-accident</link><description>A Chittagong University (CU) Chhatra Dal leader injured in a road accident in Hathazari has died after two days in hospital.
Mohammad Arif, joint general secretary of the university’s Chhatra Dal unit and a history student from the 2016–17 session, passed away on Tuesday night at Chitt</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 04:53:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Student killed in Kentucky university shooting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/student-killed-in-kentucky-university-shooting</link><description>A shooting at Kentucky State University on Tuesday left one person dead and another in critical condition, according to police, who said the suspected assailant was taken into custody.
Local police in Frankfort, the state capital, and county sheriff's deputies made the arrest and secured the campu</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 05:08:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Advisors Mahfuz Alam and Asif Mahmud to resign today</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/advisors-mahfuz-alam-and-asif-mahmud-to-resign-today</link><description>Two Interim Government Advisors are expected to step down today ahead of the announcement of the election schedule.
Information and Broadcasting Advisor Mahfuz Alam and Local Government Advisor Asif Mahmud Sajeeb Bhuiyan are set to resign today, according to senior government sourcesThe two studen</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 05:23:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hasina ‘gravely concerned’ about Khaleda’s health: Indian media</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hasina-gravely-concerned-about-khaledas-health-indian-media</link><description>Ousted prime minister Sheikh Hasina says that she is “gravely concerned” about the health of BNP chief Khaleda Zia, adding that she is praying for her, according to reports in the Indian media.
During an email interview with Indian private news agency IANS, published on Tuesday, Hasina</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 05:38:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EU members agree to cut emissions by 90% by 2040 from 1990 levels</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/eu-members-agree-to-cut-emissions-by-90-by-2040-from-1990-levels</link><description>The European Union has reached a legally binding climate agreement to reduce greenhouse gas emissions by 90% by 2040 from 1990 levels, involving the purchase of foreign carbon credits to cover 5% of the cuts, the European Parliament said on Wednesday.
The agreement will require EU industries to cu</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 05:53:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladeshi man detained in Malaysia for entering women’s restroom</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladeshi-man-detained-in-malaysia-for-entering-womens-restroom</link><description>A 35-year-old Bangladeshi man was detained by local police in Malaysia’s Johor state after he mistakenly entered a women’s restroom at the Kulai Bus Terminal on Tuesday.
Kulai District Police Chief Assistant Commissioner Tan Seng Lee said in a statement on Wednesday that the man was ta</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 06:08:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Truck driver killed in Jhenaidah road crash</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/truck-driver-killed-in-jhenaidah-road-crash</link><description>A truck driver was killed in a head-on collision between two trucks in Jhenaidah on Tuesday night. 
The deceased was identified as Rabiul Islam, 60, hailed from Shapahati village under Shalikha upazila in Magura district, reports BSS.
The accident occurred around 9:30 pm near the Markaz Mosq</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 06:23:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Zelenskyy reaffirms his refusal to cede land to Russia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/zelenskyy-reaffirms-his-refusal-to-cede-land-to-russia</link><description>Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelenskyy has reaffirmed his strong refusal to cede any territory, resisting U.S. pressure for painful concessions to Russia as he moved ahead Tuesday to rally more European support for his country. 
“Undoubtedly, Russia insists for us to give up territorie</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 07:25:22 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>