<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 16:45:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Bangladesh, Saudi Arabia sign deal on manpower recruitment</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-saudi-arabia-sign-landmark-deal-on-manpower-recruitment</link><description>Bangladesh and Saudi Arabia today (Monday) signed a landmark agreement in Riyadh on the recruitment of general workers, the first of its kind between the two countries in their 50-year history of diplomatic relations.
Bangladesh Expatriates Welfare and Overseas Employment Adviser Dr. Asif Nazrul a</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 13:28:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bulbul, Fahim elected BCB directors</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/bulbul-fahim-elected-bcb-directors</link><description>Aminul Islam Bulbul and Nazmul Abedeen Fahim got elected to the board of directors’ election of the Bangladesh Cricket Board (BCB) held at the Pan Pacific Sonargaon Dhaka on Monday.
Bulbul and Fahim were elected from Dhaka Division in Category-1 (Districts and Divisions) after obtaining 15 v</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 13:58:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Death toll from Indonesian school collapse rises to 65, search continues</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/death-toll-from-indonesian-school-collapse-rises-to-65-search-continues</link><description>The death toll from the collapse of a school in Indonesia last week has climbed to 65, authorities said on Monday, while rescuers continued to search for survivors under the rubble, seven days after the disaster.
Concrete walls and floors caved in on hundreds of mostly teenage boys at the Al Khozi</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 14:13:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fertiliser factories seek tariff relief and gas supply to avert import dependence</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/fertiliser-factories-seek-tariff-relief-and-gas-supply-to-avert-import-dependence</link><description>Fertiliser production costs in state-run factories would be 32.60 per cent lower than the import costs if the gas price is doubled to Tk 30 per cubic meter and annual production reaches around 2.0 million tonnes, as the state-run Bangladesh Chemical Industries Corporation (BCIC) claimed Monday.</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 14:28:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BB buys another US$104mn to stabilise dollar market</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bb-buys-another-us104mn-to-stabilise-dollar-market</link><description>The Bangladesh Bank (BB) has purchased an additional US$104 million from commercial banks through an auction to maintain stability in the foreign exchange market, raising the country’s foreign exchange reserves to $26.62 billion.
The central bank bought the dollars at a rate of Tk 121.80 fro</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 14:43:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP plans to make Bangladesh global supply hub, Tarique tells FT</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-plans-to-make-bangladesh-global-supply-hub-tarique-tells-ft</link><description>Acting BNP chairman Tarique Rahman, in an interview with the Financial Times, has outlined some aspects of a future economic programme for Bangladesh, including diversifying away from garment exports by becoming a “supply hub” for online retailers such as Amazon, eBay and Alibaba.
The</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 14:41:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Former police chief Mamun was “influenced” to falsely testify, says Hasina’s lawyer</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/former-police-chief-mamun-was-influenced-to-falsely-testify-says-hasinas-lawyer</link><description>Lawyer Amir Hossain has claimed that ex-police chief Chowdhury Abdullah Al-Mamun was “provoked” into giving a statement implicating suspects in a crimes against humanity case linked to the July Uprising.
The claim came on Monday during cross-examination of the case’s investigatin</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 15:41:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dr. Shadi represents FBCCI at Australia Bangladesh Business Expo</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/dr-shadi-represents-fbcci-at-australia-bangladesh-business-expo</link><description>Dr. Md. Shadi-Uz-Zaman has got the opportunity to represent the apex trade body of Bangladesh, named Federation of Bangladesh Chambers of Commerce and Industry (FBCCI), at the Australia Bangladesh Business Expo- 2025 (Venue: Sydney Masonic Centre), Sydney, Australia, organised by Australia Banglade</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 15:56:53 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>