<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 13:27:20 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>India's Goa state orders probe after nightclub fire kills 25</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/indias-goa-state-orders-probe-after-nightclub-fire-kills-25-26</link><description>Indian authorities ordered an investigation and offered compensation to victims on Sunday after a fire ripped through a nightclub in the western state of Goa, killing 25.
"I have ordered a magisterial inquiry into the entire incident to identify the cause and fix responsibility" for the fire in th</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 10:32:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Unionised RMG workers earn 10pc higher wages than non-unionised ones: Study</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/unionised-rmg-workers-earn-10pc-higher-wages-than-non-unionised-ones-study</link><description>Unionised readymade garment (RMG) factory workers earn 10 per cent higher wages than non-unionised RMG and non-RMG workers, according to a recent study.
At the sectoral level, workers in the RMG industry earn a statistically significant 19 to 22 per cent higher wage, reflecting stronger compliance</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 10:47:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh to become major consumer market by 2030: BIDA</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladesh-to-become-major-consumer-market-by-2030-bida</link><description>Bangladesh Investment Development Authority (BIDA) Executive Chairman Chowdhury Ashik Mahmud Bin Harun today (Sunday) said that Bangladesh is poised to emerge as a major global consumer market by 2030, driven by its strategic geographical location.
“Nearly 2.5 billion people live within four</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 11:02:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Students should focus on acquiring real knowledge: Touhid</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/students-should-focus-on-acquiring-real-knowledge-touhid</link><description>Foreign Affairs Adviser Md Touhid Hossain on Sunday urged students to focus on acquiring real knowledge instead of studying just to pass, as there is no alternative to knowledge-based quality education to build a better future.
“In addition, students should be encouraged to participate in sp</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 11:17:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Benin government says armed forces foil coup attempt</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/africa/benin-government-says-armed-forces-foil-coup-attempt</link><description>Benin's government said on Sunday its armed forces had foiled a coup attempt after a group of soldiers in the West African nation claimed on national television to have seized power.
The attempted coup was the latest threat to democratic rule in the region, where the military has in recent years s</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 11:32:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCP, AB Party, Rashtra Sangskar Andolon form new political alliance</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ncp-ab-party-rashtra-sangskar-andolon-form-new-political-alliance</link><description>National Citizen Party (NCP), Amar Bangladesh Party (AB Party) and Rashtra Sangskar Andolon on Monday launched a new political alliance ahead of the national election.
NCP Convener Nahid Islam made the announcement at a press conference at Dhaka Reporters Unity (DRU) in the afternoon, UNB reports.</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 11:47:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Noman Group faces inquiry into ‘money laundering’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hc-orders-investigation-into-noman-group-for-alleged-money-laundering</link><description>The High Court has ordered the disposal of an application filed with the Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) over alleged corruption and money laundering by a subsidiary of the Noman Group.
The bench of Justice JBM Hassan and Justice Aziz Ahmed Bhuiyan passed the order on Sunday.
Anwar Hossain, a re</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 12:02:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Al-Arafah Islami Bank inaugurated stall at SME Product Fair</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/al-arafah-islami-bank-inaugurated-stall-at-sme-product-fair</link><description>Al-Arafah Islami Bank participated in the 12th National SME Product Fair.
Managing Director (Acting) of the Bank Mohd. Rafat Ullah Khan inaugurated the SME stall at the Bangladesh-China Friendship Conference Center on Sunday (December 7, 2025), according to a press release.
During the inauguratio</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 12:17:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BTRC siege paralyses Agargaon, patients stranded</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/btrc-siege-brings-agargaon-to-a-standstill-leaving-even-patients-trapped</link><description>Thousands of people have been plunged into extreme difficulty as mobile phone traders blocked roads around the Bangladesh Telecommunication Regulatory Commission (BTRC) in Agargaon, bringing traffic to a near standstill.
Access to three major specialised hospitals near the BTRC office—the ch</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 12:32:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Community Bank holds Annual Risk Conference 2025</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/community-bank-holds-annual-risk-conference-2025</link><description>Community Bank Bangladesh PLC held its Annual Risk Conference 2025 on 6th December at the InterContinental Dhaka.
Mr. ANM Moinul Kabir, Director, DOS-2, Bangladesh Bank, attended as the Chief Guest, according to a press release.
Joint Directors Ms. Mahmuda Haque and Mr. M.M. Apurba Abrar were pre</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 12:47:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Azerbaijan to open embassy in Dhaka: Envoy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/azerbaijan-to-open-embassy-in-dhaka-envoy</link><description>Non-resident ambassador of Azerbaijan to Bangladesh, Elchin Huseynli today (Sunday) said that efforts are underway to open an Azerbaijani embassy here after the upcoming general election in Bangladesh.
The envoy made the remarks at a meeting today when Leyla Aliyeva and Arzu Aliyeva, daughters of</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 13:02:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt eyes finest polls in Bangladesh’s history: CA</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-eyes-finest-polls-in-bangladeshs-history-chief-adviser</link><description>Reiterating the government’s commitment to delivering a transparent and peaceful election, Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus on Sunday said the first nationwide election under the caretaker administration aims to be “the finest in the nation’s history.”
“You are</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 13:17:54 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>