<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 05:20:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>BRAC Bank inaugurates two new sub-branches in Shariatpur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/brac-bank-inaugurates-two-new-sub-branches-in-shariatpur</link><description>BRAC Bank has officially inaugurated two new sub-branches in Shariatpur District, bringing the total number of sub-branches in the bank's network to 107, according to a press release.
The sub-branches were inaugurated on October 23, 2025, by Md. Muniruzzaman Molla, Deputy Managing Director and Hea</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 16:26:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US snubs UN meeting on its human rights record</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-snubs-un-meeting-on-its-human-rights-record</link><description>A UN meeting to review the United States' human rights record opened without the US on Friday, with rights groups calling the absence a worrying sign of Washington's retreat from global engagement on such issues.
The universal periodic review process is a chance for governments and rights groups t</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 16:41:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Family accuses 'Boro Sajjad' of ordering Sarwar’s shooting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/family-accuses-boro-sajjad-of-ordering-sarwars-shooting</link><description>The father of slain Chattogram BNP activist Sarwar Hossain Babla has alleged that his son was killed on the orders of fugitive gang leader Sajjad Hossain, known locally as “Boro Sajjad”.
Sajjad, who is currently abroad, has been named as the prime suspect in a murder case filed by Sarw</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 17:56:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dreams before Aug 5 unfulfilled even after 15 months: Nur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/dreams-before-aug-5-unfulfilled-even-after-15-months-nur</link><description>Gono Odhikar Parishad President Nurul Haque Nur has said the aspirations people held before Aug 5 last year have not been fulfilled even 15 months later.
Speaking at a youth rally against drugs, terrorism and extortion at the central Shaheed Minar in Narayanganj on Friday evening, he said change c</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 18:11:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Seven ‘drug traders’ charged over murder of DU Chhatra Dal leader Shammo</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/seven-drug-traders-charged-over-murder-of-du-chhatra-dal-leader-shammo</link><description>Detective police have pressed charges against seven suspects, all identified as “drug dealers”, in the murder case of Jatiyatabadi Chhatra Dal leader SM Shahriar Alam Shammo.
Nearly five months after the murder, Inspector Md Akhtar Morshed of the Detective Branch (DB) submitted the cha</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 18:57:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Local goods behind 75.6pc of FY26 Q1 inflation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/local-goods-behind-756pc-of-fy26-q1-inflation</link><description>Bangladesh's inflation profile tilted further towards domestic sources, with home-grown supply constraints and cost pressures increasingly eclipsing imported shocks, according to the Bangladesh Bank analysis on inflation for the first quarter of the fiscal year 2025-26.
Domestically produced goods</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 19:12:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh pursues two-dozen plans to secure duty-free market access</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladesh-pursues-two-dozen-plans-to-secure-duty-free-market-access</link><description>Bangladesh pursues over two-dozen plans to secure duty-free market access to major trade-partner countries for effective graduation from least-developed country (LDC) status, sources say.
The ministry of commerce (MoC) has sketched out the sweeping, time-bound action plan under Monitoring and Eval</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 02:19:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Investors' Woes In 5 Banks' Mergers: Experts for securing interests of small stakeholders</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/investors-woes-in-5-banks-mergers-experts-for-securing-interests-of-small-stakeholders</link><description>Bankers and financial-sector experts make a strong plea that interests of the small shareholders should be protected in the merger of five Islamic banks as the regulatory declaration nullifying their net asset value for past plunders beggared them.
The central bank had failed to regulate all the c</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 02:34:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Major solar power plant to replace coal-based one at Matarbari</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/major-solar-power-plant-to-replace-coal-based-one-at-matarbari</link><description>A major 430-megawatt grid-tied solar-power plant is being established at Matarbari in Cox's Bazar instead of planned coal-fired facilities at the seaside transport-economic hub.
Officials say Coal Power Generation Company Bangladesh Limited (CPGCBL) has decided to conduct detailed feasibility stud</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 02:49:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Summit Alliance Port posts record profit of Tk 675m in FY25</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/summit-alliance-port-posts-record-profit-of-tk-675m-in-fy25</link><description>Summit Alliance Port has reported its highest-ever annual profit of Tk 675 million for FY25, marking a significant increase driven by higher revenue from container handling in export, import, and freight services.
The company, a market leader in the Inland Container Depot (ICD) and Container Freig</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 03:04:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>COP30 Summit: More than $5.5 billion announced for TFFF</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/cop30-summit-more-than-55-billion-announced-for-tfff</link><description>During a lunch at the Belém Climate Summit, President Lula received leaders from over 30 countries, the UN Secretary-General, and a representative from the World Bank on Friday at the COP30 Leader's Summit, in Belém.
The Tropical Forest Forever Facility (TFFF) was officially launched</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 03:19:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DSEX sinks below 5000-mark as Islamic banks' merger dampens market sentiment</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/dsex-sinks-below-5000-mark-as-islamic-banks-merger-dampens-market-sentiment</link><description>Toggle navigation
Stocks continued their downward trajectory this week, falling below the psychological threshold of 5,000-mark for the first time in four months amid persistent bearish sentiment.
Market analysts said investors had been suffering from a confidence crisis for a long time, while th</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 04:22:47 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>