<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 12:38:20 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Prime Bank customers to enjoy exclusive discounts on Hyundai vehicles</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/prime-bank-customers-to-enjoy-exclusive-discounts-on-hyundai-vehicles</link><description>Prime Bank PLC. customers in Bangladesh will now enjoy exclusive discounts on Hyundai vehicles.
Fair Technology Limited is the official manufacturer &amp; authorized distributor for Hyundai passenger vehicles in Bangladesh. In this regard, an agreement was signed recently at Prime Bank’s Corpora</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 11:07:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Israel says flotilla 'provocation' is over</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/israel-says-flotilla-provocation-is-over</link><description>Israel's foreign ministry said none of the flotilla's vessels had breached its Gaza blockade, and that what it called the "provocation" was now over.
One last vessel remained at a distance, the ministry said on its X account.
"If it approaches, its attempt to enter an active conflict zone and bre</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 11:22:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Flotilla to reach Gaza despite Israeli threats: Shahidul Alam</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/flotilla-to-reach-gaza-despite-israeli-threats-shahidul-alam</link><description>Bangladeshi activist and renowned photographer Shahidul Alam has issued a video message from ‘The Conscience Flotilla’, which is currently sailing towards Gaza.
Alam, who has joined the ‘Media Flotilla’ mission organised by the Freedom Flotilla Coalition to break the silenc</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 10:38:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Earthquake death toll rises to 72 in the Philippines as survivors recall moment when tragedy struck</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/earthquake-death-toll-rises-to-72-in-the-philippines-as-survivors-recall-moment-when-tragedy-struck</link><description>When firefighters brought out the body of his 4-year-old son in a bag from a budget hotel demolished by a 6.9-magnitude earthquake in the central Philippines, Isagani Gelig stooped down and gently stroked the black cadaver bag for several minutes, trying to feel his child's remains inside for the l</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 10:53:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Four injured, apparent attacker shot by police near UK synagogue on Yom Kippur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/four-injured-apparent-attacker-shot-by-police-near-uk-synagogue-on-yom-kippur</link><description>British police said on Thursday four people had been injured after reports of stabbings and a car being driven at pedestrians near a synagogue in Manchester in northwest England, and that officers had shot the suspected offender.
Greater Manchester Police said officers had been called to the incid</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 11:23:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tourists flood Cox’s Bazar despite storm warnings</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/holidaymakers-defy-storm-caution-to-celebrate-durga-puja-on-coxs-bazar-beach</link><description>Clouds blanketed the sky and relentless rain battered the shore, but Cox’s Bazar still heaves with Durga Puja crowds, where every hotel room was snapped up as holidaymakers defied the storm to revel by the sea despite a cautionary signal No. 3.
Thousands from across the country have flocked</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 11:38:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Heavy to very heavy rainfall likely in Dhaka, 6 other divisions</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/heavy-to-very-heavy-rainfall-likely-in-dhaka-6-other-divisions</link><description>Bangladesh Meteorological Department (BMD) has predicted heavy to very heavy rainfall at many places in seven divisions due to deep depression over the Northwest Bay and adjoining area during the next 48 hours commencing at 3 pm on Thursday.
“Under the influence of deep depression over</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 12:08:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>None can destroy communal harmony in Bangladesh: Adviser Nurjahan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/none-can-destroy-communal-harmony-in-bangladesh-adviser-nurjahan</link><description>Health and Family Welfare adviser Nurjahan Begum on Thursday said no one can spoil the communal harmony in Bangladesh.
"No one can destroy communal harmony in Bangladesh. Humanity and service are respected like religion. It is important for us to remember this (spirit) from our respective places,"</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 12:38:20 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>