<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 07:24:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Three killed in Madaripur road crash</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/three-killed-in-madaripur-road-crash</link><description>Three people have been killed after a bus and a truck collided near the Arial Khan Bridge on the Dhaka-Bhanga Expressway in Shibchar upazila of Madaripur district.
Zarirul Islam, chief of Shibchar Police Station, said the accident occurred around 9:45 am on Tuesday, reports bdnews24.com
One perso</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 05:00:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CHANDPUR FARMERS IN ABJECT POVERTY: 200 acres of land remain inundated since 2016</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/chandpur-farmers-in-abject-poverty-200-acres-of-land-remain-inundated-since-2016</link><description>CHANDPUR, Dec 01: More than a hundred marginal farmers of Hajiganj Upazila's Badarpur remain in acute poverty as they are unable to utilise 200 acres of their farmland since 2016 due to waterlogging.
Water could not be drained from their land as a culvert under a village road was blocked with soil</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 05:15:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Samsung unveils first multi-folding phone as competition set to heat up</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/samsung-unveils-first-multi-folding-phone-as-competition-set-to-heat-up</link><description>Samsung Electronics unveiled on Tuesday its first multi-folding smartphone, in a bid to strengthen its position in a sector of the phone market where competition is expected to intensify.
The launch of the Galaxy Z TriFold marks Samsung's bid to reinforce its footing in a segment where Chinese riv</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 05:30:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India rice imports suspended at Hili Land Port</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/india-rice-imports-suspended-at-hili-land-port</link><description>Rice imports from India have been suspended at Dinajpur’s Hili Land Port. Other goods are, however, being imported and exported as usual.
The land port stopped importing rice completely on Monday, reports bdnews24.com.
Over the past four months, 234,270 tonnes of rice have been imported thr</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 05:45:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UN chief proposes 18pc job cuts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/un-chief-proposes-slashing-2026-budget-by-577-million-cutting-18pc-of-jobs</link><description>United Nations Secretary-General Antonio Guterres on Monday formally proposed slashing the core UN budget for next year by $577 million and cutting more than 18 per cent of jobs.
Guterres is seeking ways to improve efficiency and cut costs as the world body turns 80 this year amid a cash crisis, d</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 06:00:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Liquor factory recovered at CU; two arrested</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/liquor-factory-recovered-at-cu-two-arrested</link><description>The proctorial body of Chittagong University (CU), with the help of the university police outpost, has recovered an illegal liquor factory in a makeshift room on the campus and detained two individuals.
The detainees were identified as Suman Chakma and his associate. Suman had been living and farm</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 05:30:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique expresses gratitude for 'unity and solidarity' in difficult time</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-rahman-expresses-gratitude-for-unity-and-solidarity-in-difficult-time</link><description>Tarique Rahman, the son of BNP Chairperson Khaleda Zia - who is undergoing treatment in a hospital, has expressed his gratitude to everyone for wishing for his mother’s recovery.
The BNP acting chairman said in a Facebook post on Tuesday: "The widespread expressions of concern from leaders,</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 05:45:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Man stabbed to death in Dhaka’s Kamrangirchar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/man-stabbed-to-death-in-dhakas-kamrangirchar</link><description>A man has been stabbed to death in Dhaka’s Kamrangirchar.
The victim has been identified as 25-year-old Rocky, an employee at a local grocer.
The incident occurred in front of the Boro Gram Bazar Ashrafabad High School around 3:30am on Tuesday.
Locals rescued Rocky and took him to Dhaka Me</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 06:00:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Madaripur road crash leaves 3 dead</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/madaripur-road-crash-leaves-3-dead</link><description>Three people were killed and seven others injured when a truck crashed into a bus on Dhaka-Bhanga Expressway over Arial Khan Bridge in Shibchar upazila of Madaripur district on Tuesday.
One of the deceased was identified as Munir Sheikh, 35, of Najirpur upazila in Pirojpur district.
Md Sabuj, ser</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 06:15:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hong Kong leader orders independent probe into fire that killed 151</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/hong-kong-leader-orders-independent-probe-into-fire-that-killed-151</link><description>Hong Kong's leader said on Tuesday an independent committee would be established to investigate the cause of the city's deadliest fire in decades, including oversight of renovations blamed for the disaster that has claimed 151 lives.
Police have arrested 13 people for suspected manslaughter in a c</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 06:30:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mobile phone traders at Jamuna Future Park close shops indefinitely</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/mobile-phone-traders-at-jamuna-future-park-close-shops-indefinitely</link><description>The Mobile Business Community Bangladesh (MBCB), Jamuna Future Park branch, has announced an indefinite closure of the shopping mall’s mobile market, effective from Tuesday.
Traders said they made the decision after receiving no response from the government despite repeated calls for discuss</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 06:45:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump invites Israel's Netanyahu to White House</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/trump-invites-israels-netanyahu-to-white-house</link><description>US President Donald Trump has invited Israel's Benjamin Netanyahu to the White House in the "near future," the prime minister's office said on Monday, shortly after Trump said Israel should maintain a strong and true dialogue with Syria.
A visit to the White House would mark the Israeli prime mini</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 07:00:46 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>