<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 18:40:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Govt moves to merge BIDA, BEZA, BEPZA, MIDA</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/govt-moves-to-merge-bida-beza-bepza-mida</link><description>The interim government on Monday decided to merge all investment promotion agencies (IPAs) in Bangladesh in a move aimed at simplifying procedures and making the country more investor-friendly.
The decision was taken at a meeting of the IPA Governing Board, chaired by Chief Adviser Prof Muhammad Y</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 15:22:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rent of Ekushey Book Fair reduced by 25pc</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rent-of-ekushey-book-fair-reduced-by-25pc</link><description>Cultural Affairs Adviser Mostofa Sarwar Farooki has asked the authorities concerned to reduce the rent of this year's Amar Ekushey Book Fair stall by 25 per cent.
The adviser gave the directive in response to requests from publishers, the adviser said in a Facebook post.
“Following appeals</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 15:37:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Italy visa application submissions suspended worldwide from February 11 to 18</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/italy-visa-application-submissions-suspended-worldwide-from-february-11-to-18</link><description>The Embassy of Italy in Dhaka on Monday announced a temporary worldwide suspension of visa application submissions in mid-February due to scheduled technical maintenance of the Italian visa processing system.
In an advisory, the embassy said that no visa applications of any category will be accept</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 15:52:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ACC summons Summit Group chairman for questioning over ‘illicit wealth’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/acc-summons-summit-group-chairman-for-questioning-over-illicit-wealth</link><description>Summit Group Chairman Muhammed Aziz Khan has been summoned by the Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) for questioning over allegations of acquiring wealth beyond means and money laundering.
He has been asked to appear on Thursday to provide statements, according to the graft watchdog.
The commission</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 16:07:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pre-orders open for Mizanur Rahman Sohel’s ‘Content Creator’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/others/pre-orders-open-for-mizanur-rahman-sohels-content-creator</link><description>Pre-orders have officially opened for Content Creator, the latest book by renowned writer and journalist Mizanur Rahman Sohel, aimed at individuals aspiring to build a successful career as content creators on digital platforms.
The book is now available for pre-order at a special discounted price</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 16:22:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Animal, poultry feed industry to get 20pc power rebate</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/animal-poultry-feed-industry-to-get-20pc-power-rebate</link><description>The interim government is going to offer a 20 per cent rebate on electricity bills to reduce production costs in four sectors, including animal and poultry feed manufacturing.
The decision was announced in a media statement issued by the Ministry of Fisheries and Livestock on Monday.
The statemen</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 16:37:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Minorities must not be treated as mere vote banks: CGS roundtable</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/minorities-must-not-be-treated-as-mere-vote-banks-cgs-roundtable</link><description>Speakers at a discussion on Monday highlighted the importance of equal rights and opinions of all citizens in an accountable and participatory democratic system, particularly emphasising the necessity of ensuring meaningful participation of minority communities in the context of the upcoming Nation</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 16:44:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Laundering country’s wealth to stop forever if voted to power: Jamaat ameer</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/laundering-countrys-wealth-to-stop-forever-if-jamaat-comes-to-power-shafiqur-rahman</link><description>Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islam Ameer Dr Shafiqur Rahman has vowed that stealing the country’s money will be permanently stopped if his party assumes power.
“Those who have stolen the country’s money will be held strictly accountable, and the money will be recovered from them,” h</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 16:59:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP 'practiced' polling booth capture in attacking NCP's Dhaka-18 candidate: Hasnat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bnp-practiced-polling-booth-capture-in-attacking-ncps-dhaka-18-candidate-hasnat</link><description>National Citizen Party (NCP) Chief Organiser (South Region) and Comilla-4 candidate Hasnat Abdullah on Monday alleged that the BNP started a “practice match” of capturing polling booths by carrying out attacks on NCP election campaigns and its candidate in Dhaka-18.
“Today, the k</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 17:14:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Bomb’ attack at Ctg BNP candidate’s rally</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crude-bombs-hurled-at-bnp-candidate-ershad-ullahs-election-rally-in-chattogram</link><description>Crude bombs have allegedly been hurled at an election rally of BNP candidate Ershad Ullah in the Chattogram-8 constituency, with a party leader blaming the Jamaat-e-Islami for the attack.
Five people threw improvised explosives in quick succession at the rally in Boalkhali Upazila on Monday evenin</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 17:29:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Israel retrieves last hostage body from Gaza in boost for Trump plan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/israel-retrieves-last-hostage-body-from-gaza-in-boost-for-trump-plan</link><description>Israel has retrieved the remains of the last remaining hostage held in Gaza, the military said on Monday, fulfilling a key condition of the initial phase of US President Donald Trump's plan to end the Gaza war.
The remains of police officer Ran Gvili have been identified and will be returned for b</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 17:44:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US envoy Christensen lauds Chittagong Port reforms, pledges support for modernisation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/us-envoy-christensen-lauds-chittagong-port-reforms-pledges-support-for-modernisation</link><description>US Ambassador Brent Christensen has praised reforms at Chittagong Port and pledged cooperation to modernise the facility.
Christensen led a delegation to the port on Monday, where its Chairman Rear Admiral Sayed Mohammad Moniruzzaman outlined progress made under the interim government since the Ju</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 17:59:52 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>