<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 05:03:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>LafargeHolcim unveils high-performance concrete product Powercrete</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/lafargeholcim-unveils-high-performance-concrete-product-powercrete</link><description>LafargeHolcim Bangladesh has launched "Powercrete", a specialised high-performance product designed for the ready-mix concrete (RMX) segment.
The product was unveiled at a technical seminar titled "Durable High-Performance Concrete for Sustainable Infrastructure in Bangladesh" on Sunday at a city</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 00:45:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Kay &amp; Que trading volume jumps over 70pc after Starlink deal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/kay-que-trading-volume-jumps-over-70pc-after-starlink-deal</link><description>Kay &amp; Que's share trading volume surged by over 70 per cent on Sunday following the news that it had secured a deal to sell Starlink internet connections in the country.
The listed IT company on Thursday disclosed that it had become the sales agent for Starlink Satellite Internet Service in Bangla</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 01:00:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Body formed to scrutinise report of Pay Commission</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/body-formed-to-scrutinise-report-of-pay-commission</link><description>The government on Sunday formed a committee to scrutinise and submit recommendations on the reports of National Pay Commission, Judicial Service Pay Commission, and Armed Forces Pay Committee.
Headed by Cabinet Division Secretary, the committee also consists of secretaries of Ministry of Public Ad</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 01:15:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Indiscriminate netting of juvenile fish in Chandpur stir shortage fears</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/indiscriminate-netting-of-juvenile-fish-in-chandpur-stir-shortage-fears</link><description>Indiscriminate netting of juvenile fishes in the Meghna River in Chandpur stirred fear among some veteran fishermen and merchants that serious fish crisis may occur in the next few years in the district.
Sources at the District Fisheries Office in Chandpur said many among the 46,000 registered fis</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 01:30:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Private sector growth slows in January</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/private-sector-growth-slows-in-january</link><description>Private sector activity continued to expand in January, albeit at a slower pace, as the Purchasing Managers' Index (PMI) eased to 53.9 from the previous month.
The moderation signals sustained growth momentum, though at a more measured rate amid softer global conditions.
Released on Sunday, the l</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 01:45:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC committed to free, fair, inclusive polls: CEC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ec-committed-to-free-fair-inclusive-polls-cec</link><description>Chief Election Commissioner (CEC) AMM Nasir Uddin on Sunday said the commission is committed to delivering a free, fair and inclusive national election, scheduled for February 12.
Keeping this in view, the Election Commission (EC) is addressing challenges such as misinformation while prioritising</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 02:00:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DU Sada Dal urges voters to back patriotic party</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/du-sada-dal-urges-voters-to-back-patriotic-party</link><description>Ahead of the upcoming 13th Jatiya Sangsad (JS) election, the Dhaka University (DU) Sada Dal, pro-BNP teachers' organisation, has urged citizens to vote for a patriotic party that upholds the spirit of the Liberation War and the July mass uprising, and has proven experience in governing the state.</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 02:15:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Overseas Labour Market: Govt orders crackdown on job doc forgery, fraud</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/overseas-labour-market-govt-orders-crackdown-on-job-doc-forgery-fraud</link><description>Chief Adviser Prof Muhammad Yunus directs urgent action against forgery and fake skill-training certificates as such practices are "damaging Bangladesh's reputation" on the international labour market.
The direction was issued Sunday at a meeting of the governing board of the National Skills Devel</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 02:30:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Growing gap visible in EC's efforts to ensure fair polls: TIB</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/growing-gap-visible-in-ecs-efforts-to-ensure-fair-polls-tib</link><description>A growing gap is becoming visible in the efforts of the Election Commission (EC) and other stakeholders to create a free, fair, transparent, and level playing field, as well as to organise a peaceful election, according to a TIB study.
In particular, the effective exercise of the powers vested in</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 02:45:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nagorik Oikko's Manna withdraws from Dhaka-18</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/manna-withdraws-from-dhaka-18-citing-high-election-costs</link><description>Nagorik Oikko President Mahmudur Rahman Manna has withdrawn from contesting in the Dhaka-18 seat in the national election, though he remains a candidate in Bogura-2.
Manna announced the decision on Sunday night through a Facebook post.
Attempts to reach him by phone later were unsuccessful.
He w</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 03:00:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ctg port strike withdrawn as interim govt backs out of NCT deal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ctg-port-strike-withdrawn-as-interim-govt-backs-out-of-nct-deal</link><description>The indefinite strike called by the Chittagong Port Protection Struggle Council has been suspended after the interim government announced it would not proceed with handing over operations of the New Mooring Container Terminal (NCT) to UAE-based DP World.
On Monday at 12:30 am, Md Ibrahim Khokon, o</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 03:15:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP, Jamaat vow deep reforms to boost revenue mobilisation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bnp-jamaat-vow-deep-reforms-to-boost-revenue-mobilisation</link><description>The major political parties have placed domestic revenue mobilisation at the centre of their respective economic agenda, setting specific targets to raise Bangladesh's tax-to-gross domestic product (GDP) ratio amid shrinking fiscal space.
The Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) has pledged to incre</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 04:24:05 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>