<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 14:22:47 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Prof Yunus calls for stronger, more inclusive BNCC to empower youths</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/prof-yunus-calls-for-stronger-more-inclusive-bncc-to-empower-youths</link><description>Chief Adviser Prof Muhammad Yunus has called for enhancing the quality and inclusivity of the Bangladesh National Cadet Corps (BNCC) as part of a long-term vision to engage the nation’s youths in leadership, discipline and national development.
The Chief Adviser made the remarks after a pres</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 11:19:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rohingya survivor recalls deadly boat sinking, more bodies found</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/rohingya-survivor-recalls-deadly-boat-sinking-more-bodies-found</link><description>The death toll from the sinking of a boat carrying members of Myanmar’s persecuted Rohingya Muslim minority climbed to 27 on Tuesday, as a survivor recalled a harrowing journey that left him floating for days in the Andaman Sea.
“I saw one person die. They drowned,” Iman Sharif t</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 11:34:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>35.2pc growth of remittance inflow till Nov 10</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/352pc-growth-of-remittance-inflow-till-nov-10</link><description>Inflow of remittances witnessed a year-on-year growth of 35.2 percent reaching US$1,109 million in the ten days of November, according to the latest data of Bangladesh Bank (BB) issued on Tuesday.
Last year, during the same period, the country’s remittance inflow was $820 million.
During th</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 11:49:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh Bank expands trade finance scope for OBUs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/bangladesh-bank-expands-trade-finance-scope-for-obus</link><description>The central bank has amended key provisions of its directive on Offshore Banking Units (OBUs) of scheduled banks, aiming to facilitate the country’s foreign trade, officials said.
The Bangladesh Bank (BB) on Monday issued a notification amending the OBU guidelines, originally released on Jan</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 12:04:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Treason trial against Hasina, 285 others set to begin</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/treason-trial-against-hasina-285-others-set-to-begin</link><description>A Dhaka court has transferred the sedition case filed against deposed prime minister Sheikh Hasina and 285 others on charges of taking part in “anti-state activities and attempts to oust the interim government” to a judicial court.
Dhaka Metropolitan Magistrate Ishrat Jenifar Jerin on</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 12:19:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CMM seeks enhanced security from DMP following broad daylight murder</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cmm-seeks-enhanced-security-from-dmp-following-broad-daylight-murder</link><description>The Chief Metropolitan Magistrate (CMM) of Dhaka has written to the Dhaka Metropolitan Police (DMP) commissioner requesting him to ensure security in and around the court premises following a broad daylight murder near the court area.
CMM Mohammad Mostafizur Rahman sent the letter on Tuesday, acco</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 12:34:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UNICEF says Israel blocking one million syringes needed to vaccinate Gaza children</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/unicef-says-israel-blocking-one-million-syringes-needed-to-vaccinate-gaza-children</link><description>UNICEF said on Tuesday essential items including syringes to vaccinate children and bottles for baby formula are being denied entry into Gaza by Israel, preventing aid agencies from reaching those in need in the war-devastated territory.
As UNICEF undertakes a mass children’s vaccination cam</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 12:49:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Southeast Bank holds school banking awareness, engagement program in Chattogram</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/southeast-bank-holds-school-banking-awareness-engagement-program-in-chattogram</link><description>Southeast Bank PLC. recently organized a School Banking Awareness and Engagement Program on “Introducing Collective Features and Benefits of SoutheastEduFin” for the principals, headmasters, governing bodies, and guardians of 18 schools located in the Patenga area of Chattogram.
Accord</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 13:04:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Government stresses formation of TCC to boost sustainability in leather industry</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/government-stresses-formation-of-tcc-to-boost-sustainability-in-leather-industry</link><description>The government has emphasized the formation of a Tripartite Consultative Council (TCC) for the tannery sector to strengthen social dialogue and ensure sustainable development of Bangladesh’s leather industry. The call was made during a discussion titled “Status Quo of the Tannery Sector</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 13:19:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dengue: 3 dead; 912 hospitalised in 24 hours</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dengue-3-dead-912-hospitalised-in-24-hours</link><description>Three more deaths were reported from dengue in 24 hours till Tuesday morning, raising the number of fatalities from the mosquito-borne disease in Bangladesh to 318 this year.
During the period, 912 more patients were hospitalised with viral fever, raising the total infected-case to 80, 634 this ye</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 13:34:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC invites 12 parties on first day of talks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-invites-12-parties-on-first-day-of-talks</link><description>The Election Commission has invited 12 political parties to join discussions on the first day of its planned dialogue series beginning Thursday, ahead of the February elections.
On Tuesday, EC Secretary Akhtar Ahmed said the discussions will continue throughout the month in several phases.
The co</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 13:49:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ACC to prosecute 4 recruiting agencies</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/four-recruiting-agencies-face-corruption-charges-over-embezzlement-laundering</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission is going to take legal steps against five people from four recruiting agencies over allegations of embezzlement and money laundering through syndication while sending workers to Malaysia.
On Tuesday, ACC Director General Md Akhtar Hossain said the cases will bring ch</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 14:04:48 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>