<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 12:50:32 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Drone operation banned in and around airports</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/drone-operation-banned-in-and-around-airports</link><description>Drone operations have been banned in and around all airports, including Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport, due to national security risks and safe air navigation.
The Civil Aviation Authority of Bangladesh (CAAB) issued a letter in this regard informing all the authorities concerned, said a P</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 09:38:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NDF announces 119 candidates ahead of elections</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ndf-announces-119-candidates-ahead-of-elections</link><description>The 20-party alliance led by Anwar Hossain Manju’s Jatiya Party-JP and Anisul Islam Mahmud’s National Democratic Front-NDF has announced candidates for 119 constituencies in the upcoming 13th parliamentary election.
The NDF revealed its candidates at a press conference held at Hotel Sh</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 09:53:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Police fully prepared to ensure fair, festive, peaceful elections: IGP</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/police-fully-prepared-to-ensure-fair-festive-peaceful-elections-igp</link><description>Inspector General of Police (IGP) Baharul Alam on Tuesday said that Bangladesh Police is fully capable of ensuring a fair, peaceful, and festive environment in the upcoming referendum and the 13th national election slated for February 12.
“We’re completely ready for holding the forthco</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 10:08:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UN expert alarmed by violent attacks on Daily Star, Prothom Alo</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/un-expert-alarmed-by-violent-attacks-on-daily-star-prothom-alo</link><description>Mob attacks on leading media outlets and cultural centres in Bangladesh are deeply alarming and must be investigated promptly and effectively by the government and the perpetrators brought to justice without delay, a UN expert said on Tuesday.
The interim government has ‘largely followed the</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 10:23:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Deed of Agreement signed between Trust Bank &amp; Heguang Electronic Distribution Co. Ltd. (OPPO Bangladesh)</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/deed-of-agreement-signed-between-trust-bank-heguang-electronic-distribution-co-ltd-oppo-bangladesh</link><description>A Deed of Agreement has been signed between Trust Bank PLC and Heguang Electronic Distribution Co. Ltd. (OPPO Bangladesh).
The signing ceremony was attended by Mr. Md. Kamal Hossain Sarkar, Deputy Managing Director and Head of the Islamic Banking Division of Trust Bank PLC, along with other senior</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 10:38:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hindu groups protest outside Bangladesh Deputy High Commission in Kolkata</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hindu-groups-protest-outside-bangladesh-deputy-high-commission-in-kolkata</link><description>Hindu nationalist organisations staged another demonstration outside Bangladesh's Deputy High Commission in Kolkata on Tuesday, but police intercepted them before reaching the mission premises.
The Bangiya Hindu Jagaran Mancha organised a protest march starting from Sealdah Railway Station. When h</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 10:53:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>All online VAT related activities to be conducted thru eVAT system: NBR</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/all-online-vat-related-activities-to-be-conducted-thru-evat-system-nbr</link><description>The National Board of Revenue (NBR) on Tuesday announced that all online value-added tax (VAT)-related activities will now be conducted through the eVAT System, following the renaming of the existing iVAS platform.
According to a press release of the NBR, the decision was taken to eliminate confus</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 10:39:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Australia invites Israeli President Herzog for official visit</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/australia-invites-israeli-president-herzog-for-official-visit</link><description>Australian Prime Minister Anthony Albanese said on Tuesday he called Israeli President Isaac Herzog and invited him to visit Australia, expressing his shock and dismay over the attack at the Jewish community Chanukah event on Bondi Beach last week.
Herzog said he would accept the invitation and me</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 10:54:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Who are the opposition candidates in Central African Republic’s presidential election?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/who-are-the-opposition-candidates-in-central-african-republics-presidential-election</link><description>President Faustin-Archange Touadera will face six other candidates in a presidential election to be held in Central African Republic on December 28, after a court rejected attempts to bar his two main rivals.
Here are brief details of Touadera’s opponents:
The Reuters Daily Briefing newslet</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 11:09:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Newborn found dead at Dhaka’s Chawkbazar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/newborn-found-dead-at-dhakas-chawkbazar</link><description>Police recovered the body of a male newborn, aged around one day, from a lane in Chandni Ghat area of Chawk Bazar in Dhaka capital on Tuesday afternoon.
The newborn, found in an unconscious state wrapped in black plastic, was rushed to Dhaka Medical College Hospital where physicians declared him d</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 11:24:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DU Chhatra Dal rallies to welcome Tarique’s return</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/chhatra-dal-holds-welcome-procession-on-du-campus-over-tariques-homecoming</link><description>The Dhaka University wing of Jatiyatabadi Chhatra Dal, the student wing of BNP, have taken out a “welcome rally” on the campus ahead of the homecoming of BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman.
The procession started from the Payra Chattar at Teacher-Student Centre (TSC) around 3:45pm on T</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 11:39:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Police, admin support emboldens CEC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cec-nasir-uddin-says-assurance-of-support-from-police-breaucracy-boosted-his-confidence</link><description>Chief Election Commissioner AMM Nasir Uddin has said assurances from the field administration and police have boosted his confidence about holding a fair election.
He ordered election officials and police to maintain neutrality to ensure the credibility of the parliamentary polls and referendum.</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 11:54:34 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>