<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 16:30:40 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Dhaka Bank, UNCDF partner to promote digital financial literacy for migrant families under Shafal Programme</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/dhaka-bank-uncdf-partner-to-promote-digital-financial-literacy-for-migrant-families-under-shafal-programme</link><description>Dhaka Bank PLC, in partnership with the Shafal Programme; a joint initiative of the United Nations Capital Development Fund (UNCDF) and the Embassy of Switzerland in Bangladesh has launched the “Digital Financial Literacy (DFL) for Migrant Workers &amp; Families” initiative to strengthen di</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 13:55:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Britain’s BBC ‘determined to fight’ any Trump case, chair tells staff</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/britains-bbc-determined-to-fight-any-trump-case-chair-tells-staff</link><description>Britain’s BBC is “determined to fight” any legal action filed by US President Donald Trump, saying on Monday there was no basis for a defamation case over its editing of one of his speeches.
Trump said on Friday he would likely sue the BBC this week for as much as $5 billion afte</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 14:10:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Citizens Bank PLC holds Annual Risk Conference 2025</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/citizens-bank-plc-holds-annual-risk-conference-2025</link><description>Citizens Bank PLC organized Annual Risk Conference 2025 at its Head Office in Dhaka recently, according to a press release.
Mr. A.N.M. Moinul Kabir, Director, Dept. of Offsite Supervision, Bangladesh Bank inaugurated the conference as the chief guest and delivered his valuable guidelines regarding</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 14:25:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BRAC Bank starts comprehensive training to groom new SME entrepreneurs in Sirajganj</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/brac-bank-starts-comprehensive-training-to-groom-new-sme-entrepreneurs-in-sirajganj</link><description>BRAC Bank has formally launched the second batch of intensive training for promising SME business owners in Sirajganj under the Entrepreneurship Development Programme of the Finance Division of the Ministry of Finance and Bangladesh Bank.
BRAC Bank, with support from the Finance Division of the Mi</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 14:40:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jubo Dal leader shot dead in Pallabi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/jubo-dal-leader-shot-dead-in-pallabi</link><description>A Jatiyatabadi Jubo Dal leader has been shot dead in Dhaka’s Pallabi, police say.
On Monday at 7pm, three masked men wearing helmets entered a hardware shop near C Block, close to the old police station, and shot Golam Kibria at close range.
Local resident said Kibria was the member secreta</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 14:55:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh Election: EC to launch mobile app for postal balloting Tuesday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-election-ec-to-launch-mobile-app-for-postal-balloting-tuesday</link><description>The Election Commission is set to launch a mobile app ‘Postal Vote BD’ on Tuesday (November 18) for a particular section of voters including expatriates to register to vote through the postal balloting in the 13th parliamentary election.
The ‘Postal Vote BD’ mobile app will</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 15:10:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Russian missile strike kills three, wounds 10 in Kharkiv region, Ukraine says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/russian-missile-strike-kills-three-wounds-10-in-kharkiv-region-ukraine-says</link><description>A Russian missile strike on the eastern Ukrainian city of Balakliia killed three people, with three teenagers among the 10 wounded, Kharkiv regional officials said on Monday.
The overnight attack damaged multi-storey residence blocks and destroyed scores of cars in the city centre, Oleh Synehubov,</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 15:25:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Conviction affirms no one is above law: Prof Yunus</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/conviction-affirms-no-one-is-above-law-prof-yunus</link><description>Chief Adviser Prof Muhammad Yunus on Monday said Bangladesh will face future challenges with courage and humility, highlighting that the country is now reengaging with global standards of accountability.
"With commitment to the rule of law, human rights, and each person’s potential, justice</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 15:30:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Smoke triggers panic at Dhaka airport, a month after cargo fire</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/smoke-triggers-panic-at-dhaka-airport-a-month-after-cargo-fire</link><description>Passengers at Dhaka’s Shahjalal International Airport have been thrown into panic after smoke appeared near the departure terminal, a month after a major blaze at the airport’s Cargo Village.
On Monday at 3:15pm, smoke was spotted outside the Terminal No. 1, said Fire Service duty offi</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 15:45:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCP, Samajtantrik Dal get final registration from EC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ncp-samajtantrik-dal-get-final-registration-from-ec</link><description>The National Citizen Party and Bangladesh Samajtantrik Dal (Marxist) have received final registration from the Election Commission (EC).
As no objections were filed against the parties, the EC issued the official gazette on Monday.
With this, both parties will be able to contest the upcoming elec</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 16:00:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>35.2pc growth of remittance inflow till Nov 16</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/352pc-growth-of-remittance-inflow-till-nov-16</link><description>Inflow of remittances witnessed a year-on-year growth of 35.2 percent reaching US$1,697 million in the 16 days of November, according to the latest data of Bangladesh Bank (BB) issued on Monday.
Last year, during the same period, the country's remittance inflow was $1,255 million, reports BSS.
Du</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 16:15:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Political parties say EC lacks resolve, independence to deliver credible polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/political-parties-say-ec-lacks-resolve-independence-to-deliver-credible-polls</link><description>Political parties taking part in the Election Commission’s ongoing dialogues have delivered a blunt warning: without independence and resolve, the commission cannot hope to deliver a credible national election.
Their criticism on Monday laid bare a widening crisis of confidence in the body e</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 16:30:40 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>