<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 21:17:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Experts blame lack of awareness for rising ‘Diabetic Foot’ amputations</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/experts-blame-lack-of-awareness-for-rising-diabetic-foot-amputations</link><description>An alarming number of people in Bangladesh are losing their feet due to complications from ‘diabetic foot’ disease, caused largely by ignorance and negligence, experts have warned.
Speaking at a discussion marking International Podiatry Day 2025, they stressed that increased awareness</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 16:47:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP condemns Bagerhat journalist’s killing, warns of destabilisation attempt</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bnp-condemns-bagerhat-journalists-killing-warns-of-destabilisation-attempt</link><description>BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir on Wednesday night condemned the killing of Bagerhat journalist SM Hayat Uddin, saying that a group of miscreants are once again trying to create instability and anarchy in the country for their own benefit.
“After the fall of the Awami autoc</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 17:02:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>What the EU's new biometric border checks mean for non-EU citizens</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/what-the-eus-new-biometric-border-checks-mean-for-non-eu-citizens</link><description>How all non-European Union citizens, including British visitors, travel to and from the bloc will start to change from Sunday when its long-delayed new biometric entry-check system starts operations.
The Entry/Exit System (EES) will require all non-EU citizens to register their personal details, i</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 16:36:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>J&amp;J ordered to pay $966mn in talc cancer case</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/johnson-johnson-ordered-to-pay-966mn-in-talc-cancer-case-after-jury-finds-company-liable</link><description>A Los Angeles jury ordered Johnson &amp; Johnson, opens new tab to pay $966 million to the family of a woman who died from mesothelioma, finding the company liable in the latest trial alleging its talc products cause cancer.
The family of Mae Moore, a California resident who died at age 88 in 2021, su</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 16:51:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Media infrastructure being opened for anti-fascist voices, says Information Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/media-infrastructure-being-opened-for-anti-fascist-voices-says-information-adviser</link><description>The government is opening media infrastructure for anti-fascist voices, and no media outlet will be shut down under the current administration, said Information and Broadcasting Adviser Md. Mahfuz Alam on Wednesday.
Speaking to journalists at the Secretariat ahead of a meeting with the Executive C</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 17:06:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Oman road accident kills 8 Bangladeshis, 7 from Swandip</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/oman-road-accident-kills-8-bangladeshis-7-from-swandip</link><description>Eight Bangladeshi citizens were killed in a tragic road accident in Oman on Wednesday.
Seven of the victims were residents of Sarikait Union in Swandip upazila, Chattogram.
The accident occurred around 3:20 pm local time (5:20 pm Bangladesh time) in Duqm Sidra area.
Ten of the eleven passengers</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 17:21:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka's urban disconnect</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/dhakas-urban-disconnect</link><description>Dhaka, the beating heart of Bangladesh, is a city of dazzling contradictions. From dawn to midnight, its rhythm rarely pauses - rickshaws weave through chaotic streets, buses blare horns, and skyscrapers rise from the dust as testaments to ambition and growth. Yet, beneath this restless energy lies</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 17:36:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka Central University deserves support from all, not opposition</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/dhaka-central-university-deserves-support-from-all-not-opposition</link><description>Bangladesh has witnessed an exponential growth of universities during the one and a half decades tenure of the ousted Awami League government. During this period, 87 universities, both public and private, were established, raising the total number of universities to 170 (55 public and 115 private).</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 17:51:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Reviewing bureaucrats' tax privileges</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/reviewing-bureaucrats-tax-privileges</link><description>Before delivering a new and obviously higher pay scale for employees in government service, the National Pay Commission (NPC) has brought civil servants' tax privileges under the scanner. It has asked for a report from the National Board of Revenue (NBR) on the tax privileges granted to the bureauc</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 18:06:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BD to get $3.0b in SDR for job-centric development</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bd-to-get-30b-in-sdr-for-job-centric-development</link><description>Bangladesh is going to get US$3.0 billion in special drawing right (SDR) credits from the World Bank for its job-centric development works, officials say.
However, the Bank has offered both soft-and hard-term lending under its 3-year aid package, categorizing Bangladesh as a 'Blend Country' on the</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 18:21:42 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>