<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 12:49:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Court bars disconnection of utility services to under-construction buildings</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/court-bars-disconnection-of-utility-services-to-under-construction-buildings</link><description>The High Court has issued a six-month injunction restraining the authorities concerned from disconnecting electricity, gas and water connections to under-construction buildings in Dhaka.
The order came in response to a writ petition filed by the Real Estate and Housing Association of Bangladesh (R</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 10:00:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt hikes Rooppur project cost by Tk 255.92bn</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-raises-cost-of-rooppur-nuclear-power-plant-project-by-tk-25592bn</link><description>The government has approved a Tk 255.92 billion increase in cost of the the Rooppur nuclear power plant construction project at a meeting of the Executive Committee of the National Economic Council (ECNEC).
The entire cost increase will be met from project loans. As a result, the cost of the proje</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 10:15:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Teenager dies after falling while filming Tarique rally procession in Ctg</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/teenager-dies-after-falling-while-filming-tarique-rally-procession-in-ctg</link><description>A 14-year-old boy has died after falling on the road while filming a procession linked to an election rally held by BNP leader Tarique Rahman in the port city of Chattogram.
The incident occurred on Sunday in front of Hall 24 near the city stadium.
The teenager was identified as Saidul Islam Chis</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 10:30:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Why shouldn't CEC face contempt charges? HC asks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/high-court-asks-why-cec-shouldnt-face-contempt-charges-over-party-registration-delay</link><description>The High Court has asked why contempt of court charges should not be filed against Chief Election Commissioner AMM Nasir Uddin for failing to comply with its directive to dispose of an application seeking registration of a new political party.
The bench of Justice Fahmida Quader and Justice Md Asi</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 10:45:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Reducing noise pollution is everyone's responsibility: Rizwana</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/reducing-noise-pollution-is-everyones-responsibility-rizwana</link><description>Environment, Forest and Climate Change Adviser to the Interim Government, Syeda Rizwana Hasan today said that reducing noise pollution is everyone's responsibility. 
"It cannot be left solely to the government. To control noise pollution, unnecessary honking must be stopped as it's a bad habi</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 11:00:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Authorities explain why Saddam was shown wife, child's bodies at jail gate</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/authorities-explain-why-saddam-was-shown-wife-childs-bodies-at-jail-gate</link><description>Prison authorities have issued an explanation for why the imprisoned Jewel Hassan Saddam, president of the Bagerhat Sadar Upazila Chhatra League, was allowed to see the bodies of his wife and infant child at the jail gate instead of being released on parole to attend their funeral.
On Sunday, the</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 11:15:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Veteran journalist Mark Tully, a Foreign Friend of Bangladesh, dies at 90</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/veteran-journalist-mark-tully-a-foreign-friend-of-bangladesh-dies-at-90</link><description>Veteran British-Indian journalist Sir Mark Tully, whose voice thousands tuned into on BBC Radio during the tumultuous days of the Liberation War and who conveyed the true picture of the massacres by Pakistani forces and the plight of the Bengali people, has died at the age of 90.
He died at a hosp</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 11:30:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No one should touch young voter's rights: Jamaat Ameer</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/no-one-should-touch-young-voters-rights-jamaat-ameer</link><description>Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islam Ameer Dr Shafiqur Rahman today said that the party will always be beside the young voters who participated in the July Mass Uprising with full support.
"No one should touch their votes. If anyone does, fire will burn. That slogan is over. Terrorists used to say, 'I w</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 11:31:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh expresses surprise as Hasina speaks at New Delhi event</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-expresses-surprise-as-hasina-speaks-at-new-delhi-event</link><description>The government and people of Bangladesh have expressed surprise and shock that fugitive Sheikh Hasina, convicted by the International Crimes Tribunal for crimes against humanity, was permitted to make a statement at a public event in New Delhi on January 23, the Ministry of Foreign Affairs said on</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 11:46:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Home ministry denies parole application for Jashore jail prisoner Saddam</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/home-ministry-denies-parole-application-for-jashore-jail-prisoner-saddam</link><description>The Ministry of Home Affairs has clarified that no application was submitted for the parole release of prisoner Jewel Hasan Saddam, who is currently detained in Jashore Central Jail following the death of his wife and child.
In a statement issued on the matter, the Home Ministry said neither Sadda</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 12:01:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pakistan announce T20 World Cup squad amid participation doubts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/cricket/pakistan-announce-t20-world-cup-squad-amid-participation-doubts</link><description>Pakistan on Sunday announced their squad for next month's Twenty20 World Cup, a day after their cricket board chief cast doubt over the team's participation in the global showpiece that begins on February 7.
Pakistan Cricket Board (PCB) Chairman Mohsin Naqvi, also the country's interior minister,</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 12:16:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Yunus hails SAFF women’s futsal triumph</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/yunus-congratulates-bangladesh-for-historic-saff-womens-futsal-triumph</link><description>Chief Advisor Muhammad Yunus has congratulated the Bangladesh women’s team for becoming SAFF Women’s Futsal Champions.
In a message on Sunday, he underscored the achievement as “a matter of pride for the country’s sporting arena”.
In the final of the inaugural SAFF t</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 12:31:02 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>