<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 07:37:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Past missteps haunt BSEC as fresh lobbying begins for top posts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/past-missteps-haunt-bsec-as-fresh-lobbying-begins-for-top-posts</link><description>Strong lobbying has begun for the top positions at the securities regulator after the newly elected government assumed office last week.
Market experts insist that the right leadership is imperative for the capital market to recover from decades-old wounds inflicted by fraud and self-serving polic</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 02:46:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Reimagining Bangladesh's education for Generation Alpha</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/article/reimagining-bangladeshs-education-for-generation-alpha</link><description>According to UNESCO (2023), 92 per cent of Bangladesh's Generation Alpha - born in 2010 and after - is the country's biggest and most technologically savvy group. Despite having enormous economic potential, children are taught using a mass-production, industrial-era educational system that views st</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 03:50:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh must rebuild its public universities now</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/article/bangladesh-must-rebuild-its-public-universities-now</link><description>For decades, Bangladesh has invested heavily in human capital. Public funds sustain millions of students through primary, secondary, and higher secondary education. Families allocate significant income to examinations and university preparation. Public universities are subsidised so that merit, rat</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 04:05:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Customs seize phones, cigarettes worth Tk 1m from Dubai returnee at Chattogram airport</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/customs-seize-phones-cigarettes-worth-tk-1m-from-dubai-returnee-at-chattogram-airport</link><description>Customs officials at Shah Amanat International Airport in Chattogram have seized 15 mobile phones and a large quantity of foreign cigarettes from a passenger arriving from Dubai.
The seizure was made around 10am on Saturday after the baggage of passenger Mohammad Hossain Zahed Habib was searched b</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 04:20:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mobile services may face brief disruption during NEIR test on Sunday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/mobile-services-may-face-brief-disruption-during-neir-test-on-sunday</link><description>Mobile phone connections may be temporarily disrupted during a trial run of the National Equipment Identity Register (NEIR) system.
The test will be conducted from 10am to 12pm on Sunday as part of preparations to fully implement the system from March, the Association of Mobile Telecom Operators o</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 04:35:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pakistan says it carried out cross-border strikes in Afghanistan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/pakistan-says-it-carried-out-cross-border-strikes-in-afghanistan</link><description>Pakistan said it carried out cross-border strikes on militant targets inside Afghanistan after blaming a series of recent suicide bombings - including attacks during the holy month of Ramadan - on fighters it said were operating from Afghan territory.
The strikes mark a sharp escalation in tension</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 04:50:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Social media can be addictive even for adults, but there are ways to cut back</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/others/social-media-can-be-addictive-even-for-adults-but-there-are-ways-to-cut-back</link><description>Social media addiction has been compared to casinos, opioids and cigarettes.
While there's some debate among experts about the line between overuse and addiction, and whether social media can cause the latter, there is no doubt that many people feel like they can't escape the pull of Instagram, Ti</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 05:53:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Four jailed for life over 2009 Kamrangirchar gang rape</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/four-jailed-for-life-over-2009-kamrangirchar-gang-rape</link><description>A Dhaka court has sentenced four men to life imprisonment in a gang rape case filed in 2009 in Kamrangirchar, reports bdnews24.com.
Judge Munshi Md Moshiar Rahman of the Women and Children Repression Prevention Tribunal-4 delivered the verdict on Sunday, according to Public Prosecutor Ershad Alam.</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 05:59:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>First session of parliament likely in March: Home Minister</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/first-session-of-parliament-likely-in-march-home-minister</link><description>The first session of the 13th national parliament is expected to be held next month, possibly beginning on March 12 or a day or two earlier.
Home Minister Salahuddin Ahmed shared the information in a post on his verified Facebook account tonight, reports BSS. 
In the post, he wrote that the</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 06:14:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladeshi among 8 arrested over alleged India terror plot: NDTV</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/bangladeshi-among-8-arrested-over-alleged-india-terror-plot-ndtv</link><description>India has arrested eight people, including a Bangladeshi national, suspected of plotting a major terror conspiracy with alleged backing from Pakistan’s Inter-Services Intelligence (ISI) and Bangladesh-based extremist groups.
Six suspects, identified as Mizanur Rahman, Mohammed Shabat, Umar,</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 06:29:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Saudi Ambassador meets PM Tarique Rahman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/saudi-ambassador-meets-pm-tarique-rahman</link><description>Saudi Arabia’s Ambassador to Dhaka Dr Abdullah ibn Dhafer ibn Ubayya paid a courtesy call on Prime Minister Tarique Rahman on Sunday.
The meeting was held at 11am at the Cabinet Division of the Secretariat, said Prime Minister’s Additional Press Secretary Atikur Rahaman Rumon.
Foreign</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 06:44:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Selima Rahman remains hospitalised with cardiac complications</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/selima-rahman-remains-hospitalised-with-cardiac-complications</link><description>BNP Standing Committee Member and former minister Selima Rahman remained under treatment at the Coronary Care Unit (CCU) of United Hospital in the capital with cardiac complications.
She was taken to the hospital on February 19 after experiencing sudden chest pain, said BNP Media Cell member Sayru</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 06:59:06 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>