<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 18:27:29 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Shah Rukh Khan joins billionaire elite, tops Bollywood rich list</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/entertainment/shah-rukh-khan-joins-billionaire-elite-tops-bollywood-rich-list</link><description>With a career glittering over three decades marked by soaring triumphs, blockbuster hits, and a vast international fanbase, Bollywood’s “King Khan” Shah Rukh Khan has now entered the rarified ranks of global billionaires.
According to Hindustan Times, the Hurun India Rich List 20</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 15:38:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India and China to resume direct flights after five-year freeze</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/india-and-china-to-resume-direct-flights-after-five-year-freeze</link><description>India and China will restart direct flights between designated cities this month, ending a suspension of more than five years, in a move that signals a cautious easing of bilateral tensions, India's foreign ministry said on Thursday.
There have been no direct flights between China and India since</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 15:53:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Digital payment: a catalyst for cashless economy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/digital-payment-a-catalyst-for-cashless-economy</link><description>With the proliferation of smartphones, mobile apps, and online platforms, peoples have countless options at their fingertips for conducting payments, transfers, and purchases. This transformation in the payment landscape has not only modernised transaction processes but also impacted consumer behav</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 16:23:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Record October rainfall and its implications</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/record-october-rainfall-and-its-implications</link><description>Residents in Dhaka woke up to find the city under water on October 1 when there was a staggering 132 millimetres of rainfall in just six hours between midnight and 6:00 am. By the end of the day, the total rainfall reached 203 millimetres, the highest recorded in the country during this period. Oct</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 15:52:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Addressing the problem of loss and waste of food</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/addressing-the-problem-of-loss-and-waste-of-food</link><description>Loss and waste of foods have ever remained a cause for serious concern. This has prompted the United Nations (UN) to observe the International Day of Awareness of Food Loss and Waste (IDAFLW) since 2020. Clearly, the global attention to this critical issue was belated. Even after the UN General Ass</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 16:22:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>PPR-2025: A step towards transparent governance</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/ppr-2025-a-step-towards-transparent-governance</link><description>The introduction of the Public Procurement Rules (PPR)-2025, in place of the earlier 2008 framework, represents a major policy shift in management of one of the largest channels of public expenditure in Bangladesh. With government procurement estimated at around $30 billion annually, the implicatio</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 16:37:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prayers for Palestine’s freedom echo at Cox’s Bazar immersion</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hundreds-of-thousands-unite-in-call-for-palestines-freedom-in-coxs-bazar-dashami-rituals</link><description>The farewell to Durga Puja has carried a different emotion this year in Cox’s Bazar, as prayers for the freedom of Palestine mingled with the chants of immersion on the sandy beach.
On Thursday, during Bijoya Dashami, crowds numbering in the hundreds of thousands gathered on the shore to wit</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 16:52:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tigers chase 152 against Afghans</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/gurbaz-nabi-push-afghanistan-to-151-in-first-t20-against-bangladesh</link><description>Afghanistan put up 151 for 8 against Bangladesh in their first T20, built on Rahmanullah Gurbaz’s gritty 40 and a blistering 38 from Mohammad Nabi at the Sharjah Cricket Stadium.
Electing to bat, Ibrahim Zadran and Sediqullah Atal made a steady start before Nasum Ahmed (1-18) breached Zadran</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 17:07:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Language Movement veteran Ahmed Rafiq dies</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ahmed-rafiq-iconic-language-movement-activist-dies-at-96</link><description>Veteran Language Movement activist and researcher Ahmed Rafiq has died in Dhaka at the age of 96.
He breathed his last at 10:12pm on Thursday at Dhaka’s BIRDEM Hospital after doctors removed his ventilation support, cultural activist Dipanto Rayhan, who was present at the hospital, told bdne</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 17:22:24 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>