<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 10:26:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Gold breaks $4400 for first time</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/gold-breaks-4400-for-first-time</link><description>Gold jumped past the $4,400-per-ounce level for the first time on Monday, riding on growing expectations of further US rate cuts and strong safe-haven demand, with silver also joining the rally to hit an all-time high.
Spot gold was up 1.4 per cent at $4,397.16 per ounce, as of 0502 GMT, after bre</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 07:19:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pranay Verma visits Indian visa centre in Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/pranay-verma-visits-indian-visa-centre-in-dhaka</link><description>Indian High Commissioner to Bangladesh Pranay Verma on Monday visited the Indian Visa Application Centre (IVAC) at Jamuna Future Park to take stock of the functioning of visa services.
He also interacted with visa applicants, many of whom were applying for medical visas to travel to India for trea</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 07:34:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt voter outreach campaign kicks off Monday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/govt-voter-outreach-campaign-kicks-off-monday</link><description>The interim government is set to launch a nationwide campaign aimed at boosting voter awareness and turnout ahead of next year’s parliamentary election and referendum.
The initiative, known as “Vote er Gari" (Vote Caravan), is due to be inaugurated on Monday afternoon at the National P</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 07:49:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCP leader shot in broad daylight in Khulna</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ncp-leader-shot-in-broad-daylight-in-khulna</link><description>A leader of the Jatiya Sramik Shakti, an affiliate of the National Citizen Party (NCP), has been shot in broad daylight in Khulna, reports bdnews24.com.
Motaleb Shikdar, a coordinator of the NCP's labour wing, was taken to Khulna Medical College Hospital in critical condition around midday on Mond</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 08:04:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>REHAB Fair 2025 begins Wednesday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/rehab-fair-2025-begins-wednesday</link><description>The Real Estate and Housing Association of Bangladesh (REHAB) will inaugurate the four-day REHAB Fair 2025 on December 24 at the Bangladesh-China Friendship Conference Centre in Agargaon, Dhaka.
The country’s flagship real estate exhibition will continue until December 27 and remain open fro</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 08:19:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt set to roll out nationwide voter outreach campaign on Monday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-set-to-roll-out-nationwide-voter-outreach-campaign-on-monday</link><description>The interim government is set to launch a nationwide campaign aimed at boosting voter awareness and turnout ahead of next year’s parliamentary election and referendum, reports bdnews24.com.
The initiative, known as “Vote er Gari" (Vote Caravan), is due to be inaugurated on Monday after</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 08:34:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>17 arrested over attacks on Prothom Alo, Daily Star</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/17-arrested-over-attacks-on-prothom-alo-daily-star</link><description>Police have arrested 17 people in connection with attacks on the offices of leading national dailies Prothom Alo and The Daily Star.
The arrests were made after analysing video footage of the attacks, Dhaka Metropolitan Police's Additional Commissioner for Crime and Operations SN Nazrul Islam sa</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 08:49:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>South Asia Insurance celebrates 26th anniversary</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/south-asia-insurance-celebrates-26th-anniversary</link><description>The 26th anniversary of South Asia Insurance Company Limited was celebrated at the company's head office in Dhaka recently.
The event was held under the chairmanship of Mr Muhammad Nurul Alam Chowdhury, Chief Executive Officer of South Asia Insurance Company Limited.
The event was conducted</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 09:04:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CA orders arrest of Hadi’s killers, maintain law and order before polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ca-orders-arrest-of-hadis-killers-maintain-law-and-order-before-polls</link><description>Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus has directed law enforcement agencies to swiftly arrest those involved in the killing of Osman Hadi and others engaged in illegal activities and keep the law and order situation normal at any cost before the national elections.
“Ahead of the upcoming na</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 09:19:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Law and order to improve ahead of election, hopes CEC Nasir</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/law-and-order-to-improve-ahead-of-election-hopes-cec-nasir</link><description>Chief Election Commissioner (CEC) AMM Nasir Uddin stated on Monday that he is confident the overall law-and-order situation will further improve as the election approaches.
"As the polling day approaches, you will see, InshaAllah, the law and order situation will improve further. There will be no</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 09:34:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Publishers, political, business leaders protest against mob violence</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/publishers-political-business-leaders-protest-against-mob-violence</link><description>The Newspaper Owners' Association of Bangladesh (NOAB) and the Editors’ Council have jointly organised a protest meeting against mob violence at a city hotel on Monday.
Leaders from various political parties, media and journalists’ organisations, business communities, lawyers, cultural</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 09:49:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh set to sign first EPA with Japan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladesh-set-to-sign-first-epa-with-japan</link><description>The country is likely to sign its first Economic Partnership Agreement (EPA) with Japan, under which 97 per cent of Bangladeshi goods, including readymade garments, will receive duty-free access to the Japanese market.
Advisor to the Ministry of Commerce Sheikh Basir Uddin disclosed the informatio</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 10:04:27 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>