<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 08:33:56 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>BB chief says voting for ‘symbols’, not candidates, creates autocrats</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bb-chief-says-voting-for-symbols-not-candidates-creates-autocrats</link><description>Bangladesh Bank Governor Ahsan H Mansur has criticised the tendency to vote for “symbols” rather than carefully evaluating candidates in elections.
“In that case we are obviously creating conditions for an autocrat to emerge,” said Mansur
The culture of voting by “</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 05:21:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>16,000 fossil footprints in central Bolivia reveal dinosaur behavior</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/16000-fossil-footprints-in-central-bolivia-reveal-dinosaur-behavior</link><description>Legend once had it that the huge, three-toed footprints scattered across the central highlands of Bolivia came from supernaturally strong monsters — capable of sinking their claws even into solid stone.
 
Then scientists came here in the 1960s and dispelled children's fears, determinin</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 05:36:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh’s betel nut exports snarl as 150 trucks sit idle at Benapole</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladeshs-betel-nut-exports-snarl-as-150-trucks-sit-idle-at-benapole</link><description>A deepening bottleneck at the Benapole-Petrapole trade gateway has stranded about 150 export-bound trucks loaded with betel nuts worth an estimated Tk 100 crore, exposing Bangladesh’s second-largest betel-nut industry to mounting financial risk as delays stretch into a second month.
Exporter</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 05:51:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Australia social media ban set to take effect, sparking a global crackdown</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/australia-social-media-ban-set-to-take-effect-sparking-a-global-crackdown</link><description>Australia is set to become the first country to implement a minimum age for social media use on Wednesday, with platforms like Instagram, TikTok and YouTube forced to block more than a million accounts, marking the beginning of an expected global wave of regulation.
From midnight (1300 GMT), 10 of</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 06:06:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Robi launches eco-friendly ‘Super Bikes’ for field staff</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/robi-launches-eco-friendly-super-bikes-for-field-staff</link><description>Robi Axiata PLC has introduced eco-friendly Robi Super Bikes for its field staff to support sustainable mobility and strengthen digital service delivery across rural Bangladesh.
The electric bikes, designed for the company’s field staff, aim to ensure faster, greener, and more efficient cust</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 06:21:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP ready to lead fresh drive against corruption: Tarique</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-ready-to-lead-fresh-drive-against-corruption-tarique</link><description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman on Tuesday said his party is ready to lead a fresh strong and comprehensive drive against corruption if voted to power as graft has become deeply rooted in Bangladesh and continues to disrupt the daily lives of millions of people.
 “Fighting corruption</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 06:36:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka College, Ideal College students clash again</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dhaka-college-ideal-college-students-clash-again</link><description>A month after students from Dhaka College and Ideal College brokered a “peace pact”, the two sides have clashed again.
A dispute on Tuesday over arguments and a scuffle eventually escalated to the vandalism of buses.
Since then, the two sides have been engaging in back-and-forth chase</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 06:28:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Policeman’s body recovered in Ctg, APBn suspects suicide</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/policemans-body-recovered-in-ctg-apbn-suspects-suicide</link><description>Members of the Armed Police Battalion (APBn) believe that a policeman whose body was recovered in Chattogram died by suicide.
Deepak Jyoti Khisha, superintendent of police for RAB-9, said law enforcers initially suspect that 25-year-old Nayeem Biswas hanged himself. The cause of death will be conf</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 06:43:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Orangutans at risk as Indonesia floods devastate habitat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/orangutans-at-risk-as-indonesia-floods-devastate-habitat</link><description>Before the deadly landslides and floods hit Indonesia about two weeks ago, Amran Siagian, 39, frequently met Tapanuli orangutans on a hill in the region of Sipirok, North Sumatra province.
Siagian, who has been working as a ranger to protect the endangered animal at the Orangutan Information Cente</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 06:58:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US Justice Department accuses two Chinese men of trying to smuggle Nvidia chips</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/us-justice-department-accuses-two-chinese-men-of-trying-to-smuggle-nvidia-chips</link><description>Two Chinese men are in custody for allegedly smuggling Nvidia H100 and H200 chips to China, the US Justice Department said on Monday, as President Donald Trump gave the green light for Nvidia to export its H200 chips to Beijing.
Prosecutors allege that Fanyue Gong, 43, a Chinese citizen living in</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 07:13:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India orders crisis-hit IndiGo to cut flights by 5%</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/india-orders-crisis-hit-indigo-to-cut-flights-by-5</link><description>India's aviation regulator has ordered crisis-hit IndiGo to cut its number of planned flights by 5 percent to stabilise its operations.
In a notice dated on Monday but disclosed on Tuesday, the Directorate General of Civil Aviation asked IndiGo to submit a revised schedule by Wednesday.</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 07:28:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Global pilots warn India's rest rule exemption for IndiGo raises safety concerns</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/global-pilots-warn-indias-rest-rule-exemption-for-indigo-raises-safety-concerns</link><description>India's decision to ease stricter rules on pilot rest following a wave of flight cancellations by the country's largest carrier should be reversed due to the adverse effect of fatigue on safety, the head of global pilot union group IFALPA said.
IndiGo, which controls about 65 percent of India's do</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 07:43:32 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>