<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 10:27:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Graduation may hit country's apparel exports hard: Study</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/graduation-may-hit-countrys-apparel-exports-hard-study</link><description>LDC graduation poses a significant threat, with Bangladeshi exporters likely to bear a large share of tariff costs, as they may need to absorb 40 per cent of post-graduation tariffs to remain competitive in the European Union, according to a recent study.
After Bangladesh's graduation from the LDC</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 07:39:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Iran condoles death of former PM Khaleda Zia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/iran-condoles-death-of-former-pm-khaleda-zia</link><description>The Iranian Embassy in Dhaka on Tuesday extended its sincere condolences to the government and people of Bangladesh, as well as to the leadership and members of the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP), on the passing of former Prime Minister Begum Khaleda Zia.
In a condolence message, the Embassy d</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 07:13:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Demise of Khaleda: Huge crowd gathers outside Evercare Hospital</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/demise-of-khaleda-huge-crowd-gathers-outside-evercare-hospital</link><description>A large number of BNP leaders and activists gathered outside Evercare Hospital on Tuesday following the death of BNP Chairperson and former Prime Minister Khaleda Zia.
Witnesses said several hundred people had thronged the hospital premises since Tuesday morning.
Many were seen breaking down in t</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 07:28:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Commoners enduring the bite of severe cold in Cox's Bazar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/commoners-enduring-the-bite-of-severe-cold-in-coxs-bazar</link><description>Common people are facing the brunt
of severe cold as winter chill is dominating almost everywhere in Cox's Bazar, the coastal district of southern Bangladesh.
Over the past few days, temperatures have dropped, making early mornings and nights particularly chilly. The usual coastal climate has bee</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 07:43:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sunamganj farmers worried over fishery lessee's non-cooperation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/sunamganj-farmers-worried-over-fishery-lessees-non-cooperation</link><description>SYLHET, Dec 29: Five hundred farmers of Sunamganj's two upazilas have expressed their concern regarding the shortage of irrigation water for Boro paddy cultivation on 700 acres of land - as the leaseholder of an adjacent fishery may open the sluice gates too early to benefit his fish cultivation.</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 07:58:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Growing digital adoption drives up internet banking</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/growing-digital-adoption-drives-up-internet-banking</link><description>Internet-banking transactions surged by more than 39.0 per cent to Tk 1.29 trillion during the first four months of the current fiscal year, signifying a steady shift away from cheques and other paper-based conventional payment methods.
Roughly 66.0 million transactions were carried out through in</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 08:13:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dense fog, low sunshine bring cold wave-like chill countrywide</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/dense-fog-low-sunshine-bring-cold-wave-like-chill-countrywide</link><description>Parts of the country, including Dhaka, have been experiencing cold wave-like chilling weather for the last four days due to reduced sunshine during winter caused by persistent fog, meteorologists said on Monday.
According to the Bangladesh Meteorological Department (BMD), the fog sweeping across t</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 08:28:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Industrial raw material imports: BB sets up to 270 days for usance period</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/industrial-raw-material-imports-bb-sets-up-to-270-days-for-usance-period</link><description>The central bank has allowed import of industrial raw materials-- including back-to-back import-- as well as agricultural implements and chemical fertilisers under suppliers' or buyer's credit for a usance period of up to 270 days.
On August 18, 2025, the Bangladesh Bank (BB) permitted such facili</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 08:43:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nepal PM expresses condolences over Khaleda Zia’s death</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nepal-pm-expresses-condolences-over-khaleda-zias-death</link><description>Nepalese Prime Minister Sushila Karki has expressed sorrow over the death of Khaleda Zia, BNP chairperson and the first female Prime Minister of Bangladesh.
"I am deeply saddened to learn of the passing away of Begum Khaleda Zia, BNP chairperson and the first female Prime Minister of Bangladesh,"</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 08:58:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>July-October NSC sales plummet 53.62pc</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/july-october-nsc-sales-plummet-5362pc</link><description>The net sales of National Savings Certificates (NSCs) experienced a staggering 53.62-percent year-on-year decline during the July-October period of the current fiscal year.
The sharp downturn reflects tightening liquidity conditions and a persistent rise in living costs that continue to sap the ca</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 09:13:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>End of an Era: A look back at former prime minister Khaleda Zia’s life and legacy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/end-of-an-era-a-look-back-at-former-prime-minister-khaleda-zias-life-and-legacy</link><description>Begum Khaleda Zia, the country’s first elected female Prime Minister and one of the nation’s most enduring political figures, passed away on Tuesday morning at 6 am in Evercare Hospital.
The death of the Chairperson of Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) at the age of 80, marks the end</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 09:28:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique pays heartfelt tribute to Khaleda, hails her as a loving mother</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-pays-heartfelt-tribute-to-khaleda-hails-her-as-a-loving-mother</link><description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman on Tuesday paid an emotional tribute to party Chairperson Khaleda Zia, remembering her as a tender and loving mother who was also a steadfast guardian for her family and the nation.
"My mother, BNP Chairperson Begum Khaleda Zia, has responded to the call of Almig</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 09:43:09 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>