<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 15:24:47 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Yunus orders swift purchase of bodycams for election security</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/yunus-orders-swift-purchase-of-bodycams-for-election-security</link><description>Chief Adviser Muhammad Yunus has ordered the rapid purchase of a sufficient number of body-worn cameras for law-enforcing agencies to ensure “transparency, peace and safety” during the national election.
He sets a December deadline to complete the purchase and operational training, aim</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 11:53:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Referendum ‘no’ reflects public choice: Riaz</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ali-riaz-urges-trust-in-people-if-july-charter-referendum-fails</link><description>National Consensus Commission Vice-Chairman Ali Riaz has called for trust in the people if the proposed referendum on implementing the July Charter does not yield a positive result.
On Tuesday, he explained that a failed referendum simply reflects that the public has rejected it, reports bdnews24.</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 12:08:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC seeks round-the-clock police deployment for Nirbachan Bhaban ahead of election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-seeks-round-the-clock-police-deployment-for-nirbachan-bhaban-ahead-of-election</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) on Tuesday asked Dhaka Metropolitan Police (DMP) to deploy adequate police members to ensure round-the-clock security for Nirbachan Bhaban, the Election Commission Secretariat, ahead of the 13th parliamentary election planned to be held in early February 2026.
The Comm</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 12:23:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Charter will redeem Bangladesh of past: Yunus</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-can-leave-past-behind-if-july-charter-properly-implemented-says-yunus</link><description>Chief Advisor Muhammad Yunus has said Bangladesh can “free itself from the past” if the July National Charter is implemented properly and its reform process carried out with commitment.
He made the remark on Tuesday after the National Consensus Commission, led by Vice-Chairman Ali Riaz</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 12:53:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US military strikes suspected drug vessels in eastern Pacific</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-military-strikes-suspected-drug-vessels-in-eastern-pacific</link><description>The US military killed 14 alleged drug smugglers in strikes targeting four vessels in the eastern Pacific Ocean on Monday that left one survivor, US Defense Secretary Pete Hegseth said in a post on X on Tuesday.</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 13:08:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh, Pakistan pledge stronger ties to boost mutual progress</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-pakistan-pledge-stronger-ties-to-boost-mutual-progress</link><description>Bangladesh and Pakistan on Tuesday reaffirmed their commitment to strengthening cooperation across various sectors, with a shared resolve to advance partnerships that would benefit their peoples.
Minister for Petroleum of Pakistan Ali Pervaiz Malik paid a courtesy call on Foreign Affairs Adviser o</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 13:23:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Paris St Germain set revenue record of 837 million euros</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/paris-st-germain-set-revenue-record-of-837-million-euros</link><description>Paris St Germain posted record revenue in the 2024-2025 season of 837 million euros ($976.11 million), the Champions League winners announced in their financial results on Tuesday.
PSG, third in the Deloitte Football Money League in January, beat their previous revenue high of 806 million euros.</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 13:38:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BREB procurement proposals approved by purchase committee</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/breb-procurement-proposals-approved-by-purchase-committee</link><description>The Advisors Council Committee on Government Purchase (ACCGP) on Tuesday gave approval of two procurement proposals under the project titled “Modernisation and Capacity Enhancement of BREB’s Electric Distribution System (Dhaka-Mymensingh Division) (Special Revised)”.
The project</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 14:08:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Amazon to cut about 14,000 corporate jobs in AI push</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/amazon-to-cut-about-14000-corporate-jobs-in-ai-push</link><description>Amazon said on Tuesday it will reduce its global corporate workforce by about 14,000 people, with more cuts expected next year, in a major shakeup driven in part by adoption of artificial intelligence at the tech giant.
The online retailer began laying off employees across multiple divisions as pa</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 14:23:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BRAC Bank honours coworkers for serving expatriate families with exclusive remittance services</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/brac-bank-honours-coworkers-for-serving-expatriate-families-with-exclusive-remittance-services</link><description>BRAC Bank has honoured its coworkers for their exceptional performance in driving international remittance growth and for delivering outstanding service to remittance beneficiaries.
A total of 45 individuals, including branch staff, agent banking personnel, sales teams, and agent banking partners,</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 14:38:56 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>