<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 17:20:17 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Chhayanaut ‘will not waver’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/chhayanaut-says-it-will-not-waver-in-its-course</link><description>Chhayanaut will remain steadfast in its journey, the Bengali cultural organisation has said following the arson attack and widespread vandalism on its premises on Friday.
Around 6:30pm on Saturday, the statement signed by the organisation’s President Sarwar Ali and General Secretary Laisa Ah</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 14:48:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh issues travel pass for Tarique Rahman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bangladesh-issues-travel-pass-for-tarique-rahman</link><description>The Bangladesh high commission in London has issued a travel pass for Tarique Rahman in response to the BNP leader’s application for the document, an official said.
A foreign ministry official, who spoke on condition of anonymity, said Friday the mission took just a day to issue the travel d</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 15:03:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt accountable for attacks on media: TIB</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tib-says-interim-government-cannot-evade-blame-for-attacks-on-media-free-speech</link><description>The Transparency International Bangladesh (TIB) has said the Muhammad Yunus-led interim government cannot deny responsibility for the attack on media, describing it as an assault on free media, dissent, and freedom of speech.
The TIB, local chapter of Berlin-based Transparency International—</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 15:04:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UN calls for calm, urges all to refrain from violence</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/un-calls-for-calm-urges-all-to-refrain-from-violence</link><description>The United Nations Human Rights Office urges all to remain calm and to refrain from violence in the wake of the death of July protester Sharif Osman Hadi and the violence after the death.
Jeremy Laurence, UN Human Rights Office spokesperson, on Friday said,  “We are deeply troubled by t</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 15:19:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BFUJ, DUJ condemn attacks on offices of Prothom Alo, Daily Star</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bfuj-duj-condemn-attacks-on-offices-of-prothom-alo-daily-star</link><description>Bangladesh Federal Union of Journalists-BFUJ and Dhaka Union of Journalists-DUJ have expressed deep concern over the arson attacks on the offices of Daily Prothom Alo and The Daily Star.
In a joint statement, the journalists’ bodies condemned and protested against the incidents, saying that</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 15:34:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>446th board meeting of Al-Arafah Islami Bank held</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/446th-board-meeting-of-al-arafah-islami-bank-held</link><description>446th Board meeting of Al-Arafah Islami Bank PLC was held on Thursday, at the Banks’ Head Office, according to a press release.
Chairman of the Board of Directors Khwaja Shahriar presided over the meeting. The overall business performance of the Bank was reviewed and several policy decisions</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 15:49:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sonali Bank distributes blankets at Sakhipur in Tangail</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/sonali-bank-distributes-blankets-at-sakhipur-in-tangail-1</link><description>Sonali Bank PLC distributed blankets among poor, helpless, and uprooted people who are suffering from biting cold at Sakhipur, Tangail, under the Corporate Social Responsibilities (CSR) activities.
Bank’s MD &amp; CEO Md. Shawkat Ali Khan handed over blankets to cold-hit people at Takterchala Go</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 16:04:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Public sociology to bridge academia and activism</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/public-sociology-to-bridge-academia-and-activism</link><description>Bangladesh is living through a period of extraordinary social transformations, where demographic shifts, political tensions, urbanisation pressures, environmental threats, labour market disruptions, and technological changes interact in ways that challenge older assumptions about society. Yet these</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 16:05:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Why are oppressors not remorseful of their crime?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/why-are-oppressors-not-remorseful-of-their-crime</link><description>Throughout history, oppressors have often shown little remorse or regret for actions that caused great sufferings to others. Many rulers and regimes see a lack of repentance as a sign of strength and even justify their harsh measures. Some people support these actions, believing that brutality is n</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 16:20:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Politics dies when violence speaks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/politics-dies-when-violence-speaks</link><description>In recent months, Bangladesh has seen a disturbing resurgence in acts of sabotage that many had hoped belonged to the past. Ignited in the days leading up to the verdict in Sheikh Hasina's crimes against humanity trial, this surge transformed the streets of Dhaka and beyond into stages for orchestr</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 16:35:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Skill training for local youths in areas hosting Rohingya</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/skill-training-for-local-youths-in-areas-hosting-rohingya</link><description>Undeniably, being the host to over one million Rohingya population displaced from their homeland in Myanmar, the Ukhia and Teknaf upazilas of Cox's Bazar are the most environmentally and socially challenged areas of Bangladesh. As reports go, environmentally, the localities where the Rohingya refug</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 16:50:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Putin sticks to Russian demands on Ukraine, says EU 'robbery' failed</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/putin-sticks-to-russian-demands-on-ukraine-says-eu-robbery-failed</link><description>President Vladimir Putin offered no compromise on Friday on his terms for ending the war in Ukraine and accused the European Union of attempting "daylight robbery" of Russian assets.
As US President Donald Trump seeks an end to Europe's deadliest conflict since World War Two, Putin said the onus w</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 17:05:25 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>