<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 03:13:13 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>BRUCSU polls: Six-member election commission formed</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/brucsu-polls-six-member-election-commission-formed</link><description>A six-member Election Commission has been formed for organizing the Begum Rokeya University Central Students' Union (BRUCSU) and Hall Students' Union (HTU) elections for the first time since establishment of the university. 
This decision was finalized at the 116th syndicate meeting held in t</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 18:13:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>On pre-approval regulations for high-value LCs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/on-pre-approval-regulations-for-high-value-lcs</link><description>With the holy month of Ramadan coming closer, there is a growing need to import essential commodities. In the wake of the previous Ramadan, in January 2025, Bangladesh had imported US$1 billion worth of dates, sugar, wheat, lentils, onions, chickpeas, and raw palm and soybean oil. This year, a cong</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 18:14:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Three books that make English simple, smart, and practical</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/reviews/three-books-that-make-english-simple-smart-and-practical</link><description>Once feared as a difficult subject, English is now being embraced as a skill of empowerment. Khan, a seasoned teacher and English news presenter for Bangladesh Television and Betar, has translated his decades of experience into these three accessible and impactful books, according to a press statem</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 18:29:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Is restoration of Dhaka's rivers elusive?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/is-restoration-of-dhakas-rivers-elusive</link><description>While rivers across Bangladesh face grave vulnerabilities-encroachment, pollution, siltation, and declining navigability-the situation is particularly dire for the rivers surrounding Dhaka. A couple of them are practically lifeless, having lost their channels altogether. Despite repeated calls for</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 18:44:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Go ahead to transport master plan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/go-ahead-to-transport-master-plan</link><description>To say that the communication system of Bangladesh is in a chaotic state is to say the least. One need not be an expert to reach such a conclusion. In fact, it is obvious to anyone commuting within the city or travel to destinations closer or farther from any point in the country. To resolve the cr</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 18:59:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hopes fade for legal hurdles, interagency conflicts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/hopes-fade-for-legal-hurdles-interagency-conflicts</link><description>A much-hyped drive by the post-uprising interim government to recover a cache of stolen assets may not see success during its term as intelligence-insiders find no hope yet for formidable hurdles.



Even evaded tax-recovery steps have stagnated as legal barriers restrict the realisation of s</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 19:14:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt finalises legal docs of five Islami banks’ merger</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/govt-finalises-legal-docs-of-five-islami-banks-merger</link><description>The government has finalised the memorandum and articles of association for the proposed "Sammilito Islami Bank" to be formed by merging five shariah-based commercial banks facing severe liquidity crises, officials said.
Under the two foundational legal documents recently approved by the Finance D</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 01:25:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Net sales of savings tools plunge 95.5pc in Sept</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/net-sales-of-savings-tools-plunge-955pc-in-sept</link><description>Net sales of National Savings Certificates (NSCs) plunged by 95.5 per cent year-on-year in September 2025, as tighter liquidity conditions and rising living costs continued to erode small investors' appetite for government savings instruments.
According to Bangladesh Bank (BB) data, NSC net sales</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 01:55:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Government moves to intensify crackdown on online gambling</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/government-moves-to-intensify-crackdown-on-online-gambling</link><description>The government is mulling over intensifying its crackdown on the growing menace of online gambling in Bangladesh by introducing a coordinated monitoring system and other preventive measures.
The measures include blocking relevant mobile financial service (MFS) accounts, and considering limiting in</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 02:10:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Onion prices surge 30pc in two days</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/onion-prices-surge-30pc-in-two-days</link><description>Onion prices have surged to as high as Tk 120 per kilogramme in Dhaka and other major cities within just two days, fuelled by crop damage from heavy rainfall and the continued suspension of imports from India.
Retail prices, which stood at Tk 80-85 per kg late last week, soared to Tk 100-110 on Mo</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 02:25:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>2-year T-bond yields surge</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/2-year-t-bond-yields-surge</link><description>Yields on two-year treasury bonds increased notably on Tuesday as banks showed reluctance to invest their surplus funds in government securities to manage their portfolios more efficiently.
The cut-off yield, generally known as the interest rate, on Bangladesh Government Treasury Bonds (BGTBs) ros</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 02:40:50 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>