<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 09:19:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Depression over Bay deepens, may turn into cyclone within 24 hours</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/depression-over-bay-deepens-may-turn-into-cyclone-within-24-hours</link><description>A low-pressure system over the southeast Bay of Bengal has intensified into a deep depression, with the Bangladesh Meteorological Department (BMD) warning that it could develop into a cyclonic storm within the next 24 hours.
In a special weather bulletin issued on Sunday, the BMD said that at 6 am</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 06:37:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump sets 10pc hike in tariffs on Canada</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/global/trump-sets-10pc-hike-in-tariffs-on-canada</link><description>US President Donald Trump said on Saturday he was increasing tariffs on Canada by an additional 10 per cent "above what they're paying now," as he reacted again to an ad by Canada's Ontario province, a day after it was aired during the World Series broadcast.
Trump on Thursday ended trade talks wi</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 06:52:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Another youth found dead on staircase</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/another-youth-found-dead-on-staircase</link><description>Within days of a similar gruesome discovery, another young man has been found dead in Old Dhaka, this time in the Bangshal area, with a GI cable wrapped tightly around his neck, raising alarm over a disturbing pattern of deaths in the capital’s old quarters.
The deceased, identified as Sajib</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 07:07:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Woman stabbed to death by husband in Gaibandha</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/woman-stabbed-to-death-by-husband-in-gaibandha</link><description>A woman, who was stabbed allegedly by her husband over a family feud in Gaibandha on Friday night, died while undergoing treatment on Saturday night.
The deceased was identified as Azeda Begum, 35, wife of Shamim Mia of MP Para under Gobindaganj municipality in the district, reports UNB.
Accordin</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 07:37:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pedestrian killed as metro rail bearing pad falls in Farmgate</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/pedestrian-killed-as-metro-rail-bearing-pad-falls-in-farmgate</link><description>A pedestrian was killed after a bearing pad from the metro rail structure fell on him in Dhaka’s Farmgate area on Sunday afternoon, according to local media reports.
The accident occurred around 12:20 p.m. under the Farmgate metro rail station, police said.
According to witnesses, the man w</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 07:52:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>13pc garment workers yet to receive full minimum wage hike: Study</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/13pc-garment-workers-yet-to-receive-full-minimum-wage-hike-study</link><description>Around 13 per cent of surveyed garment workers have yet to fully receive the last minimum wage adjustment, either getting only a partial increase or none at all, according to a new study.
In 2023, the government set Tk 12,500 as the minimum monthly wage for entry-level garment workers.
“Abo</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 08:22:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Army Chief Waker inducted as 9th Colonel Commandant of Engineering Corps</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/army-chief-waker-inducted-as-9th-colonel-commandant-of-engineering-corps</link><description>Chief of Army Staff General Waker-Uz-Zaman has been inducted as the 9th Colonel Commandant of the Bangladesh Army’s Engineering Corps at the Parade Ground of Qadirabad Cantonment in Natore on Sunday morning.
Upon his arrival, the cantonment commander received the army chief with a state salu</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 08:37:58 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>