<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 20:24:37 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Mymensingh shrine vandalized</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/centuries-old-shrine-in-mymensingh-vandalised-desecrated</link><description>A centuries-old shrine in Gouripur Upazila of Mymensingh has been vandalised, with attackers also throwing human waste inside the premises, police say.
The incident took place on Thursday night at the shrine of Shahjahan Uddin (R), Gouripur Police chief Kamrul Hasan said.
Locals said several devo</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 15:15:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Inquilab Moncho continues sit-in at Shahbagh demanding justice for Hadi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/inquilab-moncho-continues-sit-in-at-shahbagh-demanding-justice-for-hadi</link><description>Even in the chilling cold and wind, followers of the Inquilab Moncho on Friday night continued their sit-in programme at Shahbagh intersection to press home the demand to arrest all killers of Sharif Osman bin Hadi.
Besides, the Moncho, a platform formed centring the last year’s student-led</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 15:30:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Central bank's initiatives to curb critically swollen NPLs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/central-banks-initiatives-to-curb-critically-swollen-npls</link><description>Commendably, Bangladesh bank is now  well-aware of  the  causes of poor  recovery  of  defaulted loans  as well as delayed  case disposal  and  trying to mitigate  the  crisis  of non-performing loans (NPLs) in the  banking secto</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 15:45:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>They do not want a free press</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/they-do-not-want-a-free-press</link><description>During the height of the language movement in 1952, two national newspapers were attacked because they opposed the movement. The Morning News, owned by Khwaja Nooruddin from the Dhaka Nawab family, supported the government and kept criticising the language movement. On February 21, 1952, police sho</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 16:00:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Is Bangladesh ready for LDC exit?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/is-bangladesh-ready-for-ldc-exit</link><description>After decades on the global list of the poorest economies, Bangladesh is now set to cross an important economic threshold as it prepares to graduate from the Least Developed Country (LDC) category in November, 2026. This status change follows the country meeting all three United Nations graduation</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 16:15:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trade should take precedence over BD-India diplomatic ties</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/trade-should-take-precedence-over-bd-india-diplomatic-ties</link><description>Trading is a powerful transactional tool among nations. There are historical evidences of countries continuing trading activities between them even when they are at war. During both the World Wars, for instance, Britain imported crucial chemical dyes from Germany. Even when they were engaged in mil</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 16:30:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Russia jails diplomat for 12 years over passing secrets to US</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/moscow-sentences-russian-diplomat-to-12-years-for-passing-secrets-to-us-intelligence</link><description>A Moscow court sentenced a former Russian diplomat to 12 years in a maximum-security penal colony for selling secrets to US intelligence while on a posting to the United States, the Federal Security Service (FSB) said on Friday.
The FSB, the main successor to the Soviet-era KGB, said that Arseniy</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 17:02:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dense fog halts Daulatdia-Paturia ferries</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dense-fog-halts-ferry-services-on-daulatdia-paturia-route</link><description>Dense fog has forced authorities to suspend ferry services on the Paturia-Daulatdia route.
Bangladesh Inland Water Transport Authority’s Daulatdia office Manager Md Salahuddin said the suspension took effect from 7pm on Friday to prevent accidents.
Dense fog blurred visibility along the riv</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 17:17:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Israel recognises Somaliland as independent state</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/israel-becomes-first-country-to-formally-recognise-somaliland-as-independent-state</link><description>Israel became the first country to formally recognise the self-declared Republic of Somaliland as an independent and sovereign state on Friday -- a decision that could reshape regional dynamics and test Somalia’s longstanding opposition to its secession.
Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu sai</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 17:32:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique pays tribute to fallen 1971 war heroes at National Memorial</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-pays-tribute-to-fallen-1971-war-heroes-at-national-memorial</link><description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman has paid tribute to the fallen heroes of the 1971 Liberation War at the National Memorial in Savar.
His travel to the National Memorial, which started after 5pm from the Zia Udyan, took about five hours to complete.
Tarique laid a wreath on the National Memorial</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 18:03:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Egypt edge S Africa after Salah penalty</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/football/salah-penalty-gives-10-man-egypt-rearguard-1-0-win-over-s-africa</link><description>Mohamed Salah scored a first half penalty as 10-man Egypt defeated South Africa 1-0 in their Africa Cup of Nations Group B clash in Agadir on Friday to become the first team into the knockout stages of the competition.
Egypt have six points from their opening two games and cannot finish outside of</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 18:18:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Banks generous in rural deposit sourcing, miserly in lending</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/banks-generous-in-rural-deposit-sourcing-miserly-in-lending</link><description>Banks are increasingly sourcing deposit from the countryside but their focus on rural Bangladesh keeps fading following tightfisted disbursement of formal credits, widening urban-rural financing gaps, sources say.
At the same time, the number of bank branches in the least-developed but promising a</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 18:33:22 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>