<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 07:21:38 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>49th special BCS: 1,219 candidates clear written examination</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/49th-special-bcs-1219-candidates-clear-written-examination</link><description>As many as 1,219 candidates have passed the 49th Special BCS written examination for the recruitment of 683 teachers in government colleges.
The Public Service Commission (PSC) spokesperson SM Matiur Rahman said about the results published on Sunday night, reports bdnews24.com.
The PSC said the v</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 04:28:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Education directorate issues fire safety alert for schools</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/education-directorate-issues-fire-safety-alert-for-schools</link><description>The Directorate of Secondary and Higher Education (DSHE) has issued a safety advisory urging teachers, officials and staff at educational institutions across Bangladesh to exercise caution in using electrical equipment following a spate of major fire incidents, including one at Dhaka’s Hazrat</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 05:43:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC holds meeting with law enforcers ahead of national polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-holds-meeting-with-law-enforcers-ahead-of-national-polls</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has started a views-exchange with different law enforcement agencies and intelligences in a bid to conduct the 13th parliamentary election in free, participatory and fair manners.
The meeting titled ‘views-exchange and pre-preparation meeting’ about the law</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 05:58:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Woman held for killing mother-in-law with hammer</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/woman-held-for-killing-mother-in-law-with-hammer</link><description>Police have arrested a woman on charges of killing her mother-in-law with a hammer following a family dispute in Bancharampur upazila of Brahmanbaria.
The incident took place on Sunday at Asadnagar Madhyapara village, according to Hasan Jamil Khan, chief of Bancharampur Model Police Station.
The</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 06:13:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Stocks see mixed trend in early trading</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/stocks-see-mixed-trend-in-early-trading-152749</link><description>The week’s second trading session began with a mixed performance on the country’s two stock exchanges as the Dhaka market opened higher while the Chattogram bourse witnessed a decline.
In the first hour of trading on Monday, the key index of the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE), DSEX, advanc</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 06:28:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dense fog and chilly winds grip northern districts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dense-fog-and-chilly-winds-grip-northern-districts</link><description>With the arrival of the Bangla month of Kartik, the signs of approaching winter are becoming increasingly visible across northern districts of the country as the surroundings remain blanketed in fog during the morning.
For the past few days, the rural areas across five upazilas in Lalmonirhat dist</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 06:58:09 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>