<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 19:17:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>New doors open to Malaysia for Bangladeshi recruiting agencies</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/new-doors-open-to-malaysia-for-bangladeshi-recruiting-agencies-but-new-rules-deemed-too-strict</link><description>A new opportunity has opened up for Bangladeshi recruiting agencies to send workers to Malaysia, as the Malaysian government moves toward providing equal access for all licensed agencies from Bangladesh.
For years, recruiting agencies from other countries enjoyed greater opportunities to participa</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 16:23:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hurricane Melissa, strongest storm ever to hit Jamaica, roars onward into Cuba</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/hurricane-melissa-strongest-storm-ever-to-hit-jamaica-roars-onward-into-cuba</link><description>Hurricane Melissa unleashed devastation in Jamaica as the strongest storm on record ever to hit the Caribbean island nation, and roared later on Wednesday into eastern Cuba, smashing the city of Santiago and flooding rural land.
A Category 5 storm with sustained winds of 185 mph (298 kph) when it</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 16:53:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gold price jumps again, crosses Tk 200 thousand per bhori</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/gold-price-jumps-again-crosses-tk-200-thousand-per-bhori</link><description>After four consecutive cuts that brought gold prices below Tk 200 thousand per bhori, the price of the precious metal has surged once again, rising by Tk 8,900 per bhori, to cross the Tk 200 thousand mark in the local market.
The Bangladesh Jewellers’ Association (BAJUS) announced in a state</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 17:08:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>West Indies seal series with 14-run win over Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/west-indies-seal-series-with-14-run-win-over-bangladesh</link><description>West Indies clinched the T20I series against Bangladesh with a 14-run win in the second match at the Bir Shreshtho Flight Lieutenant Matiur Rahman Stadium in Chattogram on Wednesday.
Before the T20Is, Bangladesh beat the West Indies in a three-match ODI series.
The visitors defended 149 to take a</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 16:53:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>S Alam files arbitration against interim government at World Bank tribunal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/s-alam-files-arbitration-against-interim-government-at-world-bank-tribunal</link><description>Businessman Saiful Alam, alias S Alam, has filed an arbitration case against Bangladesh’s interim government at the World Bank, reports Financial Times.
He claims the authorities' measures to recover laundered money have caused “hundreds of millions of dollars” in losses to his f</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 17:08:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Utilising rooftops for solar power generation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/utilising-rooftops-for-solar-power-generation</link><description>The Government of Bangladesh has decided to increase solar power generation and using rooftops of the government buildings including educational institutes and hospitals. The target has been fixed to generate 2,000-3,000 MW in phases using the building rooftops. The first phase of the initiative ta</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 17:23:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Putting a price tag on life</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/putting-a-price-tag-on-life</link><description>Regular loss of lives under most unfortunate circumstances has become a part of the city dwellers' precarious existence in the bustling megacity of Dhaka. The tragic death of 35-year-old Abul Kalam Azad from the bearing pad of metro rail pier falling on his head in Farmgate area has once again brou</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 17:38:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>RCEP membership for Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/rcep-membership-for-bangladesh</link><description>With the South Asian Association for Regional Cooperation (SAARC) virtually becoming dead and buried, the compulsion for Bangladesh to join a trade and economic bloc was overriding. The urgency has been further heightened by the country's graduation from LDC (least developed country) status and the</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 17:53:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>500 workers laid off at Opsonin saline factory, amid protests</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/500-workers-laid-off-at-opsonin-saline-factory-amid-protests</link><description>About 500 workers at Opsonin Saline (OSL) Pharma Ltd in Barishal were simultaneously laid off on Wednesday, sparking protests.
The factory management delivered layoff notices to the employees by post around midday.
Following the notification, unrest broke out among the workers, who gathered in fr</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 18:08:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Negotiators hope for next tranche as eligibility check starts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/negotiators-hope-for-next-tranche-as-eligibility-check-starts</link><description>Government negotiators hope for next payout worth US$450 million from the IMF lending package for Bangladesh as eligibility spot-check starts with a Fund mission querying about updates and subsidy cuts.
The reappraisal team from the International Monetary Fund (IMF), beginning its hectic review</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 18:23:28 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>