<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 14:30:37 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>ACC to file case against Jatiya Party leaders Ranga, Panir</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/acc-to-file-case-against-jatiya-party-leaders-ranga-panir</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) has decided to prosecute Jatiya Party leaders Mashiur Rahman Ranga and Panir Uddin Ahamed on charges of “bribery” and “money laundering”.
ACC Director General Md Akhtar Hossain on Monday informed journalists about the decision to file th</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 11:15:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh stock market closes higher on strong bullish momentum</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/bangladesh-stock-market-closes-higher-on-strong-bullish-momentum</link><description>Bangladesh’s stock markets closed higher on Monday as the early gains seen in the first hour of trading were sustained throughout the session, pushing key indices up by a satisfactory margin.
At the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE), the benchmark DSEX index advanced by 56 points by the end of the</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 11:30:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IGP holds talks with CEC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/police-chief-baharul-holds-meeting-with-cec-nasir</link><description>Inspector General of Police Baharul Alam has met with Chief Election Commissioner AMM Nasir Uddin.
The meeting was held at the Nirbachan Bhaban from 5:15pm on Monday.
Election Commissioner Abul Fazal Md Sanaullah was also present during the meeting.</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 11:45:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A ‘Yes’ Vote will open the door to a new Bangladesh: Yunus</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/a-yes-vote-will-open-the-door-to-a-new-bangladesh-says-ca-in-his-message-to-nation</link><description>Bangladesh’s Interim Government Chief Adviser, Professor Muhammad Yunus, has called on citizens to vote “Yes” in the national referendum scheduled for 12 February, describing the ballot as a historic opportunity to reshape the state and lock in democratic reforms born out of last</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 12:00:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khairul Anam and Jahanara Begum Trust distributes winter clothing in Dinajpur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/khairul-anam-and-jahanara-begum-trust-distributes-winter-clothing-in-dinajpur</link><description>As part of its ongoing humanitarian initiatives, the Khairul Anam &amp; Jahanara Begum Trust organized a winter clothing distribution program for underprivileged and destitute people in Dinajpur, continuing its tradition of supporting vulnerable communities during the winter season.
The distribution t</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 12:15:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fire breaks out in moving ambulance on Mawa Expressway; 4 escapes unhurt</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fire-breaks-out-in-moving-ambulance-on-mawa-expressway-4-escapes-unhurt</link><description>A fire broke out at a moving ambulance on the Dhaka–Mawa Expressway in Munshiganj district on Monday.
The fire broke out at the Magura-bound ambulance carrying four people including a patient, due to technical glitch over Kuchiamora Bridge on the expressway in the afternoon, said deputy assi</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 12:30:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt appoints 102 magistrates for security oversight of BCS exams</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-appoints-102-magistrates-for-security-oversight-of-bcs-exams</link><description>The government has appointed 102 executive magistrates for security oversight of preliminary exams of the Bangladesh Civil Service (BCS) on January 30.
The preliminary examination (MCQ type) of the 50th BCS will be held on January 30 from 10:00 am to 12:00 pm at 92 educational institutions in the</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 12:45:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mercantile Bank promotes Tapash Paul, Sohel Khurshid to DMDs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/mercantile-bank-promotes-tapash-paul-sohel-khurshid-to-dmds</link><description>Mercantile Bank PLC has promoted Tapash Chandra Paul, PhD, and Shah Md. Sohel Khurshid to the position of Deputy Managing Director.
According to a press release, the new role recognized their long-standing contributions, leadership excelence, and strategic impact on the Bank’s growth and gov</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 13:00:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Summit Group sets sights on Bangladesh’s first data center</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/summit-group-sets-sights-on-bangladeshs-first-data-center</link><description>Summit Group, one of Bangladesh’s largest business conglomerates, is preparing to enter the country’s fast-emerging data center market. Sources say the company aims to partner with an external business entity by next year, marking a significant step toward building what could become Ban</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 13:15:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nahid, Patwary respond to show-cause notices</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ncps-nahid-patwary-respond-to-show-cause-notices-over-early-yes-vote-push</link><description>National Citizen Party (NCP) Convenor Nahid Islam and Chief Coordinator Nasiruddin Patwary have responded to show-cause notices issued against them by returning officers for alleged violations of the electoral code of conduct.
The notice followed alleged campaigning in favour of a “Yes&amp;rdquo</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 13:30:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka Bank donates bus, coaster to Shahid Ziaur Rahman Medical College under CSR programme</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/dhaka-bank-donates-bus-coaster-to-shahid-ziaur-rahman-medical-college-under-csr-programme</link><description>Dhaka Bank has donated a bus and a coaster to Shahid Ziaur Rahman Medical College, Bogura under the Corporate Social Responsibility of the bank, according to a press release.
Mr. Abdul Hai Sarker, Chairman, formally handed over the keys to Professor Dr. Md. Wadudul Hoque Tarafder, Principal of Sha</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 13:45:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump links Greenland dispute to not getting Nobel Peace Prize</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-links-greenland-dispute-to-not-getting-nobel-peace-prize</link><description>US President Donald Trump has said he no longer feels obliged to think only of peace after he did not receive the Nobel Peace Prize, as he again repeated his demand for control of Greenland.
In a message to Norway’s prime minister, Trump blamed the country for not giving him the prize, repor</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 14:00:49 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>