<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 16:35:46 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>BRAC Bank distributes over 62,000 winter clothes across Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/brac-bank-distributes-over-62000-winter-clothes-across-bangladesh</link><description>BRAC Bank has distributed more than 62,000 winter clothes nationwide to support marginalised communities affected by extreme cold, according to a press release.
As part of the initiative, the bank provided 13,000 blankets through the Chief Advisor’s Welfare Fund and the Chattogram City Corpo</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 14:17:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ancient Roman home opens to the public - with remote guided tours</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/ancient-roman-home-opens-to-the-public-with-remote-guided-tours</link><description>An ancient Roman home more than 2,000 years old has opened to the public, but its spectacular mosaics, frescoes and stucco decorations will be accessible only via remote and web-streamed guided tours.
The "House of the Griffins", named after animal decorations in one of its rooms, was an aristocra</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 14:32:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Al-Arafah Islami Bank inaugurates workshop on general banking management</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/al-arafah-islami-bank-inaugurates-workshop-on-general-banking-management</link><description>A 3-day training workshop titled 'General Banking Management' at Al-Arafah Islami Bank has begun at the bank's training institute, according to a press release.
Managing Director and CEO Mohd Rafat Ullah Khan inaugurated the Workshop as the chief guest on Tuesday, January 13, 2026.
Speaking as th</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 14:47:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Media played a crucial role in shaping politics during 1980s, 1990s: CCC Mayor</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/media-played-a-crucial-role-in-shaping-politics-during-1980s-1990s-ccc-mayor</link><description>City Mayor Dr. Shahdat Hossain said that within the political history of Bangladesh, journalism extends beyond mere news reporting.
“The mass media also significantly contribute to the formation of leadership, the construction of political images, and the direction of mass movements. The med</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 14:00:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nine 'July activists' appointed at Ctg Port</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/chittagong-port-appoints-nine-july-activists-on-contract-for-a-year</link><description>Nine “July activists” have been appointed to Chattogram Port.
The Chattogram Port Authority (CPA) hired them on a one-year contract on Monday.
“The positions they have been given are not part of the revenue cadre. They will receive their salaries according to the outsourcing pol</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 14:15:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>1000th board meeting of Agrani Bank held</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/1000th-board-meeting-of-agrani-bank-held</link><description>The 1000th Board Meeting of Agrani Bank PLC was held on 13 January 2026 at the board room of Agrani Bank’s Head Office, according to a press release.
The meeting was presided by Syed Abu Naser Bukhtear Ahmed, Chairman of the Board of Directors of Agrani Bank PLC. Among others present at the</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 14:30:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Global central bank chiefs defend Fed's Powell after Trump threat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/global-central-bank-chiefs-defend-feds-powell-after-trump-threat</link><description>Central bank chiefs from around the world lined up in support of Federal Reserve Chair Jerome Powell on Tuesday, issuing an unprecedented statement of solidarity after the Trump administration threatened him with a criminal indictment.
Powell has been threatened with a probe over Congressional tes</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 14:45:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>81-year-old Ugandan president seeks seventh term after four decades in power</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/africa/81-year-old-ugandan-president-seeks-seventh-term-after-four-decades-in-power</link><description>When Yoweri Museveni seized power in Uganda in 1986, he said "the problem of Africa in general and Uganda in particular is not the people but leaders who want to overstay in power."
The 81-year-old president and former rebel is seeking a seventh term in office on Thursday after nearly four decades</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 15:00:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Suspect snatched from police in Mymensingh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/attackers-snatch-away-suspect-after-hacking-policemen-in-mymensingh-5-injured</link><description>Five policemen have been injured after attackers hacked them to snatch away a suspect in Mymensingh.
The suspect in handcuffs escaped with the attackers.
Members of the Rapid Action Battalion and the Army have been deployed to keep the situation under control following the attack.
Police have ar</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 15:15:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Arbeloa vows to ‘fight for everything’ as Real Madrid manager</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/arbeloa-vows-to-fight-for-everything-as-real-madrid-manager</link><description>Real Madrid’s new manager Alvaro Arbeloa pledged to fight for everything as he stepped into the role vacated by Xabi Alonso and said he would stay in post as long as he was needed.
Real announced Alonso had left the club by mutual agreement on Monday, following a poor run of form and reports</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 15:30:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gas crisis drives up demand, price of electric cookers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/dhaka-gas-shortage-pushes-households-to-electric-cookers-prices-rise-by-tk-1000</link><description>Dhaka residents are turning to electric cookers as the city faces a prolonged shortage of liquefied petroleum gas (LPG).
Saimun Nahar Parma, a resident of Kazipara, said that she had to buy an induction cooker after failing to secure an LPG cylinder from local dealers.
“With two young child</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 15:45:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>World Bank predicts 2026 GDP growth to improve slightly over forecasts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/global/world-bank-predicts-2026-gdp-growth-to-improve-slightly-over-forecasts</link><description>The global economy is proving more resilient than expected, with 2026 GDP growth expected to improve slightly over forecasts from last June, the World Bank said on Tuesday while warning that growth is too concentrated in advanced countries and overall too weak to reduce extreme poverty.
The World</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 16:00:41 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>