<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 05:24:40 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Govt's no to 20pc power bill rebate facility for fish, livestock and poultry farms</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/govts-no-to-20pc-power-bill-rebate-facility-for-fish-livestock-and-poultry-farms</link><description>The government has decided not to include fisheries, hatcheries, livestock and poultry farms in its existing 20 per cent electricity bill rebate scheme, despite recognising their rising costs of production.
The decision was taken at an inter ministerial meeting, which was held recently to review a</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 02:38:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Workers urge policy support for struggling spinning mills</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/workers-urge-policy-support-for-struggling-spinning-mills</link><description>Workers and employees from the spinning sub-sector of the textile industry have called on the government for policy support to help the spinning mills overcome ongoing challenges, particularly the import of yarn at dumping rates.
The spinning mills are grappling with several issues, including esca</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 02:53:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Youth essential to build safer migration pathways</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/youth-essential-to-build-safer-migration-pathways</link><description>Youth must be placed at the centre of Bangladesh's migration governance to build safer and more resilient mobility systems, speakers observed at a national dialogue in Dhaka on Thursday.
They noted that young people already constitute a major share of global migrants and that their perspectives ar</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 03:08:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CJ inaugurates SC Secretariat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cj-inaugurates-sc-secretariat</link><description>Chief Justice (CJ) Dr. Syed Refaat Ahmed inaugurated the Supreme Court Secretariat on Thursday, describing the moment as a historic turning point for the country's judiciary.
The CJ unveiled the SC Secretariat by removing the ceremonial cloth from the cornerstone at Supreme Court (SC) Admin Buildi</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 03:23:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Three-day MIDAS SME fair begins in capital</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/three-day-midas-sme-fair-begins-in-capital</link><description>The three-day MIDAS SME Winter Fair 2025 began on Thursday at the MIDAS Centre in Dhanmondi, Dhaka, bringing together over 60 youth and women entrepreneurs from across the country.
The fair is being held from December 11 to 13.
Ms. Parveen Mahmud FCA, Chairperson of the MIDAS Board, presided over</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 03:38:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Police pick up four persons from Secretariat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/police-pick-up-four-persons-from-secretariat</link><description>Police on Thursday detained four persons from the Bangladesh Secretariat area for staging demonstrations demanding the issuance of an office order regarding payment of 20 per cent "secretariat allowance" to the employees of the top administrative headquarters of the country.
The development occurr</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 03:53:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>MOHAMMADPUR DOUBLE MURDER: Burn mark, past record help police arrest killer</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/mohammadpur-double-murder-burn-mark-past-record-help-police-arrest-killer</link><description>The Dhaka Metropolitan Police (DMP) said burn mark and previous theft record helped police to identify and arrest domestic help Ayesha. She allegedly killed her employer, Laila Afroz, and her 15-year-old daughter, Nafisa Nawal Binte Aziz, at their Mohammadpur home following a confrontation over ste</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 04:08:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tk 94.28b loan fraud: ACC to sue S Alam, Janata officials</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tk-9428b-loan-fraud-acc-to-sue-s-alam-janata-officials</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) Thursday approved five separate cases against multiple S Alam Group entities and their officials, as well as Janata Bank officials, for allegedly embezzling Tk 94.28 billion through loan irregularities, misuse of authority, and criminal breach of trust.
Accordi</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 04:23:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Godkhali florists dream big as new season approaching</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/godkhali-florists-dream-big-as-new-season-approaching</link><description>BENAPOLE, Dec 11: Known as the "Flower Capital" of Bangladesh, Godkhali in Jashore is once again buzzing with activities as the new season bringing along five back-to-back special occasions like Victory Day, Christmas, Thirty First Night, Valentine's Day and Mother Langue Day is approaching.
With</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 04:38:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Aman paddy harvest in Sylhet nearing end, 80pc already done</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/aman-paddy-harvest-in-sylhet-nearing-end-80pc-already-done</link><description>SYLHET, Dec 11: Farmers in the Sylhet region are in the midst of a busy and successful Aman paddy harvest. Over 80 per cent of the crop has already been harvested, according to farmers and officials from various upazilas.
Ataur Rahman Mia, a farmer from Baushi in Golapganj upazila, said that this</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 04:53:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Thai PM moves to dissolve parliament</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/thai-pm-moves-to-dissolve-parliament</link><description>Thailand's Prime Minister Anutin Charnvirakul announced on Thursday that he is "returning power to the people," moving to dissolve parliament and clear the way for elections earlier than previously anticipated.
Government spokesperson Siripong Angkasakulkiat told Reuters the move followed a disagr</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 05:08:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Suspect in Charlie Kirk killing appears in court, judge mulls media access</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/suspect-in-charlie-kirk-killing-appears-in-court-judge-mulls-media-access</link><description>Tyler Robinson, the accused killer of conservative activist Charlie Kirk, made his first in-person court appearance on Thursday as a judge heard arguments on what level of media access should be allowed in the high-profile criminal case.
Robinson, wearing a dress shirt and striped tie, talked with</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 05:23:13 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>