<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 05:23:38 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Over 42pc cost hike along with tenure extension proposed for CMID</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/over-42pc-cost-hike-along-with-tenure-extension-proposed-for-cmid</link><description>The National Board of Revenue (NBR) has managed to utilise only Tk 102.32 million--a mere 0.61 per cent of the total Tk 16.86 billion allocation--for a flagship project designed to modernise the country's customs system and cut international trade processing time by 25 per cent.
As a result, the I</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 03:31:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Metro rail run resumes after staff strike</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/metro-rail-run-resumes-after-staff-strike</link><description>Metro rail-crammed Dhaka's most popular mass transport-resumed operation after a halt on Friday as the striking employees postponed their strike enforced to press home their demand for service rule with some perks.
They called off their strike at the last hour of the day's train operation with an</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 02:10:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Onion prices still high despite imports, seed onions at hand</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/onion-prices-still-high-despite-imports-seed-onions-at-hand</link><description>Onion prices still remain high in the markets even though new seed onions are now available and imports have started.
Onions were sold at Tk110-140 per kg on Friday.
Meanwhile, the government increased edible oil prices by Tk6.0-7.0 per litre on December 6 last. Bottled soybean oil is now selling</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 02:25:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh inching towards a 'high debt burden nation'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/bangladesh-inching-towards-a-high-debt-burden-nation</link><description>Bangladesh is inching towards a 'high debt-burden nation' as the country's interest payment has entered into "highest expenditure club" over the last few years posting 17 per cent increase in revenue budget allocation year-on-year in the last fiscal, official data showed.
The expenditure has cross</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 02:40:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Outstanding consumer lending rises 7.1pc in Q3 of 2025</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/outstanding-consumer-lending-rises-71pc-in-q3-of-2025</link><description>The outstanding consumer loans and advances in the country's banking sector maintained an upward trend over the last two quarters of 2025, according to Bangladesh Bank (BB) data.
The volume of aggregate consumer credit exceeded Tk 1.50 trillion at the end of third quarter (July-September) of 2025,</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 02:55:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh's apparel exports can fetch $122.01b by 2030 thru investing in climate adaptation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladeshs-apparel-exports-can-fetch-12201b-by-2030-thru-investing-in-climate-adaptation</link><description>Investing in climate adaptation can help Bangladesh fetch US$122.01 billion in apparel exports by the year 2030 as a significant rise in heat waves and flooding in Dhaka over the last two decades severely impacted workers' health and factory outputs, according to a new study.
"In 2030, Bangladesh</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 03:10:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The train to Chalan Beel</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/analysis/the-train-to-chalan-beel</link><description>I phone Pobitro Adhikary when the Dhumketu Express lurches forward at 6am, telling him we have departed from the Kamalapur railway station on time. He is my childhood friend, and we have planned a train-themed exploration of the Chalan Beel. Our destination is the Dilpasar station in Pabna, but as</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 03:25:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Building material market continues to be bearish</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/building-material-market-continues-to-be-bearish</link><description>The slump in demand for key building materials, including MS rod and cement, continues due to a sluggish economy, investment slowdown, and limited implementation of public-sector development projects, sector insiders say.
They say the demand for construction materials remains almost half compared</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 03:40:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Border Road in Chittagong Hill Tracts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/analysis/border-road-in-chittagong-hill-tracts</link><description>A New Road to the Future
A quiet revolution is taking place in the wavy green hills of Bangladesh in one of the most distant frontiers of Bangladesh. The Border Road Project in Chittagong Hill Tracts (CHT) which is spearheaded and implemented by Bangladesh Army is not just a road passing through t</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 03:55:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>When hilshas jump on a ship out of Bay water</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/analysis/when-hilshas-jump-on-a-ship-out-of-bay-water</link><description>When serious issues like the February election and law and order are drawing the nation's attention, some extraordinary happenings of lighter vein are quietly doing their rounds. One such thing happened away from the land but within the country's territorial limit in the Bay of Bengal. Yes, no one</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 04:10:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BD lists 3.84m persons with disabilities: DSS</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bd-lists-384m-persons-with-disabilities-dss</link><description>Bangladesh has registered 3.84 million persons with disabilities in 12 official categories, senior government officials said at a national event on inclusive education and disability services.
Some 3.45 million of these persons are currently receiving allowances as beneficiaries, while 81,000 scho</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 04:25:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>WEEKLY STOCK MARKET: Stocks rebound as election schedule boosts market sentiment</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/weekly-stock-market-stocks-rebound-as-election-schedule-boosts-market-sentiment</link><description>The benchmark equity index of Dhaka bourse ended higher this week, paring half of the losses from the previous week, as the announcement of the national election schedule fuelled optimism in the market.
Market analysts noted that the political developments surrounding the upcoming elections offere</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 04:40:27 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>