<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 19:37:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Fewer foreign students, fewer dollars: US colleges feel the pinch</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/fewer-foreign-students-fewer-dollars-us-colleges-feel-the-pinch</link><description>DePaul University has told faculty it will immediately reduce spending following a 30 per cent decline in international enrollment this fall. The move is the latest by US colleges to cope with the disruptive education and immigration policies of President Donald Trump.
The amount of the reduction</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 16:23:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>20 injured as Jamaat, BNP clash in Chandpur over ‘edited' Facebook photo</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/20-injured-as-jamaat-bnp-clash-in-chandpur-over-edited-facebook-photo</link><description>At least 20 people have been injured in a clash between leaders and activists of the BNP and Jamaat-e-Islami in Chandpur’s Hajiganj Upazila, triggered by a Facebook post containing “distorted” images of BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman and party leader Rumin Farhana.
Hajiganj</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 16:47:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India set to receive first Afghan Taliban minister</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/india-set-to-receive-first-afghan-taliban-minister</link><description>The UN Security Council Committee has temporarily lifted a travel ban on the Afghan Taliban foreign minister, which would allow him to visit India between Oct 9 and 16, India's foreign ministry said on Friday.
If confirmed, it would be the first visit to India by a senior leader of the Taliban-run</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 17:02:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump gives Hamas until Sunday night to reach Gaza deal or 'all HELL' will break out</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-gives-hamas-until-sunday-night-to-reach-gaza-deal-or-all-hell-will-break-out</link><description>US President Donald Trump gave Palestinian Hamas militants until Sunday evening to accept his proposal to end the nearly two-year-old war with US ally Israel in the Gaza Strip, or "all HELL" would break out.
"An agreement must be reached with Hamas by Sunday Evening at SIX (6)pm, Washington, DC ti</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 17:17:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sumud Flotilla detainees begin hunger strike in Israeli custody</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/sumud-flotilla-detainees-begin-hunger-strike-in-israeli-custody</link><description>Activists detained from the Global Sumud Flotilla are on an indefinite hunger strike.
The International Committee to Break the Siege of Gaza confirmed the protest on Friday, according to Turkey’s Anadolu Agency.
The committee said the detainees began the strike from the moment they were cap</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 18:02:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Administrators picked to lead their merger into one govt bank</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/administrators-picked-to-lead-their-merger-into-one-govt-bank</link><description>Bangladesh Bank has picked and may appoint administrators to the five crisis-hit Islamic banks this week under the modus operandi for their merger into a state-owned sharia-based lender, officials said.
The central bank is executing the mergers under provisions of the Bank Resolution Ordinance 2</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 18:17:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Journalist hacked to death in Bagerhat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/journalist-hacked-to-death-in-bagerhat</link><description>A journalist was killed in an attack by miscreants in Bagerhat town on Friday evening, according to local media reports.
The victim, identified as Hayat Uddin (42), was assaulted in the Harikhali area of the town. He was rushed to Khulna Medical College Hospital in a critical condition, where on-d</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 18:32:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two debt systems: US recycles, Bangladesh bleeds</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/two-debt-systems-us-recycles-bangladesh-bleeds</link><description>Every country pays for its debt — but not every country pays with its dignity, institutions, and future. In the United States (US), the headlines scream of fiscal disaster as the national debt crosses US$36 trillion, with nearly $950 billion in annual interest payments. To many Americans, thi</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 18:47:22 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>