<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 13:35:40 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Govt to cut savings certificate profit rates from January</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/govt-to-cut-savings-certificate-profit-rates-from-january</link><description>The government is set to slash profit rates on national savings certificates (Sanchaypatra) from January 1, 2026, marking the second reduction in six months, following calls from the banking sector.
The Finance Division of the Ministry of Finance has drafted a proposal outlining the new profit rat</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 11:21:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sonali Bank holds ALCO meeting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/sonali-bank-holds-alco-meeting-1</link><description>The 255th Asset - Liabilities Committee (ALCO) meeting of Sonali Bank PLC was held at the bank’s head office conference room on 22 December, Monday.
ALCO Chairman and MD &amp; CEO of Sonali Bank, Md. Shawkat Ali Khan presided over the meeting, according to a press release.
Deputy Managing Direc</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 11:36:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shaheed Minar sit-in ends as Inqilab Moncho demands justice for Hadi within 24 hours</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/shaheed-minar-sit-in-ends-as-inqilab-moncho-demands-justice-for-hadi-within-24-hours</link><description>Inqilab Moncho has concluded its protest at the Central Shaheed Minar after issuing a 24-hour ultimatum to the government, seeking justice for the killing of Sharif Osman bin Hadi.
The platform demanded the formation of a speedy judicial tribunal and two other measures over the killing of Hadi, re</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 11:51:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Modhumoti Bank holds 141th meeting of executive committee</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/modhumoti-bank-holds-141th-meeting-of-executive-committee</link><description>The 141st meeting of the Executive Committee of Modhumoti Bank PLC was held on Monday, 22nd December 2025 at Bank’s Head Office premises.
The meeting was presided over by EC Chairman, Mr. Salahuddin Alamgir, according to a press release.
Among others, Mr. Mostafa Kamal, Mr. Mohammad Ismail</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 12:06:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>71-member Navy contingent leaves Dhaka for UNMIS</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/71-member-navy-contingent-leaves-dhaka-for-unmis</link><description>A 71-member contingent of the Bangladesh Navy, in its second phase, left Dhaka on Monday to participate in the “Bangladesh Force Marine Unit-11” deployed under the United Nations Mission in South Sudan (UNMIS).
The contingent will serve in South Sudan as a replacement for the “Ba</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 11:23:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IDRA flags challenges in scaling climate risk insurance</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/idra-flags-challenges-in-scaling-climate-risk-insurance-in-bangladesh</link><description>Climate risk insurance is becoming increasingly crucial for Bangladesh, one of the world's most climate-vulnerable countries, but structural, technical, and policy challenges have so far hindered its large-scale implementation, said Insurance Development and Regulatory Authority (IDRA) Chairman Dr</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 11:38:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ehsanul Huda dissolves Jatiya Dal to join BNP in political realignment</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ehsanul-huda-dissolves-jatiya-dal-to-join-bnp-in-political-realignment</link><description>Syed Ehsanul Huda, chairman of Bangladesh Jatiya Dal, joined BNP on Monday, dissolving his own party.
He, along with his party leaders and workers, formally joined BNP around 4:40 pm at the party Chairperson's Gulshan office by presenting a bouquet to its Secretary General, Mirza Fakhrul Islam Ala</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 11:53:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Japan prepares to restart world's biggest nuclear plant</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/japan-prepares-to-restart-worlds-biggest-nuclear-plant</link><description>Japan took the final step to allow the world's largest nuclear power plant to resume operations with a regional vote on Monday, a watershed moment in the country's return to nuclear energy nearly 15 years after the Fukushima disaster.
Kashiwazaki-Kariwa, located about 220km (136 miles) northwest o</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 12:08:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>United Finance extends support to BANCAT’s Cancer Care Home</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/united-finance-extends-support-to-bancats-cancer-care-home</link><description>United Finance PLC has partnered with the Bangladesh Cancer Aid Trust (BANCAT) to support its cancer care home Mosabbir Alok Nibash.
BANCAT, a non-profit organization, provides financial assistance for medical treatment and holistic care to cancer patients across the country. The organization curr</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 12:23:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Austrian painter Arnulf Rainer dies at 96</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/entertainment/austrian-painter-arnulf-rainer-dies-at-96</link><description>Austrian artist Arnulf Rainer has died at the age of 96, Austrian news agency APA reported on Sunday.
A versatile and often provocative exponent of abstract art, Rainer was considered one of Austria’s leading postwar artists and was a pioneer of Art Informel in his homeland. His works featur</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 12:38:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCP leader shooting: Police hunt female companion</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/police-on-hunt-for-woman-seen-with-khulna-ncp-leader-after-he-was-shot-drugs-recovered</link><description>Police are searching for a female companion who was with Motaleb Shikdar, Khulna chief of the NCP-affiliated Jatiya Sramik Shakti, when he was shot.
Law enforcers also recovered different drugs from their residence.
The incident occurred on Monday afternoon at a flat in Sonadanga of Khulna. Docto</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 12:53:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Israel approves 19 new West Bank settlements</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/israel-approves-19-new-west-bank-settlements</link><description>Israel’s Cabinet has approved plans for 19 new Jewish settlements in the occupied West Bank, further accelerating settlement expansion that critics say undermines prospects for a future Palestinian state.
Finance Minister Bezalel Smotrich said the decision raises the total number of newly ap</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 13:08:25 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>