<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 05:25:44 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>FY24 in BB’s sight as revised REER base year</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/fy24-in-bbs-sight-as-revised-reer-base-year</link><description>Bangladesh Bank (BB) is planning to revisit the base year for calculating the Real Effective Exchange Rate (REER) index to make it more realistic and representative of current market conditions, officials said.
The central bank currently uses FY2015-16 as the base year for calculating the REER ind</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 02:15:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt suspends 14 Secretariat staff</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-suspends-14-secretariat-staff</link><description>The government has temporarily suspended fourteen employees of the Bangladesh Secretariat following their involvement in a protest demanding reinstatement of the 'Secretariat allowance'.
As part of the move, the respective ministries have issued official notifications on December 15, saying the em</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 02:30:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fate of Airport-Gazipur BRT project hangs in the balance</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fate-of-airport-gazipur-brt-project-hangs-in-the-balance</link><description>The interim government has failed to decide on the much-awaited Dhaka Airport-Gazipur Bus Rapid Transit (BRT) project, which remains halted for nearly a year, officials say.
They said on Wednesday that the halt had already damaged construction materials, with the prices of new ones expected to esc</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 02:45:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fire at plastic factory cluster imperils densely packed Lalbagh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fire-at-plastic-factory-cluster-imperils-densely-packed-lalbagh</link><description>A massive fire broke out at a cluster of plastic factories in the Lalbagh area of Old Dhaka on Wednesday afternoon, creating serious safety risks in the densely-populated neighbourhood.
The fire erupted at around 1:05 pm near Chairman Ghat, according to the local people and witnesses.
The blaze w</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 03:00:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BB buys $67m more to stabilise forex mkt</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bb-buys-67m-more-to-stabilise-forex-mkt</link><description>The central bank purchased a further US$67 million through auction from seven banks in the interbank spot market on Wednesday, aiming to stabilise the exchange rate of the US dollar against the local currency.
The amount was bought under the Multiple Price Auction method, with a cut-off rate of Tk</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 03:15:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh on track to energy efficiency goals: Study</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-on-track-to-energy-efficiency-goals-study</link><description>Bangladesh's energy efficiency targets are within reach as a supportive regulatory framework and rising awareness create a favourable ecosystem, even amid supply disruptions and higher tariffs, according to a new study by an international energy think tank.
The report, released Wednesday, finds th</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 03:30:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ICT-1 takes formal charge against sacked Maj Gen Ziaul Ahsan into cognisance</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ict-1-takes-formal-charge-against-sacked-maj-gen-ziaul-ahsan-into-cognisance</link><description>The prosecution of the International Crimes Tribunal-1 (ICT-1) in Dhaka has submitted the formal charge on three specific grounds of enforced disappearances and killings of more than a hundred people against sacked Major General Ziaul Ahsan.
After a primary hearing on Wednesday, the ICT-1 headed b</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 03:45:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>High-profile EU team to observe 13th JS elections</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/high-profile-eu-team-to-observe-13th-js-elections</link><description>A high-profile European Union (EU) election observation mission will arrive in Bangladesh to observe the 13th National Parliamentary Election and the referendum, Election Commission (EC) Senior Secretary Akhtar Ahmed said on Wednesday.
"I have been hinted that between 175 and 200 election observer</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 04:00:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Delay in revised IPO rules puts a brake on listings</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/delay-in-revised-ipo-rules-puts-a-brake-on-listings</link><description>The year 2025 is nearing its end without a single company being listed, a rare event in the history of the country’s capital market.
The current commission of the Bangladesh Securities and Exchange Commission (BSEC), formed after the political changeover in August last year, has yet to final</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 04:15:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Auditors flag going-concern risk facing Global Heavy Chemicals, Metro Spinning</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/auditors-flag-going-concern-risk-facing-global-heavy-chemicals-metro-spinning</link><description>The auditors of two listed companies-Global Heavy Chemicals and Metro Spinning-have raised red flags over their ability to sustain business operations.
In their latest audit opinions included in the FY25 financial statements, the auditors said it was necessary to inform investors about the compani</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 04:30:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt issues Tk 5.8b state guarantees in favour of TCB to help procure essentials</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/govt-issues-tk-58b-state-guarantees-in-favour-of-tcb-to-help-procure-essentials</link><description>The government has issued three state guarantees totalling Tk 5.80 billion in favour of Sonali Bank to facilitate the procurement of essential commodities by the Trading Corporation of Bangladesh (TCB), sources said.
The state-run TCB under the Ministry of Commerce (MoC) is set to procure signific</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 04:45:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Biman introduces body cameras for staff at HSIA</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/biman-introduces-body-cameras-for-staff-at-hsia</link><description>Biman Bangladesh Airlines has introduced body-worn cameras for staff involved in baggage handling at Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport (HSIA) in Dhaka, aiming to strengthen security, transparency and accountability in ground handling operations.
Under the initiative, traffic staff responsible</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 05:00:56 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>