<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 10:21:59 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>'Political realities prevent my return', says Tarique</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/political-realities-prevent-my-return-says-tarique-as-he-seeks-prayers-for-khaleda</link><description>Urging everyone to continue praying for the recovery of his critically ill mother, Khaleda Zia, BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman has said that although he strongly wishes to return home and be by her side, he is unable to do so freely due to the current political realities.
In a Facebook post on</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 06:05:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nepal issues new Rs 100 note showing ‘Indian territories’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/nepal-issues-new-rs-100-note-showing-indian-territories</link><description>Nepal’s central bank on Thursday unveiled new Rs 100 currency notes featuring a revised national map that includes the disputed Kalapani, Lipulekh, and Limpiyadhura regions, territories India has long maintained are its own, reports The Times of India.
The move revives a years-long boundary</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 06:20:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khasru says BNP will replicate RMG model in other export sectors if elected</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/khasru-says-bnp-will-replicate-rmg-model-in-other-export-sectors-if-elected</link><description>BNP standing committee member Amir Khasru Mahmud Chowdhury has said they will replicate the successful RMG model in other export-oriented industries if they come to power.
Speaking at the 4th Bangladesh Economic Conference on Saturday, he said they will open facilities such as bonded warehouses an</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 06:35:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two workers burnt in Gazipur factory explosion</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/two-workers-burnt-in-gazipur-factory-explosion</link><description>Two workers have been burnt in a fire sparked by a machine explosion at a factory in Kaliakair upazila of Gazipur district.
The incident occurred on Friday evening at Madina Polymer Industries Ltd's unit in the Upazila's Board Mill area, according to Monir Hossain, a firefighter from the Kaliakair</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 06:50:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Election schedule to be declared in second week of Dec: CEC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/election-schedule-to-be-declared-in-second-week-of-dec-cec</link><description>Chief Election Commissioner AMM Nasir Uddin has said the Election Commission will announce the schedule for the next general election in the second week of December. 
“Hopefully, what we expect is that it will be declared in the second week of December. When the schedule is announced, t</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 07:05:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mock voting drill under way in Dhaka ahead of national election, referendum</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/mock-voting-drill-under-way-in-dhaka-ahead-of-national-election-referendum</link><description>A mock voting exercise is being held in Dhaka as the Election Commission (EC) tests its preparations for the upcoming 13th national election and a nationwide referendum, both scheduled to take place on the same day in February next year.
The drill began at 8:00 am on Saturday at the Sher-e-Bangla</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 07:20:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No dollar shortage ahead of Ramadan imports, says BB chief</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/no-dollar-shortage-ahead-of-ramadan-imports-says-bb-chief</link><description>Bangladesh Bank Governor Ahsan H Mansur has played down concerns over a US dollar shortage and said that he saw no obstacles to paying for essential Ramadan imports.
Speaking at the Fourth Bangladesh Economic Conference in Dhaka on Saturday, the governor said the external sector had “stabili</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 08:28:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Advisory Council offers prayers for BNP chief Khaleda’s recovery</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/advisory-council-offers-prayers-for-bnp-chief-khaledas-recovery</link><description>The interim government's Advisory Council has held a special prayer session for the recovery of BNP Chairperson Khaleda Zia, who remains in critical condition in the hospital.
The session took place on Saturday at the office of Chief Advisor Muhammad Yunus, who presided over the meeting. Religious</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 08:31:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Over 2m taxpayers file returns online in 5 months: NBR</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/over-2m-taxpayers-file-returns-online-in-5-months-nbr</link><description>More than two million taxpayers have filed their income tax returns online so far in the 2025–26 fiscal year, marking a major increase in the use of Bangladesh’s electronic tax filing system, the National Board of Revenue (NBR) said on Saturday.
Finance Adviser Dr Salehuddin Ahmed laun</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 08:46:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mirza Abbas alleges ‘slow poisoning’ of Khaleda during imprisonment</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/mirza-abbas-alleges-slow-poisoning-of-khaleda-during-imprisonment</link><description>BNP Standing Committee Member Mirza Abbas on Saturday claimed that BNP Chairperson Khaleda Zia’s illness is ‘not natural’, alleging that she was subjected to ‘slow poisoning’ while in prison under the Awami League government.
“Begum Khaleda Zia’s illness i</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 09:01:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh election: Voter registration in KSA, six other countries resumes</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-election-voter-registration-in-ksa-six-other-countries-resumes</link><description>Voter registration for Bangladeshi expatriates living in Saudi Arabia, Bahrain, Kuwait, Malaysia, Oman, Qatar and the United Arab Emirates, which was suspended due to incomplete address information, resumed on Saturday.
The registration of expatriate Bangladeshi voters in the seven countries resum</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 09:16:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IGP returns home after attending Interpol General Assembly</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/igp-returns-home-after-attending-interpol-general-assembly</link><description>Inspector General of Police (IGP) Baharul Alam returned home on Saturday after attending the 93rd General Assembly of Interpol held in Morocco.
Police chiefs and delegates from Interpol’s 196 member countries participated in the global gathering, reports UNB.
The high-level meeting discusse</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 09:31:43 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>