<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 11:24:52 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>SAARC journalists meet at Delhi University</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/saarc-journalists-meet-at-delhi-university-1</link><description>SAARC Journalists Forum (SJF) on Friday organised an international conference and tree plantation programme at the historic Gandhi Bhawan, located in the North Campus of Delhi University, in India.
Journalist leaders from various SAARC countries, university teachers, and a large number of students</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 08:01:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jailed Awami League leader Ramesh Chandra Sen dies in custody</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jailed-awami-league-leader-ramesh-chandra-sen-dies-in-custody</link><description>Former water resources minister and senior Awami League leader Ramesh Chandra Sen has died while in jail.
The 85-year-old passed away at 9:30am on Saturday, said Taufiq Hasan, a doctor at the emergency department of Dinajpur Medical College Hospital.</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 08:16:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Teknaf child injured by Myanmar gunfire dies</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/teknaf-child-injured-by-myanmar-gunfire-dies</link><description>A child from Teknaf who was seriously injured by gunfire originating from Myanmar has died under hospital care.
Huzaifa Sultana Afnan suffered a critical head injury in the incident in Whykong Union on Jan 11. She died around 9:50 am on Saturday while receiving treatment at the National Institute</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 08:31:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump refuses to apologise for video depicting Obamas as apes</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-refuses-to-apologise-for-video-depicting-obamas-as-apes</link><description>US President Donald Trump condemned but did not apologise for a video on his social media account depicting Democratic former President Barack Obama and first lady Michelle Obama as apes, a post that triggered swift, bipartisan criticism for dehumanising people of African descent.
The White House</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 08:17:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt expects responsible journalism: Shafiqul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-expects-responsible-journalism-shafiqul</link><description>Expressing deep concern over misleading reports carried out by different media outlets on Friday centering clashes between police and Inquilab Moncho, demanding justice for Shaheed Sharif Osman Hadi, Chief Adviser's Press Secretary Shafiqul Alam, Saturday said that the government expected responsib</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 08:32:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP alleges plot to manipulate national election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-alleges-plot-to-manipulate-national-election</link><description>BNP Central Election Steering Committee Spokesperson Mahdi Amin on Saturday alleged that a political party is systematically preparing for “election engineering” to influence the national election and its results.
“Some recent incidents indicate a well-planned attempt to manipula</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 08:47:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Port workers announce fresh strike at Chattogram Port from Sunday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/port-workers-announce-fresh-strike-at-chattogram-port-from-sunday</link><description>Port workers have announced a fresh indefinite work stoppage at Chattogram Port from Sunday, protesting the proposed leasing of the New Mooring Container Terminal (NCT) to foreign operator DP World and pressing four other demands.
Humayun Kabir, coordinator of Chattogram Port Protection Movement C</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 09:02:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique pledges swift reopening of Thakurgaon airport if elected</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-pledges-swift-reopening-of-thakurgaon-airport-if-elected</link><description>Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) chief Tarique Rahman has promised to make Thakurgaon Airport operational swiftly if his party forms the next government.
Speaking at an election rally on Saturday, Tarique said work on the airport was already at an advanced stage and could be completed soon after</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 09:17:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Afghanistan among world's dangerous places for mothers, newborns: UN</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/afghanistan-among-worlds-dangerous-places-for-mothers-newborns-un</link><description>Afghanistan remains one of the most perilous countries in the world for mothers and newborns due to extremely high mortality rates and persistent funding constraints, the United Nations Population Fund (UNFPA) said, according to local media reports on Saturday.
The UNFPA reported that the country</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 09:32:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP candidate Ishraque Hossain seeks removal of Sutrapur OC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-candidate-ishraque-hossain-seeks-removal-of-sutrapur-oc</link><description>BNP candidate Ishraque Hossain has called on the Election Commission to remove the chief (OC) of Sutrapur Police Station, alleging biased conduct.
Ishraque, who is contesting in the Dhaka-6 seat in the Feb 12 election, also requested that the polling centre at Cosmopolitan School and College in Su</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 10:04:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat candidates won't take plots, duty-free if elected: Shafiqur Rahman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-candidates-wont-take-plots-duty-free-if-elected-shafiqur-rahman</link><description>Jamaat-e-Islami chief Shafiqur Rahman has said that members of his party will refuse government-allocated plots and duty-free vehicles if elected to parliament.
Speaking at an election rally in Habiganj on Saturday, Shafiqur said Jamaat candidates would also publicly disclose annual income and exp</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 10:19:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nearly 35pc of election candidates have no income tax records: SHUJAN</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nearly-35pc-of-election-candidates-have-no-income-tax-records-shujan</link><description>Nearly 35 per cent of the 2,026 candidates contesting the 13th parliamentary election, or 707 individuals, have no publicly available income tax records, according to data from civil society organisation Shushashoner Jonno Nagorik (SHUJAN).
The findings were presented on Saturday at a press confer</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 10:34:28 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>