<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 16:34:06 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>'Govt moves to formulate action plan to eliminate child labour by 2030'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-moves-to-formulate-action-plan-to-eliminate-child-labour-by-2030</link><description>The government has initiated a move to formulate a national action plan to eliminate child labour from the country by 2030, Labour Secretary Sanwar Jahan Bhuiyan said on Thursday.
Eradication of child labour requires coordinated interventions—particularly in hazardous sectors—alongside</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 13:54:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Billion in irregularities’: Kamal faces graft charges</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/chargesheet-imminent-as-acc-probes-tk-1b-irregularities-claims-against-ex-minister-kamal</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) is set to submit a chargesheet against former home minister Asaduzzaman Khan Kamal over alleged irregularities involving more than Tk 1 billion in illegal assets and suspicious financial transactions.
ACC Director General Akhtar Hossain said on Thursday that th</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 14:09:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC seeks police for RO, ARO offices ahead of Bangladesh polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-seeks-police-for-ro-aro-offices-ahead-of-bangladesh-polls</link><description>The Election Commission on Thursday asked the Home Ministry to deploy a necessary number of police personnel to ensure the security of the offices of Returning Officers (ROs) and Assistant Returning Officers (AROs) ahead of the upcoming national election and the referendum, scheduled for February 1</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 14:24:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nuzhat Anwar new DSE managing director</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/nuzhat-anwar-new-dse-managing-director</link><description>Ms. Nuzhat Anwar has been appointed as the new Managing Director of Dhaka Stock Exchange PLC, who has over two decades of experience in financial markets, banking, and development finance.
The Bangladesh Securities and Exchange Commission (BSEC) on Thursday approved her appointment, says a press r</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 14:39:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ensure public safety without disrupting normal life: DMP Commissioner asks police</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ensure-public-safety-without-disrupting-normal-life-dmp-commissioner-asks-police</link><description>Dhaka Metropolitan Police (DMP) Commissioner Sheikh Md Sazzat Ali on Thursday said law enforcers must ensure public safety while allowing normal daily activities to continue uninterrupted.
He made the remarks at a meeting at the DMP Headquarters ahead of Christmas, the largest religious festival o</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 14:15:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Judiciary must see constitutional changes as reality, not threat: CJ</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/judiciary-must-see-constitutional-changes-as-reality-not-threat-cj</link><description>Chief Justice Syed Refaat Ahmed on Thursday emphasised that the judiciary should view amendments to the Constitution not as a threat, but as a reflection of democratic reality.
“People hold constitutional authority and can amend the Constitution over time. The judiciary must accept this not</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 14:30:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Saudi, French and US officials push Hezbollah disarmament plan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/saudi-french-and-us-officials-push-hezbollah-disarmament-plan</link><description>French, Saudi Arabian and American officials held talks with the head of the Lebanese army on Thursday in Paris aimed at finalising a roadmap to enable a mechanism for the disarmament of the Hezbollah group, diplomats said.
Israel and Lebanon agreed to a US-brokered ceasefire in 2024, ending more</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 14:45:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rumi faced threats without protection: Samantha</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rumi-faced-relentless-threats-found-no-protection-from-police-says-ncps-samantha</link><description>Senior NCP leader Samantha Sharmin has alleged that party activist Jannatara Rumi received no protection from police despite being subjected to continuous threats and online bullying, and lodging formal complaints.
NCP Joint Convenor Shamantha visited the Dhaka Medical College Hospital morgue on T</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 15:00:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pope Leo replaces New York’s Cardinal Dolan in shake-up of US Church</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/pope-leo-replaces-new-yorks-cardinal-dolan-in-shake-up-of-us-church</link><description>Pope Leo replaced Cardinal Timothy Dolan as leader of the Catholic Church in New York, the Vatican announced on Thursday, sidelining a prominent US Church figure in a major shake-up of the country’s Catholic leadership.
Leo, the first US pope, appointed a relatively unknown cleric from Illin</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 15:15:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt to take nationwide campaigns to ensure broader voters’ participation in polls: Info Secy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-to-take-nationwide-campaigns-to-ensure-broader-voters-participation-in-polls-info-secy</link><description>Information and Broadcasting Secretary Mahbuba Farzana on Thursday said the government will implement extensive nationwide public awareness campaigns to ensure broad-based participation of voters in the 13th national elections and referendum.
As part of this initiative, she directed the authoritie</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 15:30:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>14pc growth of remittance inflow till Dec 17</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/14pc-growth-of-remittance-inflow-till-dec-17</link><description>Inflow of remittances witnessed a year-on-year growth of 14 percent reaching US$2007 million in the seventh days of December, according to the latest data of Bangladesh Bank (BB) issued.
Last year, during the same period, the country’s remittance inflow was $1,760 million.
During the July t</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 15:45:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Students march to Indian Assistant High Commission Office in Khulna</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/students-march-to-indian-assistant-high-commission-office-in-khulna</link><description>Students held a long march towards the office of the Indian Assistant High Commissioner in Khulna on Wednesday afternoon.
The march began around 3:30 pm from Royal Mor and moved along Shamsur Rahman Road carrying banners, festoons and chanting slogans.
The joint force of police, RAB, and army per</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 16:00:59 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>