<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 14:22:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>At crowded Ukrainian cemetery, mourners yearn for war to end</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/at-crowded-ukrainian-cemetery-mourners-yearn-for-war-to-end</link><description>After losing her son to Russia's war in Ukraine, Olya Kachmaryk hopes a new US-backed peace plan can finally end the fighting - even if it could mean giving up land he fought for as a soldier.
"The more they (the Russians) come this way, the more they'll want," said Kachmaryk, 50, visiting his gra</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 11:11:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hong Kong tower fire toll rises to 128, 200 remain missing</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/hong-kong-tower-fire-toll-rises-to-128-200-remain-missing</link><description>The death toll from Hong Kong's worst fire in nearly 80 years has risen to 128 and about 200 people remain missing from the high-rise residential complex that was engulfed by the blaze, the city's security chief said on Friday.
The fire in the Wang Fuk Court development, with eight 32-storey tower</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 11:39:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mortar shell found in agricultural land in Lalmonirhat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/mortar-shell-found-in-agricultural-land-in-lalmonirhat</link><description>A mortar shell was discovered in an agricultural field in Hati Bandha Upazila, Lalmonirhat, on Friday morning.
Workers uncovered the object while excavating soil in the middle of Goddimari Adarsha village in Goddimari Union.
Local resident Md. Abul Hossain (63) was leveling his farmland using an</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 11:54:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Outrage in Sylhet after date palm trees cut down at Shahjalal's shrine</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/outrage-in-sylhet-after-date-palm-trees-cut-down-at-shahjalals-shrine</link><description>An outrage has triggered among devotees after several old date palm trees inside the premises of Hazrat Shahjalal’s (RA) shrine in Sylhet were cut down.
These trees, planted nearly 50 years ago, were an integral part of the shrine’s heritage.
The trees were felled between Monday and W</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 12:09:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nafeez Sarafat, 3 others sued for embezzling over Tk 161 billion</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ex-padma-bank-chairman-nafeez-sarafat-3-others-sued-for-embezzling-over-tk-16136-billion</link><description>The Criminal Investigation Department (CID) has filed a money laundering case against former Padma Bank chairman Chowdhury Nafeez Sarafat and three others for allegedly misappropriating Tk 161.3686 billion.
The case was filed with Gulshan Police Station on November 27 following an investigation by</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 12:24:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Protesters block Dhaka’s Shahbagh to demand Barishal-Bhola Bridge</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/protesters-block-dhakas-shahbagh-to-demand-barishal-bhola-bridge</link><description>Dhaka residents hailing from the Bhola District have blocked the capital’s Shahbagh intersection to demand the construction of a bridge linking Barishal and Bhola.
They took up positions at the intersection around 3:45pm on Friday, bringing traffic to a standstill, according to Shahbagh Poli</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 12:39:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>24 Bangladeshis imprisoned in UAE to be released soon: Asif Nazrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/24-bangladeshis-imprisoned-in-uae-to-be-released-soon-asif-nazrul</link><description>Expatriates' Welfare &amp; Overseas Employment Adviser Dr Asif Nazrul on Friday said the remaining 24 Bangladeshi nationals, who were imprisoned at various times for participating in the July uprising in the United Arab Emirates (UAE), will be released soon.
“Alhamdulillah. Our efforts under the</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 12:25:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India’s economy surges ahead of full US tariff hit</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/indias-economy-surges-ahead-of-full-us-tariff-hit</link><description>India’s economic growth accelerated to 8.2 percent year-on-year in the July-September period, boosted by strong consumer spending and a front-loading of production ahead of local festivals and punitive US tariffs.
Economists polled by Reuters had forecast a 7.3 percent expansion for the quar</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 12:40:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DU VC meets IDDEF President in city</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/du-vc-meets-iddef-president-in-city</link><description>Dhaka University (DU) Vice-Chancellor (VC) Professor Niaz Ahmed Khan has held a meeting with Mehmet Turan, president of Turkey-based non-profit Islamic organisation IDDEF.
IDDEF stands for ‘Insana Deger Veren Dernekler Federasyonu’ or ‘The Federation of Associations That Value Hu</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 12:55:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sonali Life wins South Asian Business Excellence Award for the fifth time</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/sonali-life-wins-south-asian-business-excellence-award-for-the-fifth-time</link><description>Sonali Life Insurance Company Limited has won the prestigious South Asian Business Excellence Award for the fifth consecutive year.
The award ceremony was held on 27 November in Colombo, Sri Lanka, where the company received recognition in four categories.
Sonali Life’s business partners&amp;md</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 13:10:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Zelensky's 'man for all seasons' ensnared in corruption probe</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/zelenskys-man-for-all-seasons-ensnared-in-corruption-probe</link><description>Ask Ukrainians who the country's most powerful figure is after the president and many will say Andriy Yermak, his chief of staff and a key negotiator during four years of war when Western financial and military aid has kept Kyiv in the fight.
Yermak, a friend of President Volodymyr Zelensky and hi</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 13:25:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘July Mancha’ disrupts Baul protest at Shahbagh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/july-mancha-disrupts-baul-protest-at-shahbagh</link><description>A protest demanding justice for attacks on Baul singers and the release of detained artiste Abul Sarkar had been disrupted in Shahbagh after a confrontation with a group identifying themselves as members of “July Mancha”.
The scuffle broke out around 5pm on Friday outside the Shahbagh</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 13:40:52 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>