<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 04:52:46 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Micro and macroeconomic sustainability</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/micro-and-macroeconomic-sustainability</link><description>The outcome of the February 12 general election, according to the British-American Ratings agency Fitch Ratings, has assuaged to a large degree the growing political and policy uncertainties during the last leg of the interim government. A turnaround in the political arena marked by the Bangladesh</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 18:14:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mansur makes unceremonious exit as govt appoints new governor</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/mansur-makes-unceremonious-exit-as-govt-appoints-new-governor</link><description>In an abrupt shakeup in the central bank's top echelon, the new government Wednesday appointed accountant-businessman Md. Mostaqur Rahman as new governor of the Bangladesh Bank (BB).



Dr Ahsan H. Mansur made an unceremonious exit as the government terminated his job contract as governor, amid</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 18:29:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Magnitude 5.1 earthquake in Myanmar shakes Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/magnitude-51-earthquake-in-myanmar-shakes-bangladesh</link><description>A magnitude 5.1 earthquake in Myanmar have shaken Dhaka and several other parts of Bangladesh.
The tremor struck at 10:51pm on Wednesday, according to the Bangladesh Meteorological Department’s earthquake monitoring centre.
Assistant Meteorologist Farzana Sultana said the epicentre was in M</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 18:44:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>14-year-old schoolgirl hacked to death outside home in Rayerbazar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/14-year-old-schoolgirl-hacked-to-death-outside-home-in-rayerbazar</link><description>A 14-year-old schoolgirl has been hacked to death in Dhaka’s Rayerbazar.
The attack took place outside her home around 9pm on Wednesday.
Her relatives took her to Dhaka Medical College Hospital (DMCH) around 10:15pm, where doctors declared her dead.
The victim Shahriar Sharmin Binti was th</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 19:45:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CDBL to apply for custodian licence to strengthen MF oversight</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/cdbl-to-apply-for-custodian-licence-to-strengthen-mf-oversight</link><description>The Central Depository Bangladesh Ltd. (CDBL) is set to take on the role of custodian of mutual funds (MFs) in a move aimed at expanding its portfolio and playing a supportive role in the MF industry.
The company, which has so far provided only depository services, will apply for the licence requi</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 01:53:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Auditor Shiraz Khan Basak under fresh probe over ACME IPO irregularities</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/auditor-shiraz-khan-basak-under-fresh-probe-over-acme-ipo-irregularities</link><description>The stock market watchdog has launched an inquiry into the auditing firm, Shiraz Khan Basak &amp; Co., to determine its culpability following the detection of grave irregularities in the pre-IPO financial statements of ACME Pesticides, which were audited by the firm.
A primary investigation conducted</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 02:08:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mansur tells press before leaving office amid commotion outside</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/mansur-tells-press-before-leaving-office-amid-commotion-outside</link><description>Bangladesh Bank passed a tumultuous day Wednesday amid protests and unusual exit of the central bank's top brass that badly impacted regular operations of the banking regulator.
Amid the standoff, press conference by the governor and demonstrations by officers on allegations and counter-allegation</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 02:23:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US tariff issue still evolving: Minister</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/us-tariff-issue-still-evolving-minister</link><description>The issues of reciprocal tariffs imposed by the United States and the related trade agreement are still evolving, Commerce Minister Khandaker Abdul Muktadir has said, noting that the government will review them further before making any decision.
He made the remarks on Wednesday in the context of</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 02:38:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Farmer card to deliver directly agriculture inputs, modernisation machinery, cash incentives</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/farmer-card-to-deliver-directly-agriculture-inputs-modernisation-machinery-cash-incentives</link><description>Building an authentic database as a direct digital communication backbone gets underway as the government prepares to launch the pledged Smart Farmer Card to deliver multiple agriculture-boosting incentives.
Officials say ensuring transparency and identifying genuine beneficiaries will be the key</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 02:53:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Polls spending lifts Jan VAT take</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/polls-spending-lifts-jan-vat-take</link><description>A surge in election-related spending in recent months appears to have provided a short-term boost to value-added tax (VAT) collection, with January 2026 revenue standing Tk 30 billion above the July-December monthly average.
Provisional data suggest campaign-driven economic activity injected liqui</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 03:23:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New FSRU nearby to feed growing fuel demand</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/new-fsru-nearby-to-feed-growing-fuel-demand</link><description>A new floating storage and re-gasification unit (FSRU) with a capacity to re-gasify around 600 million cubic feet per day (mmcfd) of liquefied gas is planned to feed economy's growing fuel demand.
Officials say foreign firms are queuing up to build the floating LNG-conversion plant at Kutubjom of</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 03:38:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hidden bad loans, policy disconnect put banking stability at risk: Experts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/hidden-bad-loans-policy-disconnect-put-banking-stability-at-risk-experts</link><description>Experts at a workshop on the monetary policy statement warned that deep-rooted governance failures, a surge in non-performing loans (NPLs) and weak policy coordination have emerged as major threats to stability of Bangladesh's banking sector.
They revealed that the actual NPL ratio has climbed to</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 03:53:53 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>