<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 12:42:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>CA asks for probe into Mirpur fire incident</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ca-asks-for-probe-into-mirpur-fire-incident</link><description>Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus has instructed the authorities concerned to investigate the devastating fire in a garment factory and chemical warehouse at Shialbari in the city's Mirpur area, claiming so far 16 lives and injuring several others.
"The chief adviser has been informed about t</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 09:17:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Anthrax outbreak: BAU launches field operation in affected areas</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/anthrax-outbreak-bau-launches-field-operation-in-affected-areas</link><description>A research team from Bangladesh Agricultural University (BAU) has recently initiated a field operation in several anthrax-affected regions of Sundarganj upazila in Gaibandha to trace the source and pattern of infection among livestock.
 
Led by Professor Dr. Md. Shahiduzzaman of the Departme</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 09:32:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Disruption in democracy could bring a ‘dark horse’: Warns Rizvi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/disruption-in-democracy-could-bring-a-dark-horse-warns-rizvi</link><description>BNP Senior Joint Secretary General Ruhul Kabir Rizvi on Wednesday warned that any disruption in the democratic process could lead to the ‘entry of a dark horse’, creating more uncertainty in the country’s political situation.
Talking to reporters at the party’s Nayapaltan c</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 09:47:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CUCUS polls: Voters still in line past 4pm</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cucsu-polls-voters-line-up-to-cast-ballots-even-after-4pm</link><description>Though it is past time for polling centres to close in the Chittagong University Central Students’ Union election, officials are still allowing those in line to cast their ballots.
Agency correspondent Masum Kamal said that students are still voting at 18 halls in five university buildings a</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 10:02:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Details of helicopter shootings ‘presented in court’, Chief Prosecutor says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/details-of-helicopter-shootings-presented-in-court-chief-prosecutor-says</link><description>International Crimes Tribunal Chief Prosecutor Tajul Islam says he has presented detailed information about shootings from helicopters during last year’s protests in July and August.
He spoke to the media on Wednesday after concluding his arguments before the International Crimes Tribunal-1</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 10:32:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hajj pilgrimage registration deadline extended to Thursday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hajj-pilgrimage-registration-deadline-extended-to-thursday</link><description>The registration deadline for Hajj pilgrimages has been extended to Thursday.
On Wednesday, a letter on the matter was issued from the Hajj-3 branch of the Ministry of Religious Affairs.
It says that for all concerned, including those wishing to perform Hajj in 2026, Hajj agencies, banks involved</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 11:02:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>In the ashes of Mirpur fire, two fingers lead to the discovery of Sarwar’s body</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/in-the-ashes-of-mirpur-fire-two-fingers-lead-to-the-discovery-of-sarwars-body</link><description>Since Tuesday, Amanullah has been searching the burnt building in Mirpur’s Rupnagar holding a photo of his friend Sarwar in his hand.
Sarwar worked as a helper in the garment factory housed in the building that caught fire.
On Wednesday, Amanullah said Sarwar’s body had been found at</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 11:17:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chinese autonomous driving firm WeRide taps banks for Hong Kong listing, sources say</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/global/chinese-autonomous-driving-firm-weride-taps-banks-for-hong-kong-listing-sources-say</link><description>Chinese autonomous driving firm WeRide (WRD.O) has hired Morgan Stanley (MS.N), opens new tab and China International Capital Corp (CICC) (601995.SS) to work on a dual primary listing in Hong Kong, three sources with knowledge of the matter said.
The Guangzhou-based company, which listed on Nasdaq</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 11:32:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Norway proposes widening EV tax to include mass-market Tesla models</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/norway-proposes-widening-ev-tax-to-include-mass-market-tesla-models</link><description>Norway plans to eliminate its main subsidy for electric vehicles over the next two years, the government said on Wednesday, adding thousands of dollars to the cost of new cars like Tesla's (TSLA.O) Model Y, the country's top-selling automobile.
Fully electric vehicles accounted for a record 98.3 p</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 11:47:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>'Tin Goyenda' creator Rakib Hasan is no more</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/tin-goyenda-creator-rakib-hasan-is-no-more</link><description>Rakib Hasan, creator of the teen detective series ‘Tin Goyenda’, has passed away at the age of 75.
He breathed his last on Wednesday afternoon while undergoing dialysis at Gonoshasthaya Nagar Hospital in Dhanmondi.
Masuma Maimur, adviser of Sheba Prokashoni and wife of Kazi Maymur Hos</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 12:02:08 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>