<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 03:30:04 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Turkish Deputy Minister conveys Erdogan's invitation to CA to visit Turkiye</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/turkish-deputy-minister-conveys-erdogans-invitation-to-ca-to-visit-turkiye</link><description>Turkish Deputy Minister for Foreign Affairs Ambassador Berris Ekinci on Tuesday conveyed the greetings and best wishes of President Recep Tayyip Erdogan and his invitation to Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus to visit Turkiye at a mutually convenient time.
The deputy minister conveyed the mes</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 17:17:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh elected president of UNESCO General Conference</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-elected-president-of-unesco-general-conference</link><description>Bangladesh has been elected President of the 43rd General Conference of the United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization (UNESCO), marking a historic milestone in the country’s 53-year membership with the organisation.
During the vote held today at the 222nd Session of th</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 17:43:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gold becomes costlier again, up by Tk 1,469 per bhori</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/gold-becomes-costlier-again-up-by-tk-1469-per-bhori</link><description>The price of gold has increased again by Tk 1,469 per bhori (11.664 grams), just a day after crossing the Tk 200,000 mark.
According to a statement issued by the Bangladesh Jewellers’ Association (BAJUS) on Tuesday night, the new rates will be effective from Wednesday morning.
As per the re</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 17:58:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCP preparing for February election: Sarjis</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ncp-preparing-for-february-election-sarjis</link><description>Chief Organiser (North) of the National Citizen Party (NCP), Sarjis Alam, has said that the party is actively preparing for the upcoming national elections scheduled for February.“We are visiting every district with the goal of completing our district, police station, and ward-level committee</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 18:13:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Economic pickup to spur GDP growth to 4.8pc this FY, yet higher next</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/economic-pickup-to-spur-gdp-growth-to-48pc-this-fy-yet-higher-next</link><description>Economic pickup is to spur Bangladesh's GDP growth to 4.8 per cent this fiscal year and to an impressive 6.3 per cent next, the World Bank says, also dispelling fears of export loss following the country's LDC graduation.



In its Bangladesh Development Update, published Tuesday in Dhaka, the</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 18:28:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump says he is optimistic about a Gaza deal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-says-he-is-optimistic-about-a-gaza-deal</link><description>Two years after the Gaza conflict erupted, President Donald Trump on Tuesday pledged US support for Gaza security guarantees and said he believes a deal is close to being completed for the remaining hostages.
Talking to reporters in the Oval Office, Trump said, "I think there's a possibility that</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 19:13:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Touhid urges Saudi businesses to invest in ports, power, energy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/touhid-urges-saudi-businesses-to-invest-in-ports-power-energy</link><description>Foreign Advisor Md Touhid Hossain has urged Saudi businesses to pour money in Bangladesh’s port, power and energy sectors.
He made the call on Tuesday night at the launch of the Saudi Arabia–Bangladesh Chamber of Commerce and Industry (SABCCI) in Dhaka, where a 20-member Saudi delegati</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 19:28:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ctg port handles record container volume</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ctg-port-handles-record-container-volume</link><description>Chattogram port, the country's principal seaport, has broken a 48-year record by handling the highest number of containers in the 2024-25 fiscal year (FY), according to port officials.
They attributed the achievement to the expansion of jetty and yard facilities, which improved container, cargo, a</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 01:43:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Finance adviser sceptical of WB's poverty assessment</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/finance-adviser-sceptical-of-wbs-poverty-assessment</link><description>Finance Adviser Dr Salehuddin Ahmed raised questions about reliability of the procedure of measuring poverty by the World Bank, just as the global lender presented Bangladesh situation.
"I know how they measure poverty. There are base…there are clientele (to give interview)," he told newsme</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 02:13:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Regional integration in South Asia would be ‘a win-win for all’: Dr Ishrat Hussain</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/regional-integration-in-south-asia-would-be-a-win-win-for-all-dr-ishrat-hussain</link><description>Regional integration in South Asia is not only achievable but would bring mutual benefits to all participating nations, said Dr Ishrat Hussain, economist and former Governor of the State Bank of Pakistan.
He made the remarks while addressing an event titled “Turbo Charging South Asian Capita</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 02:43:20 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>