<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 22:35:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Those responsible for low CPI ranking must be held accountable</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/those-responsible-for-low-cpi-ranking-must-be-held-accountable</link><description>That Bangladesh is world's 13th most corrupt country among the 182 states assessed by the Berlin-based Transparency International (TI) is disgraceful. Only more so because the improved ranking from 2006 to 2017 could not be maintained! The highest ever score for the country was 28 in 2017.  Du</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 18:06:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh-US trade deal: prospects and pitfalls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/bangladesh-us-trade-deal-prospects-and-pitfalls</link><description>The signing of a trade deal with the United States at the fag-end of the interim government's tenure has understandably raised many eyebrows, particularly because of its non-disclosure clauses. The limited information released so far suggests a mixed picture-one that promises new opportunities but</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 18:21:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP candidate Md Shariful Alam wins Kishoreganj-6 by huge margin</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bnp-candidate-md-shariful-alam-wins-kishoreganj-6-by-huge-margin</link><description>BNP candidate Md Shariful Alam won by a massive margin after securing 185,813 votes in all 142 polling centres In Kishoreganj-6 (Bhairab-Kuliarchar) constituency, according to unofficial results. 
His nearest rival, 11-party alliance candidate Maulana Ataullah Amin contesting with the ‘</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 18:36:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat’s Golam Parwar defeated in Khulna-5</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jamaats-golam-parwar-defeated-in-khulna-5</link><description>Khulna-5 constituency saw a closely contested race as Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami Secretary General Mia Golam Parwar was defeated in the parliamentary election.
Golam Parwar, who contested with the party’s electoral symbol 'Dandipalla' (scales), secured 144,956 votes.
The seat was won by BNP</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 18:51:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Lutfozzaman Babar wins Netrokona-4 seat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/lutfozzaman-babar-wins-netrokona-4-seat</link><description>BNP-nominated candidate and former state minister for home affairs Lutfozzaman Babar has been unofficially elected from the Netrokona-4 constituency.
He secured 160,801 votes with the sheaf of paddy symbol, defeating his nearest rival, Jamaat-e-Islami candidate Md Al Helal, by a margin of 120,961</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 19:06:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat Ameer Shafiqur Rahman wins Dhaka-15 seat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jamaat-ameer-shafiqur-rahman-wins-dhaka-15-seat</link><description>Jamaat-e-Islami Ameer Dr Shafiqur Rahman has been unofficially declared elected from the Dhaka-15 constituency in the 13th Jatiya Sangsad election.
According to the unofficial results, Dr Shafiqur secured 82,645 votes in the constituency, which has a total of 127 polling centres.
His nearest riva</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 20:01:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rumeen Farhana wins by 37,568 votes in Brahmanbaria-2</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rumeen-farhana-wins-by-37568-votes-in-brahmanbaria-2</link><description>Independent candidate Rumeen Farhana, contesting with the “duck” symbol, has been unofficially declared elected from the Brahmanbaria-2 constituency, defeating her nearest rival by a margin of 37,568 votes.
According to the results from 151 polling centres, Rumeen secured 117,495 votes</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 20:16:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat wins all four seats in Nilphamari</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jamaat-wins-all-four-seats-in-nilphamari</link><description>Candidates of Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami have secured victory in all four parliamentary constituencies in Nilphamari in the 13th national election.
The results were announced on Thursday night after vote counting by District Returning Officer and Deputy Commissioner Mohammad Nayiruzzaman.
In Nilp</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 20:49:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP wins all five parliamentary seats in Sunamganj</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bnp-wins-all-five-parliamentary-seats-in-sunamganj</link><description>BNP candidates secured victory in all five parliamentary constituencies in Sunamganj district in the 13th national election.
In Sunamganj-1 (Tahirpur, Jamalganj, Dharmapasha and Madhyanagar), BNP candidate Kamruzzaman Kamrul won the seat with 161,774 votes, contesting with the party’s electo</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 21:04:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat wins all four seats in Satkhira</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jamaat-wins-all-four-seats-in-satkhira</link><description>Candidates of Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami have won all four parliamentary seats in Satkhira district, according to unofficial results announced after vote counting.
In Satkhira-1 (Tala-Kalaroa), Jamaat candidate Izzat Ullah, contesting with the party’s scale symbol, received 220,330 votes fro</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 21:19:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP wins all five seats in Narsingdi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bnp-wins-all-five-seats-in-narsingdi</link><description>BNP candidates have secured victory in all five parliamentary constituencies of Narsingdi, according to unofficial results announced by the respective returning officers.
In Narsingdi-1 (Sadar), BNP Joint Secretary General Khairul Kabir Khokon, contesting with the party’s electoral symbol &amp;l</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 22:05:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sarjis Alam loses Panchagarh-1 battle</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/sarjis-alam-loses-panchagarh-1-battle</link><description>NCP Chief Organiser (Northern Region) Sarjis Alam was defeated in Panchagarh-1 as the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) won both parliamentary seats in Panchagarh district, according to unofficial results announced on early Friday.
Kazi Md Sayemuzzaman, Returning Officer and Deputy Commissioner o</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 22:20:14 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>