<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 14:50:54 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Fakhrul stresses unity for nation building</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/mirza-fakhrul-calls-for-unity-transparency-and-accountability-to-build-a-successful-bangladesh</link><description>Local Government, Rural Development and Co‑operatives Minister Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir has emphasised the need for collective efforts by individuals, society and the state to build a successful nation.
Speaking at a views‑exchange meeting at the Secretariat on Thursday, Fakhrul said: “Fo</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 13:29:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump to make new economic pitch in Georgia as prices stay high</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-to-make-new-economic-pitch-in-georgia-as-prices-stay-high</link><description>President Donald Trump will give the latest in a series of economic speeches in Georgia on Thursday as he seeks to persuade voters he and fellow Republicans have a plan to lower prices ahead of November’s midterm congressional elections.
Trump won re-election in 2024 in large part because of</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 13:44:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New govt to take steps to defer LDC graduation, says Commerce Minister Muktadir</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/new-govt-to-take-steps-to-defer-ldc-graduation-says-commerce-minister-muktadir</link><description>The new government will take initiatives to defer Bangladesh's graduation from the Least Developed Country (LDC) status, says Commerce, Industries, Textiles and Jute Minister Khandaker Abdul Muktadir.
Speaking to journalists at the secretariat on Wednesday, he said the government had already start</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 12:29:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shayrul Kabir Khan joins Dainik Shomoyer Alo as advisory editor</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bnp-media-cell-member-shayrul-kabir-khan-joins-dainik-shomoyer-alo-as-advisory-editor</link><description>BNP media cell member Shayrul Kabir Khan has joined the daily Shomoyer Alo as advisory editor.
He formally took up the role at the newspaper’s office in Bangla Motor on Thursday afternoon, where acting editor Shahnewaz Karim and other staff members welcomed him with flowers.
Earlier in the</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 12:44:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Property dispute among sons delays father’s funeral for 30 hours in Kurigram</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/property-dispute-among-sons-delays-fathers-funeral-for-30-hours-in-kurigram</link><description>A family feud over property inheritance has delayed a father’s funeral for nearly 30 hours in Kurigram's Nageshwari Upazila.
The funeral was later held following a written agreement mediated by village elders.
According to local residents, 75-year-old Azizar Rahman passed away due to old ag</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 12:59:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>'Curriculum review, technical modernisation among three education priorities'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/curriculum-review-technical-modernisation-among-three-education-priorities</link><description>Education Minister ANM Ehsanul Hoque Milon has announced three immediate priorities for the sector: creating conditions to bring students back to classrooms, reviewing the national curriculum and modernising technical education.
He revealed the plans while speaking to reporters at the Secretariat</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 13:14:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>British PM eyes next chapter in Dhaka-London partnership</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/british-pm-eyes-next-chapter-in-dhaka-london-partnership</link><description>British Prime Minister Keir Starmer has said he looks forward to working closely with Bangladesh Prime Minister Tarique Rahman to strengthen their partnership and advance shared priorities.
“I look forward to this next chapter in the partnership between our two countries,” he said in a</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 13:29:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Abul Kasem Khan appointed BUILD chairperson</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/abul-kasem-khan-appointed-build-chairperson</link><description>Abul Kasem Khan, Vice Chairman of AK Khan and Company Ltd, has been appointed the chairperson of Business Initiative Leading Development (BUILD) for the 2026-27 tenure.
Mr Khan, a member of the BUILD Trustee Board since 2020, assumed this leadership responsibility following a formal resolution by</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 13:44:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cultural Ministry takes elaborate programs on Shahid dibash</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cultural-ministry-takes-elaborate-programs-on-shahid-dibash</link><description>Cultural Affairs Ministry has taken elaborate programmes marking the Shahid Dibash and International Mother Language Day.
On the day the national flag will remain half mast at all government, semi-government, autonomous and private buildings and educational institutes on February 21.
Bangladesh T</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 13:59:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pakistan, US sign pact to redevelop New York's Roosevelt Hotel</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/pakistan-us-sign-pact-to-redevelop-new-yorks-roosevelt-hotel</link><description>Pakistan has signed an agreement with the United States to jointly redevelop New York's Roosevelt Hotel, according to four official documents reviewed by Reuters and two sources, in a deal between the two governments that will allow Islamabad to unlock the value of one its most prized overseas inve</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 14:14:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two killed, 10 injured in Madaripur road accident</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/two-killed-10-injured-in-madaripur-road-accident</link><description>Two people were killed and 10 others injured in a road accident in Melkai area of Dasar upazila in Madaripur district on Thursday afternoon.
According to eyewitnesses and police, a passenger bus of Imran Paribahan, traveling from Dhaka to Barishal, collided head-on with a BRTC bus coming from the</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 14:29:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Health Minister for on-site monitoring to ensure quality healthcare services</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/health-minister-for-on-site-monitoring-to-ensure-quality-healthcare-services</link><description>Health and Family Welfare Minister Sardar Md Sakhawat Hossain today (Thursday) announced that the government will conduct on-site monitoring at hospitals to ensure that doctors are providing proper and timely services to patients.
He made the announcement while speaking as the chief guest at an or</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 14:44:46 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>