<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 04:26:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Mono rail, LRT not studied under four major plans</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/mono-rail-lrt-not-studied-under-four-major-plans</link><description>Although at least four major transport plans were taken for the capital city since 1990s, the scope of launching mono rail or light rapid transit (LRT) as a mode of mass transit system was never studied.
Officials and experts termed lack of right focus on local-level passenger demands as well as d</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 02:15:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>RUET's int'l conf'ce on ECTE ends today</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/others/ruets-intl-confce-on-ecte-ends-today</link><description>RAJSHAHI, Jan 29: The closing ceremony of the 5th International Conference on Electrical, Computer and Telecommunication Engineering (ICECTE 2026) will be organised at Rajshahi University of Engineering and Technology (RUET) today (Saturday) after it started on Thursday. The Faculty of Electrical a</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 02:30:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh to seek 12-year trade grace for post-graduation era</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh-to-seek-12-year-trade-grace-for-post-graduation-era</link><description>Bangladesh is set to seek a binding 12-year transition period to safeguard its export-oriented economy from post-LDC-graduation trade challenges in a high-stakes strategy to be placed at the upcoming WTO ministerial meet.
Officials say the government has finalized a comprehensive Position Paper fo</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 02:45:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Foreign aid pipeline shrinks 3.99pc in FY 2024-25</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/foreign-aid-pipeline-shrinks-399pc-in-fy-2024-25</link><description>The pipeline of foreign aid - funds available for disbursement - narrowed to $42.09 billion in FY25, marking a 3.99-percent fall from the previous fiscal year to hit the lowest level since FY18, according to the latest Economic Relations Division (ERD) report.
Although donors disbursed $933 millio</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 01:54:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Catherine O'Hara, star of 'Schitt's Creek' and 'Home Alone,' dead at 71</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/media/catherine-ohara-star-of-schitts-creek-and-home-alone-dead-at-71</link><description>Catherine O'Hara, the Emmy-winning actor who brought the eccentric Moira Rose of "Schitt's Creek" to global acclaim, has died at 71, said a representative from the office of her manager Marc Gurvitz.
Among other roles, O'Hara also portrayed Kate McCallister, the mother of Macaulay Culkin's charact</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 02:09:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Millers urge expansion of EDF, interest cut to sustain primary textile exports</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/millers-urge-expansion-of-edf-interest-cut-to-sustain-primary-textile-exports</link><description>Primary textile-industry owners have urged Bangladesh Bank to increase the Export Development Fund (EDF) limit and cut its interest rate to help protect the export competitiveness of the country's primary textile sector, which is facing mounting financial and cost pressures.
The Bangladesh Textile</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 02:24:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Aromatic rice, non-packaged edible oil prices up</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/aromatic-rice-non-packaged-edible-oil-prices-up</link><description>Suppliers have raised the prices of aromatic rice and non-packaged edible oils ahead of Shab-e-Barat and the upcoming Ramadan.
The maximum retail price of packaged aromatic rice (Kalijeera, Chinigura) has gone up to Tk 175 per kg from Tk 155-160 a week ago.
Juel Rana, a grocer at West Dhanmondi i</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 02:39:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CPA takes tough stance on strike of port workers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/cpa-takes-tough-stance-on-strike-of-port-workers</link><description>CHATTOGRAM: The Chittagong Port Authority (CPA) has taken a tough stance on creation of any chaos over the court verdict regarding the New Mooring Container Terminal (NCT) of Chittagong port.
The CPA issued a circular signed by Omar Faruk, Director (Administration), to this effect. The circular wa</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 02:54:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Venezuela announces amnesty bill that could lead to mass release of political prisoners</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/venezuela-announces-amnesty-bill-that-could-lead-to-mass-release-of-political-prisoners</link><description>Venezuela’s acting President Delcy Rodríguez on Friday announced an amnesty bill that could lead to the release of hundreds of prisoners, including opposition leaders, journalists and human rights activists detained for political reasons.
The measure had long been sought by the United</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 03:09:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India’s EU trade deal poses threat to Bangladesh’s garment dominance</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/indias-eu-trade-deal-poses-threat-to-bangladeshs-garment-dominance</link><description>India’s newly announced free-trade agreement with the European Union (EU) could pose a serious challenge to Bangladesh’s dominance in the European garment market, according to a report by Zee News.
The deal, aimed in part at offsetting pressure from higher US tariffs, will give Indian</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 03:24:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>More than 200 killed in Congo mine collapse</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/more-than-200-killed-in-congo-mine-collapse</link><description>More than 200 people were killed this week in a collapse at the Rubaya coltan mine in eastern Democratic Republic of Congo, Lumumba Kambere Muyisa, spokesperson for the rebel-appointed governor of the province where the mine is located, told Reuters on Friday.
Rubaya produces around 15 per cent of</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 03:39:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Thousands demonstrate in Minnesota and across US to protest ICE</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/thousands-demonstrate-in-minnesota-and-across-us-to-protest-ice</link><description>Thousands of protesters took to the streets in Minneapolis and students across the United States staged walkouts on Friday to demand the withdrawal of federal immigration agents from Minnesota following the fatal shootings of two US citizens.
Students and teachers abandoned classes from California</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 03:54:18 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>