<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 13:34:38 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Protest over Hadi’s death blocks Dhaka-Barishal highway</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/protest-over-hadis-death-blocks-dhaka-barishal-highway</link><description>Students and general people blocked Dhaka-Barishal highway for several hours demanding arrest of killers of Inquilab Moncho spokesman Osman Hadi on Friday afternoon.
The disruption caused immense suffering of commuters and transport workers. 
The protesters gathered at Nathullabad Bus Termin</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 12:00:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Don’t fall into trap of instigation’: Inqilab Moncho</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/inqilab-moncho-urges-all-not-to-fall-into-trap-of-instigation</link><description>The Inqilab Moncho has urged everyone “not to fall into the trap of instigation” following the death of the platform’s convener Sharif Osman Bin Hadi.
The platform, inspired by the July Movement, demanded justice, saying it would announce a stringent programme regarding the deman</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 10:30:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bank of Japan raises rates to 30-year high, signals more hikes</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/global/bank-of-japan-raises-rates-to-30-year-high-signals-more-hikes</link><description>The Bank of Japan raised interest rates on Friday to levels unseen in 30 years, taking another landmark step in ending decades of huge monetary support and near-zero borrowing costs.
The central bank also signalled its readiness to continue raising rates by offering a slightly more upbeat view on</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 10:45:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UK welcomes EU funding agreement for Ukraine</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/uk-welcomes-eu-funding-agreement-for-ukraine</link><description>British finance minister Rachel Reeves on Friday welcomed a decision by European Union leaders to loan 90 billion euros ($105 billion) to Ukraine to fund its defence against Russia.
"I am pleased to see the agreement made today at the European Council to provide vital financial support for Ukraine</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 11:00:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Osman Hadi’s body arrives in Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/osman-hadis-body-arrives-in-dhaka</link><description>An aircraft carrying the body of Inquilab Moncho spokesman Sharim Osman Hadi, who died at a Singapore Hospital on Thursday, landed at Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport in Dhaka on Friday evening.
The Biman Bangladesh Airlines flight BG-585 carrying the body landed at the airport at 5:48 pm on</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 11:15:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ukraine clinches deal to restructure $2.6 billion in 'toxic' GDP warrants</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/ukraine-clinches-deal-to-restructure-26-billion-in-toxic-gdp-warrants</link><description>Ukraine clinched a long-awaited deal to restructure $2.6 billion of growth-linked debt on Thursday, with creditors overwhelmingly accepting a bonds-and-cash swap offer - a key step for the country to emerge from sovereign default.
Kyiv said holders of 99 per cent of the so-called GDP warrants had</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 11:30:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Journalists must be able to carry out their work without fear: MFC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/journalists-must-be-able-to-carry-out-their-work-without-fear-mfc</link><description>The Media Freedom Coalition in Bangladesh on Friday strongly condemned the attacks carried out Thursday night against journalists, editors, and media houses.
“Such acts of violence and intimidation are unacceptable and strike at the heart of press freedom and the public’s right to be i</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 11:45:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jhenaidah AL leaders’ houses torched</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/two-al-leaders-houses-attacked-torched-in-jhenaidah-after-hadis-death</link><description>The residences of two Awami League leaders have been vandalised and torched in Jhenaidah following the death of Inqilab Moncho Convenor Sharif Osman bin Hadi.
The attacks occurred in the early hours of Friday in Jhenaidah town’s Damdo and Hatkhola, according to Bellal Hossain, an additional</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 12:00:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UK imposes sanctions on perpetrators of violence against Syrian civilians</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/uk-imposes-sanctions-on-perpetrators-of-violence-against-syrian-civilians</link><description>Britain imposed sanctions on Friday on individuals and organisations it said were linked to violence perpetrated against civilians in Syria, including some who financially supported former president Bashar al-Assad's government.
While Britain has eased some sanctions on Syria as the country seeks</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 12:15:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chhayanaut protests vandalism, arson through song</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/chhayanaut-protests-vandalism-arson-through-song</link><description>Students and alumni of Bengali cultural organisation Chhayanaut and its educational wing Nalonda have taken to the streets outside its burnt and vandalised premises, protesting the attack on the institution through song.
The gathering came hours after assailants vandalised and set fire to Chhayana</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 12:30:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prothom Alo journalists allege 'premeditated attack' on office</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/prothom-alo-journalists-demand-action-against-perpetrators-of-premeditated-office-attack</link><description>The Bengali daily Prothom Alo has come under an organised attack planned by a vested quarter, the newspaper’s Executive Editor Sajjad Sharif has said.
He made the comment after attending a human chain formed at 4pm on Friday in front of his workplace, which was vandalised, looted and burned</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 12:45:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khaleda now ‘quite stable’: Zahid</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/khaleda-zias-condition-now-quite-stable-says-her-personal-physician</link><description>BNP chief Khaleda Zia’s health condition is now “quite stable” after nearly a month of treatment at Evercare Hospital in Dhaka, according to her personal physician AZM Zahid Hossain.
He shared the update during a media briefing outside the private hospital in Dhaka on Friday afte</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 13:00:54 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>