<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 16:29:17 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>UN chief urges countries to implement weather disaster warning systems</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/un-chief-urges-countries-to-implement-weather-disaster-warning-systems</link><description>UN Secretary-General Antonio Guterres urged countries on Wednesday to implement disaster warning systems to protect people against extreme weather, saying no country was safe from the effects of global warming.
“Every one of the last 10 years has been the hottest in history. Ocean heat is br</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 12:52:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rishad makes giant stride in ICC rankings</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/cricket/rishad-makes-giant-stride-in-icc-rankings</link><description>Bangladeshi leg-spinner Rishad Hossain made a huge leap in the ICC’s weekly rankings for the ODI bowlers following his incredible performance in the ongoing three-match series against West Indies at home. 
Rishad, who took nine wickets so far in the first two matches, including a record</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 13:07:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sylhet college student found dead on railway tracks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/sylhet-college-student-found-dead-on-railway-tracks</link><description>Police on Wednesday recovered the dismembered body of a college student from railway tracks in Sylhet’s South Surma upazila.
The deceased was identified as Motiur Rahman, 21, son of late Kutu Mia from Pani Chora village in Jaintiapur upazila and a second-year honours student at MC College. H</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 13:22:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>HC acquits ex-MP Habib, 43 others in Hasina’s motorcade attack cases</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hc-acquits-ex-mp-habib-43-others-in-hasinas-motorcade-attack-cases</link><description>The High Court (HC) today acquitted all the 44 people, including former BNP lawmaker Habibul Islam Habib, convicted and sentenced to different jail terms in an arms case and a case filed under The Special Powers Act, over the 2002 attack on the motorcade of the then leader of the opposition Sheikh</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 13:52:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>60-hour training needed for driver’s licences: Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-to-mandate-60-hours-of-training-before-issuing-drivers-licences-says-adviser-fouzul</link><description>Bangladesh will soon require at least 60 hours of formal training for anyone seeking a driver’s licence, according to Adviser Muhammad Fouzul Kabir Khan.
On Wednesday, the road transport adviser said the emphasis in the licensing process will shift decisively to training.
“Existing co</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 14:07:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>400th board meeting of Shahjalal Islami Bank held</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/400th-board-meeting-of-shahjalal-islami-bank-held</link><description>The 400th meeting of the Board of Directors of Shahjalal Islami Bank PLC was held on Wednesday at Corporate Head Office of the bank.
According to a press release, the meeting was presided over by the Chairman Mr. A. K. Azad. The 400th meeting of the Board of Directors celebrated with cutting a cak</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 14:22:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prime Bank, Green University sign MoU on industry–academia collaboration</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/prime-bank-green-university-sign-mou-on-industry-academia-collaboration</link><description>Prime Bank PLC, in collaboration with Green University of Bangladesh, organized a seminar titled “Financial Inclusion: Engaging &amp; Inspiring Youth in Banking” under its flagship PrimeAcademia initiative.
The event was graced by Prof. Dr. Mohammad Shorif Uddin, Vice Chancellor of Green U</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 14:37:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IFIC Bank inaugurated ATM Booth at BKMEA premises, Narayanganj</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ific-bank-inaugurated-atm-booth-at-bkmea-premises-narayanganj</link><description>To make financial transactions easier and faster, IFIC Bank has set up an ATM booth at the premises of the Bangladesh Knitwear Manufacturers &amp; Exporters Association (BKMEA) in Chashara, Narayanganj.
The booth was inaugurated in a befitting manner by the Chairman of the bank, Mr. Md. Mehmood Husain</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 14:52:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>SUST students stage sit-in demanding SUCSU election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/sust-students-stage-sit-in-demanding-sucsu-election</link><description>Students of Shahjalal University of Science and Technology (SUST) staged a sit-in on Wednesday afternoon, demanding the immediate announcement of elections for the Shahjalal University Central Students' Union (SUCSU).
A group of students began their demonstration in front of the university’s</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 15:07:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Islami Bank leads day-long events to promote cashless Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/islami-bank-leads-day-long-events-to-promote-cashless-bangladesh</link><description>A day-long colorful roadshow, seminar and stall exhibition were held in Chattogram on Wednesday marking the “Cashless Bangladesh Initiative Expansion Campaign,” organized by Bangladesh Bank in collaboration with Islami Bank Bangladesh PLC.
The roadshow started from the Agrabad intersec</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 15:37:03 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>