<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 05:21:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>SPM project waste causing extensive pollution, damage</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/spm-project-waste-causing-extensive-pollution-damage</link><description>Waste generated by the Single Point Mooring with Double Pipeline (SPM) project located in Moheshkhali upazila of Cox's Bazar is directly flowing into the nearby paddy fields, croplands and fish ponds causing widespread pollution and damage.
Local farmers and fishermen are being seriously affected</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 03:21:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rick Haque Sikder charged with Tk 215m embezzlement</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rick-haque-sikder-charged-with-tk-215m-embezzlement</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) has pressed charges against former National Bank Limited director Rick Haque Sikder and 11 others over embezzlement and laundering of approximately Tk 215 million (21.5 crore) abroad through credit card misuse.
According to the charge sheet approved by the ACC'</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 03:36:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Germany reaffirms strong partnership with BD</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/germany-reaffirms-strong-partnership-with-bd</link><description>Germany continues to be one of Bangladesh's key partners in development cooperation, focusing on climate and energy, good governance, and sustainable economic growth.
Parliamentary State Secretary to the German Federal Ministry for Economic Cooperation and Development (BMZ) and Member of the Germa</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 03:51:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Al Haramain, Mahid Securities lose TREC licences</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/al-haramain-mahid-securities-lose-trec-licences</link><description>The Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) has revoked the Trading Right Entitlement Certificate (TREC) licences of two brokerage firms - Al Haramain Securities and Mahid Securities - due to violations of rules.
The prime bourse on Wednesday announced the regulatory decision on its website. Al Haramain Securi</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 04:06:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UK and Vietnam reach deal on curbing illegal migration</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/uk-and-vietnam-reach-deal-on-curbing-illegal-migration</link><description>Britain said on Wednesday it had agreed to a deal with Vietnam to curb illegal migration in what it described as the strongest Hanoi had ever agreed with another country.
British Prime Minister Keir Starmer, under pressure to reduce the number of undocumented migrants reaching Britain to help arre</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 04:21:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Meta forecasts bigger capital costs in 2026</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/meta-forecasts-bigger-capital-costs-in-2026</link><description>Meta on Wednesday forecast "notably larger" capital expenses next year thanks to investments in artificial intelligence, including aggressively building data centers to power its AI push.
The Facebook and Instagram parent reported third-quarter revenue growth of 26 per cent that beat market estima</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 04:36:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Truck-motorcycle crash in Rajshahi sparks fire, kills one</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/truck-motorcycle-crash-in-rajshahi-sparks-fire-kills-one</link><description>A motorcycle passenger has died after his vehicle crashed into a truck in Rajshahi’s Mohonpur, sparking a fire.
The accident occurred near the Kalitola Flour Mill in Kesharhat Municipality around 5:30 am on Thursday, according to Ataur Rahman, chief of Mohonpur Police Station.
Police say th</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 05:06:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hurricane Melissa kills 25 in Haiti</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/hurricane-melissa-kills-25-in-haiti</link><description>Hurricane Melissa barrelled through the northern Caribbean on Wednesday after thrashing Cuba's second-biggest city, isolating hundreds of rural communities, unleashing devastation in Jamaica and drenching Haiti, where at least 25 were killed.
Melissa struck Jamaica on Tuesday as the strongest-ever</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 05:21:18 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>