<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 10:57:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Europe aims to rely less on US defence after Trump's Greenland push</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe-aims-to-rely-less-on-us-defence-after-trumps-greenland-push</link><description>European Commission President Ursula von der Leyen reflected a feeling of profound change among European leaders at this weekend's Munich Security Conference when she said: "Some lines have been crossed that cannot be uncrossed anymore".
Transatlantic ties have already been strained over the past</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 07:37:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>37 houses ready for incoming ministers: Adviser Adilur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/37-houses-ready-for-incoming-ministers-adviser-adilur</link><description>Thirty-seven houses have been prepared for the ministers, state ministers, and deputy ministers of the incoming government, said Housing and Public Works Adviser Adilur Rahman Khan on Monday.
The adviser said the government has so far readied 37 houses for the incoming cabinet members, reports UNB</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 07:52:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Army chief pays farewell visit to chief adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/army-chief-pays-farewell-visit-to-chief-adviser</link><description>Bangladesh's Chief of Army Staff Gen Waker-Uz-Zaman has paid a farewell visit to Chief Adviser Muhammad Yunus.
The chief adviser has thanked the army chief for the cooperation of the armed forces during the general election.
The courtesy meeting was held at the Chief Adviser’s Office in Tej</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 07:42:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>13th national election was fair and inclusive: TIB</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/13th-national-election-was-fair-and-inclusive-tib</link><description>The 13th National Parliament Election was fair, acceptable and inclusive, said Dr Iftekharuzzaman, Executive Director of Transparency International Bangladesh (TIB).
Dr Iftekharuzzaman made the remarks at a press conference held at 11:00 am on Monday (February 16) at the Midas Center in Dhanmondi</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 07:57:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCP to sign July Charter, delegation going to Jamuna this evening</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ncp-to-sign-july-charter-delegation-going-to-jamuna-on-monday-evening</link><description>The National Citizen Party (NCP) is signing the July National Charter, with a party delegation headed to the State Guest House Jamuna, the official residence of the chief adviser, on Monday evening.
The NCP made the announcement in a media statement on Monday afternoon.
The message said a delegat</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 08:12:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Woman burnt in Natore acid attack</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/woman-burnt-in-natore-acid-attack</link><description>A 65-year-old woman suffered burn injuries in an acid attack by some miscreants in Gurudaspur upazila of Natore district on Sunday.
The victim was identified as Halima Begum, mother of union parishad member Chameli Begum.
The victim’s family said Nazul, a listed criminal of Nazirpur village</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 08:27:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Israel eases land purchase rules for settlers in West Bank</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/israel-eases-land-purchase-rules-for-settlers-in-west-bank</link><description>Israel's cabinet on Sunday approved further measures to tighten Israel's control over the occupied West Bank and make it easier for settlers to buy land, a move Palestinians called a "de-facto annexation".
The West Bank is among the territories that Palestinians seek for a future independent state</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 08:42:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nepal’s FM Sharma to join oath-taking ceremony</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nepals-fm-sharma-to-join-oath-taking-ceremony</link><description>Nepal's Minister for Foreign Affairs Bala Nanda Sharma is scheduled to arrive in Dhaka on Monday night to attend the oath-taking ceremony of the newly elected government of Bangladesh.
The minister will arrive at Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport by a flight of Biman Bangladesh Airlines from</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 08:57:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ASI dies in Thakurgaon while attempting to arrest suspect</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/asi-dies-in-thakurgaon-while-attempting-to-arrest-suspect</link><description>An assistant sub-inspector (ASI) of police has died after suffering a heart attack while attempting to arrest a suspect in Pirganj Upazila of Thakurgaon.
Pirganj Police Station chief (OC) Mazharul Islam said the incident occurred around 1:00 am on Monday in Senua village under Bhomradaha Union.
S</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 09:12:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BB warns against sample notes, misleading social media content</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bb-warns-against-sample-notes-misleading-social-media-content</link><description>Bangladesh Bank (BB) has cautioned the people against using paper or objects resembling bank notes for marketing and social media content, warning that such activities are punishable offences under existing laws.
In a press release issued on Monday by the Department of Communications and Publicati</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 09:27:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CA delivers farewell address as interim govt prepares to hand over power</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/chief-adviser-delivers-farewell-address-as-interim-govt-prepares-to-hand-over-power</link><description>Chief Adviser Prof Muhammad Yunus on Monday delivered a farewell address to officers and staff at the Chief Adviser’s Office, marking the end of the interim administration’s tenure.
Following his speech, he joined officials and employees for a photo session at the office, UNB reports.</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 09:42:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CBCB congratulates BNP on election victory</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cbcb-congratulates-bnp-on-election-victory</link><description>The Catholic Bishops’ Conference of Bangladesh (CBCB) has congratulated the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) on its decisive victory in the 13th National Parliamentary Election.
President of the CBCB, Archbishop Bejoy N. D’Cruze, OMI, conveyed his greetings to the party’s Chair</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 09:57:48 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>