<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 21:50:06 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>ICT’s new chief prosecutor promises justice</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/new-ict-chief-prosecutor-aminul-promises-criminals-will-be-brought-to-justice</link><description>Md Aminul Islam, the newly appointed chief prosecutor of the International Crimes Tribunal (ICT), has pledged to ensure that offenders face the full force of the law while protecting the innocent from harassment.
Speaking after formally taking over from his predecessor, Md Tajul Islam, on Monday,</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 15:51:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NBR records 13pc growth in tax collection y-on-y in first 7 months of fiscal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/nbr-records-13pc-growth-in-tax-collection-y-on-y-in-first-7-months-of-fiscal</link><description>The National Board of Revenue (NBR) recorded a 12.90 percent growth in overall tax collection during the first seven months of the current fiscal year (FY2025–26), driven by strong performances in VAT and income tax, according to provisional data.
The National Board of Revenue collected Tk 2</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 16:06:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two more Bangladeshi garment factories achieve prestigious ‘Green’ certification</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/two-more-bangladeshi-garment-factories-achieve-prestigious-green-certification</link><description>Bangladesh’s RMG sector has reached a new milestone in eco-friendly industrialization as two more garment factories have earned the prestigious Leadership in Energy and Environmental Design (LEED) certification from the U.S. Green Building Council (USGBC).
With these new additions, the total</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 16:21:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New govt to continue reforms in banking sector: BB governor</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/new-govt-to-continue-reforms-in-banking-sector-bangladesh-bank-governor</link><description>The newly formed government will continue the ongoing reform programme in the banking sector, with priority given to controlling inflation, reducing non-performing loans and ensuring stability of the merged banks, Bangladesh Bank Governor Ahsan H Mansur said on Monday.
He made the remarks while sp</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 17:07:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Power drought tips Ukraine's economy into worst crisis since war's first year</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/power-drought-tips-ukraines-economy-into-worst-crisis-since-wars-first-year</link><description>Ukraine's economy is enduring its toughest period since the early months of Russia's invasion after sustained air strikes left its power system in tatters as the war enters a fifth year, forcing firms to cut output and shrinking state revenues.
From steel mills to miners, cement makers and food pr</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 17:22:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCP forms committee to oversee local government polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ncp-forms-committee-to-oversee-local-government-polls</link><description>National Citizen Party (NCP) has formed a committee to conduct the upcoming local government elections, appointing its Chief Organiser (North) Md Sarjis Alam as chief and Abdul Hannan Masud as member secretary.
The party disclosed the information in a message posted on its official Facebook</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 16:55:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Family Card: from political promise to national social contract</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/family-card-from-political-promise-to-national-social-contract</link><description>In Bangladesh today, countless mothers skip meals so their children can eat-a quiet sacrifice that reflects a deeper crisis of poverty, inflation, and insecurity. Nearly 28 per cent of the population now live below the poverty line, with about 9 per cent in extreme poverty. Food inflation has hover</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 17:10:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh's case for LDC deferral</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/bangladeshs-case-for-ldc-deferral</link><description>The newly elected BNP government has not wasted time over requesting the UN to defer the process of country's LDC graduation. Notably, the country was scheduled to graduate from the Least Developed Country (LDC) category on November 4, 2026 following completion of the 5-year preparatory period gran</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 17:25:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rebooting Indo-Bangla ties: Ball in India's court</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/rebooting-indo-bangla-ties-ball-in-indias-court</link><description>Relations between Bangladesh and India, bound by geography and history, have entered one of their most fragile phases in decades. The strains are not merely the residue of 1971 or the by-products of neighbourhood asymmetry. They are rooted in recent political upheavals that have reshaped Dhaka's do</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 17:40:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BSEC must come clean</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/bsec-must-come-clean</link><description>As the regulatory body of the Bangladesh capital market, the Bangladesh Securities and Exchange Commission (BSEC) has earned enough infamy. Instead of protecting the interests of investors, small investors to be more precise, it has served vested interest groups and at times is alleged to have coll</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 17:55:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt removes nine secretaries in major administrative reshuffle</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-removes-nine-secretaries-in-major-administrative-reshuffle</link><description>Nine secretaries and senior secretaries have lost their jobs after the government removed three others from their posts in a sweeping administrative shake-up.
The BNP-led government cancelled the remaining contract terms of the officials, all of whom had been appointed on contractual arrangements</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 18:10:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Vote eases political, policy uncertainty, supports macroeconomic stability</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/vote-eases-political-policy-uncertainty-supports-macroeconomic-stability</link><description>Bangladesh's general election has reduced near-term political and policy uncertainty in a turnaround that could support improvements in macroeconomic stability, says Fitch Ratings in its post-poll positive assessment.



The Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP)-led alliance has secured a parliame</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 18:25:10 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>