<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 06:50:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>NCP, 11-Party Alliance leaders, activists under ‘BNP attack’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ncp-11-party-alliance-leaders-activists-under-bnp-attack</link><description>Allegations surfaced from different parts of the country that some leaders and activists of the National Citizen Party (NCP) and the 11-Party Alliance came under attack following the 13th National Parliamentary Election, held on Thursday.
NCP spokesperson Asif Mahmud Shojib Bhuiyan, in his verifie</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 03:35:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Seven women candidates elected</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/seven-women-candidates-elected</link><description>Seven women candidates have been unofficially elected in the 13th National Parliamentary Election, according to results announced by the returning officers and the Election Commission.
Of the seven, six contested from Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP), which is set to form the government with an</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 03:50:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>WEEKLY KITCHEN MARKET REVIEW: Supply disruption pushes prices of vegetables, chicken, onion up</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/weekly-kitchen-market-review-supply-disruption-pushes-prices-of-vegetables-chicken-onion-up</link><description>Prices of vegetables, chicken and onions increased in the city markets, which traders attributed to supply disruptions due to the 13th national election and referendum.
Although vehicles carrying essential goods were officially exempted, the supply of products, including the essential items, decli</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 04:05:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AL office torched in Chandpur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/al-office-torched-in-chandpur</link><description>Miscreants torched an office of Awami League in Chandpur district town on Friday night.
 
Foyez Ahmed, Officer-in-Charge of Chandpur Model Police Station, said that miscreants set fire to the district unit AL office opposite to  official residence of Chandpur District Judge around</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 04:20:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh plans skills-based education for thousands of out-of-school children</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/bangladesh-plans-skills-based-education-for-thousands-of-out-of-school-children</link><description>For thousands of children left behind by poverty, migration, disability or family hardship, the classroom has long been out of reach in Bangladesh. Now, a new government move seeks to reopen that door—this time with skills at its core.
 
The Ministry of Primary and Mass Education has t</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 04:35:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique to hold first press meet after election win</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-to-hold-first-press-meet-after-election-win</link><description>Tarique Rahman has called a press conference following the BNP's landslide win in the Feb 12 parliamentary election.
The briefing will take place at 3pm on Saturday at the Hotel InterContinental ballroom in Dhaka, reports bdnews24.com.
Party Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir confirmed</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 04:50:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pahela Falgun brings colour, music as spring begins</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/pahela-falgun-brings-colour-music-as-spring-begins</link><description>Today marks Pahela Falgun, the first day of spring and the eleventh month of the Bangla calendar, a time that symbolises renewal, vibrancy and cultural pride for Bangladeshis.
Spring, often described as the king of seasons, arrives with a message of fullness and new life.
For many years, Banglade</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 05:05:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Over 48.2m votes cast in favour of 'Yes' in referendum</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/over-482m-votes-cast-in-favour-of-yes-in-referendum</link><description>A total of 4,82,00,660 votes have been cast in favour of 'Yes' in the referendum held on the implementation of the July National Charter, alongside the 13th Jatiya Sangsad election. 
In contrast, 2,20,71,726 votes were cast against the constitutional reform proposals (No votes), Election Comm</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 05:20:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh gazettes referendum results, 68.59% back ‘Yes’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-gazettes-referendum-results-6859-back-yes</link><description>Election Commission (EC) has gazetted the results of the July National Charter referendum on constitutional reforms, revealing that 68.59 per cent of valid votes favoured “Yes”.
On Friday night, following approval of the tally, EC Secretary Akhtar Ahmed issued the official notification</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 05:35:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>City getting back to normal after polls fever</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/city-getting-back-to-normal-after-polls-fever</link><description>The life in the capital started getting back to normal after much expected national elections and referendum held on Thursday.
The shopping malls and markets at different areas reopened on Friday, with the vehicular movement on the city streets and roads high on the day compared to Thursday (Feb 1</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 05:50:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CA congratulates Tarique on landslide victory</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ca-congratulates-tarique-on-landslide-victory</link><description>Chief Adviser of the Interim Government Professor Muhammad Yunus has extended warm congratulations to Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) Chairman Tarique Rahman on securing an overwhelming majority in the 13th Jatiya Sangsad election. 
In a congratulatory message, the Chief Adviser said, "I c</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 06:05:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bhutanese PM congratulates Tarique Rahman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/bhutanese-pm-congratulates-tarique-rahman</link><description>Prime Minister of Bhutan Tshering Tobgay today congratulated Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) Chairman Tarique Rahman on his party's massive victory in the general elections.
"Warmest congratulations to Mr. Tarique Rahman and the BNP on winning the Bangladesh General Elections," the Bhutanese Pr</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 06:20:49 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>