<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 11:19:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Army disperses protesters attempting fresh vandalism at Dhanmondi 32</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/army-disperses-protesters-attempting-fresh-vandalism-at-dhanmondi-32</link><description>The Army and police have blocked a group of people attempting to demolish the ruins of Bangabandhu Sheikh Mujibur Rahman’s residence at Dhanmondi 32.
Around 12 pm on Monday, two excavators were brought to the area by an organisation named “Red July”.
Police and later the Army di</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 09:06:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hasina to be hanged for crimes against humanity</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hasina-to-be-hanged-for-crimes-against-humanity</link><description>The International Crimes Tribunal has sentenced ousted Bangladeshi prime minister Sheikh Hasina to death for crimes against humanity for her attempts to suppress the July Uprising.
Hasina, who ruled the country for a decade and a half with an iron fist, has fled to India since she was ousted from</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 09:21:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ex-IGP Mamun gets five-year jail term for crimes against humanity</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ex-igp-mamun-gets-five-year-jail-term-for-crimes-against-humanity</link><description>The International Crimes Tribunal-1 on Monday sentenced former Inspector General of Police Chowdhury Abdullah Al Mamun to five years in prison in a case filed over crimes against humanity.
The three-member tribunal, headed by Justice Golam Mortuza Majumder, pronounced the verdict in a packed court</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 09:36:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Death sentence of former home minister Asaduzzaman Khan Kamal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/death-sentence-of-former-home-minister-asaduzzaman-khan-kamal</link><description>The International Crimes Tribunal on Monday sentenced former home minister Asaduzzaman Khan Kamal to death for crimes against humanity committed during the July mass uprising.
The verdict was delivered by a three-member panel of Tribunal-1, led by Chairman Justice Golam Mortuza Mojumdar, with Just</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 08:36:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pick-up van torched in Cumilla</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/pick-up-van-torched-in-cumilla</link><description>Miscreants set fire to a stationary pick-up van on Dhaka-Chattogram highway at Chauddagram in Cumilla district early Monday.
Mohammad Hilal Uddin Ahmed, officer-in-charge of Chauddagram Police Station, said two motorcyclists set the pick-up van on fire after pouring petrol early in the morning, UN</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 08:51:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Letter will be sent to India seeking Hasina's extradition: Asif Nazrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/letter-will-be-sent-to-india-seeking-hasinas-extradition-asif-nazrul</link><description>Legal, Justice and Parliamentary Affairs Adviser Prof Dr Asif Nazrul has said that a letter will be sent to India seeking the extradition of Sheikh Hasina.
He added that he is satisfied with the verdict in Sheikh Hasina’s trial, though not surprised by it, according to local media reports.</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 09:06:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prospect of Hasina’s political comeback in Bangladesh appears slim: ICG</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/prospect-of-hasinas-political-comeback-in-bangladesh-appears-slim-icg</link><description>The International Crisis Group on Monday said the prospect of former Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina ‘mounting a political comeback in Bangladesh now appears very slim’.
“The political repercussions of this verdict are significant," said Crisis Group's expert on Bangladesh, Senior C</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 09:21:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>APM Terminals’ Laldia investment marks new beginning for Bangladesh: Prof Yunus</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/apm-terminals-laldia-investment-marks-new-beginning-for-bangladesh-prof-yunus</link><description>Chief Adviser Prof Muhammad Yunus on Monday said Danish company APM Terminals' investment in the Laldia Terminal marks the beginning of a new era for Bangladesh's trade and foreign direct investment.
"This is a new beginning for the country. It opens a new door for larger and more diversified inve</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 09:36:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Salahuddin hails ICT verdict against Hasina, calls it a lesson against dictatorship</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/salahuddin-hails-ict-verdict-against-hasina-calls-it-a-lesson-against-dictatorship</link><description>BNP senior leader Salahuddin Ahmed on Monday said the International Crimes Tribunal-1 (ICT-1) verdict convicting deposed Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina and two others delivers justice and serves as a warning against future dictatorship.
“Justice has been established today in the International</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 09:51:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Understanding the hormones behind the chaos</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/others/understanding-the-hormones-behind-the-chaos</link><description>Girls, have you ever had an inexplicable outburst over something little? Or came down with an overwhelming feeling of anxiety? Then you questioned whether these random breakdowns were a little uncalled for. Next time you have an unexpected emotional flare-up, better check your period calendar immed</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 10:06:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hasina’s death sentence 'not an act of political vengeance': Chief Prosecutor</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hasinas-death-sentence-not-an-act-of-political-vengeance-chief-prosecutor</link><description>International Crimes Tribunal (ICT) Chief Prosecutor Tajul Islam has rejected suggestions that the death sentence for deposed prime minister Sheikh Hasina over crimes against humanity committed during attempts to suppress the July Uprising represented an "act of political retribution" against her.</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 10:21:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh attorney general hails ‘landmark’ tribunal verdict against ex-PM Hasina</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-attorney-general-hails-landmark-tribunal-verdict-against-ex-pm-hasina</link><description>The International Crimes Tribunal verdict in the crimes against humanity case against former prime minister Sheikh Hasina and two others stands as a landmark one for future generations, says Attorney General Md Asaduzzaman.
He shared his reaction with the media at the court premises after the verd</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 10:36:25 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>