<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 14:22:34 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Md Sawkatul Alam takes over as Administrator of Exim Bank</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/md-sawkatul-alam-takes-over-as-administrator-of-exim-bank</link><description>As part of the ongoing merger process involving five banks, Bangladesh Bank’s Executive Director Md. Sawkatul Alam formally took over as the Administrator of EXIM Bank on November 5, 2025.
He obtained both his bachelor’s and master’s degrees from the Department of Mathematics, Un</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 11:52:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New Logistics Policy 2025 approved to boost investment, digitalise cargo transport</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/new-logistics-policy-2025-approved-to-boost-investment-digitalise-cargo-transport</link><description>Bangladesh’s Council of Advisers on Thursday approved the National Logistics Policy 2025 — a comprehensive framework aimed at modernising the country’s logistics ecosystem, improving transport efficiency, and attracting both domestic and foreign investment.
Briefing reporters at</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 12:07:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IFIC Bank hosts 'Festival of Youth 2025' in Sylhet</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ific-bank-hosts-festival-of-youth-2025-in-sylhet</link><description>IFIC Bank organized a special workshop on financial literacy in Sylhet under the guidance of Bangladesh Bank, as part of the "Festival of Youth 2025."
The workshop was held on November 4, 2025, in collaboration with Sylhet Government Women’s College, at the college’s auditorium, accord</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 12:22:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Midland Bank provides financial assistance to metro rail victim's family</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/midland-bank-provides-financial-assistance-to-metro-rail-victims-family</link><description>Midland Bank Family provided financial assistance of Tk 15 lac to the family of late Abul Kalam, who passed away in the recent metro rail tragedy in Farmgate area, Dhaka, on October 27, 2025.
The bank provided Tk 5 lac financial assistance from its Islami Banking Fund under its Corporate Social Re</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 12:37:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prime Bank signs payroll agreement with Rahim Group</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/prime-bank-signs-payroll-agreement-with-rahim-group</link><description>Prime Bank PLC., one of the leading private commercial banks in Bangladesh, renowned for its innovative and customer-centric financial solutions, has recently signed a Payroll Agreement with Rahim Group at the bank’s Corporate Office in Dhaka.
Under this agreement, employees of Rahim Group w</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 12:52:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bank Asia arranges awareness program on Gender Equality and Prevention of Sexual Harassment</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bank-asia-arranges-awareness-program-on-gender-equality-and-prevention-of-sexual-harassment</link><description>Bank Asia PLC. organized a day-long awareness program on “Gender Equality and Prevention of Sexual Harassment” at the Bank Asia Institute for Training and Development (BAITD), Lalmatia, Dhaka, on 4 November 2025.
Ms. Rumana Akhter Tulee, Assistant Vice President of Bank Asia, conducted</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 13:07:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fire breaks out at wood pile of Rooppur Nuclear Power Plant</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fire-breaks-out-at-wood-pile-of-rooppur-nuclear-power-plant</link><description>A fire broke out at a wood pile within the Rooppur Nuclear Power Plant in Ishwardi upazila of Pabna district on Thursday.
Abul Hashem, senior station master of Rooppur Green City Fire Service, said the fire erupted at an abandoned wood pile along the Padma River on the eastern side of the power pl</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 13:37:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Poppy seeds imported under bird food label from Pakistan seized in Chattogram</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/poppy-seeds-imported-under-bird-food-label-from-pakistan-seized-in-chattogram</link><description>Chattogram Customs House has seized 24,960kg of poppy seeds that were imported from Pakistan under a false declaration as bird feed.
According to a media statement, the shipment, banned under import rules, was intercepted recently by the authorities, reports bdnews24.com.
Officials said Adib Trad</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 13:52:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Investors demand resignation of Finance Adviser, BB Governor over bank merger</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/investors-demand-resignation-of-finance-adviser-bb-governor-over-bank-merger</link><description>Stock market investors under the banner of ‘Bangladesh Pujibazar Oikya Parishad’ on Thursday demanded the resignation of Finance Adviser Dr Salehuddin Ahmed and Bangladesh Bank Governor Dr Ahsan H Mansur, alleging that the recent merger of five Shariah-based banks was decided without co</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 14:22:34 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>