<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 11:20:44 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Two killed after truck rams motorcycle in Gaibandha</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/two-killed-after-truck-rams-motorcycle-in-gaibandha</link><description>Two people have been killed and another injured after a truck ploughed into a motorcycle in Gaibandha’s Gobindaganj Upazila.
The crash occurred around 11pm on Thursday on the Rangpur–Dhaka highway near the BRAC office at Fashitola Bazar, according to police.
The two men who died were</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 08:45:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Condolence book opened in Tokyo in memory of Khaleda Zia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/condolence-book-opened-in-tokyo-in-memory-of-khaleda-zia</link><description>A condolence book was opened on Friday at the Embassy of Bangladesh in Tokyo following the demise of Khaleda Zia, a three-time former Prime Minister of the government of Bangladesh and Chairperson of Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP).
Representatives from various foreign diplomatic missions based</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 09:00:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Zaima, family members offer prayers at Khaleda’s grave amid tight security</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/zaima-family-members-offer-prayers-at-khaledas-grave-amid-tight-security</link><description>Family members of BNP chairperson and former prime minister Khaleda Zia have paid their respects at her grave, offering prayers.
Khaleda’s granddaughter Zaima Rahman, along with other family members, visited the grave around 9:30am on Friday.
She was accompanied by Syeda Sharmila Rahman, wi</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 09:15:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Old artillery shell recovered in Kushtia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/old-artillery-shell-recovered-in-kushtia</link><description>Police have recovered an old artillery shell from a village in Daulatpur upazila of Kushtia district.
The shell was found on Thursday evening at the house of late Asmat Ullah, a retired senior warrant officer of the Bangladesh Army, in Daulatkhali village under the upazila headquarters.
After spo</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 09:30:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Inquilab Moncho stages protests demanding justice for Hadi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/inquilab-moncho-stages-protests-demanding-justice-for-hadi</link><description>Inquilab Moncho on Friday staged a demonstration demanding justice for its slain spokesperson Sharif Osman Bin Hadi, with a large number of protesters in attendance.
They brought out a procession from the central mosque premises of Dhaka University after Jumu'a prayers.
During the demonstration,</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 09:45:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BGB trooper dies from gunshot wound in Kurigram; police suspect suicide</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bgb-trooper-dies-from-gunshot-wound-in-kurigram-police-suspect-suicide</link><description>A member of the Border Guard Bangladesh (BGB) has died from gunfire at a BGB camp in Kurigram's Phulbari Upazila in what police suspect is a case of suicide.
The incident occurred around 1:30 am on Friday at the Gangarhat Border Outpost (BOP), according to Phulbari Police Station chief (OC) Mahmud</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 10:00:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump says US will intervene if Iran violently suppresses peaceful protests</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-says-us-will-intervene-if-iran-violently-suppresses-peaceful-protests</link><description>US President Donald Trump on Friday said that if Iran shoots and violently kills peaceful protesters, the United States of America will come to their rescue.
"We are locked and loaded and ready to go," he said in a Truth Social post.
This follows the deaths of several people as Iran's biggest pro</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 10:00:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Renowned rhymester Sukumar Barua dies at 87</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/sukumar-barua-whose-rhymes-shaped-the-childhoods-of-generations-dies-at-87</link><description>Celebrated rhymester Sukumar Barua has died under hospital care at the age of 87.
He passed away at 6:55am on Friday at a private hospital in Gahira of Chattogram’s Raozan Upazila.
His son, Arup Ratan Barua, said Sukumar had been suffering from age-related illnesses for some time.
“T</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 10:15:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Condolence book opened at Bangladesh Embassy in Tokyo for Khaleda Zia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/condolence-book-opened-at-bangladesh-embassy-in-tokyo-for-khaleda-zia</link><description>The Embassy of Bangladesh in Tokyo on Friday opened a condolence book to pay tribute to former Prime Minister and Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) Chairperson Begum Khaleda Zia following her demise.
Representatives of various foreign diplomatic missions based in Japan visited the embassy and sig</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 10:30:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two sisters found dead under fallen tree in Gaibandha</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/two-sisters-found-dead-under-fallen-tree-in-gaibandha</link><description>The bodies of two young sisters who had earlier been reported missing have been found under a recently felled tree in Gaibandha Sadar Upazila.
The children’s bodies were discovered on Thursday evening in Khamar Raghunathpur village of Ballamjhar Union, according to bdnews24.com.
Police id</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 10:45:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pakistan court sentences journalists to life over links to protests after Imran Khan’s arrest</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/pakistan-court-sentences-journalists-to-life-over-links-to-protests-after-imran-khans-arrest</link><description>A Pakistani anti-terrorism court sentenced eight journalists and social media commentators on Friday to life imprisonment in absentia after convicting them of terrorism-related offences linked to online activity in support of jailed former prime minister Imran Khan.
The convictions stem from cases</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 11:00:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>GM Quader’s income falls, but cash holdings increase</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jatiya-party-leader-gm-quaders-income-falls-but-cash-holdings-increase</link><description>Jatiya Party Chairman GM Quader’s income over the past two years has declined but his cash holdings and overall assets appear to have increased based on the prospective candidate for the Rangpur-3 constituency’s latest wealth declaration.
A comparison of affidavits submitted ahead of t</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 11:15:01 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>