<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 11:19:06 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Exporters demand safety measures, compensation after HSIA cargo zone fire</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/exporters-demand-safety-measures-compensation-after-hsia-cargo-zone-fire</link><description>Leaders of the country’s export-oriented sectors have demanded stronger safety measures at the import cargo zone of Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport (HSIA), holding the lack of adequate precautions responsible for the recent massive fire there.
They also urged the government to provide</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 10:14:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nasir, Afridi chatty in court, Salim, Solaiman quiet</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nasir-afridi-chatty-in-court-salim-solaiman-quiet</link><description>MyTV Chairman Nasir Uddin and his son, YouTuber Tawhid Afridi, were seen chatting in the dock of the Dhaka court where they were brought on Monday morning.
In contrast, former member of parliament and Awami League leader Haji Mohammad Salim and his son, ex-lawmaker Solaiman Salim, kept their dista</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 09:04:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>July Uprising murder cases to be tried at Speedy Trial Tribunal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/july-uprising-murder-cases-to-be-tried-at-speedy-trial-tribunal</link><description>The cases filed on charges of murder committed on the orders of the Awami League government to suppress the student-led mass movement during the July Uprising, excluding cases pending in the International Crimes Tribunal, will be tried by the Speedy Trial Tribunal.
In addition, a special committee</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 09:19:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>In Trump's drug war, prisoners may be too much of a legal headache, experts say</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/in-trumps-drug-war-prisoners-may-be-too-much-of-a-legal-headache-experts-say</link><description>When two alleged drug traffickers survived a U.S. military strike last week in the Caribbean, they left the Trump administration with a decision to make: send them back home, or find a way to keep them detained.
The U.S. last month started a campaign of attacks in the Caribbean that the Trump admi</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 09:34:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Kremlin says Orban’s good ties with Trump and Putin are reason for holding summit in Hungary</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/kremlin-says-orbans-good-ties-with-trump-and-putin-are-reason-for-holding-summit-in-hungary</link><description>The Kremlin said on Monday that Budapest was chosen as the venue for an upcoming summit between Russian President Vladimir Putin and U.S. President Donald Trump because Hungarian Prime Minister Viktor Orban has good ties with both leaders.
Kremlin spokesman Dmitry Peskov told reporters: “Orb</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 10:04:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh on radar of new Asia-Pacific hacker group ‘Mysterious Elephant’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/bangladesh-on-radar-of-new-asia-pacific-hacker-group-mysterious-elephant</link><description>A new hacker group named “Mysterious Elephant” has been detected operating across the Asia-Pacific region, according to Kaspersky’s Global Research and Analysis Team (GReAT).
The group has primarily been targeting government departments and foreign affairs-related organisations a</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 10:34:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prime Bank appoints Mohammad Jashim Uddin as CFO</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/prime-bank-appoints-mohammad-jashim-uddin-as-cfo</link><description>Prime Bank PLC has appointed Mohammad Jashim Uddin as Chief Financial Officer (CFO) &amp; Head of Financial Administration Division (FAD) with immediate effect.
Jashim has been an integral part of Prime Bank since 2005, according to a media release. 
Over the years, he has served in several key</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 10:49:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka court orders murder case over actor Salman Shah’s death after 29 years</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dhaka-court-orders-murder-case-over-actor-salman-shahs-death-after-29-years</link><description>A Dhaka court has ordered the filing of a murder case in connection with the death of popular film actor Salman Shah, nearly three decades after his death rocked Bangladesh’s entertainment industry.
The order was issued on Monday by Additional Metropolitan Sessions Judge Md Jannatul Ferdous</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 11:04:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Indonesian students to protest as Prabowo marks one year in office</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/indonesian-students-to-protest-as-prabowo-marks-one-year-in-office</link><description>Indonesian student groups are planning a protest on the first anniversary of Prabowo Subianto's government in Jakarta on Monday, two months after violent demonstrations rocked the country, as the president holds a cabinet meeting to mark his first year in office.
Protesters will gather near the pr</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 11:19:06 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>