<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 08:34:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Man stabbed to death in Dhaka’s Kamrangirchar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/man-stabbed-to-death-in-dhakas-kamrangirchar</link><description>A man has been stabbed to death in Dhaka’s Kamrangirchar.
The victim has been identified as 25-year-old Rocky, an employee at a local grocer.
The incident occurred in front of the Boro Gram Bazar Ashrafabad High School around 3:30am on Tuesday.
Locals rescued Rocky and took him to Dhaka Me</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 06:00:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Madaripur road crash leaves 3 dead</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/madaripur-road-crash-leaves-3-dead</link><description>Three people were killed and seven others injured when a truck crashed into a bus on Dhaka-Bhanga Expressway over Arial Khan Bridge in Shibchar upazila of Madaripur district on Tuesday.
One of the deceased was identified as Munir Sheikh, 35, of Najirpur upazila in Pirojpur district.
Md Sabuj, ser</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 06:15:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hong Kong leader orders independent probe into fire that killed 151</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/hong-kong-leader-orders-independent-probe-into-fire-that-killed-151</link><description>Hong Kong's leader said on Tuesday an independent committee would be established to investigate the cause of the city's deadliest fire in decades, including oversight of renovations blamed for the disaster that has claimed 151 lives.
Police have arrested 13 people for suspected manslaughter in a c</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 06:30:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mobile phone traders at Jamuna Future Park close shops indefinitely</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/mobile-phone-traders-at-jamuna-future-park-close-shops-indefinitely</link><description>The Mobile Business Community Bangladesh (MBCB), Jamuna Future Park branch, has announced an indefinite closure of the shopping mall’s mobile market, effective from Tuesday.
Traders said they made the decision after receiving no response from the government despite repeated calls for discuss</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 06:45:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump invites Israel's Netanyahu to White House</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/trump-invites-israels-netanyahu-to-white-house</link><description>US President Donald Trump has invited Israel's Benjamin Netanyahu to the White House in the "near future," the prime minister's office said on Monday, shortly after Trump said Israel should maintain a strong and true dialogue with Syria.
A visit to the White House would mark the Israeli prime mini</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 07:00:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two motorcyclists die in Narsingdi road crash</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/two-motorcyclists-die-in-narsingdi-road-crash</link><description>Two friends riding a motorcycle have died after their vehicle collided head-on with an autorickshaw in Shibpur upazila of Narsingdi.
Two others were injured in the accident that occurred around 8:30 pm on Monday on the Shibpur-Manohardi road in Pacharbari, according to Shibpur Model Police Station</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 06:30:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khaleda receiving prescribed treatment, expected to recover: Dr Zahid</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/khaleda-receiving-prescribed-treatment-expected-to-recover-dr-zahid</link><description>BNP Chairperson and former Prime Minister Khaleda Zia is receiving her prescribed treatment properly and is expected to recover, her personal physician Dr AZM Zahid Hossain said on Tuesday.
“We firmly believe she will recover this time and return to us. She is properly receiving the treatmen</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 06:45:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Motorcyclist killed after truck collision in Chattogram</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/motorcyclist-killed-after-truck-collision-in-chattogram</link><description>A young man was killed when a truck hit his motorcycle on the Chattogram-Cox's Bazar highway in Lohagara upazila around midnight on Monday.
The deceased was identified as Mohammad Hasan Riyad, 28, a resident of the upazila, reports BSS. 
Dohazari Highway Police Station Officer-In-Charge (OC)</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 07:00:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Temperature drops to 13.5°C in Lalmonirhat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/temperature-drops-to-135c-in-lalmonirhat</link><description>Northern Bangladesh has begun to feel the first true grip of winter, with temperatures dipping to 13.5°C in Lalmonirhat on Tuesday, signalling a sharper seasonal shift for residents accustomed to early December's milder chill.
Between 6 am and 9 am, the Kurigram Weather Observatory recorded th</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 07:15:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EU preparing big observer mission for Bangladesh election: Miller</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/eu-preparing-big-observer-mission-for-bangladesh-election-miller</link><description>European Union (EU) Ambassador in Dhaka Michael Miller on Tuesday said the EU is preparing to send a very big election observer mission to Bangladesh to monitor what he described as the biggest democratic exercise anywhere in the world in 2026.
"This is a time when the country [Bangladesh] can cha</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 07:30:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Average life expectancy in China hits 79 years</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/average-life-expectancy-in-china-hits-79-years</link><description>China's average life expectancy reached 79 years in 2024, according to a report released Tuesday by the National Health Commission.
China's 2024 health statistics bulletin highlighted continued improvements in both maternal and child health, with maternal deaths falling to 14.3 per 100,000 and inf</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 07:45:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt declares Khaleda Zia VVIP</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-declares-khaleda-zia-vvip</link><description>The government has declared BNP Chairperson and former Prime Minister Begum Khaleda Zia a 'very very important person' (VVIP).
The decision was taken at a special meeting of the Council of Advisers, held on Tuesday at the State Guest House Jamuna, chaired by Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus.</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 08:00:51 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>