<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 17:39:39 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Spain's top court rejects father's bid to halt daughter's euthanasia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/spains-top-court-rejects-fathers-bid-to-halt-daughters-euthanasia</link><description>Spain's Constitutional Court has rejected an appeal by the father of a 25‑year‑old paraplegic woman who opposes her access to euthanasia, the court said in a statement on Friday.
In 2021, Spain became the fourth European Union country to legalise euthanasia and assisted suicide for people with inc</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 14:24:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BSEC chairman urges richer reporting as verified information protects capital market</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/bsec-chairman-urges-richer-reporting-as-verified-information-protects-capital-market</link><description>The Bangladesh Securities and Exchange Commission (BSEC) has insisted that the capital market must remain free of “garbage,” with any misleading or unverified information removed immediately.
BSEC Chairman Khondoker Rashed Maqsood said journalists are actively helping in this process b</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 14:39:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Meghmallar Bosu hospitalised after ‘overdose’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/students-union-leader-meghmallar-hospitalised-after-overdosing</link><description>Meghmallar Bosu, president of a faction of the Dhaka University unit of the Bangladesh Students’ Union, has been admitted to hospital after “taking a large dose of medicine”.
He was admitted to Dhaka’s Shaheed Suhrawardy Medical College Hospital on Friday afternoon, the org</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 14:54:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump EPA to weaken rule limiting harmful mercury, air toxics from coal plants</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-epa-to-weaken-rule-limiting-harmful-mercury-air-toxics-from-coal-plants</link><description>The Trump administration announced on Friday it will roll back air regulations for power plants limiting mercury and hazardous air toxics at an event in Kentucky, a move it says will boost baseload energy but that public health groups say will harm public health for America’s most vulnerable</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 14:30:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Portfolios reportedly allocated among eight advisers to PM Tarique</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/portfolios-reportedly-allocated-among-eight-advisers-to-pm-tarique</link><description>The government has reportedly allocated portfolios to eight advisers appointed to PM Tarique Rahman with the status of minister and state minister.
Officials said the responsibilities were assigned through a notification issued by the Cabinet Division on Friday.
According to the notification, amo</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 14:45:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hasnat Abdullah vows to serve people of all faiths equally in office</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hasnat-abdullah-vows-to-serve-people-of-all-faiths-equally-in-office</link><description>Member of Parliament Hasnat Abdullah, elected from Cumilla-4 constituency, has said he will serve people of all religions equally during the next five years.
Speaking Friday at the 21st reunion of Bangladesh Sebashram Jubo Songho in Debidwar, he said his responsibility is not only to Muslims but t</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 15:00:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Keep Ramadan commodity prices tolerable, ensure security for all: Shama Obaed</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/keep-ramadan-commodity-prices-tolerable-ensure-security-for-all-shama-obaed</link><description>State Minister for Foreign Affairs Shama Obaed Islam on Friday stressed the need to keep prices of essential commodities at a tolerable level during the holy month of Ramadan and ensure security for all, regardless of political affiliation.
She made the remarks at a views-exchange meeting with gov</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 15:15:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>FIFA and Board of Peace to support Gaza reconstruction through football</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/fifa-and-board-of-peace-to-support-gaza-reconstruction-through-football</link><description>FIFA and the Board of Peace signed a partnership agreement on Thursday to attract investment from global leaders and institutions for sustainable development in conflict-affected regions through football.
The Board of Peace, established under the US President Donald Trump, held its first meeting f</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 15:30:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mobile court fines 15 traders, seals 2 meat shops in Keraniganj market drive</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/mobile-court-fines-15-traders-seals-2-meat-shops-in-keraniganj-market-drive</link><description>A mobile court in Keraniganj conducted a market drive on Friday afternoon to keep prices of essential commodities under control during Ramadan, fining 15 shop owners and sealing two meat shops for irregularities.
The mobile court was carried out at Zinzira Bazar under Keraniganj Model Police Stati</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 15:45:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cabinet meeting rules under scrutiny as advisors join ministers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cabinet-meeting-rules-under-scrutiny-as-advisors-join-ministers</link><description>The presence of advisors at the BNP government’s first cabinet meeting has become a constitutional talking point.
Since advisors do not take an oath of confidentiality, it is unclear whether they can attend such a critical government meeting.
Experts say the matter depends largely on tradit</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 16:00:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>From 'buy America' to 'bye America', Wall Street exodus gathers pace</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/from-buy-america-to-bye-america-wall-street-exodus-gathers-pace</link><description>US investors are pulling money out of their own stock market at the fastest pace in at least 16 years as Big Tech returns fade and better-performing overseas markets look more attractive.
In the last six months, US-domiciled investors have pulled some $75 billion from US equity products, with $52</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 16:49:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Woman arrested after child’s body found stuffed in plastic drum</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/woman-arrested-after-childs-body-found-stuffed-in-plastic-drum</link><description>Police have arrested a woman for allegedly killing a 7-year-old boy and dumping his body in a plastic drum at a rubbish heap in Dhaka’s Gendaria.
The suspect, identified as 45-year-old Maya Begum alias Laboni, was arrested following the recovery of the child’s body on Wednesday, accord</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 17:04:14 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>