<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 04:34:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Air ambulance for Khaleda seeks ‘Tuesday slot’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/khaledas-london-flight-german-air-ambulance-seeks-tuesday-landing-slot</link><description>The German air ambulance hired to take BNP Chairperson Khaleda Zia to London for treatment has sought a landing slot in Dhaka for Tuesday, according to a Civil Aviation Authority of Bangladesh (CAAB) official.
The official told bdnews24.com that the request came from FAI Aviation Group through a t</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 18:38:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Former Jubo Dal leader arrested by joint forces dies in Jashore</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/former-jubo-dal-leader-arrested-by-joint-forces-dies-in-jashore</link><description>A former Jubo Dal leader, who was arrested in an operation in Jashore’s Keshabpur by joint forces, has died.
The dead has been identified as Ujjal Bishwash.
“Ujjal was sent to the hospital after he had fallen sick in the prison on Friday night. He was declared dead at the hospital,&amp;rd</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 18:53:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khaleda's foreign trip delayed</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/khaledas-foreign-trip-delayed</link><description>Ailing ex-premier and BNP chairperson Khaleda Zia's London trip is delayed as her health condition doesn't support at the moment, a spokesman said Saturday, quoting a multinational medical board's decision.
Taking the BNP chairperson abroad for advanced treatment depends on her physical condition,</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 01:15:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>PC sends ICT project back for revision over cost concerns</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/pc-sends-ict-project-back-for-revision-over-cost-concerns</link><description>The Planning Commission has returned a project proposal submitted by the ICT Division that aimed to provide reliable high-speed broadband connectivity to 39 million people and expand digital public services to boost annual ICT export capacity to $5.0 billion.
Citing excessive cost estimates, the c</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 01:30:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka expects fresh support as Berlin prepares new framework</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/dhaka-expects-fresh-support-as-berlin-prepares-new-framework</link><description>After a three-year pause, Germany and Bangladesh will resume their bilateral consultations on development cooperation in Dhaka on Tuesday, officials said on Saturday.
Officials say the discussions are expected to pave the way for renewed financial and technical support from Europe's largest econom</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 01:45:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Debit, credit cards planned to be integrated with Rapid Pass</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/debit-credit-cards-planned-to-be-integrated-with-rapid-pass</link><description>In a major step towards modernising urban mobility, the Dhaka Transport Coordination Authority (DTCA) is planning to integrate bank-issued credit and debit cards with the Rapid Pass system.
The move is intended to make metro travel smoother and more convenient, allowing passengers to use their reg</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 02:00:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>JICA seeks BB's steps to repurpose its funds for failed projects</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jica-seeks-bbs-steps-to-repurpose-its-funds-for-failed-projects</link><description>Japan International Cooperation Agency (JICA) has sought necessary steps from Bangladesh Bank (BB) to either refund or re-purpose the funds that it disbursed for certain projects.
The funds were disbursed for three sub-projects under the Two-Step Loan Component of the Urban Building Safety Project</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 02:15:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt employees rally for 5-pt demand, including pay commission</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-employees-rally-for-5-pt-demand-including-pay-commission</link><description>The Bangladesh Government Employees Coordination Council (BGECC) has called upon the government to meet their five-point charter of demands including implementation of pay commission from the next year (1st January 2026).
The council also urged the government to reinstate time scale and selection</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 02:30:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rights-based reforms urged to ensure digital safety</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rights-based-reforms-urged-to-ensure-digital-safety</link><description>Experts at a dialogue have stressed the urgent need for rights-based reforms to protect freedom of expression, privacy and civic participation in Bangladesh's evolving digital landscape.
As technology becomes an inseparable part of everyday life, online repression, data misuse, surveillance, misin</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 02:45:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bondholders may have to wait until 2032 for Beximco Sukuk principal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/bondholders-may-have-to-wait-until-2032-for-beximco-sukuk-principal</link><description>The maturity period of the Beximco Green Sukuk has been proposed to be extended by up to six years to 2032, as repayment of principal to bondholders has become uncertain amid changes in the political climate.
The recommendation came from a 21-member working committee formed by the trustee, the Inv</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 03:00:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Genex Infosys FY25 profit falls 17pc amid costly diversification</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/genex-infosys-fy25-profit-falls-17pc-amid-costly-diversification</link><description>Listed business process management (BPM) and IT services company Genex Infosys reported a 17.18 per cent year-on-year decline in profit to Tk 261.38 million in FY25.
In a filing on Thursday, the company reported earnings per share (EPS) of Tk 2.17 in FY25, down from Tk 2.62 in FY24.
The result su</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 03:45:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BAN holds 8th Startup Showcase at IUB</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ban-holds-8th-startup-showcase-at-iub</link><description>Bangladesh Angels Network (BAN), an angel investment platform, on Saturday organised its 8th Startup Showcase at the Independent University Bangladesh (IUB) auditorium in the city.
The event, sponsored by Trust Bank PLC, brought together investors, founders, and ecosystem leaders, with Sadat Ahmed</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 04:00:49 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>