<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 10:27:49 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Expatriates send nearly 140,000 postal ballots home</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/expatriates-send-nearly-140000-postal-ballots-home</link><description>Expatriates registered through the “Postal Vote BD” app to cast their votes in the 13th Jatiya Sangsad (JS) election and the referendum have begun sending back their ballots.
So far, 139,763 expatriate ballots have arrived in the country, said Salim Ahmad Khan, team leader of the OCV-S</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 07:16:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Work stoppage over NCT foreign deal halts Ctg port operations</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/work-stoppage-over-nct-foreign-deal-brings-ctg-port-operations-to-a-standstill</link><description>Chittagong Port workers and employees have launched a work stoppage to protest the decision to appoint foreign companies to operate the New Mooring Container Terminal (NCT).
The operations at the Chittagong Port have come to a halt following the enforcement of the protest by the port unit of the J</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 07:31:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Murder case filed over Jamaat leader's death in Sherpur clash</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/over-700-accused-in-murder-case-filed-over-jamaat-leaders-death-in-sherpur-clash</link><description>A murder case has been filed two days after the death of a Jamaat-e-Islami leader during clashes between supporters of rival political parties in Sherpur.
More than 700 people have been named as accused in the case, including a BNP candidate contesting the Sherpur-3 parliamentary seat.
Police sai</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 07:46:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Central Insurance holds Annual Managers’ Conference 2025</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/central-insurance-holds-annual-managers-conference-2025</link><description>Central Insurance PLC has recently organised its Annual Managers’ Conference 2025 at the Samson H Chowdhury Hall of Dhaka Club Ltd, according to a press release Saturday.
The company's Chairman Mohammed Masud Hossain attended the event as the chief guest, with Vice Chairman Mohammed Masud Ka</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 08:01:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gold records sharpest one-day fall, down Tk 15,746 per bhori</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/gold-records-sharpest-one-day-fall-down-tk-15746-per-bhori</link><description>Gold prices in the Bangladesh market fell sharply again, with the price of 22-carat gold dropping by Tk 15,746 per bhori (11.664 grams) in a single day, the Bangladesh Jewellers Association (Bajus) announced on Saturday.
In a morning notification, Bajus said the new price of 22-carat gold has been</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 08:16:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hajj visa applications to open from February 8</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hajj-visa-applications-to-open-from-february-8</link><description>The Religious Affairs Ministry has announced that applications for Hajj visas for the current year will open on February 8 and continue until March 20.
The ministry issued a notice in this regard on Thursday.
All registered Hajj pilgrims, both through government and private channels, are currentl</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 08:31:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>12 names removed from ‘July fighters’ gazette</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/12-names-removed-from-july-fighters-gazette</link><description>The government has removed the names of 12 people who were earlier enlisted in the July fighters gazette.
The Ministry of Liberation War Affairs recently issued a notification cancelling the previous gazette.
The notification said the cancellation was made under the authority granted by Section 1</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 08:46:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Swechchhasebak Dal leader killed in ‘BNP factional clash’ in Narayanganj</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/swechchhasebak-dal-leader-killed-in-bnp-factional-clash-in-narayanganj</link><description>A leader of Swechchhasebak Dal has been killed in a clash allegedly between two BNP faction at Trishkania in Kanchan municipality area in Rupganj upazila.
The deceased was identified as Azhar Uddin, 48,  senior vice-president of the Swechchhasebak Dal’s Ward No. 9 unit.
Three others&amp;md</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 09:01:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BGB to deploy 134 platoons in Dhaka ahead of election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bgb-to-deploy-134-platoons-in-dhaka-ahead-of-election</link><description>A total of 134 BGB platoons will be deployed in 51 constituencies across nine districts and four city corporations under the Dhaka Sector.
To support these deployments, 42 temporary base camps have been established. In addition, BGB’s specialised K-9 Dog Squad units will conduct targeted sea</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 09:16:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Israel military reported to accept death toll of around 70,000 in Gaza</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/israel-military-reported-to-accept-death-toll-of-around-70000-in-gaza</link><description>Israel's military has accepted that around 70,000 Palestinians were killed during the war in Gaza, after having earlier cast doubt on death tolls reported by the enclave's health officials, Israeli media reported on Friday citing senior military officials.
The United Nations has long accepted deat</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 09:31:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat pledges unity govt if voted to power</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-pledges-unity-govt-if-voted-to-power</link><description>Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami Ameer Dr Shafiqur Rahman on Saturday said his party would invite rival political parties to take part in running the country if Jamaat comes to power with a parliamentary majority.
Speaking at a rally at Chouddagram High School ground in Cumilla, he said, “If we ac</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 09:46:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Election violence: 15 injured in BNP-Jamaat clash in Bhola</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/election-violence-15-injured-in-bnp-jamaat-clash-in-bhola</link><description>At least 15 people have been injured in a clash between supporters of the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) and Jamaat-e-Islami during election campaigning in Bhola's Borhanuddin Upazila.
The violence broke out on Saturday morning in Tobgi Union's Mulaipattan village, according to Borhanuddin Pol</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 10:01:55 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>