<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 07:05:08 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nazrul Study Centre established at RU</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nazrul-study-centre-established-at-ru</link><description>Rajshahi University (RU) has established a "Nazrul Study Centre" for the first time, with the aim of promoting the literature, music, and philosophy of National Poet Kazi Nazrul Islam.
RU Vice-Chancellor (VC) Professor Dr. Saleh Hasan Naqib inaugurated the centre on Monday at the university's Kazi</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 03:51:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>International confce highlights journalism’s role in South Asian peace and cooperation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/media/international-confce-highlights-journalisms-role-in-south-asian-peace-and-cooperation</link><description>Responsible journalism plays a crucial role in strengthening peace, trust and mutual cooperation among South Asian countries, speakers said at an international conference held in New Delhi.
The conference, titled “Role of Journalism in Peace Making and Cooperation in South Asian Countries,&amp;r</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 04:06:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ctg Bandar Rokkha Sangram Parishad coordinator detained</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ctg-bandar-rokkha-sangram-parishad-coordinator-detained</link><description>CHATTOGRAM, Feb 10: Police detained Md Ibrahim Khokon, the coordinator of the Chittagong Bandar Rokkha Sangram Parishad, on Tuesday, a day after protesters suspended an indefinite strike against the government's decision to lease the New Mooring Container Terminal (NCT) to DP World.
Md Ibrahim Kho</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 04:21:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘AL indirectly active in election’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/al-indirectly-active-in-election</link><description>Despite the Awami League's official decision not to contest the national election, the party continues to exert influence on the political landscape through indirect participation and disruptive activities, according to Transparency International Bangladesh (TIB).
Speaking amid ongoing debate over</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 04:36:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EU Mission deploys 90 short-term observers to monitor election day</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/eu-mission-deploys-90-short-term-observers-to-monitor-election-day</link><description>The European Union Election Observation Mission (EU EOM) has deployed observers to monitor election day proceedings across the country.
A total of 90 short-term observers (STOs) have been assigned across all 64 administrative districts.
They will monitor all stages of the election, including the</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 04:51:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC sets up media centre to facilitate election coverage</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ec-sets-up-media-centre-to-facilitate-election-coverage</link><description>The Bangladesh Election Commission (EC) has opened a dedicated media centre to help journalists cover the 13th Jatiya Sangsad (JS) election and the referendum.
Located at Hotel InterContinental Dhaka, the Media Centre will provide foreign journalists with necessary information and logistical suppo</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 05:06:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Voting access for citizens with disabilities overlooked’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/voting-access-for-citizens-with-disabilities-overlooked</link><description>As in previous elections, the 13th Jatiya Sangsad (JS) election is set to be held without extending voting rights to the country's hundreds of citizens with various disabilities, raising concerns about inclusiveness.
The Bangladesh Society for the Change and Advocacy Nexus (B-SCAN) revealed the fi</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 05:21:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>JS polls: Four-day holiday begins</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/js-polls-four-day-holiday-begins</link><description>A four-day holiday began on Wednesday as Bangladesh prepares for the 13th Parliamentary Election and the referendum scheduled for Feb 12.
The two-day government-declared general holiday on Feb 11 and 12, combined with the weekly holidays on Friday and Saturday (Feb 13 and 14), has created a four-d</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 05:36:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Election materials heading to polling centres Wednesday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/election-materials-heading-to-polling-centres-wednesday</link><description>Voting materials, including ballot papers, will be dispatched to polling stations on Wednesday ahead of the parliamentary election and the referendum.
Election Commissioner Abul Fazl Md Sanaullah detailed the commission’s final preparations, stating that the law and order situation is "bette</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 05:51:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>800,000 officials to remain on election duty: EC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/800000-officials-to-remain-on-election-duty-ec</link><description>About 800,000 officials will be engaged in election duty in the 13th parliamentary elections and referendum to be held tomorrow.
According to the Election Commission (EC), a total of 69 returning officers and 598 assistant returning officers will remain on duty during the polls.
Voting will take</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 06:21:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DU races to promote 207 assistant registrars before VC's departure</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/du-races-to-promote-207-assistant-registrars-before-vcs-departure</link><description>The Dhaka University administration has moved to promote more than 200 assistant registrars to the rank of deputy registrar in an "unprecedented" step.
Both the vice-chancellor and the registrar have acknowledged that such a large-scale promotion move has never taken place at once at the universit</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 06:36:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>394 international observers, 197 foreign journalists to monitor polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/394-international-observers-197-foreign-journalists-to-monitor-polls</link><description>At least 394 international election observers and 197 foreign journalists have arrived in Bangladesh to observe the 13th general election and the referendum on the July National Charter, both scheduled to be held on Thursday.
Of the international observers, 80 represent various international organ</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 06:51:51 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>