<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 10:21:33 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>CID file money laundering case against Noor Ali, 13 others</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/cid-file-money-laundering-case-against-noor-ali-13-others</link><description>The Criminal Investigation Department (CID) have filed a money laundering case against Unique Eastern Private Limited owner Noor Ali and 13 others for organised extortion of over Tk 400 million.
Bdnews24.com, citing a press statement issued on Monday, stated that initial evidence of fraud amountin</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 07:44:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UK reaffirms support for free, fair and credible elections in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/uk-supports-free-fair-and-credible-elections-in-bangladesh-next-year-sarah-cooke</link><description>British High Commissioner to Bangladesh Sarah Cooke on Monday reaffirmed the United Kingdom’s support for free, fair, credible, and peaceful elections in Bangladesh in 2026.
“I reaffirmed the UK's support for free, fair, credible and peaceful elections here in Bangladesh next year,&amp;rdq</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 08:14:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New York Mayor Eric Adams drops re-election bid</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/new-york-mayor-eric-adams-drops-re-election-bid</link><description>Embattled New York City Mayor Eric Adams, who has faced a federal bribery indictment and stunningly low approval ratings as the leader of the nation's largest city, dropped his bid on Sunday for a second term.
His departure from the race, a little more than a month before Election Day, leaves the</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 08:29:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Iran executes 'one of most important spies' for Israel</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/iran-executes-one-of-most-important-spies-for-israel</link><description>Iran executed a man named Bahman Choubi-asl on Monday, the judiciary's news outlet Mizan said, saying the defendant was "one of the most important spies for Israel in Iran".
Entangled in a decades-long shadow war with Israel, Iran has executed many individuals it accuses of having links with Israe</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 07:52:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh Shines at the Open World Astronomy Olympiad with a Gold Medal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/youth-and-entrepreneurship/bangladesh-shines-at-the-open-world-astronomy-olympiad-with-a-gold-medal</link><description>The 4th Open World Astronomy Olympiad concluded with the participation of 90 contestants from 20 countries, both in person and online. 
A six-member team from Bangladesh proudly represented the country and brought home remarkable success. The Olympiad was organised by the Russian Ministry of Educa</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 08:22:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ADB, Bangladesh sign $269.1m loan, $62.6m grant agreements</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/adb-bangladesh-sign-2691m-loan-626m-grant-agreements</link><description>The Asian Development Bank (ADB) and Bangladesh on Monday signed agreements worth $269.1 million in loans and $62.6 million in grants to support water supply, power distribution, and displaced people from Myanmar.
The signing ceremony was held at the Economic Relations Division (ERD) Conference Ro</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 08:37:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Home adviser points to ‘Indian instigation’ in fuelling Khagrachhari unrest</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/home-adviser-points-to-indian-instigation-in-fuelling-khagrachhari-unrest</link><description>Home Affairs Adviser Jahangir Alam Chowdhury has lent weight to suggestions that “Indian instigation” may be behind the ongoing unrest in Khagrachhari, sparked by the alleged gang rape of a Marma schoolgirl last week.
Speaking to reporters in Dhaka on Monday, he was asked about allegat</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 08:52:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Education boards aim to publish HSC results 'by Oct 19'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/education-boards-aim-to-publish-hsc-results-by-oct-19</link><description>Education boards are targeting Oct 19 for the release of this year’s Higher Secondary Certificate (HSC) and equivalent exam results.
The evaluation of answer scripts is ongoing, according to Prof SM Kamal Uddin Haider, exam controller of the Dhaka Secondary and Higher Secondary Education Boa</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 09:07:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Five new products to be included in TCB sales from Nov: Commerce Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/five-new-products-to-be-included-in-tcb-sales-from-nov-commerce-adviser</link><description>Trading Corporation of Bangladesh (TCB) is set to add five more products, including tea and salt, from November, said Commerce Adviser Sk. Bashir Uddin on Monday.
"The inclusion of five new products in TCB's ongoing sales programme will provide further relief to low-income families and contribute</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 09:37:17 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>