<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 10:21:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Stocks see downward trend at opening</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/stocks-see-downward-trend-at-opening-15329</link><description>Trading at both the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) and the Chittagong Stock Exchange (CSE) opened on a downward trend on Sunday, with most listed companies seeing a decline in share prices during the first hour.
On the DSE, the benchmark DSEX index slipped by 7 points, while the Shariah-based DSES she</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 06:39:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Commonwealth chief meets CEC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/commonwealth-chief-meets-cec</link><description>Commonwealth Secretary General Shirley Botchwey has held talks with Chief Election Commissioner AMM Nasir Uddin as preparations intensify for Bangladesh's upcoming parliamentary elections and referendum.
The meeting took place at the Election Commission (EC) headquarters in Dhaka’s Agargaon</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 06:54:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Clash at Titumir College over hanging of Shibir banner</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/clash-at-titumir-college-over-hanging-of-shibir-banner</link><description>Several people have reportedly been injured in a clash between two sides over the hanging of an Islami Chhatra Shibir banner at Dhaka’s Government Titumir College.
The clash broke out around midnight on Saturday, but the situation has now returned to normal, Rasel Sarwar, chief of Banani Pol</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 07:50:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Grameen Bank office set on fire in Kushtia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/grameen-bank-office-set-on-fire-in-kushtia</link><description>Miscreants set fire to a Grameen Bank office by pouring petrol on PTI Road in Kushtia district headquarters on Saturday night.
The fire damaged parts of the signboard and the balcony grill but documents and materials inside the office remained unaffected.
The office is located near the residence</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 08:05:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Financial Instruments in the Banking Sector: Challenges and Way Forward</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/reviews/financial-instruments-in-the-banking-sector-challenges-and-way-forward</link><description>The accounting standards are sets of principles and guidelines required to follow in the recording of financial transactions and in the preparation and presentation of financial statements of any organisation. International Accounting Standards (IAS)/Financial Reporting Standards (IFRS) are adopted</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 08:20:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>5.3 magnitude earthquake jolts Myanmar coast</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/53-magnitude-earthquake-jolts-myanmar-coast</link><description>A 5.3-magnitude earthquake struck off the coast of Myanmar at 10:39 am (Bangladesh time) on Sunday at a depth of 10km. The tremor also affected neighbouring Thailand.
According to the United States Geological Survey (USGS), the epicentre was located in the Andaman Sea, about 267 kilometres west-so</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 08:50:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh seal 217-run win over Ireland to complete series whitewash</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/cricket/bangladesh-seal-217-run-win-over-ireland-to-complete-series-whitewash</link><description>Bangladesh clinched a dominant 217-run victory over Ireland in the second Test in Mirpur, sealing a 2-0 series whitewash.
Chasing an improbable target of 509, Ireland were bowled out for 291 on Sunday despite a dogged 259-ball 71 from Curtis Campher, who held firm even as wickets tumbled around hi</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 09:20:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP leader Zainul Abedin urges India to return Hasina</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-leader-zainul-abedin-urges-india-to-return-hasina</link><description>BNP Chairperson’s Advisory Council member Zainul Abedin Farroque on Sunday urged India to immediately return deposed Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina to Bangladesh under the existing extradition treaty to uphold the agreement and maintain friendly bilateral relations.
“The International Cr</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 09:51:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Abu Shadat Mohammad Shahin new MD of IIDFC PLC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/abu-shadat-mohammad-shahin-new-md-of-iidfc-plc</link><description>Mr. Abu Shadat Mohammad Shahin was recently appointed as the Managing Director (MD), of IIDFC PLC.
He has 25 years of distinguished experience in the banking and financial sector and recognized for his strategic leadership and in-depth industry expertise, according to a media release. 
He be</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 10:06:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mob lynches suspected robber in Pirojpur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/mob-lynches-suspected-robber-in-pirojpur</link><description>Locals have beaten a man suspected of being a robber to death in Pirojpur’s Sadar Upazila.
Another person has been injured in the incident.
The incident took place around 1:30am on Sunday in Paschim Durgapur village of the Upazila, said Pirojpur Sadar Police Station chief (OC) Rabiul Islam.</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 10:21:21 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>