<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 10:28:35 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Five held over alleged extortion-linked attack on Dhaka embroidery factory</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/five-held-over-alleged-extortion-linked-attack-on-dhaka-embroidery-factory</link><description>Five people have been arrested over an attack on an embroidery factory in Dhaka’s Adabor after workers surrounded the local police station at midnight, demanding action.
Adabor Police Station chief (OC) Abdul Malek said the factory owner, Mustafizur Rahman, filed a case naming eight people</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 07:45:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>PM chairs meeting on Dhaka airport's third terminal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/pm-chairs-meeting-on-dhaka-airports-third-terminal</link><description>Prime Minister Tarique Rahman has chaired a meeting on the long-delayed third terminal at Dhaka's Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport, with a focus on bringing the facility into operation as quickly as possible.
The meeting began on Sunday afternoon at the Secretariat, according to bdnews24.com</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 08:00:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Veteran journalist Saleem Samad passes away</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/veteran-journalist-saleem-samad-passes-away</link><description>Saleem Samad, an award-winning investigative journalist, writer and media rights defender, died at his residence in the capital on Sunday.
Saleem, also a member of the Jatiya Press Club, was Special Correspondent of English dailies The News Times, The Bangladesh Observer and The Asian Age.
His fi</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 07:45:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How information on social media shapes our thoughts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/others/how-information-on-social-media-shapes-our-thoughts</link><description>Human beings can't live without being affected by its surrounding, people, institutions, culture, technology, beliefs, and religious values; the practices, habits, and norms they inherit are derived from these. 
The information we learn, practice, and hold to thrive comes from institutions, religi</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 08:00:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DU VC Professor Niaz Ahmed Khan resigns</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/du-vc-professor-niaz-ahmed-khan-resigns</link><description>Dhaka University (DU) Vice-Chancellor Professor Dr Niaz Ahmed Khan has resigned from his post.He formally handed over the resignation letter to Education Minister ANM Ehsanul Haq Milon on Saturday (February 22). According to sources, he stepped down from his post citing personal and administrative</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 08:15:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Complaints lodged with ACC over ‘irregularities’ in foreign concession deals at Ctg port</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/complaints-lodged-with-acc-over-irregularities-in-foreign-concession-deals-at-ctg-port</link><description>Three complaints have been filed with the Anti-Corruption Commission(ACC), seeking an investigation into alleged irregularities and corruption in leasing key terminals of the Chattogram Port to foreign companies under concession agreements.
Md Al Amin Hossain, spokesperson of civil society organis</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 08:30:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Food we return to when life becomes tough</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/food/food-we-return-to-when-life-becomes-tough</link><description>In Bangladesh, comfort does not come on a silver spoon. It does not require coverage and buzz on the internet. It is more usually served and quietly eaten alongside a heap of hot rice, a ladle of dal, a spoonful of bhorta, maybe a fried chilli on the side. 
These are the foods people reach for whe</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 08:45:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two sentenced to death over 2023 murder of Tejgaon College student</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/two-sentenced-to-death-over-2023-murder-of-tejgaon-college-student</link><description>A Dhaka court has sentenced two men to death for the murder of Tejgaon College student Ikram Hossain Molla in 2023.
Dhaka Metropolitan Sessions Judge Md Sabbir Fayez delivered the verdict on Sunday, according to court official Md Riaz Hossain.
The convicts are Shanto Mia, a friend of the victim,</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 09:00:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How YouTubers are redefining filmmaking</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/entertainment/how-youtubers-are-redefining-filmmaking</link><description>The idea of a movie created by a YouTuber was considered something to look down on for a long time. It meant the movie would have terrible production values, shallow stories, and exist only to generate clicks, not to make good films.
But movies like Chris Stuckmann's Shelby Oaks and Markiplier's I</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 09:16:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two to walk gallows for killing Tejgaon College student Ekram</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/two-to-walk-gallows-for-killing-tejgaon-college-student-ekram</link><description>A Dhaka court on Sunday convicted and sentenced two people to death in a case lodged over the murder of Tejgaon College student Ekram Hossain Mollah in 2023.
The two death-row-convicts are Md Siddik and Md Shanto Miah.
Judge Md Sabbir Faiz of Dhaka Metropolitan Sessions Judge Court pronounced the</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 09:31:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>586 killed in road accidents across Bangladesh in January: report</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/586-killed-in-road-accidents-across-bangladesh-in-january-report</link><description>A total of 586 people have been killed and 1,238 injured in 597 transport accidents across Bangladesh in January, according to the Bangladesh Passenger Welfare Association.
The group disclosed the information in a press release on Sunday, saying the report was prepared based on accident news publi</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 09:46:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Saudi Arabia issues 1.4m visas for Bangladeshis, 750,000 for work</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/saudi-arabia-issues-14m-visas-for-bangladeshis-750000-for-work</link><description>Saudi Ambassador to Bangladesh Dr Abdullah Zafer H. bin Abiyah on Sunday stated that his country has issued 750,000 work visas and a total of 1.4 million visas for Bangladeshi citizens in 2025.
"There is scope for skilled and semi-skilled workers to find jobs in the Kingdom as many development wor</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 10:01:02 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>