<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 07:19:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Include anti-discrimination pledges in upcoming poll manifestos</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/include-anti-discrimination-pledges-in-upcoming-poll-manifestos</link><description>Economist Dr Debapriya Bhattacharya has urged all political parties to include firm anti-discrimination commitments in their forthcoming election manifestos and called for the enactment of a comprehensive anti-discrimination law.
"Without legal protection, fair justice, free and credible elections</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 01:15:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Internet banking transactions surge 47.5pc in Aug</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/internet-banking-transactions-surge-475pc-in-aug</link><description>Internet banking transactions in Bangladesh posted a robust growth of about 47.5 per cent year-on-year in August 2025, reaching Tk 1.12 trillion from Tk 759.39 billion in the same month of 2024, according to the latest data from the Bangladesh Bank (BB).
Although the August figure was slightly l</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 01:30:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UN chief urges faster shift to renewables to avoid climate disaster</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/un-chief-urges-faster-shift-to-renewables-to-avoid-climate-disaster</link><description>United Nations Secretary-General António Guterres has warned that the global energy landscape is changing at lightning speed, with renewable energy leading the way.
Speaking at the Energy Transition Roundtable during the Belém Climate Summit on November 7, he said last year 90 per</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 01:45:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>PROPOSED TELECOM LICENSING POLICY:  Stakeholders fear foreign dominance, rise in internet prices</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/proposed-telecom-licensing-policy-stakeholders-fear-foreign-dominance-rise-in-internet-prices</link><description>Speakers at a discussion on Saturday warned that the proposed telecom licensing policy could undermine domestic entrepreneurs, restore foreign dominance, and sharply raise internet prices.
They urged the government to review the draft guidelines, currently being prepared by the Bangladesh Teleco</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 02:00:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Experts push for discounted shares for general investors</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/experts-push-for-discounted-shares-for-general-investors</link><description>As the central bank moves forward with the merger of five troubled Islamic banks, general shareholders of these listed banks should either be offered shares of the merged entity or allowed to subscribe to its shares at a discounted price.
This view has been voiced by market experts as well as of</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 02:15:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka, Khulna among 15 districts that get new DCs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dhaka-khulna-among-15-districts-that-get-new-dcs</link><description>With the national election drawing near, the government has appointed new deputy commissioners (DCs) in 15 districts, including Dhaka, Khulna, and Bogura, transferring seven incumbents and assigning eight new officials to the posts.
The Ministry of Public Administration issued a notification late</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 04:53:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India's CVD probe into BD jute product imports faces setback</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/indias-cvd-probe-into-bd-jute-product-imports-faces-setback</link><description>India's investigation into imposing a countervailing duty (CVD) on Bangladeshi jute product imports has hit a procedural snag, with Bangladesh seeking an extra 30 days to submit its questionnaire responses, sources said.
The commerce ministry has requested the Bangladesh High Commission in New Del</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 05:08:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Lessons from Zohran's playbook for young leaders</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/article/lessons-from-zohrans-playbook-for-young-leaders</link><description>Do you ever look at the way things are and think, "There has to be a better way"? That feeling is the starting point for real change. The story of Zohran Mamdani is a powerful example. It is not a political story but a lesson in leadership for any young people with a vision. It shows how you can br</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 05:23:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The rise of micro-influencers in a post-TV world</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/article/the-rise-of-micro-influencers-in-a-post-tv-world</link><description>The days of catchy television jingles and glossy newspaper advertisements pulling in crowds are long gone. Today's consumers scroll endlessly, swipe constantly, and ignore traditional ads faster than ever, creating a massive shift in how marketing works. With digital platforms like YouTube, Faceboo</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 05:38:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ADB urges completion of stalled BRT project</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/adb-urges-completion-of-stalled-brt-project</link><description>Development partners of the Bus Rapid Transit (BRT) project have urged the government to complete the long-delayed 20.5-kilometre dedicated bus corridor, highlighting its wider benefits for urban mobility and its strong economic potential.
They argue that with over US$250 million already disbursed</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 05:53:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Formation of electoral administration kicks off with DC reshuffle</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/formation-of-electoral-administration-kicks-off-with-dc-reshuffle</link><description>The Election Commission is focusing on the field administration as it prepares for the 13th general elections. As part of the effort, deputy commissioners of 15 districts, including Dhaka, have been changed.
Election Commissioner Md Anwarul Islam Sarkar said on Sunday, "In order to create a level</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 06:08:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt laid foundation for promising new chapter in Bangladesh-US relations: Shafiqul Alam</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-laid-foundation-for-promising-new-chapter-in-bangladesh-us-relations-shafiqul-alam</link><description>Chief Adviser’s Press Secretary Shafiqul Alam on Sunday said one of the major accomplishments of their foreign policy over the past 15 months has been establishing strong relations with the US agricultural economy and the farm lobby.
"The interim government has laid the foundation for this p</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 06:23:40 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>