<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 15:22:26 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>15 injured in BNP-Gono Odhikar clash in Patuakhali's Galachipa</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/15-injured-in-bnp-gono-odhikar-clash-in-patuakhalis-galachipa</link><description>At least 15 people, including a woman, were injured in a clash between supporters of the BNP and Gono Odhikar Parishad in Galachipa upazila of Patuakhali district on Thursday night.
The incident occurred around 9:00 pm at Dakshin Kupalbera intersection in Charshiba village under Charkazal union, a</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 10:58:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ansar member dismissed over mobile phone theft at Dhaka airport's cargo complex</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ansar-member-dismissed-over-mobile-phone-theft-at-dhaka-airports-cargo-complex</link><description>An Ansar member has been expelled from the force on charges of stealing mobile phones from the cargo complex at Dhaka's Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport.
The expulsion of Zenarul Islam, a uniformed member of the auxiliary force, was announced in a statement issued by the Ansar Headquarters</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 11:13:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India sets up Army base, military station along Bangladesh border</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/india-sets-up-army-base-military-station-along-bangladesh-border</link><description>The Indian Army has operationalised a new military base in West Bengal’s North Dinajpur and is raising a new military station in Assam’s Dhubri to reinforce its capacity along the border with Bangladesh, reports the Deccan Chronicle.
The Hyderabad-based English language daily reported</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 12:06:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh to move towards election through legal basis of July Charter, says Nahid</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bangladesh-to-move-towards-election-through-legal-basis-of-july-charter-says-nahid</link><description>Bangladesh will move towards elections through a legal basis of the July Charter containing state reform initiatives, says National Citizen Party (NCP) Convener Nahid Islam.
He said, “Muhammad Yunus must issue the order of the July Charter from the point of the mass uprising. July Charter sh</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 12:21:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BB issues draft regulation for payment system operators</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/bb-issues-draft-regulation-for-payment-system-operators</link><description>Bangladesh Bank (BB) has published the draft 'Payment System Operator (PSO) Regulation 2025'.
This move is set to integrate the regulation with the existing Payment and Settlement Systems Act, 2024.
The central bank recently published the draft regulation seeking public feedback. After consultati</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 12:14:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Kushtia woman ‘strangles daughter to death, kills herself’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/kushtia-woman-strangles-daughter-to-death-kills-herself</link><description>A woman struggling in poverty has reportedly strangled her two-and-a-half-year-old daughter to death using a rope before dying by suicide in Kushtia’s Daulatpur.
The incident is said to have happened around 7pm on Thursday in Insafnagar village in Ramkrishnapur Union.
Police and locals say</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 12:29:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Britain removes sanctions on Syria's president ahead of his meeting with Trump</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/britain-removes-sanctions-on-syrias-president-ahead-of-his-meeting-with-trump</link><description>Britain removed sanctions on Syrian President Ahmad al-Sharaa on Friday, after the United Nations Security Council did the same ahead of his meeting with US President Donald Trump next week.
Britain said in a notice on the government's website that it was also lifting sanctions on Syria's interior</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 12:44:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fakhrul accuses government of creating a situation to delay polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/fakhrul-accuses-government-of-creating-a-situation-to-delay-polls</link><description>BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir on Friday accused the interim government of creating a situation over the implementation of the July National Charter with the intention of delaying the national election.
Speaking before inaugurating the party’s rally marking National Revolu</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 12:59:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Blasts injure dozens at Indonesian mosque, student suspected</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/blasts-injure-dozens-at-indonesian-mosque-student-suspected</link><description>Explosions at a mosque in Indonesia's capital Jakarta that injured dozens of people during Friday prayers could have been an attack, officials indicated, with a 17-year-old student identified as the suspected perpetrator.
Police said 55 people were in hospitals with a range of minor to serious inj</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 13:14:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fisherman dies over net casting clash in Sirajganj</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/fisherman-dies-over-net-casting-clash-in-sirajganj</link><description>A fisherman has died after allegedly being beaten by fellow fishermen during a dispute over net casting in Sirajganj.
The incident took place early on Friday in the Gohala River, said Shahjadpur Police chief Md Aslam Ali.
The dead has been identified as Bimal alias Tetul Hawlader, 60.
One of his</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 13:29:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Revolution of 1975 and July uprising stemmed from same context: Asif Mahmud</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/revolution-of-1975-and-july-uprising-stemmed-from-same-context-asif-mahmud</link><description>Youth and Sports Adviser Asif Mahmud Shojib Bhuiyan on Friday said that the Sepoy-People's Revolution of 1975 and the July Uprising of 2024 emerged from the same socio-political context.
"The context of the Sepoy-People's Revolution of 1975 is quite similar to that of the July Uprising of 2024. In</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 14:25:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP suspends three Sitakunda leaders</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-suspends-three-sitakunda-leaders</link><description>BNP has suspended three of its leaders in Sitakunda, Chattogram, over allegations of violating party discipline.
In a press release issued on Friday, signed by party Senior Joint Secretary General Ruhul Kabir Rizvi, the BNP said the action was taken for activities that went against the party&amp;rsquo</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 14:40:35 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>