<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 20:25:26 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Tarique Rahman, family convey greetings to chief adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-rahman-family-convey-greetings-to-chief-adviser</link><description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman and his family on Saturday conveyed greetings to Chief Adviser Professor Dr Muhammad Yunus.
On behalf of Tarique Rahman, his wife Dr Zubaida Rahman and their daughter Barrister Zaima Rahman, BNP Chairman’s Private Secretary ABM Abdus Sattar presented a flor</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 15:22:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCP threatens protests over dual citizens</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ncp-threatens-protests-over-dual-citizens</link><description>The National Citizen Party (NCP) has warned it will take to the streets if dual citizens are allowed to contest in the parliamentary polls.
Labelling Sunday, the final day of the EC’s appeal hearings, as a “red line”, NCP cautioned that any attempt to let dual citizens or loan de</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 16:11:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Badiul Alam Majumdar withdraws remarks on journalists amid backlash</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/badiul-alam-majumdar-withdraws-remarks-on-journalists-amid-backlash</link><description>Shushashoner Jonno Nagorik (SHUJAN) Secretary Dr Badiul Alam Majumdar on Friday night withdrew controversial remarks about journalists following strong protests from local media professionals.
Dr Badiul came under criticism after he allegedly referred to journalists as “pet dogs of political</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 16:26:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ICC and BCB hold talks over potential group changes for Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/icc-and-bcb-hold-talks-over-potential-group-changes-for-bangladesh</link><description>Recent discussions between representatives from the International Cricket Council (ICC) and the Bangladesh Cricket Board (BCB) have revisited long-standing issues.
But with one notable development, the possibility of changing Bangladesh’s group to minimise logistical challenges was formally</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 16:45:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bhasan Char declared part of Sandwip</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bhasan-char-taken-out-of-hatia-placed-under-sandwip-land-ministry</link><description>The land ministry has decided that six Mouzas of Bhasan Char will fall under Sandwip Upazila of Chattogram, not Hatia in Noakhali.
On Saturday, the ministry issued instructions to the Chattogram divisional commissioner to take necessary steps to implement the decision.
Sandwip Upazila administrat</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 17:00:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>British high commissioner meets BNP chief Tarique Rahman in Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/british-high-commissioner-meets-bnp-chief-tarique-rahman-in-dhaka</link><description>British High Commissioner to Bangladesh Sarah Catherine Cook has met BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman at the party’s Gulshan office.
BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir, Standing Committee member Amir Khosru Mahmud Chowdhury, Joint Secretary General Humayun Kabir, Chairman’s A</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 17:15:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Indonesia searching for missing surveillance plane with 11 onboard</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/indonesia-searching-for-missing-surveillance-plane-with-11-onboard</link><description>Indonesian rescuers were searching on Saturday for an ATR 42-500 fisheries surveillance aircraft that went missing with 11 people on board, officials said.
The Indonesia Air Transport plane lost contact with air traffic control at about 1:30pm (0530 GMT) around Maros region in South Sulawesi provi</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 17:30:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique turns emotional as children of disappeared BNP activists recount years of waiting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-turns-emotional-as-children-of-disappeared-bnp-activists-recount-years-of-waiting</link><description>BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman struggled to hold back his emotions on Saturday as children of several BNP leaders and activists, who became victims of enforced disappearance, broke down in tears while recalling years of waiting for their missing fathers.
The scene unfolded at the Bangladesh-China Fri</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 19:00:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tech push, buyer taste reshaping Bangladesh's apparel industry</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/tech-push-buyer-taste-reshaping-bangladeshs-apparel-industry</link><description>Apparel exporters are accelerating investment in advanced technologies to modernise production, raise productivity and strengthen long-term sustainability and global competitiveness Bangladesh's ready-made garment (RMG) industry in the fast-changing economic milieus.
From automation and robotics t</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 19:15:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>U-19 World Cup: Bangladesh lose to India despite Al Fahad five-wicket haul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/u-19-world-cup-al-fahads-five-for-in-vain-as-bangladesh-collapse-from-winning-position-against-india</link><description>In a contest dripping with tension, rain delays, and shifting equations, India U-19 held their nerve to defeat Bangladesh U-19 by 18 runs (DLS method) in a thrilling Group B encounter of the ICC Men’s Under-19 World Cup at the Queens Sports Club.
Al Fahad of Bangladesh bagged five wickets, b</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 19:30:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Iraq takes full control of air base after US withdrawal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/iraq-takes-full-control-of-air-base-after-us-withdrawal-defence-ministry-says</link><description>US forces have withdrawn from Iraq's Ain al-Asad Airbase, which housed US-led forces in Western Iraq, and the Iraqi army has assumed full control, the Iraqi defence ministry said on Saturday.
In 2024, Washington and Baghdad reached an understanding on plans for the withdrawal of US-led coalition f</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 19:45:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump vows tariffs on eight European nations over Greenland</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-vows-tariffs-on-eight-european-nations-over-greenland</link><description>President Donald Trump on Saturday vowed to implement a wave of increasing tariffs on European allies until the United States is allowed to buy Greenland, escalating a row over the future of Denmark's vast Arctic island.
In a post on Truth Social, Trump said additional 10 per cent import tariffs w</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 20:00:44 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>