<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 03:08:52 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Unleashing the youth dividend in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/unleashing-the-youth-dividend-in-bangladesh</link><description>Despite these challenges, it is clear that this is a momentous point in Bangladeshi history. This is because it is a country which is situated at a critical point in its national journey. Indeed, with a significant percentage, which is nearly 65 per cent of its population aged below 35, it is one o</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 18:04:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ensuring smooth walking for pedestrians</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/ensuring-smooth-walking-for-pedestrians</link><description>Around two-fifths of the daily commuters in Dhaka walk to reach their destinations, whereas the ratio was one-fifth two decades ago. The data are impressive, no doubt, especially since the city is not particularly conducive to smooth walking. There is a lack of safe, accessible and efficient infras</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 18:19:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>When climate crisis meets corruption</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/when-climate-crisis-meets-corruption</link><description>Bangladesh stands among the world's most climate-vulnerable nations, not only in statistical rankings but in the lived experience of millions. The country has entered an era in which the scale and frequency of natural disasters can no longer be predicted within familiar seasonal or geographical pat</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 18:34:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Poverty rising, jobs squeezing, social parameters worsening</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/poverty-rising-jobs-squeezing-social-parameters-worsening</link><description>Poverty is rising, employment shrinking and key social indicators in Bangladesh are deteriorating, says a presentation at an international meet in Dhaka about a setback on the national economic front and its spillovers.



Despite these negative trends, however, people of Bangladesh have not</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 18:49:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Stimulating investment in blue economy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/stimulating-investment-in-blue-economy</link><description>The size of the investment that the formal lending institutions, that is, banks, have already made or are willing to make in a particular sector of the economy is indicative of the particular sector's importance in the economy. From that perspective, the blue economy does not seem to play a substan</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 19:04:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>After IMF, JICA also opts to deal with political govt</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/after-imf-jica-also-opts-to-deal-with-political-govt</link><description>Japanese financier JICA follows IMF footprint as it also now tags consultation with Bangladesh's upcoming political government to budget bankrolling as the national elections are in sight for transition from the interregnum.
Officials say the Japan International Cooperation Agency (JICA) has recen</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 01:19:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>'Free trade access to largest market mostly missed, remedies overlooked'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/free-trade-access-to-largest-market-mostly-missed-remedies-overlooked</link><description>Bangladesh miserably fails to avail the enormous opportunities the world's largest market, China, has offered, mainly due to a deep-seated crisis in product diversification, competitiveness, and inept strategic execution, experts say.
China has granted Bangladesh zero-tariff entry for 98 per cent</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 01:34:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh-China sea trade thrives on rare 'empty box' model</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladesh-china-sea-trade-thrives-on-rare-empty-box-model</link><description>Bangladesh's ocean-going trade with China is expanding at an unexpectedly rapid pace despite a striking overall imbalance with the volume of shipments bound for China being very low.
The model is so unusual that shipping executives describe it as a rare exception to industry norms.
Yet, carriers</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 01:49:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCC finds ambiguities in July Charter order, seeks clarification</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ncc-finds-ambiguities-in-july-charter-order-seeks-clarification</link><description>National Citizen Party (NCP) member-secretary Akhtar Hossain has urged the government to immediately clarify the July Charter Implementation Order, saying that several ambiguities in the directive have already created confusion.
He says a lack of clarity has led to a crisis, and the government sho</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 02:04:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DMTCL looks for new financier for Diabari-Tongi section</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/dmtcl-looks-for-new-financier-for-diabari-tongi-section</link><description>The Dhaka Metro Rail Company is seeking a new financier for developing another extension of the under-operation metro rail from Diabari to Tongi although Japan has already supported development of the existing 21.7-km corridor.
According to sources, the Dhaka Mass Transit Company Limited (DMTCL) h</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 02:19:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh may be among worst sufferers of heat stress</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/bangladesh-may-be-among-worst-sufferers-of-heat-stress</link><description>Bangladesh may become one of the worst sufferers of heat stress, as Dhaka's temperature has risen by nearly 6°C over the last decade, far exceeding the global threshold of 1.5°C, experts warned.
The economic losses due to heat is projected to increase to US$2,400 billion in 2030, with the</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 02:34:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Resetting Dhaka's overhead electric cables underground stalls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/resetting-dhakas-overhead-electric-cables-underground-stalls</link><description>Shifting Dhaka's dangerously dangling overhead power-distribution-network cables underground remains stalled as two Japanese-funded projects worth around Tk 19.01 billion face rollback after prolonged dithering, sources say.
The projects were initiated under Power Division of the government nearly</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 02:49:04 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>