<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 18:35:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Modi’s effigy burnt at Dhaka University</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dhaka-university-students-burn-effigy-of-indian-pm-narendra-modi</link><description>A group of students at Dhaka University has burnt the effigy of Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi.
The students said they are against “aggression” and oppose India’s “intervention” and action to “tarnish Victory Day’s image”.
Shouting slogans such</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 15:44:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka University celebrates Victory Day with songs, films, plays</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dhaka-university-celebrates-victory-day-with-songs-films-plays</link><description>Dhaka University has marked Victory Day with songs, films, plays and illuminated landmarks across the campus, celebrating the spirit of the 1971 Liberation War.
On Tuesday, throughout the campus, memoirs, photographs and visual displays reflected the history of sacrifice that shaped Bangladesh&amp;rsq</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 15:59:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Police seek to interrogate Subrata Bain’s daughter</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jubo-dal-leader-murder-police-seek-to-interrogate-subrata-bains-daughter</link><description>Police have sought a week to question gangster Subrata Bain’s daughter in their custody in the murder case of Jubo Dal leader Arif Sikder.
The court of Dhaka Metropolitan Magistrate Hasibuzzaman has fixed Thursday to hear the remand petition filed on Tuesday by Mazharul Islam, an inspector a</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 16:14:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mustafizur becomes most expensive Bangladeshi at IPL auction</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/mustafizur-becomes-most-expensive-bangladeshi-at-ipl-auction</link><description>Bangladesh left-arm fast bowler Mustafizur Rahman became the most expensive Bangladeshi player in Indian Premier League (IPL) history on Tuesday after Kolkata Knight Riders secured his services for 9.20 crore rupees at the IPL auction.  Mustafizur, who had a base price of 2 crore, attract</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 16:29:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>President hosts Victory Day reception</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/president-shahabuddin-honours-liberation-war-heroes-their-families-at-victory-day-reception</link><description>President Mohammed Shahabuddin and his wife Rebecca Sultana have hosted a reception at Bangabhaban to mark Victory Day, honouring valiant freedom fighters and family members of the Bir Sreshtho.
The reception was held in the lawn outside Bangabhaban on Tuesday afternoon and was attended by advisor</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 16:44:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mujib Bahini’s ‘genocide’ triggered Pakistan’s ‘crackdown’: Jamaat leader</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jamaat-leader-nazrul-says-pakistans-crackdown-came-in-response-to-mujib-bahinis-genocide</link><description>The 1971 Liberation War was actually a “crackdown” by Pakistan on the "Mujib Bahini", which had carried out “genocide” prior to Mar 25, Jamaat-e-Islami’s Chattogram city chief Mohammad Nazrul Islam has said.
He also remarked that the intellectuals in Bangladesh were k</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 16:59:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP candidate show-caused over ‘breach’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bnp-candidate-ayub-show-caused-for-violating-electoral-code-in-jashore</link><description>BNP candidate show-caused over ‘breach’
The Election Commission (EC) has served a show-cause notice on TS Ayub, who secured a nomination from the BNP to run for parliament from the Jashore-4 constituency.
Bagharpara Upazila administrator (UNO) Bhupali Sarkar, who is also the assistant</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 17:14:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Victory Day celebrated nationwide with enthusiasm</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/as-ever-enthusiasm-marks-victory-day-celebrations-across-bangladesh</link><description>Bangladesh celebrated Victory Day on Tuesday with great enthusiasm, as people across the country paid homage to the martyrs of the Liberation War through ceremonies, rallies, and cultural programmes.
The celebration began with the traditional 31-gun salute ringing out across the capital at the bre</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 17:29:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Caricature of Ghulam Azam blotted out at Chittagong University</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/caricature-of-ghulam-azam-blotted-out-at-chittagong-university</link><description>A caricature of Ghulam Azam and Pro-Vice Chancellor Prof Shamim Uddin Khan, drawn by students in protest over controversial comments on Martyred Intellectuals Day, has been covered with black ink at Chittagong University.
The artwork, painted Monday outside the administrative building, was found b</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 17:44:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Balancing the scales</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/balancing-the-scales</link><description>In the serious tapestry of modern global economy, few issues are as pressing and complex as the intertwining of debt sustainability and climate financing demands. For developing nations, particularly those on the frontline of climate change, this issue has become a profound challenge that requires</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 18:00:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Clear vision changes lives</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/reviews/clear-vision-changes-lives</link><description>When we talk about healthcare and human rights, one vital aspect is often overlooked: vision. Eye care is not a niche concern-it is a fundamental component of health, productivity, and dignity. Imagine the daily challenges faced by someone who cannot see clearly: reduced productivity, limited earni</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 18:15:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CA vows to defend democratic transition</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ca-vows-to-defend-democratic-transition</link><description>As Bangladesh heads towards a landmark general election combined with constitutional referendum, scheduled for February, the head of interim government asserts that all "ill attempts of defeated forces" will be foiled to execute the country's post-uprising democratic transition.



In a natio</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 18:30:47 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>