<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 02:28:49 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Banking sector reform: a test for the new government</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/banking-sector-reform-a-test-for-the-new-government</link><description>The recent national election in Bangladesh has delivered a decisive political message. The Bangladesh Nationalist Party secured a huge majority. This is not an ordinary mandate. It reflects public frustration with economic instability and a strong desire for institutional reform. Voters have placed</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 18:19:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Market intervention: the case of TCB and OMS</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/market-intervention-the-case-of-tcb-and-oms</link><description>With the month of Ramadan fast approaching, the familiar annual spiral in the prices of essential commodities has already begun to make itself felt across the country, and with notable intensity.
Containing the seasonal and sporadic surges in the prices of daily necessities has long been a critica</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 18:34:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Overcoming tax reform challenges</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/overcoming-tax-reform-challenges</link><description>The Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) has taken the helm of the country at a time when the economy is caught on the horns of a fiscal dilemma. On the one hand, the new government has a plethora of election pledges to keep in areas such as infrastructure development, social welfare, education and h</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 18:49:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A new journey on course of democracy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/a-new-journey-on-course-of-democracy</link><description>Bangladesh has got a new government elected by the people in a largely clean and credible election. The Financial Express congratulates the new Prime Minister and the members of his Cabinet. That the people are pinning much hope on the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) is evident from the fact tha</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 19:04:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ramadan begins-</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ramadan-begins</link><description>The holy month of Ramadan began across the country today (Thursday) following the sighting of the new crescent moon on Wednesday evening.
The announcement was made after a meeting of the National Moon Sighting Committee at the conference room of Baitul Mukarram National Mosque in the capital, with</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 00:38:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Stabilising prices, smooth power supply, bettering law, order first</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/stabilising-prices-smooth-power-supply-bettering-law-order-first</link><description>Holding commodity prices in checks and uninterrupted electricity supply ahead of the fasting month Ramadan alongside bettering law-and-order situation come first in the priorities the new government set on the first day of its function.
Newly elected Prime Minister Tarique Rahman issued a slew of</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 00:53:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Days of 'patronage economy' over, finance minister says as new govt gets into function</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/days-of-patronage-economy-over-finance-minister-says-as-new-govt-gets-into-function</link><description>A priority need of the hour is democratisation of Bangladesh economy so that its benefits reach all the people, new Finance and Planning Minister Amir Khasru Mahmud Chowdhury said Wednesday
"We can't allow a patronage economy to continue," he told reporters at his Bangladesh secretariat office' as</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 01:08:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New govt to take steps to defer LDC graduation Says Commerce Minister Muktadir</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/new-govt-to-take-steps-to-defer-ldc-graduation-says-commerce-minister-muktadir</link><description>The new government will take initiatives to defer Bangladesh's graduation from the Least Developed Country (LDC) status, says Commerce, Industries, Textiles and Jute Minister Khandaker Abdul Muktadir.
Speaking to journalists at the secretariat on Wednesday, he said the government had already start</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 01:23:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Taka gains slight competitive relief</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/taka-gains-slight-competitive-relief</link><description>Bangladesh's exporters enjoyed a modest boost in December last as the country's real effective exchange rate (REER) edged down, easing pressure on the Taka and slightly improving its global competitiveness.
The latest central bank data suggest that while the currency remains somewhat overvalued, t</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 01:38:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Regulator urges compensation for shareholders before NBFI liquidation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/regulator-urges-compensation-for-shareholders-before-nbfi-liquidation</link><description>The securities regulator has sought a compensation package for investors before delisting the non-bank financial institutions (NBFIs) that are set to be liquidated.
A committee from the Bangladesh Securities and Exchange Commission (BSEC) met representatives of the central bank a few days before t</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 01:53:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Stocks extend slide as investors await policy signals from new govt</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/stocks-extend-slide-as-investors-await-policy-signals-from-new-govt</link><description>Stocks plunged for another session on Wednesday as investors cautiously assessed the potential policy direction and regulatory environment under the newly elected government.
The BNP-led government formed after oath-taking on Tuesday is yet to disclose any work plan regarding the capital market, s</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 02:08:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sub-branch loan growth outpaces banking sector average</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/sub-branch-loan-growth-outpaces-banking-sector-average</link><description>Outstanding loans and advances disbursed through sub-branches of scheduled banks recorded a notable rise in July-September 2025, outpacing overall growth in the banking sector, according to the latest data from Bangladesh Bank (BB).
Total outstanding loans through sub-branches increased from Tk 17</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 02:23:05 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>