<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 06:29:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Dollar soft as Sino-US trade tension weighs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/dollar-soft-as-sino-us-trade-tension-weighs</link><description>The US dollar slipped on Thursday as the Sino-US trade war sapped investor sentiment, while growing confidence of the US Federal Reserve cutting its policy interest rate this year also weighed on the greenback.
The euro rose 0.14% to $1.1664 in early trade, hitting a one-week high. The yen also fi</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 03:27:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Oil prices up 1pc</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/oil-prices-up-1pc</link><description>Oil prices rose by around 1% in early trade on Thursday after US President Donald Trump said Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi had pledged his country would stop buying oil from Russia, which supplies about one-third of its imports.
Brent crude futures rose 57 cents, or 0.9%, to $62.48 a barrel</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 03:57:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Modi assures India won’t buy Russian oil: Trump</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/global/modi-assures-india-wont-buy-russian-oil-trump</link><description>US President Donald Trump said on Wednesday that Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi told him that India will stop buying oil from Russia, a move Trump described as a “big step” in efforts to isolate Moscow economically.
“So I was not happy that India was buying oil, and he assur</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 04:12:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Farmer’s body recovered in Meherpur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/farmers-body-recovered-in-meherpur</link><description>The body of a farmer was recovered from a field in Gangni upazila of Meherpur district on Wednesday night.
The deceased was identified as Amir Ali, son of Salamat Ali from Halsanapara area of Harabhanga village, reports UNB.
According to his family, Amir Ali went to the field near Harabhanga Beel</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 04:27:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>United Airlines forecasts highest-ever quarterly revenue</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/global/united-airlines-forecasts-highest-ever-quarterly-revenue</link><description>United Airlines forecast stronger earnings in the current quarter on Wednesday as it expects rising travel demand and improved pricing power to produce the highest quarterly revenue in the company's history.
The Chicago-based airline expects an adjusted profit in the range of $3.00 to $3.50 per sh</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 04:57:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UN sees Bangladesh’s progress on disappearance accountability, urges fair trials</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/un-sees-bangladeshs-progress-on-disappearance-accountability-urges-fair-trials</link><description>UN Human Rights Chief Volker Türk has said the initiation of proceedings against those accused of carrying out enforced disappearances and torture under the previous government in Bangladesh was an important step towards accountability.
“I urge full respect for the most scrupulous stand</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 05:12:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>HSC result: 345 institutions achieve 100pc success</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hsc-result-345-institutions-achieve-100pc-success</link><description>A total of 345 educational institutions achieved 100 per cent pass rate in the Higher Secondary Certificate (HSC) and equivalent examinations-2025 across the country this year.
This information was revealed in the results published at 10 am today (Thursday), reports UNB. 
Last year, a total</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 05:27:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Weather may remain mainly dry</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/weather-may-remain-mainly-dry</link><description>The Bangladesh Meteorological Department (BMD) forecast the weather may remain mainly dry with partly cloudy sky across the country over the next 24 hours, beginning at 9:00 am today (Thursday). 
"Weather may remain mainly dry with partly cloudy sky across the country. But, light rain is like</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 05:57:43 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>