<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 14:43:20 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>BPPA submits its annual report to IMED</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bppa-submits-its-annual-report-to-imed</link><description>The Bangladesh Public Procurement Authority (BPPA) on Monday submitted its Annual Report for the fiscal year 2024–2025 to the Implementation Monitoring and Evaluation Division (IMED) in accordance with the provisions of the Bangladesh Public Procurement Authority Act, 2023 and the Right to In</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 11:23:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rizvi returns home from hospital</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/rizvi-returns-home-from-hospital</link><description>BNP Senior Joint Secretary General Ruhul Kabir Rizvi today (Monday) returned home after being discharged from hospital.
Rizvi was admitted to Square Hospital a few days ago with fever, cold and respiratory problems. He left the hospital this afternoon on the advice of doctors, Rizvi's personal ass</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 11:38:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ADP implementation rate at 5-year low</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/adp-implementation-rate-at-5-year-low</link><description>The Annual Development Programme (ADP) implementation rate has remained at a five-year low in the first seven months of the running fiscal year during the tenure of the interim government, continuing the trend observed over the past several months, according to the latest progress report.
Data rel</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 11:53:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt appoints five new DAGs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-appoints-five-new-dags</link><description>The government on Monday appointed five new Deputy Attorney Generals (DAGs) to represent the state in cases before the Appellate and High Court Divisions of the Supreme Court of Bangladesh.
The solicitor wing of the Ministry of Law, Justice and Parliamentary Affairs issued a gazette notification,</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 12:08:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two FE senior reporters among 12 journalists receive ERF-MRDI fellowship 2026</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/two-fe-senior-reporters-among-12-journalists-receive-erf-mrdi-fellowship-2026</link><description>Senior reporter of The Financial Express (FE) Mohammad Jubair Hasan received a fellowship under the category of bank and insurance sector, while FE senior reporter Rezaul Karim got the fellowship in the macroeconomic sector.


Ten other journalists who received fellowship are Rafikul Islam and S</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 12:23:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Power supply to be suspended in parts of Sylhet on Tuesday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/power-supply-to-be-suspended-in-parts-of-sylhet-on-tuesday</link><description>Power supply will be temporarily suspended in several key areas of Sylhet city on Tuesday due to transformer repair, renovation, and transmission line development work.
A press release on Monday, signed by the Executive Engineer of Sales and Distribution Division-3 of the Bangladesh Power Developm</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 12:38:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BGB brings back 73 fishers from Arakan Army custody via Teknaf</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bgb-brings-back-73-fishers-from-arakan-army-custody-via-teknaf</link><description>The Border Guard Bangladesh (BGB) has brought back 73 fishermen who had been held by the Arakan Army, Myanmar’s armed rebel group.
They were returned through the Jaliapara transit terminal in Teknaf around 4:30pm on Monday, said BGB Ramu Sector Commander Col Mohiuddin Ahmed.
Seven of those</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 12:53:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CEC Nasir to swear in MPs, Constitutional Council members</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cec-nasir-to-swear-in-mps-constitutional-council-members</link><description>Chief Election Commissioner AMM Nasir Uddin will administer the oaths to candidates elected in the parliamentary polls.
From 10am on Tuesday, members of parliament and the Constitutional Reform Council will take their oaths in phases before the CEC.
Election Commission Secretary Akhtar Ahmed conf</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 13:08:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DSE slips after previous surge, turnover declines</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/dse-slips-after-previous-surge-turnover-declines</link><description>The benchmark index of the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) fell on Monday, a day after a major rally, as most listed companies witnessed price erosion and overall turnover declined.
On the second trading day of the week, the DSEX, the prime index of the DSE, lost 11 points. The Shariah-based DSES dropp</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 13:23:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique Rahman meets IAB Ameer Rezaul Karim</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-rahman-meets-iab-ameer-rezaul-karim</link><description>BNP Chairman and Prime Minister-in-waiting Tarique Rahman paid a courtesy call on Pir and Islami Andolan Bangladesh (IAB) Ameer Syed Muhammad Rezaul Karim on Monday evening, just a day before forming the next government following his party’s landslide victory in Thursday’s national elec</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 13:38:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New office hours for banks and finance companies during Ramadan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/new-office-hours-for-banks-and-finance-companies-during-ramadan</link><description>Bangladesh Bank has rescheduled the office timings for all finance companies operating in observance of the upcoming holy month of Ramadan.
According to a circular issued by the Department of Financial Institutions and Markets (DFIM) on Monday, the new office timings to accommodate employees and c</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 13:53:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Maldives President to attend Tarique Rahman’s swearing-in ceremony</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/maldives-president-to-attend-tarique-rahmans-swearing-in-ceremony</link><description>Maldives President Dr Mohamed Muizzu is scheduled to arrive in Dhaka on Tuesday to attend the oath-taking ceremony of Bangladesh’s newly elected government, reaffirming close bilateral ties between the two South Asian nations.
Maldivian Foreign Minister Dr Abdulla Khaleel will accompany the</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 14:08:53 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>