<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 05:22:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Govt clarifies Google takedown request figures</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-clarifies-google-takedown-request-figures</link><description>The government has clarified the number of content removal requests sent to Google, assuring the public that no platform has been asked to delete newspaper reports or general social media content, except in cases involving defamatory misinformation.
“The government didn't request any platfor</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 03:07:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Consumers unhappy with winter veg price rise</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/consumers-unhappy-with-winter-veg-price-rise</link><description>Even though winter vegetables are arriving in the capital's markets in large volumes, their prices are still high, with a few witnessing even a hike last week.
Vendors say heavy rains in October disrupted winter vegetable production across the country.
In some areas, vegetable fields were damaged</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 03:22:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh mobile operators face rising regulatory strain</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladesh-mobile-operators-face-rising-regulatory-strain</link><description>Mobile operators worldwide are spending unprecedented amounts on cybersecurity, yet remain exposed to accelerating digital threats due to fragmented and overly prescriptive regulation, according to a new GSMA study that quantifies the growing financial and operational burden on the industry.
The r</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 03:37:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khaleda Zia's health condition very critical: Mirza Fakhrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/khaleda-zias-health-condition-very-critical-mirza-fakhrul</link><description>BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir said that the physical condition of the party chairperson and former Prime Minister Begum Khaleda Zia was 'very critical'. She now remains admitted at a hospital.
"Last night, doctors said her condition is extremely critical," Mr Fakhrul told journ</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 03:52:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Weekly Market Review: Stocks extend gains on ICB fund boost</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/weekly-market-review-stocks-extend-gains-on-icb-fund-boost</link><description>The benchmark equity index of the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) advanced for a second consecutive week, buoyed largely by fresh liquidity support from the Investment Corporation of Bangladesh (ICB).
The state-run investment bank began deploying funds into the market this week after receiving Tk 10 bi</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 03:15:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Islamic banking sector posts strong growth</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/islamic-banking-sector-posts-strong-growth</link><description>The Islamic banking sector posted strong growth across key indicators in September 2025, with deposits, investments, total assets and remittances rising year on year, even though export proceeds declined sharply, according to the latest Bangladesh Bank (BB) data.
Deposits in Islamic banks increase</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 03:30:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Empowering the disabled</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/analysis/empowering-the-disabled</link><description>We commemorate the International Day of Persons with Disabilities on the third of December every year, a day dedicated to acknowledging the struggles, achievements, and contributions of individuals with disabilities worldwide. This day serves as a platform to raise awareness, challenge misconceptio</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 03:45:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Panic reaction to earthquake is no way of facing the calamity</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/analysis/panic-reaction-to-earthquake-is-no-way-of-facing-the-calamity</link><description>Panic has gripped Dhakaites as an earthquake shook their residences violently on Friday, November 21. Another tremor, thought to be the aftershock of the Friday's one, jolted the capital and other areas the next day. This was followed by three more mild quakes, considered again the aftershocks of t</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 04:00:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Airbus issues major A320 recall, threatening global flight disruption</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/airbus-issues-major-a320-recall-threatening-global-flight-disruption</link><description>Europe's Airbus said on Friday it was ordering immediate repairs to 6,000 of its widely used A320 family of jets in a sweeping recall affecting more than half the global fleet, threatening upheaval during the busiest travel weekend of the year in the United States and disruption worldwide.
The set</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 04:15:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DSE grants FIX certification to nine more brokerage firms</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/dse-grants-fix-certification-to-nine-more-brokerage-firms</link><description>The Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) has awarded FIX (financial information exchange) certification to nine more brokerage firms as part of its initiative to introduce in-house order management systems (OMS) through API connectivity in all brokerage houses.
Mohammad Asadur Rahman, acting managing direct</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 04:30:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>POSTAL VOTING: Over 75,000 NRBs register since Nov 18</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/postal-voting-over-75000-nrbs-register-since-nov-18</link><description>Over 75,000 non-resident Bangladeshi (NRB) voters registered for postal voting, through a hybrid platform developed by the Election Commission (EC), ahead of the upcoming national election.
According to the latest data on the Out-of-Country Voting (OCV) portal, a total of 75,377 NRBs completed reg</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 04:45:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DWASA set to implement Tk 220m pilot project</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dwasa-set-to-implement-tk-220m-pilot-project</link><description>The Local Government Division (LGD) is moving to introduce a smart metering system in the water supply network, following similar modernisation efforts undertaken in the gas and power sectors.
The Dhaka Water Supply and Sewerage Authority (DWASA) is supposed to implement a Tk 220 million pilot pro</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 05:00:55 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>