<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 04:42:57 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Areas of non-existent workplace safety</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/areas-of-non-existent-workplace-safety</link><description>Workplace safety has long been a matter of serious concern but recent developments suggest that the situation has further deteriorated. Accidents and deaths arising from hazardous working conditions and compounded by persistent negligence in enforcing safety standards have cast a long shadow over t</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 18:00:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat hints at 'working with' BNP</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jamaat-tries-to-thaw-ties-with-bnp-suggests-post-poll-talks-to-work-together</link><description>The Jamaat chief commented on the election and referendum, urging a smooth, fair, and credible electoral process.
During the meeting, he recalled Jamaat’s long-term alliance with BNP, adding: “We have worked together in the past in the interest of our beloved country, and, God willing,</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 18:15:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Feroza’ stands silent, emptiness engulfs house next door too</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/feroza-stands-silent-emptiness-engulfs-house-next-door-too</link><description>A heavy, unfamiliar stillness has settled over “Feroza” in Dhaka’s Gulshan, the house where former prime minister Khaleda Zia spent the last 13 years of her life.
Even the home next door, once alive with visitors and activity, now feels drained of sound.
About one and a half mon</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 18:30:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bankers cautiously optimistic about a turnaround</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bankers-cautiously-optimistic-about-a-turnaround</link><description>Bankers sound cautiously optimistic about a turnaround in the problem-ridden banking sector on right-minded policy support following the change-making polls ahead in the new year.
Bangladesh saw so many eventful happenings in the just-past year 2025 but it was the most challenging one for banking</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 18:45:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>21 to face trial for killing Mitford scrap trader Sohag with boulder</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/21-to-face-trial-for-killing-mitford-scrap-trader-sohag-with-boulder</link><description>Months after the gruesome killing of scrap trader Lal Chand, also known as Sohag, outside Mitford Hospital in Dhaka -- where he was bludgeoned to death with a concrete boulder -- investigators have filed a chargesheet against 21 individuals at court.
The investigating officer, however, has recomme</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 19:00:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rajshahi Warriors beat Rangpur Riders in Super Over thriller</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/rajshahi-warriors-beat-rangpur-riders-in-super-over-thriller</link><description>Rajshahi Warriors staged a dramatic comeback to defeat Rangpur Riders in a Super Over after the regulation quota of overs ended in the Bangladesh Premier League (BPL).
Rangpur Riders seemed poised for victory, chasing 160 with confidence after half-centuries from Towhid Hridoy and David Malan in R</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 19:15:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NBR digitises UP system to expedite raw material imports</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/nbr-digitises-up-system-to-expedite-raw-material-imports</link><description>The National Board of Revenue (NBR) has launched fully online services enabling direct exporters to obtain Utilisation Permissions (UPs), aiming to expedite the import of raw materials and reduce lead times.
Under the new system, the Customs Bond Management System (CBMS) software has been made man</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 02:00:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Remittances hit record high in 2025</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/remittances-hit-record-high-in-2025</link><description>Remittance inflows to Bangladesh surged to an all-time high of US$32.82 billion in the calendar year 2025, underscoring the growing role of migrant workers in supporting the country's economy at a time of persistent domestic and global challenges.
The record inflows have provided crucial relief to</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 02:15:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ICD owners now agree to raise charges by 20pc</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/icd-owners-now-agree-to-raise-charges-by-20pc</link><description>Container-depot owners have now agreed to revise handling charges upward by 20 per cent instead of previously announced 81 per cent for outbound goods-laden boxes following a meeting with Chittagong Port Authority (CPA).
The Bangladesh Inland Container Depots Association (BICDA) on 20 July 2025 ha</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 02:30:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Diplomats, politicians, business leaders sign condolence book</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/diplomats-politicians-business-leaders-sign-condolence-book</link><description>Diplomats, political leaders, businesspeople and other dignitaries Thursday signed the condolence book opened at the BNP chairperson's Gulshan office as tributes to the late political matriarch abound.
It was the third and final day of signing the condolence book and thus mourning the demise of th</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 02:45:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP forms 41-member election steering committee</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-forms-41-member-election-steering-committee</link><description>The BNP on Thursday formed a 41-member election steering committee to run its campaign for the upcoming 13th Jatiya Sangsad election.
According to a press release issued on Thursday night, BNP Standing Committee member Nazrul Islam Khan has been made the chairman of the committee, while Senior Joi</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 03:00:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka welcomes Beijing's statement on national election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dhaka-welcomes-beijings-statement-on-national-election</link><description>Bangladesh on Thursday warmly welcomed a recent statement by the Chinese government expressing its wish for a smooth general election in the country, reaffirming that the election is Bangladesh’s internal affair.
In a press statement, the Ministry of Foreign Affairs said Bangladesh deeply va</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 04:15:59 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>