<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 11:16:36 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Petrol bombs hurled at Gazipur Grameen Bank branch</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/petrol-bombs-hurled-at-gazipur-grameen-bank-branch</link><description>Miscreants hurled two crude bombs at a Grameen Bank branch in Sreepur upazila of Gazipur district early Sunday.
Although no one was injured, the bank’s signboard was damaged in the attack, UNB reports.
Area Manager Md Abdur Razzak said the branch manager and four staff members were asleep i</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 07:41:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Economy is rebounding: Salehuddin</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/economy-is-rebounding-salehuddin-1</link><description>Finance Adviser Dr Salehuddin Ahmed today said that Bangladesh's economy is rebounding steadily due to different measures taken by the government to infuse dynamism in the overall economic activities.
"The economy is not destroyed; rather, it is rebounding and is in a better condition now compared</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 07:56:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh, UK discuss tourism, trade prospects</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/bangladesh-uk-discuss-tourism-trade-prospects</link><description>Bangladesh and the United Kingdom (UK) discussed prospects for expanding cooperation in tourism, trade and investment as Bangladesh High Commissioner in London Abida Islam met the Mayor and Mayoress of Oldham on Sunday.
According to the Bangladesh High Commission in London, Islam was warmly receiv</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 08:11:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Japanese-Bangladeshi REVIVAL Group to lease, restart BEXIMCO Textile Division</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/japanese-bangladeshi-revival-group-to-lease-restart-beximco-textile-division</link><description>Japanese–Bangladeshi fashion and sustainability venture REVIVAL Group Co Ltd and REVIVAL Projects Ltd will lease and restart the long-shuttered BEXIMCO Textile Division, according to a press release.
The decision paves “the way for more than 25,000 workers to regain their jobs and rebu</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 08:26:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fakhrul calls for resistance against ‘vested quarter’ ahead of Hasina verdict</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/fakhrul-calls-for-resistance-against-vested-quarter-ahead-of-hasina-verdict</link><description>BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir on Sunday urged people and political parties to resist the 'vested quarter' that, he alleged, is trying to create anarchy ahead of Monday's verdict in the case filed against 'fascist Sheikh Hasina for committing genocide'.
"The verdict in the trial</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 09:00:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>July Memorial set on fire in Feni</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/july-memorial-set-on-fire-in-feni</link><description>Miscreants set fire to the July Memorial in Muktabazar area of Feni district town early Sunday.
Police said a around 3:30 am group of helmet-wearing youths poured petrol on the monument and set it ablaze before fleeing.
Feni Superintendent of Police Habibur Rahman and senior officials visited the</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 09:15:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New iron-grey Bangladesh police uniform stirs mixed public reactions</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/new-iron-grey-bangladesh-police-uniform-stirs-mixed-public-reactions</link><description>Bangladesh police have stepped out in their newly introduced iron-grey uniform, drawing swift public attention and triggering a wave of mixed reactions in social media.
Officers in fresh metallic-toned attire were seen from Saturday early morning at several key points in the capital, marking a vis</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 09:30:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ministry warns all over fake video using Adviser Salehuddin’s image</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ministry-warns-all-over-fake-video-using-adviser-salehuddins-image</link><description>The Ministry of Finance has urged the public to remain alert about a fake video that has recently circulated on social media, allegedly using the image and likeness of Finance Adviser Dr Salehuddin Ahmed for promotional purposes.
According to an official media statement issued on Sunday, a v</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 09:34:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Arrest warrant issued against actress Mehazabien over ‘embezzlement, death threats’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/arrest-warrant-issued-against-actress-mehazabien-over-embezzlement-death-threats</link><description>A Dhaka court has issued arrest warrants against actress Mehazabien Chowdhury and her brother Alisan Chowdhury on charges of "embezzlement of Tk 2.7 million and death threats" after luring the plaintiff in with promises of making him a business partner.
Judge Afroza Tania of Dhaka Executive Magist</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 09:49:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Salehuddin urges next govt to ‘recognise’ interim administration’s groundwork</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/salehuddin-urges-next-govt-to-recognise-interim-administrations-groundwork</link><description>Finance Adviser of Bangladesh’s interim government, Dr Salehuddin Ahmed, on Sunday called on the incoming elected administration to duly recognise the foundational work and stabilising measures undertaken during the interim government’s tenure, emphasising that the coming months are cru</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 10:04:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NBR moves to make Bond Automation System compulsory after tiral</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/nbr-moves-to-make-bond-automation-system-compulsory-after-tiral</link><description>The National Board of Revenue (NBR) is set to make the use of its Bond Automation System compulsory after nearly 10 months of trial implementation, as authorities believe mandatory adoption is essential to fully realise the intended efficiency, transparency and facilitation benefits for export-orie</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 10:19:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Japan’s finance minister says stimulus package to exceed $110b, Nikkei reports</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/japans-finance-minister-says-stimulus-package-to-exceed-110b-nikkei-reports</link><description>Japan’s economic stimulus package will exceed 17 trillion yen ($110 billion), Finance Minister Satsuki Katayama said after meeting with Prime Minister Sanae Takaichi, the Nikkei business daily reported on Sunday.
Since taking office in October, Takaichi has pledged to compile a sizeable pack</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 10:34:48 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>