<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 09:53:57 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Over 1.14 million postal ballots reach returning officers by 2:00pm</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/over-114-million-postal-ballots-reach-returning-officers-by-200pm</link><description>A total of 1,143,845 postal ballots had reached returning officers as of 2:00pm on Thursday, according to data released by the Bangladesh Election Commission.
Of the total, 495,551 ballots were received from overseas voters, while 648,294 came from in-country postal voters (ICPV) through the Posta</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 07:06:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>LafargeHolcim launches salinity-resistant Holcim Coastal Guard</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/lafargeholcim-launches-salinity-resistant-holcim-coastal-guard</link><description>LafargeHolcim has launched another new product --- Holcim Coastal Guard --- a salinity and sulphate-resistant cement designed for structures exposed to coastal soil and groundwater conditions.
Mohammad Mahfuzul Hoque, commercial and logistics director of LafargeHolcim, unveiled the product at a ci</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 07:21:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Farmers make pure sugarcane jaggery along Jamuna River</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/farmers-make-pure-sugarcane-jaggery-along-jamuna-river</link><description>GAIBANDHA, Feb 11: Farmers have been traditionally producing pure sugarcane jaggery along the Jamuna River in Gaibandha district and customers arriving from far and wide say they are satisfied with their purchase of the natural sweetener made right in front of them.
The sweet scent of boiling raw</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 07:36:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Young voters shape Bangladesh's democratic moment</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/young-voters-shape-bangladeshs-democratic-moment</link><description>Bangladesh goes to the polls today (Thursday) in what many see as a defining moment in its post-uprising transition towards democratic normalcy.
With nearly 5.0 million newly enlisted voters casting ballots for the first time, the 13th national election carries an added generational weight.
For t</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 07:51:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Carrot production brings good income to Manikganj's farmers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/carrot-production-brings-good-income-to-manikganjs-farmers</link><description>MANIKGANJ, Feb 11: Carrot production has been bringing good income to thousands in Manikganj's Singair Upazila, which supplies nearly 40 per cent of the country's carrots after meeting local demand.
With favourable soil and weather, farmers are making profits of Tk 50,000 to Tk 60,000 per bigha. T</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 08:06:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Voting centres of political bigwigs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/voting-centres-of-political-bigwigs</link><description>As Bangladesh heads to the polls for the 13th Jatiya Sangsad (JS) election today (Thursday), the top brass from Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP), Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami, and National Citizen Party (NCP) have finalised their voting schedules.
The political heavyweights are set to cast their b</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 08:21:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Poultry farms face huge loss over low price of eggs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/poultry-farms-face-huge-loss-over-low-price-of-eggs</link><description>LALMONIRHAT, Feb 11: Over a thousand small and big poultry farms in five upazilas of Lalmonirhat district have been facing a huge loss due to the low price of eggs over the last few months.
According to the District Livestock Office, Lalmonirhat, there are around 1,000-1,200 poultry farms in the d</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 08:36:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>394 int'l observers, 197 foreign journalists monitor polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/394-intl-observers-197-foreign-journalists-monitor-polls</link><description>A horde of 394 international election observers and 197 foreign journalists are in Bangladesh to observe the country's crucial general election concomitant with an epoch-changing referendum on the July National Charter being held today (Thursday).
Of the international observers, 80 represent vario</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 08:51:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EU observers optimistic about voter turnout</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/eu-observers-optimistic-about-voter-turnout</link><description>The European Union Election Observation Mission (EU EOM) has expressed optimism about voter turnout and public enthusiasm in the ongoing national election.
According to the mission, voter participation at polling centres has been encouraging so far.
Speaking to journalists on Thursday (12 Februar</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 09:06:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Elections proceeding fairly, smoothly: Mirza Abbas</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/elections-proceeding-fairly-smoothly-mirza-abbas</link><description>BNP Standing Committee member and Dhaka-8 candidate Mirza Abbas said today (Thursday) that voting in the 13th parliamentary election is proceeding fairly and smoothly.
Speaking to reporters after casting his ballot at the Women's College polling center, he said, "The election is peaceful and going</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 09:21:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>23 injured as BNP, Jamaat supporters clash in Meherpur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/23-injured-as-bnp-jamaat-supporters-clash-in-meherpur</link><description>At least 23 people have been injured in clashes between supporters of the BNP and Jamaat-e-Islami in Meherpur’s Mujibnagar and Gangni Upazilas amid allegations of obstructing voters from going to polling stations.
The violence began on Thursday morning and spread across two locations, prompt</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 09:36:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A woman was told her ballot had already been cast. Banani polling paused for 24 minutes</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/a-woman-was-told-her-ballot-had-already-been-cast-banani-polling-paused-for-24-minutes</link><description>Voting has been suspended for around 24 minutes at a polling centre in the capital’s Banani area after a dispute arose over whether a voter had already cast her ballot.
The incident occurred around 1:15 pm on Thursday at the Banani Model School centre when Aklima, a resident of Korail slum</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 09:51:49 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>