<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 06:39:28 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>CA vows 'model election' as unique security oversights mounted</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ca-vows-model-election-as-unique-security-oversights-mounted</link><description>Interim government chief Prof Muhammad Yunus said Bangladesh's forthcoming 13th parliamentary election must set a democratic benchmark for the future as authorities Wednesday unveiled extensive security and monitoring deployment involving body cameras, CCTV surveillance, drones and central control</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 04:17:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EPB seeks govt, BB help to unlock Tk 1.8b in FDRs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/epb-seeks-govt-bb-help-to-unlock-tk-18b-in-fdrs</link><description>The Export Promotion Bureau (EPB) has turned to the government and the central bank for urgent help after nearly Tk 1.8 billion of its funds got trapped in fixed deposit receipts (FDRs) with 10 banks, raising concerns over stalled projects and mounting cash-flow stress.
Despite the deposits having</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 04:32:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Amending MLPA: For unverified income, property itself can be sued</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/for-unverified-income-property-itself-can-be-sued</link><description>The government is going to amend the Money Laundering Prevention Act, allowing the state to sue the "property" itself if the owner cannot prove a legitimate source of income, officials say.
If the court presumes the accused person or entity is guilty of money laundering, the person could be punish</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 04:47:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Arrest warrants issued against 5 Unilever officials in fraud case</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/arrest-warrants-issued-against-5-unilever-officials-in-fraud-case</link><description>A Dhaka court on Wednesday issued arrest warrants against Unilever Consumer Care Limited Managing Director Md Naharul Islam Molla and four other senior officials in a fraud case.
The other accused are Unilever Bangladesh Limited Finance Director Zinnia Huq, Area Manager (Central South Region) Kais</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 04:00:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>288 BNP, 224 Jamaat candidates in Bangladesh election race</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/288-bnp-224-jamaat-candidates-in-bangladesh-election-race</link><description>BNP has fielded the highest number of candidates—288—while Jamaat-e-Islami is contesting the February 12 parliamentary election with 224 candidates across the country.
A total of 1,732 contenders from 51 registered political parties and 249 independent candidates are competing in the n</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 04:15:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Brokers demand securities regrouping aligned with global standards</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/brokers-demand-securities-regrouping-aligned-with-global-standards</link><description>The DSE Brokers Association (DBA) has urged the securities regulator to reclassify securities listed on the prime bourse in line with global standards.
The association made the appeal in a letter to the chairman of the Bangladesh Securities and Exchange Commission (BSEC) on Wednesday.
Currently,</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 04:30:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New IPO rules take price discovery to global standards: BSEC chief</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/new-ipo-rules-take-price-discovery-to-global-standards-bsec-chief</link><description>New IPO rules have created scope for professional and globally accepted price discovery mechanisms, said the chief of the securities regulator.
The remark was made at a meeting on Wednesday between the Bangladesh Securities and Exchange Commission (BSEC) and the Central Depository Bangladesh Limit</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 04:45:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IPP penalties, payment delays deepen power sector crisis</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ipp-penalties-payment-delays-deepen-power-sector-crisis</link><description>Privately owned power producers are facing growing financial instability as payment delays by the state-run utility are followed by penalty deductions, raising concerns over fairness, contract compliance and energy security. 
Industry representatives warn that the practice is undermining inve</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 05:00:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Metro rail safety audit may take longer</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/metro-rail-safety-audit-may-take-longer</link><description>Inspecting the under-operation metro rail for a safety audit may take more time, as the Dhaka metro rail company lacks the required information to support any independent inspection firm.
However, officials said Dhaka Mass Transit Company Limited (DMTCL) has started working to meet the compliance</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 05:15:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Massive turnout at Alia Madrasa for Tarique’s rally</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/massive-turnout-at-alia-madrasa-for-tariques-rally</link><description>One procession after another is streaming into the Alia Madrasa ground in Sylhet as the BNP awaits the kickoff of its election campaign through a rally led by party chief Tarique Rahman.
BNP founder Ziaur Rahman and his wife, and recently departed former prime minister Khaleda Zia would also begin</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 05:30:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump backs down on Greenland tariffs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-backs-down-on-greenland-tariffs</link><description>US President Donald Trump abruptly stepped back on Wednesday from threats to impose tariffs as leverage to seize Greenland, ruled out the use of force and suggested a deal was in sight to end a dispute over the Danish territory that risked the deepest rupture in transatlantic relations in decades.</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 05:45:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Doctor beaten after patient dies at Dhaka Medical</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/doctor-beaten-after-patient-dies-at-dhaka-medical</link><description>Relatives of a patient who died at Dhaka Medical College Hospital (DMCH) have allegedly physically assaulted and abused doctors, accusing them of negligence in treatment.
Following the incident, emergency services were suspended for more than three hours from Wednesday night to early on Thursday m</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 06:00:46 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>