<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 18:48:28 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Need for keeping workplaces politically neutral</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/need-for-keeping-workplaces-politically-neutral</link><description>To strengthen administrative and economic frameworks and advance sustainable development, government and private sector employees must remain free from political influence and see that they are not exploited as instruments of those in power. Article 21(2) of our Constitution clearly states: "Every</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 16:17:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Integrating Ayurveda into health discourse in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/reviews/integrating-ayurveda-into-health-discourse-in-bangladesh</link><description>In Bangladesh, the ancient tradition of Ayurveda is a deep-seated, holistic healing practice. However, it remains a peripheral part of the modern healthcare system. This failure to integrate into the mainstream represents a missed opportunity for a more inclusive and comprehensive health model, ste</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 16:32:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Booming business of coaching centres</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/booming-business-of-coaching-centres</link><description>Private tuition or coaching has been an essential part of the country's mainstream primary and secondary education for a long time. A large section of guardians has developed the notion that only coaching centres can help their children/wards to do better results in examinations. The shadow or para</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 16:47:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>What's ailing India-Bangladesh relations?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/whats-ailing-india-bangladesh-relations</link><description>During his visit to New York for the UN General Assembly at the beginning of this month, Chief Adviser Professor Mohammad Yunus voiced a sentiment that revealed his government's growing frustration with India. In an interview with journalist Mehdi Hasan, clips of which have been making the rounds,</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 17:02:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Taking a balanced approach to trade liberalsation, AI</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/taking-a-balanced-approach-to-trade-liberalsation-ai</link><description>Despite risks of slowdown in global growth due to AI-related labour disruptions, and other issues, South Asia is still the world's fastest growing region. Growth in this region is projected to be robust at 6.6 per cent this year, but is expected to slow down to 5.8 per cent in 2026. This is, howeve</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 17:17:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Unnamed suspects charged over murder of Chattogram businessman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/unnamed-suspects-charged-over-murder-of-chattogram-businessman</link><description>Charges have been filed against unnamed suspects in the killing of businessman Abdul Hakim near Madunaghat Bridge in Chattogram, three days after the shooting.
Hakim’s wife Tasfia Alam Tanju, lodged the complaint at Hathazari Police Station on Friday, said Circle’s Additional Superinte</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 17:12:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Birds sang like dawn during solar eclipse: study</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/study-shows-how-solar-eclipse-made-some-birds-sing-like-a-new-day-dawned</link><description>On Apr 8, 2024, a total solar eclipse traversed a wide swathe of North America stretching 2,500 miles (4,000 km) from Mexico's Pacific Coast through Texas and across 14 other US states into Canada. The period of totality, when the moon covered the face of the sun, lasted about four minutes dependin</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 17:27:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Final farewell for Syed Manzoorul Islam at DU</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dhaka-university-to-pay-tribute-to-academic-syed-manzoorul-islam-saturday</link><description>Emeritus professor and writer Syed Manzoorul Islam will be taken to Dhaka University for a final farewell on Saturday.
Teachers, students, and well-wishers will pay their respects in front of the Aparajeyo Bangla sculpture at 10:30am, after which he will be taken to the Central Shaheed Minar at 11</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 17:57:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ganatantri leader Swapan Sen dies at 73</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ganatantri-leader-swapan-sen-dies-at-73</link><description>Swapan Sen, vice-president of the Chattogram district unit of the Ganatantri Party, has died at the age of 73.
He passed away early on Friday while undergoing treatment at Chattogram General Hospital, where he had been admitted for several days with age-related complications, said Mitul Das Gupta,</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 18:12:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New tax zones manned by few borrowed staffers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/new-tax-zones-manned-by-few-borrowed-staffers</link><description>Expanding tax nets for a must-have boost to Bangladesh's deficient revenues falters as the National Board of Revenue (NBR) appointed top officials to newly created tax zones mostly sans supporting staff.
Sources have said most of the zones have yet to receive approval for appointing support-staf</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 18:27:51 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>