<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 18:27:18 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Foreign loan disbursement up 35pc in Q1</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/foreign-loan-disbursement-up-35pc-in-q1</link><description>The government has said the disbursement of foreign loans in the first quarter of the ongoing fiscal year 2025-26 increased by 35 per cent compared with the same period last year.
According to data released by the Economic Relations Division (ERD) on its website on Saturday, foreign loan disbursem</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 15:01:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>50 injured in BNP-JaPa clash in Bhola</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/50-injured-in-bnp-japa-clash-in-bhola</link><description>A clash in Bhola between leaders and activists during programmes announced by the BNP and Bangladesh Jatiya Party (JaPa) has left at least 50 people injured, including policemen and journalists.
Bhola Superintendent of Police (SP) Md Shariful Haque said the incident occurred on Saturday outside th</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 15:16:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dengue: Bangladesh reports 651 hospitalisations in 24 hours</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dengue-bangladesh-reports-651-hospitalisations-in-24-hours</link><description>Bangladesh has reported 651 new hospitalisations due to dengue in the past 24 hours without any fatalities.
According to the Directorate General of Health Services (DGHS) count on Saturday, this year, as many as 70,513 dengue patients have been admitted to hospitals across the country, of whom 278</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 15:46:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two hacked to death over ‘land dispute’ in Narsingdi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/two-hacked-to-death-over-land-dispute-in-narsingdi</link><description>Two men have been killed in a machete attack over a land dispute in Narsingdi’s Raipura, police say.
The incident took place in the remote Char Subuddhi on Saturday, said Raipura Police Station chief Adil Mahmud.
He said that they had received information about the double murder, reports bd</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 16:01:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mobile court fines six noisy vehicles in Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/mobile-court-fines-six-noisy-vehicles-in-dhaka</link><description>The Department of Environment (DoE) has conducted a mobile court at Kakrail area of Dhaka to control noise pollution.
During the mobile court operation, a total of six vehicles were fined Tk 23,000 for violating Rule 8(1) of the Noise Pollution (Control) Rules, 2006, by generating excessive noise</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 16:16:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Worker killed by falling tree in Bagerhat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/worker-killed-by-falling-tree-in-bagerhat</link><description>A worker died after being crushed by a tree in Sarankhola upazila of Bagerhat on Saturday.
The deceased was identified as Sultan Hawladar, 60, a laborer and son of Anis Hawladar of Khuriyakhali village in Southkhali Union, reports UNB.
Md. Shahidullah, officer-in-charge of Sarankhola Police Stati</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 16:31:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Yunus meets chiefs of Army, Navy, Air Force</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/yunus-meets-chiefs-of-army-navy-air-force</link><description>Chief Advisor Muhammad Yunus has met with the chiefs of the Bangladesh Army, Navy, and Air Force to discuss preparations for the next national elections and the maintenance of law and order during the vote.
The meeting took place at the State Guest House Jamuna at 7pm on Saturday, the Chief Adviso</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 17:01:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Father, daughter killed in Sylhet road accident</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/father-daughter-killed-in-sylhet-road-accident</link><description>A man and his daughter were killed and four others injured in a head-on collision between a bus and a private car in Osmaninagar upazila of Sylhet on Saturday.
The deceased were identified Harun Mia and his 10-year-old daughter Anisha Begum, residents of Khadimpur village in Osmani Nagar, reports</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 17:31:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Japanese  cos bid for business in  diverse BD sectors</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/japanese-cos-bid-for-business-in-diverse-bd-sectors</link><description>Japanese companies bid big to  do business with Bangladesh in diverse sectors to seize emergent prospects, with many seeking information daily about the country's latest investment climate.
Affordable labour, local and global marketing prospects amid rising domestic consumer clientele act as</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 17:46:57 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>