<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 01:44:44 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Bogura-4 BNP candidate accused of forging undergraduate certificate</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bogura-4-bnp-candidate-accused-of-forging-undergraduate-certificate</link><description>BNP nominated candidate for Bogura-4 (Kahaloo-Nondigram) Md Mosharraf Hossain has been accused of forging an undergraduate certificate.
On Thursday afternoon, following a hearing, a Natore Court judge assigned the Police Bureau of Investigation (PBI) to investigate the case, according to Masud Ran</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 16:01:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Russia threatens full ban on WhatsApp</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/russia-threatens-full-ban-on-whatsapp</link><description>Russia's state communications watchdog threatened on Friday to block WhatsApp entirely if it fails to comply with Russian law, news agencies reported.
In August, Russia began limiting some calls on WhatsApp, owned by Meta Platforms (META.O), opens new tab, and on Telegram, accusing the foreign-own</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 16:24:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Showdown with Mexican billionaire Salinas tests Sheinbaum's power</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/showdown-with-mexican-billionaire-salinas-tests-sheinbaums-power</link><description>Ricardo Salinas Pliego, one of Mexico's wealthiest tycoons, commands an empire that stretches from banking to media, and casts himself as an anti-corruption crusader.
To Mexico's President Claudia Sheinbaum, Salinas is something altogether different: a tax dodger and right-wing agitator whos</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 16:39:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>China calls on UK to uphold 'one-China' principle</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/china-calls-on-uk-to-uphold-one-china-principle</link><description>China's Foreign Minister Wang Yi called on Britain on Friday to uphold the "one-China" principle, as Beijing seeks to rally support in its worst diplomatic dispute with Tokyo in years over democratically-governed Taiwan.
The "One China" principle, which Beijing views as meaning both sides of the T</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 16:54:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump vows migration freeze after DC attack</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-vows-to-freeze-migration-from-third-world-countries-after-dc-attack-1</link><description>US President Donald Trump said on Thursday his administration will "permanently pause" migration from all "Third World Countries", following the death of a National Guard member in an attack near the White House.
The comments mark a further escalation of migration measures Trump has ordered since</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 17:09:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Is Bangladesh's digital transformation deepening a new architecture of inequality?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/is-bangladeshs-digital-transformation-deepening-a-new-architecture-of-inequality</link><description>Bangladesh's rapid socio-economic transformation is often celebrated as one of the most compelling success stories in the Global South. The rise of the ready-made garment industry, the expansion of mobile banking and digital finance, the push toward technology-enabled services, and the ambition to</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 17:00:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No aggression in the name of religion</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/no-aggression-in-the-name-of-religion</link><description>After the July mass uprising that led to the downfall of the autocratic regime of Hasina on August 5 last year, numerous groups have emerged in the country with various demands. Though some of the demands are rational and legitimate, many were deployed mainly to create chaos. Again, some of these g</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 17:15:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Why Bangladesh fails to diversify its exports</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/why-bangladesh-fails-to-diversify-its-exports</link><description>It is never wise to put all eggs in one basket where a single misstep can cause them all to break. A nation's "basket" is its export profile and over-reliance on a single sector makes it vulnerable to volatile global demand. Yet despite decades of discussion and repeated calls for diversification,</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 17:30:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>HSIA fire probe needs to go deeper</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/hsia-fire-probe-needs-to-go-deeper</link><description>The findings by the 12-member government probe body formed following last month's devastating fire at the import cargo complex of the Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport (HSIA) are nothing extraordinary. That the fire resulting from an electrical short circuit was a pure accident and not caused</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 17:45:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ex-JCD leader killing in B’baria; family files complaint against Swechchhasebak Dal leader</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ex-jcd-leader-killing-in-bbaria-family-files-complaint-against-swechchhasebak-dal-leader</link><description>The family of slain ex-Jatiyatabadi Chhatra Dal (JCD) leader  Saddam has filed a  complaint naming a  Swechchhasebak Dal leader as the prime accused in his killing.
Saddam’s father, Mostu Mia, lodged the complaint on Friday night mentioning the names of  convenor of distr</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 18:00:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Newborn bank's BB account opens before licensing</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/newborn-banks-bb-account-opens-before-licensing</link><description>Government authorities are going great guns to operationalise the newborn Sammilito Islami Bank in state sector as its account is opened with the central bank well before licensing, sources say.



The new shariah-based bank is born out of the merger of five liquidity-crisis-ridden Islamic ba</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 18:15:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Vegetables sizzle, fish fizzle in Dhaka markets</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/vegetables-sizzle-fish-fizzle-in-dhaka-markets</link><description>Prices in Dhaka’s kitchen markets remain high despite a rise in the supply of winter vegetables, with a gap of around Tk 100 per kg between old and new potatoes.
Fish prices, however, have fallen by up to Tk 100 per kg over the week.
At Jatrabari, trader Shamsul Islam told bdnews24.com that</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 18:30:43 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>