<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 06:33:51 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Downpour, windstorm extensively damage Aman paddy in Rangpur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/downpour-windstorm-extensively-damage-aman-paddy-in-rangpur</link><description>Farmers in different upazilas of Rangpur district and Naogaon district are disappointed as heavy downpour and strong wind in the past several days have flattened and submerged standing Aman paddy, newly planted potato seeds, and early winter vegetables, causing massive damage to the crops.
Our Cor</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 02:57:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gaibandha farmers rejoice at high jute prices</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/gaibandha-farmers-rejoice-at-high-jute-prices</link><description>Farmers in Gaibandha this year have been selling jute at about twice as much the price of last few years, while the happy growers and their families spend a busy time ginning, dehusking and drying the golden fiber.
Good yield, coupled with prices ranging from Tk 3,000 to Tk 3,500 per maund from th</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 03:12:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ISPAB opposes draft new telecom guidelines</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ispab-opposes-draft-new-telecom-guidelines</link><description>The Internet Service Providers Association of Bangladesh (ISPAB) warned on Monday that the proposed new telecommunications guidelines could lead to an 18.40 per cent surge in the internet prices and a catastrophic effect on the nation's internet service providers.
The warnings and concerns were ma</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 03:27:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NYC mayoral candidates make final push ahead of Election Day</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/nyc-mayoral-candidates-make-final-push-ahead-of-election-day</link><description>From Coney Island to the Bronx, the candidates in New York City’s mayoral race spent Monday crisscrossing the five boroughs in a final, frenzied day of campaigning on the eve of Election Day.
As candidates made final pitch to voters, President Donald Trump urged New Yorkers to cast their bal</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 03:42:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt releases Tk 5b in cash incentives for exporters</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/govt-releases-tk-5b-in-cash-incentives-for-exporters</link><description>The government has released Tk 5 billion in cash incentives to support the country's exporters. This is the second tranche of the first installment for the 2025-26 fiscal year.
Earlier, Tk 10 billion was provided as the first tranche of the first installment for the current fiscal year, sources sa</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 03:57:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Three burnt in blast from ‘gas leakage’ in Feni</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/three-burnt-in-blast-from-gas-leakage-in-feni</link><description>Three people have sustained burn injuries in an explosion reportedly triggered by gas leakage at a house in Feni Sadar upazila.
The injured were identified as Md Rafiqul Islam, 40, Abul Kashem, 55, and Jesmin Akhter, 30.
All three victims were taken to the Burn Unit of Dhaka Medical College Hospi</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 04:12:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Proper disaster preparedness could cut industrial losses</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/proper-disaster-preparedness-could-cut-industrial-losses</link><description>A three-day training programme aiming to ensure continued industrial production and minimise losses during disasters kicked off at the Mongla Export Processing Zone (EPZ) in Khulna on Monday.
The Federation of Bangladesh Chambers of Commerce and Industry (FBCCI) and the Mongla EPZ Authority jointl</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 04:27:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Green diesel, aviation fuel to be produced from wastes in Ctg</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/green-diesel-aviation-fuel-to-be-produced-from-wastes-in-ctg</link><description>US-based Bringia Energy Global LLC (BEG) and Canada-based Disruptive Hydrogen Technology (DHT) have inked a memorandum of understanding (MoU) with Chattogram City Corporation (CCC) to produce green diesel and sustainable aviation fuel utilising wastes in Chattogram. Under the terms of the MoU, the</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 04:42:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Stocks open higher at DSE, CSE</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/stocks-open-higher-at-dse-cse</link><description>Stocks opened on a positive note today, with indices at both the Dhaka and Chattogram stock exchanges edging up in early trading amid a rise in investor participation.
In the first hour of trading, the benchmark DSEX index of the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) advanced by 21 points to 5,129. The Shari</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 05:12:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>JnUCSU Election: Student bodies move to form ‘inclusive panels’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/jnucsu-election-student-bodies-move-to-form-inclusive-panels</link><description>The long-awaited student union election process at Jagannath University has officially kicked off, following the publication of the Jagannath University Central Students’ Union (JnUCSU) election rules and the formation of its Election Commission, marking a distinctive step in the process.
Po</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 05:42:14 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>