<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 15:28:51 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>No Ctg port lease-out under interim government: BIDA Chairman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/no-ctg-port-lease-out-under-interim-government-bida-chairman</link><description>The interim government will not lease out the New Mooring Container Terminal at Chattogram Port during its tenure, said the head of the country’s investment authority, dismissing the reported move over finalising a deal with global port operator DP World.
Chowdhury Ashik Mahmud Bin Harun, ex</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 13:03:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Education Ministry begins MPO registration for 1,719 educational institutions</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/education-ministry-begins-mpo-registration-for-1719-educational-institutions</link><description>The Ministry of Education has started the initial process of enrolling 1,719 private educational institutions (schools and colleges) across the country in the first phase of MPO.
The ministry said that a letter has already been sent to the Finance Department seeking consent for the MPO enrollment</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 13:18:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BPSC recommends 1,457 candidates in 46th BCS</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bpsc-recommends-1457-candidates-in-46th-bcs</link><description>The Bangladesh Public Service Commission (BPSC) has provisionally recommended 1,457 candidates for different cadres through the 46th Bangladesh Civil Service (BCS) examination.
The information was revealed in a circular signed by Masuma Afrin, Controller of Examinations (Cadre) of the BPSC, on Sun</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 12:28:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>At least 20 injured in BNP–Jamaat clash in Patuakhali</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/at-least-20-injured-in-bnp-jamaat-clash-in-patuakhali</link><description>At least 20 people were injured on Sunday in a clash between activists of BNP and Jamaat-e-Islami during rival processions in Chandradwip Union of Bauphal upazila under Patuakhali-2 constituency.
According to local sources, the violence erupted in the afternoon at Bhandaria Bazar when face-to-face</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 12:43:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Indemnity was a ‘licence to kill’: Iqbal Karim Bhuiyan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/former-army-chief-calls-operation-clean-hearts-legal-cover-a-licence-to-kill</link><description>Former Bangladesh Army chief Iqbal Karim Bhuiyan has described the indemnity granted to security forces involved in the BNP-Jamaat-e-Islami government’s Operation Clean Heart as a “licence to kill”, arguing that it normalised enforced disappearances, custodial deaths, and impunity</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 12:58:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Taskin Ahmed unveils world’s highest featured AC made by Walton</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/taskin-ahmed-unveils-worlds-highest-featured-ac-made-by-walton</link><description>Walton, Bangladesh’s tech giant and No-1 air conditioners brand, has introduced a new model of Smart AC, which it describes as the world’s highest featured AC to date- integrating a wide range of IoT and Smart AI-enabled technologies.
This new model of AC is designed with Walton’</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 13:13:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Stocks retreat on week’s first trading day</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/stocks-retreat-on-weeks-first-trading-day</link><description>Stocks in Bangladesh closed lower on Sunday, the first trading day of the week, with both the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) and Chittagong Stock Exchange (CSE) posting index declines amid a reduced turnover.
At the DSE, the benchmark DSEX shed 5 points by the end of the session. The Shariah-based DSE</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 13:28:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ukraine urges acceleration of peace talks, says only Trump can broker deal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/ukraine-urges-acceleration-of-peace-talks-says-only-trump-can-broker-deal</link><description>Kyiv's foreign minister has said the Ukrainian and Russian leaders need to meet in person to hash out the hardest remaining issues in peace talks, and that only US President Donald Trump has the power to bring about an agreement.
Ukraine wants to accelerate the efforts to end the four-year-old war</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 13:43:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Japan’s Takaichi set for landslide election win</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/japans-takaichi-set-for-landslide-election-win</link><description>Japanese Prime Minister Sanae Takaichi’s coalition is set for a landslide win in Sunday’s election, exit polls showed, paving the way for her tax cuts that have spooked financial markets and military spending aimed at countering China.
Takaichi’s Liberal Democratic Party and coal</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 13:58:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trust Bank, Sheba.xyz sign MoU to launch digital nano loan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/trust-bank-shebaxyz-sign-mou-to-launch-digital-nano-loan</link><description>Trust Bank PLC has signed a Memorandum of Understanding (MoU) with leading digital fintech platform Sheba.xyz to promote digital financial inclusion in Bangladesh through the introduction of a Digital Nano Loan facility, according to a press release.
The agreement was signed at Trust Bank Head Off</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 14:13:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>912th Executive Committee meeting of Shahjalal Islami Bank held</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/912th-executive-committee-meeting-of-shahjalal-islami-bank-held</link><description>The 912th meeting of the Executive Committee (EC) of Shahjalal Islami Bank PLC (SJIB PLC) was held on February 5, 2026 at Corporate Head Office of the bank, according to a press release.
The meeting was presided over by Mr.Md. Sanaullah Shahid, the chairman of Executive Committee (EC) of the bank.</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 14:28:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt issues notification fixing Ramadan office timing</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-issues-notification-fixing-ramadan-office-timing</link><description>The government has fixed new office timings for all government, semi-government, autonomous and semi-autonomous institutions in the country for the upcoming holy month of Ramadan of the Hijri 1447.
According to the new schedule, offices will remain open from 9 am to 3:30 pm during the month of Ram</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 14:43:30 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>