<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 19:17:22 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>November rain smashes onion fields</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/november-rain-smashes-onion-fields</link><description>Onion prices shot up to Tk 100-120 a kg, marking above 30 per cent hike in last two days.
November Rain in places amid the ongoing depression in the Bay had smashed newer crops in Pabna, Rajshahi and Faridpur regions.
Onion farmers in the region are now sourcing edible onion to grow seed onion (m</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 16:11:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>World's first flying car factory starts trial production in China</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/worlds-first-flying-car-factory-starts-trial-production-in-china</link><description>XPENG AEROHT, the flying car affiliate of Chinese electric vehicle maker XPENG, on Monday began trial production at the world's first intelligent factory for mass-produced flying cars -- a milestone in the commercialization of next-generation transport.
Located in the Huangpu district of Guangzhou</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 16:55:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DU female teacher files case over dissemination of distorted photo</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/du-female-teacher-files-case-over-dissemination-of-distorted-photo</link><description>A female teacher of premier Dhaka University on Monday filed a case under the country’s tough Cyber Security Act over dissemination of her “distorted photographs” along with vulgar comments on social media platforms.
Police said assistant Professor of the university’s publi</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 17:10:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fraud posing as customs officer arrested at HSIA</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fraud-posing-as-customs-officer-arrested-at-hsia</link><description>Members of the Airport Armed Police Battalion (APBn-13) have arrested a member of an organized fraud gang posing as customs officials at Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport (HSIA).
The arrestee was identified as Md. Sabur Khan, 25, reports UNB.
According to police sources, Sabur and his accomp</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 17:25:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Marvel schedules 2026 worldwide releases for Spider-Man and Avengers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/entertainment/marvel-schedules-2026-worldwide-releases-for-spider-man-and-avengers</link><description>Marvel Studios has announced two major global release dates for 2026 that fans around the world are eagerly anticipating: July 31 and December 18.
'Spider-Man: Brand New Day' will swing into cinemas on July 31, 2026, with Tom Holland reprising his role as Peter Parker.
The production is already u</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 17:40:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Forest officer injured in poacher attack in Sundarban; 3 detained</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/forest-officer-injured-in-poacher-attack-in-sundarban-3-detained</link><description>A forest officer was injured Monday in the Sundarbans, when a group of poachers hunting deer attacked him.
The incident took place at Dimer Char in the Sarankhola range of the Sundarbans East Division in Bagerhat.
The injured officer, Rana Dev, received first aid at the temporary Dublarchar Healt</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 18:11:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Unregulated battery recycling plants</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/unregulated-battery-recycling-plants</link><description>Lead poisoning has been a serious public health issue in Bangladesh since early 1990s affecting mostly children. Suspecting that burning of leaded-gasoline was a source of lead pollution in the environment, in 1999, the government of the time banned the use of leaded gasoline. Now, informal lead-ba</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 18:26:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Safety measures must to restore confidence in metro rail</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/safety-measures-must-to-restore-confidence-in-metro-rail</link><description>It was a bright afternoon on October 26, 2025, when tragedy struck once again in Dhaka's Farmgate area. A bearing pad from the city's metro rail infrastructure fell from above, fatally hitting a young man named Abul Kalam Azad. He died on the spot-leaving behind a grieving mother, a devastated wife</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 18:41:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How much flawed is Dhaka's metro rail?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/how-much-flawed-is-dhakas-metro-rail</link><description>For tens of thousands of people, Dhaka City's iconic infrastructure as well as service is the metro rail. In the context of long tailbacks on the city's roads and streets, the service metro rail renders is refreshing and this is despite the occasional irregularities caused by technical malfunctions</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 18:56:08 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>