<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 09:23:36 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Unidentified body found near DMCH emergency ward</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/unidentified-body-found-near-dmch-emergency-ward</link><description>The body of an unidentified man, aged around 55, was recovered under the stairs of ward No. 101 at the emergency department of Dhaka Medical College and Hospital on Monday morning.
Ayub Ali, ward master of the emergency unit, said the man was found unconscious under the stairs in the morning. He w</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 06:54:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump unsure whether Tony Blair would be accepted on Gaza peace board</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-unsure-whether-tony-blair-would-be-accepted-on-gaza-peace-board</link><description>US President Donald Trump on Sunday questioned whether former UK Prime Minister Tony Blair would serve on a new "Board of Peace" that is intended to oversee the governance of Gaza, amid ongoing criticisms of Blair for his role in the Iraq War.
"I've always liked Tony, but I want to find out that h</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 07:09:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump arrives in Israel to tout a ceasefire he believes could foster lasting Middle East peace</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-arrives-in-israel-to-tout-a-ceasefire-he-believes-could-foster-lasting-middle-east-peace</link><description>President Donald Trump arrived in Israel on Monday to celebrate the U.S.-brokered ceasefire and hostage deal between Israel and Hamas, an agreement that he declared had effectively ended the war and opened the door to building a durable peace in the Middle East.
As he disembarked from Air Force On</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 06:56:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Students stage protests demanding ordinance for Dhaka Central University</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/students-stage-protests-demanding-ordinance-for-dhaka-central-university</link><description>Students have gathered on the road adjacent to Sikkha Bhaban and staged a sit-in demonstration demanding a final ordinance to combine seven government colleges previously affiliated with Dhaka University into the proposed Dhaka Central University.
They said they would not leave the road until the</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 07:11:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>MPO teachers’ strike enters Day 2</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/mpo-teachers-strike-enters-day-2</link><description>As part of their “uninterrupted sit-in” demanding 20 per cent of their basic salary as housing allowance, MPO-affiliated teachers and employees have continued their protest at the Central Shaheed Minar for a second day.
Although organisers announced an “uninterrupted sit-in&amp;rdquo</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 07:26:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Finance Ministry warns against rumours over bank merger</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/finance-ministry-warns-against-rumours-over-bank-merger</link><description>The Ministry of Finance has warned all to stay alert against a smear campaign on social media by a vested quarter regarding the ongoing bank merger process.
In a media release issued on Monday, the ministry urged investors not to pay heed to any misinformation about the merger of Islamic banks, re</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 07:41:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>HSC, equivalent results on Thursday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hsc-equivalent-results-on-thursday</link><description>The results for the Higher Secondary Certificate (HSC) and equivalent examinations will be released on Thursday, with all 10 education boards scheduled to release the results at 10:00 am, reports bdnews24.com.
Prof SM Kamal Uddin Haider, exam controller for the Dhaka Secondary and Higher Education</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 07:56:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump to get Israeli Presidential Medal of Honor</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-to-get-israeli-presidential-medal-of-honor</link><description>In the coming months, Israel's President Isaac Herzog will award Trump the Israeli Presidential Medal of Honor in recognition of his efforts to bring back Israeli hostages who were held in Gaza, according to Reuters on Monday.
“President Trump’s legacy will be remembered for generation</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 08:26:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Another prisoner dies at DMCH</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/another-prisoner-dies-at-dmch</link><description>A prisoner died at Dhaka Medical College Hospital (DMCH) early Monday, a day after a 60-year-old inmate named Miaz Uddin died there on Saturday.
The deceased was identified as Shuayebur Rahman (54), a resident of the Kansat Milik area under Shibganj Police Station in Chapainawabganj district.
Pri</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 08:41:55 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>