<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 05:24:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Govt employees' pay hike and economic challenges</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/govt-employees-pay-hike-and-economic-challenges</link><description>The Ninth National Pay Commission report, as submitted on Wednesday (January 21), is learnt to have recommended a sweeping hike in the basic salaries of government servants. Evidently, implementation of this new pay structure is going to cost the state exchequer a humongous sum of additional Tk 1.0</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 17:30:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fakhrul warns Jamaat-e-Islami poses ‘threat’ to Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fakhrul-warns-jamaat-e-islami-poses-threat-to-bangladesh</link><description>BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir has described Jamaat-e-Islami, a force that opposed the 1971 Liberation War, as a threat to the nation's safety.
He believes that the country cannot be secure in the hands of those who originally did not want the birth of Bangladesh.
Speaking at a</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 17:45:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat alleges election code violations in eight districts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jamaat-alleges-election-code-violations-in-eight-districts</link><description>Jamaat-e-Islami has alleged that the electoral code of conduct has been violated in eight districts during election campaigning.
The party said the incidents occurred between Thursday, when campaigning officially began, and Friday afternoon.
At a press conference on Friday evening, party spokespe</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 18:00:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BB seeks authority to override law, waive banks' CRR penalties</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bb-seeks-authority-to-override-law-waive-banks-crr-penalties</link><description>Bangladesh Bank moves to bolster its regulatory authority to waive, remit, or reduce penalties for banks' Cash Reserve Ratio (CRR) shortfalls in special circumstances as the central bank oversees the largest bank-consolidation effort in nation's history.



To this end, sources say, the central</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 19:26:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Affluent banks invest surplus liquidity in lower-interest state instrument</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/affluent-banks-invest-surplus-liquidity-in-lower-interest-state-instrument</link><description>A major cut in the interest rate on standing deposit facility (SDF) can hardly stop affluent banks from loading their surplus funds into the state-guaranteed deposit instrument despite lower gains than that from interbank lending.
A cardinal cause is lower call from the call-money market for funds</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 03:39:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UNHCR seeks alternative funding for Rohingyas as major donors tighten their grip</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/unhcr-seeks-alternative-funding-as-major-donors-tighten-their-grip</link><description>With contributions from the major donors drying up gradually, the UNHCR, the UN agency for protecting refugees and forcibly displaced communities, is now looking for donations from alternative countries and sources, including Bangladesh, officials said.
The UNHCR (United Nations High Commissioner</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 03:54:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cash-Based Social Safety Net Progs: Monthly allowances likely to go up</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/cash-based-social-safety-net-progs-monthly-allowances-likely-to-go-up</link><description>The interim government is likely to enhance allowances for distressed people from the next fiscal year as the cabinet committee concerned will sit tomorrow to finalise the decision, officials say.
Each allowance under the cash-based social safety-net programmes (SSNPs) may see a rise of Tk 50-100</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 04:09:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Stocks hit two-month high as national election approaches</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/stocks-hit-two-month-high-as-national-election-approaches</link><description>The benchmark index of the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) rebounded strongly from the previous week's losses, hitting a two-month high, driven by renewed buying interest in undervalued blue-chip stocks ahead of national election.
Market analysts attributed the rally to a broad-based price surge across</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 04:24:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NRBC Bank to boost CMSME financing and expand digital services</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/nrbc-bank-to-boost-cmsme-financing-and-expand-digital-services</link><description>NRBC Bank plans to boost financing in the CMSME sector while expanding its digital channels, including an app called 'Planet', to deliver financial services to unbanked and underbanked populations across the country, the bank's top policymaker has said.
"Our medium-term objectives are focused on i</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 04:39:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fear-free environment is a must for free, fair election: Fakhrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/fear-free-environment-is-a-must-for-free-fair-election-fakhrul</link><description>BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir said a fear-free environment must be ensured to hold a free and fair national parliamentary election.
He made the comment in a statement sent to the media on Friday, following the shooting of Keraniganj BNP leader Hasan Molla.
In the statement, Mi</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 04:54:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Campaigns pace up as constituency-wise voter list out</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/campaigns-pace-up-as-constituency-wise-voter-list-out</link><description>Election candidates of different political parties and independent ones are passing busy time conducting campaigns to attract voters as the Election Commission (EC) has unveiled constituency-wise final voter list.
Candidates of Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP), Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami, Nation</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 05:09:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>One-person company registration galore</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/one-person-company-registration-galore</link><description>One-person companies (OPCs) galore with a record 301 registered in just first six months of the fiscal year, surpassing the total formed in several previous full years, official data show.
According to statistics from the Office of the Registrar of Joint Stock Companies and Firms (RJSC), the six-m</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 05:24:19 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>