<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 09:19:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Pakistan sees 46pc surge in violence in Q3</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/pakistan-sees-46pc-surge-in-violence-in-q3</link><description>Pakistan has witnessed a sharp 46 percent increase in overall violence in the third quarter (Q3) of 2025, amid continued counter-terrorism operations and militant attacks, an Islamabad-based think-tank, Center for Research and Security Studies (CRSS), said on Thursday.
The country recorded at leas</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 05:59:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Son kills father for refusing to give him money</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/son-kills-father-for-refusing-to-give-him-money</link><description>A man was brutally killed by his son in Khulna city’s Bashupara Bashtola area on Thursday night after refusing to give him money, reportedly for buying drugs.
The victim Liton Khan, 50, was a fish seller and a resident of the area, reports UNB.
Kabir Hossain, officer-in-charge of Sonadanga</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 06:14:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC designs strategy to curb misuse of AI, social media ahead of next election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-designs-strategy-to-curb-misuse-of-ai-social-media-ahead-of-next-election</link><description>The Election Commission is working to design an effective strategy to fight the abuse of artificial intelligence (AI) and social media, considering the fight against misinformation and disinformation on social media as a major challenge during the upcoming national election slated for February 2026</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 06:29:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Australian scientists create natural plastics for everyday packaging</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/australian-scientists-create-natural-plastics-for-everyday-packaging</link><description>Australian scientists have developed natural plastic films from food waste sugars that could replace petroleum-based packaging, offering compostable alternatives for food and agricultural uses.
The study led by Australia's Monash University (MON) highlights the potential of a new type of biodegrad</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 06:44:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh, India emotionally linked by shared sacrifices: Verma</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-india-emotionally-linked-by-shared-sacrifices-verma</link><description>Indian High Commissioner to Bangladesh Pranay Verma has said Bangladesh and India are emotionally linked by the shared sacrifices of the Liberation War of 1971.
"India and Bangladesh share a unique and special relationship. They are connected by history and geography," he said during his recent vi</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 06:59:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>FIFA unveils 2026 World Cup official match ball</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/football/fifa-unveils-2026-world-cup-official-match-ball</link><description>FIFA on Thursday unveiled the official match ball for the 2026 World Cup, "TRIONDA," marking another milestone on the road to the first edition jointly hosted by Canada, Mexico and the United States.
The name, derived from Spanish, loosely translates as "three waves" and refers to the unity of the</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 07:14:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>European protesters block traffic, vandalise shops after Gaza aid flotilla blocked</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/european-protesters-block-traffic-vandalise-shops-after-gaza-aid-flotilla-blocked</link><description>Pro-Palestinian demonstrators in Europe on Thursday blocked traffic and vandalised shops and restaurants after Israeli forces intercepted a Gaza-bound humanitarian aid flotilla.
Israel faced international condemnation after armed Israeli soldiers boarded around 40 ships that were attempting to bre</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 07:44:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>OpenAI hits $500 billion valuation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/openai-hits-500-billion-valuation</link><description>OpenAI, the company behind ChatGPT, has reached a valuation of $500 billion, following a deal in which current and former employees sold roughly $6.6 billion worth of shares, a source familiar with the matter told Reuters on Thursday.
This represents a bump-up from its current valuation of $300 bi</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 07:59:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UK's Prince William opens up about family fears and plans to change monarchy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/uks-prince-william-opens-up-about-family-fears-and-plans-to-change-monarchy</link><description>Prince William has said protecting his family was the most important thing for him when his wife Kate and father King Charles became ill, and revealed that he will seek to modernise the monarchy when he becomes sovereign.
Speaking to Eugene Levy for the Canadian actor's TV travel show, the normall</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 08:14:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Synagogue attack on Yom Kippur kills two in UK's Manchester</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/synagogue-attack-on-yom-kippur-kills-two-in-uks-manchester</link><description>Two men were killed on Thursday when a man drove a car into pedestrians and stabbed a security guard in an attack at a synagogue where worshippers were marking Yom Kippur, the holiest day in the Jewish calendar, British police said.
Greater Manchester Police said the man who carried out the attack</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 08:29:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh condemns Israeli interception of Gaza aid flotilla</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-condemns-israeli-interception-of-gaza-aid-flotilla</link><description>Bangladesh has strongly condemned the interception of the Global Sumud Flotilla in international waters by Israeli forces. The flotilla was carrying humanitarian assistance for the people of Gaza.
“This act is a flagrant violation of international law and a brazen manifestation of Israel&amp;rsq</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 08:44:36 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>