<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 04:21:43 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>July Charter signed for 'new Bangladesh'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/july-charter-signed-for-new-bangladesh</link><description>Head of interim government Prof Muhammad Yunus and major political parties' leaders Friday signed on the July National Charter 2025 stipulating institutional reforms for rebuilding Bangladesh in spirit of the uprising that toppled the past 'fascist' regime.



"We're now newborns-it marks the b</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 18:46:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>MRT line-5 (South): Funds to dry up if project doesn't roll this year, says ADB</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/mrt-line-5-south-funds-to-dry-up-if-project-doesnt-roll-this-year-says-adb</link><description>The Asian Development Bank (ADB) has inquired about the status of the proposed MRT line-5 (south) as the project has faced a setback in the middle of the approval process, officials say.
On Friday, they said the Manila-based lender had informed the government that its MRT-5 project funds would dry</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 01:48:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Finance seeks home ministry help to execute 1,025 loan-default arrest warrants</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/finance-seeks-home-ministry-help-to-execute-1025-loan-default-arrest-warrants</link><description>Financial Institutions Division (FID) finally seeks Home Ministry's intervention for executing arrest warrants in 1,025 long-pending loan-default cases that have trapped huge sums of money, sources say.
The warrants for arrest of the 'wilful defaulters' have been issued by Money Loan Courts (Artha</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 02:03:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Banks' forex holdings drop to $3.94b amid BB’s dollar buying</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/banks-forex-holdings-drop-to-394b-amid-bbs-dollar-buying</link><description>Commercial banks' foreign-exchange (forex) holdings plummeted to $3.94 billion in September, mainly due to the central bank's growing US dollar-buying interventions, according to officials and money-market experts.
The Bangladesh Bank (BB), the country's central bank, as part of its market interve</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 02:18:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khaleda returns home from hospital</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/khaleda-returns-home-from-hospital-2</link><description>BNP Chairperson Khaleda Zia returned home on Friday night after receiving treatment at Evercare Hospital for two days.
“Madam (Khaleda) was discharged from the hospital as per the advice of the medical board,” said her personal physician Prof AZM Zahid Hossain.
He said the BNP chief l</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 02:33:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DSEX logs biggest weekly fall in a year</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/dsex-logs-biggest-weekly-fall-in-a-year</link><description>Toggle navigat
The benchmark equity index of the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) witnessed the biggest weekly fall in more than a year amid widespread sell-offs, as investors grew jittery over political and economic uncertainty.
The DSEX, the prime index of DSE, slid nearly 164 points, or 3.11 per cen</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 03:36:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>3 Afghan cricketers among 8 killed in Pakistani airstrike</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/3-afghan-cricketers-among-8-killed-in-pakistani-airstrike</link><description>At least three Afghan cricketers have been killed in a Pakistani airstrike in Afghanistan’s eastern Paktika province, according to the Afghanistan Cricket Board (ACB).
The ACB said the players, whom they identified by single names as Kabeer, Sibghatullah and Haroon, had travelled from Urgun</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 04:21:43 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>