<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 06:30:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Govt's push for e-GP faces setback as TCB seeks to use manual system</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/govts-push-for-e-gp-faces-setback-as-tcb-seeks-to-use-manual-system</link><description>The government's decade-long efforts to bring transparency to public spending is facing a setback, as the Trading Corporation of Bangladesh (TCB) has requested an exemption from the newly introduced mandatory electronic government procurement (e-GP) system.
Instead, the state-owned agency has soug</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 04:24:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Re-engineering in internal audit operations</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/analysis/re-engineering-in-internal-audit-operations</link><description>Bangladesh has come a long way in economic growth since 1972. In 1972, the gross domestic product (GDP) was US$ 5.70 billion where as in 2025 it stands at US$ 475.00 billion. Contribution to GDP from the services sector is continuously increasing since 1990. The main contributor of the service sect</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 04:39:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Three-dimensional connectedness is the clinching factor</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/analysis/three-dimensional-connectedness-is-the-clinching-factor</link><description>That a nation's close relationship or the lack of it with Nature can be a subject of study is somewhat surprising, especially when Western researchers embark on exploring nations' comparative connectedness to natural environment. To the oriental civilisations, particularly that of the Indian subcon</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 04:54:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US warns it could force 20pc flight cuts if shutdown continues</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/us-warns-it-could-force-20pc-flight-cuts-if-shutdown-continues</link><description>US Transportation Secretary Sean Duffy warned Friday he could force airlines to cut up to 20 per cent of flights if the government shutdown did not end, as US airlines on Friday scrambled to make unprecedented government-imposed reductions.
The Federal Aviation Administration instructed airlines t</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 05:09:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Plight of elderly people: a neglected issue</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/plight-of-elderly-people-a-neglected-issue</link><description>Bangladesh is widely celebrated on the international stage as a development success story. Economic growth has been impressive, infrastructure has expanded, and life expectancy has risen dramatically, reflecting gains in healthcare and quality of life. These achievements are indeed noteworthy, but</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 05:24:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Digital addiction induces tech-violence against women</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/digital-addiction-induces-tech-violence-against-women</link><description>Digital addiction has become a serious problem in the country, especially for children and adolescents, as a large number of them are already trapped in depression and frustration, leading to self-destructive attitudes. The frequent appearance of new smartphone models, coupled with the rise in vari</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 04:54:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Small businesses in a time of strain</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/small-businesses-in-a-time-of-strain</link><description>It is hard to keep up with the dizzying pace at which the country is changing. Cityscapes are evolving every day. In almost every neighbourhood, new buildings have gone up in the last decade and, wherever space allows, more are still going up. These are the years of growth and modernisation that ha</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 05:09:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Getting back nation's stolen assets</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/getting-back-nations-stolen-assets</link><description>Though recovery of money and other assets laundered out of the country by those in power during the tenure of the ousted autocracy and their crony oligarchs was declared a priority by the interim government, yet, it has proved to be a very complex and audacious task. Despite efforts by the differen</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 05:24:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fardin’s father accuses Bushra of involvement, suspect’s family denies allegation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fardins-father-accuses-bushra-of-involvement-suspects-family-denies-allegation</link><description>The mystery behind the death of the Bangladesh University of Engineering and Technology (BUET) student Fardin Noor Parash remains unresolved nearly three years after the incident, as fresh disputes have emerged over the role of Amatullah Bushra, the sole suspect in the case.
Following political sh</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 05:39:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>James Watson, co-discoverer of DNA's double helix, dead at 97</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/james-watson-co-discoverer-of-dnas-double-helix-dead-at-97</link><description>James D Watson, the brilliant but controversial American biologist whose 1953 discovery of the structure of DNA, the molecule of heredity, ushered in the age of genetics and provided the foundation for the biotechnology revolution of the late 20th century, has died at the age of 97.
His death was</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 05:54:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>President Mohammad Shahabuddin reaches Pabna on two-day visit</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/president-mohammad-shahabuddin-reaches-pabna-on-two-day-visit</link><description>President Mohammad Shahabuddin reached his home district of Pabna on Saturday morning for a two-day official visit.
The President landed at Pabna Stadium by helicopter at 9:40 am, where he was received by Deputy Commissioner Mohammad Mofizul Islam and Pabna Police Superintendent Mortoza Ali Khan.</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 06:09:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Deaf woman crushed under train in Lalmonirhat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/deaf-woman-crushed-under-train-in-lalmonirhat</link><description>A 54-year-old deaf woman was crushed under the wheels of a train at the Burimari rail route in Hatibandha upazila of Lalmonirhat district on Saturday.
The deceased was identified as Janiron Begum, wife of Osman Goni of Singimari union, UNB reports.
Quoting witnesses, Mahmudur Nabi, officer-in-cha</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 06:24:48 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>