<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 14:19:16 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Journalist killed in Dhaka road crash</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/journalist-killed-in-dhaka-road-crash</link><description>A 52-year-old journalist was killed when an unidentified vehicle hit his motorbike on Khilgaon Flyover in the capital on Sunday.
The deceased was identified as Zahir Bhuiyan, sports reporter of Daily Vorer Pata and son of Shamsuddin Bhuiya of Muradnagar upazila in Cumilla district.
Zahir, father</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 11:13:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AB Bank inaugurates its relocated Savar Branch</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ab-bank-inaugurates-its-relocated-savar-branch</link><description>AB Bank PLC has recently relocated its Savar Branch to M. A Mannan Tower, Palashbari, Dhamsona, Ashulia, Dhaka.
Mr. Syed Mizanur Rahman, Managing Director &amp; CEO, AB Bank inaugurated the branch through video conference from Bank’s head office, according to a press release.
Savar Branch Manag</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 11:28:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Al-Arafah Islami Bank distributes agricultural investment in Chuadanga</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/al-arafah-islami-bank-distributes-agricultural-investment-in-chuadanga</link><description>Al-Arafah Islami Bank’s Chuadanga Branch organised a public agricultural investment distribution programme at Alukdia in Chuadanga Sadar.
Managing Director (Acting) Mohd. Rafat Ullah Khan distributed agricultural investments worth a total of Tk 25.3 million among 201 farmers at a ceremony he</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 11:43:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BGMEA signs MoU with BFF</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/bgmea-signs-mou-with-bff</link><description>A landmark Memorandum of Understanding (MoU) was signed on Sunday between the Bangladesh Garment Manufacturers and Exporters Association (BGMEA) and the Bangladesh Football Federation (BFF), aiming to enhance the welfare of garment sector workers, promote the growth of football, and strengthen the</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 11:58:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trust Bank signs MoU with RANGS Ltd</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/trust-bank-signs-mou-with-rangs-ltd</link><description>Trust Bank PLC has recently signed an agreement with RANGS Limited, the authorised distributor of Mitsubishi Motors in Bangladesh.
Md. Wahed Ibne Shahed, Head of the Retail Banking Division of Trust Bank and Mohammad Fahim Hossain, Head of Marketing of RANGS Limited, signed the agreement on behalf</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 12:13:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump says Venezuelan airspace should be considered closed</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/trump-says-venezuelan-airspace-should-be-considered-closed</link><description>US President Donald Trump said on Saturday the airspace above and surrounding Venezuela should be considered "closed in its entirety”, but gave no further details, stirring anxiety and confusion in Caracas as his administration ramps up pressure on President Nicolas Maduro's government.
"To</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 12:28:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mercantile Bank’s Motijheel branch shifted to New Location</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/mercantile-banks-motijheel-branch-shifted-to-new-location</link><description>Mercantile Bank PLC's Motijheel branch has been shifted to Dhaka Chamber Building on Sunday (30.11.2025) to provide timely and unmatched banking services.
Managing Director of the Bank Mati Ul Hasan presided over the inaugural event and President of Dhaka Chamber of Commerce &amp; Industries (DCCI) Ta</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 12:43:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Anamul serves legal notice after exclusion from BPL auction list</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/cricket/anamul-serves-legal-notice-after-exclusion-from-bpl-auction-list</link><description>Bangladesh cricketer Anamul Haque Bijoy has served a legal notice to the Bangladesh Cricket Board (BCB), the BPL Governing Council and the Ministry of Youth and Sports after his name was left out of the players’ auction list for the upcoming BPL 2026 season.
The notice, sent by Supreme Court</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 12:58:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How AI is changing the way consumers shop this holiday season</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/how-ai-is-changing-the-way-consumers-shop-this-holiday-season</link><description>Major retailers and tech giants are rolling out new or upgraded artificial intelligence tools for the holiday shopping rush, aiming to make gift buying easier for customers and capture a bigger portion of online sales.
AI-powered shopping is still in its early phase, but the tools launched by Walm</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 13:13:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Special prayers offered at DU for Begum Khaleda Zia’s recovery</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/special-prayers-offered-at-du-for-begum-khaleda-zias-recovery</link><description>Special prayers were offered at Dhaka University (DU) on Sunday seeking the speedy recovery of former Prime Minister and BNP Chairperson Begum Khaleda Zia, who is currently suffering from a critical illness.
The doa mahfil, organised by the DU administration, took place after Zuhr prayers at the u</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 13:28:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka-Delhi ties won’t get stuck over Hasina issue: Foreign Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dhaka-delhi-ties-wont-get-stuck-over-hasina-issue-foreign-adviser</link><description>Seeking convicted former Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina’s extradition, Foreign Affairs Adviser Md Touhid Hossain on Sunday said the relations between Bangladesh and India would not get stuck over a single issue.
He said Bangladesh’s efforts will also continue in line with its demands for</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 13:43:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh Bank extends tenure of Sukuk by additional five years</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/bangladesh-bank-extends-tenure-of-sukuk-by-additional-five-years</link><description>Bangladesh Bank (BB) has extended the tenure of the first Bangladesh Government Investment Sukuk by an additional five years.
This decision, designed to protect the interests of the Sukuk holders and ensure compliance with Shariah guidelines, pushes the maturity date of the instrument back to the</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 13:58:39 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>