<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 19:16:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>An engine hotter than the sun</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/an-engine-hotter-than-the-sun</link><description>Scientists have made an engine that is hotter than the sun's core. But how hot is the sun's core? The temperature of the sun's core is around 15 million degrees Celsius. Usually, the temperature of a typical star's (our sun is also a star) centre is between 10 to 20 million degrees Celsius. To have</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 16:25:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Can the world afford to miss latest US move to end Ukraine war?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/can-the-world-afford-to-miss-latest-us-move-to-end-ukraine-war</link><description>There are moments in global affairs when the trajectory of history pauses just long enough for diplomacy to intervene. The latest US-driven effort to broker an end to the war in Ukraine may well be one of those rare moments. After more than 1,370 days of bloodshed, displacement, economic upheaval a</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 15:42:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>At last IMED diagnoses leather park's malaise!</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/at-last-imed-diagnoses-leather-parks-malaise</link><description>The imbroglio that the Savar Leather Industrial Park finds itself in is the result of ineptitude and concerns other than the overriding one to turn this facility into a world class leather hub.  Begun as early as 2003, the relocation of many tanneries from Dhaka's Hazaribagh took place in 2017</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 15:57:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt to form dedicated taskforce to boost earthquake readiness</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/government-to-establish-dedicated-taskforce-to-boost-earthquake-preparedness</link><description>Following a series of recent tremors, Chief Advisor Muhammad Yunus has said the government will form a taskforce on earthquake preparedness.
He held an emergency meeting with experts and relevant officials on Monday.
According to a statement from the Chief Advisor’s Office, the government w</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 16:12:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BBC not ‘institutionally biased’: memo author</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/bbc-is-not-institutionally-biased-says-author-of-critical-memo</link><description>The author of a report that plunged the BBC into crisis said the broadcaster was not "institutionally biased", and he had hoped his criticisms would lead to improvements.
Michael Prescott, a former editorial advisor, compiled a dossier on issues within BBC News, including failings in the editing o</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 16:27:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IU removes professor over unauthorized absence</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/iu-removes-professor-over-unauthorized-absence</link><description>The authorities of Islamic University in Kushtia dismissed Professor Bikash Chandra Singh of the Information and Communication Technology department, citing unauthorized absence and breaches of institutional discipline.
The decision was issued on Monday in an office order signed by acting registra</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 16:42:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh Bank extends loan rescheduling facility for defaulters</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladesh-bank-extends-loan-rescheduling-facility-for-defaulters</link><description>Bangladesh Bank (BB) has further expanded the scope of policy support available to classified loan borrowers.
All loans classified as adverse (defaulted) on upcoming November 30 will now be eligible for rescheduling under a special facility. This new concession aims to help restructure the busines</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 16:57:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>TIB voices concern over arrest of Baul Abul Sarkar, attack on supporters</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tib-voices-concern-over-arrest-of-baul-abul-sarkar-attack-on-supporters</link><description>Transparency International Bangladesh (TIB) has expressed deep concern over the arrest of Baul artiste Abul Sarkar in Manikganj and the mob attack on his supporters during a peaceful protest, warning that the incidents pose a serious threat to the country’s religious, social and cultural dive</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 17:12:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chattogram Port logs rise in cargo, container flow</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/chattogram-port-logs-rise-in-cargo-container-flow</link><description>Chattogram Port has recorded growth in both container and cargo handling in the first 10 months of the year, with improvements also seen in ship berthing time.
The port authority said in a statement on Monday that about 2.85 million TEUs (20-foot equivalent units) of import and export containers w</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 17:27:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Man hacked to death in front of home in Mohammadpur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/man-hacked-to-death-in-front-of-home-in-mohammadpur</link><description>Police have confirmed the death of a man from hacking at Dhaka Udyan in the capital’s Mohammadpur.
Mohammadpur Police Inspector Mofiz Uddin said the victim, identified as Billal Hossain alias Babu, 26, was hacked in front of his home at 7:45pm.
He was declared dead when taken to the hospita</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 17:58:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique warns against unchecked push for LDC graduation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-warns-against-unchecked-push-for-bangladeshs-ldc-graduation</link><description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman has warned that Bangladesh’s planned graduation from Least Developed Country (LDC) status in 2026 should not proceed without open debate, warning that such a major decision carries long-term economic consequences
In a detailed Facebook post from London on M</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 18:13:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Banks can offer spl loan-rescheduling facility up to Nov 30</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/banks-can-offer-spl-loan-rescheduling-facility-up-to-nov-30</link><description>Commercial banks now can offer special rescheduling facility for up to 10 years with a two-year grace period to borrowers whose loans are classified as of November 30, under a generous government bailout package.
In a major regulatory policy shift, the central bank issued Monday a circular relaxin</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 18:28:07 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>