<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 16:29:05 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Yunus urges religious leaders to help create election awareness</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/yunus-urges-religious-leaders-to-help-raise-public-awareness-about-election-referendum</link><description>Chief Advisor Muhammad Yunus has urged religious leaders to help raise awareness about the parliamentary polls and referendum scheduled for Feb 12.
He made the call while meeting the leaders of the Christian community on Christmas Eve on Wednesday evening at the State Guest House Jamuna.
The Chie</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 14:56:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Social Islami Bank’s administrator team meets branch managers, operation managers, sub-branch chiefs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/social-islami-banks-administrator-team-meets-branch-managers-operation-managers-sub-branch-chiefs</link><description>An exchange of views meeting between the Administrator Team of Social Islami Bank and the Branch Managers, Operation Managers, and Sub-Branch In-charges was held on 22 December 2025.
According to a press release, the meeting was conducted via the Zoom platform from the bank’s Head Office.
B</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 15:11:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pubali Bank holds its 1500th board meeting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/pubali-bank-holds-its-1500th-board-meeting</link><description>Pubali Bank PLC, one of the leading private commercial banks of Bangladesh, on Wednesday held its 1500th Meeting of the Board of Directors, marking a significant milestone in the bank’s long-standing tradition of strong corporate governance, regulatory compliance, and strategic leadership.
A</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 13:57:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Manon becomes Champion in MTB International Master’s Chess Tournament at IUB</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/manon-becomes-champion-in-mtb-international-masters-chess-tournament-at-iub</link><description>Bangladesh’s highest rated International Master (IM) Manon Reja Neer has become Champion in the MTB International Masters Chess Tournament, held at Independent University, Bangladesh (IUB) on December 14-23, 2025.
The 10-day international tournament, which featured three International Master</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 14:12:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Modhumoti Bank holds 92nd meeting of its board of directors</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/modhumoti-bank-holds-92nd-meeting-of-its-board-of-directors</link><description>The 92nd Meeting of the Board of Directors of Modhumoti Bank PLC was held on Wednesday, according to a press release.
Mr. Humayun Kabir, Chairman of the Board of Directors, among the members of the Board of Directors, Mr. Mohammad Ismail Hossain, Mr. Nemai Kumar Saha, Mr. Mostafa Kamal, Mrs. Tanji</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 14:27:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamuna Bank signs corporate deal with Best Western Plus Bay Hills, Cox’s Bazar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/jamuna-bank-signs-corporate-deal-with-best-western-plus-bay-hills-coxs-bazar</link><description>Jamuna Bank PLC has signed a corporate agreement with Best Western Plus Bay Hills, Cox’s Bazar on December 9, 2025 at Jamuna Bank Tower, Gulshan-1, Dhaka, according to a press release.
The agreement was formally signed by Noor Mohammed, Deputy Managing Director &amp; CBO of Jamuna Bank PLC, and</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 14:42:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Riaz named chief coordinator for voter awareness drive</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ali-riaz-to-lead-awareness-campaign-on-general-election-referendum</link><description>Ali Riaz, special assistant to the chief advisor with the rank of advisor, has been appointed chief coordinator for public awareness campaigns on the parliamentary polls and referendum.
The appointment was confirmed on Wednesday in a letter signed by Mohammad Abdul Wadud Chowdhury, director genera</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 14:57:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IFIC Bank holds awareness workshop on AML, CFT compliance for board members</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ific-bank-holds-awareness-workshop-on-aml-cft-compliance-for-board-members</link><description>IFIC Bank PLC organized an Awareness Workshop on Anti Money Laundering and Combating the Financing of Terrorism AML and CFT compliance for the members of the Bank’s Board of Directors on December 21, 2025.
Chairman of the bank Mr. Md. Mehmood Husain along with all members of the Board of Dir</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 15:12:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EBL wins ICMAB Bronze Award</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ebl-wins-icmab-bronze-award</link><description>Eastern Bank PLC (EBL) has won the Bronze Award in the Private Commercial Bank category at the ICMAB Best Corporate Award 2025, in recognition of its significant contribution to the banking sector and the national economy, according to a press release.
The award was formally presented by Sk. Bashi</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 15:27:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BRAC Bank, Pragati Life reward Bancassurance campaign winners with air tickets</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/brac-bank-pragati-life-reward-bancassurance-campaign-winners-with-air-tickets</link><description>BRAC Bank has recognised the top performers of its bancassurance campaign, ‘Cholo Bidesh’. The campaign was conducted in strategic partnership with Pragati Life Insurance PLC, according to a press release.
The initiative marked a notable milestone in BRAC Bank’s growing bancassur</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 15:42:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>N’ganj child killed for screaming during ‘attempted rape’: Police</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/three-in-narayanganj-kill-child-for-screaming-during-attempted-rape-say-police</link><description>A fifth-grader in Narayanganj’s Bandar Upazila has been abducted and strangled to death after she screamed while resisting an attempted rape, police say.
Bandar Police chief Golam Muktar Ashraf said one of the three arrested suspects gave a confessional statement under Section 164 on Wednesd</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 15:57:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AB Bank opens its sub-branch at Kankirhat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ab-bank-opens-its-sub-branch-at-kankirhat</link><description>AB Bank PLC inaugurated its Kankirhat sub-branch on December 24, 2025, as the 60th sub-branch of the bank. The sub-branch is located at Bhuiyan Market, Birkot, Kesharpar, Senbug, Noakhali, according to a press release.
Mr. Reazul Islam, Managing Director and CEO (Acting), AB Bank inaugurated the s</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 16:12:32 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>