<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 05:30:29 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Consequences of interim govt's indifference to law and order</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/consequences-of-interim-govts-indifference-to-law-and-order</link><description>The press wing of the Chief Adviser has admitted that 645 incidents of violence against members of the minority communities occurred in 2025 but it clarifies that of those 71 could be categorised as communal. Only recently did the Human Rights Watch (HRW) expressed its deep concern over the rising</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 17:15:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Restructuring for administrative efficiency</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/restructuring-for-administrative-efficiency</link><description>In a significant move aimed at streamlining administrative efficiency, the interim government has recently unveiled a set of restructuring decisions involving steps towards enhancing transparency, efficiency and accountability across key state institutions. Presided over by the Chief Adviser, the m</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 17:30:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP leader shot and injured in Keraniganj</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-leader-shot-and-injured-in-keraniganj</link><description>A local BNP leader was injured in a gun attack by miscreants in Keraniganj on Thursday night.The victim was identified as Hasan Mollah, secretary of Hazratpur Union BNP under the Dhaka-2 constituency, UNB reports. He was shot by unidentified assailants around 9:00pm, said M Saiful Alam, Office</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 18:16:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka court rejects journalist Anis Alamgir’s bail in anti-terror case</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dhaka-court-rejects-journalist-anis-alamgirs-bail-in-anti-terror-case</link><description>A Dhaka court has rejected journalist Anis Alamgir’s bail petition in a case filed under the Anti-Terrorism Act.
Judge Md Alamgir of the Additional Metropolitan Sessions Judge’s Court-1 passed the order on Thursday, lawyer Taslima Jahan Popy confirmed, bdnews24.com reports.
The CMM co</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 18:31:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BB autonomy, banking reform legislation before long</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bb-autonomy-banking-reform-legislation-before-long</link><description>Central bank autonomy and banking-reform bills of legislation before long as the finance adviser pledges a push within the interim government tenure as experts plead for healing chronic banking ills.
Dr Salehuddin Ahmed said at a meet Thursday that the interim government would make a final push to</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 19:39:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Process of implementing new pay scale starts forthwith</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/process-of-implementing-new-pay-scale-starts-forthwith</link><description>Take-home pay packet of public service-holders begins to fatten soon as officials at the Ministry of Finance are learnt to have started the process of implementing the just-recommended new pay scale.
People familiar with the development said the work began just after the members of the Pay Commiss</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 02:08:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>'Jamaat to build a society based on justice, dignity'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-to-build-a-society-based-on-justice-dignity</link><description>The Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami has formally launched its campaign for the upcoming national elections in the capital.
Its Ameer Dr Shafiqur Rahman inaugurated the campaign on Thursday in the Dhaka-15 constituency (Mirpur-Kafrul) as a nominated candidate.
He started the campaign through a rally at</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 02:23:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A project that ended but did not really end</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/a-project-that-ended-but-did-not-really-end</link><description>The government is yet to find ways to close one of the troubled projects of the Awami League regime, though the proposal for extending its deadline and increasing the cost was rejected in July last year.
Sources say a meeting chaired by Muhammad Fouzul Kabir Khan, adviser for rail and road transpo</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 02:38:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Control of Land Utilisation and Farm Land Protection Ordinance promulgated</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/control-of-land-utilisation-and-farm-land-protection-ordinance-promulgated</link><description>The government has promulgated the "Control of Land Utilisation and Farm Land Protection Ordinance, 2026" introducing penalties of up to three years' imprisonment or Tk 1 million in fines or both for misuse of land, including agricultural land.
The Ordinance stipulates that cultivated land must no</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 02:53:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Over 48pc candidates are businesspersons</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/over-48pc-candidates-are-businesspersons</link><description>More than 48 per cent of the candidates contesting the upcoming national elections in February are businessmen, according to the candidates' affidavits analysed by Transparency International Bangladesh (TIB).
The figure is the lowest since the ninth parliamentary election.
It was 57.67 per cent i</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 03:08:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump says US 'armada' heading toward Iran</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-says-us-armada-heading-toward-iran</link><description>President Donald Trump said on Thursday that the United States has an "armada" heading toward Iran but hoped he would not have to use it, as he renewed warnings to Tehran against killing protesters or restarting its nuclear program.
US officials, speaking on condition of anonymity, say the aircraf</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 04:15:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US withdraws from World Health Organization</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-withdraws-from-world-health-organization</link><description>The United States officially left the World Health Organization on Thursday after a year of warnings that doing so would hurt public health in the US and globally, saying its decision reflected failures in the UN health agency's management of the Covid-19 pandemic.
President Donald Trump gave noti</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 04:30:48 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>