<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 02:07:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Jamaat-BNP clash in Chuadanga leaves 14 injured</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jamaat-bnp-clash-in-chuadanga-leaves-14-injured</link><description>At least 14 people were injured in a clash between supporters of Jamaat-e-Islami and the Bangladesh Nationalist Party in Chuadanga’s Alamdanga upazila on Sunday afternoon.
The incident took place in Jugirhuda village under Khadimpur Union.
BNP leaders alleged that the clash erupted after Ja</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 16:45:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>8 Sylhet Medical University officials jailed in ACC case</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/8-sylhet-medical-university-officials-jailed-in-acc-case</link><description>A court on Sunday ordered eight officials and employees of Sylhet Medical University to be sent to jail in a corruption case filed by the Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC).
The Sylhet Metropolitan Sessions Judge, Munshi Abdul Majid, directed their imprisonment after they surrendered to the court. T</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 17:00:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh gold market breaks record as prices hit Tk 257,191 per bhori</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-gold-market-breaks-record-as-prices-hit-tk-257191-per-bhori</link><description>Gold prices in Bangladesh have surged once again, with the Bangladesh Jewellers Association (BAJUS) setting a new all-time high for the precious metal.
According to a notification issued on Sunday night, BAJUS increased the price of 22-carat gold by Tk 1,574 per bhori, fixing it at Tk 257,191 &amp;mda</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 17:15:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ASK slates denial of parole for Saddam</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/denying-saddam-parole-for-wife-and-childs-burial-violates-rights-constitution-ask</link><description>Human rights group Ain o Salish Kendra (ASK) has termed the denial of parole to Bagerhat Chhatra League leader Jewel Hasan Saddam to attend the funeral of his wife and 9‑month‑old child a clear violation of the Constitution and international law.
In a statement on Sunday, ASK said the family had f</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 16:46:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Publishers seek to defer Ekushey Book Fair beyond Feb 20</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/publishers-seek-to-defer-ekushey-book-fair-beyond-feb-20</link><description>Publishers have called for the Amar Ekushey Book Fair to be postponed until after Eid-ul-Fitr, instead of starting on post-election Feb 20 as decided earlier.
On Jan 19, 262 publishers wrote to the president of the Bangladesh Book Publishers and Sellers Association requesting a revision of the fai</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 17:01:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump threatens internatio nal order</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/trump-threatens-internatio-nal-order</link><description>The Trump Administration's sweeping Executive Order issued in the first half of January stipulates the withdrawal of the United States from dozens of United Nations bodies and international organisations. This latest decision by the United States is being viewed as a targeted assault on multilatera</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 17:16:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Invisible labour of sustainability: recognising the care work</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/reviews/invisible-labour-of-sustainability-recognising-the-care-work</link><description>A pre-dawn darkness in a village in the Rajshahi district is illuminated only by the acrid scent of smoke, invigorating a woman as she rises in her mud-walled kitchen. Her hands, hardened by years of toil, tend the chula (stove) fuelled by wood and cow dung, the fire crackling as she prepares a mea</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 17:31:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Kitchen market growing jittery once again</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/kitchen-market-growing-jittery-once-again</link><description>Kitchen market serves as the pulse of microeconomics in a country. Prices, however affordable or not, depend on supply of essentials due to seasonal variations. Winter is the time when there is a surfeit of vegetables in market and naturally prices fall. But Bangladesh is a country that often defie</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 17:46:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Saga of hapless migrant workers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/saga-of-hapless-migrant-workers</link><description>Past and present governments of Bangladesh have traditionally been very effusive in praising the hard work the migrant workers do abroad and send home their precious dollars. But they have not been equally concerned about what these foreign-bound job-seekers go through once they are in the hands of</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 18:01:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Repatriation of Rohingya not a forgotten issue</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/repatriation-of-rohingya-not-a-forgotten-issue</link><description>Strange are the ways of the world and of some world bodies. During the last Ramadan, standing beside UN Secretary General Antonio Guterres in a refugee camp, Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus expressed his hope that the Rohingya community would be able to offer their next Eid prayers in their</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 18:16:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Economy to grow at 5pc in 2026</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/economy-to-grow-at-5pc-in-2026</link><description>The General Economics Division (GED) has projected a delicate balance between a recovering growth trajectory and persistent structural hurdles, saying the economy could grow at 5.0 per cent in the current calendar year.



According to the January 2026 Economic Update and Outlook released on</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 18:31:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New pay scale could fuel bribery 'premiums' without reforms to public admin: TIB</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/new-pay-scale-could-fuel-bribery-premiums-without-reforms-to-public-admin-tib</link><description>While acknowledging the rationale behind the initiative to increase the salaries and allowances of government employees, Transparency International Bangladesh (TIB) has called for an assessment of the economic capacity to bear such an additional burden.
The organization also stressed the need for</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 19:44:16 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>