<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 03:24:40 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Jaishankar wishes Bangladesh well for polls, hopes deepened neighbourly ties</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jaishankar-wishes-bangladesh-well-for-polls-hopes-deepened-neighbourly-ties</link><description>Wishing Bangladesh well for the upcoming national election, Indian External Affairs Minister Dr S Jaishankar on Friday said the sense of neighbourlyness in the region will grow once things settle down.
"Right now, they (Bangladesh) are heading for elections. We wish them well in that elections. We</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 16:45:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Affidavit shows JSD leader Tania Rab far wealthier than Abdur Rab</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/affidavit-shows-jsd-leader-tania-rab-far-wealthier-than-abdur-rab</link><description>Tania Rab, senior vice-president of Jatiya Samajtantrik Dal-JSD, has declared assets worth nearly 14 times more than those of her husband and party chief ASM Abdur Rab.
The affidavits filed with her nomination for the Lakshmipur-4 constituency in the general election show her annual also surpasses</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 17:00:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A diplomatic note under public scrutiny</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/a-diplomatic-note-under-public-scrutiny</link><description>The condolence letter, penned and signed by Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi and addressed to Tarique Rahman in tribute to Khaleda Zia upon her passing, has arrived in Bangladesh at a moment in history laden with meaning. On one hand, since it is couched in terms of a formal expression of sympat</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 17:15:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Economy: Let's set the tone right in 2026</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/reviews/economy-lets-set-the-tone-right-in-2026</link><description>Despite known and evolving challenges, Bangladesh economy has demonstrated good consolidation in 2025. Market liquidity especially foreign currency liquidity improved much with significant rise in wage earners' remittances, moderate rise in exports and foreign aid disbursement. Inflation continued</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 17:30:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Year 2026 and a few key anniversaries</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/year-2026-and-a-few-key-anniversaries</link><description>Another year on the Gregorian calendar, the globally accepted civil calendar, began two days ago on Thursday. People around the world enthusiastically welcomed 2026. Celebrating the night of December 31 to say goodbye to the old year and greet January 1 is mainly a Western tradition. Over the decad</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 17:45:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dignified farewell to Begum Zia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/dignified-farewell-to-begum-zia</link><description>As an ending, it was the height of dignity. Hundreds of thousands of Bangladeshis from across the country gathered to pay their last respects, alongside foreign delegates, as she was laid to rest with full state honours beside her husband. This collective act of homage stood as a final testament to</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 18:00:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Developing a pre-poll cybersecurity wall</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/developing-a-pre-poll-cybersecurity-wall</link><description>With the 13th parliamentary election drawing closer and campaigns launched by different political parties going to start in full swing soon, the cyberspace is abuzz. So, alongside an expected atmosphere of festive electioneering, there are also the dangers of a rising spate of cybercrimes. Evidentl</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 18:15:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mobile-phone users startled finding myriad devices under each NID</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/mobile-phone-users-startled-finding-myriad-devices-under-each-nid</link><description>A ruckus centering the National Equipment Identity Register (NEIR) rollout has ensued and a weird revelation of umpteen devices surreptitiously connected with each NID startled mobile-phone users.



The bizarre finds stoke concerns among the users as to whether their sets were being used by fr</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 18:30:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Taka devaluation decelerates for policy buttress against dive</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/taka-devaluation-decelerates-for-policy-buttress-against-dive</link><description>Local-currency taka depreciated marginally in the just-past calendar year as policy buttress and steady dollar flow deterred steep devaluation suffered in 2024, sources say.
This is due to tighter monetary policy, strong dollar inflow and subdued demand for the greenback, according to central bank</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 02:01:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Commercial court ordinance issued</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/commercial-court-ordinance-issued</link><description>President Mohammed Shahabuddin has signed the Commercial Court Ordinance 2026, a landmark move for speedy, efficient, and transparent adjudication for commercial disputes.
The gazette, issued on Thursday night, said the ordinance would come into effect immediately.
Analysts say this initiative is</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 02:16:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt issues new shipping agent licensing rules</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/govt-issues-new-shipping-agent-licensing-rules</link><description>The government has issued the country's first-ever shipping agent licensing rules, marking a significant step towards streamlining the operations of shipping agents across the nation.
Under the new guidelines, agents who obtain licences from any river port or seaport customs station will now be ab</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 02:31:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Midsize projects also face budget downsizing</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/midsize-projects-also-face-budget-downsizing</link><description>Many midsize development schemes also find their fate entwined with megaprojects in the infrastructure sector in downsizing budget outlays as the interim government tries to make two ends meet with limited funds.
Sources say a large number of medium-scale development schemes under the Annual Devel</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 02:46:56 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>