<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 11:18:33 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Three of a family die as truck collides with ambulance in Faridpur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/three-of-a-family-die-as-truck-collides-with-ambulance-in-faridpur</link><description>Three members of a family have been killed after an ambulance collided head-on with a truck in Faridpur.
Two others were injured in the accident that occurred around 7:30 am on Saturday in the Munsurabad area on the Bhanga–Khulna highway, according to Bhanga Highway Police Station chief (OC)</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 08:14:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC to decide on Tarique, Zaima’s inclusion in voter list for 2026 polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-to-decide-on-tarique-zaimas-inclusion-in-voter-list-for-2026-polls</link><description>The Election Commission will decide on the inclusion of BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman and his daughter Zaima Rahman in the national voter list, which will be used for the upcoming general election and the referendum scheduled for February 12, 2026.
"Their names will be placed before the commi</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 08:29:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>RMG exporters seek re-fixing of cash incentives on local yarn</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/rmg-exporters-seek-re-fixing-of-cash-incentives-on-local-yarn</link><description>Apparel exporters have called for the restoration and re-fixing of cash incentives on the use of local yarn, citing the deteriorating condition of domestic spinning mills and the need to improve export competitiveness.
They have proposed restoring the cash incentive on the use of local yarn in exp</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 08:44:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Max SIMs under single NID cut down to five</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/max-sims-under-single-nid-cut-down-to-five</link><description>he Bangladesh Telecommunication Regulatory Commission (BTRC) has decided to reduce the number of SIM cards that can be registered under a single National Identity Card (NID), setting a new ceiling of five per individual, to be effective from 1 January 2026.
Under the revised policy, any SIMs excee</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 08:59:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique visits graves of brother Coco, father-in-law</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-visits-graves-of-brother-coco-father-in-law</link><description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman has visited the graves of his younger brother and father-in-law in Dhaka, a day after paying tribute at his father’s burial site.
Tarique arrived at Banani Graveyard around 2pm on Saturday to visit the grave of his younger brother, Arafat Rahman Coco. He st</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 09:45:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rashed Khan leaves Gono Odhikar Parishad to join BNP</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/rashed-khan-leaves-gono-odhikar-parishad-to-join-bnp</link><description>Rashed Khan, the general secretary of Gono Odhikar Parishad, has left the party and officially joined the BNP.
He joined the BNP by presenting a bouquet to BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir at the chairperson’s office at Dhaka’s Gulshan on Saturday, reports bdnews24.com</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 10:00:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shrine vandalised overnight in Thakurgaon</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/shrine-vandalised-overnight-in-thakurgaon</link><description>A shrine in Thakurgaon town has reportedly been vandalised under the cover of darkness, prompting tensions among local residents and devotees.
The shrine, known as the Hazrat Baba Shah Satyapir Mazar, was damaged at some point on Friday night in the Satyapir Bridge area of the town, according to T</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 09:45:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique offers fateha at graves of Pilkhana martyrs, father-in-law</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-offers-fateha-at-graves-of-pilkhana-martyrs-father-in-law</link><description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman on Saturday visited the graves of the slain army officers of the 2009 Pilkhana tragedy at the Banani Military Graveyard in the capital.
He offered fateha and paid homage to the military officers who were killed during the 2009 BDR mutiny at Pilkhana in Dhaka.
Ta</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 10:00:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Move underway to ensure 20pc power subsidy for fisheries: Adviser Farida</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/move-underway-to-ensure-20pc-power-subsidy-for-fisheries-adviser-farida</link><description>The government is working to extend a 20 per cent electricity subsidy to the fisheries sector, similar to the incentive currently enjoyed by agriculture, Fisheries and Livestock Adviser Farida Akhter said on Saturday.
"The fisheries sector does not yet receive subsidised electricity like agricultu</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 10:15:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Army chief says Switzerland can't defend itself from full-scale attack</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/army-chief-says-switzerland-cant-defend-itself-from-full-scale-attack</link><description>Switzerland cannot defend itself against a full-scale attack and must boost military spending given rising risks from Russia, the head of its armed forces said.
The country is prepared for attacks by "non-state actors" on critical infrastructure and for cyber attacks, but its military still faces</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 10:30:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>What lies ahead for Ukraine's contested Zaporizhzhia nuclear power plant?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/what-lies-ahead-for-ukraines-contested-zaporizhzhia-nuclear-power-plant</link><description>The Zaporizhzhia nuclear power plant, Europe's largest, is one of the main sticking points in US President Donald Trump's peace plan to end the nearly four-year war between Russia and Ukraine.
The issue is one of 20 points laid out by Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelenskiy in a framework peace pr</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 10:45:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Explosion at Keraniganj madrasa injures four</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/explosion-at-keraniganj-madrasa-injures-four</link><description>An explosion ripped through a madrasa in the Hasnabad area of South Keraniganj, Dhaka, on Friday morning, injuring four people, including a woman and two children, police said.
The blast occurred around 10:30 am at a single-storey building of Ummal Qura International Madrasa, blowing off the walls</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 11:00:45 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>