<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 06:38:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>CSE revises blue-chip index</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/cse-revises-blue-chip-index</link><description>The Chittagong Stock Exchange (CSE) has revised its CSE-30 Index based on the performance of listed companies.
The new index will come into effect on December 18. The port city’s bourse reviews the index twice a year.
After the latest revision, three companies have been included in the CSE-</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 03:18:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Unionised RMG workers earn 10pc more than non-unionised peers: Study</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/unionised-rmg-workers-earn-10pc-more-than-non-unionised-peers-study</link><description>A new study has found that unionised readymade garment (RMG) factory workers earn an average of 10 per cent higher wages compared to their non-unionised counterparts in the RMG sector, as well as non-RMG workers.
The study, presented at the Annual BIDS Conference, also reveals that workers in the</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 03:33:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DB detains ex-Press Club president Shawkat Mahmud</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/db-detains-ex-press-club-president-shawkat-mahmud</link><description>The Detective Branch (DB) of police detained the secretary general of the Janata Party of Bangladesh, Shawkat Mahmud, from his Malibag residence in the capital on Sunday.
Mahmud was also a former vice-chairman of BNP and a former president of the National Press Club.
Deputy Commissioner of police</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 03:48:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Special initiative taken to manage stray dogs on St. Martin's Island</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/special-initiative-taken-to-manage-stray-dogs-on-st-martins-island</link><description>The government has taken up a special initiative to manage the dog population on St. Martin's Island as part of a broader effort to protect the island's fragile environment and biodiversity, particularly its endangered marine turtles.
St. Martin's is the only coral island in Bangladesh, situated i</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 04:03:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Much-longed for bridge lies incomplete for years in Sylhet</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/much-longed-for-bridge-lies-incomplete-for-years-in-sylhet</link><description>Construction works for a bridge over the Chhora River - long demanded by students and workers in the Surma tea garden area in Madhabpur Upazila - remain incomplete for years.
The earthen access route at one side of the bridge - which enabled some people to use the structure in the absence of a con</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 04:18:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Adilur for strengthening SME Foundation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/adilur-for-strengthening-sme-foundation</link><description>Advisor for Industries, Housing and Public Works Adilur Rahman Khan has laid importance on strengthening the SME Foundation structurally to further energise the small and medium enterprise sector and accelerate its development for expanding domestic and international markets for different products.</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 04:33:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mobile phone traders demand reforms to NEIR</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/mobile-phone-traders-demand-reforms-to-neir</link><description>Mobile phone traders on Sunday staged a demonstration in the capital's Agargaon area demanding the reform of NEIR initiative.
The road in front of BTRC building was blocked as part of the protest - held under the banner of "Bangladesh Mobile Business Community" around 10 AM.
General Secretary of</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 04:48:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BD, Thailand willing to expand trade relations</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bd-thailand-willing-to-expand-trade-relations</link><description>Bangladesh and Thailand want to further expand their existing trade relations and make more effective use of maritime transport facilities between the two nations.
The views came when Thailand Ambassador to Bangladesh, Thitiporn Chirasawadi, made a courtesy call on Commerce Adviser Sk Bashir Uddin</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 05:03:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>38th AGM of Kohinoor Chemical held</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/38th-agm-of-kohinoor-chemical-held</link><description>The 38th Annual General Meeting (AGM) of Kohinoor Chemical Company (BD) Limited was held at 3:15 pm on Sunday on a digital platform.
Md Rezaul Karim, managing director of Kohinoor Chemical Company, was present at the meeting, says a media release.
Md Ebadul Karim, director, Prof Dr Anwar Hossain,</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 05:18:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt set to implement new project to digitise medical, nursing education</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/govt-set-to-implement-new-project-to-digitise-medical-nursing-education</link><description>The government has taken a project aimed at streamlining and strengthening the management of medical, population and nursing education services across the country.
The project “Integrated Improvement in the Management of Activities of the Directorate General of Medical Education (DGME), NIPO</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 05:33:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two Bangladeshi workers die in Maldives</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/two-bangladeshi-workers-die-in-maldives</link><description>Two Bangladeshi migrant workers have reportedly died from cardiac complications within a span of 12 hours in the Maldives.
The men, Ahmed Kamal, 48, and Selim Uddin, 64, were both from Moulvibazar district, reports bdnews24.com.
Md Jasim Uddin, welfare assistant at the Bangladesh High Commission,</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 05:48:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Thailand launches air strikes at Cambodia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/thailand-launches-air-strikes-at-cambodia</link><description>Thailand has launched air strikes along its disputed border with Cambodia, the Thai military said on Monday, after both countries accused the other of breaching a ceasefire agreement brokered by US President Donald Trump.
At least one Thai soldier has been killed, and four wounded in the fresh cla</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 06:03:30 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>