<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 14:23:34 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Fire erupts at DU’s Bijoy Ekattor Hall</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fire-erupts-at-dus-bijoy-ekattor-hall</link><description>A fire has broken out at a shop in Bijoy Ekattor Hall at Dhaka University following a gas cylinder explosion amid a closure for earthquake precaution, Fire Service officials and students have said.
The flames ignited around 6:30pm on Monday, though no casualties were reported.
Student Asif Khan s</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 12:45:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ExchangeKori, Star Tech launch gaming and graphics PC exchange service</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/exchangekori-star-tech-launch-gaming-and-graphics-pc-exchange-service</link><description>For the first time in Bangladesh, consumers can now trade in their old laptops or desktop computers to purchase new gaming and graphics PCs.
The special campaign, titled “Power Up Your Game,” has been introduced by device exchange platform ExchangeKori Limited, with leading gaming hard</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 13:00:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>United Finance launches startup loan ‘URise’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/united-finance-launches-startup-loan-urise</link><description>United Finance has officially launched ‘URise’, a dedicated loan program designed to empower startups under Bangladesh Bank’s refinancing scheme.
The inauguration ceremony was recently held at the company’s head office, marking a significant step toward fostering innovation</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 11:45:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cracks appear in Secretariat building due to quake</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cracks-appear-in-secretariat-building-due-to-quake</link><description>Cracks have developed in the newly constructed Building-1 of the Bangladesh Secretariat following Friday's moderate earthquake, which claimed at least 10 lives and left over 600 injured across the country.
Located in the northwest corner of the Secretariat, the building houses the Cabinet Division</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 12:00:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jimmy Cliff, reggae music pioneer, dies at 81</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/entertainment/jimmy-cliff-reggae-music-pioneer-dies-at-81</link><description>Jimmy Cliff, the legendary Jamaican singer who along with Bob Marley popularised reggae, ska and rocksteady music over a six decade career, has died, his wife Latifa Chambers announced on Facebook on Monday.
The cause was a seizure followed by pneumonia, she said.
Born James Chambers on Jul 30, 1</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 12:15:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ICAB, ICAEW facilitate membership pathways and joint educational initiatives</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/icab-icaew-facilitate-membership-pathways-and-joint-educational-initiatives</link><description>The Institute of Chartered Accountants of Bangladesh (ICAB) and the Institute of Chartered Accountants in England and Wales (ICAEW) formally signed the Extension Agreement to the existing ICAEW–ICAB Memorandum of Understanding (MoU) recently at Chartered Accountants' Hall, Moorgate Place, Lon</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 12:30:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Amazon sites in Italy raided by police in China smuggling probe, sources say</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/amazon-sites-in-italy-raided-by-police-in-china-smuggling-probe-sources-say</link><description>Italian police carried out searches and seizures at two Amazon (AMZN.O)  sites in Italy on Monday as part of an investigation into the alleged smuggling of Chinese goods, three people with direct knowledge of the matter said.
Dozens of officers from the Guardia di Finanza tax police and the c</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 12:45:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt approves Tk 7.26 billion for road, haor-area projects</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-approves-tk-726-billion-for-road-haor-area-projects</link><description>The government on Monday approved important development projects worth over Tk 7.26 billion, including road infrastructure upgrades and elevated roads in haor areas.
The approval came from the 47th meeting of the Advisers Council Committee on Government Purchase this year held today at the Cabinet</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 13:00:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Four killed in Pabna, Chuadanga road crashes</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/four-killed-in-pabna-chuadanga-road-crashes</link><description>Four people were killed in different road accidents in Pabna and Chuadanga on Monday.
In Pabna, a man and his daughter were killed when a truck hit a motorcycle on Dhaka-Pabna highway at Uttar Durgapur in Sujanagar upazila of the district on Monday evening.
The deceased were identified as Zabidul</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 13:15:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Market shows stabilization following decisions to permit rice imports:  Salehuddin</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/market-shows-stabilization-following-decisions-to-permit-rice-imports-salehuddin</link><description>Finance Adviser Dr Salehuddin Ahmed today (Monday) said that the market has shown partial stabilization following recent decisions to permit rice imports.
"The government's recent initiative to import non-Basmati rice aims to stabilise prices," he said, BSS reports. 
The finance adviser was</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 13:30:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>What other health conditions are weight-loss drugs being used and tested for?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/what-other-health-conditions-are-weight-loss-drugs-being-used-and-tested-for</link><description>Novo Nordisk said an older version of its weight-loss drug semaglutide failed to meet its main goal in late-stage trials testing whether the medicine can slow cognitive decline in Alzheimer’s patients.
The results is a blow to hopes that Alzheimer’s could open a major new market for GL</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 13:45:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IMF says Poland must prioritise curbing increase in debt</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/global/imf-says-poland-must-prioritise-curbing-increase-in-debt</link><description>Poland must prioritise curbing the rapid increase in its public debt, the International Monetary Fund said on Monday, adding that it sees rising fiscal vulnerabilities over the medium term.
Strong growth in central Europe's largest economy, driven by wage gains and loose fiscal policy, has come pa</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 14:00:59 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>