<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 16:39:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Citizens Bank holds Annual Business Conference 2026</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/citizens-bank-holds-annual-business-conference-2026</link><description>Citizens Bank PLC held its Annual Business Conference 2026 on January 17, 2026, at a resort in Munshiganj, according to a press release.
Mr. Chowdhury Mohammed Hanif Shoeb, Chairman of the bank, graced the conference as the Chief Guest and delivered strategic guidance aligned with the bank’s</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 13:28:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bank Asia Agent Banking marks its 12th anniversary with a milestone of 7.5 million customers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bank-asia-agent-banking-marks-its-12th-anniversary-with-a-milestone-of-75-million-customers</link><description>Bank Asia Agent Banking marked its 12th founding anniversary by celebrating a remarkable milestone—bringing 7.5 million customers into the formal financial system and transforming access to banking services across Bangladesh, according to a press release.
As the pioneer of Agent Banking in t</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 13:43:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Al-Arafah Islami Bank holds training course on leadership development in branch management</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/al-arafah-islami-bank-holds-training-course-on-leadership-development-in-branch-management-1</link><description>A 3-day training course titled “Leadership Development in Branch Management” has started at the bank’s Training Institute at Al-Arafah Islami Bank.
Managing Director and CEO of the bank Mohd Rafat Ullah Khan inaugurated the training workshop as the chief guest on Tuesday, accordi</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 13:58:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat-BNP clash sparks tension in Mirpur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-bnp-activists-scuffle-over-pre-polls-campaigning-triggers-tension-in-mirpur</link><description>Tension has flared in Dhaka’s Mirpur after activists of the Jamaat-e-Islami and BNP were involved in a scuffle over the distribution of campaign leaflets ahead of the official start of electioneering.
The incident took place on Tuesday evening outside the Pirerbagh Al Mubarak Mosque under Mi</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 14:13:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DNCC sets rules to protect tenants’ rights</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dncc-sets-16-rules-for-landlords-rent-hikes-allowed-every-2-years</link><description>The Dhaka North City Corporation has issued 16 instructions for landlords in Dhaka to protect tenants’ rights.
The instructions allow the rents to be hiked only once in every two years.
Tenants will have unrestricted access to their homes and the roof at all times, the instructions said.
L</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 14:28:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Padma Bridge draws Tk 30.0 billion as toll since 2022 opening</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/padma-bridge-draws-tk-300-billion-as-toll-since-2022-opening</link><description>The government has collected so far Tk 30.0 billion as revenue from the users of the Padma Bridge since its June 25, 2022 opening, Bangladesh Bridge Authority (BBA) said in a statement today.
It said the bridge that connected 21 southwestern districts with the rest of the country was increasingly</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 14:43:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>July Uprising Memorial Museum will show path to nation: CA</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/july-uprising-memorial-museum-will-show-path-to-nation-ca</link><description>Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus on Tuesday said that if the nation becomes bewildered for any reason it will find path in the July Uprising Memorial Museum, noting it has been possible to build the museum while the blood of the July martyrs is still fresh.
 “It has been possible</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 14:28:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chief adviser visits July Uprising Memorial Museum</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/chief-adviser-visits-july-uprising-memorial-museum</link><description>Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus on Tuesday inspected the progress of the final phase work of the July Uprising Memorial Museum at the Ganabhaban, residence of the ousted prime minister Sheikh Hasina, in Dhaka.
The Chief Adviser arrived at the museum around 3pm and went around the museum tha</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 14:43:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Economy suffering from ‘overregulation’: Khosru</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/economy-suffering-from-overregulation-says-amir-khosru</link><description>BNP Standing Committee member Amir Khosru Mahmud Chowdhury on Tuesday said Bangladesh’s economy, including its capital market, is currently being stifled by ‘overregulation’ and it must move towards deregulation and liberalisation to recover.
He made the remarks while speaking at</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 14:58:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘We’ve taken risk of hybrid postal balloting with courage’: CEC Nasir</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/weve-taken-risk-of-hybrid-postal-balloting-with-courage-says-cec-nasir</link><description>Chief Election Commissioner (CEC) AMM Nasir Uddin on Tuesday said the Election Commission has courageously taken the risk of introducing an IT-supported hybrid postal balloting system despite being fully aware that many problems and challenges may arise with the process.
“When our Chief Advi</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 15:13:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP promises jobs, social security, and reform in election push</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-promises-jobs-social-security-and-reform-in-election-push</link><description>Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) has conveyed its eight-point priority social policies, including a sweeping reform agenda, pledging to rebuild the country’s economy and social fabric after what they describe as years of mismanagement under the previous authoritarian regime of the Awami Lea</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 15:28:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh Bank buys $45m from two banks to bolster reserves</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh-bank-buys-45m-from-two-banks-to-bolster-reserves</link><description>In its continued effort to stabilize the foreign exchange market and build up national reserves, Bangladesh Bank (BB) purchased an additional $45 million from two commercial banks on Tuesday (January 20).
The dollars were bought at a fixed exchange rate of Tk 122.30, with the cut-off rate also set</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 15:43:47 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>