<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 12:53:56 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>3 dead as train rams pickup van in Faridpur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/3-dead-as-train-rams-pickup-van-in-faridpur</link><description>Three passengers on a pickup van have been killed after a train ploughed into their vehicle at a rail crossing in Faridpur’s Boalmari Upazila.
The incident occurred at the Sutashi Rail Crossing on Monday afternoon, according to Mizanur Rahman, chief of Kalukhali Railway Police Station.</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 10:02:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump says Iran proposed negotiations as hundreds killed in protests</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-says-iran-proposed-negotiations-as-hundreds-killed-in-protests</link><description>US President Donald Trump says Iran has proposed negotiations after his threat to strike the Islamic Republic as an ongoing crackdown on demonstrators has led to hundreds of deaths.  Trump said late Sunday that his administration was in talks to set up a meeting with Tehran, but cautioned that</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 10:17:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Wild elephant kills 20 in India’s Jharkhand as rescue teams struggle to track it</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/wild-elephant-kills-20-in-indias-jharkhand-as-rescue-teams-struggle-to-track-it</link><description>At least 20 people have been killed by a wild elephant over nine days in the eastern Indian state of Jharkhand, as forest officials continue efforts to trace and capture the animal.
The deaths occurred between Jan 1 and Jan 9 in the Chaibasa and Kolhan forest areas of West Singhbhum district, part</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 10:32:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Development project execution to remain slow this fiscal: Planning Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/development-project-execution-to-remain-slow-this-fiscal-planning-adviser</link><description>The sluggish pace of development project implementation is likely to continue through the current fiscal year, Planning Adviser Professor Wahiduddin Mahmud said on Monday.
“The implementation slowdown that we had hoped would be temporary has unfortunately continued this year as well,”</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 10:47:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DSE inches up, CSE slips as majority stocks end lower</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/dse-inches-up-cse-slips-as-majority-stocks-end-lower</link><description>The stock market closed mixed on Monday as the benchmark index of the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) edged up marginally, while the Chittagong Stock Exchange (CSE) ended lower amid broad-based price declines.
Despite remaining under pressure for most of the session, the DSE’s key index DSEX mana</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 11:02:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>3 die in Rangpur after drinking bootleg liquor</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/three-die-after-drinking-rectified-spirit-as-illegal-liquor-trade-grips-rangpur</link><description>Three people have reportedly died after consuming bootleg liquor in Rangpur Sadar and Badarganj Upazila.
Of them, two died at Nayapara of Kishmat Basantapur village in Badarganj, while the third death was reported from Chandanpat Union in Rangpur Sadar on Sunday night, according to local police.</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 11:17:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Vitol, Trafigura offer Venezuelan oil to Indian, Chinese refiners for March delivery, sources say</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/vitol-trafigura-offer-venezuelan-oil-to-indian-chinese-refiners-for-march-delivery-sources-say</link><description>Vitol and Trafigura have started discussions on Venezuelan crude oil sales with refiners in India and China for cargoes to be delivered in March, several trade sources said on Monday.
The global commodities traders confirmed on Friday they had struck agreements with the US government to help marke</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 11:32:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prime Bank expands financial literacy by distributing braille books</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/prime-bank-expands-financial-literacy-by-distributing-braille-books</link><description>Prime Bank PLC has taken another meaningful step toward inclusive banking by distributing Braille books among persons with visual impairments, ensuring that financial knowledge is accessible to all.
The initiative, carried out recently in Savar in collaboration with Team Inclusion Bangladesh, refl</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 11:47:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh Bank to launch Tk 100b bond for housing, rail projects</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh-bank-to-launch-tk-10000-bond-for-housing-rail-projects</link><description>Bangladesh Bank announced plans to issue the ‘Bangladesh Government Special Sukuk-1’, a Shariah-compliant bond worth Tk 100 billion (Tk 10,000 crore), to finance selected national infrastructure and welfare projects.
The decision was finalised after meetings held last week by the centr</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 12:02:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BGB seizes smuggled goods worth over Tk 1.56 billion in Dec</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bgb-seizes-smuggled-goods-worth-over-tk-156-billion-in-dec</link><description>Border Guard Bangladesh (BGB) have seized various types of smuggled goods and contraband drugs worth over Tk 1.5559 billion from different parts of the country including border areas in December.
Besides, 276 Myanmar nationals were pushed back while attempting to enter Bangladesh illegally, said a</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 12:17:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ICC flags Mustafiz as security risk; Asif Nazrul calls decision ‘absurd’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/icc-flags-mustafiz-as-security-risk-asif-nazrul-calls-decision-absurd</link><description>Bangladesh’s participation in the T20 World Cup hit fresh controversy on Monday after Youth and Sports Adviser Asif Nazrul said the International Cricket Council (ICC) had formally flagged pacer Mustafizur Rahman as a potential security risk.
Speaking at a press conference at the Bangladesh</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 12:32:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Banasree teen killed for refusing ‘indecent proposal’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rab-says-banasree-teenager-was-killed-for-refusing-improper-proposals</link><description>The Rapid Action Battalion (RAB) has said the 14-year-old schoolgirl found with her throat slit at her home in Banasree was killed after turning down “persistent advances” from a family employee.
The RAB revealed the matter after arresting the key suspect in the murder, 28-year-old Mil</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 12:47:49 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>