<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 05:22:30 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Crude bomb explosions wound policeman in Pallabi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/crude-bomb-explosions-wound-policeman-in-pallabi</link><description>A policeman has been injured in crude bomb explosions in Pallabi.
Police said the blasts occurred around 8:30pm near a Trust Bank booth between Pallabi Police Station and the Army Camp, bdnews24.com reports.
ASI Nurul Islam was wounded and treated at a local hospital, according to Mohammad Maksud</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 17:45:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Foreign operators, personnel getting 10-year tax holiday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/foreign-operators-personnel-getting-10-year-tax-holiday</link><description>Two foreign operating companies investing in Bangladesh's Laldia and Pangaon container terminals to handle seaborne cargoes are receiving 10-year tax holiday, the revenue authority unveils government decision on just-signed deals.



Also, foreign technical personnel working in these terminals</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 18:00:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>What's holding back growth of cashless transactions?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/whats-holding-back-growth-of-cashless-transactions</link><description>Digital financial transactions have increased by leaps and bounds over the past decade in Bangladesh, primarily driven by the impressive growth in the number of Mobile Financial Service (MFS) users. Estimates suggest that there are now more than 90 million active MFS users in the country, collectiv</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 18:15:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Import of rice alone can't stabilise market</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/import-of-rice-alone-cant-stabilise-market</link><description>Bangladesh's drive to build a substantial stock of rice to meet any contingency appears, on the face of it, to be quite logical. When the market is jittery despite a highly satisfactory boro--- the number one grain--- harvest, the government allowed 242 private traders to import rice. Now that Asia</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 18:30:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New office under finance ministry to conduct G-sec auctions</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/new-office-under-finance-ministry-to-conduct-g-sec-auctions</link><description>The government has planned to separate treasury operations from the Bangladesh Bank (BB) as part of a move to keep the monetary functions of the central bank away from fiscal dominance.
This comes after the International Monetary Fund (IMF) and the World Bank (WB) suggested the split, saying treas</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 02:00:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Higher direct taxes could reduce poverty, income inequality in Bangladesh: Study</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/higher-direct-taxes-could-reduce-poverty-income-inequality-in-bangladesh-study</link><description>Bangladesh has significant potential to reduce poverty and narrow income inequality by increasing revenue from direct taxes while reducing its heavy reliance on indirect taxes, which currently make up 67 per cent of total annual tax collection, according to a new study.
The study estimates that if</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 02:15:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Islamic banks face operational risks following systemic failures</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/islamic-banks-face-operational-risks-following-systemic-failures</link><description>Islamic banks in Bangladesh confront multiple risks and need stronger shariah governance, dedicated risk-management units and a unified operational-risk framework to safeguard institutional stability, experts say.
The risk factors stem from rising process failures, cyber-threats and governance lap</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 02:30:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Institutional reforms, long-term planning a must for sustainable investment in power, energy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/institutional-reforms-long-term-planning-a-must-for-sustainable-investment-in-power-energy</link><description>Speakers at a policy dialogue on Wednesday said Bangladesh's power and energy sector urgently required policy predictability, institutional reforms, and long-term planning to ensure sustainable investment.
They stressed that outdated policies, weak transmission systems, financial instability, and</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 03:29:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Residents allowed to use int’l cards for air tickets</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/residents-allowed-to-use-intl-cards-for-air-tickets</link><description>Bangladesh Bank has authorised resident Bangladeshis to purchase outbound air tickets from airlines operating in the country using their international cards, a move likely to improve convenience and ensure more competitive pricing for travellers.
The decision addresses long-standing difficulties p</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 03:44:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sonali Aansh profit soars 172pc on strong export demand</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/sonali-aansh-profit-soars-172pc-on-strong-export-demand</link><description>Sonali Aansh declared a staggering 172 per cent growth in profits to Tk 95.35 million in FY25.
The profit growth was attained from rising revenue as the demand for locally made jute yarn and jute twine has been increasing in the world market.
According to a stock exchange filing on Wednesday, the</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 03:59:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Apex court reinstates caretaker govt system</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/apex-court-reinstates-caretaker-govt-system-upholds-13th-amendment</link><description>The Appellate Division has declared illegal the verdict delivered 14 years ago that abolished the widely discussed non-partisan caretaker government system. At the same time, the court has upheld the 13th Amendment, effectively reinstating the caretaker government system in the Constitution.
The h</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 04:44:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Market operators warn revised IPO rules may deter new listings</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/market-operators-warn-revised-ipo-rules-may-deter-new-listings</link><description>The revised public issue rules would discourage new listings if enforced with the proposed cap on post-paid-up capital and the bar on using IPO proceeds for loan repayments, said market operators and entrepreneurs.
They expressed their views on Wednesday at a discussion on the draft rules titled B</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 04:59:48 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>