<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 11:22:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Average life expectancy in China hits 79 years</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/average-life-expectancy-in-china-hits-79-years</link><description>China's average life expectancy reached 79 years in 2024, according to a report released Tuesday by the National Health Commission.
China's 2024 health statistics bulletin highlighted continued improvements in both maternal and child health, with maternal deaths falling to 14.3 per 100,000 and inf</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 07:45:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt declares Khaleda Zia VVIP</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-declares-khaleda-zia-vvip</link><description>The government has declared BNP Chairperson and former Prime Minister Begum Khaleda Zia a 'very very important person' (VVIP).
The decision was taken at a special meeting of the Council of Advisers, held on Tuesday at the State Guest House Jamuna, chaired by Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus.</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 08:00:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Climate stress, rising input costs slow Bangladesh's farm output: BIDS study</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/climate-stress-rising-input-costs-slow-bangladeshs-farm-output-bids-study-1</link><description>Agricultural productivity in Bangladesh is losing momentum as climate pressures, rising input costs, land constraints and weak diversification weigh on the sector after years of robust gains, according to a new study by the Bangladesh Institute of Development Studies (BIDS).
The study, titled &amp;ldq</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 08:11:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>3 including ‘drug dealer’ beaten in Manikganj after robber attack announcement</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/3-including-drug-dealer-beaten-in-manikganj-after-robber-attack-announcement</link><description>Locals have beaten three people including a “drug dealer” after an announcement of a robbery was made from a mosque in Manikganj.
Those who are beaten are 27-year-old Arif, son of Dulal from Sultanpur village in Harirampur Upazila, Sagar, son of Afsar from Kalashi area in Sadar Upazila</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 08:26:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mizanur Rashid appointed new Deputy Managing Director of City Bank</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/mizanur-rashid-appointed-new-deputy-managing-director-of-city-bank</link><description>City Bank has recently appointed Mizanur Rashid as DMD &amp;amp;Chief Business Officer for its Digital Banking arm.
Mizanur Rashid brings over 30 years of diverse experience across the fintech and consumer packaged goods (CPG) industries, with a proven track record of driving scale and sustained growth.</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 08:41:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No specific information over Tarique’s return, says Foreign Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/no-specific-information-over-tariques-return-says-foreign-adviser</link><description>Foreign Affairs Adviser Md Touhid Hossain on Tuesday said they do not have any specific information regarding BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman's return to home, mentioning that he has not yet sought any travel pass.
"Travel pass will be issued if he seeks. So far, I know, he is yet to seek any t</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 08:56:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Policeman killed in road crash in Jhenaidah</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/policeman-killed-in-road-crash-in-jhenaidah</link><description>A policeman was killed in a road accident at the Talmil-Baluhar Bus Stand area in Kotchandpur upazila of Jhenaidah district on Tuesday.
The deceased was identified as Anisur Rahman Anis, 45, son of late freedom fighter Mohiuddin Biswas of Ramnagar village in Darshana upazila of Chuadanga district.</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 09:11:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two killed in truck-pickup van collision in Habiganj</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/two-killed-in-truck-pickup-van-collision-in-habiganj</link><description>Two people, including a pickup van driver, were killed in a head-on collision between a truck and a pickup van in Bahubal upazila of Habiganj district on Tuesday.
The accident took place at around 8:30 am in the Mauchak area on the Dhaka-Sylhet highway when a Dhaka-bound truck collided head-on wit</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 09:26:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka Chamber unveils DCCI Journal, Tax Guide</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/dhaka-chamber-unveils-dcci-journal-tax-guide</link><description>The Dhaka Chamber of Commerce &amp; Industry (DCCI) unveiled the second edition of 'DCCI Journal of Business and Economic Policy (DJBEP)' and the 'Tax Guide 2025-26', two of its own publications, at a simple ceremony held yesterday at the DCCI Auditorium in the capital. 
Secretary, Ministry of Co</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 09:41:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mobile phone traders block Pragati Sarani to protest unauthorised handset ban</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/mobile-phone-traders-block-pragati-sarani-to-protest-unauthorised-handset-ban</link><description>Mobile handset traders and their employees have staged a protest on the road in front of Jamuna Future Park in Dhaka for about an hour and a half over the government’s move to ban unauthorised mobile phones.
The demonstration began around 1:15pm on Tuesday, when protesters occupied both side</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 09:56:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Price of 12kg LPG cylinder increased by Tk 38</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/price-of-12kg-lpg-cylinder-increased-by-tk-38</link><description>The price of a 12-kg LPG cylinder has been re-fixed at Tk 1,253 for the month of December, up by Tk 38 from the previous month’s price of Tk 1,215.
The new price will be effective from 6 pm today (Tuesday).
Prices of other sizes of LPG cylinders – from 5.5 kg to 45 kg – will inc</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 10:11:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh can attract much more European investment: French Ambassador</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-can-attract-much-more-european-investment-french-ambassador</link><description>French Ambassador to Bangladesh Jean-Marc Séré-Charlet has said they strongly believe that Bangladesh can attract much more European investment and capital.
“We want to do more, and we strongly believe that Bangladesh can attract much more European investment and capital,&amp;rdquo</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 10:26:58 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>