<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 13:28:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Tropical storm deaths top 600 in Southeast Asia, over 4 million affected</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/tropical-storm-deaths-top-600-in-southeast-asia-over-4-million-affected</link><description>The death toll mounted to over 600 from floods and landslides caused by torrential rains across three countries in Southeast Asia, officials said on Sunday, as relief efforts for tens of thousands of displaced people continued over the weekend.
Indonesia, Malaysia and Thailand faced large-scale de</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 09:45:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Netanyahu officially asks Israeli president for pardon</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/netanyahu-officially-asks-israeli-president-for-pardon</link><description>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu has submitted an official request for his pardon to Israeli President Isaac Herzog, the Israeli president's office said on Sunday.
"The Office of the President is aware that this is an extraordinary request which carries with it significant implications. A</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 10:00:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Death toll in Hong Kong apartment complex blaze rises to 146 as the city mourns</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/death-toll-in-hong-kong-apartment-complex-blaze-rises-to-146-as-the-city-mourns</link><description>The death toll in Hong Kong’s apartment complex blaze rose to 146 on Sunday as investigators discovered more bodies in the burned-out buildings, while a steady stream of people placed bouquets of flowers at an ever-growing makeshift memorial at the scene.
The Hong Kong police Disaster Victim</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 10:15:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>'Travel pass for Tarique possible within a day if he wishes to return'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/travel-pass-for-tarique-possible-within-a-day-if-he-wishes-to-return</link><description>The interim government can issue a travel pass for the Acting BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman within a single day if he wishes to return to the country, said Foreign Affairs Adviser Md Touhid Hossain.
He stated that there are no obstacles preventing his return.
The adviser made the remarks today (Sun</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 10:30:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCP issues show-cause notice against Ariful; he quits ahead of action</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ncp-issues-show-cause-notice-against-ariful-he-quits-ahead-of-action</link><description>National Citizen Party (NCP) has issued a show-cause notice and temporarily relieved its South Region organiser Ariful Islam Talukder from all responsibilities over alleged breach of party discipline, though Ariful had already resigned before the notice was served.
According to the notice sent to</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 10:45:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mourners flock to site of deadly Hong Kong blaze as Beijing warns against protests</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/mourners-flock-to-site-of-deadly-hong-kong-blaze-as-beijing-warns-against-protests</link><description>More than a thousand people turned out on Sunday to pay tribute to the victims of Hong Kong's deadliest fire in more than 75 years, as Beijing warned it would use a national security law to crack down on any "anti-China" protest in the wake of the blaze.
The cause of the blaze at a high-rise apart</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 11:00:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dengue: 5 more die, 636 hospitalised in 24 hours</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dengue-5-more-die-636-hospitalised-in-24-hours</link><description>Five more deaths were reported from dengue in 24 hours till Sunday morning, raising the number of fatalities from the mosquito-borne disease in Bangladesh to 382 this year.
During the same period, 636 new patients were admitted to hospitals, raising the total number of dengue cases this year to 94</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 11:15:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tom Stoppard leaves 'majestic body' of intellectual work</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/entertainment/tom-stoppard-leaves-majestic-body-of-intellectual-work</link><description>Tom Stoppard, one of Britain's best-known playwrights, has died at the age of 88. Below are some tributes and reactions.
KING CHARLES AND QUEEN CAMILLA
"A dear friend who wore his genius lightly, he could, and did, turn his pen to any subject, challenging, moving and inspiring his audiences, born</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 11:30:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP postpones ‘Victory Torch roadshow’ as Khaleda remains hospitalised</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-postpones-victory-torch-roadshow-as-khaleda-remains-hospitalised</link><description>BNP on Sunday postponed its previously announced ‘Victory Torch Roadshow’ as party Chairperson Begum Khaleda Zia remains hospitalised due to illness.
BNP Senior Joint Secretary General Ruhul Kabir Rizvi announced the decision at an urgent press conference at the party’s Nayapalta</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 11:45:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bank Merger: ‘Sammilita Islami Bank’ receives final approval</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bank-merger-sammilita-islami-bank-receives-final-approval</link><description>‘Sammilita Islami Bank PLC’ (formerly United Islamic Bank PLC), created through the merger of five financially troubled Islamic banks, has officially received final approval from Bangladesh Bank.
The approval came on Sunday during a special board meeting chaired by Bangladesh Bank Gove</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 12:00:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BPL auction: Naim bags Tk 11m, Litton 7m</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/cricket/bpl-auction-naim-bags-tk-11m-litton-7m</link><description>The opening call of the Bangladesh Premier League (BPL) auction has sent excitement surging as intense bidding broke out for Mohammad Naim Sheikh.
On Sunday, the contest climbed 13 increments above his base price before finally settling, more than doubling his pay. In contrast, Bangladesh T20 capt</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 12:15:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Health Assistants Association's demo continues for second day</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/health-assistants-associations-demo-continues-for-second-day</link><description>Bangladesh Health Assistants Association staged demonstration for the second consecutive day on Sunday to press home their 6-point demand including implementation of the 10th grade for their positions.
The health assistance and others gathered in Central Shaheed Minar in the capital and staged dem</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 12:30:46 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>