<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 07:23:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Video messages of Hadi murder prime suspect under scrutiny: DMP chief</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/video-messages-of-hadi-murder-prime-suspect-under-scrutiny-dmp-chief</link><description>Dhaka Metropolitan Police (DMP) Commissioner Sheikh Md Sazzat Ali said that police were scrutinising two video messages reportedly released by Faisal Karim Masud, the prime suspect in the murder of Inquilab Moncho spokesperson Sharif Osman Hadi.
"No comments. We (police) are closely examining the</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 04:11:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt committed to ensuring justice for Hadi's murder, says Foreign Affairs Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-committed-to-ensuring-justice-for-hadis-murder-says-foreign-affairs-adviser</link><description>Foreign Affairs Adviser Md Touhid Hossain has said that the government is committed to bringing those involved in the murder of Hadi to justice.
He said work is continuing to complete the trial as quickly as possible.
"We cannot rush the judicial process. We are trying to bring back everyone invo</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 04:26:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IPO rulebook overhauled as BSEC hopes to attract ‘good companies’ in 2026</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/ipo-rulebook-overhauled-as-bsec-hopes-to-attract-good-companies-in-2026</link><description>The Bangladesh Securities and Exchange Commission (BSEC) has announced the publication of the new Initial Public Offering (IPO) rules in a gazette, voicing optimism that the reform will pave the way for quality companies to enter the capital market this year.
According to the regulator, the Bangla</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 04:41:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Reasons Bangladesh's mid-career women vanish from the workforce</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/youth-and-entrepreneurship/reasons-bangladeshs-mid-career-women-vanish-from-the-workforce</link><description>Anika stepped away from her specialist role in technology sector in Dhaka for two years to care for her newborn. It was a deliberate choice, or so she believed. Within months of returning, she discovered that the IT industry had moved on without her. Recruiters questioned her technical currency. Sa</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 04:56:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka's youths helping children dream bigger</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/youth-and-entrepreneurship/dhakas-youths-helping-children-dream-bigger</link><description>On a quiet winter morning in Dhaka, the sun struggles through the fog as children's laughter fills a schoolyard. Small hands press soil around young saplings. Inside a bright classroom, children turn book pages with wide eyes, discovering stories far beyond their textbooks.
In a city known for tra</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 05:11:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Why others should follow him</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/youth-and-entrepreneurship/why-others-should-follow-him</link><description>In a world where most people measure success in salaries and promotions, Munjer Alam chose a different path. Once the director of Finance at a prestigious multinational company, he turned away from the glow of corporate life to build something humbler, greener, and truer. An agricultural haven was</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 05:26:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India-Bangladesh ties will strengthen after normalcy restores post elections, Jaishankar says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/india-bangladesh-ties-will-strengthen-after-normalcy-restores-post-elections-jaishankar-says</link><description>India expects neighbourly relations in the region to grow stronger once the situation in Bangladesh normalises through elections, Indian External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar has said.
He expressed the hope while responding to a question about his recent visit to Bangladesh at an event in Chennai</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 05:41:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UN to meet Monday over US action in Venezuela</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/un-to-meet-monday-over-us-action-in-venezuela</link><description>The United Nations Security Council is due to meet on Monday after the US attacked Venezuela and deposed its long-serving autocratic President Nicolas Maduro, a move that UN Secretary-General Antonio Guterres views as setting "a dangerous precedent."
Colombia, backed by Russia and China, requested</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 05:56:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Maduro is 'the only president' of Venezuela, says vice president</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/maduro-is-the-only-president-of-venezuela-says-vice-president</link><description>Venezuelan Vice President Rodriguez on Saturday reaffirmed that Nicolas Maduro remains "the only president" of Venezuela, denouncing the recent U.S. military operation targeting the country's leadership.
Speaking live on state-run television, Rodriguez emphasised that Venezuela will never be a col</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 06:12:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shariatpur–Chandpur ferry services suspended due to dense fog</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/shariatpur-chandpur-ferry-services-suspended-due-to-dense-fog</link><description>Ferry services on the Shariatpur-Chandpur Harinaghat river route have been suspended since 11:30 pm on Saturday due to dense fog, disrupting transport on both sides of the river.
Bangladesh Inland Water Transport Corporation (BIWTC) Narsinghpur ferry terminal Assistant Manager Md Iqbal Hossain sai</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 06:27:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Asif Nazrul condemns BCCI's instruction to remove Mustafiz from IPL</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/cricket/asif-nazrul-condemns-bccis-instruction-to-remove-mustafiz-from-ipl</link><description>Youth and Sports Adviser Dr Asif Nazrul today expressed strong condemnation and protested an instruction of the Board of Control for Cricket in India (BCCI) to remove Bangladeshi cricketer Mustafizur Rahman from the Kolkata Knight Riders (KKR) squad.
He made the protest in a post on his verified F</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 06:42:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Stocks open higher as indices gain in first hour</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/stocks-open-higher-as-indices-gain-in-first-hour</link><description>Bangladesh's stock markets posted gains in the first hour of trading on Sunday, the opening session of the week, with indices rising at both the Dhaka and Chattogram bourses amid broad-based buying.
During the first hour, the benchmark DSEX index of the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) advanced by 43 po</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 06:57:36 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>