<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 15:55:40 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>EC revises referendum results, cuts both ‘Yes’ and ‘No’ votes</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-revises-referendum-results-cuts-both-yes-and-no-votes</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has brought a major revision to the results of the referendum held to implement the July National Charter (constitutional reform), reducing both ‘Yes’ and ‘No’ votes compared to the previously announced figures.
The revised information was publi</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 13:32:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pubali Bank holds 200th meeting of Executive Risk Management Committee</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/pubali-bank-holds-200th-meeting-of-executive-risk-management-committee</link><description>The 200th Meeting of the Executive Risk Management Committee (ERMC) of Pubali Bank PLC was held recently through a virtual platform, according to a press release.
Managing Director &amp; CEO Mohammad Ali attended the meeting as Chief Guest and Deputy Managing Directors- Ahmed Enayet Manzur, Md. Shahne</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 13:47:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>'LPG market monitoring to be intensified to ease consumers' hassle'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/lpg-market-monitoring-to-be-intensified-to-ease-consumers-hassle</link><description>Commerce Minister Khandaker Abdul Muktadir today (Thursday) said the government will strengthen Liquefied Petroleum Gas (LPG) market monitoring through local administrations to ensure that consumers do not face harassment and that no one can engage in market abuse at the retail level.
The minister</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 14:02:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Girl abducted, found dead after family seeks justice over rape</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/narsingdi-girl-15-abducted-found-dead-after-family-seeks-justice-over-rape</link><description>A 15-year-old girl was abducted from her father and later found dead in Narsingdi after her family sought justice over her rape, police, relatives and locals said.
Her body was found in a mustard field between Bilpar and Darikandi in Mahishashura Union of Sadar Upazila on Thursday, Prothom Alo rep</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 14:17:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NRBC Bank observes ‘Remittance Service Month’ during Holy Ramadan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/nrbc-bank-observes-remittance-service-month-during-holy-ramadan</link><description>NRBC Bank PLC is observing the holy month of Ramadan as a ‘Special Remittance Service Month’ to encourage expatriates to send remittances through formal banking channels and to further expand related services, according to a press release.
On this occasion, special gifts are being offe</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 14:32:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>TIB questions whether new governor can rise above conflict of interest</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tib-questions-whether-new-governor-can-rise-above-conflict-of-interest</link><description>Transparency International Bangladesh (TIB) has expressed concern over how independently the newly appointed Governor of Bangladesh Bank will be able to discharge his responsibilities, rising above conflicts of interest.
The organisation has also raised the question of how a readymade garment and</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 14:03:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>WEF chief quits after Epstein ties come to light</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/global/wef-chief-quits-after-epstein-ties-come-to-light</link><description>The president and CEO of the World Economic Forum, Borge Brende, said he was stepping down on Thursday, a few weeks after the forum launched an independent investigation into his relationship with late US sex offender Jeffrey Epstein.
Brende, who became president of the WEF in 2017, announced his</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 14:18:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DNCC engineer suspended over ‘negligence’ in Mohammadpur roadwork</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dncc-engineer-suspended-over-negligence-in-mohammadpur-roadwork</link><description>Dhaka North City Corporation (DNCC) has suspended an executive engineer for “negligence” and “misconduct” following complaints of irregularities in road construction and repair work in the Mohammadpur area.
Md Mizanur Rahman, the acting executive engineer of DNCC Zone-5, wa</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 14:33:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New governor announces measures to revive closed factories: Spokesperson</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/new-governor-announces-measures-to-revive-closed-factories-spokesperson</link><description>Newly appointed Governor Mostaqur Rahman has announced measures to revive closed factories through targeted policy support on his first day in office.
The central bank’s spokesperson Arief Hossain Khan shared the governor’s vision with journalists on Thursday.
It followed an informal</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 14:48:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Modhumoti Bank holds 143rd meeting of its executive committee</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/modhumoti-bank-holds-143rd-meeting-of-its-executive-committee</link><description>The 143rd Meeting of the Executive Committee of Modhumoti Bank PLC was held on Thursday at the bank’s Head Office premises, according to a press release.
The meeting was presided over by EC Chairman, Mr. Salahuddin Alamgir. Among others, Mr. Mostafa Kamal,Mr. Mohammad Ismail Hossain, Mr.Nema</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 15:03:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BRAC Bank’s ‘Astha’ app records Tk 2.37 trillion in digital transactions in 2025</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/brac-banks-astha-app-records-tk-237-trillion-in-digital-transactions-in-2025</link><description>BRAC Bank’s digital banking platform ‘Astha’ has recorded BDT 237,000 crore (Tk 2.37 trillion) in transaction volume in 2025, serving more than 12 lakh customers.
 ‘Astha’ App now processes BDT 24,000 crore in transactions every month, accounting for over 50 per</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 15:18:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BGMEA accords reception to newly-elected ministers, MPs from apparel sector</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bgmea-accords-reception-to-newly-elected-ministers-mps-from-apparel-sector</link><description>Bangladesh Garment Manufacturers and Exporters Association (BGMEA) on Thursday accorded a reception to its members who have been elected ministers, state ministers and Members of the Parliament in the 13th National Election.
A total of 17 members--three ministers, three state ministers and one adv</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 15:33:37 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>