<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 12:47:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Airport fire: Dhaka customs to stay open during weekend</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dhaka-customs-to-stay-open-friday-saturday-after-shahjalal-cargo-village-fire</link><description>The Dhaka Custom House will keep customs clearance operations open round-the-clock on Friday and Saturday to manage the fallout from the recent blaze at the Cargo Village of Shahjalal International Airport.
An order issued on Wednesday directed all staff members to remain on duty.
Earlier, on Tue</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 09:49:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Turkey pressing for Western fighter jets to claw back regional edge</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/turkey-pressing-for-western-fighter-jets-to-claw-back-regional-edge</link><description>Anxious to bolster its air power, Turkey has proposed to European partners and the US ways it could swiftly obtain advanced fighter jets as it seeks to make up ground on regional rivals such as Israel, sources familiar with the talks say.
NATO-member Turkey, which has the alliance's second-largest</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 10:04:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka bourse sees lowest turnover in four months</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/dhaka-bourse-sees-lowest-turnover-in-four-months</link><description>The Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) saw the lowest turnover in four months on Wednesday, with transactions falling to Tk 355 crore, despite a marginal rise in the key index.
The last time DSE saw a lower transaction was on June 23, when shares and units worth Tk 276 crore were traded. Earlier this week</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 10:34:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Deepika and Ranveer mark Diwali with daughter Dua’s first public appearance</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/entertainment/deepika-and-ranveer-mark-diwali-with-daughter-duas-first-public-appearance</link><description>Deepika Padukone and Ranveer Singh have ushered in Diwali with the public introduction of their daughter, Dua Padukone Singh.
On Tuesday, the Bollywood couple shared a series of photographs on Instagram that captured their first Diwali as a family of three.
The post, framed as a holiday greeting,</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 10:49:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Super-warming methane gas is being tackled too slowly, UN says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/super-warming-methane-gas-is-being-tackled-too-slowly-un-says-ahead-of-cop30</link><description>Almost 90 per cent of satellite-detected methane leaks flagged to governments and oil and gas companies are not being acknowledged, the UN said Wednesday ahead of the COP30 climate talks next month.
The International Methane Emissions Observatory, which integrates over 17 satellites to observe plu</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 11:19:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Apple hit with EU antitrust complaint over App Store terms</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/apple-hit-with-eu-antitrust-complaint-over-app-store-terms</link><description>Apple (AAPL.O) was hit with a complaint to EU antitrust regulators by two civil rights groups on Wednesday over the terms and conditions of its App Store and devices for allegedly breaching landmark rules aimed at reining in Big Tech.
The joint complaint by Article 19 and Germany's Society for Civ</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 11:34:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Journalists imprisoned in Belarus and Georgia win EU’s top human rights award</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/journalists-imprisoned-in-belarus-and-georgia-win-eus-top-human-rights-award</link><description>Two journalists, one imprisoned in Belarus and the other in Georgia, have won the European Union’s top human rights honor, the Sakharov Prize, European Parliament President Roberta Metsola announced on Wednesday.
Andrzej Poczobut is a correspondent for the influential Polish newspaper Gazeta</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 11:49:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DMP files 1,658 cases against traffic rule violations</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/dmp-files-1658-cases-against-traffic-rule-violations</link><description>The Traffic Division of the Dhaka Metropolitan Police (DMP) has filed 1,658 cases against motor vehicles, their owners, and drivers for violating traffic rules in a single day across the capital.
A media release of the DMP on Wednesday said that they filed those cases and realized the money on Tue</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 12:19:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Al-Arafah Islami Bank signs Strategic Partnership with Shamadhan Services Limited</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/al-arafah-islami-bank-signs-strategic-partnership-with-shamadhan-services-limited</link><description>Al-Arafah Islami Bank PLC, the country’s leading Shariah-compliant financial institution has signed a Strategic Partnership Agreement with Shamadhan Services Limited, a concern of Grameen Telecom, to strengthen digital financial services and enhance customer convenience.
The signing ceremony</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 12:34:30 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>