<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 15:43:29 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>'Policy reforms, ethical business key to competitiveness after LDC graduation'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/policy-reforms-ethical-business-key-to-competitiveness-after-ldc-graduation</link><description>Analysts and business leaders on Thursday said comprehensive policy reforms, stronger institutional efficiency and an uncompromising commitment to ethical business practices are crucial for Bangladesh to sustain its competitiveness in the post-LDC graduation era.
The observations came at a high-le</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 12:50:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Irish attorney general raises concerns on sanctioning services in Israeli settlements</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/irish-attorney-general-raises-concerns-on-sanctioning-services-in-israeli-settlements</link><description>Ireland's top government lawyer has raised several "significant" legal and practical issues in long-awaited advice on whether planned curbs on trade with Israeli settlements should be extended to services, a junior minister said on Thursday.
Ireland has been preparing a law to curb trade with sett</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 13:05:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh Bank reconstitutes UFIL board amid financial turmoil</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh-bank-reconstitutes-ufil-board-amid-financial-turmoil</link><description>Bangladesh Bank (BB) has dissolved the existing board of directors of Uttara Finance and Investments Limited and formed a new board to rescue the struggling non-bank financial institution (NBFI) from deep-rooted loan irregularities.
The listed company shared this information through the Dhaka Stoc</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 13:20:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Army flags misinformation as ‘key threat’ before polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/army-raises-alarm-over-social-media-misinformation-as-key-threat-before-polls</link><description>The Bangladesh Army considers the spread of false and misleading information on social media the “biggest threat” to the national election, a senior officer has said.
On Thursday, he called for cooperation from all quarters, warning against the misuse of artificial intelligence (AI).</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 13:23:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Grand finale of Marks Active School Genius competition held</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/grand-finale-of-marks-active-school-genius-competition-held</link><description>The grand finale of the “Marks Active School Genius” competition, organised by Marks Active School, an initiative of leading industrial conglomerate Abul Khair Group, in collaboration with 10 Minute School, has been successfully held.
Champions from each category received the Champions</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 13:38:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP set to announce election manifesto on Friday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-set-to-announce-election-manifesto-on-friday</link><description>BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman is set to announce the party’s election manifesto for the 13th parliamentary election on Friday.
BNP media cell member Sayrul Kabir Khan said the manifesto will be unveiled at 3:30pm at Sonargaon Hotel in the capital.
He said party Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 13:53:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New PM likely to take oath Feb 15 or 16: Press Secy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/new-prime-minister-likely-to-be-sworn-in-on-feb-15-or-16-says-press-secretary</link><description>The interim government will relinquish its responsibilities “quickly” following the parliamentary elections, Chief Advisor’s Press Secretary Shafiqul Alam has said.
On Thursday, he indicated that the new prime minister could take the oath three days after polling.
Speaking at a</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 14:08:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>VAT, tax relief approved for local LPG supply</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/interim-government-grants-vat-tax-exemptions-to-ease-local-lpg-supply</link><description>In a bid to maintain a steady supply of liquefied petroleum gas (LPG), the Advisory Council has approved VAT and tax exemptions at the local production and trader level.
The decisions came at a meeting of the Advisory Council at the Chief Advisor’s Office (CAO) in Dhaka’s Tejgaon on Th</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 14:23:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Epstein helps DP World in London port project, reports Telegraph</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/epstein-helps-dp-world-in-london-port-project-reports-telegraph</link><description>The sex offender Jeffrey Epstein aided Sultan Ahmed bin Sulayem, chairman of UAE port operator DP World, as he sought to extract government loan guarantees and investment for the £1.8bn London Port project, reveals the Telegraph, an influential London based daily.
According to the Daily, in</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 14:38:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>All 166 kidnapped churchgoers now rescued in northern Nigeria, Christian group says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/africa/all-166-kidnapped-churchgoers-now-rescued-in-northern-nigeria-christian-group-says</link><description>Security services have now rescued all 166 worshippers who were kidnapped by gunmen during attacks on two churches in northern Nigeria last month, a Christian group said on Thursday.
The Christian Association of Nigeria credited the power of prayer and the military for the success of the operation</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 14:53:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Inqilab Moncho stages sit-in outside Jamuna, demands UN-led probe into Hadi killing</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/inqilab-moncho-stages-sit-in-outside-jamuna-demands-un-led-probe-into-hadi-killing</link><description>Inqilab Moncho on Thursday staged a sit-in outside the Chief Adviser’s official residence, Jamuna, demanding an impartial investigation under United Nations supervision into the killing of its spokesperson Sharif Osman Hadi.
The protest began around 5pm with Inqilab Mancha Member Secretary A</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 15:08:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Morocco evacuates 143,000 people in northwest as flood precaution, interior ministry says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/morocco-evacuates-143000-people-in-northwest-as-flood-precaution-interior-ministry-says</link><description>Moroccan authorities have evacuated more than 143,000 people in the flood-prone northwestern plains, the interior ministry said on Thursday, amid rising threats of inundation from heavy rain, swollen rivers and the release of more water from full dams.</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 15:23:48 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>