<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 03:26:59 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Epoch-making Bangali singers of yesteryears</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/reviews/epoch-making-bangali-singers-of-yesteryears</link><description>Long before the arrival of Uttam Kumar (1926-80), actor-director-screenwriter Pramathesh Barua (1903-51) was the first male heartthrob of Bangla cinema. His movie version of Devdas (1935) was most authentic. Like the Cumilla-born and raised, Victoria College-educated singer-musician Sachin Dev Burm</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 16:52:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Death traps all around</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/death-traps-all-around</link><description>Death traps are everywhere in Bangladesh. They lurk in accident-prone roads where vehicles race each other recklessly, in waterways where vessels capsize without warning, in sudden outbreaks of violence over trifling matters, and in bomb hurling in public spaces. Another type of quietest but deadli</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 16:52:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bureaucratic inertia, inefficiency foil good initiatives</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/bureaucratic-inertia-inefficiency-foil-good-initiatives</link><description>Many complain that there were so many reform commissions but no commission on education. It now seems it was better that the sector was left alone. Nowadays, the focus is on the scheduled election and reform agendas hardly figure in deliberations. Chiefs of several commissions have publicly express</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 17:07:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Reducing inequality through higher taxes on the wealthy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/reducing-inequality-through-higher-taxes-on-the-wealthy</link><description>In a strategic shift, the government is preparing to raise the tax incidence on wealthy or 'high-net-worth individuals' (HNWIs) as part of its efforts to address widening income inequality. This proposed approach is outlined in the Medium- and Long-term Revenue Strategy (MLTRS) for FY2025-26 to FY2</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 17:22:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Diverse masses throng to welcome Tarique Rahman home</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/from-elders-to-teenagers-diverse-masses-throng-to-welcome-tarique-rahman-home</link><description>A sea of people from all walks of life thronged the 300 Feet Road on Thursday to welcome BNP acting chairman Tarique Rahman back to Bangladesh after 17 years in exile.
“I have come to see Tarique, as I have long admired his father and mother, and now I want to see him lead the country from t</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 17:37:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCP, Jamaat in talks to form election alliance</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ncp-jamaat-negotiate-seat-sharing-pact-to-contest-in-parliamentary-polls</link><description>The National Citizen Party (NCP) is holding talks with the Jamaat-e-Islami to form an alliance for the February elections, according to the parties’ leaders.
A Facebook post by Abdul Kader, a former coordinator of the Students Against Discrimination and one of the leaders of the July Uprisin</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 17:52:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique seeks peace, unity on homecoming</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-seeks-peace-unity-on-homecoming</link><description>On a euphoric homecoming after precious 17 years in forced political exile, BNP leader Tarique Rahman promises political bonhomie in the divisive polity and calls for rebuilding Bangladesh as safe abode for all.       
At a mammoth reception rally on return home</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 18:55:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>'Tarique’s comeback may leave positive impact on economy'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/tariques-comeback-may-leave-positive-impact-on-economy</link><description>Tarique Rahman's return from wildness after 17 years draws intense political attention, but economists and business leaders say the more consequential test lies in its implications for Bangladesh's disheveled political economy.
The economic milieu, they note, has been strained by persistently high</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 02:00:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Depositors of five crisis-hit banks can finally start withdrawals from Monday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/depositors-of-five-crisis-hit-banks-can-finally-start-withdrawals-from-monday</link><description>In a major move to stabilise the banking sector, Bangladesh Bank has approved the merger of five crisis-stricken Islamic banks into a single entity named Combined Islamic Bank PLC. The central bank confirmed on Thursday that the withdrawal process for depositors will begin next Monday or Tuesday. T</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 02:15:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Commercial disputes to see speedy resolution</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/commercial-disputes-to-see-speedy-resolution</link><description>The proposed Commercial Courts Ordinance 2025 is expected to offer a new ray of hope for the speedy resolution of commercial disputes pending in different courts across the country.
Under the ordinance, the required number of commercial courts will be established at the district level to exclusive</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 02:30:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AIIB to lend $881m for modernising BREB's power supply networks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/aiib-to-lend-881m-for-modernising-brebs-power-supply-networks</link><description>The Asian Infrastructure Investment Bank (AIIB) is set to provide US$881 million to help modernise electricity distribution networks in four divisions, aiming to enhance the reliability and efficiency of power supply for nearly 18 million consumers under the Bangladesh Rural Electrification Board (</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 02:45:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Metro rail strike averted, still uncertainty persists</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/metro-rail-strike-averted-still-uncertainty-persists</link><description>The metro-rail operator has narrowly averted a fresh strike after its board approved long-pending service rules last week, easing immediate tensions with agitating staff.
However, officials and employees alike fear that delays in making the rules effective could once again destabilise operations.</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 03:00:46 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>