<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 20:24:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>BNP expresses solidarity with Tarek’s hunger strike over his party's registration</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-expresses-solidarity-with-tareks-hunger-strike-over-his-partys-registration</link><description>BNP on Thursday expressed solidarity with Tarek Rahman, who has been observing a hunger strike in front of the Election Commission, demanding registration for his political party.
"The political party he formed definitely deserves registration. And for this just cause, he has been on hunger strike</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 16:31:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>JnUCSU Election:16,365 students enlisted as voter</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jnucsu-election16365-students-enlisted-as-voter</link><description>The Election Commission of Jagannath University (JnU) has published the draft voter list for the Jagannath University Central Students’ Union (JnUCSU) and hall union elections 2025.
The draft was published on Thursday evening on the official JnUCSU election website, reports UNB.
According t</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 16:46:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BGMEA secures special healthcare benefits for members</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bgmea-secures-special-healthcare-benefits-for-members</link><description>The Bangladesh Garment Manufacturers and Exporters Association (BGMEA) has taken a significant step to encourage its members, officials, staff, and their families to seek quality health and diagnostic services domestically instead of traveling abroad for treatment.
To this end, the BGMEA on Thursd</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 17:01:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC registers 66 local election observer organisations</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ec-registers-66-local-election-observer-organisations</link><description>The Election Commission has registered 66 organisations as local election observers as well as identified 16 more firms as eligible for registration as local election observers ahead of the upcoming 13th parliamentary election to be held in early February 2026.
“The 66 organisations have giv</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 17:16:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ex-minister Abul Hassan Mahmood Ali passes away</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ex-minister-abul-hassan-mahmood-ali-passes-away</link><description>Abul Hassan Mahmood Ali, former finance minister, foreign minister, and former lawmaker from Dinajpur-4 constituency, passed away at the age of 83 on Thursday.
He breathed his last while undergoing treatment at BIRDEM Hospital in Dhaka, family sources confirmed.
Ali had been receiving intensive c</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 18:27:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The significance of November 7 revolution</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/the-significance-of-november-7-revolution</link><description>The trend of politics in Bangladesh is quite distinct. It is unique in melody and rhythm. Its nature and mobility also have distinctive features. If its flow is obstructed or if any threat emerges, a deluge of floods result that inundates both the banks. If there is any hindrance to its melody and</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 18:42:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BB's NAV disclosure contradicts Islamic banks' claims</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bbs-nav-disclosure-contradicts-islamic-banks-claims</link><description>There is a huge gap in the net asset value (NAV) between what the troubled Islamic banks reported in their latest financial statements and what the Bangladesh Bank announced when it dissolved their boards on Wednesday.



BB Governor Ahsan H. Mansur, at a press briefing, said the NAV of the b</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 18:57:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Missed opportunities for rural tourism</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/missed-opportunities-for-rural-tourism</link><description>Rural tourism has become a major driver of local growth globally. Besides serving as an ingenious way to diversify rural economies in many countries across regions, it is preserving local culture and heritage. As a nation with rich natural and cultural resources scattered countrywide, Bangladesh ho</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 19:12:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt can consider compensation to small investors: BB</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/govt-can-consider-compensation-to-small-investors-bb</link><description>A glimmer of hope appears on the horizons for some of the shareholders in the five merged banks as the regulator considers compensating small investors beggared of investments.
The Bangladesh Bank (BB) softens its stance over the conundrum related to compensation for the 'small investors or sh</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 19:27:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Return back to Nature ensures survival of human race</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/return-back-to-nature-ensures-survival-of-human-race</link><description>Nepal has emerged as the most Nature-connected nation in the world, according to a research, first of its kind, conducted by academics from Britain and Austria. Involved with the ground-breaking research was Miles Richardson, a famed professor of Nature connectedness at the University of Derby. The</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 19:42:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Reining in online gambling</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/reining-in-online-gambling</link><description>The reported government's move to crack down on online gambling deserves unreserved commendation. For too long, this digital menace has flourished unchecked, feeding on people's vulnerabilities and taking advantage of technological loopholes. The decision, taken at a high-level meeting at the Bangl</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 19:57:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No scope to protect investors’ interests in merging five banks: BB</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/no-scope-to-protect-investors-interests-in-merging-five-banks-bb</link><description>Bangladesh Bank has said that under the Bank Resolution Ordinance 2025, there is currently no scope to consider the protection of investors’ or shareholders’ interests in the ongoing merger of five Shariah-based banks.
In a statement issued on Thursday night, the central bank clarified</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 20:12:28 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>