<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 09:23:50 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>EC urges postal voters to submit ballots promptly</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-urges-postal-voters-to-submit-ballots-promptly</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has called on expatriate voters casting their ballots by post to return them as quickly as possible to ensure they are counted.
In a statement issued on Saturday, the commission said postal ballots must reach the relevant returning officer by 4:30 pm on February 12 to</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 06:27:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘It’s their loss,’ says Azharuddin on Bangladesh's refusal to play T20 WC in India</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/its-their-loss-says-azharuddin-on-bangladeshs-refusal-to-play-t20-wc-in-india</link><description>Former India captain Mohammad Azharuddin has said Bangladesh cannot blame India’s security arrangements if it chooses not to play its T20 World Cup matches in the country.
Azharuddin, who played 99 Tests and 334 One-Day Internationals for India and led the side in 47 Tests and 174 ODIs, said</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 06:25:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Meta pauses teen access to AI characters</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/meta-pauses-teen-access-to-ai-characters</link><description>Meta is halting teens' access to artificial intelligence characters, at least temporarily, the company said in a blog post on Friday.
Meta Platforms Inc., which owns Instagram and WhatsApp, said that starting in the “coming weeks,” teens will no longer be able to access AI characters &amp;</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 06:40:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two killed in Faridpur road accident</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/two-killed-in-faridpur-road-accident-153794</link><description>Two people were killed and ten others injured in a head-on collision between a bus and a truck on the Dhaka-Barishal highway at Naupara in Bhanga upazila of Faridpur district on Saturday.
The identities of the deceased could not be known immediately.
Helal Uddin, officer-in-charge of Bhanga Highw</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 06:55:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat chief vows to revive Teesta, other dying rivers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-chief-vows-to-revive-teesta-other-dying-rivers</link><description>Jamaat-e-Islami chief Shafiqur Rahman has pledged to take initiatives to restore life to Teesta and other northern rivers if his party forms a 10-party coalition government.
At an election rally organised by the alliance in Gaibandha on Saturday, he said the initiative would not only benefit peopl</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 07:10:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique set to hit campaign trail in Ctg</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-set-to-hit-campaign-trail-in-ctg</link><description>BNP leader Tarique Rahman is set to begin the next phase of his election campaign in the port city of Chattogram on Sunday after kicking off the drive in Sylhet.
Tarique is due to arrive in Chattogram by air from Dhaka at 7:35 pm on Saturday and will stay overnight in the city, the party announced</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 07:25:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bank official dies after falling from building in Badda</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bank-official-dies-after-falling-from-building-in-badda</link><description>A bank official has died after falling from the rooftop of a residential building in Dhaka's North Badda.
The body of 30-year-old Subir Biswas was recovered on Friday afternoon from outside the building and taken to Dhaka Medical College Hospital, where doctors said he had already died. The body w</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 07:40:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Why students must co-create their education</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/why-students-must-co-create-their-education</link><description>There is a scene in the 2023 award winning Indian film 12th Fail that captures something profoundly wrong with South Asian education systems. In a small school in Chambal, teachers openly facilitate cheating during board examinations, a practice that students expect, parents demand, and the system</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 07:55:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Reimagining higher education in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/article/reimagining-higher-education-in-bangladesh</link><description>The world is shutting its doors, and the implications for developing countries are profound. Between January and May 2025, USA consulates issued roughly 95,000 F-1 visas, marking the lowest issuance total in three years, whilst the Department of Homeland Security proposed limiting students' length</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 08:10:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Youth Connect empowering a generation to lead change</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/youth-connect-empowering-a-generation-to-lead-change</link><description>Bangladesh stands at a critical juncture. With over one-third of its population aged below 30, the future of the nation will be determined not by policy, but by the ideas, skills, and leadership qualities of the youth. Climate change, increasing inequalities, employability, and the disruptor role o</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 08:25:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP rejects Jamaat’s 'India deal' claim as ‘propaganda’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-rejects-jamaats-india-deal-claim-as-propaganda</link><description>The Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) has rejected allegations by Jamaat-e-Islami that it has reached an agreement with India to return to power, describing the claim as “total propaganda”.
Mahdi Amin, spokesperson for the BNP’s Central Election Steering Committee, clarified t</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 08:40:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Karachi mall inferno came after ignored warnings, delayed response</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/karachi-mall-inferno-came-after-ignored-warnings-delayed-response</link><description>Muhammad Imran did not take the fire seriously at first, thinking it was another small spark at the Karachi mall that would be quickly extinguished by fellow shop owners.
But smoke seeped through ducts and blackened the air in seconds. The lights went out soon after and phone flashlights turned us</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 08:55:42 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>