<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 14:24:13 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Journalists must be able to carry out their work without fear: MFC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/journalists-must-be-able-to-carry-out-their-work-without-fear-mfc</link><description>The Media Freedom Coalition in Bangladesh on Friday strongly condemned the attacks carried out Thursday night against journalists, editors, and media houses.
“Such acts of violence and intimidation are unacceptable and strike at the heart of press freedom and the public’s right to be i</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 11:45:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jhenaidah AL leaders’ houses torched</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/two-al-leaders-houses-attacked-torched-in-jhenaidah-after-hadis-death</link><description>The residences of two Awami League leaders have been vandalised and torched in Jhenaidah following the death of Inqilab Moncho Convenor Sharif Osman bin Hadi.
The attacks occurred in the early hours of Friday in Jhenaidah town’s Damdo and Hatkhola, according to Bellal Hossain, an additional</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 12:00:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UK imposes sanctions on perpetrators of violence against Syrian civilians</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/uk-imposes-sanctions-on-perpetrators-of-violence-against-syrian-civilians</link><description>Britain imposed sanctions on Friday on individuals and organisations it said were linked to violence perpetrated against civilians in Syria, including some who financially supported former president Bashar al-Assad's government.
While Britain has eased some sanctions on Syria as the country seeks</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 12:15:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chhayanaut protests vandalism, arson through song</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/chhayanaut-protests-vandalism-arson-through-song</link><description>Students and alumni of Bengali cultural organisation Chhayanaut and its educational wing Nalonda have taken to the streets outside its burnt and vandalised premises, protesting the attack on the institution through song.
The gathering came hours after assailants vandalised and set fire to Chhayana</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 12:30:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prothom Alo journalists allege 'premeditated attack' on office</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/prothom-alo-journalists-demand-action-against-perpetrators-of-premeditated-office-attack</link><description>The Bengali daily Prothom Alo has come under an organised attack planned by a vested quarter, the newspaper’s Executive Editor Sajjad Sharif has said.
He made the comment after attending a human chain formed at 4pm on Friday in front of his workplace, which was vandalised, looted and burned</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 12:45:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khaleda now ‘quite stable’: Zahid</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/khaleda-zias-condition-now-quite-stable-says-her-personal-physician</link><description>BNP chief Khaleda Zia’s health condition is now “quite stable” after nearly a month of treatment at Evercare Hospital in Dhaka, according to her personal physician AZM Zahid Hossain.
He shared the update during a media briefing outside the private hospital in Dhaka on Friday afte</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 13:00:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Don’t want to vandalise Indian embassy’: Patwary</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/we-do-not-want-to-vandalise-indian-high-commission-says-ncps-nasiruddin-patwary</link><description>National Citizen Party’s (NCP) Chief Coordinator Nasiruddin Patwary has called on people to take to the streets peacefully in protest against the killing of Inqilab Moncho spokesperson Sharif Osman bin Hadi.
Speaking at a press conference outside the party’s office in Banglamotor on Fr</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 12:47:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat calls for restraint, unity after Hadi’s death</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-calls-for-restraint-unity-after-hadis-death</link><description>Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami on Thursday urged patience, responsibility and national unity following the death of Sharif Osman Hadi, spokesperson of Inquilab Moncho and a July Movement activist, who died on Wednesday while receiving treatment in Singapore.
In a statement, Jamaat Ameer Dr Shafiqur Ra</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 13:02:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Italy-based Bangladeshis send over $1.3b remittances yearly</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/italy-based-bangladeshis-send-over-13b-remittances-yearly</link><description>Bangladesh Ambassador to Italy Rakibul Haque on Friday said more than 200,000 Bangladeshi expatriates living in Italy send over USD 1.3 billion in remittances annually, making a significant contribution to Bangladesh’s economy while strengthening bilateral friendship and socio-cultural ties.</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 13:17:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Republicans risk moderates, US House majority, with no healthcare extension</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/republicans-risk-moderates-us-house-majority-with-no-healthcare-extension</link><description>Republican worries about losing their majority in the US House of Representatives next year erupted this week, when four moderates joined Democrats in a last-ditch effort to prevent a spike in healthcare costs for 24 million Americans beginning in less than two weeks.
The four - Representatives Ro</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 13:32:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two Bangladeshis killed at Sylhet border in ‘Indian Khasi firing’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/two-bangladeshis-killed-at-sylhet-border-in-indian-khasi-firing</link><description>Two Bangladeshi men were killed by gunfire allegedly from Indian Khasi people at the Sylhet border in Companiganj Upazila on Friday afternoon.
The shooting took place at the Damdama border area of Uttar Ronikhai Union, Companiganj Police chief Shafiqul Islam said.
The victims were identified only</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 13:47:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tight security at metro stations</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/heightened-security-imposed-at-dhaka-metro-stations-amid-nationwide-tensions</link><description>Strict security measures have been imposed at metro rail stations across Dhaka following incidents of attacks, vandalism and arson at different establishments amid anger and protests triggered by the death of Sharif Osman bin Hadi, convenor of Inqilab Moncho.
On Friday, Dhaka Mass Transit Company</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 14:02:53 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>