<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 07:22:22 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nat'l leaders' coop indispensable for holding free, fair JS election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/natl-leaders-coop-indispensable-for-holding-free-fair-js-election</link><description>Chief Election Commissioner (CEC) A M M Nasir Uddin on Sunday sought cooperation and suggestions from the political parties to hold the 13th National Parliamentary Election in a free, fair, and acceptable manner.
He said the Election Commission (or EC) alone cannot arrange the entire process of ho</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 05:05:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Three workers burnt in shoe factory fire in Bangshal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/three-workers-burnt-in-shoe-factory-fire-in-bangshal</link><description>Three workers sustained burn injuries after a fire broke out at a shoe factory in the Bangshal area of Dhaka early Monday.
The incident occurred around 1:40 am at the factory located in Sikkatuli Mazar Goli under Bangshal Police Station.
The injured— Ainuddin, 45, Amir Uddin, 40, and Ruman,</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 04:51:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Joy warns of violence if ban on Awami League stays</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/joy-warns-of-violence-if-ban-on-awami-league-stays</link><description>The son and adviser of ousted Bangladesh Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina said on Sunday that supporters of her Awami League would block February’s national election if a ban on the party was not lifted, warning that protests could escalate into violence.
Sajeeb Wazed's remarks to Reuters came a</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 05:06:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Five vehicles torched, crude bomb blasts overnight</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/five-vehicles-torched-crude-bomb-blasts-overnight</link><description>Several buses, a truck and a four-wheeled passenger vehicle, locally known as a “Laguna”, have been set on fire in Dhaka’s Merul Badda, Mohammadpur, Savar, Narayanganj, and Dhamrai areas.
Crude hand bombs were also detonated in parts of the capital.
Fire Service Control Room Dut</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 05:21:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bus services suspended for second day in Barishal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/bus-services-suspended-for-second-day-in-barishal</link><description>Bus services from Nathullabad Bus Terminal in Barishal remained suspended for the second consecutive day on Monday, leaving thousands of commuters grappling with the crisis.
The bus operations on 23 intra-district routes have been halted since Saturday night after students of BM College allegedly</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 05:36:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Crude bomb hurled at Grameen Industrial Park in Gazipur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/crude-bomb-hurled-at-grameen-industrial-park-in-gazipur</link><description>Miscreants hurled a crude bomb at the main gate of Grameen Industrial Park in Kaliakair upazila of Gazipur district early Monday.
Sirajul Islam, security supervisor of Grameen Industrial Park-2 in Khara Jora area, said unidentified attackers threw the crude bomb targeting the factory at dawn.
Fla</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 05:51:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Four crude bomb blasts in Manikganj</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/four-crude-bomb-blasts-in-manikganj</link><description>At least four crude bombs have reportedly exploded in an hour in Manikganj, injuring two people.
The explosions took place between 10 pm and 11 pm on Sunday in areas surrounding the city's bus stand, the United Hospital adjacent to Sadar Hospital, and the Golra Highway Police Station, according to</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 06:06:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>32 killed in DR Congo after bridge at mine collapse</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/africa/32-killed-in-dr-congo-after-bridge-at-mine-collapse</link><description>At least 32 people were killed at a copper mine after a bridge collapsed in the Democratic Republic of the Congo, local authorities said Sunday.
A total of 32 bodies have been recovered so far after the collapse at the Kalando mine in southern Lualaba province on Saturday, said Roy Kaumba Mayonde,</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 06:06:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Relatives of July uprising martyrs gather at tribunal ahead of Hasina verdict</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/relatives-of-july-uprising-martyrs-gather-at-tribunal-ahead-of-hasina-verdict</link><description>Relatives of the martyrs of last year’s July uprising gathered at the International Crimes Tribunal (ICT) area on Monday morning ahead of the verdict in the case against former Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina and two others over alleged crimes against humanity during last year’s July-Augus</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 06:21:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Elder son accused of killing mother and brother in Cumilla</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/elder-son-accused-of-killing-mother-and-brother-in-cumilla</link><description>A woman and her younger son were stabbed to death at Basantapur village in Adarsha Sadar upazila of Cumilla on Monday, allegedly by her elder son.
The deceased were identified as Rahela Begum, 65, wife of the late Azgar Ali, and her younger son Kamal Hossain, 35.
Rahela’s elder son, Billal</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 06:36:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DSE, CSE indices rise in first hour of trade</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/dse-cse-indices-rise-in-first-hour-of-trade</link><description>Bangladesh’s capital market opened on a positive note on Monday, with key indices of both the Dhaka and Chattogram stock exchanges edging up in the first hour of trading.
At the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE), the benchmark DSEX gained 35 points, while the Shariah index DSES advanced 13 points a</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 06:51:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>42 Indian Umrah pilgrims feared dead in Saudi tanker collision</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/42-indian-umrah-pilgrims-feared-dead-in-saudi-tanker-collision</link><description>At least 42 Indian Umrah pilgrims are feared dead after a bus carrying them from Makkah to Madinah collided with a diesel tanker on Monday, causing a massive fire, media reports said.
Initial reports indicate that many of the victims were women and children from Hyderabad. Unofficial sources sugge</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 07:06:53 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>