<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 05:29:47 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Shipload of American wheat arrives</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/shipload-of-american-wheat-arrives</link><description>American Ambassador Brent T. Christensen visited Chattogram seaport with a plan to reinforce commercial cooperation and strengthen bilateral ties with Bangladesh as a shipload of US wheat arrived.
On Monday, Ambassador Christensen joined Chattogram Port Authority Chairman Rear Admiral S. M. Moniru</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 02:14:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Many Bangladesh’s journalists face voting exclusion despite new postal ballot system</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/many-bangladeshs-journalists-face-voting-exclusion-despite-new-postal-ballot-system</link><description>As Bangladesh prepares for the February 12 general election and referendum, the Election Commission’s newly introduced IT-supported hybrid postal balloting system has raised hopes for voters away from their constituencies, but journalists covering polls outside their home areas are once again</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 02:29:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jute trader shot attack in Savar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jute-trader-shot-attack-in-savar</link><description>A young jute trader was shot by assailants in Ashulia of Savar on Monday afternoon.
The injured, identified as Azad Hossain, 32, sustained a bullet wound to his leg, currently undergoing treatment at Enam Medical College Hospital.
According to locals, the attack occurred around 4:30pm in the East</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 02:44:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Youth injured in clash with BGB in Sylhet dies</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/youth-injured-in-clash-with-bgb-in-sylhet-dies</link><description>A 20-year-old youth who was shot during a clash with members of the Border Guard Bangladesh (BGB) in Jaintapur upazila of Sylhet has died.
Md Atiq Ahmed succumbed to his injuries while undergoing treatment at the Intensive Care Unit (ICU) of Sylhet Osmani Medical College Hospital around 5:30</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 02:59:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ICC rejects accreditation for Bangladeshi journalists to cover T20 World Cup</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/icc-rejects-accreditation-for-bangladeshi-journalists-to-cover-t20-world-cup</link><description>The diplomatic fallout between the International Cricket Council (ICC) and Bangladesh has extended to the press box, with the global body denying accreditation to all Bangladeshi journalists for the upcoming T20 World Cup.
The decision effectively creates a media blackout for Bangladesh at the tou</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 03:14:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Imams can play key role in holding successful referendum: Jashore DC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/imams-can-play-key-role-in-holding-successful-referendum-jashore-dc</link><description>Jashore Deputy Commissioner Mohammad Ashek Hasan on Monday said the referendum is a state responsibility and cannot be conducted in a transparent and credible manner without active public participation.
Speaking at a district-level imams’ conference organised by the Islamic Foundation</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 03:29:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>At least 6,126 people killed in Iran’s crackdown on nationwide protests, activists say</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/at-least-6126-people-killed-in-irans-crackdown-on-nationwide-protests-activists-say</link><description>Iran's bloody crackdown on nationwide protests killed at least 6,126 people while many others still are feared dead, activists said Tuesday, as a U.S. aircraft carrier group arrived in the Mideast to lead any American military response to the crisis.
The arrival of the USS Abraham Lincoln ai</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 03:44:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rescue efforts under way after Philippine ferry sinks, leaving 18 dead</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/rescue-efforts-under-way-after-philippine-ferry-sinks-leaving-18-dead</link><description>Search and rescue operations continued on Tuesday for 10 people still missing after a passenger boat capsized off a southern Philippine province, with the death toll rising slightly to 18, the Philippine Coast Guard said.
Captain Noemie Cayabyab, a spokesperson at the PCG, said the total number of</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 03:59:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Israel recovers last hostage body from Gaza</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/israel-recovers-last-hostage-body-from-gaza</link><description>Israel has recovered the remains of the last remaining hostage held in Gaza, the military said on Monday, fulfilling a key condition of the initial phase of US President Donald Trump's plan to end the war in the Palestinian territory.
The remains of police officer Ran Gvili - held in Gaza for more</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 04:14:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC starts postal ballot distribution in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-starts-postal-ballot-distribution-in-bangladesh</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) says the distribution of postal ballots nationwide has officially begun.
Speaking at the Nirbachan Bhaban on Monday, EC Secretary Akhtar Ahmed said ballots are being dispatched to the registered addresses of those who have signed up for postal voting.
This facility is</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 04:29:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump says he is raising tariffs on South Korean imports after trade deal delays</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/trump-says-he-is-raising-tariffs-on-south-korean-imports-after-trade-deal-delays</link><description>President Donald Trump said on Monday he was raising tariffs on US imports of South Korean autos and other goods, blaming the legislature of an ally and a major trading partner for dragging its feet on enacting a deal agreed last year.
For South Korea, the decision, which officials in Seoul said c</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 04:44:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NATO chief wishes 'good luck' to those who think Europe can defend itself without US help</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/nato-chief-wishes-good-luck-to-those-who-think-europe-can-defend-itself-without-us-help</link><description>NATO Secretary-General Mark Rutte insisted Monday that Europe is incapable of defending itself without U.S. military support and would have to more than double current military spending targets to be able to do so.
"If anyone thinks here … that the European Union or Europe as a whole can de</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 04:59:41 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>