<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 04:42:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Chikungunya spreads fast in Dhaka: IEDCR</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/chikungunya-spreads-fast-in-dhaka-iedcr</link><description>Siddiqur Rahman, a college teacher from the city's Azimpur area had been suffering from high fever and severe fatigue in late August for several days.
Following doctor's advice, he underwent a number of tests and tested Chikungunya positive.
"What began as a mild fever soon turned into excruciati</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 01:20:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Woman dies with symptoms of anthrax in Gaibandha</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/woman-dies-with-symptoms-of-anthrax-in-gaibandha</link><description>GAIBANDHA, Oct 05: A woman named has died with symptoms of anthrax in Sundarganj Upazila of Gaibandha.
The deceased was identified as Ajena Begum (45), wife of Abul Hossain under West Belka village of Belka union in Sundarganj Upazila. Panic has spread in the area following this incident.
Accordi</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 01:50:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Banks shift to short-term T-bills ahead of election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/banks-shift-to-short-term-t-bills-ahead-of-election</link><description>Yields on Treasury bills (T-bills) showed a mixed trend on Sunday as banks channelled their excess liquidity into short-term government securities rather than longer-tenure ones amid heightened caution ahead of the upcoming national election.
The shift reflects banks' preference for shorter maturi</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 02:05:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ACC awaits 'key' documents from Bangladesh Bank in inquiry into Atiur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/acc-awaits-key-documents-from-bangladesh-bank-in-inquiry-into-atiur</link><description>Despite requests in two phases, the Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) has not received the information and documents within the stipulated time for the inquiry it launched against former Bangladesh Bank governor Atiur Rahman over a series of allegations.
The latest letter sent by the anti-graft w</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 02:20:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Government mulls appointing experts to key administrative roles through ‘lateral entry’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/government-mulls-appointing-experts-to-key-administrative-roles-through-lateral-entry</link><description>As part of the implementation of the Public Administration Reform Commission's recommendations, the government is exploring the feasibility of hiring “specialist” individuals at the joint-secretary level.
The Cabinet Division committee, formed to examine this proposal, has submitted it</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 02:35:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>8 Arab, Muslim nations welcome Hamas' stance on Gaza ceasefire</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/8-arab-muslim-nations-welcome-hamas-stance-on-gaza-ceasefire</link><description>Egypt, Jordan, the United Arab Emirates, Indonesia, Pakistan, Türkiye, Saudi Arabia and Qatar on Sunday issued a joint statement welcoming Hamas's steps toward the ceasefire plan proposed by U.S. President Donald Trump to end the war in the Gaza Strip.
According to the statement, the foreign</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 02:50:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Commercial engagements with Bangladesh to expand: Maldives President</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/commercial-engagements-with-bangladesh-to-expand-maldives-president</link><description>Bangladesh and the Maldives have reaffirmed their commitment to further strengthening the existing excellent bilateral relations and enhancing cooperation between the two friendly countries.
Dr Md Nazmul Islam, the newly appointed High Commissioner of Bangladesh to the Republic of Maldives, presen</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 04:22:20 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>