<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 12:45:32 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Maldives gives briefing on e-visas for expat Bangladeshis</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/maldives-gives-briefing-on-e-visas-for-expat-bangladeshis</link><description>The Maldives government's immigration department has shared details on how Bangladeshis are being included in its initiative to bring all migrant workers under e-visas.
On Saturday, the country's Immigration Controller General Ahmed Fasih highlighted the initiatives on the e-visa and the new mobil</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 10:55:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>S Korea to negotiate with US for favourable chip tariff terms: official</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/south-korea-to-negotiate-with-the-us-for-favourable-chip-tariff-terms-official-says</link><description>South Korea will seek favourable terms for US tariffs on imports of memory chips, a presidential office spokesperson said at a televised briefing on Sunday.
The country last year released a joint fact sheet on its trade deal with the US that included terms ensuring South Korea will not receive unf</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 11:10:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC upholds BNP candidate Aslam Chy’s nomination in Ctg-4</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ec-upholds-bnp-candidate-aslam-chys-nomination-in-ctg-4</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) on Sunday upheld the candidacy of BNP candidate Mohammad Aslam Chowdhury (Chattogram-4), rejecting the appeal petitions submitted by several banks to cancel his candidature on ground of loan default.
The Commission, chaired by Chief Election Commissioner AMM Nasir Uddi</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 11:25:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Land ministry asks to use QR code through its ‘Bhumi’ App</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/land-ministry-asks-to-use-qr-code-through-its-bhumi-app</link><description>The Ministry of Land has launched a mobile application named ‘Bhumi’ to address the emerging situation and to ensure easy, safe and reliable land services for the citizens, said a ministry release.
The government has introduced the app as organised fraud rings are creating fake/forged</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 11:40:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cumilla-10 BNP candidate Gofur also loses candidacy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/cumilla-10-bnp-candidate-gofur-also-loses-candidacy</link><description>BNP candidate for Cumilla-10 Abdul Gofur Bhuiyan on Sunday lost his candidacy following the hearing of an appeal petition by the Election Commission.
The EC rejected the nomination of the BNP candidate for Cumilla-10 on grounds of dual citizenship, accepting an appeal petition filed by Sanskrit Mu</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 11:00:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DMP files 2,167 cases for violating traffic rules</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dmp-files-2167-cases-for-violating-traffic-rules</link><description>The Traffic Division of the Dhaka Metropolitan Police (DMP) has filed 2,167 cases against motor vehicles as well as three-wheelers and motorcycles for violating traffic rules in a single day across the capital.
A media release of the DMP on Sunday said that they filed those cases and realised the</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 11:15:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dutch minister calls Trump’s Greenland tariff threat ‘blackmail’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/dutch-minister-calls-trumps-greenland-tariff-threat-blackmail</link><description>The Netherlands’ foreign minister on Sunday said that the US President Donald Trump’s threat to impose new tariffs on European allies until they agree to sell Greenland to the United States is “blackmail”.
“It’s blackmail what he’s doing ... and it’s</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 11:30:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Robber’ killed in lynch-mob attack in Noakhali</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/robber-killed-in-lynch-mob-attack-in-noakhali</link><description>A 35-year-old suspected robber was killed in a lynch-mob attack at Kalir Bazar in Kabirhat upazila of Noakhali district on Saturday night.
The deceased was identified as Mizanur Rahman Rony, son of Shahid of Joinadpur village in the upazila.
Mizanur Rahman was wanted in six criminal cases, said N</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 11:45:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Greenland welcomes European response to Trump's tariffs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/greenland-welcomes-european-response-to-trumps-tariffs</link><description>Greenland thanked European nations on Sunday for maintaining their support for the Arctic island despite being targeted by punitive tariffs from US President Donald Trump who wants to annex the Danish-ruled territory.
France, Germany, Britain and other European countries this week sent small group</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 12:00:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP delegation meets CEC as student wing protests ballot issue</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-delegation-meets-cec-as-student-wing-protests-ballot-issue</link><description>A five‑member BNP delegation has met Chief Election Commissioner AMM Nasir Uddin at the Election Commission headquarters in Agargaon, as student activists staged a sit‑in outside.
The delegation on Sunday afternoon was led by BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir. Other members include</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 12:15:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump's Greenland tariffs prompt calls for unprecedented EU counter-measures</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trumps-greenland-tariffs-prompt-calls-for-unprecedented-eu-counter-measures</link><description>The European Union faced calls on Sunday to implement a never-before-used range of economic counter-measures known as the "Anti-Coercion Instrument" as part of the bloc's response to US President Donald Trump's tariff threats against European allies over Greenland.
Trump vowed on Saturday to imple</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 12:30:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BSEC focuses on new IPO rules at stakeholder coordination meeting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bsec-focuses-on-new-ipo-rules-at-stakeholder-coordination-meeting</link><description>The Bangladesh Securities and Exchange Commission (BSEC) on Sunday convened its 5th monthly coordination meeting with capital market stakeholders, emphasising major legal reforms and the strategic direction of the market.
Held at the BSEC Multipurpose Hall in the city, the meeting was attended by</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 12:45:32 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>