<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 21:24:43 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>NRBC Bank Chairman Md. Ali Hossain Prodhania receives ‘Excellence in Corporate Governance Award’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/nrbc-bank-chairman-md-ali-hossain-prodhania-receives-excellence-in-corporate-governance-award</link><description>Md. Ali Hossain Prodhania, Chairman of the Board of Directors of NRBC Bank PLC, has been honoured with the ‘Excellence in Corporate Governance Award’ in recognition of his outstanding leadership in promoting excellence, transparency and accountability in corporate governance and for exp</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 16:10:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Meghna Bank signs Participation Agreement with BB for Startup Refinance Scheme</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/meghna-bank-signs-participation-agreement-with-bb-for-startup-refinance-scheme</link><description>Recently, with a view to fostering an innovation-led entrepreneurial ecosystem, Meghna Bank PLC has signed a Participation Agreement with Bangladesh Bank under the Startup Refinance Scheme.
The signing ceremony was graced by Ms. Nurun Nahar, Deputy Governor of Bangladesh Bank, as the chief guest,</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 16:25:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Uruguay could be a gateway for RMG exports to Mercosur: BGMEA</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/uruguay-could-be-a-gateway-for-rmg-exports-to-mercosur-bgmea</link><description>The Bangladesh Garment Manufacturers and Exporters Association (BGMEA) has identified Uruguay as a potential "gateway" for expanding Bangladesh’s ready-made garment (RMG) exports into the influential South American trade bloc, Mercosur.
The observation was made during a meeting on Thursday b</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 16:14:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ordinance amended to add retired chief justice in Supreme Court Secretariat Commission</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ordinance-amended-to-add-retired-chief-justice-in-supreme-court-secretariat-commission</link><description>The interim government has amended an ordinance to include a retired chief justice as a member of the Supreme Court Secretariat Commission.
The announcement was made on Thursday at the Foreign Service Academy by Chief Advisor’s Press Secretary Shafiqul Alam, who briefed the media on decision</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 16:29:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Accountability deferred, democracy denied</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/accountability-deferred-democracy-denied</link><description>A democracy will not often fail with the loud cracking of Glass. In fact, failure will often occur in the silent hours of fear rebranded as order, of oppression justified as stability, of institutions of democracy subverted to safeguard power rather than safeguard democracy’s citizenry. In ti</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 16:44:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Vanishing urban greenery</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/vanishing-urban-greenery</link><description>Bangladesh's capital Dhaka has been ranked among the world's fastest-growing cities, accommodating around 21 per cent of the country's total population. According to the UN's World Urbanization Prospects 2025 report, Dhaka has become the world's second most populous city, after Jakarta of Indonesia</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 16:59:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Impacts of cold spells on health and economy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/impacts-of-cold-spells-on-health-and-economy</link><description>A moderate cold wave is sweeping across at least 12 districts in the north of the country with Naogaon district recording the lowest ever temperature this year at 6.7 degree Celsius on January 6 last. Temperature in Rajshahi hovers between 7.0 and 9.0 degree Celsius for a few days now. The cold spe</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 17:14:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Blue economy: Rich in promise, poor in practice</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/blue-economy-rich-in-promise-poor-in-practice</link><description>Several years have passed since Bangladesh successfully resolved its long-standing maritime boundary disputes with Myanmar and India -- an achievement widely hailed as historic. Yet, with the passage of time, a quiet unease has set in. The verdicts of the international tribunals were not merely abo</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 17:29:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Desire to overcome despair and angst</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/reviews/desire-to-overcome-despair-and-angst</link><description>510 years ago, in 1516, Utopia by Thomas More was published in Europe. Written in Latin, the English meaning of the full Latin title is: ‘A truly golden little book, not less beneficial than enjoyable, about how things should be in a state and about the new island Utopia.’ In 1518, a re</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 17:45:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Regulatory mkt intervention ramped  up for balancing exchange rate</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/regulatory-mkt-intervention-ramped-up-for-balancing-exchange-rate</link><description>A higher inflow of remittances prompts the central bank to scale up intervention in the foreign-exchange market to forestall any imbalance in dollar-taka exchange rates and avoid its economic domino effect.
Officials say amid a steady rise inflow of remittances in recent days the Bangladesh Bank (</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 18:00:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DU syndicate proposes rechristening facilities named after Sheikh family</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/du-syndicate-proposes-rechristening-facilities-named-after-sheikh-family</link><description>Dhaka University’s top policy-making body, the syndicate, has recommended the senate to rename five campus facilities named after Sheikh Hasina’s family, including two residential halls.
The proposed changes include renaming Bangabandhu Sheikh Mujibur Rahman Hall to Shahid Osman Hadi H</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 18:15:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Main shooter in BNP leader Alamgir murder arrested in Jashore</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/main-shooter-in-bnp-leader-alamgir-murder-arrested-in-jashore</link><description>The main shooter in the murder case of BNP leader Alamgir Hossain, Tridib Chakraborty Mishuk (30), has been arrested by DB police in Jashore.
He was held on Wednesday around 7:00 pm near the Bejpara temple area of the city. Tridib is the son of Mihir Chakraborty Trinath, residing in the Chiruni Ka</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 18:30:54 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>