<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 10:10:04 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>KUMCH female student found dead in Kushtia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/kumch-female-student-found-dead-in-kushtia</link><description>Police recovered the body of a female student of Kushtia Medical College Hospital (KUMCH) hanging from the ceiling of a rented room at Housing E-Block area in Kushtia district town on Sunday evening.
The deceased was identified as Samia Nijhum, daughter of Md Abdus Salam of Chotp Shalikha area of</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 07:00:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bomb-making materials seized in Chapainawabganj</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bomb-making-materials-seized-in-chapainawabganj</link><description>Rapid Action Battalion (RAB) members recovered 6.27 kilograms of gunpowder and bomb-making materials in Shibganj upazila of Chapainawabganj district on Sunday night.
According to a press release sent by RAB-5 on Monday morning, those were seized from a mustard field in the Parghorapakhia area.
No</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 07:15:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Results of 13th JS polls to be announced by Feb 13: EC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/results-of-13th-js-polls-to-be-announced-by-feb-13-ec</link><description>The results of the 13th Jatiya Sangsad election and referendum, scheduled to be held on February 12, will be announced by the following day, Election Commissioner Anowarul Islam Sarkar said.
The election and the referendum will be held simultaneously this year, leading to speculation that the anno</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 07:30:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh set to vote in world's first Gen Z-inspired election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-set-to-vote-in-worlds-first-gen-z-inspired-election</link><description>For years under former Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina, Bangladesh’s opposition had little presence on the streets during elections, either boycotting polls or being sidelined by mass arrests of senior leaders. Now, ahead of Thursday’s vote, the roles have reversed.
Hasina’s Awami L</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 07:45:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No security threats surrounding general election, says DMP chief Sazzat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/no-security-threats-surrounding-general-election-says-dmp-chief-sazzat</link><description>Dhaka Metropolitan Police (DMP) Commissioner SM Sazzat Ali says there are no threats of violence surrounding the upcoming 13th parliamentary election.
Speaking at a media briefing on Monday, Sazzat said a total of 25,000 specially trained police personnel will be on duty for the polls, reports b</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 08:00:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ex-Army chief Iqbal Karim Bhuiyan calls for RAB, DGFI to be dissolved</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ex-army-chief-iqbal-karim-bhuiyan-calls-for-rab-dgfi-to-be-dissolved</link><description>Former Bangladesh Army chief Iqbal Karim Bhuiyan has called for the dissolution of the Rapid Action Battalion (RAB) and the Directorate General of Forces Intelligence (DGFI), accusing the two agencies of involvement in enforced disappearances and killings.
Iqbal, widely known as IKB, made the re</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 08:15:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Electioneering in JS polls to end Tuesday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/electioneering-in-js-polls-to-end-tuesday</link><description>Campaigning by candidates contesting the 13th Jatiya Sangsad elections and the referendum, scheduled for February 12, will officially end on Tuesday at 7:30 am. 
The electioneering period, which began on January 22, concludes 48 hours before polling day, in line with the rules of the Election</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 08:30:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Musk targets to build city on moon within 10 years</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/musk-targets-to-build-city-on-moon-within-10-years</link><description>SpaceX founder Elon Musk has said that the company is prioritising plans to build a self-sustaining city on the Moon before attempting a permanent settlement on Mars.
Musk explained that a lunar city is faster and more practical than going directly to Mars. The Moon is closer to Earth, with trips</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 08:30:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC bars ‘unauthorised outsiders’ from constituencies from Feb 10-13</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-bars-unauthorised-outsiders-from-constituencies-from-feb-10-13</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has announced that no one, aside from voters and authorised personnel, will be allowed to stay in parliamentary constituencies from the morning of February 10 to the afternoon of the day after the general election and referendum vote.
The EC issued a notice in this reg</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 08:45:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>2nd CA Bangladesh Cup Golf Tournament held</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/2nd-ca-bangladesh-cup-golf-tournament-held</link><description>A day-long 2nd CA Bangladesh Cup Golf Tournament 2026 was successfully concluded in a festive atmosphere at Jolshiri Golf Club (JGC) in Dhaka on Saturday.
The golf tournament brought together Chartered Accountants and golf enthusiasts from across Bangladesh for a day of competitive and collegiate</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 09:00:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BB keeps policy rate at 10pc as inflation risks persist</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/bb-keeps-policy-rate-at-10pc-as-inflation-risks-persist</link><description>Bangladesh Bank maintained a tight monetary stance for the second half of fiscal year 2025-26, keeping the policy rate unchanged at 10 per cent, as the central bank seeks to contain inflation while pushing lenders for increasing private-sector credit.
Governor Ahsan H Mansur unveiled the January&amp;n</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 09:15:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Verdict in graft case against Jubo League’s Samrat set for Feb 25</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/verdict-in-graft-case-against-jubo-leagues-samrat-set-for-feb-25</link><description>A Dhaka court is to deliver its verdict in a graft case against Ismail Hossain Chowdhury Samrat over the illegal accumulation of wealth on Feb 25.
Dhaka Special Judge Zakaria Hossain set the date for the verdict on Monday, reports bdnews24.com.
The court's High Bench Assistant Fakir Zahidul Islam</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 09:30:44 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>