<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 21:37:08 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Transport workers call off strike in Mymensingh, four districts after talks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/transport-workers-call-off-strike-in-mymensingh-four-districts-after-talks</link><description>Transport workers have withdrawn their strike in five districts of Mymensingh Division, calling in protest against the arrest of a worker accused of harassing a July Uprising protester and the suspension of 16 United Service buses.
As a result, buses will resume operations from Monday morning.
On</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 16:06:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ensuring accountability &amp; human rights</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/ensuring-accountability-human-rights</link><description>This year's International Day for Universal Access to Information (IDUAI) dawned at a grim moment for Bangladesh. It, however, helped to open many windows.
The Information Commission-the very body entrusted since 2010 with upholding citizens' access to public information-has been essentially inact</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 16:36:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Child marriage and sexual violence against girls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/child-marriage-and-sexual-violence-against-girls</link><description>Much as the nation strives to bring an end to child marriage, the unlawful matrimony continues in this country. The consequences of such premature marriage for underage girls with adult youths or men are devastating. It is the brides who pay the heaviest price. The girls given off to such marriage</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 16:51:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How reliable are methods of measuring poverty?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/how-reliable-are-methods-of-measuring-poverty</link><description>Poverty has occupied the central stage of development thinking. In fact, development is about improvement in the income level and basic living standards of the common people. It should focus first and foremost on addressing poverty among the masses. It is because of this, the World Bank (WB), the m</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 17:06:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>MDCF-2: A breakthrough in fight against child malnutrition</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/mdcf-2-a-breakthrough-in-fight-against-child-malnutrition</link><description>Just as the oral rehydration solution (ORS) developed by the icddr,b revolutionised the fight against diarrhoea worldwide, this breakthrough has the potential to make a lasting impact on malnutrition
 
It is heartening that a food supplement for undernourished children, developed by the Inte</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 17:21:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BGB soldier loses leg in landmine explosion on Bangladesh-Myanmar border</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bgb-soldier-loses-leg-in-landmine-explosion-on-bangladesh-myanmar-border</link><description>A Border Guard Bangladesh (BGB) soldier lost his leg in a landmine explosion along the Naikhongchhari border on Saturday morning.
The incident occurred around 10:50am while a BGB patrol team was operating in the Tumbru border area of Naikhongchhari upazila.
Nayek Mohammad Akhtar Hossain of</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 17:36:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>At least 44 people dead after torrential rains in Mexico</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/at-least-44-people-dead-after-torrential-rains-in-mexico</link><description>At least 44 people were killed in Mexico after days of heavy rains and flooding, the government said on Sunday.
Torrential rains from tropical storms Priscilla and Raymond triggered landslides and flooding across five states.
There were 18 people killed in Veracruz state, 16 in Hidalgo, nine in P</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 19:00:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ACC prosecutes ex-MP Iqbal, son over 'illicit wealth'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/acc-prosecutes-former-mp-iqbal-and-son-for-allegedly-acquiring-illicit-wealth</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission has brought charges of acquiring illicit wealth against former Awami League MP and Premier Bank chairman HBM Iqbal.
The agency has also filed a separate case on the same charge against his son and another former Premier Bank chair -- Imran Iqbal.
On Sunday, ACC spok</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 19:30:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rice imports hit record highs despite satisfactory stock</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/rice-imports-hit-record-highs-despite-satisfactory-stock</link><description>Rice imports into Bangladesh spiked by nearly a record 5,400 per cent in the first two months of this fiscal year as traders rushed to cash in on duty waivers coupled with price fall in India.



Economists alert to risk of farmers being deprived of fair price as government procurement has be</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 19:45:01 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>