<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 07:21:16 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Consensus Commission bins claims of Tk 830m expenditure on hospitality</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/consensus-commission-bins-claims-of-tk-830-million-expenditure-on-hospitality</link><description>The National Consensus Commission (NCC) has refuted claims that it spent Tk 830 million on hospitality, stating that its total expenditure was Tk 17.1 million, of which Tk 4.5 million was spent on hospitality.
“A very recent campaign by a certain quarter has falsely alleged that the National</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 04:11:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tea yield in Sylhet feared to face a massive shortfall</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/tea-yield-in-sylhet-feared-to-face-a-massive-shortfall</link><description>Tea production in Sylhet region is apprehended to suffer a massive shortfall this year due to drought-induced foul weather and high prices of fertilisers.
Industry insiders anticipate the fall in tea yield while there's no chance to achieve the year's target as the main season of production has al</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 05:20:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Friendship receives Earthshot Prize 2025</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/friendship-receives-earthshot-prize-2025</link><description>Friendship, a Bangladeshi social purpose organisation, has been named the winner of the Earthshot Prize 2025 in the "Fix Our Climate" category.
The Earthshot is a global environmental award that was distributed first in 2021. The local NGO has been given the prestigious award for its integrated an</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 05:35:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>National Revolution and Solidarity Day being observed</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/national-revolution-and-solidarity-day-being-observed</link><description>The National Revolution and Solidarity Day is being observed today (Friday) across the country in a befitting manner.
On this day 50 years ago, Bangladesh began a new journey through a joint revolution of the members of the armed forces and mass people emerging from a state of chaos and uncertaint</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 05:50:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Four arrested over murder of BNP activist in Raozan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/four-arrested-over-murder-of-bnp-activist-in-raozan</link><description>Police have arrested four people in connection with the murder of a BNP activist in Chattogram’s Raozan upazila last month.
The arrestees are Abdullah Khokon alias Langra Khokon, Md Maruf, Saqlain Hossain, and Ziaur Rahman. Among them, Saqlain Hossain has been shown arrested in a separate ca</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 06:05:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Recently returned expatriate worker shot dead in Khulna</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/recently-returned-expatriate-worker-shot-dead-in-khulna</link><description>A Bangladeshi expatriate worker has been shot dead in Khulna’s Rupsha only a few days after he returned to the country.
The incident occurred next to a field owned by Manik Sardar in the Ramnagar area of Noihati Union around 9:00 pm on Thursday, bdnews24.com reports.
Mahfuzur Rahman, chief</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 06:20:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Elon Musk's $1 trillion Tesla pay plan wins shareholder approval</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/elon-musks-1-trillion-tesla-pay-plan-wins-shareholder-approval</link><description>Tesla CEO Elon Musk won shareholder approval on Thursday for the largest corporate pay package in history as investors endorsed his vision of morphing the EV maker into an AI and robotics juggernaut.
The proposal was approved with over 75 per cent support, and Musk bounded to the stage of the comp</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 06:06:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AEB holds discussion on National Revolution and Solidarity Day</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/aeb-holds-discussion-on-national-revolution-and-solidarity-day</link><description>The Association of Engineers, Bangladesh (AEB), the country’s sole professional platform for nationalist-minded engineers, organised a discussion marking National Revolution and Solidarity Day 2025 on Thursday evening at the Institution of Engineers, Bangladesh (IEB) auditorium in Dhaka, acco</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 06:21:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BCB forms probe panel after harassment claims by Jahanara Alam</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/bcb-forms-probe-panel-after-harassment-claims-by-jahanara-alam</link><description>The Bangladesh Cricket Board (BCB) has announced the formation of an investigation committee after former national women’s team captain Jahanara Alam alleged that she faced sexual harassment and psychological abuse from members of the team management during the 2022 ICC Women’s World Cu</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 06:36:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Flights delayed at Delhi airport after technical glitch</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/flights-delayed-at-delhi-airport-after-technical-glitch</link><description>Aircraft movement at Delhi airport was hampered on Friday because its Air Traffic Control system suffered a technical problem, the Airports Authority of India (AAI) said after several flights were disrupted at one of the world's busiest airports.
Top airlines IndiGo, Air India and Spicejet said th</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 06:51:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Case filed over murder of ‘BNP activist’ Sarwar in Ctg shooting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/case-filed-over-murder-of-bnp-activist-sarwar-in-chattogram-shooting</link><description>The family of Sarwar Hossain Babla, who was shot and killed during a BNP event in Chattogram, has filed a case over his murder.
Seven suspects have been named in the case filed by Sarwar’s father Abdul Quader on Friday, said Jashim Uddin, the chief of Bayezid Bostami Police Station.
Two of</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 07:06:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Authorities urge calm after fire report near Rooppur nuclear plant</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/authorities-urge-calm-after-fire-report-near-rooppur-nuclear-plant</link><description>Officials from the Rooppur Nuclear Power Plant Project have urged the public not to be misled by misinformation or rumours surrounding a recent fire that broke out near the plant in Pabna.
In a statement issued on Thursday night, Saikat Ahmed, senior scientific information officer for the plant's</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 07:21:15 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>