<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 08:36:04 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Prisoner dies at Kushtia District Jail</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/prisoner-dies-at-kushtia-district-jail</link><description>A convicted prisoner died at Kushtia District Jail early Saturday.
The deceased was identified as Bidyut Ali, 27, son of Chaddu Ali of Bheramara upazila.
Kushtia Jail Super Shariful Alam said Bidyut was sent to jail about two months ago after being convicted in a drug-related case.
Initially, it</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 05:43:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India rejects any allegations of involvement in Pakistan bombing</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/india-rejects-any-allegations-of-involvement-in-pakistan-bombing</link><description>India said it rejected "any and every" allegation of involvement in a bombing at a mosque in Islamabad on Friday, that killed at least 31 people, saying such claims were baseless and pointless.
"The bombing at an Islamabad mosque earlier today is condemnable and India condoles the loss of life it</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 05:58:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Amazon shares fall as it joins Big Tech AI spending spree</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/global/amazon-shares-fall-as-it-joins-big-tech-ai-spending-spree</link><description>Amazon has announced plans to invest $200 billion (£147.7b) in artificial intelligence (AI) and infrastructure, becoming the latest US tech giant to set out a sharp rise in spending.
It dwarfs the $125bn Amazon spent on AI last year, and appeared to rattle investors. Shares were down nearly</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 06:13:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gold price in Bangladesh crosses Tk 260,000 per bhori again</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/gold-price-in-bangladesh-crosses-tk-260000-per-bhori-again</link><description>Gold prices in Bangladesh surged once again on Saturday, with the price of 22-carat gold crossing the Tk 260,000 mark per bhori, according to the Bangladesh Jewellers Association (BAJUS).
 
In a notification issued in the morning, BAJUS announced an increase of Tk 7,640 per bhori, setting th</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 06:28:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>SpaceX delays Mars plans to focus on moon landing</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/spacex-delays-mars-plans-to-focus-on-moon-landing</link><description>Elon Musk's SpaceX told investors it will prioritise going to the moon first and attempt a trip to Mars at a later time, the Wall Street Journal reported on Friday, citing sources.
The company will target March 2027 for a lunar landing without astronauts on board, the report added.
The news comes</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 06:46:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NY governor signs law allowing medical aid in dying for terminally ill residents</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/ny-governor-signs-law-allowing-medical-aid-in-dying-for-terminally-ill-residents</link><description>New York Governor Kathy Hochul on Friday signed a bill into law allowing medical aid in dying to be available for terminally ill New Yorkers with less than six months to live.
The law has parameters to ensure that patients are not coerced into choosing medical aid in dying and that no healthcare p</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 07:01:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Postal ballots of 420,000 expatriates reach Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/postal-ballots-of-420000-expatriates-reach-bangladesh</link><description>More than 420,000 postal ballots cast by expatriate Bangladeshis have arrived in the country ahead of next week’s parliamentary election.
Salim Ahmad Khan, team leader of the Election Commission’s OCV-SDI project, said 422,960 ballots had been received by 10:15 am on Saturday.
Electio</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 07:16:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh PM front-runner rejects unity govt offer, says his party set to win: Reuters</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-pm-front-runner-rejects-unity-govt-offer-says-his-party-set-to-win-reuters</link><description>Bangladesh’s leading prime ministerial contender, Tarique Rahman, on Friday rejected a proposal from his main rival for a unity government after elections next week, saying his party was confident of winning on its own.
Rahman, 60, who heads the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP), returned h</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 07:31:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India, US release framework for interim trade agreement</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/india-us-release-framework-for-interim-trade-agreement</link><description>India and the United States released a framework for an interim trade agreement to lower tariffs on Indian goods, which Indian opposition accused of favouring Washington.
The joint statement, released Friday, came after US President Donald Trump announced his plan last week to reduce import tariff</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 07:46:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>SAARC journalists meet at Delhi University</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/saarc-journalists-meet-at-delhi-university-1</link><description>SAARC Journalists Forum (SJF) on Friday organised an international conference and tree plantation programme at the historic Gandhi Bhawan, located in the North Campus of Delhi University, in India.
Journalist leaders from various SAARC countries, university teachers, and a large number of students</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 08:01:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jailed Awami League leader Ramesh Chandra Sen dies in custody</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jailed-awami-league-leader-ramesh-chandra-sen-dies-in-custody</link><description>Former water resources minister and senior Awami League leader Ramesh Chandra Sen has died while in jail.
The 85-year-old passed away at 9:30am on Saturday, said Taufiq Hasan, a doctor at the emergency department of Dinajpur Medical College Hospital.</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 08:16:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Teknaf child injured by Myanmar gunfire dies</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/teknaf-child-injured-by-myanmar-gunfire-dies</link><description>A child from Teknaf who was seriously injured by gunfire originating from Myanmar has died under hospital care.
Huzaifa Sultana Afnan suffered a critical head injury in the incident in Whykong Union on Jan 11. She died around 9:50 am on Saturday while receiving treatment at the National Institute</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 08:31:58 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>