<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 21:17:30 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Bangladesh whitewashed in T20 series</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/cricket/bangladesh-whitewashed-in-t20-series</link><description>Bangladesh tasted an ignominious whitewash in the T20 series after West Indies thrashed them by five wickets in the tour-ending third match at Bir Shrestha Shaheed Flight Lieutenant Motiur Rahman Stadium in Chattogram today.
Opener Tanzid Hasan Tamim fought lonely to hammer a scintillating 62 ball</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 18:53:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Economic slowdown &amp; youth unemployment</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/economic-slowdown-youth-unemployment</link><description>Bangladesh has long been praised for its sustained growth trajectory, supported by strong export industries, remittance inflows, and a youthful population. However, behind the overall figures lies a troubling reality: the educated youth of the country are increasingly unable to find decent jobs, wh</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 19:53:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>What to wear and what not</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/what-to-wear-and-what-not</link><description>A short video clip showing a young lady and a man exchanging verbal arguments inside a public bus went viral recently. The incident began when the lady boarded the bus and was looking for a seat. The man, sitting next to the door, murmured a few words that made the lady furious. She reacted sharply</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 20:08:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Who will take responsibility for the poor?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/who-will-take-responsibility-for-the-poor</link><description>Over the last five decades, Bangladesh has seen governments come and go, each promising to position the country as a model of development or as the next rising economic star in the region. Certain governments have, to their credit, achieved notable progress, although in an inconsistent rather than</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 20:23:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Towards an austerity-driven revised FY26 budget</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/towards-an-austerity-driven-revised-fy26-budget</link><description>As far as a new fiscal year's budget is concerned, it was a tradition that its size would be bigger than that of the previous fiscal year. But the interim government seems to have departed from that norm by reducing the size of FY26's budget compared with the FY25's reflecting a move towards fiscal</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 20:53:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Major dev partners follow 'wait and watch' policy amid political transition</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/major-dev-partners-follow-wait-and-watch-policy-amid-political-transition</link><description>At least five key development partners of Bangladesh fid not make any foreign- aid commitment in the first quarter of this fiscal year, as they seem waiting for the next elected government, insiders said Friday, as post-uprising transition is underway.



In addition, Bangladesh's largest devel</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 21:08:12 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>