<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 09:20:39 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Government proposes raising rent allowance for MPO teachers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/government-proposes-raising-rent-allowance-for-mpo-teachers</link><description>The education ministry has proposed increasing the house rent allowance for MPO-listed teachers and staff to Tk 2,000–3,000, following the rejection of the government’s previous decision to raise the amount to Tk 1,500.
The proposal also includes raising the medical allowance to Tk 1,0</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 05:41:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>WB lifts growth forecast for Middle East region, Iran suffers contraction</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/global/wb-lifts-growth-forecast-for-middle-east-region-iran-suffers-contraction</link><description>The World Bank has lifted its growth outlook for the region encompassing the Middle East, North Africa, Afghanistan and Pakistan for 2025, though trimmed its forecast for next year, citing conflict and lower oil production in Iran and Libya.
The Washington-based lender said it now expected regiona</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 05:56:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Indices fall in early trading at Dhaka, Chattogram bourses</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/indices-fall-in-early-trading-at-dhaka-chattogram-bourses</link><description>Key indices at both the Dhaka and Chattogram stock exchanges declined in the first hour of trading on Tuesday, with most companies witnessing a drop in share prices.
At the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE), the benchmark index DSEX fell by 16 points in early trading, says a UNB agency report.
The Shari</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 06:11:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Japan's Takaichi picks ex-premier Aso as party vice president</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/japans-takaichi-picks-ex-premier-aso-as-party-vice-president</link><description>Sanae Takaichi, who is expected to become Japan's next prime minister, chose former premier and party heavyweight Taro Aso on Tuesday as vice president of her ruling party, a move some analysts saw as a restraining force against big fiscal spending.
Takaichi also chose former finance minister Shun</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 06:26:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gaza talks turn to key sticking points between Israel, Hamas</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/gaza-talks-turn-to-key-sticking-points-between-israel-hamas</link><description>Delegations from Israel and Hamas held their first day of indirect negotiations in Egypt on Monday on US President Donald Trump's plan to halt the war in Gaza, wrestling with contentious issues such as demands that Israel withdraw and Hamas disarm.
Israel and Hamas have both endorsed the overall p</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 07:26:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BSEC moves to unify all securities rules to restore discipline: Chairman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/bsec-moves-to-unify-all-securities-rules-to-restore-discipline-chairman</link><description>Bangladesh Securities and Exchange Commission (BSEC) Chairman Khondoker Rashed Maqsood has said that the commission is working to bring all securities-related rules under one framework to restore discipline and curb malpractice in the capital market.
Speaking at an event on Monday marking 'World I</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 07:41:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat seeks UN’s cooperation, technical support for free and fair polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-seeks-uns-cooperation-technical-support-for-free-and-fair-polls</link><description>Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami has sought cooperation and technical assistance from the United Nations to ensure that the upcoming national election is free, fair and acceptable.
The request was made during a meeting between Jamaat Ameer Dr Shafiqur Rahman and UN Resident Coordinator in Dhaka, Gwyn Le</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 07:56:26 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>