<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 09:36:46 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Takaichi set to become Japan’s first female PM</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/takaichi-set-to-become-japans-first-female-pm</link><description>Japan's ruling party picked conservative nationalist Sanae Takaichi as its new head on Saturday, putting her on course to become the country's first female prime minister.
The Liberal Democratic Party elected Takaichi, 64, to regain trust from a public angered by rising prices and drawn to opposit</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 06:28:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Road accidents killed 417 across Bangladesh in September: report</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/road-accidents-killed-417-across-bangladesh-in-september-report</link><description>At least 417 people were killed and 682 were injured in 446 road accidents across Bangladesh in September, according to the Road Safety Foundation.
On Saturday, the foundation published its monthly report on road accidents, based on data collected from nine national dailies, seven online news port</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 06:58:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Why does Dan Brown still stay ahead in a world ruled by AI?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/entertainment/why-does-dan-brown-still-stay-ahead-in-a-world-ruled-by-ai</link><description>A man wanders through a shadowed church in Rome, clutching a note marked with strange symbols. He recalls racing through Paris to decode a secret hidden in a da Vinci painting, then standing beneath the Florentine Duomo as death itself seemed woven into the architecture. 
In Washington, he once un</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 07:28:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh making significant efforts to eliminate trafficking: US</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-making-significant-efforts-to-eliminate-trafficking-us-1</link><description>The government of Bangladesh has demonstrated overall increasing efforts to deal with the trafficking in persons compared with the previous reporting period, says the United States (US).
The US, in its recently released '2025 Trafficking in Persons Report,' said the government of Bangladesh does n</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 07:43:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh braces for cyclone risk, possible floods in October</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-braces-for-cyclone-risk-possible-floods-in-october</link><description>The Bangladesh Meteorological Department (BMD) has flagged the possibility of up to three low-pressure systems forming in the Bay of Bengal in October, one of which may intensify into a depression or a cyclone.
The Met Office made the forecast in its long-term weather outlook issued on Saturday,</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 07:58:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How the Gaza aid flotilla used cameras and data to win global attention</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/how-the-gaza-aid-flotilla-used-cameras-and-data-to-win-global-attention</link><description>When armed Israeli soldiers boarded a flotilla of boats trying to deliver food and medicine to Gaza on Wednesday night, two web developers in Glasgow scrambled to keep track of the vessels as millions of people worldwide tuned in to monitor their fate.
As grainy footage from onboard cameras broadc</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 08:31:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nation bids farewell to Language Movement veteran Ahmad Rafiq</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nation-bids-farewell-to-language-movement-veteran-ahmad-rafiq</link><description>The body of Ahmad Rafiq has been taken to the Central Shaheed Minar in Dhaka, where people from all walks of life are paying their last respects to the Language Movement veteran.
Following the tributes on Saturday, his coffin will be carried in a funeral procession to Ibrahim Medical College Hospi</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 08:46:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Islami Bank employees block Chattogram highway for almost an hour</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/islami-bank-employees-block-chattogram-highway-for-almost-an-hour</link><description>Employees of Islami Bank have staged a blockade on the Dhaka–Chattogram Highway at Faujdarhat, halting traffic for nearly an hour in protest against the bank's “special competency evaluation” programme.
Around 11am on Saturday, they formed a human chain near the Faujdarhat Police</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 09:01:52 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>