<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 14:29:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>No foreign force should harm Dhaka–Beijing ties: envoy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/chinese-ambassador-says-no-foreign-force-should-undermine-china-bangladesh-relations</link><description>China has warned that no external power should be allowed to damage its growing relationship with Bangladesh, as Beijing signalled strong support for the new government led by Prime Minister Tarique Rahman.
Speaking to reporters after a meeting with senior officials, the Chinese ambassador said Ch</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 12:06:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Habiganj BNP leader held for 'verbally abusing' police officer</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/habiganj-bnp-leader-in-custody-after-going-viral-for-insulting-police-officer</link><description>Police have detained a BNP leader in Habiganj after an audio clip surfaced where he was reportedly heard using abusive language toward a police officer.
Ferdous Chowdhury Tushar, president of the Bahubal Upazila unit of the BNP, was picked up from his residence around 12pm on Sunday, confirmed Hab</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 12:21:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CAB protests obstruction of consumer watchdog drive</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cab-protests-obstruction-of-consumer-watchdog-drive</link><description>The Consumers Association of Bangladesh (CAB) staged a human chain on Sunday to protest what it called the obstruction of a government market monitoring drive and demanded strict action against those responsible.
The demonstration took place in front of the Jatiya Press Club in the capital.
Speak</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 12:36:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Supreme Court limits Trump tariff powers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/tariff-ruling-limits-trumps-leverage-but-wont-end-uncertainty-for-trade-partners</link><description>The US Supreme Court's decision to strike down a large swath of President Donald Trump's tariffs has weakened his ability to threaten and impose tariffs at a moment's notice, but it won't end gnawing uncertainty for trade partners or companies.
Trump responded within hours to the ruling on Friday,</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 12:51:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump says he is sending a hospital ship to Greenland</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-says-he-is-sending-a-hospital-ship-to-greenland</link><description>US President Donald Trump on Saturday said he was working with Louisiana Governor Jeff Landry to send a hospital boat to Greenland, a Danish territory that Trump has said he wants to acquire.
Trump announced the plan on social media moments before hosting a dinner for Republican governors at the W</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 13:06:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>PM to confer ‘Ekushey Padak-2026’ on February 26</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/pm-to-confer-ekushey-padak-2026-on-february-26</link><description>Prime Minister Tarique Rahman is expected to distribute the ‘Ekushey Padak-2026’ at a function in the capital on February 26.
A cultural ministry press release said Prime Minister Tarique Rahman will hand over the ‘Ekushey Padak-2026’ at Osmani Memorial Auditorium at 11:00</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 12:46:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Youths aged 16 or above may avail of NID services: EC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/youths-aged-16-or-above-may-avail-of-nid-services-ec</link><description>Youths aged 16 or above will be able to avail the national identity (NID) services and card from now on, according to a decision taken by the Election Commission.
The EC on Sunday issued a notification, directing its field-level officials to extend the NID services to the Bangladesh citizens aged</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 13:01:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>More than 1,000 ‘politically-motivated’ cases to be withdrawn</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/more-than-1000-politically-motivated-cases-to-be-withdrawn</link><description>The newly-formed BNP government has moved to withdraw more than a thousand cases it says were politically motivated during the 17‑year tenure of the Awami League government led by Sheikh Hasina.
In a statement issued Sunday, Home Minister Salahuddin Ahmed said approval had been given to withdraw 1</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 13:16:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NBR invites applications for C&amp;F agent licences</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/nbr-invites-applications-for-cf-agent-licences</link><description>The National Board of Revenue (NBR) has invited applications from eligible individuals and entities for Customs Clearing and Forwarding (C&amp;amp;F) agent licences under the newly enacted Customs Clearing and Forwarding Agent Licensing Rules, 2026, aiming to enhance service quality and ensure a more compe</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 13:31:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EU lawmaker wants US trade deal vote deferred</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/eu-lawmaker-urges-delay-to-us-trade-deal-vote-after-tariff-upheaval</link><description>A senior EU lawmaker proposed on Sunday postponing a vote on the EU-US trade deal that had been planned for this week, arguing that the terms and legal basis on which the deal was struck had changed.
The US Supreme Court struck down President Donald Trump's global tariffs on Friday, prompting Trum</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 13:46:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>PM chairs meeting on ‘building a healthy Bangladesh’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/pm-chairs-meeting-on-building-a-healthy-bangladesh</link><description>Prime Minister Tarique Rahman on Sunday presided over a meeting on 'building a healthy Bangladesh'.
The meeting was held at the Prime Minister's special meeting room at the Cabinet Division in the Bangladesh Secretariat here this afternoon.
Health and Family Welfare Minister Sardar Md Sakhawat Ho</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 14:01:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jatiya Party’s vote share was systematically suppressed, Shameem Patwary alleges</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jatiya-partys-vote-share-was-systematically-suppressed-shameem-patwary-alleges</link><description>Jatiya Party Secretary General Shameem Haider Patwary has alleged that the party was premeditatedly defeated in the parliamentary elections.
Speaking at a media briefing held on Sunday at the Dhaka Reporters’ Unity auditorium, he claimed the party’s vote share was systematically suppre</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 14:16:29 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>