<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 18:39:35 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Mother ‘strangles’ daughter on ‘lover’s prompt’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/mother-strangles-daughter-on-lovers-prompt</link><description>Police in Gopalganj recovered the body of a 3-year-old girl 20 days after she went missing from Sadar Upazila, arresting her mother, who allegedly killed the child at the prompting of her lover.
On Saturday afternoon, officers broke the lock of a room in Gobra Madhya Para and found the child&amp;rsquo</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 15:27:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Voters can find polling station information in four ways</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/voters-can-find-polling-station-information-in-four-ways</link><description>Bangladesh Election Commission (EC) has introduced four simple methods for voters to obtain their voter number and polling station information to facilitate voting in the February 12 national elections and referendum.
Using these methods, voters can quickly and accurately find their voter number a</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 15:42:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mother, child killed under train in Tongi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/mother-child-killed-under-train-in-tongi</link><description>A mother and son have died after being run over by a train in Gazipur’s Tongi.
Citing family members, Tongi Railway Police Outpost chief Sub-Inspector (SI) Rahima Akhter said a Dhaka-bound Subarna Express ran them over on Saturday after leaving Chattogram.
The dead are Jannat, 35, and her s</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 15:14:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt says so-called PASHA election observers not to get EC cards</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-says-so-called-pasha-election-observers-not-to-get-ec-cards</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has postponed its decision to issue more than 10,000 election observer cards to the so-called non-governmental organisation People’s Association for Social Advancement (PASHA) for the national election.
Briefing reporters after a high-level meeting at the state g</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 15:29:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CA happy over polls preparations, says next ‘week very crucial’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ca-happy-over-polls-preparations-says-next-week-very-crucial</link><description>Expressing satisfaction over the steps taken so far as part of election-centric preparations, Chief Adviser Prof Muhammad Yunus on Saturday said the next one week would be very crucial as the twin elections – national election and referendum – are scheduled to take place on February 12.</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 15:44:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Exchange rates, international finance and the global economy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/exchange-rates-international-finance-and-the-global-economy</link><description>Exchange rates, the price of one currency in terms another currency, are crucial in international finance for influencing trade balance, investment flows and inflation. Factors influencing exchange rates include interest rates, economic activity, inflation and market confidence. For economies like</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 15:59:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Keeping market stable in Ramadan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/keeping-market-stable-in-ramadan</link><description>The holy month of Ramadan will begin in less than two weeks. It is a time when people are expected not only to deepen their spiritual devotion but also to refrain from practices that are morally indefensible and harmful to others. Yet, year after year, Ramadan is marked by a familiar and troubling</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 16:14:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Will FDI surge after election?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/will-fdi-surge-after-election</link><description>Notwithstanding various efforts and policy supports, inflow of foreign direct investment (FDI) in Bangladesh is still nominal.  The annual average net inflow of FDI stood at $1.60 billion in the last 10 years which is less than one per cent of the country's gross domestic product (GDP). Like m</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 16:29:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ctg port deal: Haste makes waste</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/ctg-port-deal-haste-makes-waste</link><description>The temporary break in the Chattogram port strike that came after six full days of disruption did little to ease tensions. Port workers have flat-out warned that operations may be shut down again as early as tomorrow unless the government scraps the deal with DP World for the New Mooring Container</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 16:44:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Monetary policy decisions under political constraints</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/monetary-policy-decisions-under-political-constraints</link><description>Bangladesh Bank is scheduled to announce its monetary policy stance for the second half of FY26 on Monday (February 9, 2026), amid persistent inflationary pressures and weakening momentum in the real sector. Advisers to the interim government have been pressing for a reduction in the policy rate, c</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 17:15:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gold prices fall in overnight reversal after morning peak</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/gold-prices-fall-in-overnight-reversal-after-morning-peak</link><description>Gold prices in Bangladesh fell by Tk 3,266 per bhori on Saturday night, hours after a sharp increase earlier in the day, as the Bangladesh Jewellers Association (BAJUS) announced a fresh price adjustment.
In a notification BAJUS fixed the price of 22-carat gold at Tk 258,824 per bhori (11.664 gram</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 17:30:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fresh Ctg port strike call draws business outcry</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/fresh-ctg-port-strike-call-draws-business-outcry</link><description>Crisis in Chittagong port for protests against terminal lease to foreign operators deepens with planned strike resumption today that will aggravate the severe container congestion already caused by six days' strike by workers and employees.
Shiploads of cargos stayed stuck at sea and docks in a na</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 17:45:49 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>