<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 14:20:46 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Pakistan says Afghan Taliban must rein in militants for ceasefire to hold</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/pakistan-says-afghan-taliban-must-rein-in-militants-for-ceasefire-to-hold</link><description>Pakistan's ceasefire agreement with the Afghan Taliban hinges on their ability to rein in militant attacks on Islamabad from their soil, Defence Minister Khawaja Muhammad Asif told Reuters on Monday.
A Taliban spokesperson and its defence ministry did not immediately respond to a request for comme</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 12:12:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>72nd Risk Management Committee meeting of Shahjalal Islami Bank held</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/72nd-risk-management-committee-meeting-of-shahjalal-islami-bank-held</link><description>The 72nd meeting of the Risk Management Committee (RMC) of Shahjalal Islami Bank PLC was held on 15th October 2025 at its Corporate Head Office of the bank.
The meeting was presided over by Engineer Md. Towhidur Rahman, Chairman of the Risk Management Committee of the bank, according to a media re</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 12:27:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Travel ban imposed on Subhash Singha Roy, his wife</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/travel-ban-imposed-on-subhash-singha-roy-his-wife</link><description>A court in Dhaka on Monday imposed a travel ban on journalist and UniMed UniHealth Pharmaceuticals Ltd. director Subhash Singha Roy and his wife and former lawmaker Mamata Hena Lovely over graft allegations.
Dhaka Metropolitan Senior Special Judge Md Sabbir Faiz passed the order, allowing a plea o</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 11:16:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Haji Salim, his son put on 4-day remand</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/haji-salim-his-son-put-on-4-day-remand</link><description>A Dhaka court on Monday placed Haji Mohammad Salim, former lawmaker of Awami League (Dhaka-7) and his son Solaiman Salim on a four-day remand in a murder case filed with Shahbagh Police Station.
Dhaka Chief Metropolitan Magistrate GM Farhad Ishtiak passed the order when police produced them before</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 11:31:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladeshi journalist Imran selected for PEN Canada’s ‘Voices of Freedom’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladeshi-journalist-imran-selected-for-pen-canadas-voices-of-freedom</link><description>Bangladeshi journalist and writer Abdullah Al Imran has been selected for the international reading series “Voices of Freedom”, organised by literary organisation PEN Canada.
The event is scheduled for Nov 12 evening at the Toronto Reference Library, where Imran will present his own wr</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 11:46:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BIDA chief leads strategic mission to South Korea</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bida-chief-leads-strategic-mission-to-south-korea</link><description>A high-level delegation from Bangladesh, led by Chowdhury Ashik Mahmud Bin Harun, Executive Chairman of the Bangladesh Investment Development Authority (BIDA), arrived in the Republic of Korea (ROK) today for a five-day strategic mission aimed at attracting foreign direct investment (FDI) and enhan</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 12:01:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ACC submits charge sheet against Atiur, Barakat over debt forgery, embezzlement</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/acc-submits-charge-sheet-against-atiur-barakat-over-debt-forgery-embezzlement</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) on Monday submitted charge sheet against 26 people, including former governor of Bangladesh Bank Dr Atiur Rahman and former chairman of Janata Bank Prof Dr Abul Barakat for debt forgery and embezzlement of over Taka 2.97 billion.
Director General of the Anti Co</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 12:46:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Korea reaffirms support to UNHCR for humanitarian assistance for Rohingyas in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/korea-reaffirms-support-to-unhcr-for-humanitarian-assistance-for-rohingyas-in-bangladesh</link><description>The Republic of Korea on Monday reaffirmed its support to UNHCR, the UN Refugee Agency, for critical humanitarian assistance and protection for Rohingya refugees in Bangladesh, with a contribution of USD 5 million to strengthen disability inclusion and protection efforts, as well as provide essenti</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 13:16:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Crude bomb explodes near NCP meeting hall in Bogura</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crude-bomb-explodes-near-ncp-meeting-hall-in-bogura</link><description>A crude bomb has exploded outside the venue of a National Citizen Party coordination meeting in Bogura.
No casualties were reported.
Inside the Bogura District Council hall on Monday, the meeting continued with NCP Chief Organiser (North) Sarjis Alam present.
The incident took place around 3:30p</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 13:31:06 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>