<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 06:31:33 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>23 killed in nightclub fire in India's Goa</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/23-killed-in-nightclub-fire-in-indias-goa</link><description>At least 23 people died after a fire at a nightclub in India's Goa state, the chief minister of the state said on Sunday, as videos on social media showed ambulances lining up to help the injured.
The incident occurred around 12:04 am local time (1834 GMT Saturday) in the village of Arpora, the st</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 04:35:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India warns IndiGo of regulatory action</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/india-warns-indigo-of-regulatory-action</link><description>India's aviation watchdog on Saturday warned airline IndiGo of regulatory action after it cancelled thousands of flights over the last week, stranding passengers and forcing government action to limit a surge in airfares caused by the crisis.
The country's biggest airline, IndiGo cancelled the fli</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 04:50:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Youth stabbed to death in Jashore</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/youth-stabbed-to-death-in-jashore</link><description>A 22-year-old youth was stabbed to death near Ansar Camp in Bejpara of  Jashore town on Saturday midnight
Tanvir, son of Mintu from Shankarpur Hazarigat, was found bleeding near the camp around 12:55 am, reports UNB.
Locals rushed him to Jessore 250-Bed General Hospital, where doctors declar</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 05:05:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>220 MW Sonagazi solar plant gets green light</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/220-mw-sonagazi-solar-plant-gets-green-light</link><description>In a major push toward clean energy, the government has taken up a plan to ramp up renewable power generation and reduce reliance on coal and fuel-based electricity that contributes to environmental degradation.
The project titled “Construction of Sonagazi 220MW Solar Power Plant,&amp;rdqu</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 05:20:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>7.0-magnitude earthquake hits Alaska</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/70-magnitude-earthquake-hits-alaska</link><description>An earthquake with a magnitude of 7.0 jolted the US state of Alaska at 2041 GMT on Saturday, the US Geological Survey (USGS) said.
Tremors were felt in the state's capital, Juneau, and in Whitehorse, the capital of Canada's Yukon territory, reports Xinhua, citing local media.
According to the USG</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 04:45:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Medical representative killed in Gaibandha road crash</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/medical-representative-killed-in-gaibandha-road-crash</link><description>A representative of a veterinary medicine company was killed in a road accident on the Gaibandha-Sadullapur Road at Narayanpur area in Sadar upazila on Saturday.
The deceased was identified as Nazir Hossain, 23, son of Amirul Islam of Pakurtala village under Kamalerpara union in Saghata upazila, r</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 05:00:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>18 killed after migrant boat sinks off southern Greece</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/18-killed-after-migrant-boat-sinks-off-southern-greece</link><description>At least 18 people died after a boat carrying migrants capsized off the southern coast of Crete, Greece's public broadcaster ERT reported on Saturday.
The vessel sank about 26 nautical miles (48.2 km) south of Ierapetra, a town on the island's southern shoreline. According to the Hellenic Coast Gu</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 05:15:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Japan turns to new technology as dementia cases surge</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/japan-turns-to-new-technology-as-dementia-cases-surge</link><description>Japan is grappling with a fast-growing dementia crisis as thousands of older people wander from their homes each year.
Police data shows that more than 18,000 dementia patients went missing in 2023, and almost 500 were later found dead.
The number of such cases has doubled since 2012, highlightin</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 05:30:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Turag building fire under control; 23 rescued</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/turag-building-fire-under-control-23-rescued</link><description>Firefighters extinguished a blaze that broke out in a 10-storey residential building in Turag, on the outskirts of the capital, after one and a half hours of intensive efforts early Sunday.
A total of 23 residents were rescued from the building, with five sustaining minor injuries. No serious inju</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 05:45:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>'Politics driven by illicit income fuels extortion, weak governance and poor education'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics-driven-by-illicit-income-fuels-extortion-weak-governance-and-poor-education</link><description>Politics driven by illicit income inevitably fosters extortion and muscle power, said Planning Adviser Dr Wahiduddin Mahmud.
He also said that such practices even influence education outcomes, contributing to poor quality and high dropout rates.
He made these remarks on Sunday while speaking at a</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 06:00:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC meets to set schedule for national election, referendum</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-meets-to-set-schedule-for-national-election-referendum</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) is holding a meeting to fix the schedule for the 13th parliamentary election and a national referendum expected to take place simultaneously in February next year.
The meeting, chaired by Chief Election Commissioner (CEC) AMM Nasir Uddin, began at the EC headquarters i</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 06:15:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Freedom fighter, wife killed in Rangpur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/freedom-fighter-wife-killed-in-rangpur</link><description>A freedom fighter and his wife were found dead with their throats slit at their home in Taraganj upazila of Rangpur early Sunday.
The deceased were identified as freedom fighter Jogesh Chandra Roy, 75, a retired headteacher of a local government primary school, and his wife Surbonna Roy, 60, resid</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 06:30:41 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>