<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 09:41:06 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Seven Chhatra League men among 11 held in Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/seven-chhatra-league-men-among-11-held-in-dhaka</link><description>Detectives have detained 11 people, including seven leaders and activists of the banned Bangladesh Chhatra League, the student wing of the deposed Awami League, during an overnight operation in the capital.
Deputy Commissioner of DMP’s Media and Public Relations Division Muhammad Talebur Rah</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 06:03:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mother alleges foul play as two siblings found dead in Narail pond</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/mother-alleges-foul-play-as-two-siblings-found-dead-in-narail-pond</link><description>Two siblings drowned in a pond in Kalia upazila of Narail district on Tuesday afternoon.
The deceased were identified as Taslima Khatun, 15, a 10th-grade student of Bardiya Girls’ Secondary School, and her brother Kawsar Sheikh, 8, a 2nd-grade student of Shibanandapur Government Primary Scho</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 06:33:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hefazat activists block highways in Ctg after leader’s death in road crash</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/hefazat-activists-block-highways-in-ctg-after-leaders-death-in-road-crash</link><description>Leaders and activists of Hefazat-e-Islam Bangladesh blocked the Chattogram–Khagrachhari and Chattogram–Rangamati highways on Wednesday, demanding justice over the death of one of their leaders in a road accident, halting traffic on both routes.
Police said Maulana Sohel Chowdhury, an e</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 06:48:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chattogram Airport gets boost with Flydubai’s return, SalamAir expansion</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/chattogram-airport-gets-boost-with-flydubais-return-salamair-expansion</link><description>After a hiatus following the suspension of flight operations from Chattogram’s Shah Amanat International Airport, Flydubai is set to resume services, while SalamAir expands its operations.
Flydubai, based in the United Arab Emirates, will operate daily flights from Chattogram, with a total o</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 07:33:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Islamist militants kill 11 Pakistan paramilitary troops in ambush, sources say</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/islamist-militants-kill-11-pakistan-paramilitary-troops-in-ambush-sources-say</link><description>Islamist militants ambushed a Pakistani military convoy near the Afghan border on Wednesday, killing nine paramilitary soldiers and two officers, sources said, with the Pakistani Taliban claiming responsibility.
Roadside bombs hit the convoy before a large number of militants launched a gun attack</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 07:48:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fresh charges filed against Hasina over enforced disappearances</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fresh-crimes-against-humanity-charges-filed-against-hasina-over-enforced-disappearances</link><description>Formal charges have been filed at the International Crimes Tribunal in two cases of crimes against humanity tied to the enforced disappearances of opposition figures during the tenure of the Awami League regime.
Former prime minister Sheikh Hasina, who was ousted in the July Uprising, is the main</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 08:03:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EU to send observers for upcoming national election: Khosru</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/eu-to-send-observers-for-bangladeshs-upcoming-national-election-khosru</link><description>The European Union (EU) has decided to send election observers to Bangladesh for the upcoming national election, BNP Standing Committee member Amir Khosru Mahmud Chowdhury said on Wednesday.
“The EU has decided to send observers following requests from the government and the Election Commiss</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 08:33:20 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>