<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 12:40:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Ministry warns all over fake video using Adviser Salehuddin’s image</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ministry-warns-all-over-fake-video-using-adviser-salehuddins-image</link><description>The Ministry of Finance has urged the public to remain alert about a fake video that has recently circulated on social media, allegedly using the image and likeness of Finance Adviser Dr Salehuddin Ahmed for promotional purposes.
According to an official media statement issued on Sunday, a v</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 09:34:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Arrest warrant issued against actress Mehazabien over ‘embezzlement, death threats’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/arrest-warrant-issued-against-actress-mehazabien-over-embezzlement-death-threats</link><description>A Dhaka court has issued arrest warrants against actress Mehazabien Chowdhury and her brother Alisan Chowdhury on charges of "embezzlement of Tk 2.7 million and death threats" after luring the plaintiff in with promises of making him a business partner.
Judge Afroza Tania of Dhaka Executive Magist</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 09:49:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Salehuddin urges next govt to ‘recognise’ interim administration’s groundwork</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/salehuddin-urges-next-govt-to-recognise-interim-administrations-groundwork</link><description>Finance Adviser of Bangladesh’s interim government, Dr Salehuddin Ahmed, on Sunday called on the incoming elected administration to duly recognise the foundational work and stabilising measures undertaken during the interim government’s tenure, emphasising that the coming months are cru</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 10:04:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NBR moves to make Bond Automation System compulsory after tiral</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/nbr-moves-to-make-bond-automation-system-compulsory-after-tiral</link><description>The National Board of Revenue (NBR) is set to make the use of its Bond Automation System compulsory after nearly 10 months of trial implementation, as authorities believe mandatory adoption is essential to fully realise the intended efficiency, transparency and facilitation benefits for export-orie</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 10:19:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Japan’s finance minister says stimulus package to exceed $110b, Nikkei reports</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/japans-finance-minister-says-stimulus-package-to-exceed-110b-nikkei-reports</link><description>Japan’s economic stimulus package will exceed 17 trillion yen ($110 billion), Finance Minister Satsuki Katayama said after meeting with Prime Minister Sanae Takaichi, the Nikkei business daily reported on Sunday.
Since taking office in October, Takaichi has pledged to compile a sizeable pack</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 10:34:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Media industry stakeholders call for industry-led self-regulation framework to ensure press freedom</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/media-industry-stakeholders-call-for-industry-led-self-regulation-framework-to-ensure-press-freedom</link><description>The news media industry must take the lead to establish a structured and industry-driven system for self-regulation to safeguard press freedom, strengthen accountability, rebuild public trust, and uphold high journalistic standards.
The issue was raised during three consultation meetings organized</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 10:30:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trust Bank, BFIU unite to bolster anti-money laundering efforts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/trust-bank-bfiu-unite-to-bolster-anti-money-laundering-efforts</link><description>A regional workshop titled “Proactive Transaction Monitoring – Finding Key Indicators for Detecting Money Laundering” was held on November 12, 2025, at City Hotel, Cox’s Bazar.
The event was organized by the Bangladesh Financial Intelligence Unit (BFIU) and hosted by Trust</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 10:45:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Restriction of vehicular movement inside cantonment on Nov 21</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/restriction-of-vehicular-movement-inside-cantonment-on-nov-21</link><description>Restrictions have been imposed on vehicular movement inside the Dhaka Cantonment on November 21, marking Armed Forces Day, according to a release from the Inter-Services Public Relations (ISPR) this afternoon.
To keep the roads of Dhaka Cantonment (main road from Shaheed Jahangir Gate to the Staff</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 11:00:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Robust auditing, governance crucial for future of Islamic finance: BB chief</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/robust-auditing-governance-crucial-for-future-of-islamic-finance-bb-chief</link><description>Bangladesh Bank (BB) Governor Ahsan H Mansur on Sunday said that the future growth and stability of Bangladesh’s Islamic banking sector are dependent upon the implementation of robust accounting, governance, and auditing practices.
“Adherence to high auditing standards is crucial for m</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 11:15:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No level playing field due to three advisors’ ‘misleading role’, say eight religion-based parties</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/no-level-playing-field-due-to-three-advisors-misleading-role-say-eight-religion-based-parties</link><description>The leaders of eight religion-based parties have said “misguidance” from three interim government advisors is hindering the level playing field.
On Sunday, Jamaat-e-Islami Secretary General Mia Golam Porwar, on behalf of the eight parties, announced that their movement will continue un</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 11:30:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AB Bank inaugurates its relocated Kakrail Branch</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ab-bank-inaugurates-its-relocated-kakrail-branch</link><description>AB Bank PLC. has recently relocated its Kakrail Branch to 82, Kakrail Road, Ramna, Dhaka.
Mr. Syed Mizanur Rahman, Managing Director &amp; CEO, AB Bank, inaugurated the new premises with all modern banking facilities, according to a media release. 
Officials of the bank, along with valued client</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 11:45:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt secrecy blocks disclosure: Salehuddin</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/government-secrecy-prevents-disclosure-of-many-developments-adviser-salehuddin-says</link><description>Finance Adviser Salehuddin Ahmed has responded to claims that “nothing is happening”, saying many developments cannot be revealed because of government-imposed “secrecy”.
Speaking at the national award ceremony for DRU’s Best Special Report of the Year on Sunday, he s</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 12:00:44 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>