<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 17:32:11 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Three parties stage protests in front of EC demanding registration</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/three-parties-stage-protests-in-front-of-ec-demanding-registration</link><description>Three political parties, which were denied registration by the Election Commission, staged demonstrations in front of Nirbachan Bhaban on Wednesday, demanding official recognition.
The three parties—Aam Janatar Dal, Bangladesh Justice and Development Party, and Moulik Bangla—staged sep</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 13:57:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ambassador Mushfiqul promotes Bangladesh-Mexico trade ties at Querétaro</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ambassador-mushfiqul-promotes-bangladesh-mexico-trade-ties-at-queretaro</link><description>Bangladesh and Mexico have explored the new avenues of cooperation in trade, investment, pharmaceuticals and manufacturing, with emphasis on strengthening institutional partnerships between the business chambers of both the countries.
Bangladesh Ambassador to Mexico Mushfiqul Fazal Ansarey underto</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 14:12:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DU tops Bangladeshi universities in QS Asia Rankings again</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/du-tops-bangladeshi-universities-in-qs-asia-rankings-again</link><description>University of Dhaka (DU) has once again been ranked as the top university in Bangladesh in the QS Asia University Rankings, published by the UK-based education and research organization Quacquarelli Symonds (QS).
According to the rankings released on Tuesday, Dhaka University secured the 132nd pos</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 14:27:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fakhrul condemns gun attack on BNP’s candidate in Chattogram</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/fakhrul-condemns-gun-attack-on-bnps-candidate-in-chattogram</link><description>BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir on Wednesday strongly condemned the gun attack on the party’s candidate for Chattogram-8 Ershad Ullah, describing it as a clear attempt to create chaos and disrupt the upcoming 13th national election.
In a statement, he also demanded the imme</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 14:42:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BSF fires sound grenades at Lalmonirhat-Patgram border</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bsf-fires-sound-grenades-at-lalmonirhat-patgram-border</link><description>Tensions flared at the Lalmonirhat-Patgram border as the Indian Border Security Force (BSF) fired three rounds of sound grenades early Wednesday morning, triggering panic among locals.
The incident occurred near the Serampur Union in Patgram Upazila, in proximity to the Bangladesh-India border at</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 14:57:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Reza Kibria joins BNP; likely to contest polls from Habiganj-1</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/reza-kibria-joins-bnp-likely-to-contest-polls-from-habiganj-1</link><description>Reza Kibria, son of late former finance minister Shah AMS Kibria, has joined BNP and is likely to contest the upcoming national election from the Habiganj-1 constituency.
“I have already joined BNP and filled up its primary membership form some days ago,” Reza told UNB on Wednesday.
H</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 15:27:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Muntasir Mahmud permanently expelled from NCP</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/muntasir-mahmud-permanently-expelled-from-ncp</link><description>The National Citizen Party (NCP) has permanently expelled its southern region organiser Muntasir Mahmud on charges of breaching party discipline.
According to a party statement issued on Wednesday, the decision was made by the NCP’s disciplinary committee.
Muntasir, who had been working at</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 15:42:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Envoy stresses stronger trade, energy and tourism ties with Nepal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/envoy-stresses-stronger-trade-energy-and-tourism-ties-with-nepal</link><description>Bangladesh Ambassador to Nepal Md Shafiqur Rahman has called for deepening economic cooperation between Bangladesh and Nepal through enhanced trade, connectivity, and investment in joint ventures, particularly in the sectors of energy and tourism.
The envoy made the remarks this afternoon during a</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 16:12:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BGMEA briefs IMF on RMG risks, urges govt to prioritize FTAs to counter LDC graduation challenge</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bgmea-briefs-imf-on-rmg-risks-urges-govt-to-prioritize-ftas-to-counter-ldc-graduation-challenge</link><description>A delegation from the International Monetary Fund (IMF) met with the Bangladesh Garment Manufacturers and Exporters Association (BGMEA) on Wednesday to discuss the current state and future risks of the country's ready-made garment (RMG) sector, aiming to ensure macroeconomic stability.
The meeting</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 16:42:06 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>