<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 07:19:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Yunus urges rights groups to increase visits to Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/yunus-urges-rights-groups-to-increase-visits-to-bangladesh</link><description>Chief Advisor Muhammad Yunus has called on international human rights organisations to increase their engagement with Bangladesh.
He made this call on Monday during a meeting with a human rights delegation led by Kerry Kennedy, president of the Robert F Kennedy Human Rights organisation, at a hote</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 04:00:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump says US to impose 100pc tariff on movies made outside the country</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/trump-says-us-to-impose-100pc-tariff-on-movies-made-outside-the-country</link><description>US President Donald Trump said on Monday he would impose a 100 per cent tariff on all films produced overseas that are then sent into the US, repeating a threat made in May that would upend Hollywood's global business model.
The step signals Trump's willingness to extend protectionist trade polici</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 04:30:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khelafat Majlis announces 11-day programme</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/khelafat-majlis-announces-11-day-programme</link><description>Islamist party Khelafat Majlis has announced an 11-day programme, including a mass procession in Dhaka, to demand a legal framework for the July Uprising as part of a 5-point agenda.
The plans were outlined in a statement signed by party chief Maulana Mamunul Haque and Secretary General Maulana Ja</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 05:00:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two ex-MPs, 11 leaders of banned AL arrested</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/two-ex-mps-11-leaders-of-banned-al-arrested</link><description>Detective Branch (DB) police arrested two former members of parliament (MPs) and 11 other leaders and activists of banned Awami League (AL) and affiliated bodies from different areas in the capital.
The arrestees are Faizur Rahman Badal, former MP of Brahmanbaria-5 constituency and also president</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 05:15:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Some 34pc crops, worth 4pc of GDP, lost pre-consumption</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/some-34pc-crops-worth-4pc-of-gdp-lost-pre-consumption</link><description>Bangladesh loses about 34 per cent of its farm produce before it reaches consumers, which is equal to 4.0 per cent of the country's gross domestic product (GDP), said experts on Monday.
Addressing a national conference titled "Towards Zero Food Waste and Loss: Building a Sustainable Food Value Cha</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 05:30:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ERF Institute launches academic programme</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/erf-institute-launches-academic-programme-1235</link><description>Finance Adviser Dr Salehuddin Ahmed inaugurating the academic programme of the Economic Reporters Forum (ERF) Institute on its premises in the capital on Monday. — FE Photo
 
The Economic Reporters Forum (ERF) Institute started the journey of its academic programme on Monday.</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 05:45:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Women to get legal rights soon to take children to workplaces: Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/women-to-get-legal-rights-soon-to-take-children-to-workplaces-adviser</link><description>Dr Wahiduddin Mahmud, Adviser to the Ministry of Planning, said women would soon have the legal rights to take their children to workplaces, as the interim government is working to establish a provision in this regard.
He said women are not only carrying the lion's share of unpaid household work,</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 06:00:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UN chief pledges full support for Bangladesh’s democratic transition</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/un-chief-pledges-full-support-for-bangladeshs-democratic-transition</link><description>United Nations Secretary-General António Guterres has expressed his full support and solidarity with Bangladesh’s ongoing democratic transition and reform initiatives.
He made the remarks during a meeting with Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus at the UN Headquarters in New York o</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 06:15:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NU makes ICT course mandatory at UG level</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/nu-makes-ict-course-mandatory-at-ug-level</link><description>With technical assistance from the ICT Division's Aspire to Innovate (a2i) programme and UNICEF, the National University (NU) has, for the first time, introduced a mandatory four-credit Information and Communication Technology (ICT) course at the undergraduate (UG) level.
The initiative aims to tr</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 06:30:21 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>