<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 06:28:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Tokyo Gas completes feasibility study for country’s first land-based LNG terminal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/tokyo-gas-completes-feasibility-study-for-bangladeshs-first-land-based-lng-terminal</link><description>Japanese energy major Tokyo Gas Co Ltd has completed a full feasibility study for Bangladesh's first land-based LNG-import terminal at Matarbari Island in the Bay of Bengal, raising hopes of finally advancing a project that has faced years of delay.
The study covers detailed technical assessments</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 03:58:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>RU JCD candidates feed stray animals amid campus closure during Durga Puja</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ru-jcd-candidates-feed-stray-animals-amid-campus-closure-during-durga-puja</link><description>"Oikkoboddho Notun Projonmo" panel candidates, nominated by Jatiyatabadi Chhatra Dal (JCD) for RUCSU polls, have stepped forward to feed the cats and dogs residing at campus as its closure has curtailed the availability of food they consume.
Residential hall dining facilities, canteens, and nearby</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 04:13:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Vegetable prices spike; chilli Tk 350, brinjal Tk 200</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/vegetable-prices-spike-chilli-tk-350-brinjal-tk-200</link><description>Vegetable prices rose again last week, with green chilli selling at up to Tk 350 a kg and brinjal reaching Tk 200 a kg, as heavy rains damage crops and push up prices of other vegetables.
Meanwhile, prices of rice, beef, chicken, eggs, potato, and onions remain unchanged, though still at previousl</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 04:28:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Production hit at Gazipur factories due to low gas pressure</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/production-hit-at-gazipur-factories-due-to-low-gas-pressure</link><description>Gas pressure has dropped in parts of the Gazipur zone under Titas Gas Transmission and Distribution Company, disrupting production at garment factories and textile mills, industry insiders say.
Titas officials say a fire broke out in a gas line near the Chandra intersection on the Dhaka-Tangail hi</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 04:43:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BD sets fresh target of GHG emission cut by 2035 in NDC 3.0</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/bd-sets-fresh-target-of-ghg-emission-cut-by-2035-in-ndc-30</link><description>Bangladesh has set a fresh target of green house gas (GHG) emission reduction, 26.74 million tonnes of carbon dioxide equivalent (MtCO2eq), by 2035 in its latest Nationally Determined Contribution (NDC 3.0), a national plan to show global commitment to the Paris Agreement (PA) ahead of the COP 30.</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 04:58:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Container catches fire at Ctg Port</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/container-catches-fire-at-ctg-port</link><description>A fire broke out in a container loaded with computer and mobile accessories at the Chittagong sea port's New-mooring Container Terminal (NCT) on Wednesday.
The blaze, suspected to have been caused by mobile batteries, started at around 8 PM and was swiftly brought under control by port staff and f</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 05:13:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Locals demonstrate for footbridges, zebra crossings at Purbachal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/locals-demonstrate-for-footbridges-zebra-crossings-at-purbachal</link><description>Locals formed on Thursday a human chain blocking the Purbachal's 300 Feet Road demanding the construction of footbridges, zebra crossings and proper traffic management.
The demonstration was held at Mastul near the Balu Bridge in Purbachal in the morning.
Local residents in their thousands joined</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 05:28:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Anthrax fears grip Mithapukur after residents fall ill</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/anthrax-fears-grip-mithapukur-after-residents-fall-ill</link><description>Panic has gripped residents of Amaipur Sonarpara village in Mithapukur upazila of Rangpur district after several people showed symptoms of anthrax.
Dr. MA Halim Lavlu, Disease Control Officer at Mithapukur Upazila Health Complex, said that seven people are currently receiving treatment for suspect</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 05:43:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Saudi Arabia launches new licensing system for Hajj housing</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/saudi-arabia-launches-new-licensing-system-for-hajj-housing</link><description>Saudi Arabia has introduced a new licensing system for pilgrim accommodations in Makkah and Madinah for the 2026 Hajj season. 
Under a new directive from the Ministry of Hajj and Umrah, temporary hostel licences will now be issued through a service developed in coordination with the tourism m</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 05:58:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Massive fire erupts at Chevron refinery near Los Angeles</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/massive-fire-erupts-at-chevron-refinery-near-los-angeles</link><description>Fire crews were battling massive flames at a Chevron refinery just outside of Los Angeles on Thursday night.
California Gov. Gavin Newsom’s office confirmed on the social platform X that the large fire had erupted at the company’s refinery in El Segundo.
The company did not immediatel</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 06:13:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ADB, Envoy Textiles ink $30m sustainability loan deal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/adb-envoy-textiles-ink-30m-sustainability-loan-deal</link><description>The Asian Development Bank (ADB) signed a $30 million sustainability-linked loan agreement with Envoy Textiles.
The transaction with Envoy is the follow-on to a textile manufacturing project with the ADB in 2022, according to an ADB news release on Thursday.
This is ADB's first sustainability-lin</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 06:28:09 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>