<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 11:21:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Growing digital adoption drives up internet banking</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/growing-digital-adoption-drives-up-internet-banking</link><description>Internet-banking transactions surged by more than 39.0 per cent to Tk 1.29 trillion during the first four months of the current fiscal year, signifying a steady shift away from cheques and other paper-based conventional payment methods.
Roughly 66.0 million transactions were carried out through in</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 08:13:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dense fog, low sunshine bring cold wave-like chill countrywide</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/dense-fog-low-sunshine-bring-cold-wave-like-chill-countrywide</link><description>Parts of the country, including Dhaka, have been experiencing cold wave-like chilling weather for the last four days due to reduced sunshine during winter caused by persistent fog, meteorologists said on Monday.
According to the Bangladesh Meteorological Department (BMD), the fog sweeping across t</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 08:28:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Industrial raw material imports: BB sets up to 270 days for usance period</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/industrial-raw-material-imports-bb-sets-up-to-270-days-for-usance-period</link><description>The central bank has allowed import of industrial raw materials-- including back-to-back import-- as well as agricultural implements and chemical fertilisers under suppliers' or buyer's credit for a usance period of up to 270 days.
On August 18, 2025, the Bangladesh Bank (BB) permitted such facili</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 08:43:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nepal PM expresses condolences over Khaleda Zia’s death</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nepal-pm-expresses-condolences-over-khaleda-zias-death</link><description>Nepalese Prime Minister Sushila Karki has expressed sorrow over the death of Khaleda Zia, BNP chairperson and the first female Prime Minister of Bangladesh.
"I am deeply saddened to learn of the passing away of Begum Khaleda Zia, BNP chairperson and the first female Prime Minister of Bangladesh,"</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 08:58:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>July-October NSC sales plummet 53.62pc</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/july-october-nsc-sales-plummet-5362pc</link><description>The net sales of National Savings Certificates (NSCs) experienced a staggering 53.62-percent year-on-year decline during the July-October period of the current fiscal year.
The sharp downturn reflects tightening liquidity conditions and a persistent rise in living costs that continue to sap the ca</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 09:13:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>End of an Era: A look back at former prime minister Khaleda Zia’s life and legacy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/end-of-an-era-a-look-back-at-former-prime-minister-khaleda-zias-life-and-legacy</link><description>Begum Khaleda Zia, the country’s first elected female Prime Minister and one of the nation’s most enduring political figures, passed away on Tuesday morning at 6 am in Evercare Hospital.
The death of the Chairperson of Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) at the age of 80, marks the end</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 09:28:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique pays heartfelt tribute to Khaleda, hails her as a loving mother</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-pays-heartfelt-tribute-to-khaleda-hails-her-as-a-loving-mother</link><description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman on Tuesday paid an emotional tribute to party Chairperson Khaleda Zia, remembering her as a tender and loving mother who was also a steadfast guardian for her family and the nation.
"My mother, BNP Chairperson Begum Khaleda Zia, has responded to the call of Almig</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 09:43:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Junior scholarship exam set for Dec 31 postponed after Khaleda Zia’s death</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/junior-scholarship-exam-set-for-dec-31-postponed-after-khaleda-zias-death</link><description>Education authorities have postponed the junior scholarship exams scheduled for Wednesday following the declaration of state mourning for former prime minister and BNP chief Khaleda Zia.
The Science and Bangladesh and Global Studies exams will now be held on Jan 5, officials said on Tuesday.
The</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 09:44:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Online Editors Alliance mourns death of Khaleda Zia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/online-editors-alliance-mourns-death-of-khaleda-zia</link><description>The Online Editors Alliance (OEA) has expressed deep sorrow at the death of Begum Khaleda Zia, three-time former prime minister of Bangladesh, chairperson of the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP), and a leading symbol of the country’s democratic movement.
In a condolence message issued on T</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 09:59:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khaleda's death a blow to Bangladesh’s stability: Joy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/khaleda-zias-death-a-blow-to-stabilising-bangladesh-says-hasinas-son-joy</link><description>Sajeeb Wazed Joy, the son of ousted prime minister Sheikh Hasina, has expressed condolences over the death of BNP chief and former premier Khaleda Zia.
In a post on X on Tuesday, Joy extended his sympathies to Khaleda’s family and supporters, describing her death as a blow to the country&amp;rsq</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 10:14:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh announces three days of state mourning for Khaleda Zia. Here’s how it will be observed</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-announces-three-days-of-state-mourning-for-khaleda-zia-heres-how-it-will-be-observed</link><description>The interim government has declared three days of state mourning following the death of former prime minister and BNP chief Khaleda Zia.
On Tuesday, the Cabinet Division issued a gazette notification announcing the mourning period from Wednesday to Friday, following a special meeting of the govern</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 10:29:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Limiting SIMs to 5 per NID a rumour: BTRC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/limiting-sims-to-5-per-nid-a-rumour-btrc</link><description>Recent media reports suggesting that the government has decided to reduce the SIM registration limit to five per NID from January 1, 2026 are incorrect and misleading.
Such misinformation creates unnecessary confusion among customers and businesses, said a Bangladesh Telecommunication Regulatory C</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 10:44:14 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>