<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 09:37:43 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Tribunal receives charge sheet against Shamim Osman, 12 others</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tribunal-receives-charge-sheet-against-shamim-osman-12-others</link><description>The prosecution has submitted a formal charge sheet to the International Crimes Tribunal against former Narayanganj lawmaker Shamim Osman and 12 others, including his son, over alleged crimes against humanity committed during the July Uprising.
Prosecutor Gazi MH Tamim confirmed on Monday that t</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 07:07:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nassa Group’s assets to be sold to clear workers’ dues: Labour adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/nassa-groups-assets-to-be-sold-to-clear-workers-dues-labour-adviser</link><description>Labour and Employment Adviser Brigadier General (Retd) M Sakhawat Hossain has said a decision has been taken to sell the assets of Nassa Group, in line with a court order, to pay workers’ dues and service benefits.
He made the remarks on Sunday while presiding over the 15th meeting of the Ad</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 07:22:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>National election: Govt orders licensed firearms surrendered by Jan 31</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/national-election-govt-orders-licensed-firearms-surrendered-by-jan-31</link><description>The government has ordered all licensed firearms to be deposited at the nearest police stations by January 31, ahead of the national election scheduled for February 12.
The directive was issued through a notification by the Ministry of Home Affairs on Sunday.
The notification also bans the carryi</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 07:38:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka court orders embezzlement case against S Alam, PK Halder to trial</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dhaka-court-orders-embezzlement-case-against-s-alam-pk-halder-to-trial</link><description>A Dhaka court has framed charges against 13 people, including S Alam Group Chairman Mohammad Saiful Alam and former managing director of Reliance Finance Limited (now Aviva Finance Limited) Prashanta Kumar (PK) Halder, in a case over the embezzlement of Tk 320 million.
Dhaka Special Judge’s</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 07:53:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mob kills two suspected cattle thieves in Manikganj</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/mob-kills-two-suspected-cattle-thieves-in-manikganj</link><description>Two suspected cattle lifters were killed in a lynch-mob attack at Imannagar village in Singair upazila of Manikganj district early Monday.
The deceased were identified as Majnu, 35, son of Tota Mia of Dashani village and Deen Islam, 23, son of Bandu Mia of Choyani village in the upazila, reports U</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 08:08:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Death toll from high-speed train collision in Spain rises to 39</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/death-toll-from-high-speed-train-collision-in-spain-rises-to-39</link><description>The death toll from Sunday's collision between a derailing high-speed train and a second oncoming train in southern Spain has risen to 39, with 152 people injured, state broadcaster RTVE reported on Monday, citing police sources.
The accident happened at 7:45 pm local time (1845 GMT) on Sunday nea</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 08:23:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Magnitude 6 earthquake strikes northwestern Kashmir</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/magnitude-6-earthquake-strikes-northwestern-kashmir</link><description>An earthquake of magnitude 6 struck northwestern Kashmir in Pakistan on Monday, the European Mediterranean Seismological Center (EMSC) said.
The quake was at a depth of 35km (21.75 miles), the EMSC said.</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 08:15:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rumeen Farhana summoned over election code ‘breach’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/rumeen-farhana-summoned-over-election-code-breach</link><description>Independent candidate Rumeen Farhana has been served a show-cause notice for allegedly breaching the electoral code of conduct in the Brahmanbaria-2 constituency, with instructions to appear in person before the district administration to explain her actions.
An order has been issued through a not</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 08:30:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Boiler crack halts Barapukuria power plant production</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/boiler-crack-halts-barapukuria-power-plant-production</link><description>Power generation at the Barapukuria Thermal Power Plant in Dinajpur has come to a complete halt after a crack was detected in the boiler.
On Monday, Chief Engineer Abu Bakar Siddique said the plant, which has four units and a total capacity of 525MW, completely halted production, reports bdnews24.</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 08:45:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>World Economic Forum and Salesforce introduce agentic AI assistant at Davos 2026</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/world-economic-forum-and-salesforce-introduce-agentic-ai-assistant-at-davos-2026</link><description>Salesforce (NYSE: CRM), the world’s #1 CRM, on Monday, announced the activation of the World Economic Forum’s institutional knowledge powered by Agentforce 360 to support over 3,000 of the world’s most influential leaders at the 2026 World Economic Forum Annual Meeting.
The forum</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 09:00:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BGMEA, BKMEA slam ‘unilateral’ move to withdraw bonded facility on yarn imports</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bgmea-bkmea-slam-unilateral-move-to-withdraw-bonded-facility-on-yarn-imports</link><description>Leaders of the Bangladesh Garment Manufacturers and Exporters Association (BGMEA) and the Bangladesh Knitwear Manufacturers and Exporters Association (BKMEA) on Monday alleged that the Ministry of Commerce has made a unilateral recommendation to withdraw the bonded warehouse facility on yarn import</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 09:15:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump says 'it will be done' on getting 'Russian threat' away from Greenland</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-says-it-will-be-done-on-getting-russian-threat-away-from-greenland</link><description>US President Donald Trump said on Sunday that Denmark has not been able to do anything to get the "Russian threat" away from Greenland, and said, "Now it is time, and it will be done!!!"
"NATO has been telling Denmark, for 20 years, that "you have to get Russian threat away from Greenland." Unfort</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 09:30:42 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>