<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 14:21:43 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Sharp fall in indices drags down trading at DSE, CSE</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/sharp-fall-in-indices-drags-down-trading-at-dse-cse</link><description>Trading at both the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) and the Chittagong Stock Exchange (CSE) ended on a bearish note on Monday as key indices suffered sharp losses, with most stocks closing lower and turnover declining.  On the second trading day of the week, the DSE's benchmark index DSEX drop</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 11:38:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>WH Smith draws up plans to find a new chairman, Sky News reports</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/wh-smith-draws-up-plans-to-find-a-new-chairman-sky-news-reports</link><description>Travel retail group WH Smith is drawing up plans to find a new chairman amid a battle to restore investors' faith in the company, Sky News reported on Sunday.
The search for two new non-executive directors is expected to lead to the recruitment of a candidate capable of replacing Annette Court wit</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 11:53:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>German foreign minister puts emphasis on close ties before US trip</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/german-foreign-minister-puts-emphasis-on-close-ties-before-us-trip</link><description>German Foreign Minister Johann Wadephul emphasised the importance of transatlantic relations on Sunday as he left for a trip to Washington that takes place at a delicate time due to tensions over U.S. interests in Greenland and Venezuela.
“Never before has it been so crucial to invest in the</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 12:08:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh standoff 'a litmus test' for ICC chair Jay Shah, reports NDTV</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/bangladesh-standoff-a-litmus-test-for-icc-chair-jay-shah-reports-ndtv</link><description>The escalating standoff regarding Bangladesh's refusal to travel to India for the T20 World Cup has placed ICC Chairman Jay Shah under severe pressure, according to a report by an Indian media outlet.  The report by NDTV suggests that Shah faces a "stern test" as he attempts to broker a s</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 12:23:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Son of Iran's toppled shah seeks a role as protests expand</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/son-of-irans-toppled-shah-seeks-a-role-as-protests-expand</link><description>In a nation where opposition to almost half a century of clerical rule has long been fragmented, the son of the last shah of Iran has become a prominent voice spurring on protesters staging the biggest anti-government demonstrations in years.
Reza Pahlavi, 65, has sought to speak as a national lea</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 11:38:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ACC in no position to investigate info on candidates' affidavits</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/acc-in-no-position-to-investigate-info-on-candidates-affidavits</link><description>Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) Chairman Dr Mohammad Abdul Momen on Sunday said he does not want to see individuals who own assets not disclosed in their election affidavits as future rulers of the country.
He made the remarks while responding to a question at the founding anniversary programme o</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 11:53:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Seize building of wife of Hasina’s APS: Court</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/court-orders-seizure-of-10-storey-building-owned-by-wife-of-hasinas-aps-liku</link><description>A court has ordered the seizure of a 10-storey building belonging to the wife of Gazi Hafizur Rahman Liku, assistant private secretary to Sheikh Hasina.
Rahima Akter’s building, located in Keraniganj on the outskirts of Dhaka, has been valued at Tk 94.85, according to court records.
Dhaka M</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 12:08:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NBR integrates ASYCUDA World system with BGMEA’s e-UD platform</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/nbr-integrates-asycuda-world-system-with-bgmeas-e-ud-platform</link><description>The National Board of Revenue (NBR) has integrated the ASYCUDA World system with the Bangladesh Garment Manufacturers and Exporters Association’s (BGMEA) electronic Utilisation Declaration (e-UD) platform, aiming to modernise bond management and expedite customs clearance for export-oriented</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 12:23:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Liverpool's Bradley to undergo surgery on knee injury</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/liverpools-bradley-to-undergo-surgery-on-knee-injury</link><description>Liverpool right back Conor Bradley will undergo surgery after injuring his knee in the 0-0 draw at Arsenal, the Premier League club announced on Sunday, with a return to action this season in doubt.
Bradley fell awkwardly near the touchline in stoppage time in an incident that sparked a melee when</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 12:38:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh missing $700b packaging market amid policy bottlenecks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladesh-missing-700b-packaging-market-amid-policy-bottlenecks</link><description>Bangladesh is missing out on untapped opportunities in the global packaging market—estimated at around $700 billion—due to inadequate policy support and the absence of export incentives, said Md Shahriar, president of the Bangladesh Garment Accessories and Packaging Manufacturers and Ex</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 12:53:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>SBAC Bank signs MoU with Best Western Plus Bay Hills Hotel</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/sbac-bank-signs-mou-with-best-western-plus-bay-hills-hotel</link><description>SBAC Bank PLC signed a Memorandum of Article with Best Western Plus Bay Hills Hotel located in Himchari, Cox’s bazar at the Bank’s Head Office recently.
In the presence of S. M. Mainul Kabir, Managing Director and CEO of SBAC Bank; Mohammad Shafiul Azam, Head of Digital Financial Inclu</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 13:08:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>China extending medical facilities for Bangladeshi patients</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/china-extending-medical-facilities-for-bangladeshi-patients</link><description>A delegation of eight specialist doctors from two renowned Chinese hospitals—Guangzhou Fosun Chancheng Hospital and Shenzhen Hengsheng Hospital—recently visited Bangladesh as part of an initiative by the Belt and Road Healthcare Center to extend medical cooperation between the two count</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 13:23:44 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>