<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 12:47:06 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Press secretary warns of crackdown on banned Awami League’s street protests</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/press-secretary-warns-of-crackdown-on-banned-awami-leagues-street-protests</link><description>Shafiqul Alam, the press secretary to Chief Advisor Muhammad Yunus, has warned of a strict crackdown on any attempts by the banned Awami League to stage programmes on the streets of Dhaka, reports bdnews24.com.
In a post in English on his verified Facebook account on Monday, Shafiqul cautioned the</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 09:35:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Teachers’ sit-in programme enters 3rd day, advisor visits 5 schools</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/teachers-sit-in-programme-enters-3rd-day-advisor-visits-5-schools</link><description>The sit-in programme staged by assistant teachers from government primary schools pushing for a list of demands, including pay at the 10th-grade level, has entered its third day.
On Monday, work stoppages were under way for a second day at several schools, while some others reportedly continued th</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 10:30:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ECNEC approves 12 development projects involving Tk 71.50 billion</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/ecnec-approves-12-development-projects-involving-tk-7150-billion</link><description>The Executive Committee of the National Economic Council (ECNEC) today approved 12 development projects involving an overall expenditure of Taka 71.50 billion (7,150.21 crore). 
The entire amount will be financed from the government's own resources, BSS reports. 
The approval came at th</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 10:45:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fingerstyle guitarist Antu Das emerges as rising star in Bangladesh's music scene</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/fingerstyle-guitarist-antu-das-emerges-as-rising-star-in-bangladeshs-music-scene</link><description>Bangladesh’s music scene has found a new favorite in fingerstyle guitarist, music director, and singer Antu Das.
The talented musician, who grew up in Rangpur’s Pakpara as the youngest son of acclaimed photojournalist Ranjit Das, has been quietly shaping his place in the industry with</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 11:00:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>GMP Commissioner Nazmul Karim Khan suspended</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/gmp-commissioner-nazmul-karim-khan-suspended</link><description>The government has suspended Gazipur Metropolitan Police (GMP) Commissioner Nazmul Karim Khan, two months after he was withdrawn from his post.
The Home Affairs Ministry issued a notification in this regard on Monday.
According to the notification, Nazmul Karim Khan has been suspended from govern</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 10:19:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BIMSTEC Secy Gen meets ADB president, others</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bimstec-secy-gen-meets-adb-president-others</link><description>BIMSTEC Secretary General Indra Mani Pandey visited Manila from November 6 to 7 to meet with President of Asian Development Bank (ADB) and other members of its senior management.
During his meeting with ADB President Masato Kanda, Indra highlighted the long-standing cooperation between BIMSTEC and</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 10:34:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Plot underway to erase Liberation War spirit: Fakhrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/plot-underway-to-erase-liberation-war-spirit-fakhrul</link><description>BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir on Monday alleged that a vested group is conspiring to erase the spirit of Bangladesh’s 1971 Liberation War.
“Those who had collaborated with the Pakistani army to kill freedom fighters and committing atrocities against women are now at</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 10:49:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt may consider compensating investors in troubled 5-bank merger: BB</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/govt-may-consider-compensating-investors-in-troubled-5-bank-merger-bb</link><description>Executive Director and Spokesperson of the Bangladesh Bank (BB) Arif Hossain Khan on Monday said that the government may consider compensating general investors who have been affected by the merger of five troubled Islamic banks.
“If small, affected investors approach the government with an</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 11:04:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>10 get life in prison for Rajbari murder</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/10-get-life-in-prison-for-rajbari-murder</link><description>A Rajbari court has sentenced 10 people to life in prison for killing a man by slitting his throat over a family feud in Pangsha Upazila.
Rajbari Additional District and Sessions Judge Ashok Kumar delivered the verdict on Monday afternoon in the presence of eight of the suspects, said Abdul Razzak</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 11:19:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>KSA bars pilgrims with incurable diseases from performing Hajj: Ministry</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ksa-bars-pilgrims-with-incurable-diseases-from-performing-hajj-ministry</link><description>The Saudi government has announced that people suffering from severe health conditions or incurable diseases will not be allowed to perform Hajj, said the Ministry of Religious Affairs.
In a press release on Monday, the ministry said the Saudi Ministry of Hajj and Umrah has instructed all countrie</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 11:34:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New Delhi police detain dozens in anti-pollution protests</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/new-delhi-police-detain-dozens-in-anti-pollution-protests</link><description>Indian police detained dozens of people during a rare protest at the famed India Gate monument in New Delhi demanding action to curb an annual scourge of toxic air swathing the capital and its surrounding region.
Sunday’s protest by crowds of all ages holding banners and chanting slogans bef</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 11:49:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Interim govt will decide on July Charter implementation now: Advisor Rizwana</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/interim-govt-will-decide-on-july-charter-implementation-now-advisor-rizwana</link><description>The government will make a decision on its own regarding the implementation of the July Charter as political parties have not reached a consensus among themselves, says Environment Advisor Syeda Rizwana Hasan.
The advisor made the statement in response to a question while speaking to the media at</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 12:04:24 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>