<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 10:25:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Bangladesh, Pakistan resume economic dialogue after two decades</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/bangladesh-pakistan-resume-economic-dialogue-after-two-decades</link><description>Bangladesh and Pakistan have resumed their bilateral economic dialogue after nearly two decades through the 9th Joint Economic Commission (JEC) meeting, aiming to boost cooperation in trade, investment, energy and technical sectors.
The meeting began at the NEC conference room in Dhaka on Monday m</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 07:06:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt clarifies: Cabinet will continue functioning beyond November</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-clarifies-cabinet-will-continue-functioning-beyond-november</link><description>The interim government has issued a statement clarifying that the Cabinet and the Advisory Council will continue functioning beyond November, dismissing confusion created by recent remarks from Information Adviser Mahfuz Alam.
At a “Meet the Reporters” event organised by the Dhaka Repo</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 07:51:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC to hold inter-ministry meeting to assign election-time duties</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ec-to-hold-inter-ministry-meeting-to-assign-election-time-duties</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has called a meeting with various ministries and agencies to remind them of their responsibilities during the 13th national parliamentary election.
The meeting will be attended by top officials of 31 ministries, as well as secretaries, director generals, and chairmen</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 08:21:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh, Pakistan pledge to boost trade, tech and energy cooperation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-pakistan-pledge-to-boost-trade-tech-and-energy-cooperation</link><description>Bangladesh and Pakistan agreed to strengthen bilateral and regional cooperation across key sectors, including trade, agriculture, information technology, food, energy and connectivity, following the 9th Joint Economic Commission (JEC) meeting held in Dhaka on Monday, the first in two decades.
Fina</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 09:06:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Stocks extend losses as turnover slumps on cautious trading</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/stocks-extend-losses-as-turnover-slumps-on-cautious-trading</link><description>The benchmark DSEX index extended its losing streak for a second consecutive session on Sunday, dragged down by cautious trading and a notable decline in turnover, reflecting subdued investor sentiment and risk aversion.
The DSEX shed 0.78 per cent to close at 5,086.86 points, marking continued we</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 09:21:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Former mayor Atiqul now arrested in case over trader's murder</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/former-mayor-atiqul-now-arrested-in-case-over-traders-murder</link><description>Former Dhaka North mayor Atiqul Islam has been placed under arrest in another case, this time over the killing of trader Tajul Islam during the July Uprising.
Dhaka Metropolitan Magistrate Mahbub Alam issued the order after a hearing on Monday, said Sub-Inspector Atiqur Rahman of the Prosecution D</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 09:36:05 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>