<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 10:23:57 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Asaduzzaman resigns as attorney general to contest in parliamentary elections</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/asaduzzaman-resigns-as-attorney-general-to-contest-in-parliamentary-elections</link><description>Md Asaduzzaman has tendered his resignation as attorney general to the president, formally stepping down from the country’s top legal post.
Deputy Attorney General Md Jahirlul Islam Sumon told bdnews24.com that Asaduzzaman handed in his resignation letter at the Attorney General’s Offi</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 04:41:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Zubayer Rahman Chowdhury takes oath as Chief Justice</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/zubayer-rahman-chowdhury-takes-oath-as-chief-justice</link><description>Justice Zubayer Rahman Chowdhury on Sunday took oath as the 26th Chief Justice of Bangladesh.
President Mohammed Shahabuddin administered the oath at Bangabhaban at 10:30am on Sunday.
Chief Adviser Prof Muhammad Yunus, among others, attended the oath-takig ceremony which was broadcast live by Ban</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 04:56:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NBR extends income tax return deadline to January 31</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nbr-extends-income-tax-return-deadline-to-january-31</link><description>The government has extended the deadline for submitting income tax returns for individual taxpayers for the second time for the 2025–26 tax year.
According to an order issued by the National Board of Revenue (NBR), the return submission deadline has been extended from December 31, 2025 to Ja</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 05:11:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>More countries reject Israel's recognition of Somaliland</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/more-countries-reject-israels-recognition-of-somaliland</link><description>A growing number of countries on Saturday rejected Israel's recognition of Somalia’s breakaway region of Somaliland as an independent nation a day earlier, the first by any country in more than 30 years.
It wasn't known why Israel made the declaration Friday or whether the country was expect</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 05:26:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP collects Tarique Rahman’s nomination papers for Dhaka-17 seat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bnp-collects-tarique-rahmans-nomination-papers-for-dhaka-17-seat</link><description>Nomination papers for BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman have been collected for the Dhaka-17 constituency ahead of the 13th national election.
The papers were picked up on Sunday morning from the office of the Dhaka Divisional Commissioner in Segunbagicha by BNP chairperson's aide ABM Abdus Satta</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 06:43:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat not a ‘reliable ally’, NCP may pay ‘heavy price’, says Samantha</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-not-a-reliable-ally-ncp-may-pay-heavy-price-says-samantha</link><description>Samantha Sharmin, senior joint convenor of the National Citizen Party (NCP), has said Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami is “not a reliable ally” and warned that the party may have to “pay a heavy price” if it seeks cooperation or reaches any agreement with the Islamist group.
She</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 06:58:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Charge sheet in Haadi murder case likely within 10 days</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/charge-sheet-in-haadi-murder-case-likely-within-10-days</link><description>Police expect to submit a charge sheet within the next seven to ten days in the murder case of Sharif Osman Hadi, spokesperson of Inqilab Moncho.
“We will be able to submit the charge sheet within the next seven to ten days, Insha’Allah,” said Additional Commissioner of Dhaka Met</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 07:13:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hadi murder: Two associates of Faisal arrested in India</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hadi-murder-two-associates-of-faisal-arrested-in-india</link><description>Police say they have now confirmed that Faisal Karim, the prime suspect in the killing of Inqilab Moncho leader Sharif Osman Hadi, is no longer in the country.
At a media briefing on Sunday, Dhaka Metropolitan Police (DMP) Additional Commissioner SN Md Nazrul Islam said investigators had establish</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 07:28:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Government cancels certificates of 71 fake freedom fighters</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/government-cancels-certificates-of-71-fake-freedom-fighters</link><description>The government has cancelled the freedom fighter certificates of 71 individuals after determining that they were not involved in Bangladesh’s Liberation War, officials said.
A gazette notification annulling the certificates was issued on December 24, following an earlier official order by th</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 08:15:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCP leader Tajnuva Jabeen resigns amid reports of Jamaat alliance</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ncp-leader-tajnuva-jabeen-resigns-amid-reports-of-jamaat-alliance</link><description>Tajnuva Jabeen, a senior leader of the National Citizen Party (NCP), has resigned from the youth-led political group amid reports of a potential alliance between the party and Jamaat-e-Islami.
She announced her decision in a Facebook post at 12:35pm on Sunday, reports bdnews24.com.
Tajnuva had be</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 08:30:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique visits BNP chairperson’s office</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-visits-bnp-chairpersons-office</link><description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman visited the party chairperson's office in the capital's Gulshan area on Sunday, marking his first visit to the office since his return to the country.
BNP Standing Committee Member Khandaker Mosharraf Hossain received Tarique Rahman at 1:42 pm, said BNP media cel</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 09:15:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sylhet Gas Fields Limited's AGM held</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/sylhet-gas-fields-limiteds-agm-held</link><description>The 43rd Annual General Meeting of Sylhet Gas Fields Limited (SGFL), one of the gas and petroleum products producing companies of Petrobangla, was held on 18 December 2025 at 7:00pm at the conference room of the company’s Dhaka Liaison Office at Petrocenter, Dhaka.
The meeting was presided o</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 09:30:50 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>