<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 17:19:35 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>BGB recovers 24 electric detonators along Sunamganj border</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/bgb-recovers-24-electric-detonators-along-sunamganj-border</link><description>Members of Border Guard Bangladesh (BGB) recovered 24 powerful electric detonators during a drive along Tahirpur border in Sunamganj district on Friday morning.
A patrol team of Charagaon Border Outpost (BOP) under Sunamganj Battalion conducted the drive near the border pillar 1195/1-S at Maizhati</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 13:57:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gulistan market fire contained</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/gulistan-market-fire-contained</link><description>The fire at the Khadder Bazar Shopping Complex in Dhaka’s Gulistan has been contained after about one and a half hours of effort.
Fire Service Media Officer Anwarul Islam said the flames were brought under control around 7pm on Friday.
Earlier, the Fire Service received reports of a fire in</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 14:12:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Launch loses route permit after Meghna collision</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/adventure-9-launch-route-permit-cancelled-after-fatal-meghna-collision</link><description>Authorities have cancelled the route permit of the MV Adventure-9 launch following a collision between two passenger vessels on the Meghna River in Chandpur that left four people dead.
Barishal Bangladesh Inland Water Transport Authority (BIWTA) Assistant Director Md Solaiman said on Friday evenin</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 14:27:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Death toll in Syria mosque bombing reaches 8</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/death-toll-in-syria-mosque-bombing-reaches-8</link><description>A bombing at a mosque located in the Syrian city of Homs during Friday prayers killed at least eight people and wounded 18 others, authorities said.
Images released by Syria’s state-run Arab News Agency showed blood on the mosque’s carpets, holes in the walls, shattered windows and fir</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 14:30:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Online textbooks available from Sunday: NCTB</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/nctb-says-online-versions-of-textbooks-for-primary-secondary-levels-available-from-sunday</link><description>The National Curriculum and Textbook Board (NCTB) has announced that it will publish online versions of textbooks for primary and secondary levels from Sunday.
Students will be able to access PDF copies of these textbooks on the NCTB website.
NCTB Public Relations Officer SM Asaduzzaman said stud</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 14:45:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BPL 2025-26: Shanto’s unbeaten ton powers Rajshahi to opening-day win over Sylhet</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/cricket/bpl-2025-26-shantos-unbeaten-ton-powers-rajshahi-to-opening-day-win-over-sylhet</link><description>Najmul Hossain Shanto opened the Bangladesh Premier League (BPL) with a statement inning on Friday, becoming the first centurion of the season.
He guided Rajshahi Warriors to an eight-wicket victory over Sylhet Titans in the tournament’s opening match at the Sylhet International Cricket Stad</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 15:00:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mymensingh shrine vandalized</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/centuries-old-shrine-in-mymensingh-vandalised-desecrated</link><description>A centuries-old shrine in Gouripur Upazila of Mymensingh has been vandalised, with attackers also throwing human waste inside the premises, police say.
The incident took place on Thursday night at the shrine of Shahjahan Uddin (R), Gouripur Police chief Kamrul Hasan said.
Locals said several devo</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 15:15:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Inquilab Moncho continues sit-in at Shahbagh demanding justice for Hadi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/inquilab-moncho-continues-sit-in-at-shahbagh-demanding-justice-for-hadi</link><description>Even in the chilling cold and wind, followers of the Inquilab Moncho on Friday night continued their sit-in programme at Shahbagh intersection to press home the demand to arrest all killers of Sharif Osman bin Hadi.
Besides, the Moncho, a platform formed centring the last year’s student-led</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 15:30:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Central bank's initiatives to curb critically swollen NPLs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/central-banks-initiatives-to-curb-critically-swollen-npls</link><description>Commendably, Bangladesh bank is now  well-aware of  the  causes of poor  recovery  of  defaulted loans  as well as delayed  case disposal  and  trying to mitigate  the  crisis  of non-performing loans (NPLs) in the  banking secto</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 15:45:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>They do not want a free press</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/they-do-not-want-a-free-press</link><description>During the height of the language movement in 1952, two national newspapers were attacked because they opposed the movement. The Morning News, owned by Khwaja Nooruddin from the Dhaka Nawab family, supported the government and kept criticising the language movement. On February 21, 1952, police sho</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 16:00:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Is Bangladesh ready for LDC exit?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/is-bangladesh-ready-for-ldc-exit</link><description>After decades on the global list of the poorest economies, Bangladesh is now set to cross an important economic threshold as it prepares to graduate from the Least Developed Country (LDC) category in November, 2026. This status change follows the country meeting all three United Nations graduation</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 16:15:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trade should take precedence over BD-India diplomatic ties</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/trade-should-take-precedence-over-bd-india-diplomatic-ties</link><description>Trading is a powerful transactional tool among nations. There are historical evidences of countries continuing trading activities between them even when they are at war. During both the World Wars, for instance, Britain imported crucial chemical dyes from Germany. Even when they were engaged in mil</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 16:30:53 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>