<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 06:33:56 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Stocks tumble amid growing political concerns</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/stocks-tumble-amid-growing-political-concerns</link><description>Stocks took a sharp downturn this week, reversing the gains made in the previous week, as jittery investors, unsettled by growing political unrest, rushed to dump their holdings across major sectors.
Analysts pointed to the escalating political concerns, particularly after the Election Commission</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 03:00:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Seven more market intermediaries get extra time to adjust negative equity</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/seven-more-market-intermediaries-get-extra-time-to-adjust-negative-equity</link><description>The Bangladesh Securities and Exchange Commission (BSEC) has given additional time to seven more market intermediaries to ensure compliance with provisioning requirements for unrealised losses and adjustments to negative equity.
The extension will take effect after December 31, when the current de</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 03:15:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NDF president Anisul's house set on fire in Chattogram</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ndf-president-anisuls-house-set-on-fire-in-chattogram</link><description>Miscreants set fire to the house of Barrister Anisul Islam Mahmud, president of the National Democratic Front (NDF), in Hathazari upazila of Chattogram district on Friday night.
Witnesses said some unidentified people swooped on the residence of Anisul around 11:40 pm and carried out vandalism.
L</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 04:33:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How ADR reshaping labour dispute redressal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/analysis/how-adr-reshaping-labour-dispute-redressal</link><description>In this dynamic era of industrialisation, the relationship between workers and employers is not merely a legal or administrative matter -- it is one of the key pillars of a nation's economic stability, productivity, and social harmony. The better the working environment, the greater the satisfactio</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 04:48:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IUB's ICEBTM 2025: A bold academic push against Bangladesh's jobless crisis</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/analysis/iubs-icebtm-2025-a-bold-academic-push-against-bangladeshs-jobless-crisis</link><description>One key reason behind China's rapid economic growth is its success in aligning the needs of industry with the skills produced by universities. China deliberately promoted close cooperation between academia and industry, creating mechanisms that move scientific research quickly into commercial use.</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 05:03:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>When civilisation ceases to exist</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/analysis/when-civilisation-ceases-to-exist</link><description>Evolution of civilisation is a long process. From its tentative beginning, a civilisation also ascends its summit at certain point and then the decline of the process also begins. Like human species or any other living being a civilisation sees many ups and downs and ultimately meets its end. Sever</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 05:18:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Zubaida flies back to London</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/zubaida-flies-back-to-london</link><description>Zubaida Rahman, the wife of BNP leader Tarique Rahman, has set off for London ahead of her husband’s planned return to Bangladesh after more than a decade in the UK.
She left Dhaka on a Biman Bangladesh Airlines flight from Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport around 8:30 am on Saturday, a</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 05:03:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>WEEKLY KITCHEN MARKET: Vegetables, chicken, eggs get cheaper</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/weekly-kitchen-market-vegetables-chicken-eggs-get-cheaper</link><description>Prices of vegetables, newly-harvested onions and potatoes, eggs and chicken declined in last week.
New onions are selling in Dhaka for Tk 80-100 per kg, which is about Tk 10 less than the previous week, according to market sources.
A visit to Shekhertek-8, Rayer Bazar and a few other markets on F</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 05:18:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chhayanaut students take to street to protest attack</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/chhayanaut-students-take-to-street-to-protest-attack</link><description>Students and alumni of Bengali cultural organisation Chhayanaut and its educational wing Nalonda took to the street outside its burnt and vandalised building in the capital on Friday, protesting the latest attack on the institution.
The gathering took place hours after assailants vandalised and se</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 05:33:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Admission test of DU Science unit postponed</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/admission-test-of-du-science-unit-postponed</link><description>Dhaka University (DU) on Friday postponed its Science unit admission test, scheduled for today (Saturday), as a mark of respect following the death of Sharif Osman Hadi.
Saturday will be observed as a day of mourning at the DU, a press note says.
The revised schedule for the postponed examination</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 05:48:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Christiansen confirmed as US envoy to BD</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/christiansen-confirmed-as-us-envoy-to-bd</link><description>Brent Christiansen has been confirmed as the next US Ambassador to Bangladesh at a time of political transitions and heightened regional sensitivity in the South Asian nation.
Sources say the US Senate, the upper house of the American parliament, Congress, has consented to his current diplomatic a</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 06:03:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Extortionist arrested with arms, ammo in Ctg</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/extortionist-arrested-with-arms-ammo-in-ctg</link><description>CHATTOGRAM Dec 19: Police arrested an alleged extortionist on Thursday night over an extortion attempt at a construction site in Chattogram's Panchlaish area, where a group of attackers allegedly opened fire after the project owner refused to pay Tk 5.0 million. The arrested person, Md Didar (36),</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 06:18:50 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>