<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 15:19:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>CUCSU polls: Chhatra Dal, Shibir face off near arts building over LED screen incident</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cucsu-polls-chhatra-dal-shibir-face-off-near-arts-building-over-led-screen-incident</link><description>Tension has flared between the Jatiyatabadi Chhatra Dal and Islami Chhatra Shibir near Chittagong University arts building as vote counting continues in the CUCSU polls.
Their activists confronted each other occurred on Wednesday afternoon, following a dispute over an LED screen installed outside</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 12:34:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt rescinds police officers transfer order to ACC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-rescinds-police-officers-transfer-order-to-acc</link><description>The government on Wednesday rescinded the transfer order of two supernumerary police superintendents to Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) as directors.
The Public Administration ministry cancelled the transfer orders of Md Abu Yusuf and Md Zahidur Rahman while the both are currently posted at the p</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 12:49:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mahbub Alam joins Southeast Bank as additional managing director</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/mahbub-alam-joins-southeast-bank-as-additional-managing-director</link><description>Md. Mahbub Alam joined Southeast Bank PLC as Additional Managing Director (AMD) on Tuesday, according to a press release. Prior to joining Southeast Bank PLC, he served as a Deputy Managing Director (DMD) at NCC Bank.
He started his career with Bangladesh Institute of Development Studies (BIDS) in</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 13:04:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CJ meets Thai Justice Minister in Bangkok to strengthen judicial cooperation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/chief-justice-meets-thai-justice-minister-in-bangkok-to-strengthen-judicial-cooperation</link><description>Chief Justice (CJ) of Bangladesh Dr. Syed Refaat Ahmed and Thailand’s Minister of Justice Rutthaphon Naowarat held a bilateral meeting in Bangkok on Wednesday, aiming to boost judicial cooperation.
During the meeting, the Chief Justice briefed the Thai Minister of Justice on the ongoing acti</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 13:34:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pubali Bank donates bus to Govt. Saadat College, Karatia, Tangail</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/pubali-bank-donates-bus-to-govt-saadat-college-karatia-tangail</link><description>Pubali Bank PLC has donated a bus for the use of students of Government Saadat College, Karatia, Tangail as part of its social responsibility, according to a press release.
On this occasion, Chief Guest of the program Mohammad Ali, Managing Director and CEO of Pubali Bank PLC, officially handed ov</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 13:49:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tickets now available online for Bangladesh–West Indies ODI series</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/cricket/tickets-now-available-online-for-bangladesh-west-indies-odi-series</link><description>Tickets for the ODI series between Bangladesh and West Indies are now available online.
According to the Bangladesh Cricket Board (BCB), ticket sales for the three-match ODI series opened on Wednesday morning through the website www.gobcbticket.com.bd and the “Go BCB Ticket” mobile app</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 14:04:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prime Bank partners with Dusai Resort and Spa to offer exclusive discounts for cardholders</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/prime-bank-partners-with-dusai-resort-and-spa-to-offer-exclusive-discounts-for-cardholders</link><description>Prime Bank PLC has entered into a strategic partnership with Dusai Resort and Spa to provide exclusive benefits for its valued debit cardholders.
According to a press release, a signing ceremony to commemorate the partnership was recently held at Prime Bank’s Corporate Office in Dhaka.
Thro</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 14:19:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>March to Jamuna Thursday: MPO teachers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/mpo-teachers-announce-march-to-jamuna-from-shahbagh-thursday-over-nationalization</link><description>Teachers and staff of MPO-registered institutions have announced a march to the State Guest House Jamuna on Thursday if their demands for the nationalisation of all private schools are not fulfilled.
The announcement came at Central Shaheed Minar after a three-hour blockade at Shahbagh on Wednesda</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 14:34:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Insurance sector still lags behind in gaining public trust: Guardian Life CEO</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/insurance-sector-still-lags-behind-in-gaining-public-trust-guardian-life-ceo</link><description>Bangladesh's insurance sector continues to lag behind in gaining customer trust despite the country’s technological advancements, said Sheikh Rakibul Karim, Acting CEO of Guardian Life Insurance Limited.
Speaking at a workshop titled "Financial Discipline in the Insurance Sector", held on We</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 14:49:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>July Charter signing to be an occasion of national celebrations, hopes Prof Yunus</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/july-charter-signing-to-be-an-occasion-of-national-celebrations-hopes-prof-yunus</link><description>Chief Adviser and head of the National Consensus Commission on Wednesday expressed optimism that the signing ceremony of the ‘July National Charter 2025’ will become an occasion of celebration for the whole nation.
“You have made it possible which appeared to be impossible. We wi</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 15:04:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamuna Bank partners with bKash</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/jamuna-bank-partners-with-bkash</link><description>Jamuna Bank PLC has signed an agreement with bKash to provide 24/7 cash management services for bKash distributors, agents and merchants.
The signing took place on 15 October at Jamuna Bank’s head office in Gulshan, Dhaka, with Mirza Elias Uddin Ahmed, MD &amp; CEO of Jamuna Bank, and Mr. Kamal</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 15:19:03 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>