<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 03:15:47 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nachol UNO made OSD</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nachol-uno-made-osd</link><description>The government has made Upazila Nirbahi Officer (UNO) Md Kamal Hossain of Nachol, Chapainawabganj an Officer on Special Duty (OSD) for allegedly using fake information to get a government job under the freedom fighter quota.
The Ministry of Public Administration issued a notification on Wednesday</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 17:44:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Inflation &amp; wage dynamics in BD</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/inflation-wage-dynamics-in-bd</link><description>Bangladesh Bank, as a forward-looking central bank, is dedicated to maintaining price stability and a robust financial system by promoting inclusive and broad-based economic growth, job creation, and poverty reduction. A sound comprehension of the fundamental elements that influence price level mov</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 17:59:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Election campaigning must go greenElection campaigning must go green</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/election-campaigning-must-go-greenelection-campaigning-must-go-green</link><description>Candidates from different political parties for the 13th parliamentary elections have already started trying to make their presence felt, even before announcement of election schedules by the Election Commission. They are quite eager to reach the voters, and their supporters have already started di</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 18:14:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shareholders return empty-handed with NAV nullified</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/shareholders-return-empty-handed-with-nav-nullified</link><description>Shareholders return empty-handed with net asset value (NAV) of their shares turning zero as the merger of five liquidity-crisis-ridden commercial banks into a big-dream Islamic bank begins.



The central bank Wednesday officially started the merger process through dissolving boards of the bank</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 18:29:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Food security remains elusive</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/food-security-remains-elusive</link><description>No nation can be proud if only 32.9 per cent of its population have full food security. Of the rest, 22.75 face extreme food insecurity and 44.57 per cent people enjoy marginal food security which otherwise translates into vulnerability of food availability. Their fragile food availability can dete</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 18:44:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Army wants fair election within govt roadmap</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/army-wants-fair-election-within-govt-roadmap</link><description>The Bangladesh Army wants the upcoming national election to be held as per the roadmap set by the interim government, believing that a timely election will further improve political stability and help normalise the country's law-and-order situation
Lieutenant General Md Mainur Rahman, General Offi</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 01:26:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dengue toll hits single-day high of 10 this year</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dengue-toll-hits-single-day-high-of-10-this-year</link><description>Dengue fever claimed 10 more lives, the highest single-day fatalities of the year, across the country during the past 24 hours until Wednesday.
With the latest count, the death toll from the mosquito-borne disease crossed the 300-mark to reach 302 this year.
During the 24-hour period, some 1,069</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 01:41:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pilot basically to blame for tragedy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/pilot-basically-to-blame-for-tragedy</link><description>The pilot is to primarily blame for the terrible plane crash at Milestone School and College in Dhaka's Uttara as his failure to control the aircraft led to the tragedy, official inquiry report reveals and recommends preventives.
Headed by Principal Staff Officer of the Armed Forces Division Lieut</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 02:11:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>October inflation edges down to 8.17pc</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/october-inflation-edges-down-to-817pc</link><description>Inflation in Bangladesh edged down with October recording 8.17 per cent, official data showed Wednesday, as food prices yielded some respite although nonfood necessities remained obdurate.
Analysts say the inflation rate in the past month could have fallen further from previous month's count hadn'</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 02:41:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NBR rules out mid-yr tax hike before polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/nbr-rules-out-mid-yr-tax-hike-before-polls</link><description>The government has firmly told the International Monetary Fund (IMF) that it will not impose any new tax or raise the rate of existing ones before the next national budget that will be prepared under a new government.
Officials said the stance reflects both legal and political considerations as th</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 02:56:46 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>