<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 10:26:05 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Inqilab Mancha urges people to avoid violence</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/inqilab-mancha-urges-people-to-avoid-violence</link><description>Inqilab Moncho on Friday urged people to refrain from any form of violence over the death of its spokesperson Sharif Osman Bin Hadi who died at a Singapore hospital on Thursday a week after a gun attack on him.
In a Facebook post, the socio-cultural platform—formed in the wake of the July Re</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 05:35:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Australia plans gun buyback after Bondi massacre, as surfers honour victims</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/australia-plans-gun-buyback-after-bondi-massacre-as-surfers-honour-victims</link><description>Australia will launch a national gun buyback scheme following the mass shooting in Sydney, Prime Minister Anthony Albanese said on Friday, as hundreds of surfers and swimmers paddled out at Bondi Beach to honour victims.
The buyback would be similar to gun reforms introduced soon after the massacr</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 05:50:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCP’s Hannan Masud files GD over ‘death threats’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ncps-hannan-masud-files-gd-over-death-threats</link><description>Abdul Hannan Masud, the senior joint chief convenor of the National Citizen Party (NCP) and the party’s candidate for the upcoming Noakhali-6 parliamentary election, has allegedly received death threats.
Masud’s uncle Shamsul Tibriz, the chief convenor of the NCP’s Hatiya Upazila</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 06:05:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>As global scrutiny grows, Chinese firms look to call Singapore home</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/as-global-scrutiny-grows-chinese-firms-look-to-call-singapore-home</link><description>A growing number of Chinese companies are looking to domicile in Singapore, betting a move to the trade-focused city-state would reduce risks their operations get disrupted by Sino-US geopolitical tensions.
The trend, billed as "Singapore washing" by some analysts, started gaining traction near th</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 06:20:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Police chief inspects Daily Star, Prothom Alo buildings after arson attack</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/police-chief-inspects-daily-star-prothom-alo-buildings-after-arson-attack</link><description>Inspector General of Police (IGP) Baharul Alam has gone to inspect the damage to the buildings housing the Dhaka head offices of major newspapers Prothom Alo and The Daily Star.
He arrived for the inspection of the two buildings at 9am on Friday.
Abdullah Al Imran, additional deputy commissioner</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 06:35:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Attacks on two leading newspapers amount to an attack on the free press, says CA Yunus</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/attacks-on-two-leading-newspapers-amount-to-an-attack-on-the-free-press-says-ca-yunus</link><description>Chief Advisor Muhammad Yunus has spoken to the editors of leading daily newspapers Prothom Alo and The Daily Star over the phone following the attacks on their Dhaka offices.
The Chief Advisor’s Office said Yunus conveyed his deepest sympathies to Prothom Alo Editor Matiur Rahman and Daily S</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 07:24:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Family calls for memorial to slain activist Osman Hadi at Shahbagh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/family-calls-for-memorial-to-slain-activist-osman-hadi-at-shahbagh</link><description>The family of Sharif Osman Hadi, the Inqilab Moncho convenor who died after being shot in Dhaka, has called for a memorial to be built in his honour at Shahbagh.
After news of Hadi's death broke on Thursday, relatives gathered at his family home in Jhalakathi's Nalchity on Friday. Several family m</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 07:39:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Inquilab Moncho shares image of ‘Hadi's coffin’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/inquilab-moncho-shares-image-of-hadis-coffin</link><description>Inquilab Moncho on Friday shared the coffin of Sharif Osman Bin Hadi, spokesperson of the platform, who passed away while receiving treatment in Singapore on Thursday.
Posting a photo of the coffin wrapped with the flag of Bangladesh on its official Facebook page, the platform quoted Hadi, "I have</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 07:54:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP calls emergency meeting tonight</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-calls-emergency-meeting-tonight</link><description>BNP has called an emergency meeting scheduled to take place at the chairperson’s political office in Gulshan at 8:30pm on Friday.It also postponed two programmes set for today, citing the “overall situation” in the country, 
BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir&amp;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 08:28:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hadi’s death an irreparable loss to nation: Rizwana</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hadis-death-an-irreparable-loss-to-nation-rizwana</link><description>The tragic demise of Sharif Osman Bin Hadi, a frontline activist of the July Uprising and spokesperson of Inquilab Moncho, is an irreparable loss to the country and its people, Environment Adviser Syeda Rizwana Hasan said on Friday.
In a condolence message, Rizwana, also Adviser to the Ministry of</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 08:43:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt condemns mob violence, vows justice for attacks on journalists</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-condemns-mob-violence-vows-justice-for-attacks-on-journalists</link><description>The interim government has urged citizens to resist all forms of mob violence and has condemned acts of intimidation, arson and destruction of property, describing the current period as a critical moment in the country’s democratic transition.
In a statement issued on Thursday, the governmen</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 08:58:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US, EU express condolences over Osman Hadi’s death</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/us-eu-express-condolences-over-osman-hadis-death</link><description>The United States and European Union missions in Dhaka have expressed condolences over the death of political activist Sharif Osman Bin Hadi, who was shot in the capital last week.
Both missions posted messages on social media on Friday mourning his death and offering sympathies to his family and</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 09:58:30 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>