<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 05:40:43 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Lower interest to single digits, help economy grow</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/lower-interest-to-single-digits-help-economy-grow</link><description>Business leaders on Thursday urged the central bank to reinstate single-digit lending rates.
They deplored that ramped-up interest, currently hovering above 14 per cent, was harming business growth, investment and global competitiveness.
The strong plea for rate cut was made during a meeting with</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 19:37:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>July Charter to be signed October 15 at political grand show</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/july-charter-to-be-signed-october-15-at-political-grand-show</link><description>A nagging standoff ends as political parties and the consensus commission unanimously decide the July Charter will be signed on October 15 at an open-air assembly, though its referendum timing yet undecided.
The decision was finalised at a meeting of the commission on Thursday with so-far squabbli</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 01:46:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Current-account surplus further up, spurs economic activity</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/current-account-surplus-further-up-spurs-economic-activity</link><description>Bangladesh's current-account surplus has increased, with the August figure having nearly doubled to US$500 million over the previous month's, giving a much-needed shot in the arm economic activity.
Official statistics show the CAS upswing is powered by strong remittance inflows and robust export p</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 02:16:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt approves merger of 5 Islamic banks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/govt-approves-merger-of-5-islamic-banks</link><description>The Advisory Council on Thursday approved a proposal to form a new bank by merging five financially distressed Islamic banks, officials said.
The new bank, likely to be named United Islamic Bank, will be established under the Bank Resolution Ordinance 2025.
The Advisory Council, chaired by Chief</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 02:31:45 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>