<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 11:21:33 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>DMP bans rallies, processions around CJ’s residence, Judges Complex</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dmp-bans-rallies-processions-around-cjs-residence-judges-complex-1</link><description>Dhaka Metropolitan Police (DMP) has imposed a ban on rallies, processions, demonstrations and gatherings around Chief Justice’s residence, Judges Complex, the main gate of Bangladesh Supreme court, Mazar Gate, Jam-e-Mosque gate, the main gates of International Crimes Tribunal 1 and 2 and Bang</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 09:39:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fakhrul calls for unity to uphold gains of July mass uprising</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/fakhrul-calls-for-unity-to-uphold-gains-of-july-mass-uprising</link><description>BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir on Tuesday urged political leaders and people to remain united in safeguarding the gains of last year’s July mass uprising, saying the sacrifices of the young people who lost their lives must not go in vain.
“Let us work together to con</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 09:54:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BTRC says ‘no’ to used mobile imports, traders stand firm</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/btrc-says-no-to-used-mobile-imports-traders-refuse-to-budge</link><description>After protests, building sieges, and arson attacks, the Bangladesh Telecommunication Regulatory Commission (BTRC) has remained adamant on its decision to ban unauthorised mobile phones.
Following a meeting with officials on Tuesday, grey market mobile phone traders said a compromise has not been r</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 10:09:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Graft won't end unless the corrupt are shunned: Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/corruption-wont-end-unless-society-shuns-the-corrupt-says-finance-adviser</link><description>Finance Adviser Salehuddin Ahmed believes corruption will never be eradicated unless corrupt individuals are socially rejected.
“When we were young, we rarely heard about corruption. Our fathers would avoid those who were corrupt. They would even hesitate to marry their children into those f</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 09:21:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New RPO ordinance amends postal ballot rules, expands judicial powers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/new-rpo-ordinance-amends-postal-ballot-rules-expands-judicial-powers</link><description>Bangladesh has issued a gazette amending several articles of the Representation of the People Order (RPO), bringing changes to postal ballot counting, the powers of election officials, and the authority of the judicial committee.
The changes have been made ahead of the 13th parliamentary election</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 09:36:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fire breaks out at seven-storey building in Indonesia’s Jakarta, 20 dead</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/fire-breaks-out-at-seven-storey-building-in-indonesias-jakarta-20-dead</link><description>A fire broke out at a seven-storey building in Indonesia’s capital Jakarta on Tuesday, an official said on Tuesday, with 20 people confirmed dead.
The fire has been extinguished and efforts to find more possible victims inside the building continue, Susatyo Purnomo Condro, the head of Centra</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 09:51:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump unveils $12b aid package for farmers hit by trade war</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/trump-unveils-12b-aid-package-for-farmers-hit-by-trade-war</link><description>US President Donald Trump on Monday unveiled a $12 billion aid package for American farmers, the latest government effort to shore up a key political constituency hurt by the financial fallout from his trade policies.
Farm groups and Republican farm-state lawmakers have sought the aid in part to s</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 10:06:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>31 govt officials promoted to ADC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/31-govt-officials-promoted-to-adc</link><description>The government has promoted 31 senior assistant secretary-level officers to Additional Deputy Commissioners (ADCs).
The Ministry of Public Administration issued a gazette notification in this regard on Monday night.
The newly promoted officers have been empowered with the authority of Additional</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 10:21:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Japan lifts tsunami warning after 7.5-magnitude earthquake</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/japan-lifts-tsunami-warning-after-75-magnitude-earthquake</link><description>Japanese authorities lifted tsunami warnings on Tuesday hours after a powerful 7.5-magnitude earthquake shook northeastern regions, injuring at least 30 people and forcing about 90,000 residents to evacuate their homes.
The earthquake struck off the coast at 11:15 p.m. (1415 GMT) on Monday, and th</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 10:36:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>RU teacher calls Begum Rokeya an ‘infidel’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ru-teacher-calls-begum-rokeya-an-infidel</link><description>A Rajshahi University teacher has come under fire after branding Begum Rokeya Sakhawat Hossain, a pioneer of women’s rights, an “infidel” in a social media post.
Khandaker Mahmudul Hasan, an associate professor of the university’s physics department, made the controversial</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 10:51:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>e-GP tender crosses 10-lakh mark</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/e-gp-tender-crosses-10-lakh-mark</link><description>The electronic Government Procurement (e-GP) system of the Bangladesh Public Procurement Authority (BPPA) has experienced a year of remarkable increase in tender volume, registrations of tenderers and procuring entities, and the estimated cost of tenders.
Introduced in 2011, the e-GP is a centrali</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 11:06:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BB buys $202m through dollar auction</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bb-buys-202m-through-dollar-auction</link><description>Bangladesh Bank (BB) today purchased US$202 million from 13 commercial banks through multiple auction methods as part of its ongoing strategy to curb the depreciation of the US dollar against the taka and revitalise the remittance and export sectors. According to central bank data, it bought d</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 11:21:33 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>