<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 04:53:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>JSS member killed in ‘gun battle’ with Army in Bandarban</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jss-member-killed-in-gun-battle-with-army-in-bandarban</link><description>A suspected member of the Parbatya Chattoggram Jana Sanghati Samity (JSS) has been killed in an alleged gunfight between members of the organisation and the Army in Bandarban’s Rowangchhari.
A statement issued by the Inter Services Public Relations (ISPR) said the incident occurred around 5p</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 03:45:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump warns countries that 'play games' with US trade deals will face higher tariffs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/trump-warns-countries-that-play-games-with-us-trade-deals-will-face-higher-tariffs</link><description>US President Donald Trump on Monday warned countries against backing away from recently negotiated trade deals with the US after the Supreme Court struck down his emergency tariffs, saying that if they did, he would hit them with much higher duties under different trade laws.
Trump, in a series of</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 02:16:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Police association calls for uniform change within days of govt transition</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/police-service-association-calls-for-uniform-change-within-days-of-govt-transition</link><description>Within a week of the new government taking office, the Bangladesh Police Service Association has demanded a reversal of the recently introduced police uniform, saying most officers oppose the change and were not consulted before the decision was made.
In a statement issued on Monday night, the ass</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 02:31:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>PCA could be signed shortly: EU envoy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/pca-could-be-signed-shortly-eu-envoy</link><description>Bangladesh and the European Union discussed Monday the possibilities of signing a free-trade agreement (FTA), as the EU desires to expand the multifaceted bilateral relations.
The issue was highlighted during discussion between foreign minister Dr Khalilur Rahman and a delegation of EU Ambassadors</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 02:46:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Aminul Islam takes charge as ICT chief prosecutor</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/aminul-islam-takes-charge-as-ict-chief-prosecutor</link><description>The government has appointed Md Aminul Islam, a pro-BNP Supreme Court lawyer, as the new chief prosecutor of the International Crimes Tribunal (ICT) in Dhaka, replacing Muhammad Tajul Islam.
The Ministry of Law, Justice and Parliamentary Affairs issued a notification on Monday, confirming the appo</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 03:01:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Culex density rises in Dhaka, may peak in March</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/culex-density-rises-in-dhaka-may-peak-in-march</link><description>The high density of Culex mosquitoes in the capital and other parts of the country is unlikely to ease anytime soon, experts say, at least until the rains arrive and local government authorities become fully functional.
The surge in mosquitoes has made life uncomfortable both indoors and outdoors,</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 03:16:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nine hurt in Ctg gas blast</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nine-hurt-in-ctg-gas-blast</link><description>CHATTOGRAM, Feb 23: Nine persons, including a child, were injured in a gas explosion at Halima Manzil in the port-city's Halishahar area on Monday. The victims were identified as Shipon (30), Sumon (40), Shaon (17), Anas (07), Aimman (09), Shakwat (46), Ayesha (04), Pakhi (35), and Rani (40).
Accu</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 03:31:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DCCI flags extortion, opaque US trade deal as risks to economic recovery</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/dcci-flags-extortion-opaque-us-trade-deal-as-risks-to-economic-recovery</link><description>Rampant extortion, deteriorating law and order and an opaque trade agreement with the United States are threatening to suffocate Bangladesh's fragile economic recovery, the Dhaka Chamber of Commerce &amp; Industry (DCCI) has warned.
Speaking at a press conference on Monday titled "Expectations from th</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 03:46:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Karwan Bazar traders announce lower profit sales during Ramadan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/karwan-bazar-traders-announce-lower-profit-sales-during-ramadan</link><description>Traders at Karwan Bazar on Monday made an announcement to sell several essential items at lower profit margins during the holy month of Ramadan.
The announcement which aims to help stabilise prices of daily necessities such as lemons, edible oil, and sugar was made at a press conference organised</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 04:01:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Despite strong profits, Biman's total assets decline for third straight year</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/despite-strong-profits-bimans-total-assets-decline-for-third-straight-year</link><description>Despite repeated claims by Biman Bangladesh Airlines that it has remained profitable over the five consecutive years, the national carrier's total assets have continued to decline.
According to the airline's latest audited financial statements, total assets stood at Tk 168.72 billion at the end of</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 04:16:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Miscreants vandalise BNP office in Natore</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/miscreants-vandalise-bnp-office-in-natore</link><description>Miscreants vandalised a local BNP office in Naldianga upazila of Natore on Monday evening.
Rakib Hossain, a local Jubo Dal leader, said a group of assailants attacked the BNP office at Ward No. 9 in Chatarbhag Market of Brakhpur Union and caused extensive damage.
The incident occurred during Ifta</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 04:31:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fire guts valuables at Khulna shopping mall</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fire-guts-valuables-at-khulna-shopping-mall</link><description>A fire gutted the valuables of five shops at Baitun Nur Shopping Complex near New Market in Khulna city early Tuesday.
Witnesses said the fire started around 11:30 pm, and locals informedthe  Khulna Fire Service immediately.
Six fire units of Khulna Fire Service brought the blaze under contr</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 04:46:32 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>