<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 14:21:41 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>How July Uprising firebrand Osman Hadi burst into the spotlight</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/how-july-uprising-firebrand-osman-hadi-burst-into-the-spotlight</link><description>The shooting of Sharif Osman bin Hadi, an independent candidate in Dhaka-8 and convener of the Inquilab Mancha platform, a day after the election schedule was announced has sparked intense debate in the political arena.
It has also brought renewed attention to Osman Hadi’s political stance,</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 12:28:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A 6.9 magnitude earthquake causes small tsunami waves off northeastern Japan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/a-69-magnitude-earthquake-causes-small-tsunami-waves-off-northeastern-japan</link><description>A 6.9 magnitude earthquake shook northeastern Japan and caused small tsunami waves but no apparent damage Friday, days after a stronger quake in the same region.
Friday’s quake occurred off the east coast of Aomori prefecture, in the north of Honshu, the main Japanese island, at a depth of 2</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 12:43:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Protesters block road in Jhalakathi over Osman Hadi shooting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/protesters-block-road-in-jhalakathi-over-osman-hadi-shooting</link><description>Leaders and activists of the Students Against Discrimination have blocked roads in Jhalakathi’s Sadar Upazila in protest over the shooting of Osman Hadi, convoner of the Inquilab Mancha platform.
Hadi’s family home is in Nalchity Upazila of Jhalakathi district.
The blockade began at 4</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 12:58:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Passengers suffer after metro shutdown</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/commuters-suffer-as-metro-service-suspended-over-work-stoppage</link><description>Commuters are suffering as a work stoppage by the Dhaka Mass Transit Company Limited (DMTCL) staff led to the shutdown of metro rail services.
The unannounced closure of the service prompted many people to change their plan, returning home from metro stations, while others expressed their annoyanc</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 13:13:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Keep politics out of hospital: Health Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/keep-politics-out-of-hospital-health-adviser</link><description>Health Adviser Nurjahan Begum has urged medical professionals to draw a firm line between their political affiliations and their duties, warning that hospitals must never become extensions of party activity.
Addressing physicians, nurses and staff at Chattogram Medical College Hospital on Friday a</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 12:28:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>2 youths die after consuming alcohol in Pabna</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/2-youths-die-after-consuming-alcohol-in-pabna</link><description>Two youths died allegedly after consuming alcohol in Pabna city early Friday, police said.
The deceased were identified as Suman Sarkar, 35, son of Sanchit Sarkar, and Mamun, 32, son of Habibur Rahman, of Gopalpur and Radhanagar Maktab villages respectively.
Sukhi Khatun, a nurse at Pabna General</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 12:43:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ukraine says it retakes parts of Kupiansk, encircling Russian troops</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/ukraine-says-it-retakes-parts-of-kupiansk-encircling-russian-troops</link><description>Ukrainian forces have retaken parts of the northeastern town of Kupiansk and several villages around it in an operation that encircled Russian troops, a Ukrainian military commander said on Friday.
The Russian military said in November that it had taken full control of Kupiansk. Ukraine denied the</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 12:58:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>TIB holds environment-focused training for judges</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tib-holds-environment-focused-training-for-judges</link><description>Transparency International Bangladesh (TIB) organised a day-long training on Thursday aimed at enhancing judges’ capacity to enforce environmental laws and ensure justice.
The workshop, held at TIB’s Dhanmondi office in consultation with the Supreme Court and supported by the Law Minis</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 13:13:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US admiral leading US troops in Latin America to step down</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-admiral-leading-us-troops-in-latin-america-to-step-down</link><description>The admiral in charge of US military forces in Latin America will retire two years early on Friday, amid rising tensions with Venezuela that include Wednesday's seizure of an oil tanker and more than 20 deadly strikes on suspected drug-smuggling boats.
Three US officials and two people familiar wi</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 13:28:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Man admits to ‘killing’ freedom fighter to steal Tk 8,000</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/man-confesses-to-killing-freedom-fighter-wife-in-rangpur-for-tk-8000</link><description>A man has confessed to killing a freedom fighter and his wife in Rangpur’s Taraganj after planning to steal money from their home to repay a debt of around Tk 8,000, police say.
Rangpur Superintendent of Police Marufat Hossain shared the information during a media briefing on Friday after th</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 13:43:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fakhrul sees Hadi shooting as ‘plot to derail election'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fakhrul-sees-hadi-shooting-as-plot-to-derail-election</link><description>BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir has described the shooting of Sharif Osman bin Hadi, a potential independent contender for Dhaka-8 and convenor of the Inquilab Mancha platform, as “a conspiracy to derail the general election”.
On Friday afternoon, during a discussion</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 13:58:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC reinstates 4 seats in Bagerhat, 5 seats in Gazipur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-reinstates-4-seats-in-bagerhat-5-seats-in-gazipur</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has reinstated four parliamentary seats in Bagerhat and five in Gazipur following an Appellate Division order, ahead of the 13th parliamentary election and the referendum on the July National Charter (Constitutional Reform) Implementation Order 2025, both scheduled for</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 14:13:51 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>