<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 13:40:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Fuel prices to remain unchanged in March</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/fuel-prices-to-remain-unchanged-in-march</link><description>The prices of diesel, octane, petrol, and kerosene will remain unchanged in March, the Energy and Mineral Resources Division has said.
On February 26, the division sent a letter to the chairman of Bangladesh Petroleum Corporation (BPC) instructing that all types of fuel prices be kept steady.
The</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 08:46:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh condemns sovereignty violations in Gulf states</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-condemns-sovereignty-violations-in-gulf-states</link><description>Bangladesh on Sunday condemned the violation of sovereignty of some countries, including Bahrain, Iraq, Jordan, Kuwait, Qatar, Saudi Arabia and the United Arab Emirates.
Bangladesh hopes that calm will prevail at the earliest, and peace, security and stability will be restored soonest across the r</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 10:30:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt plans to speed up ADP implementation despite late fiscal push</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/govt-plans-to-speed-up-adp-implementation-despite-late-fiscal-push</link><description>The newly formed government has taken a move to expedite the annual development rate (ADP) of the country to an expected level although two-thirds of the fiscal period has been gone under the interim government.
Finance and Planning Minister Amir Khosru Mahmud Chowdhury gave the directive during h</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 10:45:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khamenei’s death: Who will be Iran’s next supreme leader?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/khameneis-death-who-will-be-irans-next-supreme-leader</link><description>The death of Iran’s Supreme Leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei after almost 37 years in power raises paramount questions about the country’s future. The contours of a complex succession process began to take shape the morning after Khamenei’s assassination.
Here is what to know:
A te</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 11:00:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Magnitude 5.8 earthquake strikes Japan, GFZ says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/magnitude-58-earthquake-strikes-japan-gfz-says</link><description>An earthquake of magnitude 5.8 struck Kyushu, in Japan, the German Research Centre for Geosciences said on Sunday.
The quake was at a depth of 122 km (75.81 miles), GFZ said.</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 11:15:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US-sanctioned oil tanker hit off Oman coast</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-sanctioned-oil-tanker-hit-off-oman-coast</link><description>A Palau-flagged oil tanker under US sanctions was hit on Sunday off Oman’s Musandam peninsula, injuring four people, the country’s maritime security centre said, without specifying what hit the vessel.
The attack followed earlier drone strikes elsewhere in the Gulf country, at the comm</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 11:30:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>In polarised Iran, Khamenei's death triggers celebrations and grief</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/in-polarised-iran-khameneis-death-triggers-celebrations-and-grief</link><description>Some Iranians grieved while others celebrated the death of Supreme Leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei, exposing a deep fault line in a country stunned by the sudden demise of the man who ruled for 36 years.
Iranian state TV announced his death in the early hours of Sunday, the voice of the broadcaster</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 11:45:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Remittance inflow increases by 19.5pc in February</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/remittance-inflow-increases-by-195pc-in-february</link><description>Expatriate Bangladeshis sent US$3.02 billion remittances in February, which was around 19.5 percent higher than the corresponding month of the previous year.
Expatriates sent home $2.53 billion in the same month the previous year, according to the latest data from the Bangladesh Bank, BSS reports.</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 12:00:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Global reaction to the killing of Iran’s Khamenei</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/global-reaction-to-the-killing-of-irans-khamenei</link><description>Iran’s Supreme Leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei was killed in US and Israeli strikes, state media confirmed as another wave of attacks hit the country on Sunday.
Below is international reaction to his death.
EUROPEAN UNION FOREIGN POLICY CHIEF KAJA KALLAS
“The death of Ali Khamenei is a</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 12:15:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Where US and Israeli forces struck Iran</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/where-us-and-israeli-forces-struck-iran</link><description>The United States and Israel launched their most ambitious attacks on Iran in decades on Saturday in an operation that killed Supreme Leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei.
The biggest foreign-policy gamble of US President Donald Trump’s presidency comes after he campaigned for reelection as a &amp;ldqu</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 12:30:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Afghanistan says it thwarted a Pakistani airstrike attempt on Bagram Air Base</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/afghanistan-says-it-thwarted-a-pakistani-airstrike-attempt-on-bagram-air-base</link><description>Afghanistan said Sunday it had thwarted attempted airstrikes on Bagram Air Base, the former US military base north of Kabul, while cross-border fighting between Pakistan and Afghanistan stretched into a fourth day.
The fighting has been the most severe between the neighbors for years, with Pakista</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 12:45:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>PM orders urgent measures for safety of Bangladeshis in Middle East</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/pm-orders-urgent-measures-for-safety-of-bangladeshis-in-middle-east</link><description>Prime Minister Tarique Rahman has ordered urgent measures to ensure the safety of Bangladeshi nationals in Iran and across the Middle East amid escalating regional conflict, as flight cancellations and fears of rising fuel prices add to mounting concern.
After arriving at his office at the se</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 13:00:40 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>