<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 14:52:08 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Editors’ Council urges govt to drop harassment cases against journalists</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/editors-council-urges-govt-to-drop-harassment-cases-against-journalists</link><description>The Editors’ Council on Wednesday urged the government to withdraw false and harassing cases filed against journalists.
In a statement, the council said that since August 5, 2024, many journalists have been falsely accused in murder and other cases. Some journalists are still in jail, while</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 13:23:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>'Governor change at central bank part of wider administrative reshuffle'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/governor-change-at-central-bank-part-of-wider-administrative-reshuffle</link><description>Finance Minister Amir Khosru Mahmud Chowdhury on Wednesday said the change in the governorship of Bangladesh Bank was part of a broader administrative reshuffle undertaken by the new government to implement its priorities and policy agenda.
“Changes have not taken place in Bangladesh Bank on</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 13:38:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sonali Bank signs agreement with Popular Diagnostic</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/sonali-bank-signs-agreement-with-popular-diagnostic</link><description>Sonali Bank PLC signed an agreement with Popular Diagnostic Centre Limited at the bank's head office mini conference room on Wednesday, according to a press release.
Deputy Managing Director of Sonali Bank, Md. Rezaul Karim and Deputy General Manager of Polpular Diagnostic Centre, Achinto Kumar Na</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 12:25:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Apex launches Eid campaign ‘Style-e No.1’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/apex-launches-eid-campaign-style-e-no1</link><description>This Eid, Apex Footwear Limited walks into the spotlight with the largest campaign of the year, celebrating its position as it reflects Apex’s vision to become the ultimate Eid’s No.1 stylish destination for families across the nation.
This campaign marks the reunion of two of the coun</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 12:40:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Takeaways from Trump's State of the Union address to Congress</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/takeaways-from-trumps-state-of-the-union-address-to-congress</link><description>President Donald Trump delivered his State of the Union address to a joint session of Congress on Tuesday, a potentially pivotal moment as the White House seeks to firm up support among Republican voters ahead of November's midterm election.
Trump spoke against a backdrop of rising tensions with I</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 12:55:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>bKash enables Zakat-donations to over 50 organisations supporting the underprivileged</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bkash-enables-zakat-donations-to-over-50-organisations-supporting-the-underprivileged</link><description>Through bKash, Zakat and donations can now be easily sent to more than 50 charitable and volunteer-based organisations working across the country, ensuring that financial assistance reaches thousands of vulnerable people in need.
Throughout the year, bKash enables users to donate directly to vario</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 13:10:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Modhumoti Bank signs agreement with Unitrend Limited</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/modhumoti-bank-signs-agreement-with-unitrend-limited</link><description>Modhumoti Bank PLC signed an agreement with Unitrend Limited (affiliated with McCANN WorldGroup) on Sunday at the bank’s head office in Gulshan area of Dhaka.
Mr. Md. Shafiul Azam, Managing Director &amp; CEO of Modhumoti Bank PLC., and Mr. Muneer Ahmed Khan, Managing Director &amp; Creative Chief o</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 13:25:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EU seeks early measures to remove NTBs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/eu-seeks-early-measures-to-remove-ntbs</link><description>The European Union (EU) has sought quick measures to remove non-tariff barriers (NTBs), promoting business confidence and ensuring non-discrimination.
“We look for early measures to remove NTBs, promote business confidence, and ensure non-discrimination,” said the EU Embassy on Wednesd</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 13:40:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DSCC wants professionalism to deliver PM’s ‘Green City–Clean City’ vision</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dscc-administrator-wants-professionalism-to-implement-pms-green-city-clean-city-vision</link><description>Acting on the directives of Prime Minister Tarique Rahman, the newly-appointed administrator of Dhaka South City Corporation (DSCC) on Wednesday instructed officials to work with the highest level of professionalism and dedication to transform Dhaka into a modern ‘Green City and Clean City.&amp;r</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 13:55:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Renu Begum of Shariatpur wins motorcycle on cash remittance</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/renu-begum-of-shariatpur-wins-motorcycle-on-cash-remittance</link><description>Renu Begum, a client of the Naria branch in Shariatpur, won the fourth motorcycle in the Cash Remittance Festival by receiving remittance through Ria Money Transfer at Islami Bank Bangladesh PLC.
She wins this prize against a remittance of Tk. 85,300 sent by Masum Hossain, an expatriate in Italy,</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 14:10:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pragati Insurance holds 340th board meeting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/pragati-insurance-holds-340th-board-meeting</link><description>The 340th meeting of the Board of  Directors of  Pragati Insurance PLC was held on  24 February 2026 at the Head Office of the company.
Syed M. Altaf Hussain, Chairman of the company, presided over the meeting, according to a press release. 
Besides, Director Alhaj Khalilur Ra</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 14:25:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The election was the easy part, now comes the reckoning</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/the-election-was-the-easy-part-now-comes-the-reckoning</link><description>On 12 February 2026, Bangladesh did something important. Nearly 60% of its citizens voted. Polling day was largely calm. The Election Commission under the interim administration managed a process that was orderly and participatory. In a country where elections have too often carried fear in their w</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 14:40:33 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>