<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 05:31:04 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Eastern Lubricants posts Q2 profit despite operating loss</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/eastern-lubricants-posts-q2-profit-despite-operating-loss</link><description>Eastern Lubricants Blenders' direct expenses (cost of production) exceeded its total revenue in the second quarter of FY26, mainly due to lower sales and higher production costs.
The state-run entity's revenue stood at around Tk 88 million in the October-December quarter of FY26, compared to direc</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 02:46:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How to turn idle screen time into something creative with AI</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/how-to-turn-idle-screen-time-into-something-creative-with-ai</link><description>We all have been there. Picking up the phone for a quick look and suddenly losing an entire evening to an endless scroll of grim headlines and chaotic opinions. It feels passive, heavy, and strangely addictive. We end up regretting the time lost, yet repeat the cycle anyway.
But our screens don't</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 03:01:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sylhet candidates count heavily on expat donations, loans for Feb polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/sylhet-candidates-count-heavily-on-expat-donations-loans-for-feb-polls</link><description>SYLHET. Jan.27: Candidates in the six parliamentary constituencies of Sylhet are significanty dependeing on donations and loans from expatriates and relatives to carry out their election campaigns in the 13th national election shcheduled for February 12, reveal their nomination papers and expenditu</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 03:16:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh misses out on global poultry trade</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladesh-misses-out-on-global-poultry-trade</link><description>Despite building one of the country's largest agro-based industries in terms of investment and employment, Bangladesh has failed to secure a meaningful share of the global poultry-export market.
While neighbours India and China have expanded shipments to Middle Eastern and Western markets, Banglad</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 03:31:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Metro-rail expansion hits dead end with projects stalled</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/metro-rail-expansion-hits-dead-end-with-projects-stalled</link><description>Nearly half a million commuters benefit daily from Bangladesh's maiden operational metro rail -- many making a joy ride over Dhaka city -- its projected expansion has effectively stalled with projects gathering dust.
Sector analysts also air doubt about government intention in continuing any proje</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 03:46:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Outbound migration soars, but lack of data leaves returnees vulnerable</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/outbound-migration-soars-but-lack-of-data-leaves-returnees-vulnerable</link><description>Bangladesh continues to witness steady growth in outbound migration, with record-breaking remittance earnings, but the government is still not equipped to accurately track the returnee migrant workers.
While there is data on the number of workers sent abroad, there is no regular update on how many</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 04:01:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ACC to charge three serving bureaucrats</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/acc-to-charge-three-serving-bureaucrats</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) has decided to file separate cases against three serving bureaucrats for allegedly securing government jobs by submitting forged certificates to the Bangladesh Public Service Commission (BPSC).
According to ACC, it has approved the initiation of cases under Rul</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 04:16:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Abu Sayed murder verdict any day</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/abu-sayed-murder-verdict-any-day</link><description>The International Crimes Tribunal-2 (ICT-2) in Dhaka has concluded the trial proceedings in a crimes against humanity case filed over the killing of Begum Rokeya University, Rangpur (BRUR) student Abu Sayed during the July-August 2024 mass uprising.
The tribunal has set the case for verdict, which</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 04:31:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh bans motorcycles nationwide three days before election, referendum</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-bans-motorcycles-nationwide-three-days-before-election-referendum</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has imposed a three-day ban on motorcycle movement across the country ahead of the parliamentary election and referendum.
In a letter sent to the Ministry of Road Transport and Bridges on Tuesday, the commission instructed the authorities to take necessary measures to</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 04:46:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nagorik Oikko's Manna says BNP obstructing campaign, issuing threats</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/nagorik-oikkos-manna-says-bnp-obstructing-campaign-issuing-threats</link><description>Nagorik Oikko Convenor Mahmudur Rahman Manna has alleged that BNP activists are obstructing his election campaign and issuing threats in Bogura-2 constituency.
Manna made the allegations at a press conference at the Bogura Press Club around 8:30pm on Tuesday.
He said attempts to harass him began</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 05:01:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt to meet stakeholders again on Feb 3 over yarn bond exclusion</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/govt-to-meet-stakeholders-again-on-feb-3-over-yarn-bond-exclusion</link><description>The government will meet stakeholders again on February 3 as the major parties have failed to reach any consensus on the exclusion of the yarn-import bond facility.
The parties are the Bangladesh Textile Mills Association (BTMA), the Bangladesh Garment Manufacturers and Exporters Association (BGME</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 05:16:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Deputy chief minister of India's Maharashtra dies in plane crash</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/deputy-chief-minister-of-indias-maharashtra-dies-in-plane-crash</link><description>The deputy chief minister of India's western state of Maharashtra, Ajit Pawar, was killed on Wednesday as his charter aircraft went down in flames, television channels said.
Video showed billows of smoke rising from some of the burning wreckage of the plane, scattered across an open field.
Media</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 05:31:03 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>