<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 10:20:16 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Hindu community celebrates Kumari Puja</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hindu-community-celebrates-kumari-puja</link><description>Hindus across the country celebrated Kumari Puja on the Maha Ashtami on Tuesday as part of the five-day Durga Puja.
The main attraction of Maha Ashtami is Kumari Puja where a pre-pubescent girl is worshipped as “Mother Goddess”.
In the capital city, hundreds of Hindu devotees offered</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 08:23:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Peaceful election is now biggest challenge for police, says IGP Baharul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/peaceful-election-is-now-biggest-challenge-for-police-says-igp-baharul</link><description>Inspector General of Police (IGP) Baharul Alam believes successfully conducting the parliamentary election is the force’s biggest challenge right now.
He made the statement on Tuesday in response to a question from journalists at a briefing held at the Police Headquarters.
The police chief</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 08:38:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Three private packages announced for 2026 Hajj</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/three-private-packages-announced-for-2026-hajj</link><description>Private travel agencies have announced three Hajj packages for next year following the government’s announcement of its official packages.
Farid Ahmed Mazumder, secretary general of the Hajj Agencies Association of Bangladesh (HAAB), announced the packages at a hotel in Dhaka’s Naya Pa</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 07:26:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>One SUST student expelled, 24 suspended  over ragging</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/one-sust-student-expelled-24-suspended-over-ragging</link><description>The authorities of Shahjalal University of Science and Technology (SUST) have expelled one student and suspended 24 others for several terms for ragging freshers.
Fahim Muntasir, a 2nd year student of the Economics Department of the university, was expelled, reports UNB.
The authorities took the</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 07:41:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt hopeful of recovering part of laundered funds by February: Salehuddin</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/govt-hopeful-of-recovering-part-of-laundered-funds-by-february-says-finance-adviser</link><description>Finance Adviser Dr Salehuddin Ahmed on Monday said the process of bringing back laundered money is advancing gradually through legal and institutional mechanisms, though it requires time and cannot be done overnight.
“Bringing the money back is not like calling up a Swiss bank and asking the</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 08:11:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Typhoon Bualoi death toll rises to 19 in Vietnam as Hanoi streets flooded</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/typhoon-bualoi-death-toll-rises-to-19-in-vietnam-as-hanoi-streets-flooded</link><description>Vietnam's death toll from Typhoon Bualoi rose to 19 with another 21 people still missing, the government said on Tuesday, making it the most devastating storm to hit the country this year as heavy rains caused severe flooding in Hanoi and across northern provinces.
Bualoi made landfall on Monday i</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 08:26:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mother, daughter found dead in Thakurgaon</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/mother-daughter-found-dead-in-thakurgaon</link><description>Police recovered the decomposed body of a 45-year-old woman and her daughter from their house at Madarganj in Sadar upazila of Thakurgaon district on Monday night.
The deceased were identified as Samila Rani, wife of Jagadish Chandra Roy and her daughter Shapla Rani, 18, of the village, reports UN</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 08:56:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EBL to facilitate the digital holding tax collection of CCC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ebl-to-facilitate-the-digital-holding-tax-collection-of-ccc</link><description>Eastern Bank PLC( EBL) will serve as the sole banking partner to implement and operate the digitized holding tax collection system of the Chattogram City Corporation. 
Dr. Shahadat Hossain, Mayor of Chattogram City Corporation, and Ahmed Shaheen, Additional Managing Director of EBL, signed an MoU</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 09:11:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A car bombing outside a Pakistani security force headquarters kills at least 8 people</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/a-car-bombing-outside-a-pakistani-security-force-headquarters-kills-at-least-8-people</link><description>Militants set off a powerful car bomb outside the headquarters of Pakistan’s paramilitary security forces in the southwestern city of Quetta on Tuesday, killing at least eight people and wounding several others, authorities said.
Before detonating their vehicle, four attackers who were insid</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 09:26:03 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>