<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 07:22:14 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>BGB seeks public, media support to curb rumours, smuggling in Lalmonirhat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/bgb-seeks-public-media-support-to-curb-rumours-smuggling-in-lalmonirhat</link><description>Border Guard Bangladesh (BGB–Teesta Battalion) has urged the media and local residents of Lalmonirhat to help prevent rumours and smuggling along the district’s border areas, stressing that community cooperation is vital for strengthening border security.
Brigadier General ASM Naser, R</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 05:16:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>4th GolfHouse Corporate Cup kicks off in Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/4th-golfhouse-corporate-cup-kicks-off-in-dhaka</link><description>The fourth annual GolfHouse Corporate Cup Golf Tournament 2025 began on Friday at Kurmitola Golf Club (KGC) in Dhaka.
Lieutenant General Mohammad Shaheenul Haque, commandant, National Defence College and also vice president of Kurmitola Golf Club, along with A M M Nazrul Hosen, founder and editor</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 05:31:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>At least 56 dead as severe floods, landslides batter Sri Lanka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/at-least-56-dead-as-severe-floods-landslides-batter-sri-lanka</link><description>At least 56 people have died and 21 remain missing after days of torrential rain triggered widespread flooding and landslides across Sri Lanka, one of the country’s worst weather disasters in recent years.
The central district of Badulla, known for its sprawling tea estates, was among the ha</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 05:46:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US to permanently pause migration from 'Third World Countries'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-says-us-will-permanently-pause-migration-from-third-world-countries</link><description>US President Donald Trump said on Thursday that his administration will work to "permanently pause" migration from all "Third World Countries" to allow the US system to fully recover.
Trump did not identify any countries by name or explain what he meant by third-world countries or "permanently pau</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 06:01:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Youth fatally stabbed amid ‘teen gang feud’ in Khulna</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/youth-fatally-stabbed-amid-teen-gang-feud-in-khulna</link><description>A young man has been stabbed to death during a clash between rival youth gangs in Khulna.
The victim, identified as 21-year-old Ishan, was attacked on Thursday evening near the Khalishpur Fair Clinic intersection, according to Khalishpur Police Station chief Mir Atahar Ali.
He died on the way to</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 06:16:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Police arrest construction firm bosses over Hong Kong fire</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/police-arrest-construction-firm-bosses-over-hong-kong-fire</link><description>Hong Kong police arrested the bosses of a construction company on suspicion of manslaughter on Thursday over the city's worst fire in nearly 80 years, which killed at least 83 people with scores more listed as missing.
By the early hours of Friday, firefighters had mostly contained the blaze ragin</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 05:52:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP condemns alleged Jamaat attack on electioneering in Pabna</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-condemns-alleged-jamaat-attack-on-electioneering-in-pabna</link><description>Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) has strongly condemned a planned attack by armed Jamaat-e-Islami activists on its leaders, activists, and civilians during an election campaign in Pabna’s Ishwardi on Thursday afternoon.
In a statement signed by BNP Senior Joint Secretary General Ruhul Kabi</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 06:07:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Israeli forces kill two Palestinians in West Bank who appeared to be surrendering</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/israeli-forces-kill-two-palestinians-in-west-bank-who-appeared-to-be-surrendering</link><description>Israeli security forces shot two Palestinian men on Thursday who appeared to be surrendering and unarmed during a raid in the Israeli-occupied West Bank, Palestine TV news footage showed.
In the footage, the men are seen exiting a building surrounded by armed Israeli forces in the northern West Ba</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 06:22:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chinese investors can help transform Bangladesh into manufacturing hub: Prof Yunus</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/chinese-investors-can-help-transform-bangladesh-into-manufacturing-hub-prof-yunus</link><description>Chief Adviser Prof Muhammad Yunus has welcomed China’s interest in Bangladesh’s manufacturing sectors, noting that investors from the world’s second-largest economy could help transform Bangladesh into a manufacturing hub producing goods for export to developed nations, including</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 06:37:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Man stabbed to death in ‘late-night mugging’ in Ctg</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/man-stabbed-to-death-in-late-night-mugging-in-chattogram</link><description>A man has been killed during a 'late-night mugging' in Chattogram.
The incident occurred opposite the Chattogram District Council building in the port city’s Kotwali Thana on Thursday night.
The victim has been identified as 30-year-old Md Ismail. He hailed from Lakshmipur, but lived in the</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 06:52:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump says he may cut income tax 'completely' because of tariff income</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/trump-says-he-may-cut-income-tax-completely-because-of-tariff-income</link><description>US President Donald Trump said on Thursday his administration may slash income tax completely over the next couple of years because of government revenue generated from tariffs.
"Over the next couple of years, I think we'll substantially be cutting and maybe cutting out completely, but we'll be cu</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 07:07:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>KUET student suspended for stabbing fellow student</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/kuet-student-suspended-for-stabbing-fellow-student</link><description>Khulna University of Engineering and Technology (KUET) authorities have suspended a student for stabbing a fellow student over a dispute regarding street painting and stall locations for the first-year admission test.
The accused, Kazi Sadiq Mahmud, is a student of the Civil Engineering Department</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 07:22:14 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>