<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 03:13:16 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Experts criticise MRT-6 probe body, call for tech overhaul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/experts-criticise-mrt-6-probe-body-call-for-tech-overhaul</link><description>The first investigation report on the initial bearing pad incident on the elevated structure of Dhaka's Mass Rapid Transit Line 6 (MRT-6) last year failed to examine the possible displacement of nearby pads, raising questions about its thoroughness, according to experts.



The Financial Expr</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 00:28:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Local pesticide makers hit by tax burden</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/local-pesticide-makers-hit-by-tax-burden</link><description>Local manufacturers of pesticides are struggling to stay competitive as they face tax rates more than eleven times higher than those imposed on importers of finished products.
Industry leaders warn that the steep tariff gap is discouraging investment, idling factory capacity, and preventing Bang</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 00:43:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Court to be off-limits to litigants from 2026</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/court-to-be-off-limits-to-litigants-from-2026</link><description>The government has decided not to allow land owners to file cases with courts for land record or khatiyan-related correction from next year.
As part of the move, the Ministry of Land (MoL) has taken a measure to resolve the issues through Bangladesh Digital Survey (BDS).
The MoL also aims to di</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 00:58:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BD to launch nat’l phone registry Dec 16</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bd-to-launch-natl-phone-registry-dec-16</link><description>Bangladesh will roll out the long-awaited National Equipment Identity Register (NEIR) on December 16, marking a major step towards curbing mobile-based fraud, blocking illegal handset imports, and ensuring greater transparency in the telecom sector.
The move, announced on Wednesday by the Bangla</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 01:13:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ICB lays bare wounds in hope of immediate govt support</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/icb-lays-bare-wounds-in-hope-of-immediate-govt-support</link><description>The state-owned Investment Corporation of Bangladesh (ICB) has finally revealed its true financial picture, declaring a loss of Tk 12.14 billion for FY25 after making full provisions that had previously been deferred.



"Corrupt people, linked to the past regime, misused public money to serv</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 01:28:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Horlicks rebound fuels Unilever Consumer Care's strong Q3 recovery</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/horlicks-rebound-fuels-unilever-consumer-cares-strong-q3-recovery</link><description>Unilever Consumer Care bounced back strongly in the third quarter through September this year, supported by higher sales of Horlicks amid easing inflationary pressure, compared to the same quarter last year.



Sales of Horlicks gradually climbed over the past three consecutive quarters to Se</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 01:43:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bata slips deeper into the red in Q3 after protest-linked vandalism</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/bata-slips-deeper-into-the-red-in-q3-after-protest-linked-vandalism</link><description>Despite higher sales, Bata Shoe Company saw its losses escalate 153 per cent year-on-year to Tk 144 million in the third quarter through September this year, having to navigate "exceptional circumstances."
"Several retail locations were affected by acts of vandalism, which disrupted operations a</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 01:58:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>HSIA CARGO VILLAGE FIRE: BGMEA seeks govt help for swift insurance claim settlement</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/hsia-cargo-village-fire-bgmea-seeks-govt-help-for-swift-insurance-claim-settlement</link><description>The country's readymade garment (RMG) sector has urged the government to intervene to ensure prompt settlement and payment of insurance claims following the devastating fire at the import cargo village of Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport (HSIA).



In a recent letter to the Financial In</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 02:13:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Education sector in a sorry state, not possible to improve overnight</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/education-sector-in-a-sorry-state-not-possible-to-improve-overnight</link><description>Despite the importance of nation building, Bangladesh's education sector is in a sorry state; and it is not possible to improve the situation overnight, Planning Adviser Wahiduddin Mahmud said on Wednesday.
"The situation is so pathetic that merely an education commission cannot bring positive c</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 02:43:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Teesta cries for survival as northern Bangladesh’s lifeline runs dry</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/teesta-cries-for-survival-as-northern-bangladeshs-lifeline-runs-dry</link><description>Once a mighty river that breathed life into northern Bangladesh, the Teesta now lies silent and broken, as its shimmering waters replaced by stretches of sand and its flow reduced to a faint memory for the millions who once depended on it.
The lifeline of two crore people lies gasping for breath a</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 02:58:15 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>