<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 18:29:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Pubali Bank holds ‘Annual Risk Conference 2025’ to uphold excellence, innovation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/pubali-bank-holds-annual-risk-conference-2025-to-uphold-excellence-innovation</link><description>Committed to its tradition of excellence and innovation, Pubali Bank PLC strives to provide the best banking services to its customers, according to a press release.
To ensure robust risk management and regulatory compliance, the bank organized the ‘Annual Risk Conference 2025’ recentl</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 15:00:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Islami Bank receives MasterCard Excellence Awards-2025</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/islami-bank-receives-mastercard-excellence-awards-2025</link><description>Islami Bank Bangladesh PLC received MasterCard Excellence Awards-2025 in three categories, according to a press release.
The bank won the “Excellence in MasterCard Prepaid Business (Cross-Border), “Excellence in MasterCard Debit Business (Cross-Border) and “Excellence in MasterCa</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 15:15:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EXIM Bank holds Business Development Conference in Cumilla Region</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/exim-bank-holds-business-development-conference-in-cumilla-region</link><description>EXIM Bank held a Business Development Conference for the Cumilla Region on Saturday, according to a press release.
Administrator of EXIM Bank and Executive Director of Bangladesh Bank Md. Sawkatul Alam attended the conference as the Chief Guest. Regional Manager of the Cumilla Region Md. Maksudul</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 15:30:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Community Bank signs MoU with May International Trade Services</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/community-bank-signs-mou-with-may-international-trade-services</link><description>Community Bank Bangladesh PLC and May International Trade Services Ltd have officially signed a MOU at the Former’s Head Office on recently to implement Global Trade Intelligence Platform, according to a press release.
KimiwaSaddat, Managing Director (Current Charge) of Community Bank Bangla</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 15:37:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Top defaulter Sasco Tex BD’s MD Atiar Rahman Dipu, his wife Papia Rahman arrested</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/top-defaulter-sasco-tex-bds-md-atiar-rahman-dipu-his-wife-papia-rahman-arrested</link><description>Managing Director of Messrs Sasco Tex (BD) Ltd Atiar Rahman Dipu, one of the top defaulting investment clients of Al-Arafah Islami Bank, and his wife and company Director Papia Rahman were arrested last night at approximately 11:45 PM from the Mirpur Pallabi DOHS area in the capital.
On Sunday, 23</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 15:52:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Deposit Protection Ordinance’ issues to boost confidence in banking sector</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/deposit-protection-ordinance-issues-to-boost-confidence-in-banking-sector</link><description>The government has issued the ‘Deposit Protection Ordinance, 2025’ to enhance the protection of depositors and increase public confidence in the country’s banking sector.
Considering the importance of financial sector stability during the dissolution of parliament, the president</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 16:07:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hezbollah chief of staff killed in Israeli strike on Beirut, Israeli media says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/hezbollah-chief-of-staff-killed-in-israeli-strike-on-beirut-israeli-media-says</link><description>Hezbollah's chief of staff Ali Tabtabai was killed in an Israeli strike on a southern suburb of Beirut on Sunday, multiple Israeli media outlets reported, citing Israeli sources.</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 16:22:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No recession risk for US economy as a whole, Bessent tells NBC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/no-recession-risk-for-us-economy-as-a-whole-bessent-tells-nbc</link><description>Treasury Secretary Scott Bessent on Sunday said the 43-day government shutdown caused an $11 billion permanent hit to the U.S. economy, but he was optimistic about growth prospects next year given easing interest rates and tax cuts.
Bessent told NBC's "Meet the Press" program that parts of the US</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 16:37:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>COP30 deal exposes fragile climate unity</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/cop30-deal-exposes-fragile-climate-unity-as-us-steps-back</link><description>In the final fractious hours of the UN climate summit in Brazil, when a deal to advance the world's fight against global warming was slipping out of reach, COP30 President Andre Correa do Lago reminded them about the cost of failure.
This was the first international climate conference since the ad</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 16:52:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bhutan PM sends bouquet for Khaleda Zia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bhutan-pm-sends-bouquet-for-khaleda-zia</link><description>Bhutan’s Prime Minister Tshering Tobgay has sent a bouquet for Khaleda Zia, according to BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir.
The flowers were handed over around 8pm on Sunday at the InterContinental Dhaka, where a BNP delegation met the Bhutanese leader.
Fakhrul said the prim</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 17:07:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nearly 200,000 Ukrainians in US thrown into legal limbo</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/nearly-200000-ukrainians-in-us-thrown-into-legal-limbo-by-trump-immigration-crackdown</link><description>Kateryna Golizdra has survived six months in legal limbo - so far. She thinks she can hold out another six months, waiting for Donald Trump's administration to decide the fate of a humanitarian programme that allowed some 260,000 people who fled the war in Ukraine to live and work in the United Sta</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 17:22:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nearly 12,000 Afghan refugees return home in single day</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nearly-12000-afghan-refugees-return-home-in-single-day</link><description>A total of 2,102 Afghan families with 11,855 members returned to their homeland from neighboring Iran and Pakistan on Saturday, Afghanistan's High Commission for Addressing Returnees Problems said Sunday.
The commission provides temporary shelters, nourishment, water, medical care, and transportat</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 17:37:59 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>