<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 15:19:26 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>4 dengue deaths, 1,143 hospital admissions recorded in 24 hours</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/4-dengue-deaths-1143-hospital-admissions-recorded-in-24-hours</link><description>Another four people have died of dengue fever in Bangladesh over the past 24 hours, pushing the nationwide death toll this year to 263.
The Directorate General of Health Services (DGHS) bulletin released on Sunday said the latest victims included three men and one woman.
They died in Dhaka Medica</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 12:34:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Recommendations for implementing July Charter to be submitted on Monday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/recommendations-for-implementing-july-charter-to-be-submitted-on-monday</link><description>Recommendations on implementing the initiatives taken in state reforms over a year-long discussion are set to be submitted to the government on Monday.
A member of the Consensus Commission told bdnews24.com, “On Monday, the commission members led by Vice-Chairman Ali Riaz will meet with the</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 12:49:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Student drowns in Rajshahi University swimming pool</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/student-drowns-in-rajshahi-university-swimming-pool</link><description>A Rajshahi University student has drowned in the institution’s swimming pool.
The incident occurred around 5:30pm on Sunday, said the university’s proctor Mahbubur Rahman.
The victim, Sayma Hossain, was a Sociology student from the 2020-21 academic session and a resident of Mannujan H</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 13:04:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gulshan &amp; Motijheel hold 20pc of Dhaka’s bank deposits; Bhashantek has at least</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/gulshan-motijheel-hold-20pc-of-dhakas-bank-deposits-bhashantek-has-at-least</link><description>Motijheel and Gulshan areas hold the highest concentration of wealth, collectively accounting for nearly 20 percent of the total bank deposits in the country.
The combined bank deposits in these two areas amount to Tk 3,96,724.73 crore.
An analysis of latest bank deposit data across Dhaka’s</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 13:19:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Premier Bank celebrates 26 years of banking</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/the-premier-bank-celebrates-26-years-of-banking</link><description>The Premier Bank PLC proudly marked its 26th Anniversary today, Sunday, October 26, 2025, celebrating a remarkable journey under the theme "Banking for Greater Good."
The event was inaugurated by Dr. Arifur Rahman, Chairman of the Board of Directors, at the bank's Head Office in Banani, Dhaka, acc</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 13:49:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shahjalal Islami Bank signs MoU with American Wellness Center, Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/shahjalal-islami-bank-signs-mou-with-american-wellness-center-dhaka</link><description>Shahjalal Islami Bank PLC signed a Memorandum of Understanding (MoU)with American Wellness Center, Dhaka on 26th October 2025 at the Corporate Head Office of the bank.
The Managing Director of Shahjalal Islami Bank PLC Mr. Mosleh Uddin Ahmed and the Chairman of American Wellness Center Mr. Md. Mah</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 14:04:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sudan’s RSF says it captured al-Fashir army headquarters</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/sudans-rsf-says-it-captured-al-fashir-army-headquarters</link><description>Sudan’s paramilitary Rapid Support Forces said on Sunday they had captured the army headquarters in the city of al-Fashir, the Sudanese army’s last stronghold in the Darfur region in the west of the country.
A video posted by the RSF showed its soldiers cheering in front of a sign for</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 14:19:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Putin’s investment envoy Dmitriev continues talks with US officials</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/putins-investment-envoy-dmitriev-continues-talks-with-us-officials</link><description>Russian President Vladimir Putin’s special envoy for investment and economic cooperation, Kirill Dmitriev, said on Sunday that he had continued talks with representatives of President Donald Trump’s administration in the United States.
Dmitriev told Reuters on Oct 24 that he was in the</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 14:34:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>PBIL and LixCap forge strategic partnership to catalyze impact investments in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/pbil-and-lixcap-forge-strategic-partnership-to-catalyze-impact-investments-in-bangladesh</link><description>In a landmark move to connect global capital with Bangladesh's expanding opportunities, Prime Bank Investment PLC. (PBIL), a leading Bangladeshi investment bank and wholly owned subsidiary of Prime Bank PLC., has signed a comprehensive Memorandum of Understanding (MoU) with LixiaCapsiaGestionis LLC</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 14:49:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt to cut SIM limit per user before elections: Home adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-to-cut-sim-limit-per-user-before-elections-home-adviser</link><description>Home Adviser Lieutenant General (Retd.) Md. Jahangir Alam Chowdhury today said the number of mobile SIMs that can be registered under a single subscriber’s National Identity Card (NID) will be reduced before the upcoming national elections.
 “The current limit of 15 SIMs per NID w</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 15:04:26 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>