<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 22:25:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Russia slams Trump, Israel for ‘irresponsible attack’ on Iran</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/russia-slams-trump-israel-for-irresponsible-attack-on-iran</link><description>Russia on Saturday criticised US President Donald Trump and Israel for embarking on a dangerously irresponsible attack on Iran which Moscow said was plunging the entire Middle East into the abyss.
The United States and Israel launched strikes on Iran, targeting its leadership and plunging the Midd</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 16:56:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Supreme leader is alive as far as I'm aware: Iran's foreign minister</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/supreme-leader-is-alive-as-far-as-im-aware-irans-foreign-minister</link><description>Iranian Foreign Minister Abbas Araghchi said Iran’s Supreme Leader, Ayatollah Seyyed Ali Khamenei, is alive “as far as I know,” speaking in an interview with NBC following US and Israeli strikes, CNN reports. 
“Almost all officials are safe and sound and alive,”</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 17:11:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Footpaths to be cleared in an orderly way through dialogue after eid: Rabiul Alam</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/footpaths-to-be-cleared-in-an-orderly-way-through-dialogue-after-eid-rabiul-alam</link><description>Footpaths in the city will be freed from illegal occupation in a planned and orderly manner through dialogue with city authorities, traders and hawkers after Eid-ul-Fitr, said Road Transport and Bridges, Railways, and Shipping Minister Sheikh Rabiul Alam on Saturday.
He made the remarks while inau</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 17:26:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gold posts massive Tk 7,640 single-day hike in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/gold-posts-massive-tk-7640-single-day-hike-in-bangladesh</link><description>Gold prices in Bangladesh surged by Tk 7,640 per bhori in a single day as the Bangladesh Jewellers Association (BAJUS) revised rates twice on Saturday, setting the price of 22-carat gold at Tk 268,680 per bhori (11.664 grams).
BAJUS first announced a Tk 4,374 hike in the morning and later raised t</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 17:41:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka deeply concerned over safety of Bangladeshis in Middle East</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/dhaka-deeply-concerned-over-safety-of-bangladeshis-in-middle-east</link><description>Bangladesh on Saturday expressed deep concern over the welfare of its citizens in the Middle East in the wake of recent hostilities in the region including Iran.
Bangladesh has already initiated actions to ensure the safety and security of its premises in Tehran, its diplomats and other staff in t</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 17:56:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Why is anti-mosquito drive failing?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/why-is-anti-mosquito-drive-failing</link><description>Some recent media reports have highlighted the mosquito menace bedevilling life after sunset. Mosquitoes seem to be breeding unchecked in the absence of any effective eradication strategy by the city corporations and municipalities. The mosquito population is so dense in the surroundings that it ha</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 17:42:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt gambles on BB governor appointment</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/govt-gambles-on-bb-governor-appointment</link><description>The appointment of a businessman as the governor of the country's central bank has come as a complete surprise to many. Surprise, because never before a businessman was chosen as head of the Bangladesh Bank. The departure, which many consider under humiliating circumstances, of Dr Ahsan H Mansur, t</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 17:57:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Agri loan waiver and the questions it raises</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/agri-loan-waiver-and-the-questions-it-raises</link><description>The government's decision to waive agricultural loans of up to Tk 10,000 along with accrued interest for 1.2 million farmers is a welcome move to ease the burden on a vulnerable segment of the population. Small and marginal farmers usually operate with very little margin for error. They face unpred</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 18:12:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US, Israel strike Iran, targeting top leaders</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-israel-strike-iran-targeting-top-leaders</link><description>The United States and Israel carried out military strikes on Iran on Saturday, targeting its top leaders and plunging the Middle East into a conflict that President Donald Trump said would end a security threat to the US and give Iranians a chance to topple their rulers, reports Reuters.
I</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 18:27:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Challenges facing the new government</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/challenges-facing-the-new-government</link><description>Unarguably, the BNP-led government now in charge of the helm of state power is in the birth throes of new governance. Though no stranger in running a government in Bangladesh, BNP finds itself facing a new set of challenges- political, economic and geo-political. Much water has flown under the brid</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 18:42:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trumpian world order and US economy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/trumpian-world-order-and-us-economy</link><description>US President Donald Trump calls for a new world order, stating the United Nations (UN) must actively cooperate with the "Board of Peace." His remarks at Davos-2026 emphasise global stability, diplomatic engagement, and peace-focused initiatives. Trump is now being described as possibly the US's mos</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 18:57:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Iran’s supreme leader Khamenei killed in strikes, Israeli sources say</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/irans-supreme-leader-khamenei-killed-in-strikes-israeli-sources-say</link><description>Israel has confirmed that Iran’s supreme leader was killed in strikes on Saturday, according to two Israeli sources familiar with the matter, CNN reports. 
One of the sources said Israel had obtained a photo of Ayatollah Ali Khamenei’s dead body, according to the report. 
Th</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 21:00:38 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>