<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 05:44:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Labour leaders demand festival allowance, overtime facilities</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/labour-leaders-demand-festival-allowance-overtime-facilities</link><description>Leaders of the National Shop Employees Federation (NSEF) on Friday demanded festival allowances and overtime facilities for nearly six million workers employed in shops, retail outlets, shopping malls, and chain stores across the country.
The demand was raised by the federation's General Secretary</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 01:49:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Most essentials' prices soar as Ramadan begins</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/most-essentials-prices-soar-as-ramadan-begins</link><description>The prices of various essential commodities, including beef, lemon, brinjal, cucumber, onion, tomato, green chilli, dates, broiler chicken, and types of fish increased in the capital's kitchen markets with the beginning of Ramadan last week.
Traders said the demand of these items rose ahead of the</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 02:04:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CNG stations closed from 3:00-9:00pm till March 14</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cng-stations-closed-from-300-900pm-till-march-14</link><description>The government has revised the operating hours of CNG refuelling stations during Ramadan to ensure uninterrupted gas supply to the power sector during iftar.
The decision was announced in a notification, issued by the Energy and Mineral Resources Division on Friday.
According to the notification,</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 02:19:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Horrifying abuses on trafficked victims at scam centres: UN report</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/horrifying-abuses-on-trafficked-victims-at-scam-centres-un-report</link><description>A UN report on Friday detailed the grave abuses against those trafficked into scam centres from dozens of countries across the world, mostly in Southeast Asia, including Bangladesh.
Scam centres are compounds often connected with transnational criminal networks through which various criminal activ</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 02:34:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ansar-VDP Development Bank seeks 3-yr extension</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ansar-vdp-development-bank-seeks-3-yr-extension</link><description>Ansar-VDP Development Bank has sought extension of the state guarantee on a Tk 10-billion "Agriculture and Rural Credit" facility for another three years, aiming to help sustain economic momentum for marginalized communities and ensure national food security.
The Bank made the request in a letter</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 02:49:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Language compatibility in an age of AI-driven automation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/analysis/language-compatibility-in-an-age-of-ai-driven-automation</link><description>Political hegemony often imposes language and cultural hegemonies. The dismantling of colonial power following the World War II may have withdrawn the political stranglehold across the continents but the influence of the two others refuses to go. This subcontinent and the French colonies in Africa</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 03:04:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mismanagement and banking sector reform</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/analysis/mismanagement-and-banking-sector-reform</link><description>For nearly two decades, Bangladesh's banking sector has remained under persistent public scrutiny. While weaknesses in governance and financial discipline are not new, the scale and frequency of mismanagement have intensified markedly over the last 10 to 15 years. Rising non-performing loans, repea</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 03:19:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How to ensure peaceful work environment</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/analysis/how-to-ensure-peaceful-work-environment</link><description>Ramadan is a holy month for Muslims, marked by self-control, spiritual purification, and worship. However, this period also presents special challenges for industrial establishments in safeguarding workers' well-being and maintaining a healthy and balanced work environment. Long abstinence from foo</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 03:34:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Youth killed in Jhenaidah road crash</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/youth-killed-in-jhenaidah-road-crash</link><description>A truck collision in Pobhati Kalarhat area of Jhenaidah district town on Friday night left one young man dead and another seriously injured.
The accident occurred around 11:00 pm when a truck hit a motorcycle, reports UNB.
The deceased has been identified as Shanto Shahriar Rahman Shanto (31), so</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 03:53:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US Supreme Court strikes down Trump’s global tariffs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/global/us-supreme-court-strikes-down-trumps-global-tariffs</link><description>The U.S. Supreme Court on Friday struck down President Donald Trump’s sweeping global tariffs, delivering a significant setback to a central pillar of his economic agenda.
In a 6-3 ruling, the court said Trump’s use of an emergency powers law to impose wide-ranging import duties, inclu</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 04:08:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump imposes 10pc tariff on all countries</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/global/trump-imposes-10pc-tariff-on-all-countries</link><description>U.S. President Donald Trump has signed an executive order to impose 10 per cent tariffs on imported goods from all countries, according to a social media post on Friday.
The move came hours after the Supreme Court ruled in a 6-3 vote that his tariff policy under the International Emergency Economi</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 04:23:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nation remembers language heroes on Amar Ekushey</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nation-remembers-language-heroes-on-amar-ekushey</link><description>The nation is observing 'Amar Ekushey', the Language Martyr's Day and the International Mother Language Day early Saturday, marking the supreme sacrifice of the language heroes for upholding the dignity of the mother tongue, Bangla.
The day is also being observed around the world as UNESCO recogni</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 04:38:17 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>