<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 14:20:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Govt pays $360.99m for 11 cargos of LNG in Nov</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/govt-pays-36099m-for-11-cargos-of-lng-in-nov</link><description>The government has paid $360.99 million against 11 cargos of Liquefied Natural Gas (LNG) totaling around 35.2 million MMBTu in November to ensure energy security along with meeting the growing demand of the country.
“We’re importing LNG regularly under long term, short term agreement a</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 10:45:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How the US freight rail industry got dirtier than coal power plants</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/how-the-us-freight-rail-industry-got-dirtier-than-coal-power-plants</link><description>BNSF Railway, one of the crown jewels of Warren Buffett’s sprawling Berkshire Hathaway conglomerate, calls itself an environmental leader in the US rail industry with the cleanest locomotive fleet in North America.
“When you see our orange locomotives’ and freight cars’ ste</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 11:00:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Students hurl shoes at Razakar hate monument at Dhaka University</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/students-hurl-shoes-at-razakar-hate-monument-at-dhaka-university</link><description>Students have thrown shoes at the Razakar hate monument at Dhaka University on the occasion of the Martyred Intellectuals Day, observed across Bangladesh on Sunday.
On Dec 14, 1971, as Pakistan’s surrender neared during the Liberation War, its forces killed numerous intellectuals, bdnews24.c</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 11:15:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India rejects assertions made by Bangladesh interim govt</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/india-rejects-assertions-made-by-bangladesh-interim-govt</link><description>India on Sunday categorically rejected the assertions made by the interim government of Bangladesh, noting that India has never allowed its territory to be used for activities inimical to the interests of the friendly people of Bangladesh.
“We expect that the interim government of Bangladesh</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 11:30:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Family left grieving over peacekeeper Shobuj’s death</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/police-hold-person-of-interest-after-brown-university-shooting-leaves-two-dead</link><description>Providence police have detained a “person of interest” in connection with the Brown University shooting that left two students dead and another nine people wounded at the U.S. Ivy League school.
Providence’s Chief Public Information Officer for Public Safety Kristy DosReis told R</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 11:45:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka seeks India’s help to catch Hadi attackers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-urges-india-to-block-escape-routes-to-prevent-hadi-attackers-from-crossing</link><description>The interim government has sought India’s cooperation in arresting those who shot Sharif Osman bin Hadi, spokesperson of Inqilab Moncho, and in preventing the suspects from fleeing Bangladesh.
The Ministry of Foreign Affairs said on Sunday that Indian High Commissioner Pranay Verma was summo</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 12:00:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>SpaceX insider share sale sets $800 billion valuation amid possible IPO</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/global/spacex-insider-share-sale-sets-800-billion-valuation-amid-possible-ipo</link><description>SpaceX is preparing to go public next year and has opened a secondary share sale that would value the company at $800 billion, according to a letter to shareholders sent by the company's CFO Bret Johnsen and reviewed by Reuters.
The Elon Musk-led company's move towards a public listing, which coul</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 12:15:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dengue: 5 dead; 387 hospitalised in 24 hours</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dengue-5-dead-387-hospitalised-in-24-hours</link><description>Bangladesh on Sunday witnessed a sudden surge in dengue cases, with five more deaths and 387 new hospitalisations recorded across the country in the last 24 hours.
According to the Directorate General of Health Services (DGHS), the latest fatalities bring this year’s death toll from the mosq</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 12:30:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UCB holds Townhalls across 16 regions with a commitment to customer satisfaction</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ucb-holds-townhalls-across-16-regions-with-a-commitment-to-customer-satisfaction</link><description>At the same time, on the same day, United Commercial Bank held Townhalls simultaneously across 16 regions of the country.
In some regions, the bank’s Chairman was present; in others, the Managing Director, AMDs, DMDs, and senior officials led the sessions, according to a media release.
Unit</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 12:45:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hadi shooting incident hit like 'a bolt from the blue': CEC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hadi-shooting-incident-hit-like-a-bolt-from-the-blue-says-cec-nasir</link><description>Chief Election Commissioner AMM Nasir Uddin has said the shooting of Inqilab Moncho Convenor Sharif Osman bin Hadi hit him “like a bolt from the blue”.
He made the comment at the beginning of a meeting with law enforcers over election-time preparations.
Hadi, an independent election h</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 13:00:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Stocks slide on week’s opening day</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/stocks-slide-on-weeks-opening-day</link><description>Bangladesh’s stock market began the week on a bearish note on Sunday, with key indices falling on both the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) and the Chittagong Stock Exchange (CSE), as prices declined for the majority of listed companies.
On the DSE, the benchmark DSEX shed 30 points, while the Sha</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 13:15:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chile votes in presidential race expected to lurch country to the right</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/chile-votes-in-presidential-race-expected-to-lurch-country-to-the-right</link><description>Chileans will vote in a runoff presidential election on Sunday that is expected to result in the South American country's sharpest rightward shift since the end of the military dictatorship in 1990.
Nearly 15.6 million registered voters in Chile are set to cast ballots. Polls will close at 6 p.m.</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 13:30:48 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>