<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 13:01:56 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Bangladesh approves withdrawal of declaration under CAT article 14(1)</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-approves-withdrawal-of-declaration-under-cat-article-141</link><description>The government has approved a proposal to withdraw Bangladesh’s declaration under Article 14(1) of the Convention against Torture and Other Cruel, Inhuman or Degrading Treatment or Punishment (CAT) to effectively ensure compensation and rehabilitation rights for victims of state torture or en</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 10:31:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat vows solutions to Feni floods after talks with India</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jamaat-vows-solutions-to-feni-floods-after-talks-with-india</link><description>Jamaat-e-Islami chief Shafiqur Rahman has pledged to resolve the flooding in Feni through talks with India if the 11-party alliance comes to power.
He made the promise at an election rally in Feni on Friday.
“The embankments, the absence of which has caused your suffering, have not yet been</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 10:46:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CPJ urges political parties to safeguard press freedom</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/journalists-group-urges-bangladesh-parties-to-commit-to-press-freedom-ahead-of-polls</link><description>The Committee to Protect Journalists (CPJ) has written to Bangladesh’s main political parties ahead of the Feb 12 national election, urging them to take urgent steps to safeguard press freedom and ensure the safety of journalists.
In separate letters sent on Jan 29, the New York-based media</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 11:01:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Abu Sayed's family to seek justice during Tarique Rahman's visit</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/abu-sayeds-family-to-seek-justice-during-tarique-rahmans-visit</link><description>The family of Abu Sayed, the first martyr of the July 2024 mass uprising, say they will urge BNP chief Tarique Rahman to ensure the swift implementation of the verdict in his killing when he visits their village.
Tarique is due to begin his party’s election campaign in Rangpur on Friday by v</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 11:16:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCP presents ‘Manifesto of Youth and Dignity’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ncp-presents-manifesto-of-youth-and-dignity</link><description>The National Citizen Party (NCP) is announcing a 36-point manifesto ahead of the 13th parliamentary election.
The party’s election promises are being announced at a function titled “Manifesto of Youth and Dignity” at a hotel in Dhaka on Friday afternoon.
The new party, composed</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 11:31:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>53pc ready to vote for BNP; 48pc seek Tarique as next PM, survey finds</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/53pc-ready-to-vote-for-bnp-48pc-seek-tarique-as-next-pm-survey-finds</link><description>Nearly 53 per cent of people are ready to vote for BNP candidates across the country, while more than 47 per cent want Tarique Rahman as the next prime minister, a survey released on Friday reveals.
The survey titled “People’s Election Pulse Survey Round 3” was conducted jointly</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 11:46:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Corrupt Mymensingh jail staff helped free murder suspects: RAB</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rab-says-corrupt-prison-staff-helped-free-three-murder-suspects-from-myemensingh-jail</link><description>The Rapid Action Battalion (RAB) says corrupt prison officials helped three murder suspects walk free from Mymensingh Central Jail without bail documents.
RAB-14 Commander Naimul Hasan said the men were released with the assistance of “dishonest” jail staff. He made the remarks at a pr</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 11:31:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique urges voters to reaffirm Bogura as BNP bastion in election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-urges-voters-to-reaffirm-bogura-as-bnp-bastion-in-election</link><description>Tarique Rahman has urged party activists to prove that Bogura remains a BNP stronghold by voting for the party’s “Sheaf of Paddy” symbol in the parliamentary elections.
He addressed a roadside rally at Mokamtala Bus Stand in Shibganj Upazila around 3pm on Friday.
Speaking at the</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 11:46:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>10 hurt in BNP-NCP clash at Hatia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/10-hurt-in-bnp-ncp-clash-at-hatia</link><description>At least 10 people have been injured in clashes between activists of the BNP and the National Citizen Party (NCP) during the inauguration of a ferry service in Hatia, an island Upazila of Noakhali.
The confrontation broke out at around 3:30pm on Friday at the Nalchira Ferry Terminal, centring on a</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 12:01:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>China to lift restrictions on UK lawmakers, PM Starmer says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/china-to-lift-restrictions-on-uk-lawmakers-pm-starmer-says</link><description>China is set to lift restrictions which it had imposed on a group of British lawmakers, Prime Minister Keir Starmer said on Friday, meaning that they will now be free to travel to China.
Starmer made the announcement during his four-day visit to China, the first by a UK leader in eight years, aime</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 12:16:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique pays tribute at July martyr Abu Sayed’s grave in Rangpur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-pays-tribute-at-july-martyr-abu-sayeds-grave-in-rangpur</link><description>BNP chief Tarique Rahman has paid his respects at the grave of Abu Sayed, the first martyr of the July 2024 mass uprising.
Tarique began his party’s election campaign in Rangpur on Friday by visiting the grave in Pirganj Upazila's Babonpur village. He travelled to the village from Bogura aft</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 12:31:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>People to participate in election spontaneously: EC Sanaullah</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/people-to-participate-in-election-spontaneously-ec-sanaullah</link><description>Election Commissioner Abul Fazal Muhammad Sanaullah expressed optimism about the upcoming polls, saying he expects citizens to participate spontaneously and actively, reflecting the vibrancy of democracy.
“There are only 12 days left for the election. I am very satisfied with the preparation</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 12:46:38 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>