<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 10:29:18 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Verdict in Ashulia body burning case on Feb 5</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/verdict-in-ashulia-body-burning-case-on-feb-5</link><description>The International Crimes Tribunal (ICT) has set Feb 5 to deliver its verdict in a crimes against humanity case involving the killing and burning of bodies in Ashulia during the July 2024 mass uprising.
The date was fixed on Sunday by a three-member ICT-2 bench headed by Justice Nazrul Islam Chowdh</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 07:30:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India dismisses Epstein claims involving PM Modi as baseless</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/india-dismisses-epstein-claims-involving-pm-modi-as-baseless</link><description>The Indian government has rejected claims made in newly released emails from the late financier and convicted sex offender Jeffrey Epstein, calling them baseless assertions that deserve no credibility.
In a statement issued on Saturday, the Ministry of External Affairs said the references in the e</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 07:45:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Three-day Light Engineering Expo to begin in Dhaka on February 2</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/three-day-light-engineering-expo-to-begin-in-dhaka-on-february-2</link><description>A three-day Bangladesh Light Engineering Expo 2026 will begin in the capital on February 2 (Monday), aiming to make the country’s promising light engineering sector more competitive and export-oriented.
Organisers said the expo would showcase domestic industrial capacity, reduce import</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 08:00:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Travel ban imposed on DNCC Administrator Azaz</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/travel-ban-imposed-on-dncc-administrator-azaz</link><description>A Dhaka court has slapped a travel ban on Mohammad Azaz, administrator of Dhaka North City Corporation (DNCC), who is under investigation over corruption allegations.
Dhaka Metropolitan Senior Special Judge Sabbir Faiz passed the order on Sunday following an application by the Anti-Corruption Comm</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 07:49:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chhatra Dal protests Jamaat Ameer’s anti-women remarks on X</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/chhatra-dal-protests-jamaat-ameers-anti-women-remarks-on-x</link><description>Jatiyatabadi Chhatra Dal (JCD) on Sunday staged a protest march on Dhaka University campus, condemning  the offensive remarks about women made from the verified X account of Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami Ameer Shafiqur Rahman.
The protest was held in response to a post circulated on social media</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 08:04:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khulna and Jashore next as Tarique Rahman steps up election campaign</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/khulna-and-jashore-next-as-tarique-rahman-steps-up-election-campaign</link><description>Khulna and Jashore will be the next stops in BNP chief Tarique Rahman’s election campaign.
Tarique will address election rallies in both south-western cities on Monday, said Shairul Kabir Khan, a member of the party’s media cell.
According to the schedule, Tarique will leave Dhaka by</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 08:19:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Postal Vote: 157,798 expatriate ballots reach country</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/postal-vote-157798-expatriate-ballots-reach-country</link><description>A total of 157,798 expatriate ballots cast through the "Postal Vote BD" mobile app for the 13th Jatiya Sangsad (JS) election and referendum have so far reached Bangladesh. At the same time, 461,604 expatriate voters have already completed their voting.
Salim Ahmad Khan, Team Leader of the 'OCV-SDI</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 08:34:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No scope for vote rigging in expatriate voting process: EC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/no-scope-for-vote-rigging-in-expatriate-voting-process-ec</link><description>Election Commissioner Brigadier General (retd) Abul Fazal Md Sanaullah on Sunday said there is no scope for irregularities in the expatriate voting process.
“Live verification has been made mandatory and intelligence agency members will be deployed to ensure ballot security,” he said a</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 08:49:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tk 331mn in 46 accounts of former MP Nasim frozen amid corruption probe</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tk-331mn-in-46-accounts-of-former-mp-nasim-frozen-amid-corruption-probe</link><description>A Dhaka court has ordered the freezing of 46 bank accounts containing over Tk 331.9 million belonging to AFM Bahauddin Nasim, a former member of parliament, and his associates.
Dhaka Metropolitan Senior Special Judge Sabbir Faiz passed the order on Sunday following an application by the Anti-Corru</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 09:04:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP alleges voter migration in Dhaka, demands EC data</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-alleges-voter-migration-in-dhaka-demands-ec-data</link><description>BNP on Sunday alleged that an unusually large number of voters had been migrated to certain constituencies in Dhaka city and other parts of the country, and demanded constituency-wise data on voter migration from the Election Commission.
The allegation came as a BNP delegation, led by Election Ste</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 09:34:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP casts doubt on Jamaat’s hacking claim over Shafiqur's ‘misogynistic’ post</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-casts-doubt-on-jamaats-hacking-claim-over-shafiqurs-misogynistic-post</link><description>The BNP has expressed scepticism over Jamaat-e-Islami’s claim that a “misogynistic” post published from the X account of its chief Shafiqur Rahman was the result of hacking.
Jamaat said the post was made after hackers briefly took control of Shafiqur's verified X account. The BNP</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 09:49:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ex-state minister Farhad arrested over ‘corruption’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/former-state-minister-farhad-now-shown-arrested-in-corruption-case</link><description>Former state minister for public administration Farhad Hossain has been shown arrested in a graft case initiated by the Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC).
Dhaka Metropolitan Senior Special Judge Sabbir Faiz made the decision on Sunday following a plea by the investigating officer in the case.
ACC</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 10:04:19 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>