<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 21:30:57 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Fire in Banani doused after an hour</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fire-in-banani-doused-after-an-hour</link><description>A fire that broke out in a residential building in the capital’s Banani Chairmanbari has been brought under control after almost an hour of efforts.
The Fire Service received the report of the blaze around 7pm on Friday.
Fire Service spokesperson Anwarul Islam said the fire was brought unde</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 15:50:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Those who persecuted Hindus in 71 are back in elections’, says Salahuddin</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/those-who-persecuted-hindus-in-71-are-back-in-elections-says-salahuddin</link><description>BNP Standing Committee member Salahuddin Ahmed on Friday said that those who persecuted the country’s Hindu community during the 1971 Liberation War have returned in a new form to contest elections, raising concerns about the safety of all citizens in Bangladesh.
Speaking at an interaction m</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 16:05:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rohinya survivors hope ICJ find Myanmar liable for genocide</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/rohingya-survivors-expect-uns-highest-court-to-find-myanmar-committed-genocide</link><description>Rohingya survivors of the 2017 military crackdown in Myanmar expect the International Court of Justice, the United Nations' highest court, to rule the country committed genocide against them, they said on Friday.
A judgment is expected in three-to-six months' time following three weeks of hearings</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 16:37:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique questions Jamaat’s five-year alliance with BNP</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-asks-why-jamaat-was-in-alliance-for-five-years-if-bnp-was-bad</link><description>Tarique Rahman has publicly challenged Jamaat-e-Islami over its past alliance with the BNP, asking why the party remained in coalition for five years if it now portrays the BNP as “bad”.
Speaking at a campaign rally at Rangpur’s Collectorate Eidgah Ground on Friday night, the BNP</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 16:52:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCT foreign deal destabilising country: BaSaD’s Masud</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/government-destabilising-country-with-nct-foreign-deal-before-election-says-basads-masud-rana</link><description>The Socialist Party of Bangladesh’s (BaSaD-Marxist) Central Coordinator Masud Rana has said the government is destabilising the country ahead of the parliamentary polls by signing a contract to appoint foreign operators at the New Mooring Container Terminal (NCT) of Chattogram.
He alleged th</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 17:07:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BCB files GD against ‘fabricated’ fixing rumors involving president</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/bcb-files-gd-against-fabricated-fixing-rumors-involving-president</link><description>The Bangladesh Cricket Board (BCB) has strongly refuted social media claims alleging that its President, Aminul Islam Bulbul, is under investigation for corruption, labeling the rumors as “entirely unfounded, false, and fabricated.”
To combat the spread of this misinformation, the boar</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 17:08:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Europe can save the world from Trump</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/europe-can-save-the-world-from-trump</link><description>Something unusual happened at the World Economic Forum (WEF) this year which is reverberating through the corridors of power in Europe and elsewhere. The banker-turned politician Mark Carney, currently the prime minister of Canada, had the audacity to say that the emperor was naked.  Everyone</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 17:23:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Election manifestos part of nation's history</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/election-manifestos-part-of-nations-history</link><description>Though national elections are drawing closer, with less than two weeks to go, the contesting political parties have yet to unveil their election manifestos. The candidates, however, have made various commitments to voters. To what extent they will be able to fulfil the commitments, if elected, is t</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 17:38:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Playing the victim while sitting on loot</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/playing-the-victim-while-sitting-on-loot</link><description>Bangladesh's push to recover stolen assets has entered a much trickier and consequential stage with business tycoon Mohammad Saiful Alam dragging the country to international arbitration under the Bangladesh-Singapore bilateral investment treaty. Having acquired Singaporean citizenship only in rece</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 17:53:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Readying poultry sector for global export market</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/readying-poultry-sector-for-global-export-market</link><description>The country's poultry industry, despite being a leading agro-industrial sector--- which meets the entire domestic demand for poultry meat and eggs, draws a large amount of investment (to the tune of Tk 400 billion) and employs a huge workforce--- is yet to gain a foothold in the international poult</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 18:08:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique Rahman urges ‘Yes’ vote in referendum</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-rahman-urges-yes-vote-in-referendum</link><description>BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman on Friday called upon all to cast a ‘Yes’ vote in the upcoming referendum to be held together with the national election on February 12 next.
​Addressing a massive public rally at the historic Collectorate Eidgah ground in Rangpur, Tarique Rahman emphasised</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 20:07:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Charge rational interest rate on loans</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/charge-rational-interest-rate-on-loans</link><description>Government's finance division wants fixing rational interest on loans from microfinance banks as it finds the rates irrationally high in case of microcredit, taken by small borrowers, sources have said.
It specifically wants that the microfinance banks charge simple interest from borrowers inste</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 20:22:32 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>