<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 12:45:34 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Three entities under Health Ministry to be strengthened</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/three-entities-under-health-ministry-to-be-strengthened</link><description>The government has presented a major development initiative aimed at strengthening the operational capacity, administrative efficiency, and educational quality of three key government agencies under the Medical Education and Family Welfare Division.
A development project, titled “Integrated</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 11:04:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>From food to fashion, how we feel in winter in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/others/from-food-to-fashion-how-we-feel-in-winter-in-bangladesh-1</link><description>What comes to your mind when we hear the word 'Winter'? A lazy morning filled with fog, a man cycling somewhere, wearing a muffler and a shirt that barely covers his body to keep warm? Or the smell of freshly made Pitha by our mothers and grandparents? A long time care-free vacation when exams come</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 09:59:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Debapriya urges stronger govt, EC role to rebuild trust</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/debapriya-urges-stronger-govt-ec-role-to-rebuild-trust</link><description>Distinguished Fellow of the Centre for Policy Dialogue (CPD) Dr Debapriya Bhattacharya on Thursday urged the government and the Election Commission to take ‘stronger’ and more ‘transparent’ measures to restore public confidence ahead of the national election.
He made the ca</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 10:14:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two foreign firms to get 10-year tax holiday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/government-grants-sweeping-10-year-tax-holiday-to-two-foreign-firms-at-laldia-pangaon-terminals</link><description>Two foreign companies tasked with developing a container terminal at Laldia Char in Chattogram and a river terminal in Pangaon will receive up to 10 years of tax-free benefits, the National Board of Revenue (NBR) has confirmed.
NBR Chairman Abdur Rahman Khan said the exemptions fall under existing</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 10:29:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Part of Massa's UK lawsuit against F1, FIA and Ecclestone can continue</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/part-of-massas-uk-lawsuit-against-f1-fia-and-ecclestone-can-continue</link><description>Part of Felipe Massa's lawsuit against Formula One, its ex-boss Bernie Ecclestone and the governing FIA over the 2008 world championship can continue, London's High Court ruled on Thursday.
Former Ferrari driver Massa was suing for a declaration that he should have won the 2008 championship, which</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 10:44:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Stocks end week lower as DSE indices snap four-day rally</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/stocks-end-week-lower-as-dse-indices-snap-four-day-rally</link><description>After four consecutive days of gains, the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) closed the week with a decline on Thursday, as all major indices and most share prices fell.
At the end of the day’s trading, the benchmark DSEX dropped by 32 points, while the Shariah-based DSES declined by 11 points and t</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 10:59:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt clears draft law to establish separate a secretariat for SC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-clears-draft-law-to-establish-separate-a-secretariat-for-supreme-court</link><description>The interim government on Thursday cleared the draft of Supreme Court Secretariat Ordinance 2025 to set up a separate secretariat of the higher court, aiming to ensure the full independence of the judiciary.
The approval came from a meeting of the council of advisers held with Chief Adviser Prof M</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 11:14:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt mulls going to ICC to bring back Hasina, Kamal: Asif Nazrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-mulls-going-to-icc-to-bring-back-hasina-kamal-asif-nazrul</link><description>The government is thinking about going to the International Criminal Court (ICC) in Rome for bringing back fugitive convicts, ousted prime minister Sheikh Hasina and former home minister Asaduzzaman Khan Kamal from India.
"We will hold a meeting soon to decide whether we can approach the Internati</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 11:29:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BB stops direct public services at all offices</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bb-stops-direct-public-services-at-all-offices</link><description>Bangladesh Bank (BB) is set to discontinue several public services from tomorrow offered directly over the counter at all its offices.
The services that will stop at Bangladesh Bank offices include the sale of savings certificates and prize bonds, the exchange of torn or mutilated notes, and all r</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 11:44:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh launches Bench Book to strengthen judicial response to human trafficking</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladesh-launches-bench-book-to-strengthen-judicial-response-to-human-trafficking</link><description>In a significant milestone toward enhancing Bangladesh’s judicial response to human trafficking and promoting a victim-centred approach to justice, the Ministry of Law, Justice and Parliamentary Affairs, in collaboration with the United Nations Office on Drugs and Crime (UNODC) and the Intern</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 11:59:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>We don’t afford to allow any exogenous or indigenous forces: Dhaka tells CSC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/we-dont-afford-to-allow-any-exogenous-or-indigenous-forces-dhaka-tells-csc</link><description>Bangladesh on Thursday pledged its readiness to work hand in hand to ensure a “stable, secure, peaceful and prosperous” Indian Ocean region and to confront the common challenges, stressing that they do not afford to allow any exogenous or indigenous forces.
“We do not afford to a</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 12:29:25 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>