<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 05:27:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>BNP demands release of teacher held over offensive remarks about Tarique</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-demands-release-of-teacher-held-over-offensive-remarks-about-tarique</link><description>BNP on Saturday demanded the immediate and unconditional release of teacher AKM Shahidul Islam, who was arrested over allegations of making derogatory remarks about BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman.
The party made the demand in a statement, signed by its Senior Joint Secretary General Ruhul Kabi</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 02:55:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How TV shows like 'Mo' and 'Muslim Matchmaker' allow Arab and Muslim Americans to tell their stories</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/entertainment/how-tv-shows-like-mo-and-muslim-matchmaker-allow-arab-and-muslim-americans-to-tell-their-stories</link><description>Whether it’s stand-up comedy specials or a dramedy series, when Muslim American Mo Amer sets out to create, he writes what he knows.
The comedian, writer and actor of Palestinian descent has received critical acclaim for it, too. The second season of Amer's “Mo” documents Mo Najj</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 03:10:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Myanmar polls open amid civil war</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/myanmar-polls-open-amid-civil-war</link><description>Overshadowed by civil war and doubts about the credibility of the polls, voters in Myanmar were casting their ballots in a general election starting on Sunday, the first since a military coup toppled the last civilian government in 2021.
The junta that has since ruled Myanmar says the vote is a ch</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 03:25:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bus accident leaves 15 dead in Guatemala and government declares 3-day national mourning period</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/bus-accident-leaves-15-dead-in-guatemala-and-government-declares-3-day-national-mourning-period</link><description>An intermunicipal bus veered off a road in Guatemala and fell into a deep ravine, killing 15 passengers and injuring at least 15 others, authorities said Saturday, and declared three days of national mourning.
The accident happened Friday night outside the town of Totonicapan along a route known a</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 03:40:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Iran’s president says his country is in a full-scale war with the West</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/irans-president-says-his-country-is-in-a-full-scale-war-with-the-west</link><description>Iranian President Masoud Pezeshkian said Saturday his country is in a full-scale war with the U.S., Israel and Europe ahead of Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu ’s meeting Monday with U.S. President Donald Trump.
Pezeshkian said in an interview published on the website of the country</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 03:55:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>China issues draft rules to regulate AI with human-like interaction</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/china-issues-draft-rules-to-regulate-ai-with-human-like-interaction</link><description>China's cyber regulator on Saturday issued draft rules for public comment that would tighten oversight of artificial intelligence services designed to simulate human personalities and engage users in emotional interaction.
The move underscores Beijing's effort to shape the rapid rollout of consume</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 04:10:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>MoYS submits Tk 2.01b Vehicle Driving Training Project to PC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/moys-submits-tk-201b-vehicle-driving-training-project-to-pc</link><description>The Ministry of Youth and Sports (MoYS) has submitted the DPP of the Vehicle Driving Training Project (Phase II), taken at an estimated cost of Tk 2.01 billion, to the Planning Commission (PC), aiming to expand the Department of Youth Development's (DYD) driving training programme for unemployed yo</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 04:25:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Italy arrests nine over alleged Hamas funding through charities</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/italy-arrests-nine-over-alleged-hamas-funding-through-charities</link><description>Italian prosecutors said on Saturday they had arrested nine people on suspicion of financing Hamas through charities based in Italy, in an operation coordinated by anti-mafia and anti-terrorism units.
The suspects are accused of "belonging to and having financed" the Palestinian group, which the E</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 04:26:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Asaduzzaman resigns as attorney general to contest in parliamentary elections</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/asaduzzaman-resigns-as-attorney-general-to-contest-in-parliamentary-elections</link><description>Md Asaduzzaman has tendered his resignation as attorney general to the president, formally stepping down from the country’s top legal post.
Deputy Attorney General Md Jahirlul Islam Sumon told bdnews24.com that Asaduzzaman handed in his resignation letter at the Attorney General’s Offi</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 04:41:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Zubayer Rahman Chowdhury takes oath as Chief Justice</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/zubayer-rahman-chowdhury-takes-oath-as-chief-justice</link><description>Justice Zubayer Rahman Chowdhury on Sunday took oath as the 26th Chief Justice of Bangladesh.
President Mohammed Shahabuddin administered the oath at Bangabhaban at 10:30am on Sunday.
Chief Adviser Prof Muhammad Yunus, among others, attended the oath-takig ceremony which was broadcast live by Ban</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 04:56:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NBR extends income tax return deadline to January 31</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nbr-extends-income-tax-return-deadline-to-january-31</link><description>The government has extended the deadline for submitting income tax returns for individual taxpayers for the second time for the 2025–26 tax year.
According to an order issued by the National Board of Revenue (NBR), the return submission deadline has been extended from December 31, 2025 to Ja</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 05:11:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>More countries reject Israel's recognition of Somaliland</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/more-countries-reject-israels-recognition-of-somaliland</link><description>A growing number of countries on Saturday rejected Israel's recognition of Somalia’s breakaway region of Somaliland as an independent nation a day earlier, the first by any country in more than 30 years.
It wasn't known why Israel made the declaration Friday or whether the country was expect</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 05:26:01 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>