<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 08:30:22 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Meta defeats antitrust case over Instagram, WhatsApp acquisitions</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/meta-defeats-antitrust-case-over-instagram-whatsapp-acquisitions</link><description>Facebook parent company Meta Platforms defeated a US attempt to unwind its acquisitions of Instagram and WhatsApp on Tuesday when a federal judge ruled the company does not hold a social media monopoly.
The ruling gives Big Tech its first decisive win against the antitrust crackdown started in Pre</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 05:11:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Japan counts cost of China's travel boycott as tensions flare</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/global/japan-counts-cost-of-chinas-travel-boycott-as-tensions-flare</link><description>Within days of China urging its citizens not to travel to Japan due to a diplomatic dispute, Tokyo-based tour operator East Japan International Travel Service had lost 80 per cent of its bookings for the remainder of the year.
The small firm, which specialises in group tours largely for Chinese cl</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 05:26:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat, NCP, other parties join EC’s dialogue</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-ncp-other-parties-join-ecs-dialogue</link><description>Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami, the National Citizen Party (NCP) and other political parties joined the Election Commission’s dialogue on Wednesday morning as part of its ongoing consultations ahead of the next general election, scheduled for February 2026.
The discussion began at 10:40 am at th</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 05:41:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Stocks open higher at DSE, CSE</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/stocks-open-higher-at-dse-cse-1523695</link><description>Stocks opened higher at both the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) and the Chittagong Stock Exchange (CSE) on Wednesday, with most companies posting gains in the first hour of trading.
During the opening hour, DSE’s benchmark index, DSEX, gained 46 points, while the Shariah-based DSES and the blue-</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 05:56:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Japan's biggest fire in nearly 50 years ravages 170 buildings, kills one</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/japans-biggest-fire-in-nearly-50-years-ravages-170-buildings-kills-one</link><description>A fire ripped through more than 170 buildings and killed one person in a southern Japanese coastal city on Wednesday, with military and firefighting helicopters scrambling to extinguish the country's largest urban blaze in almost half a century.
Aerial footage from broadcasters showed houses reduc</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 06:11:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trade bodies concerned over condition of spinning mills</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/trade-bodies-concerned-over-condition-of-spinning-mills</link><description>Three major export-oriented organisations -- Bangladesh Garment Manufacturers and Exporters Association (BGMEA), Bangladesh Knitwear Manufacturers and Exporters Association (BKMEA) and Bangladesh Textile Mills Association (BTMA) in a meeting expressed deep concern over the condition of local spinni</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 06:26:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Accord soon to increase Dutch investment in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/accord-soon-to-increase-dutch-investment-in-bangladesh</link><description>Chief Adviser Prof Muhammad Yunus Tuesday reaffirmed his government's commitment to holding next polls early February as a Dutch met him and discussed current situation and investment plans.
The visiting Dutch Vice-Minister for International Cooperation, Pascalle Grotenhuis, commended Bangladesh's</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 06:41:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Student unions of DU, JU, RU, CU seek dismissal of teachers backing Hasina</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/student-unions-of-du-ju-ru-cu-seek-dismissal-of-teachers-backing-hasina</link><description>The ultimatum was announced through a joint-statement by the vice presidents of Dhaka University Central Students' Union (DUCSU), Jahangirnagar University Central Students' Union (JUCSU), Rajshahi University Central Students' Union (RUCSU) and Chittagong University Central Students' Union (CUCSU).</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 06:56:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Israeli airstrike on a Palestinian refugee camp in Lebanon kills 13 people, Lebanese ministry says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/israeli-airstrike-on-a-palestinian-refugee-camp-in-lebanon-kills-13-people-lebanese-ministry-says</link><description>An Israeli airstrike on a Palestinian refugee camp in southern Lebanon on Tuesday killed 13 people and wounded several others, state media and government officials said. It was the deadliest strike on Lebanon since a ceasefire in the Israel-Hezbollah war a year ago.
 
The drone strike</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 07:11:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CEC urges political parties to help boost voter turnout</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/cec-urges-political-parties-to-help-boost-voter-turnout</link><description>Chief Election Commissioner (CEC) AMM Nasir Uddin has called on political parties to help encourage voters to return to polling stations and to ensure strict compliance with the electoral code of conduct ahead of the upcoming national election.
Speaking on Wednesday at the Election Commission (EC)</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 07:26:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Court orders freeze on 45mn Meghna Bank shares belonging to ex-land minister, family</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/court-orders-freeze-on-45mn-meghna-bank-shares-belonging-to-ex-land-minister-family</link><description>The Criminal Investigation Department has received a court order to freeze approximately 45 million shares of Meghna Bank belonging to former land minister Saifuzzaman Chowdhury Javed, his brother, and others related to them.
In a statement on Wednesday, the CID said: "The action was taken followi</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 07:41:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh to forgo Victory Day parade for second year</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-to-forgo-victory-day-parade-for-second-year</link><description>Bangladesh is set to mark Victory Day without a military parade for the second year in a row under the interim government.
Home Affairs Advisor Jahangir Alam Chowdhury announced the development after a meeting on the security preparations surrounding Victory Day at the Secretariat on Wednesday.
T</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 07:56:26 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>