<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 04:16:44 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Beggars may not have a choice but the government should have</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/analysis/beggars-may-not-have-a-choice-but-the-government-should-have</link><description>Who says beggars have no choice? They surely have choices for selecting their way of drawing their would-be benevolent public's attention. The range of ways to attract notice is vastly wide. Some of those are ingenious and some others are crude or macabre and still some others are in between the tw</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 02:15:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Down the rabbit hole</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/analysis/down-the-rabbit-hole</link><description>With so much infighting around, from schoolroom killings to ethnic cleansing, the world today is a violent place to live in. More so with the rise of social media. It quickly exposes the wrongdoings that would have otherwise remained hidden under the carpet. Rich or poor, anyone can be caught unawa</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 02:30:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>What the new govt and embassies can do</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/analysis/what-the-new-govt-and-embassies-can-do</link><description>Bangladesh's economy is significantly supported by expatriates' income, or remittances. Millions of Bangladeshi workers employed across the globe enrich the country's foreign exchange reserves through their labour, skills, and sacrifice. The money they send not only supports the reserves but also p</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 02:45:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ekushey's dignity in the age of word bombs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/analysis/ekusheys-dignity-in-the-age-of-word-bombs</link><description>February 21 is the self-awakening day to the Bengali nation. Through the Language Movement, Bengalis realized that state identity is not built on religion. It is built by language and culture. This realization led to the rise of Bengali nationalism which later played a decisive role in the birth of</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 03:00:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cybersecurity bulwark to be built under aided project</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/cybersecurity-bulwark-to-be-built-under-aided-project</link><description>A security bulwark is being built around Bangladesh's burgeoning digital activity under a Tk 6.7-billion project to ensure cybersecurity against threats, hacks and heists, officials say.
The Information and Communication Technology Division (ICTD) under the Ministry of Posts, Telecommunications an</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 02:15:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BB to phase out 14-day repo from May 3</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bb-to-phase-out-14-day-repo-from-may-3</link><description>The existing repo facilities are being squeezed further as the Bangladesh Bank (BB) is set to phase out its 14-day liquidity window in a move to make banks manage funds more efficiently.
The Debt Management Department of the central bank recently issued guidelines for open-market operation (OMO) b</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 02:30:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Eid sales yet to gain momentum in capital</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/eid-sales-yet-to-gain-momentum-in-capital</link><description>Eid sales in different shopping malls in the capital are yet to gain momentum as the majority of buyers are remaining tight-fisted at the month-end amid inflationary pressure, according to traders.
They say persistent increases in the prices of essentials, such as rice, edible oil, and utilities,</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 02:45:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Plane carrying newly printed currency crashes, killing 15</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/plane-carrying-newly-printed-currency-crashes-killing-15</link><description>Lockheed C-130 Hercules cargo plane carrying newly printed Bolivian banknotes crashed Friday near the capital, leaving at least 15 people dead, injuring others and damaging numerous vehicles, officials said.
Defense Minister Marcelo Salinas said the aircraft skidded off the runway while landing at</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 03:00:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Man dies in AC explosion in Old Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/man-dies-in-ac-explosion-in-old-dhaka</link><description>A man succumbed to burn injuries following an air conditioner explosion at a house in Narinda, Old Dhaka.
The deceased, Mohammad Selim (33), passed away around 10:40 pm on Friday at the ICU of the National Burn and Plastic Surgery Institute, reports UNB.
Two others, Md. Moktar Bepari (55) and Sel</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 03:15:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jubo Dal activist stabbed to death in Khulna</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/jubo-dal-activist-stabbed-to-death-in-khulna</link><description>A Jubo Dal activist was stabbed to death in Senhati, Dighalia upazila, Khulna on Friday, police said, in an attack reportedly linked to a previous feud.
The incident occurred around 7:30 pm, reports UNB.
The deceased has been identified as Murad Khan (45), son of Khan Mansur Ali of Hajigram in Di</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 03:30:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Such wars benefit no one,’ says Bangladesh FM on Pakistan-Afghanistan clash</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/such-wars-benefit-no-one-says-bangladesh-fm-on-pakistan-afghanistan-clash</link><description>Bangladesh has not issued a formal statement on the conflict between Pakistan and Afghanistan, but is trying to persuade both sides as a friendly state, according to Foreign Minister Khalilur Rahman.
Returning from a special session of the OIC Executive Committee on Israel’s occupation of Pa</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 03:45:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Paramount to buy Warner Bros Discovery in $110b deal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/paramount-to-buy-warner-bros-discovery-in-110b-deal</link><description>Warner Bros Discovery has agreed to be acquired by Paramount Skydance in a $110 billion deal, ending a high-stakes bidding war after Netflix walked away from its agreement with the HBO Max owner.
The deal, with an equity value of $81 billion, is expected to close in the third quarter of 2026, the</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 04:00:44 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>