<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 13:12:38 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Billboard removal begins in Ctg</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/chattogram-begins-citywide-billboard-removal-mayor-says-no-pressure</link><description>Chattogram City Corporation Mayor Shahadat Hossain has launched an operation to remove illegal billboards, declaring that the port city will be cleared of all such structures.
During eviction drive at Kazir Dewri intersection around 3pm on Thursday, the mayor said no type of billboard would be per</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 09:56:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>SHUJAN questions EC on ‘hurried’ gazette after vote rigging doubts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/shujan-questions-ec-on-hurried-gazette-after-vote-rigging-doubts</link><description>Shushashoner Jonno Nagorik (SHUJAN) has questioned why the Election Commission (EC) issued the election gazette late at night without any probe, despite allegations of vote rigging and doubts over whether the election was fair.
The issue was raised on Thursday at a press conference held at the Nat</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 10:11:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>2 BNP leaders arrested over ‘assault, looting, fraud’ in Lakshmipur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/2-bnp-leaders-arrested-over-assault-looting-fraud-in-lakshmipur</link><description>Two BNP leaders have been arrested in Lakshmipur’s Raipur in connection with multiple cases of assault, looting and fraud, police said.
After being arrested on Wednesday, they were produced in court on Thursday afternoon, following four separate arrest warrants issued against them, Raipur Po</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 10:26:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ICT proceedings will go on: Tajul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/chief-prosecutor-tajul-says-judicial-process-at-ict-will-continue</link><description>International Crimes Tribunal (ICT) Chief Prosecutor Tajul Islam has reaffirmed that the tribunal’s judicial proceedings will continue, regardless of the status of the current prosecution team.
Speaking at the ICT premises on Thursday, Tajul said the government has unofficially signalled tha</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 10:41:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hero Alom detained after police ‘pursuit’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/police-chase-down-hero-alom-for-arrest-over-alleged-rape</link><description>Police have arrested popular content creator Ashraful Alom, widely known as Hero Alom, in connection with a rape case filed in Bogura.
He was detained around 2pm on Thursday from a place near the Shajahanpur Police Station on the Dhaka-Bogura Highway.
Additional Police Superintendent Mostofa Mojn</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 10:56:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UK police arrest King Charles’ brother Andrew, BBC reports</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/uk-police-arrest-king-charles-brother-andrew-bbc-reports</link><description>King Charles’ younger brother Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor was on Thursday arrested on suspicion of misconduct in public office over allegations he sent confidential government documents to Jeffrey Epstein, the BBC reported.
Thames Valley Police said earlier this month officers were considerin</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 11:11:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>PM chairs inter-ministerial meeting on tree plantation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/pm-chairs-inter-ministerial-meeting-on-tree-plantation</link><description>Prime Minister Tarique Rahman presided over an inter-ministerial meeting at the Cabinet Division meeting room at the Bangladesh Secretariat today (Thursday).
The inter-ministerial meeting was held on 'Planting 25 crore trees in five years' and the national level river-canal-water bodies excavation</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 11:26:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No action to be allowed beyond established rules: Information Minister</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/no-action-to-be-allowed-beyond-established-rules-information-minister</link><description>Information and Broadcasting Minister Zahir Uddin Swapan on Thursday said the government will not allow any action or decision to be implemented outside the Constitution and established rules.
“Decisions cannot be accepted under mob pressure. Any incident or crisis will be resolved strictly</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 11:41:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hungary considers cutting power, gas exports to Ukraine in Russian oil row</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/hungary-considers-cutting-power-gas-exports-to-ukraine-in-russian-oil-row</link><description>Hungary is considering cutting off power and gas exports to Ukraine unless Kyiv resumes Russian oil shipments to the country via the Druzhba pipeline, Prime Minister Viktor Orban's chief of staff told a briefing on Thursday.
Hungary and Slovakia, which have the only remaining refineries in the Eur</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 11:58:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BCB announces 2026 central contracts: 28 players retained, top tier remains vacant</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/bcb-announces-2026-central-contracts-28-players-retained-top-tier-remains-vacant</link><description>The Bangladesh Cricket Board (BCB) has published its new central contract list for the national men’s team for 2026, featuring a total of 28 cricketers.
Notably, no player has been awarded the highest ‘A Plus’ category in the latest grading system, which evaluates players based o</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 12:13:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Israeli forces and Hamas committed atrocity crimes in Gaza, UN report says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/israeli-forces-and-hamas-committed-atrocity-crimes-in-gaza-un-report-says</link><description>Israeli forces, Hamas and other Palestinian armed groups have both committed serious violations of international humanitarian law in Gaza and carried out atrocity crimes, a UN report published on Thursday said.
Intensified Israeli attacks and the forcible transfer of Palestinians appeared aimed at</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 12:28:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>913th EC meeting of Shahjalal Islami Bank held</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/913th-ec-meeting-of-shahjalal-islami-bank-held</link><description>The 913th meeting of the Executive Committee (EC) of Shahjalal Islami Bank PLC (SJIB PLC) held on 18th February 2026 at Corporate Head Office of the bank.
The meeting was presided over by Mr. Md. Sanaullah Shahid, the Chairman of Executive Committee (EC) of the Bank, according to a press release.</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 12:43:40 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>