<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 06:28:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>US to impose 25pc tariff on medium-, heavy-duty trucks starting Nov. 1</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/global/us-to-impose-25pc-tariff-on-medium-heavy-duty-trucks-starting-nov-1</link><description>U.S. President Donald Trump announced Monday that a 25 percent tariff on imported medium- and heavy-duty trucks will take effect on Nov. 1.
"Beginning November 1st, 2025, all Medium and Heavy Duty Trucks coming into the United States from other Countries will be Tariffed at the Rate of 25 percent,</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 03:08:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Lutfey Siddiqi holds bilateral talks with Singapore ministers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/lutfey-siddiqi-holds-bilateral-talks-with-singapore-ministers</link><description>Chief Adviser’s Special Envoy on International Affairs Lutfey Siddiqi held bilateral talks with Singapore’s Health Minister Ong Ye Kung, Foreign Minister Vivian Balakrishnan and State Minister (Manpower) Dinesh Vasu Dash at their respective offices recently.
At the invitation of Grace</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 03:23:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Udayan Express’ derails in Sylhet, snapping rail links with rest of country</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/udayan-express-derails-in-sylhet-snapping-rail-links-with-rest-of-country</link><description>The “Udayan Express” train has derailed in Sylhet’s Moglabazar, snapping the rail links between Sylhet and the rest of the country.
The accident occurred on Tuesday morning, according to Nurul Islam, manager of Sylhet Railway Station.
The train was headed from Chattogram to Sylh</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 03:38:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Singapore teachers among most active users of AI in education: survey</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/singapore-teachers-among-most-active-users-of-ai-in-education-survey</link><description>Singaporean teachers have emerged as some of the world's most active users of artificial intelligence (AI) in education, with 75 percent reporting that they use AI to teach or support student learning, according to a cross-country survey released Tuesday.
By comparison, the global average was 36 p</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 03:53:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US visa no longer a passport to love for Indians</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-visa-no-longer-a-passport-to-love-for-indians-after-trump-h-1b-squeeze</link><description>Sidhi Sharma wanted to marry an Indian citizen with a high-flying job in the United States.
But the 19-year-old medical student from India's northern Haryana state dropped the idea after seeing recent headlines about US President Donald Trump's immigration crackdown.
"I had always dreamed of sett</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 04:23:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ICT charges to disqualify individuals from Parliament, other public offices</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ict-charges-to-disqualify-individuals-from-parliament-other-public-offices</link><description>The interim government has ruled that any person facing formal charges at the International Crimes Tribunal (ICT) will be disqualified from holding or contesting for the post of Member of Parliament.
A gazette notification issued by the Law Ministry on Monday (October 6) states that once charges a</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 04:53:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique says cooling of Bangladesh-India relations reflects 'people's decision'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-says-cooling-of-bangladesh-india-relations-reflects-peoples-decision</link><description>BNP’s Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman has stressed that if his party comes to power in the upcoming national election, its foreign policy will be predicated on the principle of “Bangladesh first”.
He also believes that the chill in relations between India and Bangladesh since the</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 05:23:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BCB polls went 'beyond fixing', says former cricketer Debabrata</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/bcb-polls-went-beyond-fixing-says-former-cricketer-debabrata</link><description>Former cricketer Debabrata Pal, a losing candidate in the Bangladesh Cricket Board (BCB) elections, has alleged widespread government interference and manipulation in the voting process.
Struggling to hold back tears, Debabrata, who secured just seven votes in the race for director in Category-3,</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 05:38:32 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>