<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 12:48:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>All looted heavy weapons recovered: Home Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/all-looted-heavy-weapons-recovered-home-adviser</link><description>All heavy weapons looted from law enforcement agencies have now been recovered, Home Affairs Adviser Lt Gen (retd) Jahangir Alam Chowdhury said on Friday.
"There is no failure on the government's part in recovering weapons looted from the police. They are being recovered and will continue to be re</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 09:40:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Asim Munir appointed Pakistan’s first Chief of Defence Forces</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/asim-munir-appointed-pakistans-first-chief-of-defence-forces</link><description>Pakistan has appointed Field Marshal Syed Asim Munir as the country’s first Chief of Defence Forces (CDF), further consolidating his authority at the top of the military hierarchy.
President Asif Ali Zardari approved Prime Minister Shehbaz Sharif’s recommendation to name Munir both chi</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 09:55:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No positive response from India yet on Hasina’s extradition: Foreign Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/no-positive-response-from-india-yet-on-hasinas-extradition-foreign-adviser</link><description>Foreign Affairs Adviser Md Touhid Hossain on Friday said the government of India has not yet given any positive response to Bangladesh's request to extradite ousted Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina.
"We want Sheikh Hasina to be sent back. She is convicted, and the highest judicial institution has sent</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 10:10:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Political roadmap will be drawn up in next few weeks: Mahi B Chowdhury</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/political-roadmap-will-be-drawn-up-in-next-few-weeks-mahi-b-chowdhury</link><description>A long-term political roadmap and the fate of the nation will be determined in the next few weeks, says Mahi B Chowdhury, the son of late president AQM Badruddoza.
Mahi’s comment appeared on his Facebook page on Friday, reports bdnews24.com.
A spokesman for Bikalpa Dhara, Bangladesh, Mahi</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 10:25:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EU rare earths push is 10 years late: Boliden CEO</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/eus-rare-earths-push-is-10-years-late-and-more-needs-to-be-done-boliden-ceo-says</link><description>The European Union should have taken action on rare earths 10 years ago, the boss of Swedish miner Boliden (BOL.ST) said on Friday, commenting on the European Commission's plan to fast-track 3 billion euros ($3.5 billion) into 25 key mineral projects.
The importance of rare earth resources, poweri</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 11:15:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US sets 2027 deadline for Europe-led NATO defense, officials say</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-sets-2027-deadline-for-europe-led-nato-defense-officials-say</link><description>The United States wants Europe to take over the majority of NATO's conventional defense capabilities, from intelligence to missiles, by 2027, Pentagon officials told diplomats in Washington this week, a tight deadline that struck some European officials as unrealistic.
The message, recounted by fi</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 11:30:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EU fines X $140m over content rules; TikTok settles</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/eu-fines-x-140-mln-for-breaching-online-content-rules-tiktok-settles-with-concessions</link><description>Elon Musk's social media company X was fined 120 million euros ($140 million) by EU tech regulators on Friday for breaching EU online content rules, the first sanction under landmark legislation which will likely draw the US government's ire.
Rival TikTok staved off a penalty with concessions.
Eu</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 11:15:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Madrasa student found dead after 'rape' in Gopalganj</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/madrasa-student-found-dead-in-gopalganj-family-allege-rape-by-institutions-superintendent</link><description>Police have recovered the body of a female madrasa student in Gopalganj’s Muksudpur.
Family members of the 14-year-old victim allege she committed suicide “out of shame” after being raped by the superintendent of her madrasa, who was allegedly aided by one of the female teachers</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 11:30:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Air ambulance from Germany to take Khaleda to London</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/air-ambulance-from-germany-to-take-khaleda-to-london-flight-to-arrive-in-dhaka-on-saturday</link><description>The Qatar government has arranged for an air ambulance from Germany to take BNP Chairperson Khaleda Zia from Dhaka to London for medical treatment.
Asadur Rahman Asad, a spokesman for the Qatar Embassy in Dhaka said the aircraft is to land in Dhaka on Saturday afternoon.
BNP chief Khaleda was sch</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 11:45:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Questioning whether Tarique is voter ‘irrelevant’, says AG</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/questioning-whether-tarique-is-voter-irrelevant-says-ag</link><description>Attorney General (AG) Md Asaduzzaman on Friday said it is "irrelevant" to debate whether BNP acting chairperson Tarique Rahman is a Bangladeshi voter, despite his intention to contest the national election.
"Since he has sought to run in the election, it must be assumed he is a citizen and a voter</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 12:00:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt urges medical technologists, pharmacists to return to duty</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-urges-medical-technologists-pharmacists-to-return-to-duty</link><description>The government on Friday said that necessary processes are underway to address the longstanding demand of medical technologists and pharmacists for implementation of the 10th grade, urging them to withdraw their ongoing work abstention and immediately resume duties in the greater public interest.</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 12:15:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Putin, Modi agree to strengthen India-Russia trade, friendship</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/putin-modi-agree-to-strengthen-india-russia-trade-friendship</link><description>Russian President Vladimir Putin and Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi agreed on Friday to expand and diversify trade beyond oil and defence despite Western pressure on New Delhi to scale back its decades-old close ties with Moscow.
India, the world's top buyer of Russian arms and seaborne oil,</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 12:30:48 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>