<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 17:20:49 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Spain to investigate Meta for alleged Android privacy breaches</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/spain-to-investigate-meta-for-alleged-android-privacy-breaches</link><description>Spain’s parliament will investigate Meta for possible privacy violations of its Facebook and Instagram users, Spanish Prime Minister Pedro Sanchez said on Wednesday.
“In Spain, the law is above any algorithm or any large technology platform. And anyone who violates our rights will pay</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 14:09:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Israeli military strikes southern Lebanon after evacuation warning</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/israeli-military-strikes-southern-lebanon-after-evacuation-warning</link><description>The Israeli military carried out powerful airstrikes in two villages in southern Lebanon on Wednesday, witnesses said, pressing a campaign of near-daily attacks in the border region where Israel says it is targeting Iran-backed Hezbollah.
The Israeli military said it was striking "several Hezbolla</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 14:24:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IFIC Bank customers, employees to get special discounts at Japan Bangladesh Friendship Hospital</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ific-bank-customers-employees-to-get-special-discounts-at-japan-bangladesh-friendship-hospital</link><description>IFIC Bank PLC has signed a Memorandum of Understanding (MoU) with Japan Bangladesh Friendship Medical Services Limited to provide exclusive healthcare benefits to its customers, employees, and their family members.
The agreement was signed on Wednesday (19 November 2025) at a ceremony held at IFIC</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 14:39:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>SC verdict on caretaker govt system on Thursday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/sc-verdict-on-caretaker-govt-system-on-thursday</link><description>The Appellate Division of the Supreme Court will deliver its judgment on Thursday on an appeal challenging its earlier verdict that abolished the caretaker government system for conducting national elections.
A seven-member bench led by Chief Justice Dr Syed Refaat Ahmed is scheduled to announce t</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 14:54:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Saudi crown prince heads to a friendlier US Congress</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/saudi-crown-prince-heads-to-a-friendlier-us-congress</link><description>Lawmakers are set to meet with Saudi Crown Prince Mohammed bin Salman at the US Capitol on Wednesday on the second day of a visit to the United States that has aimed to tout stronger-than-ever economic and security ties with Washington while brushing off scrutiny of his human rights record.
Presid</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 15:09:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hartal called in Rangamati over ‘quota bias’ in primary teacher recruitment</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hartal-called-in-rangamati-over-quota-bias-in-primary-teacher-recruitment</link><description>A group of jobseekers has announced a hartal in Rangamati from 6am Thursday to 6pm Friday, alleging quota discrimination in the district council’s recruitment of primary assistant teachers.
The call came at a press conference on Wednesday afternoon at a restaurant in Banorupa under the banne</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 15:24:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP demands ROs, AROs from EC’s staff in elections</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bnp-demands-ros-aros-from-ecs-staff-in-elections</link><description>Bangladesh Nationalist Party-BNP on Wednesday demanded appointments of returning officers (ROs) and assistant returning officers (AROs) from the Election Commission’s own staff in the elections to bring a positive change in the country’s politics.
“If you show courage once to tak</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 15:12:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka-Aricha highway remained suspended for 3-hrs as brick kiln workers block road</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dhaka-aricha-highway-remained-suspended-for-3-hrs-as-brick-kiln-workers-block-road</link><description>Vehicular movement on Dhaka-Aricha highway remained suspended for three houses as the workers of different brick kilns blocked the highway protesting the government decision to dismantle the brick kilns and declared Savar as “degraded airshed” by the Department of Environment (DoE).
Wi</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 15:27:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>100 rooms of a colony burned to ashes in Gazipur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/100-rooms-of-a-colony-burned-to-ashes-in-gazipur</link><description>At least 100 rooms of a tin shed colony were destroyed in a massive fire that broke out in the Jorun area of Konabari in Gazipur.
The fire started at 5 pm on Wednesday in a room of the colony and quickly spread to the surrounding rooms. Initially, locals tried to extinguish the fire, but as it int</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 15:42:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India resumes business visas for Bangladeshis, Pranay Verma says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/india-resumes-business-visas-for-bangladeshis-pranay-verma-says</link><description>India has again started issuing business visas for Bangladeshi nationals, the Indian high commissioner in Dhaka has said.
Applications are being handled on a fast-track basis in emergencies, Pranay Kumar Verma said while speaking at an event titled “Pharma Connect” in Dhaka’s Bar</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 15:57:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>South Korean ferry with 267 on board runs aground, rescue underway</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/south-korean-ferry-with-267-on-board-runs-aground-rescue-underway</link><description>A South Korean passenger ferry carrying 267 passengers and crew ran aground on Wednesday off the southwestern tip of the Korean peninsula, triggering a rescue operation and stirring memories of a major ferry disaster in 2014.
President Lee Jae Myung, who is currently travelling in the Middle East,</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 16:12:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Returning officers should be Commission officials, not district administration: Moyeen Khan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/returning-officers-should-be-commission-officials-not-district-administration-moyeen-khan</link><description>BNP Standing Committee Member Dr Abdul Moyeen Khan today said the Election Commission (EC) should appoint its own officials as returning officers for the upcoming 13th National Parliament Election instead of relying on the district administration.
"If returning officers and assistant returning off</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 16:27:29 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>