<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 11:19:57 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Tarique leaves for 300 feet area from airport</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-leaves-for-300-feet-area-from-airport</link><description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman left Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport on Thursday afternoon for the reception venue in 300 feet area in a bulletproof bus.
The bus carrying Tarique Rahman and others departed the airport for the reception venue at 12:40 pm, where he is scheduled to briefly</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 07:02:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chattogram Royals owners withdraw on eve of BPL over unpaid dues</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/chattogram-royals-owners-withdraw-on-eve-of-bpl-over-unpaid-dues</link><description>The owners of Chattogram Royals have relinquished control of the franchise just a day before the start of the Bangladesh Premier League (BPL).
They failed to meet financial obligations to players, leaving BCB to step in and take temporary charge of the team.
The franchise owner, Abdul Kaiyum, inf</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 07:17:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique calls Yunus from airport</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-calls-yunus-from-airport</link><description>BNP leader Tarique Rahman spoke by phone with Chief Advisor Muhammad Yunus shortly after landing in Dhaka.
During the conversation, Tarique thanked the interim government for the arrangements made for his return, particularly the security measures, reports bdnews24.com.
“On my behalf and on</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 07:32:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique emotionally touches Bangladesh soil barefoot</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-emotionally-touches-bangladesh-soil-barefoot</link><description>Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman on Thursday made an emotional touch to Bangladesh soil barefoot at the airport after he was accorded a warm reception and emotional greetings there on arrival from London.
He touched down on the soil with dew-dropped grasses barefoo</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 08:03:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Party on the wrong path’: NCP leader announces resignation on Facebook</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/party-on-the-wrong-path-ncp-leader-announces-resignation-on-facebook</link><description>Mir Arshadul Hoque, the chief coordinator of the National Citizen Party’s (NCP) Chattogram Metropolitan unit, has announced his resignation in a statement on social media.
In a Facebook post on Thursday, Arshadul announced that he was stepping down from all positions within the party. He als</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 08:18:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique with his pet cat, Jebu, in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-with-his-pet-cat-jebu-in-bangladesh</link><description>Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman's pet cat, Jebu, accompanied him to Bangladesh today upon his arrival at Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport.
After landing at Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport this morning, Jebu was seen being carried in a box alongside hi</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 08:33:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique reaches July 36 Expressway from airport under tight security</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-reaches-july-36-expressway-from-airport-under-tight-security</link><description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman reached the July 36 Expressway from Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport on Thursday, travelling in a red-and-green vehicle under heavy security.
His motorcade entered the expressway at around 2:00 pm on December 25 and proceeded slowly amid tight protection pr</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 09:21:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat chief Shafiqur picks up nomination papers for Dhaka-15 seat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-chief-shafiqur-picks-up-nomination-papers-for-dhaka-15-seat</link><description>Jamaat-e-Islami chief Shafiqur Rahman has collected a nomination form for the Dhaka-15 seat ahead of the upcoming 13th general elections.
On Thursday, a delegation led by Jamaat's Assistant Secretary General Ehsanul Mahbub Zubair picked up the nomination papers on Shafiqur's behalf, according to M</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 09:36:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique expresses gratitude to all upon his return to Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-expresses-gratitude-to-all-upon-his-return-to-bangladesh</link><description>Tarique Rahman, leader of the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP), has expressed his gratitude to the nation after returning home, ending an exile that lasted over 17 years.
At 1:40pm on Thursday, while en route to a reception stage on Purbachal's July 36 Expressway, commonly known as the 300 Feet</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 09:53:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique’s return will fill political ‘vacuum’: Press Secy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tariques-return-will-fill-political-vacuum-says-press-secretary</link><description>Chief Advisor’s Press Secretary Shafiqul Alam has said the return of BNP leader Tarique Rahman will help fill a political “vacuum” in Bangladesh and make the country’s democratic transition “smoother”.
“We welcome him. He is the leader of Bangladesh’</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 10:08:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>In first Christmas sermon, Pope Leo decries conditions for Palestinians in Gaza</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/in-first-christmas-sermon-pope-leo-decries-conditions-for-palestinians-in-gaza</link><description>Pope Leo decried conditions for Palestinians in Gaza in his Christmas sermon on Thursday, in an unusually direct appeal during what is normally a solemn, spiritual service on the day Christians across the globe celebrate the birth of Jesus.
Leo, the first U.S. pope, said the story of Jesus being b</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 10:23:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP wants to build a safe Bangladesh: Tarique</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-wants-to-build-a-safe-bangladesh-tarique</link><description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman on Thursday said his party aims to build a safe Bangladesh where people of all ages and backgrounds can live without fear.
“We want to build a Bangladesh together—the Bangladesh a mother dreams of. That means a safe Bangladesh,” he said. “</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 10:38:30 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>