<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 16:34:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>CA describes DNA test of unclaimed bodies of July uprising major step toward justice</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ca-describes-dna-test-of-unclaimed-bodies-of-july-uprising-major-step-toward-justice</link><description>Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus today said that the initiative of collecting DNA samples to confirm identities of those, who were buried as unclaimed individuals during the July Uprising (2024), is a significant progress toward justice for families of those people.
“This effort to unc</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 14:00:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US seizing Venezuela-linked, Russian-flagged oil tanker after weeks-long pursuit</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-seizing-venezuela-linked-russian-flagged-oil-tanker-after-weeks-long-pursuit</link><description>The US was attempting on Wednesday to seize a Russian-flagged oil tanker being shadowed by a Russian submarine, after a more than two-week-long pursuit across the Atlantic as part of a US "blockade" of Venezuelan oil exports, two US officials told Reuters.
This appeared to be the first time in rec</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 14:15:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BRAC Bank introduces scholarship support for employees' children with disabilities</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/brac-bank-introduces-scholarship-support-for-employees-children-with-disabilities</link><description>BRAC Bank has introduced a scholarship programme to support the education of employees' children with disabilities, reinforcing its commitment to inclusion, dignity, and equal opportunity.
Under the scholarship programme, BRAC Bank will provide monthly financial assistance for each eligible child.</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 14:30:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CID arrests accused in Liza Akhter murder case after 17 months</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cid-arrests-accused-in-liza-akhter-murder-case-after-17-months</link><description>The Criminal Investigation Department (CID) has arrested an accused in the murder case of Liza Akhter, who was shot dead during the Anti-Discrimination Student Movement in the capital’s Shantinagar area.
The arrest was made after one year and five months of the incident. The arrestee is Maht</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 14:45:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>National election: 295 appeals filed against nomination decisions</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/national-election-295-appeals-filed-against-nomination-decisions</link><description>A total of 131 appeals have been filed with the Election Commission (EC) on the third day against the order of the Returning Officer to accept and cancel nomination papers in the upcoming 13th National Parliament election.
A total of 295 appeals have been filed till the last three days, EC officia</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 15:00:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>4 to die over 19-year-old Cox’s Bazar murder</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/four-sentenced-to-death-over-19-year-old-murder-in-coxs-bazar</link><description>A Chattogram court has sentenced four people to death in connection with the murder of a man over a land dispute in Cox’s Bazar’s Kutubdia 19 years ago.
Chattogram District and Sessions Judge Md Hemayet Uddin delivered the verdict on Wednesday afternoon.
Public Prosecutor of the Chatt</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 14:39:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sarjis welcomes scrutiny; calls for action against misinformation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/sarjis-welcomes-scrutiny-calls-for-action-against-misinformation</link><description>National Citizen Party (NCP) Chief Organiser for Northern Region Sarjis Alam on Wednesday said he is open to scrutiny by relevant authorities and would accept legal action if any corruption allegation against him is established through proper investigation.
“Bangladesh has several agencies a</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 14:54:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shibir-backed candidates lead top three JnUCSU posts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/shibir-backed-candidates-lead-top-three-jnucsu-posts</link><description>Tallies from 26 polling centres in the Jagannath University Central Students’ Union (JnUCSU) elections have shown Islami Chhatra Shibir-supported candidates ahead in the three top posts.
In a dramatic turn for the vice-president (VP) race, Shibir-backed candidate Riazul Islam has overtaken A</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 15:09:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CA for setting up independent institution to conduct research on power, energy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ca-for-setting-up-independent-institution-to-conduct-research-on-power-energy</link><description>Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus on Wednesday instructed the authorities concerned to set up an independent institution for conducting research on power and energy sectors, saying that it must not operate under a ministry.
“There must be a separate institution for research and developm</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 15:24:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Biman pilot faces probe after passenger dies</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/biman-pilot-faces-probe-after-passenger-dies</link><description>A passenger travelling from Sylhet to London died after falling ill on board a Biman Bangladesh flight, prompting an investigation into the pilot’s actions.
The incident occurred on Dec 31 on flight BG 201, operated by Captain Alia Mannan. Airline officials said the passenger became unwell w</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 15:39:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>LC openings surge as dollar crisis eases, but settlement remains sluggish: Bangladesh Bank report</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/lc-openings-surge-as-dollar-crisis-eases-but-settlement-remains-sluggish-bangladesh-bank-report</link><description>Letter of Credit (LC) openings for essential commodities, industrial raw materials, and capital machinery have seen a significant rise as dollar supply increased with a stable exchange rate.
For the first five months (July–November) of FY 2025-26, the overall Letter of Credit (LC) opening fo</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 15:54:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP front leader shot dead in Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/bnp-front-leader-shot-dead-in-dhaka</link><description>Former general secretary of Dhaka north unit of the BNP’s volunteer wing Azizur Rahman Muchabbir has been gunned down in the capital.
Another man, identified as Anwar Hossain, was injured in the attack.
The incident occurred shortly after 8pm on Wednesday when unidentified gunmen opened fir</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 16:09:37 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>