<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 12:40:08 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Democracy cannot be established if election is obstructed: Khosru</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/democracy-cannot-be-established-if-election-is-obstructed-khosru</link><description>BNP Standing Committee Member Amir Khosru Mahmud Chowdhury today (Sunday) said democracy cannot be established if elections are obstructed.
“The election is a correction process and filtration process. We must not obstruct the flow of this election. If we obstruct it, there will be no scope</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 09:09:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Metro rail service from Agargaon to Motijheel suspended for now</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/metro-rail-service-from-agargaon-to-motijheel-suspended-for-now</link><description>Dhaka Metro Rail service will not resume on the section from Agargaon to Motijheel on Sunday due to the collapse of a bearing pad that caused the death of a pedestrian, according to DMTCL Managing Director Faruque Ahmed told reporters at Dhaka's Farmgate.
Speaking to reporters at the site of the a</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 09:24:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Youth’s role vital in democratic transition process: Sarjis</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/youths-role-vital-in-democratic-transition-process-sarjis</link><description>NCP Northern Region Chief Organizer Sarjis Alam on Sunday said that the role of youth is essential in the process of democratic transition in the post-uprising reality.
“It was the youth who took to the streets and fought uncompromisingly against the fascist structure when people’s tru</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 09:54:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Four sentenced to death for gangrape of woman in Barishal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/four-sentenced-to-death-for-gangrape-of-woman-in-barishal</link><description>A Barishal court has handed down the death penalty to four men for gangraping a housewife in 2016.
Barishal Women and Children Repression Prevention Tribunal Judge Md Rakibul Islam delivered the verdict on Sunday.
The convicts are Russel Gazi, 44, Khokon Khan, 32, Rajib Jamaddar, 34, and Jahid Ha</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 10:24:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ADB to fund $300m in 2 projects in water supply, sanitation &amp; city region development</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/adb-to-fund-300m-in-2-projects-in-water-supply-sanitation-city-region-development</link><description>The Asian Development Bank (ADB) is likely to come up with a hefty amount of around $300 million in two projects in Bangladesh in 2027 in the cluster towns water supply and sanitation and in city region development as part of its continued efforts to improve the amenities in the towns and cities of</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 10:54:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Citizen Service Centres to deliver land services at DC offices: Land Secretary</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/citizen-service-centres-to-deliver-land-services-at-dc-offices-land-secretary</link><description>The government has taken an initiative to establish citizen service centres at every Deputy Commissioner’s (DC) office across the country to make land-related services more accessible to the public, said Senior Secretary of the Land Ministry ASM Saleh Ahmed.
“People often face harassme</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 11:09:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>What are bearing pads and why are they installed on bridges and metro lines?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/what-are-bearing-pads-and-why-are-they-installed-on-bridges-and-metro-lines</link><description>The repeated fall of bearing pads from Dhaka’s metro line -- twice within five weeks -- has stirred widespread curiosity about what they are and how they function.
Some have even asked whether a rubber-made pad could cause death upon impact. The last incident occurred on Sept 18, halting met</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 11:24:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Second metro pad collapse in a month renews alarm</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/metro-rail-fatality-reignites-safety-concerns-after-similar-pad-collapse-in-september</link><description>Metro rail authorities have gone on high alert after a pedestrian was killed when a bearing pad fell from the elevated rail line in Farmgate -- barely a month after a similar collapse disrupted train services for hours.
The accident occurred around 12:30pm on Sunday when the heavy rubber pad dropp</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 11:54:41 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>