<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 11:21:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Global growth to slow to 2.6pc in 2025: UN report</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/global/global-growth-to-slow-to-26pc-in-2025-un-report</link><description>Global growth will slow to 2.6 per cent in 2025, down from 2.9 per cent in 2024, due to growing pressure from financial volatility and geopolitical uncertainty facing global trade and investment, the United Nations Trade and Development (UNCTAD) said in a report released on Tuesday.
The UNCTAD's T</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 08:42:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Youth dies after being hit by train in Khulna</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/youth-dies-after-being-hit-by-train-in-khulna</link><description>A young man was killed on Wednesday after being run over by a train in the Daulatpur rail gate area of Khulna city.
Police said the victim, identified as Touhidur Rahman, 25, was crossing the railway line when a Khulna-bound passenger train from Chilahati hit him, killing him on the spot.
Azad Ra</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 08:57:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Helicopters to land near Evercare under SSF protocol</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/helicopters-to-land-near-evercare-under-ssf-protocol</link><description>The government has said that Army and Air Force helicopters will conduct test landings and takeoffs at two open fields near Dhaka’s Evercare Hospital, where former prime minister Khaleda Zia is currently undergoing treatment.
The members of the public have been asked not to be confused by th</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 09:12:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Man killed in Nilphamari road accident</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/man-killed-in-nilphamari-road-accident</link><description>A man was killed in a road accident at Banoful intersection in Nilphamari district town on Wednesday.
The deceased was identified as Shawkat Ali, 68, son of Jasim Uddin, of East Kukhapara in the town. Ali was the night guard of a market, reports BSS.
The accident took place on the Nilphamari-Said</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 08:45:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Against the odds, Bangladeshi female e-gamers claim their space in e-sports</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/others/against-the-odds-bangladeshi-female-e-gamers-claim-their-space-in-e-sports-1</link><description>"Women are not good with technology, let alone gaming. Gaming is for 'boys' only."- A common phrase to strike against younger girls who want to play online games. Since the advent of Artificial Intelligence, we have gone beyond many of its uses. Recently, people have been pursuing e-gaming as a c</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 09:00:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>If equality prevails, next UN chief will be a woman, says top contender Grynspan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/if-equality-prevails-next-un-chief-will-be-a-woman-says-top-contender-grynspan</link><description>Rebeca Grynspan, Costa Rica's former vice president and a frontrunner to become the next United Nations secretary-general, said that if equality triumphs over discrimination, the world body will finally see its first woman lead it.
The process to elect the next UN chief formally kicked off last we</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 09:15:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DMP files 1,853 cases for traffic rules violation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dmp-files-1853-cases-for-traffic-rules-violation</link><description>The Traffic Division of Dhaka Metropolitan Police (DMP) has filed 1,853 cases for violating traffic rules in different parts of the capital on Tuesday.
During the drives, DMP filed 272 cases under Motijheel zone, 197 cases in Wari zone, 224 cases in Tejgaon zone, 351 in Gulshan zone, 232 in Uttara</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 09:30:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt is 'well-prepared' ahead of Ramadan: Commerce Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/govt-is-well-prepared-ahead-of-ramadan-commerce-adviser</link><description>Commerce Adviser Sk. Bashir Uddin today (Wednesday) said that the government is 'well-prepared' to ensure an adequate supply of essential items ahead of the forthcoming holy Month of Ramadan.
He noted the increased LC openings for essential commodities and recent reductions in the prices of sugar,</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 09:45:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Indian cumin worth almost Tk 10mn seized in Brahmanbaria’s Bijoynagar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/indian-cumin-worth-almost-tk-10mn-seized-in-brahmanbarias-bijoynagar</link><description>The Border Guard Bangladesh (BGB) has seized 3,000kg of Indian cumin in an operation in Brahmanbaria’s Bijoynagar Upazila.
Members of BGB-25 Battalion intercepted a truck loaded with the smuggled spices in the Islampur area on Tuesday, according to Lt Col Jabbar Ahmed, the unit's commander.</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 10:00:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Students rally for Central University ordinance</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/students-protest-outside-dhaka-college-demanding-issuance-of-central-university-ordinance</link><description>Students from several colleges, including Eden Mohila College and Dhaka College, have launched a demonstration, demanding the issuance of an ordinance establishing a Central University.
They began the protest around 1pm on Wednesday, causing severe traffic congestion in the New Market area and dif</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 10:15:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two children rescued in Faridpur through 999 services</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/two-children-rescued-in-faridpur-through-999-services</link><description>Two children, aged three and a half and one and a half years, were successfully rescued after being trapped inside a locked room in Khalasidangi Baburchar under Sadarpur Police Station on Tuesday afternoon.
The incident came to light when the children's guardian called the National Emergency Servi</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 10:30:47 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>