<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 05:29:54 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Restoring investor confidence biggest challenge ahead</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/restoring-investor-confidence-biggest-challenge-ahead</link><description>As a new year dawns, an economic post-mortem of the bygone year reflects a story of resilience, reform and recalibration. While public expectations were sky-high at the outset of the interim government, the economy failed to stage a decisive turnaround over the past one and a half years. Neverthele</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 17:45:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Developing a multimodal communications system</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/developing-a-multimodal-communications-system</link><description>A baseline study carried out recently finds that Tk 3.0 trillion was spent on railways, roads and bridges to develop the country's communications system in the past 15 years without achieving the desired results. According to a report published in this newspaper on Tuesday last under the National I</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 18:00:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khaleda's passing leaves irreplaceable void: Modi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/khaledas-passing-leaves-irreplaceable-void-but-her-vision-legacy-will-endure-modi</link><description>Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi has said that Begum Khaleda Zia’s passing has created an irreplaceable void, but her vision and legacy will endure.
"I am confident that her ideals will be carried forward under your able leadership of the Bangladesh Nationalist Party, and will continue to</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 18:15:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat-e-Islami open to unity government after February vote</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jamaat-e-islami-open-to-unity-government-after-february-vote</link><description>A once-banned Bangladeshi Islamist party, poised for its strongest electoral showing in February's parliamentary vote, is open to joining a unity government and has held talks with several parties, its chief told Reuters on Wednesday.
Opinion polls suggest that Jamaat-e-Islami will finish a close</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 18:30:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Russia's Putin, in New Year address, voices confidence in victory in Ukraine</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/russias-putin-in-new-year-address-voices-confidence-in-victory-in-ukraine</link><description>Russian President Vladimir Putin used his annual televised New Year's address to rally his troops fighting in Ukraine, saying he believed in them and in victory in a war that he has framed as part of an existential struggle with the West.
US President Donald Trump is trying to broker an end to the</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 18:45:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pray for mother: Tarique</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/pray-for-mother-tarique</link><description>Tarique Rahman, acting chairperson of Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) on Wednesday appealed to all to pray for his mother and former prime minister of Bangladesh Begum Khaleda Zia.



While attending the Namaz-e-Janaza of the party chairperson at the South Plaza of the Jatiya Sangsad, Tari</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 19:00:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New Year brings no unmixed blessing</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/new-year-brings-no-unmixed-blessing</link><description>Bangladesh joins the world in hailing 2026 with cautious expectations of a socioeconomic resurgence, as 2025 draws to a close amid historic political developments and unresolved economic strains.
The passing of former prime minister and BNP chairperson Khaleda Zia cast a long shadow over the year,</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 02:45:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Revenue strain deepens as NBR turmoil dents collection in 2025</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/revenue-strain-deepens-as-nbr-turmoil-dents-collection-in-2025</link><description>The year 2025 ended with deepening concern over Bangladesh's weakening domestic revenue mobilisation, prompting economists and policymakers to warn about the government's ability to meet rising public expenditure.
The National Board of Revenue (NBR) went through unprecedented turmoil at both its h</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 03:00:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Uncertainty in politics undermines economic rebound</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/uncertainty-in-politics-undermines-economic-rebound</link><description>A mixed economic picture comes clear in the yearbook 2025 with Bangladesh having witnessed its external accounts fairly strengthened while stubborn inflation, weak private investment and deep-rooted stress in banking continuing to weigh on growth prospects.
The year opened on a firmer footing exte</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 03:15:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CCC, army to jointly build int’l-standard hospital in Ctg</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ccc-army-to-jointly-build-intl-standard-hospital-in-ctg</link><description>Chattogram City Corporation (CCC) and the Bangladesh Army will jointly build an "international-standard" hospital in the port city, aiming to provide quality healthcare at affordable costs to the general public.
The announcement came on Tuesday at the seventh general meeting of the committee forme</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 03:30:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Market likely to rebound in 2026 with clouds clearing over politics, economy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/market-likely-to-rebound-in-2026-with-clouds-clearing-over-politics-economy</link><description>Bangladesh's capital market is expected to see a year of resurgence in 2026 from its current rock-bottom level, aided by political stability and macroeconomic recovery following the parliamentary election scheduled for February 12.
The year 2025 proved challenging for the country's capital market,</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 04:32:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Three die in Dhaka road accidents</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/three-die-in-dhaka-road-accidents</link><description>Three people have been killed in separate road accidents in Dhaka.
Two of them died when an autorickshaw and a motorcycle collided head-on near the Mouchak Flyover, while a policeman was killed when a covered van rammed his motorcycle on the Khilgaon Flyover, bdnews24.com reports.
The Mouchak acc</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 04:47:16 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>