<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 11:37:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Prime Bank signs deal with Go Girls to offer travel package for women customers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/prime-bank-signs-deal-with-go-girls-to-offer-travel-package-for-women-customers</link><description>Prime Bank PLC. has signed a strategic agreement with Go Girls, enabling the bank’s Women Customers to enjoy exclusive discounts on travel packages.
In this regards a signing ceremony was held recently at the bank’s corporate office in Gulshan, according to a media release. 
As p</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 09:17:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Salahuddin accuses Jamaat of backing vested quarter trying to disrupt election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/salahuddin-accuses-jamaat-of-backing-vested-quarter-trying-to-disrupt-election</link><description>BNP senior leader Salahuddin Ahmed, on Saturday, in an oblique reference, accused Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami of siding with a vested quarter trying to create political unrest and obstruct the next national election.
"We are suspecting that this political party (Jamaat) is working in support of for</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 09:32:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Midland Bank signs MoU with Ifad Auto</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/midland-bank-signs-mou-with-ifad-auto</link><description>Midland Bank PLC. signed a Memorandum of Understanding (MoU) with IFAD Motors Ltd., the country’s authorized distributor and manufacturer of Royal Enfield motorcycles in Bangladesh.
The MoU signing ceremony was held at the Bank’s Head Office in Gulshan-2, Dhaka on September 23, 2025, a</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 10:02:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gill takes charge as India’s new ODI captain, Rohit stays in squad</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/gill-takes-charge-as-indias-new-odi-captain-rohit-stays-in-squad</link><description>India have appointed Shubman Gill as the new captain of the ODI side, replacing Rohit Sharma. The decision came right ahead of the series against Australia.
Despite losing the captaincy, Rohit remains in the squad alongside Virat Kohli.
Both senior batters are returning to international cricket f</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 10:17:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BGB-BSF's commander-level meeting held at Maheshpur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bgb-bsfs-commander-level-meeting-held-at-maheshpur</link><description>A battalion commander level meeting of Border Guard Bangladesh (BGB) and Indian Border Security Force (BSF) was held today at the Maheshpur border in the district to prevent border killing and smuggling.
The meeting was held around 8 am at the Zero Line adjacent to the border pillar 53 in the Mati</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 10:08:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>22-day ban: Nearly 100 tonnes of hilsa sold overnight in Faridpur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/22-day-ban-nearly-100-tonnes-of-hilsa-sold-overnight-in-faridpur</link><description>Around 100 tonnes of hilsa were sold from Friday night to Saturday morning as a nightlong Hilsa fair was held under the Hashamdia Flyover in Bhanga municipality of Faridpur district.
A huge crowd of buyers from nearby upazilas were seen in the fair as a 22-day nationwide ban on hilsa fishing began</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 10:38:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dengue: 1 more death, 374 cases reported in 24 hours</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dengue-1-more-death-374-cases-reported-in-24-hours</link><description>One more death from dengue was  reported in the 24 hours till Saturday morning as Bangladesh continues to grapple with a surge in infections.
With the latest fatalities, the total number of deaths from the mosquito-borne disease in Bangladesh has risen to 203 this year, according to the Direc</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 10:53:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>All vessels approaching Gaza together after regrouping in middle of sea: Shahidul Alam</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/all-vessels-approaching-gaza-together-after-regrouping-in-middle-of-sea-shahidul-alam</link><description>Bangladeshi photographer Shahidul Alam has said the vessel Conscience, a participant of Gaza-bound vessels under the global initiative Freedom Flotilla Coalition (FFC) and Thousands Madleens to Gaza (TMTG), is now approaching together to Gaza together with other boats in the initiative.
In a Faceb</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 11:23:43 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>