<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 13:24:57 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Community Bank holds AML &amp; CFT Conference 2025</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/community-bank-holds-aml-cft-conference-2025</link><description>Community Bank Bangladesh PLC. organized its Annual AML &amp; CFT Conference 2025 with the active participation of officials from across the Bank. The day-long conference was held on Saturday (1 November 2025).
Mr. Md. Mofizur Rahman Khan Chowdhury, Head (Acting) of the Bangladesh Financial Intelligen</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 11:22:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Suha Travels Thailand brings surprise to medical tourism</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/suha-travels-thailand-brings-surprise-to-medical-tourism</link><description>Suha Travels Thailand has brought a new surprise to medical tourism at the 13th Bangladesh Travel and Tourism Fair (BTTF) being held at Bangladesh-China Friendship Conference Center in the capital.
The company has brought the services of 15 renowned hospitals in Thailand to its fingertips. It has</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 11:37:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UN chief calls for justice for crimes against journalists</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/un-chief-calls-for-justice-for-crimes-against-journalists</link><description>United Nations Secretary-General António Guterres has said that journalists around the world face growing dangers while searching for the truth, including verbal abuse, legal threats, physical attacks, imprisonment, and torture.
“Some are even killed,” he said in his message mar</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 11:52:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UGC and British Council sign agreement at House of Lords to improve quality of education</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ugc-and-british-council-sign-agreement-at-house-of-lords-to-improve-quality-of-education</link><description>A partnership agreement has been signed between the Higher Education Acceleration and Transformation (HEAT) project, being implemented by University Grants Commission (UGC) of Bangladesh and the British Council to enhance the quality of education in Bangladesh’s higher education sector.
This</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 12:07:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>'Poor governance' led to regime changes in Bangladesh: India's security chief</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/poor-governance-led-to-regime-changes-in-bangladesh-indias-security-chief</link><description>India’s National Security Advisor Ajit Doval has said changes of government in Bangladesh, Nepal, and Sri Lanka over the past three and a half years stemmed from “poor governance”, reports bdnews24.com, citing The Hindu.
On Friday, he described governance as the central pillar of</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 12:22:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt moves to make SMEs a driving force of economy: CA’s office</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/govt-moves-to-make-smes-a-driving-force-of-economy-cas-office</link><description>Four consecutive high-level meetings of the Investment Coordination Committee (ICC) have been held as part of a major initiative to position the Small and Medium Enterprise (SME) sector as a core driver of the national economy.
Key reforms and decisions are underway, with several significant polic</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 12:09:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mercantile Bank signs agreement with Esquire Electronics</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/mercantile-bank-signs-agreement-with-esquire-electronics</link><description>Mercantile Bank PLC has signed a cash management agreement with Esquire Electronics Limited at the bank’s Head Office on Thursday (30/10/2025).
Managing Director of Esquire Electronics Arifur Rahman and Dr. Md Zahid Hossain, DMD and CBO of the bank signed the agreement on behalf of respectiv</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 12:39:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BCB retains Shanto as Test captain despite resignation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/cricket/bcb-retains-shanto-as-test-captain-despite-resignation</link><description>Time has eased the tensions, and the Bangladesh Cricket Board has persuaded Najmul Hossain Shanto to continue leading the Test team.
The batsman, who had resigned from captaincy four months ago, has agreed to remain at the helm, sparing the board from selecting a new leader.
On Saturday, BCB anno</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 12:54:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prime Bank signs payroll agreement with SQ Lights Ltd</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/prime-bank-signs-payroll-agreement-with-sq-lights-ltd</link><description>Prime Bank PLC, one of the leading private commercial banks in Bangladesh renowned for its innovative and customer-centric financial solutions, has recently signed a Payroll Agreement with SQ Lights Ltd. at the bank’s Corporate Office in Dhaka.
Under this agreement, employees of SQ Lights Lt</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 13:09:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Standard Bank holds its 419th board meeting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/standard-bank-holds-its-419th-board-meeting</link><description>The 419th Board Meeting of Shari'ah-based bank, Standard Bank PLC. was held on 30 October 2025 at the bank’s Boardroom, Head Office, Dhaka.
Chairman of the Board of Directors Mohammed Abdul Aziz presided over the meeting, according to a press release. 
It was attended by Vice Chairman</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 13:24:57 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>