<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 10:20:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Indian court tells doctors to fix their handwriting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/others/indian-court-tells-doctors-to-fix-their-handwriting</link><description>At a time when most people use keyboards to write, does handwriting really matter?
Yes, say Indian courts, if the writer is a doctor.
Jokes around the notoriously bad handwriting of many doctors that can only be deciphered by pharmacists are common in India, as around the world. But the latest or</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 07:26:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Malaysia targets 300,000 tourists from Bangladesh in 2026</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/malaysia-targets-300000-tourists-from-bangladesh-in-2026</link><description>Malaysia has unveiled an ambitious plan to attract 47 million international visitors, including 300,000 from Bangladesh, next year under its flagship Visit Malaysia 2026 campaign, aiming to boost regional tourism and strengthen global connectivity.
Malaysian Deputy Minister of Tourism, Arts and Cu</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 07:41:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Wherever you are, be a part of history by voting': CEC tells expats</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/wherever-you-are-be-a-part-of-history-by-voting-cec-tells-bangladeshi-expats</link><description>For the first time, Bangladeshi expatriates will be able to cast their votes in national elections through a newly introduced digital system, Chief Election Commissioner (CEC) AMM Nasir Uddin has revealed.
In a video message to expatriates broadcast on the Election Commission’s YouTube chann</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 08:11:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pope Leo criticises 'inhuman' treatment of immigrants in US</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/pope-leo-criticises-inhuman-treatment-of-immigrants-in-us</link><description>Pope Leo on Tuesday appeared to offer his strongest criticism yet of US President Donald Trump's hard-line immigration policies, questioning whether they were in line with the Catholic Church's pro-life teachings.
"Someone who says I am against abortion but I am in agreement with the inhuman treat</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 08:08:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Couple killed in lightning strike in Kurigram</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/couple-killed-in-lightning-strike-in-kurigram</link><description>A couple was killed in a lightning strike at Saheber Alga village in Ulipur upazila of Kurigram district on Tuesday night.
The deceased were identified as Jahangir Hossain, 42, a farmer and his wife, Rubi Begum, 35, of the village, reports UNB.
Quoting local people, Md Zillur Rahman, officer-in-c</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 08:38:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Air chief leaves for Turkey</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/air-chief-leaves-for-turkey</link><description>Chief of Air Staff Air Marshal Hasan Mahmood Khan left Dhaka on Wednesday for a five-day official visit to Turkey at the invitation of the Commander of the Turkish Air Force.
According to the Inter-Services Public Relations (ISPR), the visit, scheduled from October 1 to 5, will include meetings wi</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 08:53:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Durga Puja and the city's festival of light and life</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/culture/durga-puja-and-the-citys-festival-of-light-and-life</link><description>As the dhak drums beat louder and the smell of incense lingers in the air, Dhaka seems to put on a new skin in autumn. The capital, so often weary with traffic jams, dust, and endless work, suddenly bursts into colour and light. Durga Puja, the largest Sanatani festival in Bangladesh, is not just a</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 09:08:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Taste of home: Global dishes with local ingredients in Dhaka streets</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/food/taste-of-home-global-dishes-with-local-ingredients-in-dhaka-streets</link><description>Walk down almost any street in Dhaka and the change is hard to miss. Every corner of this city is filled with a variety of restaurants-Dumplings steam in roadside stalls.
Sushi rolls appear in small restaurants. Burgers are sold alongside French fries. Global cuisine has been a staple of the city'</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 09:23:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt seeks public opinions on pay scale reform</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-seeks-public-opinions-on-pay-scale-reform</link><description>The government is soliciting opinions from the public and stakeholders to make revisions to the national pay scale that are widely acceptable.
A panel formed to review the existing structure has prepared four separate questionnaires to gather opinions online with the aim of making recommendations</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 09:38:17 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>