<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 15:22:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Venezuela’s oil facilities unscathed in US strike, sources say</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/venezuelas-oil-facilities-unscathed-in-us-strike-sources-say</link><description>Venezuela's state-run oil production and refining were operating normally on Saturday and suffered no damage from a US strike to extract the country's president, two sources with knowledge of the operations of energy company PDVSA said.
US forces captured President Nicolas Maduro, US President Don</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 12:48:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>World reacts to US strikes on Venezuela</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/world-reacts-to-us-strikes-on-venezuela</link><description>Following are reactions to Saturday's US strikes on Venezuela.
RUSSIA FOREIGN MINISTRY
"This morning, the United States committed an act of armed aggression against Venezuela. This is deeply concerning and condemnable."
"The pretexts used to justify such actions are unfounded. Ideological animos</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 13:03:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shocked Venezuelans hunker down, unsure of what comes next</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/shocked-venezuelans-hunker-down-unsure-of-what-comes-next</link><description>Venezuelan security forces patrolled largely empty streets at dawn in the capital, Caracas, on Saturday, hours after loud explosions woke residents to the news that US commandos had bombed the country and captured President Nicolas Maduro.
Streets close to the Miraflores presidential palace were d</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 13:18:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Mobs’ being used to cancel nominations: Manna</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/mobs-being-used-to-cancel-nominations-manna</link><description>Mahmudur Rahman Manna, president of the Nagorik Oikko, has alleged that valid nominations are being cancelled “by force and by creating mobs”.
He made the complaint on Saturday evening after leaving the returning officer’s office in Segunbagicha, Dhaka.
The Nagorik Oikko chief s</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 13:33:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rastro Songskar’s Hasnat Kaiyum knocked out of Kishoreganj-5 race after scrutiny</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/rastro-songskars-hasnat-kaiyum-knocked-out-of-kishoreganj-5-race-after-scrutiny</link><description>Hasnat Kaiyum, chief coordinator of Rastro Songskar Andolan, has been ruled ineligible to run for parliament from the Kishoreganj-5 constituency.
Independent aspirant Sheikh Mujibur Rahman Iqbal, president of the Upazila unit of the BNP, has also been barred from standing for that seat, bdnews24.c</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 13:48:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt committed to ensuring justice in Osman Hadi murder: Foreign adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-committed-to-ensuring-justice-in-osman-hadi-murder-foreign-adviser</link><description>Foreign Affairs Adviser Md Touhid Hossain has said that the government is committed to bringing those involved in the murder of Osman Hadi to justice.
The adviser said, "The process is continuing to complete the trial as quickly as possible."
“We cannot rush the judicial process. We are try</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 14:03:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Family moved by nation’s outpouring of grief for Khaleda Zia: Tarique</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/family-moved-by-nations-outpouring-of-grief-for-khaleda-zia-tarique</link><description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman said on Saturday his family has been deeply moved by the continued outpouring of condolences and prayers from across the country and abroad following the death of his mother and former Prime Minister Khaleda Zia.
In a post on his official Facebook page, “As</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 14:18:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Venezuela vice president Rodriguez in Russia, four sources say</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/venezuela-vice-president-rodriguez-in-russia-four-sources-say</link><description>Venezuelan Vice President Delcy Rodriguez is in Russia, four sources familiar with her movements said on Saturday, after President Donald Trump said President Nicolas Maduro had been seized by US forces after an attack on the country.
Her brother, Jorge Rodriguez, the head of the national assembly</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 14:22:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Wahiduzzaman promoted to director of Bangladesh Bank</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/wahiduzzaman-promoted-to-director-of-bangladesh-bank</link><description>Wahiduzzaman Sardar, previously serving as additional director, has been promoted to the position of director (Research) at Bangladesh Bank.
The central bank’s Human Resources Department-1 issued an official notification regarding the promotion on Thursday, January 1.
Wahiduzzaman began his</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 14:37:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Brazil says US crossed 'unacceptable line' over military strikes on Venezuela</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/brazil-says-us-crossed-unacceptable-line-over-military-strikes-on-venezuela</link><description>Brazil's President Luiz Inacio Lula da Silva on Saturday condemned the U.S. military attack on neighbor Venezuela and the capture of his Venezuelan counterpart Nicolas Maduro, saying it crossed "an unacceptable line."
 
"These acts represent a grave affront to Venezuela's sovereignty and yet</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 14:52:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Advisor Fouzul to meet stakeholders amid LPG market volatility</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/advisor-fouzul-to-meet-stakeholders-amid-lpg-market-volatility</link><description>The price of a 12 kg LPG cylinder, officially fixed at Tk 1,253, has climbed by nearly Tk 1,000 in parts of Dhaka, leaving household users struggling as supplies tighten across the capital.
Against this backdrop, Power and Energy Advisor Fouzul Kabir Khan has said he will sit in discussions with s</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 15:07:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>JCD vows to confront conspiracies under Tarique Rahman’s leadership</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jcd-vows-to-confront-conspiracies-under-tarique-rahmans-leadership</link><description>Bangladesh Jatiyatabadi Chhatra Dal (JCD) President Rakibul Islam Rakib on Saturday said the organisation would firmly confront all ongoing conspiracies against the country under the leadership of BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman.
He made the remarks after paying tribute and offering prayers at</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 15:22:12 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>