<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 15:19:41 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Germany's Merz doubts Trump's Ukraine plan deadline can be met</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/germanys-merz-doubts-trumps-ukraine-plan-deadline-can-be-met</link><description>German Chancellor Friedrich Merz said on Sunday that he is not convinced that a solution agreeable to Ukraine based on the United States' 28-point plan will be found by the deadline set by President Donald Trump.
"Today is Sunday. President Trump's plan is to reach an agreement on Thursday. We are</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 13:15:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BGMEA for immediate inspection of factories</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bgmea-for-immediate-inspection-of-factories</link><description>The Bangladesh Garment Manufacturers and Exporters Association (BGMEA) advised its members to immediately inspect their factory buildings for any structural flaws following Friday's earthquake, warning of possible aftershocks and urging factories to strengthen safety systems.
In a notification iss</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 13:30:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pope Leo appeals for release of 315 kidnapped from Nigeria school</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/africa/pope-leo-appeals-for-release-of-315-kidnapped-from-nigeria-school</link><description>Pope Leo asked on Sunday for the immediate release of children and staff abducted this week from a Catholic school in Nigeria, one of the worst mass kidnappings ever recorded there.
Gunmen in Nigeria kidnapped students and teachers from St Mary's school in the northwest of the country on Friday, t</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 12:15:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>2 killed in Chuadanga road crash</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/2-killed-in-chuadanga-road-crash</link><description>Two people were killed and two others injured when a bus hit a van at Alukdia in Sadar upazila of Chuadanga district on Sunday.
The deceased were identified as Parvina Khatun, 45, wife of Raju Ahmed and Ramjan, 28, of Kacharipara village.
The accident occurred around 1pm when the Meherpur-bound b</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 12:30:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP will never compromise on core principles of Islam: Tarique Rahman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-will-never-compromise-on-core-principles-of-islam-tarique-rahman</link><description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman on Sunday said that his party has never compromised on the core principles of Islam and will not do so in the future.
"BNP has never compromised on the core principles or fundamental beliefs of Islam and we will not do so in the future, Insha'Allah," he said.
Ta</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 12:45:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nestlé Bangladesh’s Director ASM Hafizul Islam awarded ‘Chief Business Officer of the Year’ by Bangladesh Brand forum</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/nestle-bangladeshs-director-asm-hafizul-islam-awarded-chief-business-officer-of-the-year-by-bangladesh-brand-forum</link><description>Nestlé Bangladesh's Director of Nutrition &amp; Dairy Business, Mr. ASM Hafizul Islam, has been awarded the prestigious 'Chief Business Officer/Business Director of the Year' at the Bangladesh C-Suite Awards 2025, organized by the Bangladesh Brand Forum.
This esteemed accolade recognizes except</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 13:00:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US, Ukrainian and European officials meet in Geneva for talks on peace plan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-ukrainian-and-european-officials-meet-in-geneva-for-talks-on-peace-plan</link><description>Ukrainian, U.S. and European officials gathered in Geneva on Sunday to discuss a draft plan presented by Washington to end the war in Ukraine, after Kyiv and its allies voiced alarm over what they saw as major concessions to the aggressor Russia.
On Friday, U.S. President Donald Trump said Ukraini</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 13:15:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka Medical College suspends academic activities till Nov 29 amid quake fear</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dhaka-medical-college-suspends-academic-activities-till-nov-29-amid-quake-fear</link><description>Dhaka Medical College has suspended all academic activities until November 29 amid fear following the recent earthquakes.
A notice, signed by Prof Dr Md Kamrul Alam, Principal of Dhaka Medical College, was issued in this regard on Sunday, UNB reports. 
According to the notice, an emergency m</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 13:30:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Remittance inflow crosses $2.13bn in 22 days of November</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/remittance-inflow-crosses-213bn-in-22-days-of-november</link><description>Bangladesh received US$2.13 billion in remittances during the first 22 days of November, according to updated figures released by Bangladesh Bank on Sunday.
With this, the total remittance inflow for the ongoing fiscal year (FY 2025-26) reached $12.28 billion between July and November 22.
The cou</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 13:45:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>32,000 headmaster posts vacant in primary schools: Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/32000-headmaster-posts-vacant-in-primary-schools-adviser</link><description>Primary and Mass Education Adviser Professor Dr Bidhan Ranjan Roy Poddar on Sunday said nearly 32,000 headmaster posts are vacant in primary schools in the country, which is creating a major obstacle in school management.
He told reporters after inaugurating the newly constructed playground of Bag</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 14:00:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Israeli military says it struck Hezbollah militant in Beirut's southern suburbs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/israeli-military-says-it-struck-hezbollah-militant-in-beiruts-southern-suburbs</link><description>The Israeli military said on Sunday that it struck a militant from the Lebanese Iran-aligned Hezbollah group in the capital Beirut's southern suburbs.
The strike hit a main road in Beirut’s southern suburbs, where residents told Reuters they heard the roar of warplanes before the blast.
Peo</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 14:15:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Army chief meets Pakistan’s HIT chairman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/army-chief-meets-pakistans-hit-chairman</link><description>Pakistan’s Heavy Industries Taxila (HIT) Chairman Lt Gen Shakir Ullah Khattak has met with Chief of Army Staff Gen Waker-Uz-Zaman in Dhaka.
The meeting took place at Army Headquarters in the capital on Sunday, according to a post on the verified Facebook page of the Bangladesh Army.
During</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 14:30:45 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>