<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 10:26:17 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Crude bomb detonated in front of Grameen Bank headquarters</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crude-bomb-detonated-in-front-of-grameen-bank-headquarters</link><description>A crude explosive has been detonated in front of the Garmeen Bank main branch in Dhaka’s Mirpur, reports bdnews24.com.
The incident occurred around 3:45am on Monday, according to Sajjad Roman, chief of Mirpur Model Police Station.
“We looked at the CCTV footage and saw two people come</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 06:36:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Indonesia grants national hero status to late strongman President Suharto</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/indonesia-grants-national-hero-status-to-late-strongman-president-suharto</link><description>Indonesia awarded the title of national hero on Monday to late President Suharto, who was forced out of office in 1998 by violent protests that ended a three-decade rule marred by accusations of mass human rights violations, corruption and nepotism.
The title was conferred in a ceremony presided o</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 06:51:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No records of JUCSU fund kept for 30 years</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/no-records-of-jucsu-fund-kept-for-30-years</link><description>For nearly three decades, students of Jahangirnagar University have been contributing fees to the Jahangirnagar University Central Students' Union (JUCSU) fund, but the university treasury holds no comprehensive financial records of the fund, states JUCSU General Secretary Mazharul Islam.
He made</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 07:06:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Delhi police detain dozens in anti-pollution protests</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/delhi-police-detain-dozens-in-anti-pollution-protests</link><description>Indian police detained dozens of people during a rare protest at the famed India Gate monument in New Delhi demanding action to curb an annual scourge of toxic air swathing the capital and its surrounding region.
Sunday's protest by crowds of all ages holding banners and chanting slogans before po</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 07:21:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC Anwarul Islam declares ‘Jihad’ to hold elections in February</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-anwarul-islam-declares-jihad-to-hold-elections-in-february</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has announced a 'Jihad' (all-out war) to hold a free and fair election, as the future of the country depends on the polls, said EC Commissioner Md. Anwarul Islam Sarker.
Speaking at a daylong workshop titled 'Identifying Challenges and Solutions for Polling Officials i</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 07:01:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Eleven found dead in Thai-Malaysia search after Rohingya migrant boat sinks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/eleven-found-dead-in-thai-malaysia-search-after-rohingya-migrant-boat-sinks</link><description>The number of people confirmed dead after a boat carrying members of Myanmar's persecuted Rohingya community sank near the Thailand-Malaysia border rose to 11 on Monday, authorities said, with about 70 people believed to have been on board the capsized vessel.
The status of another boat carrying 2</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 07:16:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>34 Awami League leaders, activists arrested from different parts of Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/34-awami-league-leaders-activists-arrested-from-different-parts-of-dhaka</link><description>Police have arrested 34 leaders and activists of the banned Awami League and its affiliate organisations in raids in different parts of Dhaka.
The Dhaka Metropolitan Police (DMP) said in a statement that they were arrested in multiple raids by the Detective Branch (DB) on Sunday night.
The DMP sa</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 07:31:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Appellate Division upholds bail for Latif Siddique</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/appellate-division-upholds-bail-for-latif-siddique</link><description>The Appellate Division has upheld the High Court’s bail order for former minister Abdul Latif Siddique in a case filed under the Anti-Terrorism Act.
The three-member appellate bench led by Justice Zubair Rahman Chowdhury issued the order, scrapping the motion to deny the bail submitted by th</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 07:46:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh Bank Deputy Director reported missing</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-bank-deputy-director-reported-missing</link><description>Naim Rahman, Deputy Director of Bangladesh Bank, has been reported missing since Sunday, raising concerns over his well-being.
According to mobile tracking data, Naim Rahman’s last known location was in the Sayedabad area of Dhaka at 12:53 pm on Sunday. Since then, there has been no contact</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 08:01:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Stocks dip sharply at opening as DSE, CSE see big decline</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/stocks-dip-sharply-at-opening-as-dse-cse-see-big-decline</link><description>Trading at the country's two major bourses - the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) and the Chittagong Stock Exchange (CSE) - began on Monday with a sharp decline, as most company shares slipped during the first hour of trading.
The DSE's key index, DSEX, dropped by 19 points, while the Shariah-based DSES</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 08:16:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>When rivers swallow land: Bangladesh’s endless battle with erosion</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/when-rivers-swallow-land-bangladeshs-endless-battle-with-erosion</link><description>On an overcast morning, Nurun Nabi loads bamboo poles and tin sheets onto a wooden boat. His home, built just a year ago on a fragile island in the Brahmaputra River, is on the verge of being swallowed by water.
It is the second time the farmer and father of four has had to move in a year.
"The r</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 08:31:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Press secretary warns of crackdown on banned Awami League’s street protests</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/press-secretary-warns-of-crackdown-on-banned-awami-leagues-street-protests</link><description>Shafiqul Alam, the press secretary to Chief Advisor Muhammad Yunus, has warned of a strict crackdown on any attempts by the banned Awami League to stage programmes on the streets of Dhaka, reports bdnews24.com.
In a post in English on his verified Facebook account on Monday, Shafiqul cautioned the</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 09:35:57 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>