<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 11:19:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Fakhrul sees new opportunity to build liberal democratic Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/fakhrul-sees-new-opportunity-to-build-liberal-democratic-bangladesh</link><description>BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir on Saturday said a new scope has opened before the nation to build a liberal democratic Bangladesh.
“People are now hopeful as a scope has been created for building a liberal democratic Bangladesh,” he said.
Fakhrul made the remarks wh</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 07:38:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gas valve burst causes pressure drop, disrupting supply across Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/gas-valve-burst-causes-pressure-drop-disrupting-supply-across-dhaka</link><description>A sharp drop in gas pressure has disrupted supply across Dhaka after a key valve exploded on the distribution line.
Residents in areas including Dhanmondi, Mohammadpur, Shyamoli, New Market, Hazaribagh and Gabtoli are receiving little or no gas supply.
State-run distributor Titas Gas said the pro</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 07:53:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tasnim Jara gets back candidacy on appeal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tasnim-jara-gets-back-candidacy-on-appeal</link><description>Tasnim Jara, a former National Citizen Party (NCP) leader, regained her candidacy status on Saturday, the first day of the appeal hearing.
The Election Commission has upheld the candidacies of Tasnim Jara and Jamaat-e-Islami's AHM Hamidur Rahman Azad for the upcoming national election.
The decisi</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 08:08:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>International Conference on Mother Language and Awards 2026 held at Nalanda Open University</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/others/international-conference-on-mother-language-and-awards-2026-held-at-nalanda-open-university</link><description>A two-day international conference focusing on mother language, human rights, peace, and press freedom was held on January 4–5 at Nalanda Open University in Rajgir, Bihar. The event was jointly organized by Nalanda Open University and the SAARC Journalists Forum.
Titled International Confere</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 08:23:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>'We don't want to go back to pre-Aug 5 days': Tarique</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/we-dont-want-to-go-back-to-pre-aug-5-days-tarique</link><description>BNP leader Tarique Rahman has said there is “no reason” for the country to return to the political conditions that existed before the toppling of the Awami League regime on August 5, 2024.
“We don’t want to go back to pre-August 5 days. There’s no reason for us to do</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 08:38:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Titas begins repair work to restore gas supply</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/titas-begins-repair-work-to-restore-gas-supply</link><description>State-run distributor Titas Gas Transmission and Distribution PLC on Saturday began repair work on a damaged gas valve on Mirpur Road and a gas pipeline under the Turag River to restore normal gas supply in the city.
According to a Titas Gas press release issued today, a four-inch diameter valve i</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 08:53:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NASA cuts space station mission due to astronaut's health issue</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/nasa-cuts-space-station-mission-due-to-astronauts-health-issue</link><description>In a rare move, NASA is cutting a mission aboard the International Space Station short after an astronaut had a medical issue.
The space agency said Thursday the US-Japanese-Russian crew of four will return to Earth in the coming days, earlier than planned.
NASA cancelled its first spacewalk of t</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 09:08:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>China, Russia, Iran start 'BRICS Plus' naval exercises in South African waters</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/china-russia-iran-start-brics-plus-naval-exercises-in-south-african-waters</link><description>China, Russia and Iran began a week of joint naval exercises in South Africa's waters on Saturday in what the host country described as a BRICS Plus operation to "ensure the safety of shipping and maritime economic activities".
 
BRICS Plus is an expansion of a geopolitical bloc originally c</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 09:23:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cox's Bazar-2: Jamaat’s Hamidur Rahman Azad gets candidacy back</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/coxs-bazar-2-jamaats-hamidur-rahman-azad-gets-candidacy-back</link><description>The Election Commission on Saturday declared the candidature of Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islam’s aspirant for Cox’s Bazar-2 AHM Hamidur Rahman Azad valid after hearing his appeal petition.
Earlier, the returning officer concerned declared his nomination paper invalid during the scrutiny, UN</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 09:59:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tigers act normal despite controversies, says Shanto</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/bangladesh-players-act-normal-despite-controversies-says-shanto</link><description>Bangladesh players are often forced to mask the impact of controversies in the build-up to, and during, major tournaments, despite how the external noise affects them, Test captain Najmul Hossain Shanto said.
Uncertainty looms over Bangladesh’s participation in the Twenty20 World Cup followi</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 10:14:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Banglalink launches nationwide Wi-Fi calling service</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/banglalink-launches-nationwide-wi-fi-calling-service</link><description>Banglalink, the country’s leading innovative digital operator, has officially launched its nationwide Voice over Wi Fi (VoWiFi) calling service, enabling customers across Bangladesh to make high quality voice calls using Wi Fi alongside mobile networks.
With the nationwide rollout, customers</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 10:29:35 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>