<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 23:32:28 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Lutfozzaman Babar wins Netrokona-4 seat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/lutfozzaman-babar-wins-netrokona-4-seat</link><description>BNP-nominated candidate and former state minister for home affairs Lutfozzaman Babar has been unofficially elected from the Netrokona-4 constituency.
He secured 160,801 votes with the sheaf of paddy symbol, defeating his nearest rival, Jamaat-e-Islami candidate Md Al Helal, by a margin of 120,961</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 19:06:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat Ameer Shafiqur Rahman wins Dhaka-15 seat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jamaat-ameer-shafiqur-rahman-wins-dhaka-15-seat</link><description>Jamaat-e-Islami Ameer Dr Shafiqur Rahman has been unofficially declared elected from the Dhaka-15 constituency in the 13th Jatiya Sangsad election.
According to the unofficial results, Dr Shafiqur secured 82,645 votes in the constituency, which has a total of 127 polling centres.
His nearest riva</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 20:01:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rumeen Farhana wins by 37,568 votes in Brahmanbaria-2</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rumeen-farhana-wins-by-37568-votes-in-brahmanbaria-2</link><description>Independent candidate Rumeen Farhana, contesting with the “duck” symbol, has been unofficially declared elected from the Brahmanbaria-2 constituency, defeating her nearest rival by a margin of 37,568 votes.
According to the results from 151 polling centres, Rumeen secured 117,495 votes</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 20:16:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat wins all four seats in Nilphamari</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jamaat-wins-all-four-seats-in-nilphamari</link><description>Candidates of Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami have secured victory in all four parliamentary constituencies in Nilphamari in the 13th national election.
The results were announced on Thursday night after vote counting by District Returning Officer and Deputy Commissioner Mohammad Nayiruzzaman.
In Nilp</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 20:49:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP wins all five parliamentary seats in Sunamganj</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bnp-wins-all-five-parliamentary-seats-in-sunamganj</link><description>BNP candidates secured victory in all five parliamentary constituencies in Sunamganj district in the 13th national election.
In Sunamganj-1 (Tahirpur, Jamalganj, Dharmapasha and Madhyanagar), BNP candidate Kamruzzaman Kamrul won the seat with 161,774 votes, contesting with the party’s electo</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 21:04:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat wins all four seats in Satkhira</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jamaat-wins-all-four-seats-in-satkhira</link><description>Candidates of Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami have won all four parliamentary seats in Satkhira district, according to unofficial results announced after vote counting.
In Satkhira-1 (Tala-Kalaroa), Jamaat candidate Izzat Ullah, contesting with the party’s scale symbol, received 220,330 votes fro</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 21:19:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP wins all five seats in Narsingdi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bnp-wins-all-five-seats-in-narsingdi</link><description>BNP candidates have secured victory in all five parliamentary constituencies of Narsingdi, according to unofficial results announced by the respective returning officers.
In Narsingdi-1 (Sadar), BNP Joint Secretary General Khairul Kabir Khokon, contesting with the party’s electoral symbol &amp;l</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 22:05:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sarjis Alam loses Panchagarh-1 battle</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/sarjis-alam-loses-panchagarh-1-battle</link><description>NCP Chief Organiser (Northern Region) Sarjis Alam was defeated in Panchagarh-1 as the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) won both parliamentary seats in Panchagarh district, according to unofficial results announced on early Friday.
Kazi Md Sayemuzzaman, Returning Officer and Deputy Commissioner o</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 22:20:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP's Ishraque Hossain wins Dhaka-6 constituency</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bnps-ishraque-hossain-wins-dhaka-6-constituency</link><description>BNP-nominated candidate Ishraque Hossain, son of former Dhaka mayor late Sadeque Hossain Khoka, has won the Dhaka-6 parliamentary seat in the 13th National Election, according to unofficial results.
Ishraque Hossain secured 78,141 votes, while his nearest rival Abdul Mannan — contesting unde</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 22:42:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat candidate Masood Sayeedi wins  Pirojpur-1 seat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jamaat-candidate-masood-sayeedi-wins-pirojpur-1-seat</link><description>Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami candidate Masood Sayeedi, son of Jamaat leader and former lawmaker Delwar Hossain Sayeedi, has been declared winner from Pirojpur-1 constituency in unofficial results of the 13th Jatiya Sangsad Election.
He bagged 1,32,659 votes, while his nearest rival BNP candidate Ala</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 22:57:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mirza Abbas beats Nasiruddin Patwary by 5000 votes</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/mirza-abbas-beats-nasiruddin-patwary-by-5000-votes</link><description>BNP candidate Mirza Abbas Uddin Ahmed has unofficially won the Dhaka-8 parliamentary seat, defeating his nearest rival Nasiruddin Patwari by more than 5,000 votes.
The result was announced by Dhaka Divisional Commissioner and Returning Officer Sharafuddin Ahmed Chowdhury in the early hours of Frid</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 23:12:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat candidate Jahirul Islam wins Ctg-16 seat unofficially</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jamaat-candidate-jahirul-islam-wins-ctg-16-seat-unofficially</link><description>Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami candidate Jahirul Islam has been declared winner from the Chattogram-16 constituency in unofficial results of the 13th Jatiya Sangsad Election.
He bagged 93,167 votes while his nearest rival BNP candidate Mishkatul Islam Chowdhury got 83,105 votes, reports BSS.
Election</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 23:27:20 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>