<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 14:42:46 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Indian media, AL spreading disinformation about Bangladesh: Press Secretary</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/indian-media-al-spreading-disinformation-about-bangladesh-press-secretary</link><description>Indian media outlets and the ousted Awami League are spreading disinformation about Bangladesh, Chief Adviser’s Press Secretary Shafiqul Alam said on Monday.
“We have seen newspapers, including a prominent one, publishing false information, despite it being among the most widely read B</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 12:36:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Walton inaugurates ACC Kappa Compressor</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/walton-inaugurates-acc-kappa-compressor</link><description>Walton, Bangladesh’s first and only compressor manufacturer, has launched the production of the renowned European ACC brand’s Kappa Compressor, featuring compact design, high efficiency, durability, and environmental sustainability, marking a historic milestone for Walton and the countr</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 12:51:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shab-e-Barat: Yunus calls to shun injustice</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/yunus-urges-muslims-to-illuminate-national-life-by-avoiding-injustice-on-shab-e-barat</link><description>Chief Advisor Muhammad Yunus has called on Muslims to embrace Islam’s “unique beauty” by avoiding all forms of injustice and wrongdoing, and to illuminate the national life through righteous deeds.
His message came on Monday ahead of Shab-e-Barat, which will be observed on Tuesda</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 13:06:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CBS upgrade underway at Al-Arafah Islami Bank</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/cbs-upgrade-underway-at-al-arafah-islami-bank</link><description>The Core Banking System (CBS) upgrade program of Al-Arafah Islami Bank PLC is currently underway with the objective of enhancing technological capabilities, building a modern banking infrastructure, and ensuring safer, faster, and uninterrupted banking services for customers.
The CBS upgrade progr</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 13:21:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Midland Bank PLC receives licence from Mastercard</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/midland-bank-plc-receives-licence-from-mastercard</link><description>Md. Ahsan-uz-Zaman, Managing Director &amp; CEO of Midland Bank PLC, received a Mastercard-affiliated membership licence from Syed Mohammad Kamal, Country Manager of Mastercard Bangladesh, at a ceremony held at the bank’s head office in Dhaka on Sunday, 1st Feb 2026.
This partnership establishes</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 12:39:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>WB to provide $150.75m to Bangladesh for RAISE Project</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/wb-to-provide-15075m-to-bangladesh-for-raise-project</link><description>An additional financing agreement and a grant agreement were signed yesterday between the government of Bangladesh and the International Development Association (IDA) of the World Bank (WB) Group for an amount of US$ 150 million loan and US$0.75 million grant to implement the “Recovery and Ad</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 12:54:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique Rahman greets Muslims on Shab-e-Barat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-rahman-greets-muslims-on-shab-e-barat</link><description>BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman has extended heartfelt greetings to Muslims in Bangladesh and across the world on the occasion of the holy Shab-e-Barat, wishing continued happiness, peace and prosperity for all.
In a message marking the holy Sheb-e-Barat, he said, “Shab-e-Barat is one of the mos</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 13:09:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BB buys $218.50m through dollar auction</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bb-buys-21850m-through-dollar-auction</link><description>Bangladesh Bank (BB) on Monday purchased $218.50 million from 16 commercial banks through multiple auction methods as part of its ongoing strategy to curb the depreciation of the US dollar against the taka and revitalise the remittance and export sectors.
According to central bank data, it bought</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 13:24:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Stocks surge as market turnover tops Tk 7 billion in 2026</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/stocks-surge-as-bangladesh-market-turnover-tops-tk-7-billion-in-2026</link><description>Bangladesh’s capital market saw a major boost on Monday as the turnover at the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) crossed Tk 7.0 billion for the first time this year, alongside a broad-based rally in share prices.
The total turnover on the DSE stood at Tk 7.46 billion worth of shares and units durin</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 13:39:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ctg Port workers call another 24-hour strike</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/chittagong-ports-staff-workers-call-fresh-24-hour-strike-against-nct-lease-to-foreign-handler</link><description>The Chittagong Port workers and employees have called another 24-hour strike in protest against the lease of the New Mooring Container Terminal (NCT) to a foreign company.
The Chittagong Port Protection Struggle Committee announced the industrial action on Tuesday morning, with the strike schedule</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 13:54:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>10-taka banknote featuring ‘Graffiti-2024’ to hit market on Tuesday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/10-taka-banknote-featuring-graffiti-2024-to-hit-market-on-tuesday</link><description>Bangladesh Bank (BB) is set to release a new 10-taka denomination banknote on Tuesday as part of its new series titled “Historical and Archaeological Architecture of Bangladesh.”
The new note, bearing the signature of Bangladesh Bank Governor Dr. Ahsan H. Mansur, will be issued initial</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 14:09:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat wants to push Bangladesh back, says Fakhrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-wants-to-push-bangladesh-back-says-fakhrul</link><description>BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir on Monday alleged that Jamaat-e-Islam aims to turn Bangladesh into an Afghanistan-like state, raising concerns over the party’s political agenda and its potential impact on national stability.
“They want to take Bangladesh backward. The</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 14:24:05 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>