<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 06:11:41 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>CSE platform ready, yet open-ended fund trading remains offline</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/cse-platform-ready-yet-open-ended-fund-trading-remains-offline</link><description>Despite regulatory clearance and the availability of a trading platform, it remains unclear why open-ended mutual funds have yet to become tradable online.
The Chittagong Stock Exchange (CSE) completed setting up an online trading platform nearly a year ago and also conducted a mock trading sessio</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 03:06:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Stocks open week flat amid policy uncertainty</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/stocks-open-week-flat-amid-policy-uncertainty</link><description>Stocks opened the week nearly flat on Sunday as investors mostly remained watchful, waiting for the potential policy direction and regulatory changes under the newly elected government.
Market analysts said cautious investors preferred to realize gains from the recent election-driven rally, while</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 03:21:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ACC files cases against ex-MP Sheikh Afil, wife</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/acc-files-cases-against-ex-mp-sheikh-afil-wife</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) has filed two separate cases against former Jashore-1 MP and his wife Tahera Sobha over allegations of acquiring illegal wealth worth Tk 623.1 million beyond known sources of income.
Sheikh Afil Uddin is the elder brother of Sheikh Bashir Uddin, a former advise</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 03:36:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat condemns minister's remark on ‘Inquilab Zindabad’ slogan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-condemns-ministers-remark-on-inquilab-zindabad-slogan</link><description>Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami has protested the Power, Energy, and Mineral Resources Minister Iqbal Hasan Mahmud's comments regarding the slogan ‘Inquilab Zindabad.’
Assistant Secretary General of Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami and Head of its Central Publicity and Media Department Advocate A</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 03:51:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>586 die, 1,238 hurt in 597 accidents in January: BJKS</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/586-die-1238-hurt-in-597-accidents-in-january-bjks</link><description>A total of 586 people were killed and 1,238 injured in 597 accidents across roads, railways and waterways in January, according to data compiled by the Bangladesh Jatri Kalyan Samity (BJKS).
Of the total, 546 people were killed and 1,204 injured in 552 road accidents, while 37 railway accidents ki</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 04:06:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ctg residents frustrated as prices of essentials rise during Ramadan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/ctg-residents-frustrated-as-prices-of-essentials-rise-during-ramadan</link><description>Chattogram residents are frustrated with the market of essential kitchen items as buyers say prices have been hiked unusually from the first day of Ramadan -- jumping much higher by the day compared to the same time last year in the Muslim fasting month.
Talking with the FE, customers at Kajirdewr</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 04:21:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Aman rice procurement exceeds target</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/aman-rice-procurement-exceeds-target</link><description>The government's Aman rice procurement has exceeded its target, reaching 1.02 million tonnes so far.
The higher procurement prices set by the government encouraged millers and farmers to supply their produce.
In November, the government set a target to procure 0.7 million tonnes of the staple --</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 04:36:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP leader sustains bullet injuries in Dhaka’s Kalabagan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-leader-sustains-bullet-injuries-in-dhakas-kalabagan</link><description>A local leader of the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) sustained bullet injuries in Dhaka’s Kalabagan area on Sunday night.
The injured Shafiqur Rahman, 55, is the joint general secretary of Kalabagan Ward-16 BNP. He is the son of late Mofidul Islam of Sidlai village under Burichang Police</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 04:51:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rupali Bank pays homage to language martyrs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/rupali-bank-pays-homage-to-language-martyrs</link><description>State-owned Rupali Bank PLC has paid tribute to the martyrs of the Language Movement on the occasion of Martyrs' Day and International Mother Language Day 2026, says a press statement.
The bank’s Managing Director, Kazi Md Wahidul Islam, led the tribute by placing a wreath at the Central Sha</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 05:06:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>9 critically injured in suspected kitchen gas blast in Chattogram</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/9-critically-injured-in-suspected-kitchen-gas-blast-in-chattogram</link><description>Nine people, including a child, have been critically injured in a suspected gas explosion at a residential building in Chattogram’s Halishahar.
The incident occurred early on Monday morning at Halima Manzil in Block H of Halishahar, where accumulated gas in a kitchen on the third floor of a</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 05:21:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Man, son among four killed in clash between rival groups in Narail</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/man-son-among-four-killed-in-clash-between-rival-groups-in-narail</link><description>Four people, including a man and his son, have been killed in a clash stemming from a long-running turf war between rival factions in Narail Sadar Upazila.
The incident occurred around 5 am on Monday in Barakula village under Singasholpur Union, said Oli Mia, chief (OC) of Narail Sadar Police Stat</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 05:36:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tajul removed, Aminul Islam named new ICT chief prosecutor</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tajul-removed-aminul-islam-named-new-ict-chief-prosecutor</link><description>The government has cancelled the appointment of Mohammad Tajul Islam as chief prosecutor of the International Crimes Tribunal (ICT) and appointed Advocate Aminul Islam in his place.
The Ministry of Law, Justice and Parliamentary Affairs issued a notification in this regard on Monday (February 23)</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 05:51:49 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>