<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 17:26:40 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>‘Deliberate negligence’ in Khaleda’s treatment: Dr FM Siddiqui</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/deliberate-negligence-in-khaledas-treatment-dr-fm-siddiqui</link><description>Dr FM Siddiqui, one of the physicians who treated Khaleda Zia, has demanded an investigation into what he described as “deliberate negligence” in her medical care at the Bangladesh Medical University.
He raised the allegation on Friday while speaking at a citizens’ condolence mee</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 14:33:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jubo Dal leader held over petrol pump worker’s death in Rajbari</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/jubo-dal-leader-held-over-petrol-pump-workers-death-in-rajbari</link><description>Rajbari police have arrested former district Jubo Dal president Abul Hashem Sujan and his driver Kamal Hossain over the death of a petrol pump worker allegedly run over by their vehicle.
The victim, Ripon Saha, 32, worked at Karim Filling Station near Goalanda Mor.
Police said he was crushed outs</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 14:48:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Finance adviser urges patience on new pay scale, backs referendum</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/finance-adviser-urges-patience-on-new-pay-scale-backs-referendum</link><description>Finance Ministry Adviser Dr. Salehuddin Ahmed on Friday asked government officials to be patient regarding the new pay scale.
He said the pay scale has been prepared after 10 years.
“There are many calculations. A committee has been formed. They are working. After the committee submits its</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 15:03:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fire guts 26 rooms in Gazipur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/fire-guts-26-rooms-in-gazipur</link><description>A fire broke out at a residential colony in Kashimpur area of Gazipur on Friday morning, destroying at least 26 rooms.
The incident occurred in a colony owned by a man named Biplob, located near GMS Garments factory in Sardaganj area of Kashimpur.
On receiving information, a unit of DBL Fire Serv</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 15:18:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP chief Tarique holds virtual meeting with US trade delegation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-chief-tarique-holds-virtual-meeting-with-us-trade-delegation</link><description>BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman has met with a United States trade delegation to discuss bilateral trade, tariffs and future economic cooperation, the party said.
The meeting was held on Friday morning via video call from his residence in Gulshan, according to the BNP Media Cell.
The US delegation, h</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 15:33:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Africa Cup of Nations commercial revenue up by 90%, says CAF</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/africa-cup-of-nations-commercial-revenue-up-by-90-says-caf</link><description>The Confederation of African Football said it has had a 90 percent increase in commercial revenue for the Africa Cup of Nations in Morocco, calling it “the most successful commercial story in the history of African football” but without providing any figures.
CAF said on Friday this wa</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 15:48:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Three-day Circularity Workshop ‘CIRCO’ successfully completed for the first time in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/three-day-circularity-workshop-circo-successfully-completed-for-the-first-time-in-bangladesh</link><description>The first-ever three-day circularity workshop titled ‘CIRCO Track’ was successfully completed in Bangladesh, highlighting the importance of reducing raw material usage through circular practices across industries, particularly in the ready-made garment (RMG) and textile sectors.
The wo</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 15:45:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UK navy launches new crewless helicopter to counter North Atlantic threats</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/uk-navy-launches-new-crewless-helicopter-to-counter-north-atlantic-threats</link><description>Britain’s Royal Navy said on Friday its first full-sized autonomous helicopter, designed to track submarines and carry out other high-risk missions amid rising North Atlantic tensions, had completed its maiden flight.
Europe's defence sector has been reshaped since Russia's full-scale invasi</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 16:00:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Woman killed in 'gunfight between traffickers, armed group’ in Teknaf</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/woman-killed-in-gunfight-between-traffickers-armed-group-in-teknaf</link><description>Police have recovered the bullet-hit body of a young woman from the Teknaf Upazila Health Complex following a reported gunfight in Cox’s Bazar.
Md Saiful Islam, chief of Teknaf Model Police Station, said police took custody of the body from the hospital after Friday evening.</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 16:15:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt installs Osman Hadi’s elder brother at Bangladesh mission in UK</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-installs-osman-hadis-elder-brother-at-bangladesh-mission-in-uk</link><description>The interim government has appointed Sharif Osman bin Hadi's brother Omar bin Hadi as second secretary at the Bangladesh Assistant High Commission in Birmingham, United Kingdom.
Omar bin Hadi is the elder brother of Osman Hadi, convenor of the Inqilab Moncho shot by unidentified assailants in Dhak</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 16:30:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump may tariff countries that don’t go along with his Greenland plan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-may-tariff-countries-that-dont-go-along-with-his-greenland-plan</link><description>President Donald Trump on Friday said he may put a tariff on countries that do not support his plan for the United States to control Greenland.
"I may put a tariff on countries if they don't go along with Greenland, because we need Greenland for national security," Trump said at a White House heal</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 16:45:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Election Commission restores candidacy for 18 aspirants</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/election-commission-restores-candidacy-for-18-aspirants</link><description>On the seventh day of appeals over nomination rejections for the parliamentary polls, the Election Commission approved 18 more pleas, overturning the returning officers’ previous decisions.
With the latest restorations on Friday, as many as 353 candidates have regained their eligibility.
Co</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 17:00:43 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>