<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 12:46:11 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>CID files Tk 16.1b money laundering case against Nafeez Sarafat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cid-files-tk-161b-money-laundering-case-against-nafeez-sarafat</link><description>The Criminal Investigation Department (CID) has filed a case accusing former Padma Bank chairman Chowdhury Nafeez Sarafat, members of his family, and an associate of laundering more than Tk 16.13 billion.
The case was lodged at Gulshan Police Station on Thursday under the Money Laundering Preventi</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 09:43:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Foreign firms challenge liquor policy of India's Maharashtra in court</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/foreign-firms-challenge-liquor-policy-of-indias-maharashtra-in-court</link><description>Diageo and Pernod Ricard’s Indian lobbying group has sued Maharashtra state over a sharp tax hike on their affordable brands and for excluding the companies from a new lower tax category reserved for some local firms.
Maharashtra accounts for 7% of India’s premium liquor consumption an</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 09:56:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bicyclist stabbed to death in Ctg</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bicyclist-stabbed-to-death-in-ctg</link><description>A bicyclist was stabbed to death by muggers in Lal Dighi area of the port city of Chattogram early Friday, said police.
The incident occurred near Zilla Parisahd Market, just a hundred yards off Kotwali Police Station around 2:30am.
The deceased was identified as Ismail Hossain, 33, a resident fr</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 10:11:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khaleda in 'critical condition': BNP;s Fakhrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/khaleda-in-critical-condition-says-bnp-mirza-fakhrul</link><description>BNP Chairperson Khaleda Zia is in a “critical condition,” Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir has told the media.
His remarks came following a special prayer session after the Jummah prayers on Friday at Paltan Central Jame Mosque.
He said, “You know that our leader Be</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 10:26:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>'Stop kowtowing to political parties': Fakhrul to journalists</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bnps-mirza-fakhrul-urges-journalists-to-steer-clear-of-partisanship</link><description>Senior BNP leader Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir has urged journalists to break free from the clutches of political parties, warning that partisanship has blighted the country’s media landscape.
Speaking at the biennial conference of the Bangladesh Federal Union of Journalists (BFUJ) at the Nat</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 10:41:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Genome study reveals milestone in history of cat domestication</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/genome-study-reveals-milestone-in-history-of-cat-domestication</link><description>Whether they are a Siamese, Persian, Maine Coon, or Domestic Shorthair, there are hundreds of millions of cats living with people around the world. But despite their popularity as pets, the history of cat domestication has remained difficult for scientists to decipher.
A new genome study is provid</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 10:56:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>At crowded Ukrainian cemetery, mourners yearn for war to end</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/at-crowded-ukrainian-cemetery-mourners-yearn-for-war-to-end</link><description>After losing her son to Russia's war in Ukraine, Olya Kachmaryk hopes a new US-backed peace plan can finally end the fighting - even if it could mean giving up land he fought for as a soldier.
"The more they (the Russians) come this way, the more they'll want," said Kachmaryk, 50, visiting his gra</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 11:11:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hong Kong tower fire toll rises to 128, 200 remain missing</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/hong-kong-tower-fire-toll-rises-to-128-200-remain-missing</link><description>The death toll from Hong Kong's worst fire in nearly 80 years has risen to 128 and about 200 people remain missing from the high-rise residential complex that was engulfed by the blaze, the city's security chief said on Friday.
The fire in the Wang Fuk Court development, with eight 32-storey tower</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 11:39:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mortar shell found in agricultural land in Lalmonirhat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/mortar-shell-found-in-agricultural-land-in-lalmonirhat</link><description>A mortar shell was discovered in an agricultural field in Hati Bandha Upazila, Lalmonirhat, on Friday morning.
Workers uncovered the object while excavating soil in the middle of Goddimari Adarsha village in Goddimari Union.
Local resident Md. Abul Hossain (63) was leveling his farmland using an</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 11:54:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Outrage in Sylhet after date palm trees cut down at Shahjalal's shrine</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/outrage-in-sylhet-after-date-palm-trees-cut-down-at-shahjalals-shrine</link><description>An outrage has triggered among devotees after several old date palm trees inside the premises of Hazrat Shahjalal’s (RA) shrine in Sylhet were cut down.
These trees, planted nearly 50 years ago, were an integral part of the shrine’s heritage.
The trees were felled between Monday and W</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 12:09:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nafeez Sarafat, 3 others sued for embezzling over Tk 161 billion</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ex-padma-bank-chairman-nafeez-sarafat-3-others-sued-for-embezzling-over-tk-16136-billion</link><description>The Criminal Investigation Department (CID) has filed a money laundering case against former Padma Bank chairman Chowdhury Nafeez Sarafat and three others for allegedly misappropriating Tk 161.3686 billion.
The case was filed with Gulshan Police Station on November 27 following an investigation by</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 12:24:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Protesters block Dhaka’s Shahbagh to demand Barishal-Bhola Bridge</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/protesters-block-dhakas-shahbagh-to-demand-barishal-bhola-bridge</link><description>Dhaka residents hailing from the Bhola District have blocked the capital’s Shahbagh intersection to demand the construction of a bridge linking Barishal and Bhola.
They took up positions at the intersection around 3:45pm on Friday, bringing traffic to a standstill, according to Shahbagh Poli</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 12:39:29 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>