<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 05:31:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Jatiya Party begins election campaign amid concerns</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jatiya-party-launches-election-campaign-amid-worries-over-fairness-level-playing-field</link><description>The Jatiya Party is heading into the campaign in 196 constituencies, raising concerns that include possible “election engineering”.
Secretary General Shameem Haider Patwary said there is anxiety among candidates over potential obstacles to campaigning and the absence of a “level</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 17:36:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New US Ambassador to Bangladesh raises concern over China</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/new-us-ambassador-to-bangladesh-raises-concern-over-chinas-regional-influence</link><description>Newly appointed US Ambassador to Bangladesh Brent T Christensen on Wednesday said he is concerned about broader Chinese influence in South Asia, stressing that they have a host of options available to try to help their partner militaries meet their capability needs.
‘You know, as I sai</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 17:31:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>'The Ugly American'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/the-ugly-american</link><description>A novel with the eponymous title was written in the sixties by two Americans, Eugene Burdick and William Lederer, that was later made into a Hollywood movie. The book was a critique of the scatter-brained foreign policy pursued by American administration in the sixties' cold war era, particularly i</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 17:51:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Addressing the youth job challenge</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/reviews/addressing-the-youth-job-challenge</link><description>The July 2024 Mass Movement brought to the fore the long-standing unaddressed development challenges of rising inequalities in wealth, income, and economic opportunities. A particularly concerning reflection of these inequalities is the growing incidence of youth unemployment. Addressing this matte</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 18:06:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Loan defaulters should be in jail, not parliament</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/loan-defaulters-should-be-in-jail-not-parliament</link><description>The remark of an election commissioner that the loan-defaulting candidates were being validated ‘with a heavy heart’ speaks volumes for the Commission’s predicament in the absence of a robust legal mechanism and decisive political backing, writes Atiqul Kabir Tuhin
Non-performing</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 18:21:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Draft Money Loan Court Act comes to nought</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/draft-money-loan-court-act-comes-to-nought</link><description>The Ministry of Law's refusal to endorse the draft of the Artha Rin Adalat Ain (Money Loan Court Act) and its suggestion, instead, to amend the existing laws renders the whole exercise redundant. An unceremonious rejection, this MoL decision smacks of highhandedness at its best and undue sympathy f</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 18:36:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt employees' salary proposed to be jacked up by max 142pc</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-employees-salary-proposed-to-be-jacked-up-by-max-142pc</link><description>Government employees' pay is recommended to be ramped up by 142 per cent to Tk 160,000 at the highest and Tk 20,000 lowest, generating dismay among economists.



The Pay Commission submitted its report to Chief Adviser of the interim government Prof Muhammad Yunus on Wednesday, recommending su</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 18:51:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt considers keeping two public banks thru merging rest</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/govt-considers-keeping-two-public-banks-thru-merging-rest</link><description>Keeping only two larger public-sector banks through merging the rest is under government consideration to manage them well, the central bank governor said Wednesday while unveiling latest banking-sector overhaul packages.
Dr Ahsan H. Mansur, the Bangladesh Bank Governor, was speaking as chief gues</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 02:30:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>1972 candidates in race for 298 JS seats</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/1972-candidates-in-race-for-298-js-seats</link><description>A total of 1972 candidates have been finalised to contest the vote in 298 parliamentary constituencies during the 13th national elections scheduled for February 12 this year.
The aspirants are now ready to kick off their campaigns after they were allocated respective electoral symbols by the retur</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 04:02:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CA vows 'model election' as unique security oversights mounted</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ca-vows-model-election-as-unique-security-oversights-mounted</link><description>Interim government chief Prof Muhammad Yunus said Bangladesh's forthcoming 13th parliamentary election must set a democratic benchmark for the future as authorities Wednesday unveiled extensive security and monitoring deployment involving body cameras, CCTV surveillance, drones and central control</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 04:17:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EPB seeks govt, BB help to unlock Tk 1.8b in FDRs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/epb-seeks-govt-bb-help-to-unlock-tk-18b-in-fdrs</link><description>The Export Promotion Bureau (EPB) has turned to the government and the central bank for urgent help after nearly Tk 1.8 billion of its funds got trapped in fixed deposit receipts (FDRs) with 10 banks, raising concerns over stalled projects and mounting cash-flow stress.
Despite the deposits having</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 04:32:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Amending MLPA: For unverified income, property itself can be sued</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/for-unverified-income-property-itself-can-be-sued</link><description>The government is going to amend the Money Laundering Prevention Act, allowing the state to sue the "property" itself if the owner cannot prove a legitimate source of income, officials say.
If the court presumes the accused person or entity is guilty of money laundering, the person could be punish</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 04:47:39 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>