<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 14:50:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Bangladesh, United States seek to expand cooperation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-united-states-seek-to-expand-cooperation</link><description>Bangladesh and the United States are seeking to elevate their partnership to “new heights”, with both sides highlighting broader collaboration across key sectors of engagement.
The courtesy call, held at the foreign ministry on Monday, comes as the new administration in Dhaka begins it</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 11:35:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>75th Risk Management Committee meeting of Shahjalal Islami Bank held</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/75th-risk-management-committee-meeting-of-shahjalal-islami-bank-held</link><description>The75th meeting of the Risk Management Committee (RMC) of Shahjalal Islami Bank PLC held recently at its Corporate Head Office of the bank, according to a press release.
The meeting was presided over by Engineer Md. Towhidur Rahman, Chairman of the Risk Management Committee of the bank. Among othe</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 11:50:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Agent banking deposits in Bangladesh makes a big jump</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/agent-banking-deposits-in-bangladesh-makes-a-big-jump</link><description>Bangladesh’s agent banking sector is defying conventional trends, recording strong deposit growth even as the number of agents and service outlets declines.
According to the latest report from Bangladesh Bank, total deposits in agent banking reached Tk 49,356 crore at the end of 2025, up 18</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 12:05:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prime Bank holds ‘Empowering Youth’ event at IUT</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/prime-bank-holds-empowering-youth-event-at-iut</link><description>Prime Bank PLC, through its flagship platform PrimeAcademia, recently organized a seminar titled “Empowering Youth” at the Islamic University of Technology (IUT) in collaboration with the IUT Career &amp; Business Society (CBS).
The event reflected Prime Bank’s continued commitment t</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 12:20:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>National Bank launches remittance operations with dLocal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/national-bank-launches-remittance-operations-with-dlocal</link><description>National Bank PLC, one of Bangladesh’s leading remittance procuring banks, has launched Remittance operations with dLocal Limited, a globally recognized Electronic Money Institution (EMI) based in Malta.
According to a press release, this launching aims to strengthen cross-border remittance</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 12:35:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump renews attack on US Supreme Court, vows other tariffs, licenses</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-renews-attack-on-us-supreme-court-vows-other-tariffs-licenses</link><description>President Donald Trump renewed his condemnation of the US Supreme Court on Monday after it ruled against his sweeping tariff program last week, vowing to turn to other tariff powers and licenses but giving no details.
"The court has also approved all other Tariffs, of which there are many, and the</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 12:50:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt warns of disciplinary action over irregular office attendance</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-warns-of-disciplinary-action-over-irregular-office-attendance</link><description>The Ministry of Law has taken a strict stance against irregularities in office attendance, warning officials and employees of disciplinary action for late arrival, unauthorised absence, or leaving office early without permission.
In an office order issued on Monday, the Law and Justice Division of</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 13:05:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Modhumoti Bank celebrates milestone of achieving Tk 100.00 billion in deposits</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/modhumoti-bank-celebrates-milestone-of-achieving-tk-10000-billion-in-deposits</link><description>Modhumoti Bank PLC has achieved the milestone of Tk 100.00 billion in deposits, according to a press release.
This success was celebrated through an informal ceremony held at the bank’s Head Office on Sunday.
The event was attended by Mr. Md. ShafiulAzam, Managing Director &amp; CEO of the bank</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 13:20:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Midland Bank launches MDB Digital Nano Loan for existing MDB customers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/midland-bank-launches-mdb-digital-nano-loan-for-existing-mdb-customers</link><description>Midland Bank PLC (MDB) launched “MDB Digital Nano Loan” for all existing customers, marking a significant step in its digital banking journey.
According to a press release, the initiative aligns with Bangladesh Bank’s directive under BRPD Circular No. 11 dated June 02, 2022, whic</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 13:35:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Islami Bank holds board meeting on Monday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/islami-bank-holds-board-meeting-on-monday</link><description>A meeting of the board of directors of Islami Bank Bangladesh PLC was held on Monday at the Islami Bank Tower, according to a press release.
Professor Dr. M. Zubaidur Rahman, chairman of the bank, presided over the meeting. Mohammad Khurshid Wahab, chairman of the executive committee, Professor Dr</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 13:50:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘TARA Uddokta Mela 2026’ to showcase all-women entrepreneur products</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/tara-uddokta-mela-2026-to-showcase-all-women-entrepreneur-products</link><description>BRAC Bank is hosting ‘TARA Uddokta Mela 2026’, a three-day fair, to promote locally made products by women entrepreneurs and create a market for these products, according to a press release.
The fair will take place from February 27 to March 1, 2026, every day from 10:00am to 11:00pm d</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 14:05:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Amar Ekushey Book Fair 2026 set to begin on February 26</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/amar-ekushey-book-fair-2026-set-to-begin-on-february-26</link><description>The Amar Ekushey Book Fair 2026 has been postponed by a day and will now commence on February 26 instead of the earlier scheduled February 25.
The date is rescheduled for the second time as it was scheduled on February 20 earlier.
The inauguration ceremony will be held at Rabindra Chattar, Bangla</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 14:20:58 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>