<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 18:39:05 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Jamaat seeks vote recount in 30 seats</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-seeks-vote-recount-in-30-seats</link><description>Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami has sought a recount of votes in at least 30 constituencies in the 13th parliamentary election, alleging widespread rigging, fraud and irregularities.
Speaking at a press conference at the party’s central office in Moghbazar in the capital, Assistant Secretary Gene</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 14:54:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Commonwealth chief congratulates Tarique, BNP on election win</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/commonwealth-chief-congratulates-tarique-bnp-on-election-win</link><description>Commonwealth Secretary-General Shirley Botchwey has extended her congratulations to BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman and his party following their victory in the parliamentary elections.
 “I commend all citizens and institutions who contributed to a peaceful electoral process and referendum</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 15:29:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Germany greets Tarique Rahman, BNP for election victory</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/germany-greets-tarique-rahman-bnp-for-election-victory</link><description>Germany has congratulated BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman and his party - Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) - on the election victory.
“Germany looks forward to working closely with the new government and the Jatiya Sangsad to further strengthen our political and economic ties, and to continue</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 15:44:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Arundhati Roy pulls out of Berlin film festival over jury comments on political films</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/arundhati-roy-pulls-out-of-berlin-film-festival-over-jury-comments-on-political-films</link><description>Indian novelist Arundhati Roy announced on Friday she was pulling out of the Berlin Film Festival after the head of the festival jury said filmmakers should avoid overtly political films.
Roy, winner of the Booker Prize in 1997 for her novel “The God of Small Things”, said in a stateme</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 15:59:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Some 99 MPs elected for first time in JS</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/some-99-mps-elected-for-first-time-in-js</link><description>As many as 99 candidates from different political parties, including Tarique Rahman, have won victory after participating for the first-time in the Jatiya Sangsad (JS) polls held February 12.
In the polls, as many as 10 young leaders of the second generation, successors of senior BNP leaders, have</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 16:14:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Siraz Uddin Miah named new cabinet secretary</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/siraz-uddin-miah-named-new-cabinet-secretary</link><description>The government has terminated the contract of cabinet secretary Sheikh Abdur Rashid and appointed M Siraz Uddin Miah as his successor, days before the new administration is sworn in.
The decision was announced in two separate official notifications issued on Friday.
One notification said the rema</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 16:29:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UK, allies say they’re convinced Kremlin critic Navalny was poisoned</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/uk-allies-say-theyre-convinced-kremlin-critic-navalny-was-poisoned</link><description>Britain, France, Germany, Sweden and the Netherlands are convinced that late Kremlin critic, Alexei Navalny, was poisoned with a lethal toxin in an Arcticpenal colony two years ago, they said in a joint statement on Saturday.
The five governments said their findings were based on analyses of sampl</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 16:44:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Newly elected MPs, new cabinet to be sworn in on Tuesday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/newly-elected-mps-new-cabinet-to-be-sworn-in-on-tuesday</link><description>The oath-taking ceremony of the newly elected members of parliament and new cabinet members will take place on Tuesday.
News portals said Chief Election Commissioner AMM Nasir Uddin will administer the oath of office to the newly elected members of parliament at Jatiya Sangsad on Tuesday morn</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 16:59:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>African Union summit clouded by Saudi-UAE rivalry in Horn of Africa</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/african-union-summit-clouded-by-saudi-uae-rivalry-in-horn-of-africa</link><description>A feud between Saudi Arabia and the United Arab Emirates across the Horn of Africa is overshadowing this weekend’s African Union summit, though most of the continent’s leaders will try to avoid taking sides, nine diplomats and experts said.
What began as a rivalry in Yemen has spread a</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 17:14:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Convincing people was BNP’s ‘engineering’, says Tarique Rahman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/convincing-people-was-bnps-engineering-says-tarique-rahman</link><description>BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman on Monday said convincing people to get two-thirds majority in the national election was their ‘engineering’ and no other manipulative tactics.“Convincing the people of the country and bringing them over to our side was our engineering. Alhamdulillah, w</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 17:29:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Post-poll violence: Supporter of independent candidate killed in Bagerhat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/post-poll-violence-supporter-of-independent-candidate-killed-in-bagerhat</link><description>A supporter of an independent candidate died on Saturday after being injured in a post-election clash with BNP supporters in Kachua upazila of Bagerhat.
The victim was identified as Osman Sardar, 29, son of Shahjahan Sardar of Par Nawapara village in Bagerhat Sadar upazila. He died around 11</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 17:44:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Inflation and cost of living crisis</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/inflation-and-cost-of-living-crisis</link><description>Bangladesh is facing its most severe cost-of-living crisis in recent history, characterised by the highest inflation in South Asia, projected at roughly 8.9 per cent in 2025 and expected to remain high in 2026. According to the Bangladesh Bureau of Statistics (BBS) data, inflation in Bangladesh inc</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 17:59:37 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>