<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 10:23:13 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>ChatGPT’s free ride is ending as OpenAI rolls out new plan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/chatgpts-free-ride-is-ending-as-openai-rolls-out-new-plan</link><description>OpenAI says it will soon start showing advertisements to ChatGPT users who aren’t paying for a premium version of the chatbot.
The artificial intelligence company said Friday it hasn’t yet rolled out ads but will start testing them in the coming weeks.
It’s the latest effort by</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 06:45:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shortage of lighterage vessels hampers cargo unloading</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/shortage-of-lighterage-vessels-hampers-cargo-unloading</link><description>CHATTAGRAM, Jan 16: Cargo handling operations at the outer anchorage of Chattogram port have been severely hampered due to an acute shortage of lighterage vessels, raising concerns over possible supply disruptions ahead of the holy month of Ramadan.
The disruption has slowed the unloading of goo</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 07:00:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>OMCH interns go on strike protesting attack on fellow</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/omch-interns-go-on-strike-protesting-attack-on-fellow</link><description>Interns at Sylhet Osmani Medical College and Hospital went on work abstention on Saturday morning, protesting the attack on a female intern allegedly by the relatives of a patient early Saturday.
Hospital sources said an altercation ensued between some interns and relatives of a patient over treat</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 07:15:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Death toll in Iran protests over 3,000, rights group says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/death-toll-in-iran-protests-over-3000-rights-group-says</link><description>More than 3,000 people have died in Iran's nationwide protests, rights activists said on Saturday, while a "very slight rise" in internet activity was reported in the country after an eight-day blackout.
The US-based HRANA group said it had verified 3,090 deaths, including 2,885 protesters, after</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 07:30:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>35 swimmers set out to cross Bangla Channel</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/35-swimmers-set-out-to-cross-bangla-channel</link><description>Thirty-five swimmers, including two women, have begun an attempt to swim across the Bangla Channel, a stretch of water off the coast of Bangladesh known for its strong currents.
The swim began in Cox's Bazar's Teknaf, with participants setting out from Shah Porir Dwip and aiming to reach the north</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 07:45:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Foreign adviser calls 15-year capital flight ‘bank robbery in broad daylight’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/foreign-adviser-calls-15-year-capital-flight-bank-robbery-in-broad-daylight</link><description>Foreign Affairs Adviser Touhid Hossain on Saturday described the massive capital flight from Bangladesh over the past 15 years as 'bank robbery in broad daylight'.
Speaking as the chief guest at the SAFA International Conference 2026, he highlighted that a significant portion of wealth had been si</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 08:00:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Eminent citizens urge BNP to uphold Khaleda's ideals</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/eminent-citizens-urge-bnp-to-uphold-khaledas-ideals</link><description>Eminent citizens, editors, academics, professionals and political observers on Friday commemorated Khaleda Zia as a leader who transcended partisan politics through dignity, restraint and a steadfast commitment to democratic values, urging BNP to emulate her ideals.
Speaking at a civic condolence</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 08:15:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Foreign operator of Pangaon terminal up with halved usage-cost plan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/foreign-operator-of-pangaon-terminal-up-with-halved-usage-cost-plan</link><description>Derelict-like Pangaon Inland Container Terminal (PICT) is poised for renascence as its Switzerland-based foreign operator formally begins operating the trade facility today with plans to halve the box-transportation costs.
Sources say the company, Medlog SA, comes up with this and ancillary offers</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 08:30:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>$1b Package For ERL Unit-2: IsDB technical mission likely in late January</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/1b-package-for-erl-unit-2-isdb-technical-mission-likely-in-late-january</link><description>The Islamic Development Bank (IsDB) is likely to send a technical mission to Bangladesh in late January as it may lend a record high of $1.0 billion for setting up an oil refinery, officials say.
The delegation aims to finalise the terms of the financing package for the long-delayed Eastern Refine</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 08:45:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mamunul Haque responds to EC show-cause over alleged code breach</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/mamunul-haque-responds-to-ec-show-cause-over-alleged-code-breach</link><description>Bangladesh Khelafat Majlis candidate Mamunul Haque has submitted a reply to a show-cause notice from the Election Commission (EC), rejecting allegations of violating the electoral code of conduct in the Dhaka-13 constituency.
He denied breaching the rules by distributing leaflets in favour of the</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 09:00:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Free, fearless media vital to Bangladesh democracy: Journalists</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/free-fearless-media-vital-to-bangladesh-democracy-journalists</link><description>Editors, journalists and media leaders from across the country on Saturday underscored the vital role of a free, independent, active and fearless media in sustaining democracy, warning that any attempt to silence media organisations ultimately threatens the rights of society as a whole.
“The</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 09:15:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Teknaf residents accuse armed group of planting landmines in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/teknaf-residents-accuse-armed-group-of-planting-landmines-in-bangladesh</link><description>Landmine explosions have become a grim reality along the Bangladesh-Rakhine border, leaving civilians wounded and heightening fears amid the ongoing civil war in Myanmar.
For the first time, however, a landmine blast inside Bangladesh severely injured a resident in Teknaf’s Whykong, causing</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 09:30:52 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>