<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 15:52:49 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>ICT brings formal charges against Menon, Qamrul over ‘killing’ during July Uprising</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ict-brings-formal-charges-against-menon-qamrul-over-killing-during-july-uprising</link><description>The International Crimes Tribunal (ICT) has formally charged Bangladesh Workers Party chief Rashed Khan Menon and former food minister Qamrul Islam with crimes against humanity over “killings” during the July Uprising.
On Tuesday, Prosecutor Gazi MH Tamim said “two charges of mur</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 12:52:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tax halved to 5.0pc on savings certificate up to Tk 500,000</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/nbr-cuts-source-tax-to-5-from-10-on-interest-for-investments-up-to-tk-500000</link><description>The National Board of Revenue (NBR) has said interest on National Savings Certificates (NSCs), popularly known as “Shonchoypotro”, for investments up to Tk 500,000 will be subject to a 5 per cent source tax, not 10 per cent.
A senior NBR official confirmed on Tuesday that the board sen</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 13:07:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Kamran Akmal slams ICC’s ‘double standards’ as Pakistan stand firm on skipping India clash</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/kamran-akmal-slams-iccs-double-standards-as-pakistan-stand-firm-on-skipping-india-clash</link><description>Former Pakistan wicketkeeper-batter Kamran Akmal has launched an attack on the International Cricket Council (ICC), urging the Pakistan Cricket Board (PCB) to stand firm on its decision to boycott the high-profile group match against India in the upcoming T20 World Cup.
Akmal's comments come amid</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 13:22:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Businessman arrested in Lakshmipur with six illegal election seals</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/businessman-arrested-in-lakshmipur-with-six-illegal-election-seals</link><description>Police in Lakshmipur have arrested a businessman, Sohel Rana, with six illegally made election seals. A mobile phone and a computer were also seized during the operation.
Sohel was detained Tuesday afternoon from Mariam Press on Puraton Adalat Road in the town. He is a resident of Tumchar Union in</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 13:37:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>July Museum highlights climax of 36 days, Hasina’s misrule: Foreign Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/july-museum-highlights-climax-of-36-days-hasinas-misrule-foreign-adviser</link><description>Foreign Affairs Adviser Md Touhid Hossain on Tuesday said the July Mass Uprising Memorial Museum reflects Bangladesh people’s struggle against the misrule of former Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina.
“The museum showcases the climax of the 36 days of the July uprising, but it also highlight</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 13:52:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique to deliver election address on BTV</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-to-deliver-election-address-on-btv</link><description>BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman will deliver an election address to the nation on Bangladesh Television (BTV) on February 9 ( Monday) ahead of the national election for February 12 next.
Following a letter sent to the Election Commission by BNP, Tarique Rahman has been allocated the time to air his sp</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 14:07:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt Purchase Committee approves fertiliser purchase deals</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-purchase-committee-approves-fertiliser-purchase-deals</link><description>The government on Tuesday approved separate proposals for procuring some 210 thousand metric tons of fertiliser from various sources to meet the country’s agricultural demand during the upcoming crop seasons.
The approvals came from the 5th meeting of the Advisers Council Committee on Govern</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 14:22:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>TIB failed to recognise work on reforms: Finance Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tib-failed-to-recognise-work-on-reforms-finance-adviser</link><description>Finance Adviser Dr Salehuddin Ahmed on Tuesday said Transparency International Bangladesh (TIB) has failed in many cases to properly recognise the government’s ongoing reform initiatives, arguing that not all reforms are immediately visible.
He made the remarks while speaking to reporters at</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 14:37:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>TIB failed to recognise work on reforms: Finance Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tib-failed-to-recognise-work-on-reforms-finance-adviser-1</link><description>Finance Adviser Dr Salehuddin Ahmed on Tuesday said Transparency International Bangladesh (TIB) has failed in many cases to properly recognise the government’s ongoing reform initiatives, arguing that not all reforms are immediately visible.
He made the remarks while speaking to reporters at</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 14:52:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Government sacks Biman MD Shafiqur, puts bureaucrat Humaira in charge</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/government-sacks-biman-md-shafiqur-puts-bureaucrat-humaira-in-charge</link><description>The government has fired Biman Bangladesh Airlines Managing Director and Chief Executive Officer Shafiqur Rahman after his arrest on charges of torturing a child domestic worker.
The Ministry of Civil Aviation and Tourism announced the decision in an office order on Tuesday.
Humaira Sultana, an a</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 15:07:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nurul Azim joins Shimanto Bank as MD &amp; CEO</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/nurul-azim-joins-shimanto-bank-as-md-ceo</link><description>Experienced banker Md. Nurul Azim has officially assumed office on Tuesday (03 February) as the Managing Director and Chief Executive Officer (MD &amp; CEO) of Shimanto Bank PLC. 
Prior to joining Shimanto Bank, he served as the Managing Director of Islamic Finance and Investment PLC, according t</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 15:22:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Purchase Committee approves power purchase proposals from three power plants</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/purchase-committee-approves-power-purchase-proposals-from-three-power-plants</link><description>The government on Tuesday approved power purchase proposals from three major combined cycle power plants at re-determined levelised tariffs, aiming to ensure grid stability while optimising electricity generation costs.
The approvals came from the 5th meeting of the Advisers Council Committee on G</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 15:37:51 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>