<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 22:19:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>External debt sustainability in the face of climate change</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/reviews/external-debt-sustainability-in-the-face-of-climate-change</link><description>There are two elements of standard public debt sustainability analysis. The sustainability of external debt and the sustainability of domestic debt. They are inter-related but often have different dimensions. Both are very important. As such, traditional debt sustainability assessment (DSA) conduct</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 16:58:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The danger of antibiotic resistance</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/the-danger-of-antibiotic-resistance</link><description>The invention of antibiotics was a milestone in the history of modern medicine and those were hailed as miracle drugs for their ability to prevent infections. These lifesaving drugs are now losing their effectiveness globally, much to the concern of health experts. The situation is particularly ala</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 16:29:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How short-sightedness bedevils industrial development</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/how-short-sightedness-bedevils-industrial-development</link><description>Accusing fingers were raised from some quarters at the three devastating fire incidents at Shialbari, Mirpur, Chittagong Export Process Zone (CEPZ) and the cargo village of Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport (HSIA) within a span of just five days. They found the bogey of sabotage. Such prematur</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 16:44:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Easing problems facing shrimp and fish export</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/easing-problems-facing-shrimp-and-fish-export</link><description>Releasing the outstanding cash assistance would provide at least a temporary reprieve. While it may not reverse the long-term export slump, timely disbursement could restore liquidity and enable exporters to meet commitments
 
Bangladesh's once-thriving shrimp- and frozen fish-export sector</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 16:59:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Putin says Russia will never bow to US pressure</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/putin-says-russia-will-never-bow-to-us-pressure</link><description>President Vladimir Putin said on Thursday that Russia would never bow to pressure from the United States or any other country, and cautioned that the response to any strikes deep into Russia would be very serious and overwhelming.
US sanctions are an "unfriendly" act and "will have certain consequ</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 17:29:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Next election to be most consequential in decades, says Brent Christensen</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/next-election-to-be-most-consequential-in-decades-says-brent-christensen</link><description>Brent Christensen, nominee for US Ambassador to Bangladesh, on Thursday said the people of Bangladesh will go to the polls early next year – the country’s most consequential election in decades – to choose a new government and a new path forward.
"The United States supports Bangl</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 17:44:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pakistan bans violent Islamist party for second time in four years</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/pakistan-bans-violent-islamist-party-for-second-time-in-four-years</link><description>Pakistan banned a violent Islamist party under the country's anti-terrorism law on Thursday, the government said, days after the group clashed with police in an anti-Israel rally and five people were killed.
Pakistan's cabinet has approved the ban, the government said in a statement.
The far-righ</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 17:59:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Messi extends Inter Miami contract to 2028</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/messi-extends-inter-miami-contract-to-2028</link><description>Lionel Messi has extended his contract with MLS side Inter Miami to 2028, the club announced on Thursday, a boost for the North American league as the Argentine great keeps his career going.
The eight-times Ballon d'Or winner had previously said that Inter Miami would be his last club but the 38-y</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 18:29:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BB now better equipped to handle errant banks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bb-now-better-equipped-to-handle-errant-banks</link><description>A clearly defined drive begins in acquisitions and mergers of problem banks as the regulator Thursday issued regulations for the Bank Resolution Ordinance 2025 made by the interim government for banking-sector reforms.



Officials said the regulations, rolled out by Bangladesh Bank-- the centr</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 18:59:30 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>