<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 13:36:37 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>The human onslaught on Karnaphuli</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/the-human-onslaught-on-karnaphuli</link><description>Karnaphuli is the lifeline of the country's economy as the Chittagong Port, the prime seaport of the country, is situated on this river. But the river is being polluted rampantly due to unabated dumping of toxic chemicals and solid waste into its water from the riverside industrial units. As a resu</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 10:42:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC registers 81 local observer groups ahead of polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/election-commission-registers-81-local-observer-groups-ahead-of-polls</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has registered 81 local observer organisations for a five-year term ahead of the parliamentary polls and referendum.
EC Assistant Director Md Ashadul Haque of the public relations branch confirmed the development on Monday.
More than 300 organisations had applied this</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 10:57:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Going green gets tough amid funding gap</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/going-green-gets-tough-amid-funding-gap</link><description>The ship-breaking industry in Chattogram, which was categorised as "Red" by the Department of Environment (DoE) on April 26 of 2023 is yet to be categorised as "Orange. As a result, the industry is suffering a lot and the supply of scrap iron for re-rolling mills in the country is being hampered. A</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 11:12:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Kremlin says India will continue to buy Russian oil if it's profitable</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/kremlin-says-india-will-continue-to-buy-russian-oil-if-its-profitable</link><description>The Kremlin said on Monday that India would continue buying oil wherever it was profitable to do so in order to ensure its own economic interests.
US President Donald Trump doubled tariffs on Indian goods to 50 percent in August to punish New Delhi for buying Russian oil, which Washington said was</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 11:27:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The controls indicate the scale of discrimination</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/the-controls-indicate-the-scale-of-discrimination</link><description>The trade and business at the commercial hub of Chattogram are suffering a lot, as the local businesses cannot supply the imported goods to other parts of the country smoothly due to the restrictive weighing scale set up at Boro Darogahat on the Dhaka-Chattogram highway.
Earlier, the goods-carryin</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 11:42:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Liberating Bangladesh was no mistake: Manju</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jp-chairman-manju-says-bangladeshs-independence-should-never-be-underestimated</link><description>Jatiya Party Chairman Anwar Hossain Manju has said Bangladesh's independence "should never be underestimated", though Bengalis have yet to overcome “a tendency to be jealous of others’ success”.
Speaking at the launch of the National Democratic Front (NDF) on Monday, he stressed</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 11:57:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prime Bank hosts inaugural ceremony of Bangladesh Bank's ‘Customer Awareness Week 2025’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/prime-bank-hosts-inaugural-ceremony-of-bangladesh-banks-customer-awareness-week-2025</link><description>Prime Bank PLC., in collaboration with Bangladesh Bank, recently organized the inaugural ceremony of ‘Customer Awareness Week 2025 (Dhaka Division)’ at the City Convention Hall in Kishoreganj. This event is organized under the theme ‘Building Awareness for Financial Security&amp;rsquo</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 12:12:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Conspiracies underway to undermine democracy: Tarique Rahman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/conspiracies-underway-to-undermine-democracy-tarique-rahman</link><description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman on Monday said the country is witnessing an abnormal situation due to the absence of democracy and a lack of accountable governance, warning that several plots are underway to undermine the democratic system and ensure its collapse.
Speaking at the concluding ses</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 12:27:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chattogram's forgotten Sazzalela's Dance Hall to become Bangladesh's maiden civil defence museum</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/chattograms-forgotten-sazzalelas-dance-hall-to-become-bangladeshs-maiden-civil-defence-museum</link><description>Tucked away onto Nawab Siraj-ud-Daulah Road in Chattogram's Chandanpura area, a timeworn structure stands steeped in history and faded grandeur. Once alive with the rhythmic jingle of ankle bells and the melodies of midnight performances, the 250-year-old Sazzalela's Dance Hall is now set to be reb</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 12:42:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>4th International Symposium on Quality Assurance in Engineering Education begins in Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/4th-international-symposium-on-quality-assurance-in-engineering-education-begins-in-dhaka</link><description>The 4th International Symposium on Quality Assurance in Engineering Education through Accreditation commenced in Dhaka on Monday, aiming to enhance and standardize the quality of engineering education in Bangladesh.
The two-day event, scheduled for December 8–9, is jointly organized by the B</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 12:57:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ACC files case against Obaidul Quader, 13 others for expressway flat scam</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/acc-files-case-against-obaidul-quader-13-others-for-expressway-flat-scam</link><description>The Anti Corruption Commission (ACC) on Monday filed a case against former chairman of Bangladesh Bridge Authority and former minister Obaidul Quader and 13 others over allegations of allocating flats to government officials and influential persons on the land acquired for resettling those affected</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 13:12:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shahadat Hossain Selim joins BNP dissolving his party</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/shahadat-hossain-selim-joins-bnp-dissolving-his-party</link><description>Shahadat Hossain, chairman of the Bangladesh Liberal Democratic Party (BLDP), joined BNP on Monday dissolving his own party.
He formally joined the party around 4:20 pm at the BNP chairperson’s Gulshan office, presenting a bouquet to BNP Standing Committee member Amir Khosru Mahmud Chowdhury</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 13:27:59 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>