<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 13:28:37 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>DU Fine Arts dean says ‘Sarat Utsob’ was postponed, not cancelled</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/du-fine-arts-dean-says-sarat-utsob-was-postponed-not-cancelled</link><description>Dhaka University's Faculty of Fine Arts Dean Azharul Islam has said reports of the “Sarat Utsob”, organised by Satyen Sen Shilpi Group to mark the arrival of autumn, being cancelled due to "objections" from some quarters are wide of the mark.
The festival has merely been postponed, rat</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 11:58:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Malaysia plans to spend $111 billion in 2026, boost tax collection</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/malaysia-plans-to-spend-111-billion-in-2026-boost-tax-collection</link><description>Malaysia said on Friday it plans to boost tax collection and strengthen social protection systems next year, as it looks to bolster government revenue amid external uncertainties.
Speaking in parliament, Prime Minister Anwar Ibrahim announced a budget of 470 billion ringgit ($111.40 billion) for 2</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 12:13:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CA thanks Erdoğan for cooperation in release of Shahidul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ca-thanks-erdogan-for-cooperation-in-release-of-shahidul</link><description>Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus on Friday thanked Turkish President Recep Tayyip Erdogan for his cooperation in securing the release of renowned Bangladeshi photographer and human rights activist Shahidul Alam and his repatriation from Israel.
Referring to Turkish sources, the Chief Adviser</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 11:15:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Latest US sanctions on Iranian oil deal blow to China's Sinopec</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/latest-us-sanctions-on-iranian-oil-deal-blow-to-chinas-sinopec</link><description>The latest US sanctions on Iranian petroleum exports deal a blow to Chinese refining giant Sinopec by targeting a terminal through which the state major handles one-fifth of its crude oil imports, industry executives and analysts said.
The sanctions announced on Thursday further complicate US-Chin</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 11:30:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Photographer Shahidul leaves Israel for Türkiye: CA press wing</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/photographer-shahidul-leaves-israel-for-turkiye-ca-press-wing</link><description>Renowned Bangladeshi photographer and human rights activist Shahidul Alam left Israel for Türkiye by a flight, Chief Adviser’s Press Wing said referring to Turkish sources.
“A flight took off from Israel this afternoon with renowned Bangladeshi photographer and human rights activi</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 11:45:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Peru Congress ousts president, successor vows ‘war on crime’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/peru-congress-ousts-president-successor-vows-war-on-crime</link><description>Peru's lawmakers swore in Congress chief Jose Jeri as the country's new president less than an hour after unanimously voting to remove President Dina Boluarte, as anger mounted over rising crime and accusations of corruption.
One of the world's least popular leaders was ousted shortly after midnig</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 12:00:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ex-chief of Bangladesh Navy Sarwar Jahan Nizam dies</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ex-chief-of-bangladesh-navy-sarwar-jahan-nizam-dies</link><description>Former Chief of Naval Staff Vice Admiral (Retd) Sarwar Jahan Nizam died at 9.15 am on Friday at Combined Military Hospital (CMH) in Dhaka.
He was 73. Members of the Bangladesh Navy, including the current chief of naval staff, have expressed deep sorrow over his death, an Inter-Services Public Rela</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 12:45:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat demands inclusion of PR proposal in referendum</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-demands-inclusion-of-pr-proposal-in-referendum</link><description>The Jamaat-e-Islami has demanded that the proposal for elections under a system of proportional representation (PR) be included in the referendum on the July Charter.
Secretary General Mia Golam Porwar made the call during a brief speech on Friday at the south gate of Baitul Mukarram National Mosq</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 13:00:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India to reopen embassy in Kabul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/india-upgrades-ties-with-afghanistans-taliban-says-it-will-reopen-kabul-embassy</link><description>India on Friday upgraded ties with Afghanistan's Taliban administration, giving a boost to the diplomatically isolated group, by announcing it would reopen its embassy in Kabul that was shut after the Taliban seized power in 2021.
The Afghan Taliban administration will also send diplomats to New D</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 13:15:08 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>