<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 11:18:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Six die in Karachi shopping mall fire</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/six-die-in-a-fire-at-shopping-mall-in-pakistans-karachi</link><description>At least six people have been killed in a massive fire that erupted at the Gul Plaza shopping mall in Pakistan’s Karachi, bdnews24.com reported citing Dawn.
The Pakistani newspaper said the operation to put out the blaze is still underway hours after it sparked.
On Sunday morning, South Dep</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 08:00:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Man arrested for ‘killing’ seven-year old daughter in Sherpur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/man-arrested-for-killing-seven-year-old-daughter-in-sherpur</link><description>A father allegedly strangled his daughter to death at Char Basanti Purba Para village of Nakla upazila of Sherpur on Sunday.
The deceased was Morium, 7, daughter of Babu Mia.
His another daughter, Mim Akter, aged three and a half years, was admitted to Sherpur District Hospital with injuries on n</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 08:15:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Police not protectors of any political party: Home adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/police-not-protectors-of-any-political-party-home-adviser</link><description>Home Affairs Adviser Lieutenant General (retd) Md Jahangir Alam Chowdhury on Sunday said the police are not protectors of any political party, as they are state employees funded by taxpayers’ money.
He emphasised that the primary responsibility of the police force is to serve the people and</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 08:30:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Minor boy killed in Jatrabari road crash</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/minor-boy-killed-in-jatrabari-road-crash</link><description>An 11-year-old boy was killed when a truck ran over him in the Jatrabari area of Dhaka on Sunday.
The deceased was identified as Md Zahid, 11, reports UNB.
Inspector Md Faruk, in charge of Dhaka Medical College and Hospital (DMCH) police camp, said the accident occurred around 12:30 am when the t</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 08:45:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Strong demand for cancellation of draft energy–power master plan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/strong-demand-for-cancellation-of-draft-energy-power-master-plan</link><description>Civil society organisations have strongly objected to the interim government’s 25-year “Energy &amp; Power Sector Master Plan (EPSMP): 2026-2050”.
At a press conference held on Sunday at the Dhaka Reporters Unity (DRU) auditorium, speakers demanded the immediate suspension and comple</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 09:00:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt clarifies CA’s support for ‘Yes’ vote in referendum</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-clarifies-cas-support-for-yes-vote-in-referendum</link><description>The interim government today (Sunday) clarified the Chief Adviser's support for the "Yes" vote in the forthcoming referendum is consistent with democratic norms in Bangladesh, outlining six major points in favour of the government's stance.
"Recent commentary has raised concerns that the Interim G</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 09:15:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt releases list of 80 vaccination centres for Hajj pilgrims</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-releases-list-of-80-vaccination-centres-for-hajj-pilgrims</link><description>The Ministry of Religious Affairs has published a list of 80 vaccination centres in the country for Hajj pilgrims to receive the required vaccines.
The ministry issued a notification in this regard, UNB reports. 
As per the Saudi government’s directives, Hajj pilgrims who have passed h</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 09:30:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Interns at Sylhet Osmani hospital call off work stoppage</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/interns-at-sylhet-osmani-hospital-call-off-work-stoppage</link><description>Intern doctors at Sylhet MAG Osmani Medical College Hospital have announced that they will call off their work stoppage after receiving assurances that their demands will be met.
After a meeting with the hospital authorities on Sunday afternoon, intern Mohammad Sadiq said that the protesting inter</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 09:30:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Verified deaths in Iran protests reaches at least 5,000: official</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/iranian-official-says-verified-deaths-in-iran-protests-reaches-at-least-5000</link><description>An Iranian official in the region said on Sunday the authorities had verified at least 5,000 people had been killed in protests in Iran, including about 500 security personnel, blaming "terrorists and armed rioters" for killing "innocent Iranians".
The official, who declined to be named due to the</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 09:45:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rule of law biggest challenge despite progress: Asif Nazrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rule-of-law-biggest-challenge-despite-progress-asif-nazrul</link><description>Law Adviser Dr Asif Nazrul on Sunday said establishing the rule of law remains the country’s biggest challenge, though significant progress has been made in that direction.
He, however, cautioned that achieving lasting success would be difficult without sincerity and commitment from an elect</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 10:00:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP plans separate department for families of July martyrs, fighters: Tarique</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-plans-separate-department-for-families-of-july-martyrs-fighters-tarique</link><description>BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman on Sunday said his party plans to create a separate department under the Ministry of Liberation War Affairs to support the families of martyrs and fighters of the July 2024 mass uprising, if it comes to power.
Speaking at a views-exchange programme with the families of</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 10:15:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Massive fire kills 6 in Karachi, destroys shopping centre</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/massive-fire-kills-6-in-karachi-destroys-shopping-centre</link><description>Firefighters in Pakistan's largest city were fighting to extinguish a massive blaze on Sunday that has killed six people and reduced parts of a shopping mall to rubble in Karachi's historic downtown.
Videos showed flames rising from the building as firefighters laboured through the night to stop t</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 10:30:47 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>