<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 21:18:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Jamaat candidate fined Tk 20,000 for violating election code in Feni</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jamaat-candidate-fined-tk-20000-for-violating-election-code-in-feni</link><description>Dr. Fakhruddin Manik, the Jamaat-e-Islami candidate for Feni-3 (Daganbhuiya-Sonagazi), has been fined Tk 20,000 for violating the election code of conduct.
On Friday afternoon, a mobile court held at Bibi Fatema Orphanage Madrasa in Daganbhuiya Upazila imposed the penalty. The court was conducted</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 15:45:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nomination of 5, including BNP nominee, cancelled in Jashore</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nomination-of-5-including-bnp-nominee-cancelled-in-jashore</link><description>The nomination papers of five candidates, including a BNP nominee, have been rejected in the verification process for two parliamentary constituencies in Jashore ahead of the 13th national election.
The decision was announced on Friday by District Commissioner and Returning Officer Mohammad Ashek</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 16:00:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Theft at temple in Sirajganj, police launch investigation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/theft-at-temple-in-sirajganj-police-launch-investigation</link><description>A temple in the Purbo Solapara neighbourhood of Tarash municipality in Sirajganj was hit by a daring theft, with thieves breaking open the donation box and making off with cash and other valuables.
The incident has sparked widespread anger among locals in the temple area. Tarash police station OC</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 16:15:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rajshahi Police Constable withdrawn over woman's TikTok video in uniform</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rajshahi-police-constable-withdrawn-over-womans-tiktok-video-in-uniform</link><description>A police constable in Rajshahi has been withdrawn from his post after a woman filmed a TikTok video wearing his uniform, on Thursday.
Constable Saifuzzaman, stationed at Kashiadanga Police Station, came under scrutiny after it was reported that he was living with a woman named Sima Khatun without</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 16:30:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jaishankar wishes Bangladesh well for polls, hopes deepened neighbourly ties</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jaishankar-wishes-bangladesh-well-for-polls-hopes-deepened-neighbourly-ties</link><description>Wishing Bangladesh well for the upcoming national election, Indian External Affairs Minister Dr S Jaishankar on Friday said the sense of neighbourlyness in the region will grow once things settle down.
"Right now, they (Bangladesh) are heading for elections. We wish them well in that elections. We</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 16:45:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Affidavit shows JSD leader Tania Rab far wealthier than Abdur Rab</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/affidavit-shows-jsd-leader-tania-rab-far-wealthier-than-abdur-rab</link><description>Tania Rab, senior vice-president of Jatiya Samajtantrik Dal-JSD, has declared assets worth nearly 14 times more than those of her husband and party chief ASM Abdur Rab.
The affidavits filed with her nomination for the Lakshmipur-4 constituency in the general election show her annual also surpasses</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 17:00:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A diplomatic note under public scrutiny</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/a-diplomatic-note-under-public-scrutiny</link><description>The condolence letter, penned and signed by Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi and addressed to Tarique Rahman in tribute to Khaleda Zia upon her passing, has arrived in Bangladesh at a moment in history laden with meaning. On one hand, since it is couched in terms of a formal expression of sympat</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 17:15:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Economy: Let's set the tone right in 2026</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/reviews/economy-lets-set-the-tone-right-in-2026</link><description>Despite known and evolving challenges, Bangladesh economy has demonstrated good consolidation in 2025. Market liquidity especially foreign currency liquidity improved much with significant rise in wage earners' remittances, moderate rise in exports and foreign aid disbursement. Inflation continued</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 17:30:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Year 2026 and a few key anniversaries</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/year-2026-and-a-few-key-anniversaries</link><description>Another year on the Gregorian calendar, the globally accepted civil calendar, began two days ago on Thursday. People around the world enthusiastically welcomed 2026. Celebrating the night of December 31 to say goodbye to the old year and greet January 1 is mainly a Western tradition. Over the decad</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 17:45:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dignified farewell to Begum Zia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/dignified-farewell-to-begum-zia</link><description>As an ending, it was the height of dignity. Hundreds of thousands of Bangladeshis from across the country gathered to pay their last respects, alongside foreign delegates, as she was laid to rest with full state honours beside her husband. This collective act of homage stood as a final testament to</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 18:00:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Developing a pre-poll cybersecurity wall</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/developing-a-pre-poll-cybersecurity-wall</link><description>With the 13th parliamentary election drawing closer and campaigns launched by different political parties going to start in full swing soon, the cyberspace is abuzz. So, alongside an expected atmosphere of festive electioneering, there are also the dangers of a rising spate of cybercrimes. Evidentl</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 18:15:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mobile-phone users startled finding myriad devices under each NID</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/mobile-phone-users-startled-finding-myriad-devices-under-each-nid</link><description>A ruckus centering the National Equipment Identity Register (NEIR) rollout has ensued and a weird revelation of umpteen devices surreptitiously connected with each NID startled mobile-phone users.



The bizarre finds stoke concerns among the users as to whether their sets were being used by fr</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 18:30:55 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>