<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 05:22:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Tax target revised upward by Tk 540b</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/tax-target-revised-upward-by-tk-540b</link><description>The government has reviser the tax-revenue-collection target upward by Tk 540 billion to meet a growing need for internal resources to manage budget deficit.
Debt service has become a major headache for the government as loans taken from foreign and domestic sources have reached an optimum level.</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 01:53:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Early signs of economic recovery emerge amid sluggish growth: MCCI</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/early-signs-of-economic-recovery-emerge-amid-sluggish-growth-mcci</link><description>The first quarter (Q1) of the current fiscal year shows early signs of economic recovery, though overall growth remains sluggish, the Metropolitan Chamber of Commerce and Industry, Dhaka (MCCI) has said.
"Improvements in exports, imports, inflation, and remittances have helped stabilise foreign-cu</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 02:08:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Agent banking loses steam amid new female participation rule</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/agent-banking-loses-steam-amid-new-female-participation-rule</link><description>The expansion of agent banking in Bangladesh has slowed, both in terms of outlets and agents, a development widely attributed to a new regulatory requirement aimed at increasing female participation in the sector.
Bangladesh Bank data shows the number of new agent bankers fell from 16,019 in Decem</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 02:23:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bhutan's first transit shipment thru Ctg port set for release today</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bhutans-first-transit-shipment-thru-ctg-port-set-for-release-today</link><description>CHATTOGRAM: Bhutan's maiden transit shipment through Chattogram port is scheduled for delivery today (Tuesday), two months after its arrival was delayed due to pending approvals from multiple agencies.
The container, unloaded in September, remained stuck as several clearances were not issued on ti</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 02:38:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt lends Tk 10b to troubled ICB to invest in stocks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/govt-lends-tk-10b-to-troubled-icb-to-invest-in-stocks</link><description>The Investment Corporation of Bangladesh (ICB) gets a Tk10-billion in interest-bearing government loan to invest in stocks to resuscitate bearish bourses of the country, sources say.
It's seen as a significant move as the decision comes just days after reports surfaced regarding the Finance Minist</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 03:39:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tradecap trading halted after licence renewal withheld with no explanation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/tradecap-trading-halted-after-licence-renewal-withheld-with-no-explanation</link><description>Trading at Tradecap Stock Brokerage was suspended on Monday because the securities regulator did not respond to its licence renewal application when the Dhaka bourse sought clearance.
The brokerage firm said it had worked for nine months to ensure compliance with regulatory requirements for the re</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 03:11:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nine children killed in Pakistani attack in Afghan province, Taliban says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/nine-children-killed-in-pakistani-attack-in-afghan-province-taliban-says</link><description>At least nine children and a woman were killed after Pakistani forces bombed the home of a local resident in Afghanistan's Khost province, Afghan Taliban spokesman Zabihullah Mujahid said on Tuesday.
Mujahid said Pakistan also carried out raids in the provinces of Kunar and Paktika, injuring four</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 03:26:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Most banks see high technology costs, cybersecurity concerns as key barriers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/most-banks-see-high-technology-costs-cybersecurity-concerns-as-key-barriers</link><description>Some 90 per cent of surveyed banks have identified the high cost of technology as the key obstacle to the digitalisation of trade finance in Bangladesh, a research report has revealed.
The report, titled 'Digitalization of Trade Finance: Status and Prospects', also revealed other significant barri</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 03:41:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sramik Karmachari Oikya Parishad to blockade Ctg port tomorrow</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/sramik-karmachari-oikya-parishad-to-blockade-ctg-port-tomorrow</link><description>CHATTOGRAM, Nov 24: Leaders of the Sramik Karmachari Oikya Parishad (SKOP) will impose a three-hour blockade of the Chittagong Port beginning at 10:00 am tomorrow, as their meeting with officials of Chittagong Port Authority (CPA) failed on Monday.
CPA Secretary Omar Faruk, however, said that the</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 03:56:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>France seeks to boost investment in BD</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/france-seeks-to-boost-investment-in-bd</link><description>France has expressed strong interest in expanding its investment footprint in Bangladesh, particularly in the pharmaceutical and Information and Communication Technology (ICT) sectors.
French Ambassador Jean-Marc Serre-Charlet made the commitment during a meeting with Commerce Adviser Sk Bashir Ud</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 04:11:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>200 sued, but none named, over attack on followers of Baul Abul Sarkar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/200-sued-but-none-named-over-attack-on-followers-of-baul-abul-sarkar</link><description>A case has been filed against 200 unidentified individuals in connection with the attack on followers of Baul artiste Abul Sarkar, police said on Monday evening.
Md Aminul Islam, Inspector (Investigation) of Manikganj Sadar Police Station, said injured Baul artiste Abdul Alim filed the case. The a</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 04:26:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Include water issues in election manifesto</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/include-water-issues-in-election-manifesto</link><description>International Farakka Committee (IFC) Bangladesh called on all the political parties to include the country's most pressing water issues in their election manifestoes.
They made the call at a press briefing in the city on Monday, says a press release.
IFC New York Chairman Sayed Tipu Sultan and I</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 04:41:10 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>