<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 17:57:54 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Miscreants fire blanks at BNP activist’s house in Raozan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/miscreants-fire-blanks-at-bnp-activists-house-in-raozan</link><description>Armed miscreants opened fire on the house of an expatriate BNP activist in Raozan of Chattogram around noon on Wednesday (February 11), a day before Bangladesh’s polls.
The incident took place at the house of Rustom Ali in Shamsherpara village under Kodolpur Union. Rustom Ali, a BNP activist</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 14:44:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat complains to EC about attacks, intimidation on election eve</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-complains-to-ec-about-attacks-intimidation-on-election-eve</link><description>Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islam on Wednesday lodged a series of complaints with the Election Commission, alleging attacks, intimidation of its leaders and activists and vandalism of party offices across the country in an attempt to undermine the election-friendly environment ahead of Thursday’s ele</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 14:59:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Australia begin T20 World Cup with 67-run win over Ireland</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/australia-begin-t20-world-cup-with-67-run-win-over-ireland</link><description>Australia launched their Twenty20 World Cup campaign with a commanding 67-run victory over Ireland in Colombo on Wednesday, powered by four-wicket hauls from Nathan Ellis and Adam Zampa.
Australia shrugged off the last-minute pullout of captain Mitchell Marsh to post 182-6 in 20 overs, after stand</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 15:14:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC dismisses rumours, says voting will go ahead without a doubt</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-dismisses-rumours-says-voting-will-go-ahead-without-a-doubt</link><description>Hours before Bangladesh heads to the general election, the Election Commission has dismissed rumours that the vote might not take place.
In a notice issued Wednesday evening, the EC urged voters not to be misled and to cast their ballots between 7:30am and 4:30pm on Thursday.
The commission said</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 15:25:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Any attempt to thwart elections to face mass resistance: BNP</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/any-attempt-to-thwart-elections-to-face-mass-resistance-bnp</link><description>BNP on Wednesday warned that any attempt to obstruct Thursday’s elections or create any disorder would face mass resistance from people, stressing that a firm stance by the Election Commission (EC) is crucial to ensure a peaceful polling environment.
“Whoever tries to resist the electi</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 15:40:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IRS improperly disclosed confidential immigrant tax data to DHS, Washington Post reports</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/irs-improperly-disclosed-confidential-immigrant-tax-data-to-dhs-washington-post-reports</link><description>The Internal Revenue Service improperly disclosed confidential tax information of thousands of people to federal immigration authorities, the Washington Post reported on Wednesday, citing three people familiar with the situation.
The newspaper said the IRS recently discovered the mistake and is wo</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 15:55:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>2 Jamaat polling agents jailed in Mirpur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/2-jamaat-polling-agents-jailed-in-mirpur</link><description>A mobile court has sentenced two polling agents representing the Jamaat-e-Islami to two years in prison for entering a booth and attempting to exert undue influence in Dhaka’s Mirpur.
The incident occurred at the Shaheed Smriti High School centre on the eve of the parliamentary election on W</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 16:10:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BUBT professor’s wife Fahmin Afroz Taslim dies at 59</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bubt-professors-wife-fahmin-afroz-taslim-dies-at-59</link><description>Fahmin Afroz Taslim, wife of Prof Dr Muhammad Mahboob Ali of the Bangladesh University of Business and Technology (BUBT), has passed away.
She died in Dhaka on Monday, Feb 9, after suffering from a complicated illness. She was 59.
She is survived by her son, Nawazish Muhammad Ali, and other relat</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 16:25:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US to join WHO meeting on influenza vaccine composition</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/us-to-participate-in-meeting-on-influenza-vaccine-composition-who-official-says</link><description>The United States will participate in a World Health Organisation meeting at the end of the month to determine the composition of upcoming influenza vaccines, the agency's official said at a press conference on Wednesday.
Maria Van Kerkhove, the WHO's director for epidemic and pandemic preparednes</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 16:40:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC warns of action over vote‑buying</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/election-commission-vows-strict-action-if-proof-of-vote-trading-emerges</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has warned of “strict action” if evidence of vote buying emerges in the national election and referendum.
The warning came in a media statement issued around 9pm on Wednesday, a day before polling, amid widespread discussion over alleged cash transactions a</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 16:55:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Iran says it won't negotiate over its missile capabilities</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/iran-says-it-wont-negotiate-over-its-missile-capabilities</link><description>Iran's missile capabilities are its red line and are not a subject to be negotiated, an adviser to Iran's supreme leader said on Wednesday, as Tehran and Washington eye a new round of talks to avert conflict.
US and Iranian diplomats held indirect talks last week in Oman, amid a regional naval bui</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 17:10:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Central law and order cell set up for polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-sets-up-central-law-and-order-cell-ahead-of-election</link><description>The Election Commission has set up a Central Law and Order Coordination Cell to help ensure that the national election and referendum are held in a fair and peaceful manner.
The cell is operating from Room 417 of the Election Commission building.
It has been established to facilitate information-</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 17:25:21 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>