<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 10:23:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Elon Musk becomes first person worth $700 billion</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/elon-musk-becomes-first-person-worth-700-billion</link><description>Tesla CEO Elon Musk's net worth surged to $749 billion late Friday after the Delaware Supreme Court reinstated Tesla stock options worth $139 billion that were voided last year, according to Forbes' billionaires index.
Musk's 2018 pay package, once worth $56 billion, was restored by the Delaware S</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 05:15:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India shuts visa application centre in Ctg over security concerns</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/india-shuts-visa-application-centre-in-ctg-over-security-concerns</link><description>The Indian Visa Application Centre (IVAC) in Chattogram has been closed indefinitely due to security concerns.
The Indian Assistant High Commission announced that all operations at the centre will remain suspended from Sunday until further notice.
In a statement, published on the visa application</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 05:30:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Stocks open on negative note</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/stocks-open-on-negative-note</link><description>Trading at both the Dhaka and Chattogram stock exchanges began on a negative note on Sunday, with key indices falling in the first hour amid widespread price declines.
At the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE), the benchmark DSEX index shed 21 points in early trading.
The Shariah-based DSES index fell by</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 05:45:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Motorcyclist killed after losing control in Jhenaidah</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/motorcyclist-killed-after-losing-control-in-jhenaidah</link><description>A youth was killed, and another was injured after a motorcycle lost control in front of the Cadet College of Jhenaidah on Saturday night. 
The deceased was identified as Tanvir Rahman, 25, while the injured pillion rider is Akash Hossain, 22, reports BSS.
Tanvir Rahman is the son</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 06:00:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Janaza of 6 Bangladeshi peacekeepers killed in Sudan held</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/janaza-of-6-bangladeshi-peacekeepers-killed-in-sudan-held</link><description>The namaz-e-Janaza of six Bangladeshi peacekeepers, who were killed in a drone attack on a UN peacekeeping base in Sudan’s Abyei region, were held on Sunday morning at the central mosque of Dhaka Cantonment.
Representatives from the Chief Adviser, Chief of Army Staff General Waker-Uz-Zaman,</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 06:15:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>In Antarctica, photos show a remote area teeming with life amid growing risks from climate change</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/in-antarctica-photos-show-a-remote-area-teeming-with-life-amid-growing-risks-from-climate-change</link><description>The Southern Ocean is one of the most remote places on Earth, but that doesn't mean it is tranquil. Tumultuous waves that can swallow vessels ensure that the Antarctic Peninsula has a constant drone of ocean. While it can be loud, the view is serene — at first glance, it is only deep blue wat</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 06:30:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Police arrest former UP chairman’s son over threat to NCP leader in Noakhali</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/police-arrest-former-up-chairmans-son-over-threat-to-ncp-leader-in-noakhali</link><description>Police have arrested a man on charges of threatening to kill Abdul Hannan Masud, a senior joint chief coordinator of the National Citizen Party (NCP) and a potential candidate for the Noakhali-6 constituency.
The arrestee, Israt Raihan Ome, is the son of former chairman of Charishwar Union Parisha</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 07:15:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Man murdered in bed while wife sleeps next to him</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/man-murdered-in-bed-while-wife-sleeps-next-to-him</link><description>Police have recovered the throat-slit body of a man from his own house in Naria Para village of Netrokona Sadar.
The deceased was identified as Helal Uddin, 60, son of the late Ashrab Uddin of the same village. Helal was a farmer.
He had been sleeping in his room with his wife, Bedena Akhter. Ear</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 07:30:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ACC files three cases against S Alam Group entities over Tk 62b 'loan embezzlement'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/acc-files-three-cases-against-s-alam-group-entities-over-tk-62b-loan-embezzlement</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) has filed three more cases against companies linked to the controversial business conglomerate S Alam Group over allegations of large-scale loan embezzlement during the tenure of the ousted Awami League government.
The cases accuse the group’s chairman Sa</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 08:01:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CEC holds meeting with chiefs of three services</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cec-holds-meeting-with-chiefs-of-three-services</link><description>Chief Election Commissioner (CEC) AMM Nasir Uddin held an hour long meeting with the chiefs of Bangladesh Army, Navy and Air Force at Nirbachan Bhaban in Dhaka on Sunday.
The meeting began around 12pm and ended at 1pm.
However, the outcomes of the meeting are yet to be made public.
The CEC is sc</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 08:16:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ministry of Home Affairs to hold emergency meeting this evening</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ministry-of-home-affairs-to-hold-emergency-meeting-this-evening</link><description>The Ministry of Home Affairs has called an emergency press conference at 5:30pm today to brief journalists on the country’s overall law and order situation.
Home Affairs Advisor Lieutenant General (retd.) Md. Jahangir Alam Chowdhury is expected to answer questions from reporters at the brief</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 08:31:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No breach attempt at Bangladesh High Commission during protest: India</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/no-breach-attempt-at-bangladesh-high-commission-during-protest-india</link><description>About the reported demonstration in front of the Bangladesh High Commission in New Delhi on December 20, official spokesperson at the Indian Ministry of External Affairs Randhir Jaiswal on Sunday said there was no attempt to breach the fence or create a security situation at any time.
India is com</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 10:00:12 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>