<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 07:51:11 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>US greets BNP, Tarique Rahman on poll victory</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/us-greets-bnp-tarique-rahman-on-poll-victory</link><description>The United States has congratulated the people of Bangladesh for successfully holding the national election, and extended its best wishes to the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) and its chairman Tarique Rahman for their historic victory.
In a statement issued by the US Embassy on Friday morning,</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 02:55:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat pledges positive politics</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-pledges-positive-politics</link><description>Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami Ameer Dr Shafiqur Rahman has alleged that results of a number of constituencies were not being declared.
"We are certain as we have signed papers that show that we (Jamaat alliance candidates) are leading. But the outcome of the voting is yet to be declared," he told the</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 03:10:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>First-time voters turn out in force</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/first-time-voters-turn-out-in-force</link><description>First-time voters turned out in large numbers across the capital on Thursday, many expressing enthusiasm and high expectations for political and institutional change.
For these young citizens, the 13th national election represents more than a routine exercise in democracy - it is an opportunity to</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 03:25:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Global media hail peaceful Bangladesh polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/global-media-hail-peaceful-bangladesh-polls</link><description>International media outlets have described Thursday's parliamentary elections in Bangladesh as largely peaceful and mostly free of violence, as vote counting progressed following the country's first national election since the 2024 mass uprising.
Global coverage framed the election as a significan</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 03:40:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Barrister Fuad congratulates his opponent on victory</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/barrister-fuad-congratulates-his-opponent-on-victory</link><description>Barishal-3 (Babuganj–Muladi) candidate Barrister Fuad has congratulated his opponent, Zainul Abedin, on his electoral victory, expressing gratitude to the voters and party leaders who supported him throughout the campaign.
In a Facebook post on Friday morning, he thanked the 61,192 respected</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 04:58:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Modi congratulates Tarique Rahman on BNP’s decisive poll victory</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/modi-congratulates-tarique-rahman-on-bnps-decisive-poll-victory</link><description>Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi on Friday conveyed his warm congratulations to Tarique Rahman on leading BNP to a decisive victory in the Parliamentary elections in Bangladesh.
“This victory shows the trust of the people of Bangladesh in your leadership,” Modi said in a message.
I</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 05:13:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat warns of tough movement if electoral manipulation is found</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-warns-of-tough-movement-if-electoral-manipulation-is-found</link><description>Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami on Friday warned of launching a tough movement if people’s opinions and voting rights are manipulated through any conspiracy.
Jamaat’s Assistant Secretary General Ehsanul Mahbub Jubayer came up with the warning while talking to reporters on The Election &amp;nbsp</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC withholds results of three constituencies</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-withholds-results-of-three-constituencies</link><description>The Election Commission has decided to withhold the results of three constituencies as court cases are pending against the declared winning candidates.
The constituencies are Sherpur-2, Chattogram-2 and Chattogram-4.
The EC issued three separate letters in this regard on Thursday.
The EC said th</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 05:43:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Syndicate profits from illegal Rohingya settlements established razing hills</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/syndicate-profits-from-illegal-rohingya-settlements-established-razing-hills</link><description>COX'S BAZAR, Feb 12: A well-organised syndicate has allegedly been running a lucrative rental business by establishing illegal Rohingya settlements outside the registered refugee camps in Ukhiya and Teknaf of Cox's Bazar, cutting down hills to create makeshift housing.
During a joint forces operat</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 05:58:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pakistan PM congratulates Tarique Rahman, pledges closer ties</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/pakistan-pm-congratulates-tarique-rahman-on-election-win-pledges-closer-ties</link><description>Pakistan's Prime Minister Shehbaz Sharif has congratulated Tarique Rahman on "leading the BNP to a resounding victory" in the elections.
"I look forward to working closely with the new Bangladesh leadership to further strengthen our historic, brotherly multifaceted bilateral relations and advance</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 06:30:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Use of chemical fertilisers deteriorates soil quality in Pabna</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/use-of-chemical-fertilisers-deteriorates-soil-quality-in-pabna</link><description>PABNA, Feb 12: The quality of soil in Pabna's arable land has been deteriorating due to the use of chemical fertilisers and the resulting situation include abnormal rise of phosphorus and reduction of pH and organic matter in the soil, among other technical factors, according to soil researchers.</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 06:45:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Houses built for homeless get stolen in Gaibandha</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/houses-built-for-homeless-get-stolen-in-gaibandha</link><description>GAIBANDHA, Feb 12: Some 76 vacant houses out of the 110 built to shelter the homeless and the landless in Chandipur village of Gaibandha's Gobindaganj were stolen, leaving only concrete-made poles behind.
The houses, built under the former government's Guchchagram project, featured tin roofs and</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 07:00:46 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>