<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 11:18:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Jamaat, seven other parties hold meeting with CEC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-seven-other-parties-hold-meeting-with-cec</link><description>Delegations from eight political parties who came to the Election Commission (EC) to submit a memorandum demanding a referendum in November have met Chief Election Commissioner AMM Nasir Uddin.
EC Secretary Akhtar Ahmed was also present at the meeting, which began at 1pm on Thursday, reports bdn</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 08:44:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Factors affecting growth of industrial credit</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/factors-affecting-growth-of-industrial-credit</link><description>The modest surge in the disbursement of industrial credit in the last fiscal year may be considered as a sign of a rebound in the industrial activities in the country, as well as overall economic growth. Although many other economic indicators are already available, the central bank released the an</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 08:38:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Child kidnapped using 'devil breath' in Dhaka rescued, 3 held</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/child-kidnapped-using-devil-breath-in-dhaka-rescued-3-held</link><description>Members of Rapid Action Battalion (RAB)-4 rescued a four-year-old girl, who was abducted using ‘devil breath’, from Pallabi area of Dhaka and arrested three people from Keraniganj of Dhaka on Wednesday.
The arrestees were Swapan Sardar, 41, Beauty Begum, 40 and Nargis Begum, 30, UNB re</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 08:53:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hold polls by February to save country from ‘civil war-like situation’: Patwary</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/hold-polls-by-february-to-save-country-from-civil-war-like-situation-patwary</link><description>National Citizen Party (NCP) chief coordinator Nasiruddin Patwary on Thursday urged the government to hold elections by February to save the country from a ‘civil war-like situation’.
“The country is heading toward a different kind of situation. Announce elections by February. If</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 09:23:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC to sit for first inter-ministry meeting ahead of election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ec-to-sit-for-first-inter-ministry-meeting-ahead-of-election</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) will exchange views with the senior officials of ministries, departments, directorates, agencies and authorities with connections to preparations for the 13th national parliamentary election.
Chief Election Commissioner AMM Nasir Uddin will preside over the meeting at</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 09:38:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>4 SPs promoted to DIG</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/4-sps-promoted-to-dig</link><description>Four Superintendents of Police (SPs)  have been promoted to Deputy Inspector General (DIG).
The Public Security Division under the Home Ministry issued a notification in this regard on Thursday, UNB reports. 
They are-Md. Shahrier, superintendent of Anti-Terrorism unit, Mohammad Abdul K</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 09:53:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Education cadre lecturers warn of 'work stoppage' for promotions</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/education-cadre-lecturers-warn-of-work-stoppage-demanding-promotions</link><description>“Promotion-deprived” lecturers of the Bangladesh Civil Service (BCS) General Education Cadre have demanded that those eligible be promoted by Nov 12.
They warned of a work stoppage if their demand is not met.
The lecturers staged a sit-in demonstration at the Shikkha Bhaban premises s</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 10:23:52 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>