<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 23:17:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Jatiya Party leader Mamunur Rashid ‘co-conspirator’ to US citizen, police say</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jatiya-party-leader-mamunur-rashid-co-conspirator-to-us-citizen-police-say</link><description>Police have claimed that Kazi Md Mamunur Rashid, secretary general of the Raushon Ershad-led faction of the Jatiya Party, was working as an associate of Enayet Karim Chowdhury, a US citizen of Bangladeshi origin who was detained for “suspicious movement” on Dhaka’s Minto Road.
Ba</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 16:37:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ACC reassigns investigation of Shakib’s ‘illicit’ wealth to Sajjad</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/acc-reassigns-investigation-of-shakibs-illicit-wealth-to-sajjad</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission has appointed Sajjad Hossain, who was investigating the money laundering charges against Shakib Al Hasan, to lead the inquiry into the cricketer’s alleged illegal assets.
Earlier, Mahbubul Alam, the ACC's deputy director, was responsible for investigating the c</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 17:36:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Extortion attempt’ in Chattogram’s Bayazid as armed men fire shots, attack workers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/extortion-attempt-in-chattograms-bayazid-as-armed-men-fire-shots-attack-workers</link><description>An armed gang has halted construction at a building site in Chattogram’s Bayazid after firing blank shots in public and assaulting workers over an “extortion demand”.
The incident took place on Saturday morning at Uttara Housing Society under Bayazid Bostami Police Station, promp</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 17:51:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nepal's revolution and India's backyard diplomacy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/nepals-revolution-and-indias-backyard-diplomacy</link><description>Kathmandu’s blazes of this month are not just Nepal’s issue—their peril is for South Asia. The explosion of protests by Nepal’s impatient youth against corruption, elitism, and inequality toppled Prime Minister KP Sharma Oli and rattled the very foundations of Nepal’s</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 18:06:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>What is happening to hilsa?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/what-is-happening-to-hilsa</link><description>Is hilsa really leaving the shores of Bangladesh? Reports of constantly falling hilsa catch during the peak monsoon breeding season (July to October) is indeed concerning. Though hilsa's share of the nation's total fish production is only 12 per cent, yet hilsa, which is Bangladesh's national fish</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 18:21:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Inflation battle faces fresh hurdles</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/inflation-battle-faces-fresh-hurdles</link><description>Managing inflation remains the thorn in the interim government's side. Just when there were signs of respite a couple of months ago, consumer prices have surged again-this time driven by the twin shocks of rising rice and vegetable prices. To compound matters, edible oil markets are beginning to be</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 18:36:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Exploring potential of service sector</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/exploring-potential-of-service-sector</link><description>Bangladesh has failed to keep pace with the burgeoning service sector worldwide in line with digital economy. But the country's demography with the highest ever percentage of working population of 39.39 per cent should have taken advantage of the service sector instead of pursuing cheap labour in t</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 18:51:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Police fired over 305,000 rounds during Uprising: probe finds</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/police-fired-over-305000-rounds-during-uprising-probe-finds</link><description>During the student protests in the July Uprising last year, police fired as many as 305,311 rounds of ammunition across the country under instructions from deposed prime minister Sheikh Hasina, an investigation has revealed.
These bullets were used in an attempt to suppress the movement, with 95,3</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 19:06:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two-thirds of female garment workers marry before 18: study</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/study-reveals-two-thirds-of-garment-workers-marry-before-18-in-bangladesh</link><description>A study has found that two out of three female garment workers in Bangladesh marry before the age of 18, shedding light on the harsh realities faced by women working in the country’s apparel industry.
The research, conducted by the International Centre for Diarrhoeal Disease Research, Bangla</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 19:21:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>WB offers budget support credit for smooth transition</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/wb-offers-budget-support-credit-for-smooth-transition</link><description>Bangladesh expects US$300-500 million in fresh budget support from the World Bank as the WB has offered the credit to assist with its smooth graduation from the least-developed country (LDC) status in November next year, officials say.
A delegation of the World Bank made the overtures at a rec</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 19:36:49 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>