<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 11:20:04 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Election, referendum to be held on same day: Yunus</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/election-referendum-to-be-held-on-same-day-yunus</link><description>Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus has announced that the upcoming national election and referendum will be held on the same day as part of the implementation process of the July National Charter.
He made the announcement in a televised address to the nation at 2:30 pm on Thursday, following a</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 09:45:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BTV to get autonomy as part of institutional reforms: Mahfuj Alam</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/btv-to-get-autonomy-as-part-of-institutional-reforms-mahfuj-alam</link><description>Information and Broadcasting Adviser Md. Mahfuj Alam today (Thursday) said that the journey of a new Bangladesh began through the sacrifices of the martyrs and the injured of the July Revolution in 2024.
"The spirit of this revolution is guiding us on the path of building a discrimination-free, ju</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 10:00:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Grand inauguration of month-long video content creation competition centered on Ziaur Rahman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/grand-inauguration-of-month-long-video-content-creation-competition-centered-on-ziaur-rahman</link><description>In observance of 'National Revolution and Solidarity Day 2025,' Jatiyatabader Pathshala and 7th November Projonmo (7th November Generation) have jointly organized a month-long video content creation competition centered on Shaheed President Ziaur Rahman (Bir Uttam). 
 
The event is bein</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 09:05:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Husband sentenced to death for murder of female doctor at hotel</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/husband-sentenced-to-death-for-murder-of-female-doctor-at-hotel</link><description>A court has sentenced Rezaul Karim Reza to death in a case for killing his wife, Dr Jannatul Naim Siddika, after taking her to a residential hotel in Dhaka's Kalabagan.
Dhaka Metropolitan Sessions Judge Md Sabbir Foyez delivered the verdict in the case on Thursday, reports bdnews24.com.
In additi</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 09:20:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AL reaping benefits from BNP-Jamaat’s counter programmes: Patwary</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/al-reaping-benefits-from-bnp-jamaats-counter-programmes-patwary</link><description>National Citizen Party (NCP) Chief Coordinator Nasiruddin Patwary on Thursday said the ousted Awami League is gaining an advantage from the ongoing cycle of counter programmes separately announced by the BNP and Jamaat-e-Islami.
“One day BNP announces a programme, the next day Jamaat respond</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 09:35:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP policymakers’ emergency meeting this evening</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-policymakers-emergency-meeting-this-evening</link><description>The BNP Standing Committee is set to hold an emergency meeting on Thursday evening following the Chief Adviser’s announcement that the next national election and a referendum will be held on the same day, along with the approval of the July National Charter implementation order.
The meeting</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 09:50:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AL office vandalised, torched in Gulistan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/awami-league-central-office-in-gulistan-vandalised-set-on-fire</link><description>A group of people have vandalised and torched the Awami League’s central office in Gulistan.
They entered the office chanting slogans against the Awami League after 1pm on Thursday, and vandalised it. They also heaped some banners inside the office and set fire to it.
The Awami League, whos</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 10:05:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>43 AL activists arrested over 'sabotage bids'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/police-arrest-43-awami-league-activists-in-dhaka-over-sabotage-attempts</link><description>Police have arrested 43 workers of the Awami League and its affiliates in raids across Dhaka.
In a statement released on Thursday, the Dhaka Metropolitan Police (DMP) said its detectives made the arrests.
The arrestees were involved in “sabotage attempts and flash processions”, the DM</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 10:20:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chief advisor’s address ‘violated’ July Charter: Salahuddin</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/chief-advisors-address-violated-july-charter-salahuddin</link><description>Senior BNP leader Salahuddin Ahmed has alleged that Chief Advisor Muhammad Yunus “violated” the July National Charter in his televised address to the nation on Thursday.
“In his speech, the chief advisor breached the signed July National Charter,” the Standing Committee mem</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 10:35:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>WTO affirms support for Bangladesh’s trade transition post-LDC graduation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/wto-affirms-support-for-bangladeshs-trade-transition-post-ldc-graduation</link><description>The World Trade Organization (WTO), a Geneva based intergovernmental organization that regulates and facilitates international trade, has affirmed its commitment to providing robust support for Bangladesh as the nation approaches its scheduled graduation from Least Developed Country (LDC) status in</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 10:50:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BSEC issues gazette on ‘Mutual Fund Regulations 2025’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bsec-issues-gazette-on-mutual-fund-regulations-2025</link><description>The Bangladesh Securities and Exchange Commission (BSEC), the country’s capital market regulator, has issued a gazette on ‘Bangladesh Securities and Exchange Commission (Mutual Fund) Regulations 2025’.
The new regulation became effective immediately upon its publication, said a p</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 11:05:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Inspirational seminar on peace and nonviolence held at ISU</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/inspirational-seminar-on-peace-and-nonviolence-held-at-isu</link><description>An inspiring seminar titled “Peace and Nonviolence: Inspiring Positive Change in Individuals and Society” was held at International Standard University (ISU) on Wednesday afternoon.
The event aimed to promote the values of peace, empathy, and nonviolence as essential tools for building</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 11:20:04 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>