<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 04:27:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Passenger bus catches fire at Dhaka's Dholaipar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/passenger-bus-catches-fire-at-dhakas-dholaipar</link><description>A passenger bus caught fire at Dholaipar intersection in Dhaka  on Wednesday evening.
The fire broke out around 6:38 pm, according to fire service officials.
Upon receiving the report, two units from the Postogola Fire Station rushed to the spot and brought the blaze under control within abo</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 16:53:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Train catches fire at Tejgaon Railway Station</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/train-catches-fire-at-tejgaon-railway-station</link><description>A stationary train has caught fire at Tejgaon Railway Station in Dhaka.
Dhaka Railway Police Station chief Zainal Abedin said the incident occurred around 9:30 pm on Wednesday.
“No one was injured in the fire,” he confirmed.
A video circulating on social media shows flames engulfing</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 17:08:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Evaly owners sentenced to five years in prison</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/evaly-owners-sentenced-to-five-years-in-prison</link><description>A Dhaka court has sentenced Mohammad Rassel, managing director of the e-commerce company Evaly, and his wife, the company’s Chairman Shamima Nasrin, to five more years in prison in a fraud case.
Additional Chief Metropolitan Magistrate Md Zakir Hossain delivered the verdict on Wednesday, rep</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 17:23:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Helping citizens share responsibility for democratic climate adaptation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/helping-citizens-share-responsibility-for-democratic-climate-adaptation</link><description>Climate change is not only an environmental or scientific problem; it is fundamentally a social, ethical, and political challenge. Dr Chloe Lucas, an environmental social scientist at the University of Tasmania, approaches this complexity through her pioneering project titled "Helping Citizens Shar</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 17:54:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tackling water scarcity in Barind tracts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/tackling-water-scarcity-in-barind-tracts</link><description>That ground water table is falling dangerously low is a major worry for the country. This has been going on over the last few decades and experts have been repeatedly sounding alarms. Over-extraction to meet the growing need of an increasing population is the obvious reason. Some of the extracted w</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 18:09:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Beyond Bangladesh's graduation from LDC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/beyond-bangladeshs-graduation-from-ldc</link><description>At a time when a high-level United Nations (UN) team arrives in Dhaka to discuss Bangladesh's progress for graduation from its least developed country (LDC) status to a developing nation, Japan brings off a tariff reform allowing continuation of the generalised system of preference (GSP) for the ne</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 18:24:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Danish shipping giant Maersk outfit signing $550m deal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/danish-shipping-giant-maersk-outfit-signing-550m-deal</link><description>Danish shipping giant Maersk is set to take charge of developing and operating Bangladesh's Laldia Container Terminal (LCT) in Chattogram under a US$550-million deal through its one subsidiary, opening avenues for enhancing foreign investment, officials say.



An official announcement was made</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 20:27:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Next govt ‘needs time’ to decide on LDC graduation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/next-govt-needs-time-to-decide-on-ldc-graduation</link><description>Bangladesh's graduation from the Least Developed Country (LDC) status now hangs in the balance as the interim administration and the private sector have opined for giving space to the next elected government to finalise the decision, insiders said.
The government and the private sector are divided</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 02:09:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Central bank orders strong action to rein in soaring default loans</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/central-bank-orders-strong-action-to-rein-in-soaring-default-loans</link><description>Bangladesh Bank has directed commercial banks to take immediate and forceful measures to rein in the rapid growth of non-performing loans (NPLs), which have become a critical concern for the country's financial stability.
At a meeting held at the central bank's headquarters on Wednesday, senior of</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 02:24:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka braces for volatile Thursday as police urge calm</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dhaka-braces-for-volatile-thursday-as-police-urge-calm</link><description>Two days of vehicle arson and sporadic crude bomb blasts in the capital Dhaka and beyond have stoked public anxiety ahead of a politically charged Thursday.
Police say security has been tightened citywide and insist there is nothing to fear, pledging to stop any sabotage.
On Wednesday evening, ar</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 02:57:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>'DMTCL not working on scrapping any project'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/dmtcl-not-working-on-scrapping-any-project</link><description>The Dhaka metro rail company is not working on scrapping any metro rail project, nor has conflicts with any development partner, its managing director has said.
Rather, it was working on developing its own parameters of standards to ensure safe metro journeys for all, Dhaka Mass Transit Company Li</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 03:12:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Efforts to transform child nutrition, maternal health services</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/efforts-to-transform-child-nutrition-maternal-health-services</link><description>As Bangladesh's economy continues to grow, certain public health challenges persist -- particularly in child health, nutrition, maternal health, and adolescent well-being. To ensure lasting and sustainable progress in these sectors, donor-dependent interventions alone are no longer sufficient; inno</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 03:27:29 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>