<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 14:33:22 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Police to grill Pabitra Kumar in custody for four days over ‘child abuse’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/police-to-grill-pabitra-kumar-in-custody-for-four-days-over-child-abuse</link><description>Police have been granted approval to question Pabitra Kumar Barua, an administrative officer allegedly involved in the abuse of a child at a school in Dhaka’s Paltan, in their custody for four days.
Dhaka Additional Chief Metropolitan Magistrate Md Sefatullah passed the order after a hearing</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 11:57:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two teens in Teknaf injured by gunfire from Myanmar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/two-teens-in-teknaf-injured-by-gunfire-from-myanmar</link><description>Two teenage fishermen have been injured by gunfire while fishing in the Naf River along the Bangladesh–Myanmar border in Teknaf.
The incident occurred on Tuesday near Whykong Union, according to Sub-Inspector (SI) Khokon Kanti Rudra, chief of the local police outpost.
The injured youths all</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 12:12:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Daffodil International University to hold 13th Convocation Wednesday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/daffodil-international-university-to-hold-13th-convocation-wednesday</link><description>The 13th Convocation of Daffodil International University is going to be held tomorrow, January 28, 2026, at Swadhinata Sommelon Kendro of the university.
Delegated by Mohammad Sahabuddin, President of the People’s Republic of Bangladesh and Chancellor of Daffodil International University, P</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 12:27:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rangpur lynching: Family ‘threatened’ after suspects get bail</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/rangpur-lynching-family-threatened-after-suspects-get-bail</link><description>In Rangpur’s Taragonj Upazila, the family of Ruplal Das and his son-in-law Pradeep Lal -- both beaten to death in a “mob” attack -- has alleged that suspects released on bail are now threatening them to withdraw the murder charges.
The threats and intimidation are aimed at forcin</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 12:42:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CA inaugurates e-Learning Programme in three hill districts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ca-inaugurates-e-learning-programme-in-three-hill-districts</link><description>Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus on Tuesday formally inaugurated the e-Learning Programme in 12 schools across the three hill districts in Chattogram.
He launched the programme virtually from the state guest house Jamuna here this noon and exchanged views with teachers and students of the 12</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 12:57:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique says Jamaat’s silence in power exposes hollowness of its corruption claims</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-says-jamaats-silence-in-power-exposes-hollowness-of-its-corruption-claims</link><description>If the four-party alliance government was corrupt, then why did Jamaat-e-Islami’s two top leaders never resign at the time? Tarique Rahman has raised the question, challenging Jamaat’s present-day criticism of the BNP.
On Tuesday, he referred to a particular political party, pointing t</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 12:30:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat express concern over attack on Nasiruddin Patwary</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-express-concern-over-attack-on-nasiruddin-patwary</link><description>Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami on Tuesday strongly condemned and protested the obstruction of electioneering activities and the attack on Dhaka-8 constituency parliamentary candidate Nasiruddin Patwary.
 “Nasiruddin Patwary, Chief Coordinator of National Citizen Party (NCP) and 11-party all</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 12:45:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>PayPal shows interest in Bangladesh: Lutfey Siddiqi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/paypal-shows-interest-in-bangladesh-lutfey-siddiqi</link><description>Chief Adviser's Special Envoy on International Affairs Lutfey Siddiqi on Tuesday said that PayPal has shown its interest in Bangladesh, but it would take time as the multinational financial technology company uses to follow a lengthy procedure to enter any market.
"On the sidelines of the World Ec</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 13:00:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ACC sues 3 BCS cadres for using fake certificates to get job</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/acc-sues-3-bcs-cadres-for-using-fake-certificates-to-get-job</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) on Tuesday filed three cases against three BCS cadres on charges of obtaining jobs in the Bangladesh Civil Service (BCS) by submitting forged academic certificates to the Public Service Commission (PSC).
Among them, two joined the BCS Administration Cadre and o</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 13:15:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Abbas ordered attack on Patwary, Tarique consented: Nahid</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/abbas-ordered-attack-on-patwary-tarique-consented-nahid</link><description>NCP Convenor Nahid Islam has alleged that the “attack” on the party’s Dhaka-8 candidate Nasiruddin Patwary was carried out on the “instructions” of BNP candidate Mirza Abbas, with the “consent” of Tarique Rahman.
Speaking at a press conference on Tuesday a</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 13:30:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Newly-formed Shari’ah Supervisory Committee meets with Board of Directors of Islami Bank</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/newly-formed-shariah-supervisory-committee-meets-with-board-of-directors-of-islami-bank</link><description>An exchange of views between the Board of Directors of Islami Bank Bangladesh PLC and the members of the newly formed Shar‘ah Supervisory Committee was held on Tuesday at the Islami Bank Tower, according to a press release.
Professor Dr. M. Zubaidur Rahman, chairman of the bank, Mohammad Khu</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 13:45:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IFIC Bank opens ATM Booth at Arbella premises, Gazipur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ific-bank-opens-atm-booth-at-arbella-premises-gazipur</link><description>To make financial transactions easier and faster, IFIC Bank installed an ATM booth at the premises of Arbella Fashion Limited, located in Sreepur, Gazipur.
The booth was formally inaugurated on Tuesday, by the bank’s Head of Operations, Mr. Helal Ahmed, and the Managing Director of Arbella F</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 14:00:42 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>