<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 15:28:41 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Tarique Rahman at Jamaat Ameer‘s residence</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-rahman-at-jamaat-ameers-residence</link><description>BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman arrived at Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami Ameer Shafiqur Rahman on Sunday evening, just two days before forming the next government following his party’s massive victory in Thursday’s national election.
Tarique reached the Jamaat chief’s residence in Bashu</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 12:45:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Uttara Bank inaugurates new premises of Kalabagan Branch</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/uttara-bank-inaugurates-new-premises-of-kalabagan-branch</link><description>Uttara Bank PLC inaugurated the new premises of Kalabagan Branch in Dhaka through a function on Sunday, according to a press release.
Mr. Md. Abul Hashem, Managing Director &amp; CEO of Uttara Bank PLC, inaugurated the new premises of the branch at Green Landmark Tower, Holding No-129, Mirpur Road, wa</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 13:00:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sudden spike in price of lemons</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/sudden-spike-in-price-of-lemons</link><description>The price of lemons has suddenly skyrocketed at Dhaka’s wet markets, reaching Tk 100-Tk 120 per four pieces in some places.
Traders say poor harvest and limited supplies have driven up prices. But buyers are reluctant to buy such reasoning for a Tk 80-100 jump in price.
Small lemons were se</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 13:15:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two killed, seven injured in Cumilla road crash</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/two-killed-seven-injured-in-cumilla-road-crash</link><description>Two people were killed and seven others were injured when a bus hit an auto-rickshaw and plunged into a roadside ditch on Dhaka-Chattogram highway in Daudkandi upazila of Cumilla district on Sunday.
The deceased were identified as Faruk Hossain, 38, an auto-rickshaw driver of Daudkandi upazila and</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 13:30:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gaza’s Nasser Hospital condemns move by MSF to suspend most services</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/gazas-nasser-hospital-condemns-move-by-msf-to-suspend-most-services</link><description>One of Gaza’s last functioning large hospitals condemned the move by an international organization to pull out of operations over concerns about armed men, claiming on Sunday that the hospital had installed civil police for security. The move comes as at least 10 Palestinians were killed in c</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 13:45:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BCIA expects capital market turnaround under new govt</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bcia-expects-capital-market-turnaround-under-new-govt</link><description>Bangladesh Capital Market Investor Association (BCIA) on Sunday expressed optimism that Bangladesh’s capital market will rebound within the next six months if the newly elected BNP government takes prudent and timely measures.
In a statement congratulating the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (B</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 14:00:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>MTB inks deal with TK Group on advanced cash management solution</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/mtb-inks-deal-with-tk-group-on-advanced-cash-management-solution</link><description>Mutual Trust Bank PLC (MTB) and T.K. Group have recently signed an agreement for Cash Management Services at a simple ceremony at MTB Centre, the bank’s Corporate Head Office, Gulshan-1, Dhaka, according to a press release.
Under this arrangement, T.K. Group will be able to process &amp; manage</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 13:49:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Indian Parliament Speaker, Saarc dignitaries to attend Bangladesh cabinet swearing-in</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/indian-parliament-speaker-saarc-dignitaries-to-attend-bangladesh-cabinet-swearing-in</link><description>India’s Lok Sabha Speaker Om Birla will represent New Delhi at the swearing-in ceremony of Bangladesh’s newly elected government in Dhaka on Tuesday, India’s Ministry of External Affairs has confirmed.
In a statement issued on Sunday, the ministry said Birla would attend the inau</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 14:04:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Modhumoti Bank holds 93rd meeting of board of directors</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/modhumoti-bank-holds-93rd-meeting-of-board-of-directors</link><description>The 93rd Meeting of the Board of Directors of Modhumoti Bank PLC was held on Sunday, according to a press release.
Mr. Humayun Kabir, Chairman of the Board of Directors, among the members of the Board of Directors, Mr. Mohammad Ismail Hossain Mr. Nemai Kumar Saha, Mr. Salahuddin Alamgir, Mr. Mosta</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 14:19:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BRAC Bank inaugurates sub-branch in Dhaka’s Monipuri Para</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/brac-bank-inaugurates-sub-branch-in-dhakas-monipuri-para</link><description>BRAC Bank has inaugurated a new sub-branch at Monipuri Para in Dhaka. With this addition, the bank’s sub-branch network now stands at 116, according to a press release.
Tareq Refat Ullah Khan, Managing Director and CEO of BRAC Bank, formally inaugurated the sub-branch at JDPC Bhaban, 145, Mo</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 14:34:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bank Asia partners with Chef’s Table for exclusive Ramadan privileges for cardholders</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bank-asia-partners-with-chefs-table-for-exclusive-ramadan-privileges-for-cardholders</link><description>Bank Asia PLC has partnered with Chef’s Table to offer exclusive Ramadan privileges for its debit and credit cardholders. Under this agreement, Bank Asia’s cardholders will enjoy a 10 per cent discount at all Chef’s Table outlets throughout the holy month of Ramadan, according to</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 14:49:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Al-Arafah Islami Bank opens training program on leadership and communication skills</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/al-arafah-islami-bank-opens-training-program-on-leadership-and-communication-skills</link><description>A two-day training course on ‘Connect, Influence, Grow: Leadership, Communication and Interpersonal Excellence’ has begun at the Bank’s Training Institute, according to a press release.
Managing Director and CEO of the bank Mohd. Rafat Ullah Khan inaugurated the training workshop</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 15:04:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>