<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 05:22:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Spectrum auction to fetch Tk 2.37 billion per unit</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/spectrum-auction-to-fetch-tk-237-billion-per-unit</link><description>Bangladesh plans to earn Tk 2.37 billion per unit from 700MHz spectrum auction as the government approves the long-awaited financial terms for selling the highly coveted telecommunications backbone. 
The Finance Division has endorsed the modus operandi, clearing a major regulatory hurdle and</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 02:15:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Paddy prices slightly lower as import continues, millers dominate market</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/paddy-prices-slightly-lower-as-import-continues-millers-dominate-market</link><description>Paddy prices during the ongoing Aman harvest season are slightly lower than last year’s, with farmers and market observers attributing the decline to continued rice imports and the strong presence of millers in the market.
According to the Department of Agricultural Marketing, dry guti swarn</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 02:30:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Exchange rate rise erodes export competiveness</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/exchange-rate-rise-erodes-export-competiveness</link><description>Bangladesh's exports may get costlier to foreign buyers while imports cheaper as the local currency, taka, appears increasingly overvalued in the foreign-exchange basket in real terms.
Economists explain that this economic paradox appears for sluggish import demand, weak private-sector credit grow</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 02:45:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Disaster-induced emergency: Finance ministry asked to keep specific allocations for rescue operations</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/disaster-induced-emergency-finance-ministry-asked-to-keep-specific-allocations-for-rescue-operations</link><description>Instead of keeping funds in the form of block allocations, the finance ministry has been requested to keep specific budgetary allocations to carry out rescue operations in case of disaster-related emergencies, officials say.
It has also been requested to keep allocations for fiscal rescue operatio</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 03:00:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ACC files 512 cases, freezes Tk 222b worth of bank accounts in a year</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/acc-files-512-cases-freezes-tk-222b-worth-of-bank-accounts-in-a-year</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) filed a total of 512 cases and froze Tk 222 billion worth of bank accounts between December 2024 and October 2025.
The figures were revealed at a view-exchange meeting on the occasion of the Commission's 21st anniversary at its headquarters in Dhaka on Tuesday.</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 03:15:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CIC unlocks 2 bank lockers of Hasina</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cic-unlocks-2-bank-lockers-of-hasina</link><description>The Central Intelligence Cell unlocked two lockers of ousted Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina on Tuesday at Agrani Bank's principal branch.
CIC, accompanied by magistrates, bank officials, broke open the locker nos. 751 and 753 as per Bangladesh Bank Guidelines.
Official sources said they found a con</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 03:30:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Petrobangla to import 7 more LNG cargoes annually to boost fertiliser production</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/petrobangla-to-import-7-more-lng-cargoes-annually-to-boost-fertiliser-production</link><description>State-run Petrobangla has decided to import at least seven additional LNG cargoes annually-preferably from the spot market-using the proceeds from the recent tariff hike in order to feed the gas-starved fertilizer factories.
"We'll include the plan for additional liquefied natural gas (LNG) cargo</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 03:45:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fortune Shoes' profit nosedives as non-operating income dries up</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/fortune-shoes-profit-nosedives-as-non-operating-income-dries-up</link><description>Fortune Shoes' profit nosedived to Tk 19 million in FY25 as non-operating income shrank significantly.
The shoe manufacturer's profit tumbled 77 per cent year-on-year in FY25, according to a stock exchange filing on Tuesday.
Fortune Shoes, based mainly in the southern division of Barishal, report</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 04:00:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Eight more firms given extended deadlines to adjust negative equity</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/eight-more-firms-given-extended-deadlines-to-adjust-negative-equity</link><description>The securities regulator has granted additional time to eight more market intermediaries to ensure compliance with provisioning requirements for unrealised losses and to adjust negative equity.
The extension will take effect after December 31 this year, when the current deadline expires.
"Some in</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 04:15:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>British High Commission cautions against visa fraud, warns of 10-year travel ban</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/british-high-commission-cautions-against-visa-fraud-warns-of-10-year-travel-ban</link><description>The British High Commission in Dhaka has issued a warning over visa fraud, advising applicants to rely only on official sources and verified information.
In a media statement on Tuesday, it said anyone caught attempting visa fraud could face a 10-year travel ban, bdnews24.com reports.
Quoting Bri</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 04:30:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Partners, family members killed 137 women a day worldwide in 2024</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/partners-family-members-killed-137-women-a-day-worldwide-in-2024-un-finds</link><description>The United Nations has released new data showing that more than 50,000 women and girls were killed by intimate partners or family members in 2024, equivalent to one every 10 minutes or 137 per day.
According to Al Jazeera, the figures are from a joint assessment by the United Nations Office on Dru</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 04:45:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt to provide full support for rehabilitation of Karail fire victims: CA</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-to-provide-full-support-for-rehabilitation-of-karail-fire-victims-ca</link><description>Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus has expressed deep concern over the devastating fire in the city's Karail slum and extended his sympathy to the affected families, assuring that the government will provide all necessary support for their rehabilitation.
"The suffering of the families who hav</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 05:00:57 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>