<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 11:22:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Man killed in mob beating over theft suspicion</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/man-killed-in-mob-beating-over-theft-suspicion</link><description>A35-year-old man was beaten to death by a mob over allegations of theft at Snikantanagar Bazar in Ramnagar Union in Jashore Sadar upazila early Friday.
The deceased was identified as Shamim, son of Chabdu.
He was a resident of Baladanga village in the Sadar upazila, reports UNB.
According to pol</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 07:30:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CWAB president Mithun reports threats against players</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/cwab-president-mithun-reports-threats-against-players</link><description>The crisis in Bangladesh cricket has taken a serious turn as Mohammad Mithun, president of the Cricketers' Welfare Association of Bangladesh (CWAB), said he has been receiving severe threats involving physical harm to players.
Mithun alleged that he has been receiving abusive calls and WhatsApp me</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 07:31:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bag of crude bombs found in Gazipur college pond</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/bag-of-crude-bombs-found-in-gazipur-college-pond</link><description>A bag containing crude bombs, locally known as 'cocktails', has been caught in a fishing net cast on a pond in Gazipur’s Sreepur Upazila.
Sreepur Police Station chief Mohammad Nasir Ahmed said the bombs were found around 8:00 am on Friday in the pond of Piyar Ali College in the Maona Bazar a</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 07:46:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>RAB recovers Highway Police firearm ‘looted’ during July Uprising in Cumilla</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rab-recovers-highway-police-firearm-looted-during-july-uprising-in-cumilla</link><description>The Rapid Action Battalion (RAB) has recovered two firearms in Cumilla, including one that was looted from the Highway Police during the July Uprising, reports bdnews24.com.
The weapons were found abandoned in a roadside pond in Muradnagar Upazila around 2am on Thursday, said RAB-11 Company Comm</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 08:01:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two workers killed in Rangamati road crash</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/two-workers-killed-in-rangamati-road-crash</link><description>Two workers were killed and another was seriously injured when a pickup truck overturned and fell into a roadside ditch on the Asambasti-Kaptai road in Rangamati district town last night.
The deceased were identified as Sadek Chakma, 38, and Milan Chakma, 50, both residents of Kamilachhari area in</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 08:16:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Major blaze extinguished in deprived area of South Korea's Gangnam district</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/major-blaze-extinguished-in-deprived-area-of-south-koreas-gangnam-district</link><description>A major fire that broke out early on Friday in a deprived area of the upmarket Gangnam district of Seoul was brought under control and fully extinguished about eight hours later, a fire official said.
"We are relieved that we were able to extinguish the fire without any casualties," the official s</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 08:31:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Inqilab Moncho stages protests demanding justice for Hadi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/inqilab-moncho-stages-protests-demanding-justice-for-hadi</link><description>Inqilab Moncho on Friday staged a demonstration demanding justice for its slain spokesperson, Sharif Osman bin Hadi, with a large number of protesters in attendance.
The protesters organised a procession from the central mosque premises of Dhaka University after Jumma prayers. During the demonstra</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 09:28:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dubai air taxis to begin commercial flights by year-end, Transport Authority says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/dubai-air-taxis-to-begin-commercial-flights-by-year-end-transport-authority-says</link><description>Electric air taxis developed by Joby Aviation are set to begin commercial operations in Dubai by the end of this year, Dubai's Roads and Transport Authority Chairman Mattar Al Tayer said on Friday.
Joby Aviation conducted the first test flight of its fully electric air taxi in the emirate in June</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 09:43:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>China calls on U.S. to abandon fixation on use of force against Iran</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/china-calls-on-us-to-abandon-fixation-on-use-of-force-against-iran</link><description>A Chinese envoy on Thursday called on the United States to abandon its fixation on the use of force against Iran.
Recent developments in Iran have drawn widespread attention. The United States has continued to make statements on the situation in Iran and has openly threatened Iran with the use of</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 09:58:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Islami Andolan to contest election on its own, field candidates in 268 seats</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/islami-andolan-to-contest-election-on-its-own-field-candidates-in-268-seats</link><description>Islami Andolan Bangladesh has announced that it will field candidates for 268 seats in the 13th parliamentary election and contest on its own instead of joining the Jamaat-e-Islami-led alliance, reports bdnews24.com.
Party spokesman Gazi Ataur Rahman said it had left the Jamaat alliance due to the</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 10:30:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Civic memorial for former PM Khaleda Zia under way</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/civic-memorial-for-former-pm-khaleda-zia-under-way</link><description>A civic memorial is being held at the Parliament complex to mark the death of former prime minister Khaleda Zia.
The event began at 3pm on Friday at the Parliament's South Plaza and is being chaired by former chief justice Syed JR Mudassir Husain, bdnews24.com reports. 
Senior leaders from a</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 10:45:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Social media platforms removed 4.7m accounts after Australia banned them for children</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/social-media-platforms-removed-47m-accounts-after-australia-banned-them-for-children</link><description>Social media companies have revoked access to about 4.7 million accounts identified as belonging to children in Australia since the country banned use of the platforms by those under 16, officials said.
“We stared down everybody who said it couldn’t be done, some of the most powerful a</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 11:00:47 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>