<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 14:22:39 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Not worried about political parties’ remarks, relations cordial: Asif Nazrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/not-worried-about-political-parties-remarks-relations-cordial-asif-nazrul</link><description>Law Affairs Adviser Dr Asif Nazrul on Thursday said the interim government is not worried about political parties’ occasional remarks questioning the neutrality of advisers, noting that such comments may stem from ‘political strategy or genuine concerns’.
“We don’t ta</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 10:48:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Advisory Council approves draft amendment to RPO</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/revised-rpo-bars-fugitives-introduces-transparency-measures-to-ensure-fair-elections</link><description>The interim government’s Advisory Council on Thursday, approved a draft amendment to the Representation of the People Order (RPO), introducing a provision that candidates, even if part of an electoral alliance, must contest the national elections under their respective party symbols.
The app</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 11:18:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prime Bank employees and customers to get exclusive discounts from Délifrance</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/prime-bank-employees-and-customers-to-get-exclusive-discounts-from-delifrance</link><description>Prime Bank PLC has entered into a strategic partnership with Les Bleus Ltd (Délifrance) to offer exclusive dining and gifting discounts for its employees and customers.
The signing ceremony marking this collaboration was recently held at Prime Bank’s Corporate Office in Dhaka, accordi</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 11:33:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh sets new record with 36 factories earning LEED certification in a year</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladesh-sets-new-record-with-36-factories-earning-leed-certification-in-a-year</link><description>The Bangladesh apparel industry has achieved a new global milestone in sustainable manufacturing with 36 factories earning international environmental compliance certifications in a single year.
The record-breaking achievement in 2025 surpasses the previous high of 30 certifications awarded in 202</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 11:48:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Community Bank Bangladesh holds its 69th board meeting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/community-bank-bangladesh-holds-its-69th-board-meeting</link><description>The 69th Board Meeting of Community Bank Bangladesh PLC. was held at the Police Headquarters on Wednesday, 22 October 2025.
The meeting was chaired by Mr. Baharul Alam, BPM, Inspector General of Police, Bangladesh and Chairman of Community Bank Bangladesh PLC, according to a media release.</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 12:03:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sarkar, Saif lift Tigers to 296</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/sarkar-91-saif-80-power-bangladesh-to-296-against-west-indies</link><description>Bangladesh banished any doubts raised by the slow, dark pitch at Mirpur with an imposing 296 for 8 against West Indies in the third and final ODI, powered by a blistering 176-run opening stand between Soumya Sarkar and Saif Hassan.
Saif’s maiden ODI fifty was a statement of intent as he smas</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 12:18:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Education institutions asked to comply with cyber security ordinance</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/education-institutions-asked-to-comply-with-cyber-security-ordinance</link><description>The Directorate of Secondary and Higher Education (DSHE) has instructed all personnel working in educational institutions to strictly comply with the Cyber Security Ordinance, 2025.
The directive was issued through an official order signed by Khalid Hossain, Assistant Director of the DSHE, on Wedn</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 12:33:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Over 63,000 dengue patients hospitalised this year</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/over-63000-dengue-patients-hospitalised-this-year</link><description>Bangladesh has recorded 803 new dengue hospital admissions in the past 24 hours, pushing the total for this year to 63,170 patients.
This year’s hospitalisations rank as the fourth-highest on record, according to health directorate count.
The highest was in 2023, when 321,179 patients were</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 12:48:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>England win T20 series in New Zealand as rain ruins final game</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/england-win-t20-series-in-new-zealand-as-rain-ruins-final-game</link><description>England claimed a 1-0 victory in their three-match Twenty20 series against New Zealand after rain curtailed Thursday's final match in Auckland.
The touring side secured the triumph courtesy of a commanding 65-run victory in Monday's second T20, after the first match was abandoned following the com</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 13:03:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Russia, at war, faces double trouble</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/russia-at-war-faces-double-trouble-trump-ultimatum-and-a-hit-to-oil-sales-to-india</link><description>Russia, the world's second largest oil exporter, is weighing how to respond to US sanctions on top oil firms Rosneft and Lukoil and the prospect of lower sales to its biggest buyer, India.
President Vladimir Putin, who sent troops into Ukraine in 2022, has been in discussions with US President Don</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 13:18:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Japan's Mount Fuji sees snow for first time this winter, 21 days later than usual</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/japans-mount-fuji-sees-snow-for-first-time-this-winter-21-days-later-than-usual</link><description>The peak of Japan's Mount Fuji was capped with snow for the first time this winter on Thursday, reaching the milestone 21 days later than the average since records began in 1894, the meteorological agency said.
This year's snowfall came two weeks earlier than 2024, when snow settled on the 3,776-m</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 13:33:35 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>