<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 23:22:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Victory Day celebrated nationwide with enthusiasm</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/as-ever-enthusiasm-marks-victory-day-celebrations-across-bangladesh</link><description>Bangladesh celebrated Victory Day on Tuesday with great enthusiasm, as people across the country paid homage to the martyrs of the Liberation War through ceremonies, rallies, and cultural programmes.
The celebration began with the traditional 31-gun salute ringing out across the capital at the bre</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 17:29:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Caricature of Ghulam Azam blotted out at Chittagong University</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/caricature-of-ghulam-azam-blotted-out-at-chittagong-university</link><description>A caricature of Ghulam Azam and Pro-Vice Chancellor Prof Shamim Uddin Khan, drawn by students in protest over controversial comments on Martyred Intellectuals Day, has been covered with black ink at Chittagong University.
The artwork, painted Monday outside the administrative building, was found b</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 17:44:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Balancing the scales</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/balancing-the-scales</link><description>In the serious tapestry of modern global economy, few issues are as pressing and complex as the intertwining of debt sustainability and climate financing demands. For developing nations, particularly those on the frontline of climate change, this issue has become a profound challenge that requires</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 18:00:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Clear vision changes lives</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/reviews/clear-vision-changes-lives</link><description>When we talk about healthcare and human rights, one vital aspect is often overlooked: vision. Eye care is not a niche concern-it is a fundamental component of health, productivity, and dignity. Imagine the daily challenges faced by someone who cannot see clearly: reduced productivity, limited earni</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 18:15:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CA vows to defend democratic transition</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ca-vows-to-defend-democratic-transition</link><description>As Bangladesh heads towards a landmark general election combined with constitutional referendum, scheduled for February, the head of interim government asserts that all "ill attempts of defeated forces" will be foiled to execute the country's post-uprising democratic transition.



In a natio</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 18:30:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>From connectivity to competitiveness</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/from-connectivity-to-competitiveness</link><description>The “Digital Bangladesh” slogan, which emerged in 2009, echoed a collective dream of embracing technology across all aspects of life. The dream had a modest yet revolutionary vision: to “connect people and enable digital inclusion to reach out to all Bangladeshis.” In its fi</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 18:00:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Austerity and its uneven burden on revised ADP</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/austerity-and-its-uneven-burden-on-revised-adp</link><description>The scale and composition of the Revised Annual Development Programme (RADP) for the current fiscal year reveal a far larger contraction than many had anticipated, particularly in sectors that underpin human development. While some degree of rationalisation was inevitable amid tight fiscal space, r</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 18:15:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Post-July 2024 efforts at revamping judiciary</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/post-july-2024-efforts-at-revamping-judiciary</link><description>Bangladesh's judicial system has faced many challenges since the country's in dependence. The 1972 Constitution, for instance, established a Supreme Court and formally adopted the principle of the separation of the judiciary from the executive organs of the state. The development of the judiciary h</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 18:30:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>15 hurt in BNP-Jamaat scuffle in Bhola</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bnp-jamaat-scuffle-leaves-15-people-injured-in-bhola-on-victory-day</link><description>At least 15 people have been injured in a scuffle between the activists of the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) and Jamaat-e-Islami during a Victory Day event in Bhola’s Daulatkhan.
Daulatkhan Police chief Saiful Islam Shikder said the incident occurred at the Ghaznavi Stadium on Tuesday.</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 18:45:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>'Spare us more humiliation': war heroine pleads</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/spare-us-more-humiliation-war-heroine-pleads</link><description>Since the Liberation War, "Birangona" or war heroine Sheikh Fatema Ali has found no respite from humiliation.
The wartime rape victim has been continuously neglected and subjected to slander and social stigma.
The war crimes survivor has never found peace, nor even a chance to heal the wounds inf</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 19:00:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>1,104 infiltration attempts from Bangladesh: India</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/1104-infiltration-attempts-from-bangladesh-in-11-months-2556-arrested-says-india</link><description>India logged 1,104 infiltration attempts from Bangladesh between January and November this year, leading to the arrest of 2,556 people, Junior Home Minister Nityanand Rai has told parliament.
Rai also said during the full year of 2024, authorities detected 977 infiltration attempts along the Bangl</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 19:15:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hadi attack probe: Key suspect’s father held</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hadi-attack-prime-suspects-father-detained-as-rab-widens-investigation</link><description>The Rapid Action Battalion (RAB) has detained the father of Faisal Karim Masud, the key suspect in the attack on Inqilab Moncho leader Sharif Osman bin Hadi, as the investigation into the attempted killing intensifies.
After the detention, the RAB said it had recovered two firearms from Narsingdi</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 19:30:49 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>