<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 10:20:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>BNP announces 10-day programme to mark Nov 7</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-announces-10-day-programme-to-mark-nov-7</link><description>BNP on Sunday announced a 10-day programme to observe with due respect ‘National Revolution and Solidarity Day’, marking the ‘civil-military uprising’ on November 7, 1975.
BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir announced the programmes at a press conference at th</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 06:56:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Six murders in Kushtia: Tribunal orders to open trial against Hanif, 3 others</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/six-murders-in-kushtia-tribunal-orders-to-open-trial-against-hanif-3-others</link><description>The International Crimes Tribunal has ordered to open the trial against Awami League Joint General Secretary Mahbubul Alam Hanif and three others in a case filed over the killing of six people during the July Uprising in Kushtia.
The International Crimes Tribunal-2, led by Justice Md Nazrul Islam</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 07:41:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Campaign kicked off for 13th national election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/campaign-kicked-off-for-13th-national-election</link><description>The campaign period for Bangladesh's 13th national election, scheduled to take place in February next year, is officially under way.
The Chief Advisor’s Office (CA0) released the first campaign teaser on Sunday, urging citizens to take part in what has been described as one of the most signi</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 07:56:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ICT orders trial against Inu over six Kushtia killings</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ict-orders-trial-against-inu-over-six-kushtia-killings</link><description>The International Crimes Tribunal-2 (ICT-2) on Sunday ordered the initiation of trial against former Information Minister and Jatiya Samajtantrik Dal (Jasad) president Hasanul Haq Inu over six killings in Kushtia during last year's uprising.
A three-member tribunal, headed by Justice Nazrul Islam</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 08:26:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Zakir Naik’s visit to Dhaka depends on home, foreign ministries'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/zakir-naiks-visit-to-dhaka-depends-on-home-foreign-ministries</link><description>Adviser for Religious Affairs A.F.M. Khalid Hossain said that the possible visit of Indian Islamic preacher Dr Zakir Naik to Bangladesh will depend entirely on the decisions of the Home and Foreign Ministries.
Speaking to the reporters after a meeting at the Ministry of Religious Affairs at the Se</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 09:11:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Attempt on to create anarchy through false propaganda: Fakhrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/attempt-on-to-create-anarchy-through-false-propaganda-fakhrul</link><description>BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir today (Sunday) alleged that an attempt is underway to create anarchy in the country by spreading false propaganda on social media.
He said, "The enemies of Bangladesh are rearing their heads again and starting to rise up. As time passes, a maliciou</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 09:26:01 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>