<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 12:52:26 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>UK hospitals facing 'worst case scenario' from super flu, doctors warn</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/uk-hospitals-facing-worst-case-scenario-from-super-flu-doctors-warn</link><description>Hospitals in Britain are facing a "worst case scenario" from a wave of super flu, healthcare bosses warned on Thursday, as flu hospitalisations jumped 55 per cent in a week.
Health leaders have told people who feel ill to wear face masks when using public transport, while some hospitals are requir</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 10:14:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shaukat Mahmood put on five-day remand</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dhaka-court-grants-police-five-days-to-question-shaukat-mahmood-in-custody</link><description>A Dhaka court has granted police five days to interrogate Shaukat Mahmood, a former Jatiya Press Club president and Janata Party Bangladesh general secretary, in their custody.
Dhaka Metropolitan Magistrate Fahmina Khandakar Anna passed the remand order on Thursday.
Sub-Inspector Jinnat Ali of th</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 11:06:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Mango emerges as Bangladesh’s next high-potential export’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/mango-emerges-as-bangladeshs-next-high-potential-export</link><description>Bangladesh has achieved remarkable export growth in recent years, with the agricultural products steadily gaining traction. As the country prepares for graduation from the Least Developed Country (LDC) status, diversification of agricultural exports has become increasingly essential to strengthen g</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 11:21:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat Ameer meets Japanese business delegation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-ameer-meets-japanese-business-delegation</link><description>Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami Ameer Dr. Shafiqur Rahman held a meeting on Thursday with a visiting delegation from the Japan External Trade Organization (JETRO), Japan’s official investment and trade promotion body.
The meeting was held in a cordial and constructive atmosphere at the Jamaat chi</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 10:29:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>M23 consolidates control over Congo town in blow to peace talks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/africa/m23-consolidates-control-over-congo-town-in-blow-to-peace-talks</link><description>The M23 rebel group consolidated control over the strategic town of Uvira in eastern Democratic Republic of Congo on Thursday, residents said, as Kinshasa warned that the Rwanda-backed advance could derail US President Donald Trump's efforts to broker peace in the region.
Sporadic gunfire echoed o</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 10:44:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Islami Bank holds 42nd AGM</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/islami-bank-holds-42nd-agm</link><description>The 42nd Annual General Meeting of Islami Bank Bangladesh PLC was held on Thursday (December 11, 2025), at Kurmitola Golf Club of the Capital.
Professor Dr. M. Zubaidur Rahman, chairman of the bank, presided over the meeting, according to a press release.
Mohammad Khurshid Wahab, chairman of the</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 10:59:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC seeks two magistrates at upazila level on election duty</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-seeks-two-magistrates-at-upazila-level-on-election-duty</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has asked the public administration ministry to engage at least two executive magistrates at the upazila level immediately after the announcement of polls schedule, said the commission officials.
“The commission asked the senior secretary of the public administra</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 11:14:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Students, DUCSU leader chase teacher off campus</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/ducsu-leader-leads-chase-as-prof-jamal-leaves-campus-after-harassment-claims</link><description>A Dhaka University professor aligned with the Awami League–backed Blue Panel has been chased off campus after students confronted him over an alleged unauthorised meeting at the Faculty of Social Sciences.
The incident unfolded shortly after 1pm on Thursday when sociology department Prof AKM</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 11:29:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chinese investors meet BGMEA leaders</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/chinese-investors-meet-bgmea-leaders</link><description>A high-level delegation of Chinese investors from a wide range of industries meets with leaders of the Bangladesh Garment Manufacturers and Exporters Association (BGMEA) on Thursday to explore opportunities for diversified investment in Bangladesh.
The meeting, held at the BGMEA Complex in Uttara,</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 11:44:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh election, referendum on Feb 12; schedule announced</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-election-referendum-on-feb-12-schedule-announced</link><description>The much-sought national election and a referendum on the July (Reform) Charter will simultaneously be held on February 12 (Thursday) under a non-political government after 18 years, as the Election Commission announced the schedule on Thursday evening.
Chief Election Commissioner AMM Nasir Uddin</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 11:59:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Police HQ besieged demanding IGP’s resignation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/police-headquarters-besieged-demanding-resignation-of-igp-baharul-alam</link><description>Police headquarters have been besieged by the Shaheed Pintu Smriti Sangsad, demanding the resignation of Inspector General of Police Baharul Alam.
The organisation’s rally towards the police headquarters was blocked near Government Employees Hospital at 4pm on Thursday.
“They stayed f</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 12:14:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamuna Bank signs Foreign Remittance Drawing Agreement with Horizon Remit SdnBhd, Malaysia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/jamuna-bank-signs-foreign-remittance-drawing-agreement-with-horizon-remit-sdnbhd-malaysia</link><description>Jamuna Bank PLC has recently entered into a Foreign Remittance Drawing Agreement with Horizon Remit SdnBhd in Malaysia, marking a significant milestone in strengthening its global remittance network.
The partnership aims to enhance cross-border remittance services through mutual cooperation, impro</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 12:29:58 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>