<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 14:23:35 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Journalists imprisoned in Belarus and Georgia win EU’s top human rights award</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/journalists-imprisoned-in-belarus-and-georgia-win-eus-top-human-rights-award</link><description>Two journalists, one imprisoned in Belarus and the other in Georgia, have won the European Union’s top human rights honor, the Sakharov Prize, European Parliament President Roberta Metsola announced on Wednesday.
Andrzej Poczobut is a correspondent for the influential Polish newspaper Gazeta</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 11:49:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DMP files 1,658 cases against traffic rule violations</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/dmp-files-1658-cases-against-traffic-rule-violations</link><description>The Traffic Division of the Dhaka Metropolitan Police (DMP) has filed 1,658 cases against motor vehicles, their owners, and drivers for violating traffic rules in a single day across the capital.
A media release of the DMP on Wednesday said that they filed those cases and realized the money on Tue</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 12:19:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Al-Arafah Islami Bank signs Strategic Partnership with Shamadhan Services Limited</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/al-arafah-islami-bank-signs-strategic-partnership-with-shamadhan-services-limited</link><description>Al-Arafah Islami Bank PLC, the country’s leading Shariah-compliant financial institution has signed a Strategic Partnership Agreement with Shamadhan Services Limited, a concern of Grameen Telecom, to strengthen digital financial services and enhance customer convenience.
The signing ceremony</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 12:34:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dengue: 2 die, 762 hospitalised</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/bangladesh-reports-four-more-dengue-deaths-762-hospitalisations-in-a-day</link><description>Another two patients have died of dengue fever in Bangladesh over the past 24 hours, pushing the nationwide death toll this year to 255.
The Directorate General of Health Services (DGHS) bulletin released on Wednesday said the latest victims included one woman and one man.
They all died in Mugda</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 11:49:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt issues new guidelines for eco-friendly tourism on St. Martin’s Island</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-issues-new-guidelines-for-eco-friendly-tourism-on-st-martins-island</link><description>The government has issued new guidelines to promote eco-friendly tourism on St. Martin’s Island, aiming to preserve the island’s unique natural beauty, environment, and biodiversity.
The Environment-2 Wing of the Ministry of Environment, Forest and Climate Change issued a notification</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 12:04:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat delegation reaches Jamuna to hold talks with chief adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jamaat-delegation-reaches-jamuna-to-hold-talks-with-chief-adviser</link><description>A four-member Jamaat delegation has arrived at Jamuna, the official residence of Chief Adviser Muhammad Yunus, to hold talks with him.
The delegation entered Jamuna at 5:45 pm on Wednesday.
The members of the delegation are Amir Syed Abdullah Mohammad Taher, Secretary General Mia Golam Parwar, As</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 12:19:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Standard Chartered, CAMPE launch ‘Shikhya Shurokkha’ to curb dropout and strengthen rural education</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/standard-chartered-campe-launch-shikhya-shurokkha-to-curb-dropout-and-strengthen-rural-education</link><description>Standard Chartered Bangladesh and the Campaign for Popular Education (CAMPE) have signed an agreement to launch Shikhya Shurokkha, a community-based initiative aimed at reducing school dropout rates, providing access to online learning resources, and improving learning outcomes in rural and margina</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 12:49:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AB Bank inaugurates 23 New Agent outlets</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ab-bank-inaugurates-23-new-agent-outlets</link><description>AB Bank Limited virtually inaugurated 23 new Agent Banking outlets today, further strengthening its outreach across the country.
Managing Director &amp; CEO Mr. Syed Mizanur Rahman formally announced the opening of these new outlets during a virtual inauguration ceremony held at the Bank’s Head</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 13:04:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Customs House, Dhaka to remain open on Oct 24, 25</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/customs-house-dhaka-to-remain-open-on-oct-24-25</link><description>The Customs House, Dhaka will remain open on October 24 and 25 (Friday and Saturday) to ensure smooth continuation of import, export, and business operations during the post-disaster interim period.
According to an office order issued, all customs assessment teams under the jurisdiction of Customs</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 13:19:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bengal Commercial Bank hosts 'Closing Ceremony' of month-long 'Entrepreneurship Development Program'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bengal-commercial-bank-hosts-closing-ceremony-of-month-long-entrepreneurship-development-program</link><description>Bengal Commercial Bank organised the Certificate Awarding Ceremony on the Closing of the month-long “Entrepreneurship Development Program” successfully for the development of the small and medium industries.
The Bank conducted this training program as part of the “Skills for Indu</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 13:34:31 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>