<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 01:46:30 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>College in Mymensingh closed after attacks over ‘love conflict’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/others/college-in-mymensingh-closed-after-attacks-over-love-conflict</link><description>A college in Mymensingh city has been closed indefinitely to control the situation after a series of attacks over a “love dispute”.
The attack on Shambhuganj GKP College took place throughout Monday, said Kotwali Model Police chief Md Shibirul Islam.
Principal Sultana Parveen said, &amp;l</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 16:15:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Touhid rejects Indian media claim on terror plot</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/touhid-rejects-indian-media-claim-on-terror-plot</link><description>Foreign Affairs Adviser Md. Touhid Hossain has dismissed Indian media reports claiming that Pakistan's Lashkar-e-Taiba chief Hafiz Saeed plotted attacks in India using Bangladeshi soil, terming the allegation baseless and unbelievable.
Responding to questions from journalists at the Ministry of Fo</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 16:30:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Police extends ban on rallies, gatherings near Ctg port</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/police-extends-ban-on-rallies-gatherings-near-ctg-port</link><description>The Chattogram Metropolitan Police has extended the ban on all political, labour, and social rallies, processions, human chains, and street meetings near the port for another month.
The decision, announced in a media statement on Tuesday, aims to keep import-export operations smooth and uninterrup</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 16:45:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>I really want to go back: Messi on Barcelona return</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/football/i-really-want-to-go-back-messi-on-barcelona-return</link><description>Lionel Messi admits that he and his wife Antonela Roccuzzo are “constantly talking” about a future return to Barcelona.
The Argentine maestro went viral on social media after posting a picture of himself strolling on the pitch of the new Camp Nou on Monday. It was a nighttime visit, co</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 17:00:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>44th BCS results published after rectifying ‘errors’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/44th-bcs-results-published-after-rectifying-errors</link><description>The Public Service Commission (PSC) has released a revised version of the 44th Bangladesh Civil Service (BCS) examination result, recommending 1,676 candidates for appointment after resolving earlier discrepancies.
The “extended supplementary” announcement on Tuesday marks the third is</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 17:15:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US airlines cancel 1200 flights amid shutdown</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-airlines-cancel-1200-flights-amid-shutdown</link><description>Airlines cancelled nearly 1,200 flights on Tuesday, the fifth consecutive day they have topped 1,000 since the government imposed mandatory flight reductions to address safety concerns.
Last week, the Federal Aviation Administration instructed airlines to cut 4 percent of daily flights starting on</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 17:30:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh-China trade in commercial services: what the numbers reveal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/bangladesh-china-trade-in-commercial-services-what-the-numbers-reveal</link><description>Bangladesh-China bilateral trade in commercial services increased more than four times over the last two decades, although the volume of trade in commercial services is far below that of merchandise. At present, trade in commercial services with China accounts for less than one-tenth of trade in go</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 17:45:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mamdani's democratic socialism: A test case for US governance</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/mamdanis-democratic-socialism-a-test-case-for-us-governance</link><description>Now that the dust has begun to settle after Zohran Mamdani's decisive victory in the New York mayoral election, the question that looms large is whether he can deliver on his ambitious promises as a self-declared democratic socialist. His victory, though confined to one of the world's most diverse</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 18:00:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Regulatory maze chokes growth of agro-processing industry</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/regulatory-maze-chokes-growth-of-agro-processing-industry</link><description>Bangladesh's agro-processing industry, one of the country's most promising growth sectors, is enmeshed in a web of regulatory tangles, costly testing requirements and weak coordination among government agencies, industry leaders say.



"Producers are forced to deal with multiple regulators to</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 18:15:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tax incentives vs IMF conditionalities</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/tax-incentives-vs-imf-conditionalities</link><description>One of the conditions Bangladesh was to meet for utilising the multilateral lender IMF's US$4.7 billion loan package has been improvement in the country's tax-to-GDP ratio, one of the lowest in the world. Currently, the ratio is 6.6 per cent, which the IMF wants to be raised to 8.4 per cent within</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 18:30:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Turkish military plane with 20 on board crashes In Georgia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/turkish-military-plane-with-20-on-board-crashes-in-georgia</link><description>A Turkish C-130 military cargo plane with at least 20 personnel on board crashed in Georgia on Tuesday after taking off from Azerbaijan but the number of casualties and the cause of the incident were not immediately clear.
Initial video from the scene near the Azerbaijan border showed chunks of tw</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 19:32:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ethics, trust, and inclusive growth define Midland Bank's journey</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ethics-trust-and-inclusive-growth-define-midland-banks-journey</link><description>Midland Bank PLC, a fourth-generation bank in Bangladesh, has attained steady progress through prudent management, ethical values, digital innovation, and a focus on inclusive growth. In an exclusive interview with The Financial Express, the bank's Managing Director and CEO, Md Ahsan-uz Zaman, disc</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 21:00:44 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>