<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 10:23:29 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Tarique heads to Election Commision to enrol as voter</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-heads-to-election-commision-to-enrol-as-voter</link><description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman has set off for the Election Commission headquarters to register as a voter after visiting the graves of slain Inquilab Moncho leader Osman Hadi and National Poet Kazi Nazrul Islam.
His motorcade departed from the National Poet’s Mausoleum complex at Dhaka</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 06:39:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dense fog disrupts flights at Dhaka airport</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/dense-fog-disrupts-flights-at-dhaka-airport</link><description>Several international flights were unable to land at Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport on Saturday morning due to dense fog, airport sources said.
The flights were diverted to Chattogram, Kolkata, and Bangkok as visibility dropped sharply over the capital, Civil Aviation Authority of Banglade</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 06:54:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique arrives at EC’s NID wing to register as voter</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-arrives-at-ecs-nid-wing-to-register-as-voter</link><description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman arrived at the Election Commission's National Identity Wing in the city's Agargaon area on Saturday to complete his National Identity Card (NID) registration and enlist himself as a voter.
He reached the National Identity Wing office, located at the Electoral Tra</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 07:27:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Zaima Rahman completes voter registration</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/zaima-rahman-completes-voter-registration</link><description>Zaima Rahman, the daughter of BNP leader Tarique Rahman, has completed the formalities to be registered as a voter ahead of the upcoming general election.
She provided fingerprints, iris scans and other biometric information at the Election Training Institute (ETI) building in Agargaon on Saturd</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 07:42:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique Rahman to receive NID within 24 hrs: NID DG</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-rahman-to-receive-nid-within-24-hrs-nid-dg</link><description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman is expected to receive his National Identity Card (NID) within 24 hours of completing his voter registration, ASM Humayun Kabir, Director General of the National Identity Registration Wing at the Election Commission, said on Saturday.
"Tarique Rahman has already</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 07:57:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka Capitals assistant coach dies after collapsing before BPL match</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/dhaka-capitals-assistant-coach-dies-after-collapsing-before-bpl-match</link><description>Dhaka Capitals’ assistant coach Mahbub Ali passed away after collapsing on the field just minutes before the start of their Bangladesh Premier League (BPL) match against Rajshahi Warriors in Sylhet on Saturday.
He was taken to a hospital after the collapse, where he died.
The incident occur</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 07:59:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Three of a family die as truck collides with ambulance in Faridpur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/three-of-a-family-die-as-truck-collides-with-ambulance-in-faridpur</link><description>Three members of a family have been killed after an ambulance collided head-on with a truck in Faridpur.
Two others were injured in the accident that occurred around 7:30 am on Saturday in the Munsurabad area on the Bhanga–Khulna highway, according to Bhanga Highway Police Station chief (OC)</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 08:14:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC to decide on Tarique, Zaima’s inclusion in voter list for 2026 polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-to-decide-on-tarique-zaimas-inclusion-in-voter-list-for-2026-polls</link><description>The Election Commission will decide on the inclusion of BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman and his daughter Zaima Rahman in the national voter list, which will be used for the upcoming general election and the referendum scheduled for February 12, 2026.
"Their names will be placed before the commi</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 08:29:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>RMG exporters seek re-fixing of cash incentives on local yarn</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/rmg-exporters-seek-re-fixing-of-cash-incentives-on-local-yarn</link><description>Apparel exporters have called for the restoration and re-fixing of cash incentives on the use of local yarn, citing the deteriorating condition of domestic spinning mills and the need to improve export competitiveness.
They have proposed restoring the cash incentive on the use of local yarn in exp</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 08:44:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Max SIMs under single NID cut down to five</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/max-sims-under-single-nid-cut-down-to-five</link><description>he Bangladesh Telecommunication Regulatory Commission (BTRC) has decided to reduce the number of SIM cards that can be registered under a single National Identity Card (NID), setting a new ceiling of five per individual, to be effective from 1 January 2026.
Under the revised policy, any SIMs excee</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 08:59:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique visits graves of brother Coco, father-in-law</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-visits-graves-of-brother-coco-father-in-law</link><description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman has visited the graves of his younger brother and father-in-law in Dhaka, a day after paying tribute at his father’s burial site.
Tarique arrived at Banani Graveyard around 2pm on Saturday to visit the grave of his younger brother, Arafat Rahman Coco. He st</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 09:45:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rashed Khan leaves Gono Odhikar Parishad to join BNP</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/rashed-khan-leaves-gono-odhikar-parishad-to-join-bnp</link><description>Rashed Khan, the general secretary of Gono Odhikar Parishad, has left the party and officially joined the BNP.
He joined the BNP by presenting a bouquet to BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir at the chairperson’s office at Dhaka’s Gulshan on Saturday, reports bdnews24.com</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 10:00:22 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>