<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 19:18:06 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Syria to start currency swap on January 1, central bank governor says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/syria-to-start-currency-swap-on-january-1-central-bank-governor-says</link><description>Syria will start swapping old banknotes for new ones from January 1, 2026, Central Bank Governor Abdelkader Husrieh said on Thursday, under a plan to replace Assad-era notes to try to strengthen the currency's value.
Syria’s new government, led by Syrian President Ahmed al-Sharaa, is seeking</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 15:35:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Forest great Robertson, ‘Picasso of our game’, dies at 72</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/football/forest-great-robertson-picasso-of-our-game-dies-at-72</link><description>John Robertson, the Nottingham Forest winger described by his manager Brian Clough as “a Picasso of our game”, has died at the age of 72, the Premier League club said on Thursday.
He was a key member of Clough’s all-conquering Forest team, assisting Trevor Francis’s winner</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 15:50:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique Rahman returns home amid rapturous reception</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-rahman-returns-home-amid-rapturous-reception</link><description>Ending his 17 years in exile, BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman returned to Bangladesh on Thursday, greeted by a rapturous reception from hundreds of thousands of jubilant supporters, marking his homecoming as a historic and triumphant event.
The BNP leader’s arrival marked a significant mo</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 16:07:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Israeli military says it killed a member of Iran’s Quds Force in Lebanon</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/israeli-military-says-it-killed-a-member-of-irans-quds-force-in-lebanon</link><description>The Israeli military said on Thursday that its forces killed a member of Iran's Quds Force in Lebanon who had been involved in planning attacks from Syria and Lebanon.
The military identified the man as Hussein Mahmoud Marshad al-Jawhari, calling him a key operative in the force's unit 840.
He wa</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 16:22:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New Year 2026 and Bangladesh's journey towards peace, progress, and prosperity</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/new-year-2026-and-bangladeshs-journey-towards-peace-progress-and-prosperity</link><description>As Bangladesh welcomes the dawn of 2026, the nation finds itself at a decisive moment in its journey toward sustainable development, political stability, and social inclusion. This year is more than a simple turning of the calendar; it represents a critical juncture to reflect upon past achievement</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 16:37:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Epoch-making Bangali singers of yesteryears</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/reviews/epoch-making-bangali-singers-of-yesteryears</link><description>Long before the arrival of Uttam Kumar (1926-80), actor-director-screenwriter Pramathesh Barua (1903-51) was the first male heartthrob of Bangla cinema. His movie version of Devdas (1935) was most authentic. Like the Cumilla-born and raised, Victoria College-educated singer-musician Sachin Dev Burm</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 16:52:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Death traps all around</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/death-traps-all-around</link><description>Death traps are everywhere in Bangladesh. They lurk in accident-prone roads where vehicles race each other recklessly, in waterways where vessels capsize without warning, in sudden outbreaks of violence over trifling matters, and in bomb hurling in public spaces. Another type of quietest but deadli</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 16:52:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bureaucratic inertia, inefficiency foil good initiatives</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/bureaucratic-inertia-inefficiency-foil-good-initiatives</link><description>Many complain that there were so many reform commissions but no commission on education. It now seems it was better that the sector was left alone. Nowadays, the focus is on the scheduled election and reform agendas hardly figure in deliberations. Chiefs of several commissions have publicly express</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 17:07:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Reducing inequality through higher taxes on the wealthy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/reducing-inequality-through-higher-taxes-on-the-wealthy</link><description>In a strategic shift, the government is preparing to raise the tax incidence on wealthy or 'high-net-worth individuals' (HNWIs) as part of its efforts to address widening income inequality. This proposed approach is outlined in the Medium- and Long-term Revenue Strategy (MLTRS) for FY2025-26 to FY2</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 17:22:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Diverse masses throng to welcome Tarique Rahman home</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/from-elders-to-teenagers-diverse-masses-throng-to-welcome-tarique-rahman-home</link><description>A sea of people from all walks of life thronged the 300 Feet Road on Thursday to welcome BNP acting chairman Tarique Rahman back to Bangladesh after 17 years in exile.
“I have come to see Tarique, as I have long admired his father and mother, and now I want to see him lead the country from t</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 17:37:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCP, Jamaat in talks to form election alliance</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ncp-jamaat-negotiate-seat-sharing-pact-to-contest-in-parliamentary-polls</link><description>The National Citizen Party (NCP) is holding talks with the Jamaat-e-Islami to form an alliance for the February elections, according to the parties’ leaders.
A Facebook post by Abdul Kader, a former coordinator of the Students Against Discrimination and one of the leaders of the July Uprisin</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 17:52:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique seeks peace, unity on homecoming</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-seeks-peace-unity-on-homecoming</link><description>On a euphoric homecoming after precious 17 years in forced political exile, BNP leader Tarique Rahman promises political bonhomie in the divisive polity and calls for rebuilding Bangladesh as safe abode for all.       
At a mammoth reception rally on return home</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 18:55:09 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>