<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 15:38:16 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>China to lift restrictions on UK lawmakers, PM Starmer says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/china-to-lift-restrictions-on-uk-lawmakers-pm-starmer-says</link><description>China is set to lift restrictions which it had imposed on a group of British lawmakers, Prime Minister Keir Starmer said on Friday, meaning that they will now be free to travel to China.
Starmer made the announcement during his four-day visit to China, the first by a UK leader in eight years, aime</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 12:16:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique pays tribute at July martyr Abu Sayed’s grave in Rangpur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-pays-tribute-at-july-martyr-abu-sayeds-grave-in-rangpur</link><description>BNP chief Tarique Rahman has paid his respects at the grave of Abu Sayed, the first martyr of the July 2024 mass uprising.
Tarique began his party’s election campaign in Rangpur on Friday by visiting the grave in Pirganj Upazila's Babonpur village. He travelled to the village from Bogura aft</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 12:31:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>People to participate in election spontaneously: EC Sanaullah</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/people-to-participate-in-election-spontaneously-ec-sanaullah</link><description>Election Commissioner Abul Fazal Muhammad Sanaullah expressed optimism about the upcoming polls, saying he expects citizens to participate spontaneously and actively, reflecting the vibrancy of democracy.
“There are only 12 days left for the election. I am very satisfied with the preparation</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 12:46:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Arteta shrugs off title pressure ahead of Arsenal's trip to stubborn Leeds</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/arteta-shrugs-off-title-pressure-ahead-of-arsenals-trip-to-stubborn-leeds</link><description>Mikel Arteta is keen not to let Arsenal's three-match winless streak in the Premier League affect the players, calling for his team to stay grounded as they pursue their first English top-flight title since 2003-04.
Sunday's home loss to Manchester United shaved Arsenal's lead at the top to four p</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 12:52:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India-EU free trade deal may affect Bangladesh’s garment market: Report</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/india-eu-free-trade-deal-may-affect-bangladeshs-garment-market-report</link><description>India’s historic free trade agreement with the European Union (EU) is already reverberating across South Asia, with Bangladesh and Pakistan among the countries most immediately affected, bdnews24.com reports citing Zee News.
The deal will eliminate or sharply reduce tariffs on over 90 percen</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 13:07:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shahjalal University student drowns in Sylhet’s Lalakhal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/shahjalal-university-student-drowns-in-sylhets-lalakhal</link><description>A student of Shahjalal University of Science and Technology (SUST) has died while bathing at Lalakhal, a tourist spot in Sylhet.
The incident occurred on Friday afternoon at Lalakhal Zeropoint, according to Jaintapur Police chief Mohammad Mahbubur Rahman Molla.
The drowned, identified as Musab Am</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 13:22:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rickshaw driver sent kidnapped child home after abducting him: RAB</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/rickshaw-driver-sent-kidnapped-child-home-after-abducting-him-rab</link><description>A 3-year-old boy abducted outside Mugda Hospital in Dhaka was sent to his ancestral home in Gaibandha by the rickshaw driver who kidnapped him, the Rapid Action Battalion (RAB) has said.
Following reports of the abduction, the driver, identified as 41-year-old Chan Mia, was arrested at Wireless Ga</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 13:37:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCP vows ‘reform-oriented’ roadmap</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ncp-unveils-36-point-manifesto-pledging-state-reform-justice-for-july-atrocities</link><description>The National Citizen Party (NCP) has announced a 36-point election manifesto aimed at constructing a “realistic and reform-oriented roadmap” before the February elections.
According to the party, the manifesto builds upon its vision of “governance, principled policies, and reform</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 13:52:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP’s Sirajganj-3 candidate Ainul Haque hospitalized</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnps-sirajganj-3-candidate-ainul-haque-hospitalized</link><description>BNP candidate for the Sirajganj-3 (Raiganj–Tarash) constituency, Ainul Haque, has been hospitalised in Dhaka for heart treatment.
He underwent surgery at Evercare Hospital in the capital on Thursday, during which two stents were placed in his heart, said Khandaker Selim Jahangir, former pres</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 14:15:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Iran prepared for 'fair' talks with US, Araqchi says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/iran-prepared-for-fair-talks-with-us-but-not-on-defence-capabilities-araqchi-says</link><description>Iran is prepared for the resumption of talks with the United States, but they should be fair and not include Iran's defence capabilities, Iran's chief diplomat said on Friday, as regional powers work to prevent military conflict between the two foes.
US President Donald Trump said on Thursday he p</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 14:30:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hasnat pledges crackdown on extortionists, drug dealers in Debidwar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/hasnat-pledges-crackdown-on-extortionists-drug-dealers-in-debidwar</link><description>Hasnat Abdullah, the chief organizer of the National Citizens' Party (NCP) Southern Region and the 11-party alliance nominee for the Cumilla-4 (Debidwar) constituency, on Friday declared that he would hound the extortionists, drug dealers, and loan defaulters if gets elected in the forthcoming parl</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 14:45:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EU says no post-Brexit energy deal without UK payments</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/eu-says-no-post-brexit-energy-deal-without-uk-payments</link><description>European Union countries will demand that Britain contributes financially to poorer EU member states' development as part of any deal to re-link the two sides' energy markets, according to EU documents and diplomats.
As part of efforts to reset relations following Britain's exit from the EU, the t</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 15:00:59 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>