<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 07:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Delays, dollar depreciation push up EC4J project cost to Tk 1,264 crore</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/delays-dollar-depreciation-push-up-ec4j-project-cost-to-tk-1264-crore</link><description>The cost of the Export Competitiveness for Jobs (EC4J) project, designed to boost Bangladesh’s export diversification and employment generation, has ballooned by nearly Tk 159 crore due to prolonged delays in implementation and rising foreign exchange costs.
According to official documents s</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 04:35:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Doctors urge timely treatment as breast cancer rises sharply in Rangpur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/doctors-urge-timely-treatment-as-breast-cancer-rises-sharply-in-rangpur</link><description>Breast cancer cases in Rangpur are increasing at an alarming rate, with 102 out of 267 cancer patients who underwent surgery in the last five months diagnosed with the disease, doctors at Rangpur Medical College (RMC) said Thursday.
“Many women are dying because they do not receive timely tr</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 04:50:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Saudi cuts Umrah visa entry validity to one month</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/saudi-cuts-umrah-visa-entry-validity-to-one-month</link><description>The Ministry of Hajj and Umrah of Saudi Arabia has reduced the validity period for the entry visa for Umrah from three months to one month from the date of issuance. 
However, the validity period for the stay after the pilgrim's arrival in Saudi Arabia remains unchanged at three months for pi</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 05:20:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>8 shops gutted in Kurigram fire</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/8-shops-gutted-in-kurigram-fire</link><description>Eight business establishments were gutted in a fire at Kachakata Bazaar in Nageshwari Upazila of Kurigram early Friday.
On information, a unit of the Nageshwari Fire Service rushed to the scene and brought the blaze under control within an hour, said Saiful Islam, team leader of the fire service.</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 05:35:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Schoolboy electrocuted in Panchagarh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/schoolboy-electrocuted-in-panchagarh</link><description>A schoolboy was electrocuted in Tetulia upazila of Panchagarh district on Thursday evening.
The deceased was identified as Asif Rana, 15, son of Nur Jamal of Chutchutia Gachh area under Tirnoihat union. He was a ninth-grade student of Shalbahan High School, reports BSS.
The incident occurred in t</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 05:50:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump sets refugee ceiling at record-low 7,500 with focus on white South Africans</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/trump-sets-refugee-ceiling-at-record-low-7500-with-focus-on-white-south-africans</link><description>US President Donald Trump set the refugee admissions ceiling at 7,500 for fiscal year 2026, the lowest cap on record, a White House document published on Thursday said, part of a broader effort to reshape refugee policies in the US and worldwide.
Trump said in an annual refugee determination dated</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 06:05:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Wrong-way van driver dies after collision with truck</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/wrong-way-van-driver-dies-after-collision-with-truck</link><description>A van driver was killed after being hit by a truck while crossing the road in the wrong direction on the Hatikumrul-Dhaka-Pabna road in Ullapara upazila of Sirajganj on Friday.
The deceased was identified as Ranzu Ahmed, 35, son of Yasin Ali from Chariashika Dakshin Para village in the same upazil</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 06:50:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rejoinder (2025-10-31)</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/rejoinder-2025-10-31</link><description>United Commercial Bank (UCB) has ruled out any discussion regarding a possible merger, saying that no such initiative is under consideration by either Bangladesh Bank (BB) or the bank itself.
The country's first-generation private commercial bank (PCB) also reaffirmed that there is no merger issue</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 07:20:05 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>