<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 06:39:26 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Thailand looks to sign free trade deal with Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/thailand-looks-to-sign-free-trade-deal-with-bangladesh</link><description>Thailand has expressed strong interest in opening negotiations on a bilateral free-trade agreement with Bangladesh, a move that could significantly expand trade and encourage Thai investment, as Dhaka intensifies efforts to deepen economic and diplomatic engagement with South-east Asia.
The newly-</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 02:11:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ACC approves case against S Alam Group, Zaman Syndicate</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/acc-approves-case-against-s-alam-group-zaman-syndicate</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) on Sunday approved filing a case against the "Zaman Syndicate," linked to Nabil Group, and officials of S Alam Group, over a Tk 10.08-billion-loan fraud and money laundering at Islami Bank Bangladesh PLC's Pabna branch.
According to the ACC, Md Aminul Islam, ma</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 02:26:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>T-bill yields rise ahead of year-end closing</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/t-bill-yields-rise-ahead-of-year-end-closing</link><description>Yields on treasury bills (T-bills), particularly long-term ones, rose on Sunday as banks appeared reluctant to park excess liquidity in government securities ahead of the year-end closing.
The cut-off yield on 91-day T-bills remained unchanged at 10.55 per cent, while the yield on 182-day T-bills</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 02:41:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Large-caps drive volatility in struggling stock market</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/large-caps-drive-volatility-in-struggling-stock-market</link><description>The wobbling equity market has experienced heightened volatility over the past three weeks, driven primarily by significant price erosion among market leaders, including Grameenphone.
A combination of factors, including a decline in foreign portfolio investments, concerns over the viability of s</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 02:56:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>First Security Islami Bank reveals true financial health</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/first-security-islami-bank-reveals-true-financial-health</link><description>First Security Islami Bank has shocked its stakeholders by revealing a staggering loss of Tk 575.8 billion for the first nine months of 2025, significantly increasing the losses previously reported for the same period.
This revision follows a directive from Bangladesh Bank, which has raised concer</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 03:41:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BD’s capital market missing from global investment discourse</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/bds-capital-market-missing-from-global-investment-discourse</link><description>Bangladesh remains largely absent from global and regional discussions on capital markets and investment, former Bangladesh Bank governor Dr Mohammed Farashuddin said on Saturday.
He noted that stock markets in cities such as Karachi, Lahore, Mumbai, Bangkok and Colombo -- and even Bhutan -- are r</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 03:56:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt addresses challenges of shipbreaking industry</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/govt-addresses-challenges-of-shipbreaking-industry</link><description>Secretary of the Ministry of Industries Mohammad Obaidur Rahman said the government is working to resolve the longstanding challenges faced by the shipbreaking industry through policy support and capacity-building initiatives.
He made the remarks while inaugurating the office of the Bangladesh S</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 04:28:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BPCS consortium signs SLTE supply deal with Nokia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bpcs-consortium-signs-slte-supply-deal-with-nokia</link><description>The Bangladesh Private Cable System (BPCS) Consortium has signed an agreement with Nokia for the supply of Submarine Line Terminal Equipment (SLTE), marking a significant step forward for the Cox's Bazar-Singapore submarine cable project.
The agreement was signed on Sunday evening at a ceremony he</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 04:43:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>School bus accident in Colombia kills 17, injures 20</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/school-bus-accident-in-colombia-kills-17-injures-20</link><description>Seventeen people were killed and 20 were injured after a bus carrying school children fell off a cliff in a rural area in northern Colombia, the local governor said on Sunday night.
In a post on X earlier in the day, the governor of Antioquia, Andres Julian, said the bus was travelling from the Ca</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 04:58:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Events you can attend and places to visit to celebrate the day</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/others/events-you-can-attend-and-places-to-visit-to-celebrate-the-day</link><description>If you take a rickshaw ride in the evening, roaming around the city, and suddenly notice all the high rises once dark, glittering in red and green, you will know December has arrived, precisely our victory day. 
The capital bathes in colour every year on 16 December. This year, as the city celebra</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 05:29:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh Polls: Permission must for social, religious events before electioneering</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-polls-permission-must-for-social-religious-events-before-electioneering</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has allowed the celebration of the national and international days and arrangements of social and religious events during the pre-campaign period with prior permission or consent from the returning officers concerned.
The directive was issued through a circular release</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 05:44:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hong Kong's legal clampdown on Jimmy Lai, tycoon and China critic</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/hong-kongs-legal-clampdown-on-jimmy-lai-tycoon-and-china-critic</link><description>Hong Kong media tycoon and pro-democracy activist Jimmy Lai was found guilty on Monday in his landmark security trial on charges of conspiracy to collude with foreign forces and sedition, which could mean life in prison.
The 78-year-old Lai, founder of the pro-democracy Apple Daily newspaper who h</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 05:59:04 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>