<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 12:49:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Candidates must file nomination in person</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/candidates-must-file-nomination-in-person</link><description>Intending candidates of the 13th Jatiya Sangsad election must submit their nomination papers to the returning officers (ROs) or assistant returning officers (AROs) in person, said the Election Commission (EC) in a circular.
The circular, issued on Friday, said the candidates must appear in person</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 08:31:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Osman Hadi, Inquilab Mancha member and Dhaka-8 hopeful, shot in Bijoynagar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/osman-hadi-inquilab-mancha-member-and-dhaka-8-hopeful-shot-in-bijoynagar</link><description>Osman Hadi, an independent candidate who planned to contest the Dhaka-8 parliamentary seat in the upcoming national election, has been shot.
The incident occurred in Dhaka's Bijoynagar after Jummah prayers on Friday. He has been taken to Dhaka Medical College Hospital for treatment, reports bdnews</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 09:46:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>30 recently promoted DIGs posted, 9 police officers transferred</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/30-recently-promoted-digs-posted-9-police-officers-transferred</link><description>Thirty police officers recently promoted to the rank of deputy inspector general (DIG) have been given official postings.
In addition, four more additional DIGs and five superintendents of police (SPs) have been transferred in a wider reshuffle.
The Ministry of Home Affairs issued two separate no</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 09:45:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Thailand's snap poll set to boost odds for PM Anutin, but risks loom</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/thailands-snap-poll-set-to-boost-odds-for-pm-anutin-but-risks-loom</link><description>Thailand’s Prime Minister Anutin Charnvirakul looks set to tap burgeoning nationalism over a border conflict with Cambodia to boost his appeal in a general election stemming from his dissolution of parliament after less than 100 days in power.
The political manoeuvering came after fierce bor</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 10:00:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Those seeking election delay are in anti-democracy camp: Salahuddin</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/those-seeking-election-delay-are-in-anti-democracy-camp-salahuddin</link><description>Stating that some parties have accepted the national election and referendum schedule with heavy hearts, BNP senior leader Salahuddin Ahmed on Friday said those who had earlier pushed for delaying the polls belong to an “anti-democracy camp”.
“The announcement of the election sch</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 10:15:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Yunus expresses deep concern over shooting of independent candidate hopeful in Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/yunus-expresses-deep-concern-over-shooting-of-independent-candidate-hopeful-in-dhaka</link><description>Interim government Chief Adviser Professor Dr Muhammad Yunus has expressed deep concern over the shooting of Sharif Osman Hadi, spokesperson of Inqilab Moncho and a potential independent candidate for Dhaka-8, who was critically injured after being attacked by assailants in the capital’s Bijo</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 10:30:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mirza Abbas jeered as he visits injured Hadi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-leader-mirza-abbas-faces-angry-chants-as-he-visits-injured-hadi</link><description>Senior BNP leader Mirza Abbas has come under fire from supporters of Sharif Osman bin Hadi when he arrived at the hospital to see the injured independent hopeful for Dhaka-8 and Inqilab Mancha convener.
Around 4pm on Friday, as Abbas, the BNP-nominated candidate for the constituency, reached the e</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 10:45:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US preparing to seize more tankers off Venezuela's coast</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/us-preparing-to-seize-more-tankers-off-venezuelas-coast-after-first-ship-taken-sources-say</link><description>The US is preparing to intercept more ships transporting Venezuelan oil following the seizure of a tanker this week, as it increases pressure on Venezuelan President Nicolas Maduro, six sources familiar with the matter said on Thursday.
The seizure was the first interdiction of an oil cargo or tan</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 11:00:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Osman Hadi in ‘critical’ condition</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/gunshot-dhaka-8-independent-candiate-osman-hadi-in-critical-condition</link><description>The condition of Sharif Osman bin Hadi, an independent candidate for Dhaka-8 who has been shot, is said to be "critical".
Assailants riding on three motorcycles shot and wounded him on Box Culvert Road in the capital’s Bijoynagar area after Friday’s Juma prayers, police said.
Hadi, th</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 11:15:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sajid laid to rest at family graveyard</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/sajid-laid-to-rest-at-family-graveyard</link><description>Two-year-old Sajid, who died after falling into an abandoned deep tubewell in Tanore upazila of Rajshahi, was buried at a family graveyard on Friday morning.
Maulana Mizanur Rahman led the janaza held at Koelhat village, after which the child was laid to rest. 
From early morning, villagers</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 11:30:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP condemns attack on Hadi, demands quick arrest of attackers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bnp-condemns-attack-on-hadi-demands-quick-arrest-of-attackers</link><description>BNP on Friday expressed deep concern over the attack on independent candidate Sharif Osman Hadi and demanded the immediate arrest of those involved in the attack.
In a statement issued on Friday, BNP Senior Joint Secretary General Ruhul Kabir Rizvi said the incident is part of a “dangerous a</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 11:45:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mongolian envoy meets Fakhrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/mongolian-envoy-meets-fakhrul</link><description>BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir on Friday met Mongolian Non-Resident Ambassador Ganbold Dambajav at the BNP Chairperson’s Gulshan office.
The ambassador’s flag-bearing car entered the office premises at around 11am, where Mirza Fakhrul welcomed him.
BNP Standing Comm</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 12:00:45 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>