<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 11:18:57 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Tiger trapped in poachers’ snare in Sundarbans; rescue operation underway</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/tiger-trapped-in-poachers-snare-in-sundarbans-rescue-operation-underway</link><description>A Royal Bengal Tiger has been trapped in a snare set by deer poachers in the Sundarbans near Boiragi Bari along the Sarkir canal in Mongla upazila of Bagerhat district.
A local fisherman first spotted the tiger inside the trap around noon on Saturday, about half a kilometre away from human habitat</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 08:16:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh Bank rolls out risk-based supervision to rebuild depositor confidence</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh-bank-rolls-out-risk-based-supervision-to-rebuild-depositor-confidence</link><description>Bangladesh Bank has launched a new Risk-Based Supervision (RBS) framework, marking a major shift in how the country’s banking and financial institutions are monitored as authorities seek to restore confidence among depositors after years of sectoral stress.
The central bank on Sunday formall</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 08:31:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mustafizur, Taskin to lead Bangladesh's bowling at T20 World Cup</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/mustafizur-taskin-to-lead-bangladeshs-bowling-at-t20-world-cup</link><description>Fast bowlers Mustafizur Rahman and Taskin Ahmed will lead Bangladesh's bowling attack at next month's Twenty20 World Cup while batter Jaker Ali was axed as the country's cricket board (BCB) named their 15-man squad for the tournament on Sunday.
Taskin, who has taken 106 wickets in 86 T20Is, return</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 08:46:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Numerous teenagers among the dead in Swiss bar blaze, police say</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/numerous-teenagers-among-the-dead-in-swiss-bar-blaze-police-say</link><description>Teenagers as young as 14 and 15 years old were among those who died in the bar fire on New Year’s Eve that killed 40 people in Switzerland, police said on Sunday.
Police in Valais said they had identified 16 more of those who died in the blaze in Crans-Montana, one of the worst disasters in</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 09:01:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>9,111 killed in road accidents in 2025</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/9111-killed-in-road-accidents-in-2025</link><description>Road accidents have killed 9,111 people and injured 14,812 others across the country in 2025, according to the Bangladesh Passenger Welfare Association.
The organisation says a total of 6,729 road accidents were recorded during the year, says a bdnews24.com report.
Of these, 2,493 involved motorc</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 09:16:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka, Islamabad foreign affairs chiefs hold telephone talks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dhaka-islamabad-foreign-affairs-chiefs-hold-telephone-talks</link><description>Foreign Affairs Adviser Md Touhid Hossain and Pakistan's Deputy Prime Minister and Foreign Minister Senator Mohammad Ishaq Dar held a telephone conversation on Sunday and discussed issues of mutual interest.
They reviewed Bangladesh-Pakistan relations and reaffirmed their commitment to enhancing c</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 09:31:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Why homemakers' labour still doesn't count</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/why-homemakers-labour-still-doesnt-count</link><description>Imagine a company that depends entirely on one person. That person manages HR, balances the accounts, cooks the meals, teaches lessons, and plans every event, all without pay or a single day off. That person works 15 hours a day, seven days a week, yet work is invisible on the balance sheet—n</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 09:46:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>503 killed in Bangladesh road accidents in December: RSF report</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/503-killed-in-bangladesh-road-accidents-in-december-rsf-report</link><description>A total of 503 people lost their lives and 1,186 others were injured in 547 road accidents across the country in December last year, according to data released by the Road Safety Foundation (RSF).
Besides, at least 14 people were killed and five injured in nine waterway accidents while 36 people d</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 10:01:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DMP bans gatherings near Secretariat, CA’s residence again</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dmp-bans-gatherings-near-secretariat-chief-advisors-residence-again</link><description>Dhaka Metropolitan Police (DMP) has once again imposed a ban on gatherings at several key locations in the capital, citing public order and security concerns.
In a public notice issued on Sunday, DMP Commissioner SM Sazzat Ali said all forms of meetings, rallies, mass gatherings, processions, huma</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 10:16:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tejgaon College students leave roads</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tejgaon-college-students-leave-roads-after-4-hours</link><description>Student protesters of Tejgaon College who blocked the road in the Farmgate area protesting the death of a fellow peer following a clash between two groups at the college hostel, have left after almost four hours.
Traffic movement resumed after 2:00pm on Sunday when the students withdrew from the r</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 10:31:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nomination scrutiny ends Sunday, EC issues appeal guidelines</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nomination-scrutiny-ends-sunday-ec-issues-appeal-guidelines</link><description>The scrutiny of nomination papers by Returning Officers for the 13th Jatiya Sangsad Election will be completed on Sunday, while the Election Commission (EC) has also released the prescribed format for filing appeals against the acceptance or rejection of nomination papers. 
Appeals can be sub</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 10:46:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BERC hikes LPG price for Jan, admits lacks of control over retailers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/berc-hikes-lpg-price-for-jan-admits-lacks-of-control-over-retailers</link><description>Bangladesh Energy Regulatory Commission (BERC) has raised the price of a 12-kg LPG cylinder by Tk 53 to Tk 1,306 for January, but admitted it cannot guarantee retailers will follow the official price.
BERC announced the new prices at its Ramna office in the afternoon, which came into effect from 6</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 11:01:48 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>