<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 14:23:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Elections in New York, New Jersey and Virginia offer early test of Trump's agenda</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/elections-in-new-york-new-jersey-and-virginia-offer-early-test-of-trumps-agenda</link><description>Voters in New Jersey and Virginia will choose their next governors on Tuesday in a pair of races that will serve as an early gauge of the American electorate's response to President Donald Trump's norm-shattering nine months in office.
Meanwhile, in New York City's mayoral race, Democratic nominee</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 10:50:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BGMEA seeks joint initiative with US cotton exporters for proportionate tariff reduction</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bgmea-seeks-joint-initiative-with-us-cotton-exporters-for-proportionate-tariff-reduction</link><description>Bangladesh’s apparel exporters have expressed interest in working jointly with U.S. cotton exporters to secure proportionate tariff reductions by promoting the use of American raw materials in the country’s garment industry.
As the recently announced U.S. executive order that allows pr</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 11:05:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Romania to set up fund for critical flood infrastructure</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/romania-to-set-up-fund-for-critical-flood-infrastructure</link><description>Romania will set up an infrastructure fund to address flood emergencies over at least five years, a requirement to unblock European Union recovery funds, Environment Minister Diana Buzoianu said.
The country has seen some of its worst floods in at least two decades in 2024 and this year, causing 1</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 11:20:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US government shutdown ties record, as congressional inaction takes toll</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-government-shutdown-ties-record-as-congressional-inaction-takes-toll</link><description>The U.S. government shutdown on Tuesday entered its 35th day, matching a record set during President Donald Trump’s first term for the longest in history, as Republicans and Democrats in Congress continue to blame each other for the standoff.
The toll increases by the day. Food assistance fo</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 11:35:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IUB launches ‘Mahale Voices’ to keep endangered Mahale language alive</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/iub-launches-mahale-voices-to-keep-endangered-mahale-language-alive</link><description>Independent University, Bangladesh (IUB) has launched a research-based book titled Mahale Voices to support the preservation of the endangered Mahale language, spoken by the Mahale community in the Rajshahi region.
The book was unveiled on October 29, 2025, at the DMK Lecture Gallery on the IUB ca</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 12:05:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP suspends Kamal Jaman Mollah’s nomination in Madaripur-1</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-suspends-kamal-jaman-mollahs-nomination-in-madaripur-1</link><description>BNP on Tuesday suspended the nomination of Kamal Jaman Mollah for the Madaripur-1 constituency.
The announcement came in a press release signed by the party’s Senior Joint Secretary General Ruhul Kabir Rizvi.
The release said Kamal Jaman Molla’s name was announced during a press confe</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 12:20:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DU issues show-cause notice to 403 students over July uprising violence</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/du-issues-show-cause-notice-to-403-students-over-july-uprising-violence</link><description>Dhaka University has issued show-cause notices to 403 Bangladesh Chhatra League (BCL) leaders and activists for their involvement in the illegal and violent incidents that took place on and around the campus during the July uprising.
 
According to an official Notice issued by the university</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 12:50:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Afghanistan earthquake kills 21, historic sites damaged</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/afghanistan-earthquake-kills-21-historic-sites-damaged</link><description>Survivors of a powerful earthquake in northern Afghanistan spent Monday night outdoors in freezing temperatures as rescue operations continued and historical sites suffered damage.
The 6.3-magnitude quake struck just before 1 a.m. Monday near Khulm in Samangan province, killing 21 and injuring ove</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 13:05:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>37 prisoners to be freed on ‘special consideration’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/37-long-term-prisoners-granted-sentence-remission-under-twenty-years-rule</link><description>The Department of Prisons has decided to release 37 prisoners who have served more than 20 years behind bars, taking into account their conduct, prison record, age, and the nature of their offences.
The decision was announced on Tuesday through an order issued by the department, which said the rem</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 13:35:10 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>