<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 08:57:18 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Govt issues ordinance forming Dhaka Central University</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/govt-issues-ordinance-forming-dhaka-central-university</link><description>The Bangladesh government has issued an ordinance forming the Dhaka Central University colleges to manage higher education and research at seven public colleges in the capital.
However, the ordinance does not divide the seven colleges into four schools as proposed in the initial draft. Instead, th</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 05:45:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>T20 World Cup Crisis: ICC and BCB agree on 'formula' as PCB seeks PM’s nod</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/t20-world-cup-crisis-icc-and-bcb-agree-on-formula-as-pcb-seeks-pms-nod</link><description>A major breakthrough in the ongoing T20 World Cup crisis appears imminent following a marathon five-hour meeting between the International Cricket Council (ICC), the Pakistan Cricket Board (PCB) and the Bangladesh Cricket Board (BCB) in Lahore on Sunday.
Sources indicate that a resolution could be</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 06:00:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mobile phones banned near polling centres</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/mobile-phones-banned-near-polling-centres</link><description>The Election Commission has banned mobile phones within 400 yards of polling centres during the national election and referendum on Feb 12.
Senior Assistant Secretary Md Shahidul Islam issued instructions to returning officers on Sunday to enforce the restriction, reports bdnews24.com.
Only presi</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 06:15:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two killed in Munshiganj road crash</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/two-killed-in-munshiganj-road-crash</link><description>Two people were killed after a pickup was hit by an unknown vehicle in Srinagar upazila of Munshiganj district on Monday.
The deceased were pickup driver Sujan, 37, hailed from Baliadanga area in Rajarhat upazila of Jashore district and Isarul, son of Jiban of Dumuria upazila in Khulna, reports UN</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 06:30:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Banks sign NDAs with global consortiums to sue absconding money launderers abroad: BB governor</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/banks-sign-ndas-with-global-consortiums-to-sue-absconding-money-launderers-abroad-bb-governor</link><description>Bangladesh Bank (BB) Governor Dr Ahsan H Mansur on Monday said commercial banks have signed nondisclosure agreements (NDAs) with 12 global consortiums to file civil suits against absconding money launderers in foreign countries.
“As far as my knowledge is concerned, most banks have signed th</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 06:45:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>KUMCH female student found dead in Kushtia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/kumch-female-student-found-dead-in-kushtia</link><description>Police recovered the body of a female student of Kushtia Medical College Hospital (KUMCH) hanging from the ceiling of a rented room at Housing E-Block area in Kushtia district town on Sunday evening.
The deceased was identified as Samia Nijhum, daughter of Md Abdus Salam of Chotp Shalikha area of</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 07:00:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bomb-making materials seized in Chapainawabganj</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bomb-making-materials-seized-in-chapainawabganj</link><description>Rapid Action Battalion (RAB) members recovered 6.27 kilograms of gunpowder and bomb-making materials in Shibganj upazila of Chapainawabganj district on Sunday night.
According to a press release sent by RAB-5 on Monday morning, those were seized from a mustard field in the Parghorapakhia area.
No</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 07:15:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Results of 13th JS polls to be announced by Feb 13: EC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/results-of-13th-js-polls-to-be-announced-by-feb-13-ec</link><description>The results of the 13th Jatiya Sangsad election and referendum, scheduled to be held on February 12, will be announced by the following day, Election Commissioner Anowarul Islam Sarkar said.
The election and the referendum will be held simultaneously this year, leading to speculation that the anno</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 07:30:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh set to vote in world's first Gen Z-inspired election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-set-to-vote-in-worlds-first-gen-z-inspired-election</link><description>For years under former Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina, Bangladesh’s opposition had little presence on the streets during elections, either boycotting polls or being sidelined by mass arrests of senior leaders. Now, ahead of Thursday’s vote, the roles have reversed.
Hasina’s Awami L</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 07:45:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No security threats surrounding general election, says DMP chief Sazzat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/no-security-threats-surrounding-general-election-says-dmp-chief-sazzat</link><description>Dhaka Metropolitan Police (DMP) Commissioner SM Sazzat Ali says there are no threats of violence surrounding the upcoming 13th parliamentary election.
Speaking at a media briefing on Monday, Sazzat said a total of 25,000 specially trained police personnel will be on duty for the polls, reports b</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 08:00:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ex-Army chief Iqbal Karim Bhuiyan calls for RAB, DGFI to be dissolved</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ex-army-chief-iqbal-karim-bhuiyan-calls-for-rab-dgfi-to-be-dissolved</link><description>Former Bangladesh Army chief Iqbal Karim Bhuiyan has called for the dissolution of the Rapid Action Battalion (RAB) and the Directorate General of Forces Intelligence (DGFI), accusing the two agencies of involvement in enforced disappearances and killings.
Iqbal, widely known as IKB, made the re</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 08:15:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Electioneering in JS polls to end Tuesday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/electioneering-in-js-polls-to-end-tuesday</link><description>Campaigning by candidates contesting the 13th Jatiya Sangsad elections and the referendum, scheduled for February 12, will officially end on Tuesday at 7:30 am. 
The electioneering period, which began on January 22, concludes 48 hours before polling day, in line with the rules of the Election</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 08:30:42 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>