<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 04:26:43 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Sinopec set to drill five new gas wells in Bhola</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/sinopec-set-to-drill-five-new-gas-wells-in-bhola</link><description>China's state-owned oil- and gas-exploration-company Sinopec is poised to secure a contract to drill five new gas wells on gas-rich Bhola island, as Bangladesh moves to ramp up domestic production of the fuel amid mounting energy demand.
Bangladesh Petroleum Exploration and Production Company Ltd</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 01:38:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IMED flags irregularities, mismanagement in Padma Oil HQ project</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/imed-flags-irregularities-mismanagement-in-padma-oil-hq-project</link><description>The Implementation Monitoring and Evaluation Division (IMED) under the Planning Ministry has found serious irregularities, fund misuse, and mismanagement in the project to construct the head office of Padma Oil Company Limited in Chattogram, which has remained incomplete for over a decade.
Officia</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 01:53:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BD to establish first national actuarial instituteq</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bd-to-establish-first-national-actuarial-instituteq</link><description>Bangladesh is taking steps to set up a national actuarial institute to build a pool of qualified professionals capable of assessing and managing complex financial and insurance-related risks.



The move, led by the Insurance Development and Regulatory Authority (IDRA), seeks to enhance the cou</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 02:08:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>METRO RAIL BEARING PAD ACCIDENT: Ridership sees little impact in absence of viable alternatives</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/metro-rail-bearing-pad-accident-ridership-sees-little-impact-in-absence-of-viable-alternatives</link><description>The recent Dhaka metro-rail bearing-pad accident has had little impact on overall ridership, as most passengers continue to use the service due to a lack of alternatives.
However, analysts say the incident's effects are visible in operational disruptions, resulted a temporary suspension of train s</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 02:23:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC revises poll symbol list, includes 'Water Lily Bud'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-revises-poll-symbol-list-includes-water-lily-bud</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) on Thursday unveiled a revised list of 119 electoral symbols, now incorporating the 'Water Lily Bud' (Shapla Koli).
A revision to the election regulations was issued in this connection in a notice signed by EC Secretary Akhtar Ahmed on the day.
But the National Citi</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 02:38:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NBR extends deadline for paper return application to November 15</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nbr-extends-deadline-for-paper-return-application-to-november-15</link><description>The National Board of Revenue (NBR) has extended the deadline for individual taxpayers to apply for permission to file their income-tax returns in paper form until November 15, pushing back the original deadline of October 31.
Under the current fiscal year's regulations, all taxpayers-except for c</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 02:53:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Legal notice challenges BR's e-ticketing deal with Shohoz</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/legal-notice-challenges-brs-e-ticketing-deal-with-shohoz</link><description>A Supreme Court lawyer has served a legal notice on several government authorities, demanding the suspension of the contract between the Ministry of Railways and Shohoz, the private vendor responsible for Bangladesh Railway's online ticketing services.
The notice seeks action within seven days, ci</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 03:08:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two-day Int’l Cancer Congress begins in city</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/two-day-intl-cancer-congress-begins-in-city</link><description>The two-day Bangladesh International Cancer Congress 2025, organized by the Oncology Club, Bangladesh, began at a hotel in the capital on Thursday.
Speaking at the inaugural session, experts highlighted that the rising incidence of cancer in Bangladesh and other developing countries is largely dri</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 03:23:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Top banks' inherent strengths drive profit growth in Jan-Sept</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/top-banks-inherent-strengths-drive-profit-growth-in-jan-sept</link><description>Well-performing banks offset a year-on-year decline in net interest income in the nine months through September with higher returns from investments in government securities.



Market-based interest rates helped lenders earn more in interest during the period compared to the same period last y</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 03:38:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hurricane Melissa death toll climbs to 44</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/hurricane-melissa-death-toll-climbs-to-44</link><description>Hurricane Melissa's confirmed death toll climbed to 44 on Thursday, according to official reports, after wreaking destruction across much of the northern Caribbean and picking up speed as it headed toward Bermuda.
Jamaica's information minister told Reuters at least 19 deaths had been confirmed, b</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 04:23:27 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>