<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 12:48:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Explosion at mosque in Syria's Homs kills three, says local official</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/explosion-at-mosque-in-syrias-homs-kills-three-says-local-official</link><description>Three people were killed and five injured when an explosion struck a mosque in an Alawite neighbourhood in the Syrian province of Homs on Friday, a local official said.
Syrian state media said security forces had imposed a cordon around the area and were investigating.
Local officials told Reuter</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 09:54:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Only a credible election can heal Bangladesh’s deep wounds: Press Secretary</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/only-a-credible-election-can-heal-bangladeshs-deep-wounds-press-secretary</link><description>Chief Adviser’s Press Secretary Shafiqul Alam on Friday said Bangladesh bears deep wounds—an ever-widening fracture that only a truly credible election can heal.
In a post from his verified Facebook account, he said the general election and the referendum are now just seven weeks away&amp;</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 10:09:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>White House to present plans for Trump's East Wing ballroom in January</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/white-house-to-present-plans-for-trumps-east-wing-ballroom-in-january</link><description>The White House will unveil new details on President Donald Trump's planned East Wing ballroom during a hearing early next month, according to a federal commission tasked with reviewing the project.
The new ballroom, which Trump has said would cost $400 million and would dwarf the adjacent White H</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 10:24:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two missing as freight vessel hit by launch capsizes in Narayanganj</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/two-missing-as-freight-vessel-hit-by-launch-capsizes-in-narayanganj</link><description>A sand-laden freight vessel has capsized in the Buriganga River in Narayanganj’s Fatullah after it was hit by a launch carrying passengers.
At least two workers went missing in the incident that occurred in the Dharmaganj area around 6:15 am on Friday, according to Pagla River Police Outpost</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 10:39:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Former Malaysian PM Najib convicted in 1MDB corruption case</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/former-malaysian-pm-najib-convicted-in-1mdb-corruption-case</link><description>Malaysia’s High Court on Friday convicted former Prime Minister Najib Razak in a major corruption case linked to the multibillion-dollar 1MDB state fund scandal.
The court found Najib, 72, guilty of four counts of abuse of power and 21 counts of money laundering involving more than $700 mill</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 10:54:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mild cold wave hits Chuadanga, disrupts normal life</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/mild-cold-wave-hits-chuadanga-disrupts-normal-life</link><description>A mild cold wave is sweeping across the southwestern district of Chuadanga, disrupting normal life.
According to the local met office, the district recorded this season’s lowest 9.6 degrees Celsius of temperature at 9am on Friday. Vehicles were seen moving with headlights to prevent any unwa</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 11:09:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique pays tribute at Ziaur Rahman’s grave</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-pays-tribute-at-ziaur-rahmans-grave</link><description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman on Friday paid homage to late President Ziaur Rahman by visiting his mausoleum at Zia Udyan in Sher-e-Bangla Nagar, Dhaka.
He entered the mausoleum premises at around 4:40 pm. Party leaders and activists gathered in Chandrima Udyan and nearby areas lined the road</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 11:24:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>148 tonnes of waste cleared from Tarique rally venue</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/dncc-clears-148-tonnes-of-waste-from-tarqiue-rahmans-rally-venue-in-purbachal</link><description>Dhaka North City Corporation has cleared 148 tonnes of waste from Purbachal’s July 36 Expressway, commonly known as the 300 Feet Road, where BNP’s Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman attended a reception upon returning home after 17 years in exile.
In a statement on Friday, the DNCC said it</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 11:24:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Meta takes down Asif Mahmud’s official Facebook page</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/meta-takes-down-asif-mahmuds-official-facebook-page</link><description>Meta has removed the verified Facebook page of Asif Mahmud Shojib Bhuyain, who recently stepped down from his role as an advisor to the interim government to contest the upcoming general election.
In a post on his personal Facebook account on Friday, Asif said that his official page, which had mor</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 11:39:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Thai defence minister to attend truce talks with Cambodia, PM says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/thai-defence-minister-to-attend-truce-talks-with-cambodia-pm-says</link><description>Thailand's defence minister will join ongoing talks with Cambodia on Saturday that could lead to a truce, the Thai premier said on Friday, as border clashes between the two Southeast Asian neighbours continued for a third week.
If the defence minister is able to come to an agreement with his Cambo</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 11:54:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fire at Gulistan market</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fire-at-gulistan-market</link><description>A fire has broken out on the roof of the eight-storey Gulistan Khaddar Bazar Super Complex in Dhaka.
The incident was reported at 5:28pm on Friday, according to Fire Service duty officer Ruzina Akter.
“Six units have been deployed to control the blaze,” she added.
The cause of the fi</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 12:09:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sakhawat announces compensation for launch accident victim</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/sakhawat-announces-compensation-for-launch-accident-victim</link><description>Shipping Adviser Brigadier General (retd) Dr M Sakhawat Hossain today said the government will provide Tk 150,000 each to the families of the persons died in a lunch accident at Chandpur on Friday.
Families of the each injured persons will get Taka 50,000, he said while talking to reporters after</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 12:24:27 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>