<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 21:27:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Horns banned around Secretariat from Tuesday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/honking-banned-in-and-around-secretariat-from-tuesday-police-warn-of-penalties</link><description>Drivers who honk their horns in and around the Bangladesh Secretariat will face punitive action from Tuesday, Dhaka Metropolitan Police (DMP) has warned, as the heart of government is formally declared a “silent zone”.
In a public notice issued on Sunday and signed by DMP Commissioner</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 16:12:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCT deal: 12 more staff moved after protests</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/nct-deal-12-more-staff-moved-after-protests</link><description>The Chittagong Port Authority (CPA) has transferred 12 more employees who joined the protests against leasing the New Mooring Container Terminal (NCT) to a foreign company.
They were transferred through an order signed by the chief personnel officer of the CPA on Sunday.
With the latest transfers</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 16:27:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Officer suspended for faking father to secure ‘freedom fighter’ quota job</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/officer-suspended-for-faking-father-to-secure-freedom-fighter-quota-job</link><description>The Ministry of Public Administration has temporarily suspended Md Kamal Hossain, OSD and Senior Assistant Secretary, after he was sent to jail over allegations of faking his family background to secure a university admission and a BCS administration cadre job under the freedom fighter quota.
A mi</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 17:14:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Former Chhatra Dal leader’s car fired upon in Narayanganj</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/former-chhatra-dal-leaders-car-fired-upon-in-narayanganj</link><description>A former Jatiyatabadi Chhatra Dal leader’s car has been shot at while he was returning home after campaigning for the Sheaf of Paddy symbol in Narayanganj.
The incident took place around 7:40pm on Sunday on the road next to Araihazar Bazar, said Araihazar Police chief Md Alauddin.
He said t</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 17:29:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Grammys poised to rewrite music's record books</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/entertainment/grammys-poised-to-rewrite-musics-record-books</link><description>Puerto Rican rapper Bad Bunny and the KPop singers of “Golden” will face off on Sunday at a Grammys ceremony poised to crown several first‑time winners of the US music industry’s biggest honors.
Bad Bunny is competing for album of the year with "Debí Tirar Más Fotos</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 17:00:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Power supply to be suspended in parts of Sylhet on Monday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/power-supply-to-be-suspended-in-parts-of-sylhet-on-monday</link><description>Power supply will be temporarily suspended in several important areas of Sylhet on Monday (Feb 2) due to transformer renovation and maintenance work as well as transmission line development activities.
A press release on Sunday, signed by Abdur Razzak, Executive Engineer of the Sales and Distribut</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 17:15:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Focus on trade-based money laundering</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/focus-on-trade-based-money-laundering</link><description>Illicit fund flows pose a significant risk to the integrity of the banking system and present persistent challenges for regulators operating under risk-based supervisory frameworks. In recent years, Bangladesh has formally moved towards implementing risk-based supervision, reflecting a broader shif</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 17:30:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Canadian PM's visit to China -- a turning  point in bilateral relations</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/reviews/canadian-pms-visit-to-china-a-turning-point-in-bilateral-relations</link><description>Strategic analysts have commented that Canada's Prime Minister Mark Carney accepted an invitation to visit China extended by President Xi Jinping and that this signalled a "turning point" in the countries' relationship.
The invite came after the two leaders met for 40 minutes on the sidelines of t</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 17:45:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Blaming bureaucracy for governance failure now makes no sense</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/blaming-bureaucracy-for-governance-failure-now-makes-no-sense</link><description>Muhammad Fouzul Kabir Khan, the adviser in charge of the Ministries of Power, Energy and Mineral Resources, Roads and Bridges, and Railways was at his oratorical best when he was grilling bureaucracy during an inauguration of a programme held at the BRTC Training Institute in the city on January 27</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 18:00:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A world without the UN?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/a-world-without-the-un</link><description>As the World War I or WWI ended, the victors of the war made the Covenant of the League of Nations, in short, League, in January 1920, wherein the Treaty of Versailles was included. The mission was to maintain world peace. But it failed in its mission because the vanquished in the WWI was treated l</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 18:15:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rationalising microcredit interest rates</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/rationalising-microcredit-interest-rates</link><description>As the government seeks to reform the microfinance sector, which has long been plagued by irregularities and high interest rates, a crucial question has emerged: should lending rates of microfinance banks be capped? The newly promulgated Microfinance Bank Ordinance proposes transforming eligible mi</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 18:30:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CA directs opening FTA talks with EU</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/ca-directs-opening-fta-talks-with-eu</link><description>Chief Adviser Prof Muhammad Yunus Sunday directed opening free-trade agreement (FTA) negotiations with the European Union forthwith to safeguard Bangladesh's trade preferences in its largest export market as the current duty-free access is set to expire.
The head of interim government stressed the</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 19:33:17 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>