<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 10:28:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Van driver killed after being hit by truck in Dhaka’s Jurain</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/van-driver-killed-after-being-hit-by-truck-in-dhakas-jurain</link><description>A van driver was killed early Monday after being hit by a speeding truck while crossing the road in Balur Maidan area of Jurain under Shyampur Police Station in Dhaka.
The accident occurred around 3:00 am, police said.
The deceased was identified as Md Ibrahim, 40, son of the late Anisul Mia of S</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 07:18:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mobile phone prices set to fall as NBR slashes import duty</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/mobile-phone-prices-set-to-fall-as-nbr-slashes-import-duty</link><description>The National Board of Revenue (NBR) has slashed customs duty on imported mobile phones by 60 per cent aimed at keeping handset prices within the purchasing capacity of consumers amid rising living costs.
The NBR issued two separate statutory regulatory orders in this regard.
According to an NBR n</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 07:33:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Overnight protest over SUST election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/overnight-protest-over-sust-election</link><description>Students at Shahjalal University of Science and Technology have held meetings with the university administration and the Shahjalal University Central Students Union Election Commission following overnight protests over the issuing of a notice by the Election Commission.
The students are demanding</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 07:48:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>China's heavy reliance on Iranian oil imports</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/chinas-heavy-reliance-on-iranian-oil-imports</link><description>China, the world's largest crude importer, is the main buyer of oil from OPEC producer Iran, leaving Beijing uniquely exposed to any supply disruption from conflict in the Middle East.
Beijing, which is also the biggest buyer of oil from Venezuela and a top importer of oil from Russia, has used pu</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 08:30:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Purbachal plot graft: Verdict in case against Hasina, Tulip, Ruponti on Feb 2</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/purbachal-plot-graft-verdict-in-case-against-hasina-tulip-ruponti-on-feb-2</link><description>A Dhaka court will deliver its verdict in a case filed by the Anti-Corruption Commission over corruption in the allocation of land plots in Purbachal against former prime minister Sheikh Hasina and her nieces Tulip Siddiq -- a British MP -- and Azmina Siddiq Ruponti on Feb 2.
A total of 18 suspect</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 08:45:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jhut warehouse gutted in Gazipur fire</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jhut-warehouse-gutted-in-gazipur-fire</link><description>A fire gutted a jhut (garment waste) warehouse in Salna area of Gazipur on Tuesday morning.
The fire broke out at the jhut warehouse around 12:30 pm and engulfed the adjoining houses, said Hiron Mia, station officer of Bhogra Modern Fire Service Station, reports UNB.
On information, four firefigh</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 09:00:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Auditors to face action over zeroed bank shares: Adviser Salehuddin</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/auditors-to-face-action-over-zeroed-bank-shares-adviser-salehuddin</link><description>Finance Adviser Dr Salehuddin Ahmed on Tuesday said the auditors of five banks whose shares have recently been reduced to zero would face action, as the government is examining the context in which shareholders had purchased those shares.
The banks are First Security Islami Bank, Social Islami Ban</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 09:01:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CA urges South Asian academics to align education with youth aspirations</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ca-urges-south-asian-academics-to-align-education-with-youth-aspirations</link><description>Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus today (Tuesday) called upon the academics to align the education system with the youths' expectations and aspirations and stressed on revival of the SAARC to enhance regional academic cooperation.
"Today, I feel very excited that academics at the highest leve</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 09:16:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ICC Bangladesh holds workshop on Legal and Compliance Perspectives under Documentary Credits</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/icc-bangladesh-holds-workshop-on-legal-and-compliance-perspectives-under-documentary-credits</link><description>ICC Bangladesh organized a day-long workshop on Legal and Compliance Perspectives under Documentary Credits on 10 January in Chattogram.
ICCB Secretary General Ataur Rahman inaugurated the workshop and distributed certificates among the participants, while A T M Nesarul Hoque, Executive Vice Presi</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 09:31:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh summons Myanmar envoy over border firing</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-summons-myanmar-envoy-over-border-firing</link><description>The Bangladesh government has summoned Myanmar’s ambassador to Dhaka over the shooting of a child near the Teknaf border during the ongoing internal conflict in the neighbouring country.
The foreign ministry called in Ambassador U Kyaw Soe Moe on Tuesday afternoon and expressed deep concern</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 09:46:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ICC seeks shift in Bangladesh stance, BCB holds firm</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/icc-urges-bangladesh-to-reconsider-india-venue-bcb-remains-firm</link><description>The International Cricket Council (ICC) has asked Bangladesh to reconsider its decision not to play in India for the T20 World Cup.
The Bangladesh Cricket Board (BCB), however, reaffirmed its stance, insisting that its matches be held outside India.</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 10:01:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>SAD file complaint against Salman, 24 others</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/students-against-discrimination-file-complaint-at-ict-against-salman-24-other-businessmen</link><description>Students Against Discrimination (SAD) has sought action against 25 businessmen for supporting former prime minister Sheikh Hasina during the July Uprising.
On Tuesday, the group’s Legal Cell Secretary Motasim Billah Mahfuz submitted a complaint against the accused to the prosecution of the I</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 10:16:22 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>