<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 12:46:56 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Understanding the hormones behind the chaos</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/others/understanding-the-hormones-behind-the-chaos</link><description>Girls, have you ever had an inexplicable outburst over something little? Or came down with an overwhelming feeling of anxiety? Then you questioned whether these random breakdowns were a little uncalled for. Next time you have an unexpected emotional flare-up, better check your period calendar immed</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 10:06:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hasina’s death sentence 'not an act of political vengeance': Chief Prosecutor</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hasinas-death-sentence-not-an-act-of-political-vengeance-chief-prosecutor</link><description>International Crimes Tribunal (ICT) Chief Prosecutor Tajul Islam has rejected suggestions that the death sentence for deposed prime minister Sheikh Hasina over crimes against humanity committed during attempts to suppress the July Uprising represented an "act of political retribution" against her.</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 10:21:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh attorney general hails ‘landmark’ tribunal verdict against ex-PM Hasina</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-attorney-general-hails-landmark-tribunal-verdict-against-ex-pm-hasina</link><description>The International Crimes Tribunal verdict in the crimes against humanity case against former prime minister Sheikh Hasina and two others stands as a landmark one for future generations, says Attorney General Md Asaduzzaman.
He shared his reaction with the media at the court premises after the verd</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 10:36:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gunmen kill vice principal, abduct female students in attack on Nigerian school</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/gunmen-kill-vice-principal-abduct-female-students-in-attack-on-nigerian-school</link><description>Gunmen attacked a government boarding school in Nigeria’s Kebbi state early on Monday, killing the vice principal and abducting an unspecified number of female students, according to a security report and a school official.
The assailants, armed with rifles and reportedly using coordinated t</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 10:00:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>State-appointed lawyer for Hasina says death penalty has left him ‘pained’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/state-appointed-lawyer-for-hasina-says-death-penalty-has-left-him-pained</link><description>State-appointed defence lawyer Amir Hossain has said ousted Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina’s death sentence for crimes against humanity for attempting to suppress the July Uprising has left him “deeply pained”.
Amir also represented former home minister Asaduzzaman Khan Kamal in th</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 10:15:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Southeast University Board of Trustees holds 140th meeting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/southeast-university-board-of-trustees-holds-140th-meeting</link><description>The 140th board meeting of Southeast University Trust (SEUT) was held on Wednesday, November 12, 2025, at the university’s permanent campus in Tejgaon, Dhaka.
The meeting was presided over by Mr. Rezaul Karim, Chairman of the SEU Trust, and attended by distinguished members of the Board of T</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 10:30:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fakhrul calls Hasina verdict ‘end of all dictatorships’ in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/fakhrul-calls-hasina-verdict-end-of-all-dictatorships-in-bangladesh</link><description>BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir on Monday said the verdict delivered against deposed Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina marks ‘the burial of all forms of dictatorship’ in Bangladesh.
“We believe that today’s verdict is not just a judgment on Sheikh Hasina’</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 10:45:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No public unrest after Hasina verdict: Home Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/no-public-unrest-after-hasina-verdict-home-adviser</link><description>Home Affairs Adviser Lt Gen (retd) M Jahangir Alam Chowdhury has said the overall situation in the country remains calm following the death sentences handed down to Sheikh Hasina and former home minister Asaduzzaman Khan Kamal in a case related to crimes against humanity during last year's July-Aug</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 11:00:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BEPZA signs land lease agreements with two foreign firms</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bepza-signs-land-lease-agreements-with-two-foreign-firms</link><description>The Bangladesh Export Processing Zones Authority (BEPZA) on Monday signed land lease agreements with two fully foreign-owned companies to establish new industrial units at the BEPZA Economic Zone, marking an inflow of USD 70.66 million in the light engineering and garment accessories sectors.
The</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 11:15:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BB to halt sale of savings certificates, prize bonds</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bb-to-halt-sale-of-savings-certificates-prize-bonds</link><description>Bangladesh Bank is set to discontinue five types of customer-level services, including the sale of Savings Certificates (Sanchayapatra) and Prize Bonds, as part of a major move to modernise its operations and strengthen security at its main offices.
The central bank’s Motijheel office will i</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 11:30:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Execute Hasina’s death sentence within one month: Nahid</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/execute-hasinas-death-sentence-within-one-month-nahid</link><description>National Citizen Party (NCP) Convener Nahid Islam has demanded that the death sentence of deposed prime minister Sheikh Hasina, who fled to India in the face of the July Uprising, be carried out within a month, reports bdnews24.com.
The three-member International Crimes Tribunal-1, led by Justice</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 11:45:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt calls Hasina's verdict historic, urges people to stay calm, restraint</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-calls-hasinas-verdict-historic-urges-people-to-stay-calm-restraint</link><description>The interim government today called the death penalty handed down to deposed prime minister Sheikh Hasina and ousted home minister Asaduzzaman Khan Kamal for crimes against humanity as a historic verdict, urging the people to remain calm, restrained and responsible.
"The death sentences handed dow</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 12:00:52 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>