<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 07:39:30 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Health sector steeped in unhealthy practices in procurement, equipment use</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/health-sector-steeped-in-unhealthy-practices-in-procurement-equipment-use</link><description>High-value medical equipment purchased over a year ago remains largely unused, exposing critical gaps in resource utilisation and public money's value.
Such neglect and waste officially detected under the Expansion of the National Institute of Neurosciences and Hospital (NINS) project only shows t</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 04:35:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NBR approves duty-free raw materials import for partial exporters</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/nbr-allows-partial-exporters-to-import-duty-free-raw-material-against-bank-guarantee</link><description>In a bid to expand export trade, the National Board of Revenue (NBR has allowed partial export-oriented industrial units to import raw materials duty-free against a bank guarantee, according to a statement Monday.
According to a notice issued on Thursday (September 25), exporters who are unable to</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 05:05:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Section 144 restrictions continue in Khagrachhari</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/section-144-restrictions-continue-in-khagrachhari</link><description>The indefinite ban on public gatherings in Khagrachhari remains in force amid deadly unrest over the alleged rape of Marma schoolgirl, although the group protesting the incident has eased its road blockade on the Dhaka and Chattogram highways.
In a Facebook post on Monday, the "Jumma Chhatra-Janat</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 05:20:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Indices gain in early trading at DSE, CSE</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/indices-gain-in-early-trading-at-dse-cse</link><description>Indices at the Dhaka and Chattogram bourses witnessed a rise in the first hour of trading on Monday, as most company shares saw price hikes.
At the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE), the key index DSEX advanced by 8 points during the opening hour of the week's second trading day.
Of the other two indice</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 05:35:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Denmark bans drone flights after fresh drone sightings at military bases</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/denmark-bans-drone-flights-after-fresh-drone-sightings-at-military-bases</link><description>Denmark ordered a ban on Sunday on civil drone flights, after drones were observed at several military facilities overnight, following a week in which drone sorties caused the temporary closures of several Danish airports.
The Danish military said in a statement it had deployed "several capacities</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 05:50:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Death toll climbs to 40 after stampede at political rally for actor Vijay in southern India</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/death-toll-climbs-to-40-after-stampede-at-political-rally-for-actor-vijay-in-southern-india</link><description>The death toll following a stampede at a political rally for a popular Indian actor and politician in the southern state of Tamil Nadu has climbed to 40, the state's health minister said Sunday, as medics treated at least 124 injured in hospitals.
Ma Subramanian told The Associated Press that 36 v</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 06:20:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Suryakumar says champions India 'denied' the trophy after Asia Cup win</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/suryakumar-says-champions-india-denied-the-trophy-after-asia-cup-win</link><description>India captain Suryakumar Yadav said his side had been denied the chance to hoist the Asia Cup trophy on Sunday after it was removed from the presentation ceremony following their refusal to accept it from Pakistan's interior minister Mohsin Naqvi.
India beat Pakistan by five wickets in the final a</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 07:05:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Vessel with 52, 500 tonnes of Russian wheat arrives in Kutubdia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/vessel-with-52-500-tonnes-of-russian-wheat-arrives-in-kutubdia</link><description>A vessel carrying around 52, 500 tonnes of wheat from Russia has arrived at Kutubdia outer anchorage in the Bay of Bengal.
The vessel 'MV PERTH I', carrying the consignment imported under a cash purchase agreement, docked at Kutubdia in Kutubdia, according to a media release sent from the Ministry</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 07:20:22 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>