<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 04:27:29 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>High interest, weak investment to blame: Experts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/high-interest-weak-investment-to-blame-experts</link><description>Bangladesh's economy is trapped in a difficult-to-break vicious cycle of high interest rates, persistent inflation, weak investment, and slowing gross domestic product (GDP) growth, making it increasingly challenging to revive private-sector activities, experts say.
They note that the financial se</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 01:51:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Long-awaited 700 MHz spectrum auction on Jan 14</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/long-awaited-700-mhz-spectrum-auction-on-jan-14</link><description>The government has fixed January 14 next year for the auction of the long-awaited 700 MHz spectrum, signalling a decisive move towards releasing a band that has been locked in legal and regulatory disputes for nearly two decades.
The date was formally announced in the Instructions for Radio Freque</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 02:06:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Central bank to rationalise pay as Islamic banks merge</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/central-bank-to-rationalise-pay-as-islamic-banks-merge</link><description>Bangladesh Bank (BB) plans to rationalise the salary structures of employees at the five struggling Islamic banks set for merger, as part of efforts to reduce their administrative costs.
Speaking to reporters, BB assistant spokesperson Mohammad Shahriar Siddiqui said the five banks will be consoli</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 02:21:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Banking sector under elevated stress amid politico-economic volatility</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/banking-sector-under-elevated-stress-amid-politico-economic-volatility</link><description>Bangladesh's banking sector faces elevated asset-quality stress amid economic and political volatility, says global rating-agency S&amp;amp;P and pinpoints the spots of vulnerabilities.
"Weak consumption and investment, coupled with structural reforms under the IMF program, have exposed deep-rooted fragil</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 01:30:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US becomes Bangladesh’s 2nd-largest trading partner</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/us-becomes-bangladeshs-2nd-largest-trading-partner</link><description>The United States has recently emerged as Bangladesh's second-largest trading partner, driven by a notable expansion in bilateral trade with the world's largest economy.
Officials familiar with the development say the shift may be linked to successful negotiations between Dhaka and Washington, dur</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 01:45:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ACC to open probe against DNCC boss Md Ejaz</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/acc-to-open-probe-against-dncc-boss-md-ejaz</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) has decided to launch an inquiry against Mohammad Ejaz, the Administrator of Dhaka North City Corporation (DNCC), over allegations of abuse of power, various irregularities, corruption, and taking bribes.
A senior ACC official confirmed the development to the m</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 02:00:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>State insurer wants food directorate to resume coverage</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/state-insurer-wants-food-directorate-to-resume-coverage</link><description>Sadharan Bima Corporation (SBC) has requested the food directorate to resume purchasing insurance coverage from the state-run insurer, in line with legal requirements that mandate government entities to buy coverage from the corporation.
Officials said the appeal follows a long period during which</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 02:15:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fashion brands thriving on exploitation in South Asia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/fashion-brands-thriving-on-exploitation-in-south-asia</link><description>Global fashion brands are thriving on the exploitation of a vast low-paid and unpaid workforce -- mostly women -- across the South Asian garment supply chain, including Bangladesh, according to two reports released by Amnesty International.
The reports, published on Thursday, stated that millions</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 02:30:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khaleda in CCU, BNP seeks prayers for her speedy recovery</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/khaleda-in-ccu-bnp-seeks-prayers-for-her-speedy-recovery</link><description>BNP Chairperson Begum Khaleda Zia was transferred to the Coronary Care Unit (CCU) on Thursday from her cabin at Evercare Hospital in the city.
Khaleda Zia is currently under the care of local and foreign specialists from the hospital's medical board. This information was shared by Shairul Kabir Kh</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 02:45:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>75pc of banking customers still excluded from digital services</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/75pc-of-banking-customers-still-excluded-from-digital-services</link><description>Despite the ongoing digital transformation in the banking sector, about 75 per cent of total customers in the country still remain outside any digital banking services, according to a study by the Bangladesh Institute of Bank Management (BIBM).
"The percentage of total customers who currently use</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 03:00:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>One unit of Matarbari Power Plant shut due to technical fault</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/one-unit-of-matarbari-power-plant-shut-due-to-technical-fault</link><description>Production at one unit of Matarbari Ultra Super Critical Coal Fired Power Plant has been remaining halted due to a technical fault for last one week, concerned sources said.
Sources said the production has been halted for the past week due to ash accumulation in the boiler. It may take another mon</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 03:15:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Schoolgirl found hanging in cowshed in Sylhet</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/schoolgirl-found-hanging-in-cowshed-in-sylhet-1</link><description>A fourth-grader was found hanging dead in a cowshed in Sylhet's Zakiganj on Thursday evening.
The incident occurred on Thursday (November 27) in Amlashid village of Barthakuri Union.
Police recovered the body of Jhuma Akter, 10, daughter of day labourer Harun Mia, UNB reports.
According to local</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 03:30:47 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>