<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 04:27:20 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Income tax on waived interest raises questions among corporate</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/income-tax-on-waived-interest-raises-questions-among-corporate</link><description>"Where any interest or part thereof is waived by a scheduled bank or a financial institution in favour of a company registered with the RJSC, such waived amount shall be deemed as income of the company and shall be taxable in an assessment year in which such waiver is made," reads Section 67(8) of</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 16:16:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Time to regulate online content creators</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/time-to-regulate-online-content-creators</link><description>Social media offers a unique platform for independent content creators to express themselves freely, experiment with new ideas, and both enlighten and entertain their audiences. This unprecedented freedom of  creating and publishing online content has unleashed countless talents, many of whom</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 16:31:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Setbacks LDCs are up against in global trade</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/setbacks-ldcs-are-up-against-in-global-trade</link><description>For more than a decade, the global community has been working towards the goal of doubling the share of global exports from the Least Developed Countries (LDCs) to two per cent by 2020, up from one per cent a decade ago. There has been the United Nations (UN) Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs') c</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 16:46:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bus catches fire in Gazipur due to engine glitch</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bus-catches-fire-in-gazipur-due-to-engine-glitch</link><description>A passenger bus caught fire on the Dhaka–Mymensingh highway in the Chaydana area of Gazipur city on Saturday evening due to an engine malfunction.
The blaze erupted around 7:30 pm, burning all the seats of the bus. No injuries were reported, as both the driver and passengers were able to eva</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 17:01:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Paying heed to IMF's revenue warning</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/paying-heed-to-imfs-revenue-warning</link><description>The persistent challenge of elevating revenue collection remains the central economic puzzle that Bangladesh has attempted to solve for many years. From enacting a new income tax law in 2023 to expanding and reorganising both the Income Tax wing and the Customs and VAT wing, the government has intr</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 17:16:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gold price drops by Tk 5,447 per bhori at week’s start</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/gold-price-drops-by-tk-5447-per-bhori-at-weeks-start</link><description>After four consecutive hikes, the Bangladesh Jewellers Association (BAJUS) has reduced gold prices by Tk 5,447 per bhori, bringing the new rate for 22-carat gold to Tk 208,272 per bhori.
The revised prices will take effect from Sunday, the association said in a statement on Saturday night, UNB rep</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 18:09:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP to ensure more business-friendly environment if voted to power: Khosru</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-to-ensure-more-business-friendly-environment-if-voted-to-power-khosru</link><description>BNP Standing Committee member Amir Khosru Mahmud Chowdhury has said that if the BNP returns to power, it will take steps to ensure a more business-friendly environment for entrepreneurs across the country.
He made the remarks on Saturday while speaking at the Faridpur Divisional Business Forum mee</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 18:24:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh garment export to EU confronting crowding-out effect</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladesh-garment-export-to-eu-confronting-crowding-out-effect</link><description>Bangladesh's garment export to the European Union faces crowding-out effect as major competitors, hitting US tariff walls, are making forays into the country's largest shipment destination, exporters say.
China, Vietnam, Cambodia and Pakistan have incrementally raised their concentration on the Eu</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 02:08:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Well-off banks parking surplus funds into state-guaranteed securities</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/well-off-banks-parking-surplus-funds-into-state-guaranteed-securities</link><description>Standing deposit facility (SDF) interest cut cannot dent affluent banks' reliance on the state-guaranteed securities as they are hugely investing surplus funds in the deposit window despite lower gains.
Officials and money-market analysts say the demand on the interbank call-money market dampens d</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 02:23:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Remittances from US, UAE fall sharply in last two quarters</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/remittances-from-us-uae-fall-sharply-in-last-two-quarters</link><description>Bangladesh's two major remittance corridors -- the United States and the United Arab Emirates -- witnessed significant year-on-year (YoY) declines in inflows during the last two quarters, raising concerns over the sustainability of the growth momentum.
According to the latest Bangladesh Bank (BB)</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 02:38:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>'Employers prioritise problem-solving skills over grades'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/employers-prioritise-problem-solving-skills-over-grades</link><description>Securing employment based solely on academic results has become increasingly difficult as employers now prioritise problem-solving abilities, said Dr Muhammad Fouzul Kabir Khan, Adviser of the Interim Government for the Ministries of Road Transport and Bridges, Railways, and Power, Energy and Miner</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 03:23:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>3rd US wheat shipment reaches Mongla</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/3rd-us-wheat-shipment-reaches-mongla</link><description>A fresh consignment of wheat from the United States has arrived at the outer anchorage of Mongla Port, marking the third shipment under the government-to-government (G2G) purchase deal.
The vessel, MV WECO TATI, is carrying 60,875 tonnes of wheat under cash purchase contract G to G-01, signed as p</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 03:38:59 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>