<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 18:32:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Man killed in Chandpur road crash</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/man-killed-in-chandpur-road-crash</link><description>A motorcycle rider was killed and another injured in a road accident at Madanergaon village in Faridganj upazila of Chandpur district on Thursday.
The deceased was Junaid Badsha Talukder, 45, son of Maulana Idris Talukder of Manikraj village of the upazila, reports BSS.
The accident took place ar</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 15:28:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DMP files 1,583 cases against traffic rules violations</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dmp-files-1583-cases-against-traffic-rules-violations</link><description>As part of the ongoing campaign to bring traffic system under control, Dhaka Metropolitan Police's (DMP) Traffic Division has filed a total of 1,583 cases against vehicles, owners and its drivers for violating traffic rules.
Deputy Commissioner (Media and Public Relations Division) of Dhaka Metrop</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 15:43:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CA to decide on implementation of Consensus Commission’s recommendations, referendum: Asif Nazrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ca-to-decide-on-implementation-of-consensus-commissions-recommendations-referendum-asif-nazrul</link><description>Law Adviser Professor Dr Asif Nazrul on Thursday said that Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus will take the final decision regarding the implementation of the National Consensus Commission’s recommendations and referendum.
“Two proposals of the Consensus Commission were discussed i</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 16:13:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cox’s Bazar gets its first plastic recycling plant to reuse waste</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/coxs-bazar-gets-its-first-plastic-recycling-plant-to-reuse-waste</link><description>The first municipal plastic recycling plant in Cox’s Bazar was officially inaugurated recently, aiming to transform single-use plastic waste into valuable resources.
The initiative, established in Mithaichori of Ramu Upazila, was hailed by guests as a milestone for sustainable waste manageme</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 16:28:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh loses $24b in income in 2024 due to extreme heat: Report</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/bangladesh-loses-24b-in-income-in-2024-due-to-extreme-heat-report</link><description>Bangladesh lost $24 billion as extreme heat cut its labour productivity in 2024, revealed The Lancet Countdown on Health and Climate Change report published earlier this week.
The change in weather pattern also increased by 90 per cent over the period from 1951-1960 to 2015-2024 the transmission p</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 16:05:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mahmudullah improving after hospitalisation with dengue</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/cricket/mahmudullah-improving-after-hospitalisation-with-dengue</link><description>Former Bangladesh captain Mahmudullah Riyad has been admitted to a hospital in Dhaka with dengue but is now recovering.
Mahmudullah’s wife, Jannatul Kawsar Mishti, shared the news on social media Thursday, posting a photo of him lying in a hospital bed with the caption.
“When Allah lo</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 16:20:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fire breaks out at Mohammadpur Meena Bazar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fire-breaks-out-at-mohammadpur-meena-bazar</link><description>A fire broke out at a Meena Bazar outlet in the capital’s Mohammadpur Mohammadia Housing Society in Dhaka on Thursday night.
The blaze started around 9:04 pm, confirmed a duty officer at the Fire Service and Civil Defence Headquarters Control Room, reports UNB.
On information, two fire serv</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 16:35:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt approves new Human Rights Commission Ordinance</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-approves-new-human-rights-commission-ordinance</link><description>The interim government has approved the National Human Rights Commission Ordinance 2025, significantly expanding the commission’s jurisdiction and mandate.
The approval came during a meeting of the Advisory Council on Thursday, where two other ordinances, the Artificial Organ Transplantation</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 16:50:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mumbai police rescue 17 children taken hostage at acting school</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/mumbai-police-rescue-17-children-taken-hostage-at-acting-school</link><description>Police in India’s Mumbai have rescued 17 children from a hostage situation at a local studio, where a man was killed in an exchange of gunfire during a rescue operation.
According to a report by NDTV, the incident occurred on Thursday in Powai, a neighbourhood in Mumbai, when the suspect, id</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 17:05:44 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>