<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 10:56:26 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Six hand bombs recovered in Bagerhat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/six-hand-bombs-recovered-in-bagerhat</link><description>Members of a joint security force have recovered six hand bombs abandoned in Bagerhat.
Md Masum Khan, chief of Bagerhat Sadar Model Police Station, said the bombs were recovered in the wee hours of Wednesday near a sluice gate in the Harikhali area of the town.
However, no one was arrested during</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 07:18:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCP leaders set to cast ballots in election tomorrow</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ncp-leaders-set-to-cast-ballots-in-election-tomorrow</link><description>The National Citizen Party (NCP) leadership will cast votes across the country on February 12 during the first general election since the 2024 mass uprising.
The Financial Express has documented the voting times and locations for NCP-led alliance figures.
Dhaka
Nahid Islam, NCP Convener, will vo</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 07:33:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two killed in Bagerhat road crash</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/two-killed-in-bagerhat-road-crash-1568732</link><description>Two men have been killed after a three-wheeled passenger vehicle, locally known as a Mahindra, collided head-on with a freight truck in Bagerhat Sadar upazila.
The crash occurred around 12 am on Tuesday on the Khulna–Mongla regional highway at Chulkathi Chaltetla, said Katakhali Highway Poli</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 07:48:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>WB approves $370m to improve waste management, restore Dhaka rivers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/world-bank-approves-370m-to-improve-waste-management-restore-dhaka-rivers</link><description>The World Bank’s Board of Executive Directors has approved $370 million in financing to improve sanitation and solid waste management services in Dhaka and nearby areas, aiming to reduce water pollution and restore rivers and canals.
The support will fund the Metro Dhaka Water Security and R</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 08:03:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>83 women candidates vying in polls: EC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/83-women-candidates-vying-in-polls-ec</link><description>A total of 83 women, out of 2,028 candidates from 50 political parties and independent ones, are contesting in 299 seats in the 13th Jatiya Sangsad polls slated for Thursday.
Of them, 63 female candidates are from parties, and 20 are independent, while 1,692 male candidates are vying in the polls</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 08:18:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>12 petrol bombs, 15 cocktails recovered in Rajshahi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/12-petrol-bombs-15-cocktails-recovered-in-rajshahi</link><description>Members of Rapid Action Battalion (RAB) recovered 12 petrol bombs and 15 cocktails from Chhotobangram area under the Chandrima Police Station in Rajshahi city on Tuesday night.
On a tip-off, a team of the elite force conducted a raid at the area around 11.45 pm and recovered the explosives, r</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 08:33:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>26,515 police deployed in capital for election security: DMP</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/26515-police-deployed-in-capital-for-election-security-dmp</link><description>A total of 26,515 police personnel have been deployed across the capital to ensure maximum security during the national election and referendum, said DMP Deputy Commissioner (Media) Muhammad Talebur Rahman on Wednesday.
Specialised units, including the Bomb Disposal Unit, SWAT, K-9 Unit and Crime</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 08:48:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Over 1,400 polling stations in Dhaka flagged as 'high risk'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/over-1400-polling-stations-in-dhaka-flagged-as-high-risk</link><description>More than 1,400 polling stations across 13 constituencies in Dhaka have been identified as high risk ahead of the 13th national election, according to officials.
Dhaka Divisional Commissioner and Returning Officer Sharaf Uddin Ahmed Chowdhury said striking forces will be deployed in greater number</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 09:03:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jahangir visits PHQ control room, two police stations in the city</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jahangir-visits-phq-control-room-two-police-stations-in-the-city</link><description>Home Adviser Lieutenant General (Retd.) Md. Jahangir Alam Chowdhury today (Wednesday) visited the Central Control Room at Police Headquarters (PHQ) to review law enforcement preparedness ahead of tomorrow’s general elections and referendum-2026, according to a press release.
During the visit</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 09:18:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US moves to counter China in Bangladesh, plans to pitch defence alternatives</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/us-moves-to-counter-china-in-bangladesh-plans-to-pitch-defence-alternatives</link><description>The United States is concerned about China's expanding presence in South Asia and is planning to offer Bangladesh’s next government US and allied defence systems as alternatives to Chinese hardware, Washington's ambassador to Dhaka told Reuters.
Bangladesh votes in a general election on Thur</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 09:33:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Vested group spreading falsehoods out of fear: Dr Shafiqur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/vested-group-spreading-falsehoods-out-of-fear-dr-shafiqur</link><description>Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami Ameer Dr Shafiqur Rahman on Wednesday alleged that a vested quarter is spreading disinformation out of fear of the party’s growing popularity and public support.
In a post on his verified Facebook page, he said that as the nation prepares for a free, fair and credi</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 09:48:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Banglabandha Land Port closed for 3 days for elections</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/banglabandha-land-port-closed-for-3-days-for-elections</link><description>Import and export activities through the Banglabandha Land Port in Panchagarh will remain suspended for three consecutive days due to the 13th parliamentary election.
However, passenger movement will remain normal on the two days before and after the voting day, but not on election day itself.
As</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 10:03:54 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>