<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 11:24:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Mar 4 set for verdict in Rampura crimes against humanity case</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/mar-4-set-for-verdict-in-rampura-crimes-against-humanity-case</link><description>The International Crimes Tribunal has fixed Mar 4 for delivering its verdict in a crimes against humanity case over killings during the July Uprising in Dhaka's Rampura.
Five people, including former Dhaka Metropolitan Police commissioner Habibur Rahman, are facing charges in connection with the k</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 07:44:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UK pledges close cooperation with Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/uk-pledges-close-cooperation-with-bangladesh</link><description>The United Kingdom (UK) has expressed its commitment to working closely with Bangladesh on shared priorities of economic growth, migration, climate and security following the country’s parliamentary elections.
“We look forward to the new government advancing democratic, economic and so</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 07:59:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AL leader dies in hospital after falling ill in jail</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/al-leader-dies-in-hospital-after-falling-ill-in-jail</link><description>A local leader of the Bangladesh Awami League died at Rangpur Medical College and Hospital on Sunday, after falling critically ill while in custody.
The deceased, Shamikul Islam Lipon, was president of the Gaibandha district unit of the Awami League, reports UNB.
Lipon, who had been in custody fo</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 08:14:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CAO pushes back against ‘misinformation’ over cabinet secretary's exit</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cao-pushes-back-against-misinformation-over-cabinet-secretarys-exit</link><description>The Chief Advisor’s Office (CAO) has called for restraint amid “misinformation and speculative statements” surrounding the cancellation of Cabinet Secretary Sheikh Abdur Rashid’s contractual appointment.
In a statement issued on Sunday, the CAO said various media outlets ha</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 08:29:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCP preparing to form shadow cabinet as ‘watchdog’, says Asif Mahmud</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ncp-preparing-to-form-shadow-cabinet-as-watchdog-says-asif-mahmud</link><description>The National Citizen Party (NCP) is preparing to form a shadow cabinet, according to party spokesperson and former interim government advisor Asif Mahmud Shojib Bhuyain.
In a post on his Facebook page on Sunday, Asif, who also chairs the party’s central election management committee, said th</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 08:44:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh will not tolerate secret politics any longer, says Chhatra Dal’s Rakib</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bangladesh-will-not-tolerate-secret-politics-any-longer-says-chhatra-dals-rakib</link><description>Chhatra Dal President Rakibul Islam Rakib has called on Jamaat-e-Islami and its student wing Islami Chhatra Shibir to make all its committees public.
“Bangladesh will not abide secret politics any longer,” he said in a Facebook post at 1am on Sunday. “All Jamaat-e-Islami and Chha</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 09:37:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>999 receives 8,380 election-related calls during JS-polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/999-receives-8380-election-related-calls-during-js-polls</link><description>National Emergency Service 999 received a total of 8,380 phone calls related to the national election as it implemented a special operational plan to ensure a free, fair and peaceful election.
Under the special plan, 999 provided election-related emergency services through round-the-clock coordina</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 09:52:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP sought Parliament South Plaza venue for MPs’ swearing-in: Law advisor</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bnp-sought-parliament-south-plaza-venue-for-mps-swearing-in-law-advisor</link><description>The oath-taking ceremony for newly elected MPs and members of the cabinet will be held at the South Plaza of Parliament at the request of the BNP, Law Adviser Asif Nazrul has said.
Speaking to reporters at the Secretariat on Sunday, Nazrul said members of parliament will take their oath at 10 am o</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 09:55:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Titas Gas pressure low due to LNG terminal maintenance</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/titas-gas-pressure-low-due-to-lng-terminal-maintenance</link><description>Gas supply to areas with Titas Gas connections will be severely low until midnight on Monday due to maintenance work at the LNG terminal.
The closure of the terminal had decreased the amount of gas available from LNG, the distribution company authority said in a statement on Sunday.
As a result,</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 10:10:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Report into Hadi murder due Feb 19</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/court-sets-feb-19-deadline-for-hadi-murder-probe-report</link><description>A court has ordered investigators to submit their report in the murder case of Inqilab Moncho Convenor Sharif Osman Hadi by Feb 19.
The report was due to be submitted on Sunday. However, the investigation officer, Assistant Superintendent of Police of Criminal Investigation Department Abdur Qadir</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 10:25:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat-led alliance to challenge results in 32 constituencies</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-led-alliance-to-challenge-results-in-32-constituencies</link><description>The Jamaat-e-Islami-led 11-party alliance has alleged irregularities in vote counting and result publication in at least 32 constituencies and said it will seek legal remedy.
Representatives of the alliance met four election commissioners at the Election Commission headquarters on Sunday and submi</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 10:40:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cannabis smoke fills the air as Nepal marks Shivaratri festival</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/cannabis-smoke-fills-the-air-as-nepal-marks-shivaratri-festival</link><description>Hindu holy men and mostly young devotees openly puffed on cannabis smoke on Sunday, marking one of Nepal’s biggest annual festivals.
Tens of thousands lined up to pray at the Pashupatinath, the temple of the Hindu god Shiva in the capital Kathmandu, during the Shivaratri festival.
Marijuana</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 10:55:08 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>