<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 17:00:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Abbas, Nazrul, Rizvi, 7 others made advisers to prime minister</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/abbas-nazrul-rizvi-7-others-made-advisers-to-prime-minister</link><description>The government has appointed 10 individuals as advisers to Prime Minister Tarique Rahman under Rule 3(b) of the Rules of Business, 1996, according to news portals.
Among them, five advisers have been granted the status of minister, and the rest of them have been granted the status of state ministe</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 13:36:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Former football captain Aminul appointed state minister for sports</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/former-football-captain-aminul-appointed-state-minister-for-sports</link><description>Former national football team captain Aminul Haque has been appointed as the State Minister for the Ministry of Youth and Sports under the technocrat quota.
Aminul, a leader of the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP), has been active in politics following his retirement from professional sports.
H</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 13:51:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cricket legends urge immediate medical care for Imran Khan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/cricket-legends-urge-immediate-medical-care-for-imran-khan</link><description>A group of former international cricket captains has urged Pakistan’s government to provide “immediate and adequate medical attention” to jailed former prime minister and cricket legend Imran Khan, citing concerns over his deteriorating health in custody.
In a letter sent to Prim</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 14:06:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Southeast Bank wins J.P. Morgan’s Award</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/southeast-bank-wins-jp-morgans-award</link><description>Southeast Bank PLC wins “The 2025 U.S. Dollar Clearing Elite Quality Recognition Award for Outstanding Achievement of Best-in-Class” of J.P. Morgan Chase Bank, N.A., the largest bank in the United States.
The ceremony was graced by the Chairman of Southeast Bank PLC., Mr. M. A. Kashem</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 14:21:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Midland Bank inaugurated its relocated Bheramara Branch</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/midland-bank-inaugurated-its-relocated-bheramara-branch</link><description>Midland Bank PLC (MDB) formally inaugurated its relocated Bheramara Branch at Babor Ali Super Market, Holding No. 271-01 &amp; 02, Bheramara -Pragpur Highway Road, Word No. 06, Bheramara Pouroshava on February 16, 2026.
Md. Ahsan-uz Zaman, Managing Director &amp; CEO of the Bank inaugurated the Branch as</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 14:36:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pubali Bank inaugurates 518th Branch at Iswarganj in Mymeningh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/pubali-bank-inaugurates-518th-branch-at-iswarganj-in-mymeningh</link><description>Pubali Bank PLC has inaugurated its 518th branch at Iswarganj, Mymeningh recently with a view to providing modern banking services, according to a press release.
Md. Shahnewaz Khan, Deputy Managing Director of Pubali Bank PLC., formally inaugurated the branch as the Chief Guest. Md. Faizul Hoque S</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 14:51:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Islami Bank remittance clients to get 20 Motorcycles</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/islami-bank-remittance-clients-to-get-20-motorcycles</link><description>Islami Bank Bangladesh PLC will provide a motorcycle through digital raffle draw on every banking day (Sun-Thursday) for sending cash remittance through Ria Money Transfer.
Remittance recipients will also get a key ring as a common gift. This offer will continue from 19 February to 18 March, 2026</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 15:06:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCC Bank signs agreement with Unisoft Systems Limited on digital loan management system</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ncc-bank-signs-agreement-with-unisoft-systems-limited-on-digital-loan-management-system</link><description>NCC Bank has formally launched its Digital Loan Management System (DLMS) across all branches, marking a significant milestone in the Bank’s ongoing digital transformation journey.
According to a press release, the state-of-the-art solution has been designed and implemented by Unisoft Systems</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 15:21:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Uzzal Hossain appointed PM’s Protocol Officer-1</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/uzzal-hossain-appointed-pms-protocol-officer-1</link><description>Md. Uzzal Hossain, Senior Assistant Secretary of the Ministry of Public Administration, has been appointed on deputation as Protocol Officer-1 to the Prime Minister’s office.
According to a notification issued by the Ministry of Public Administration, his service has been placed at the Prime</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 15:36:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Maldivian President meets PM Tarique Rahman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/maldivian-president-meets-pm-tarique-rahman</link><description>Maldivian President Dr Mohamed Muizzu met newly elected Prime Minister Tarique Rahman at his Sangsad Bhaban office in Dhaka after he took the oath of office as the 11th Prime Minister of Bangladesh on Tuesday afternoon.
Prime Minister's daughter Zaima Rahman, new minister Dr Khalilur Rahman and of</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 15:51:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Crowne Plaza Dhaka Airport inaugurated</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/crowne-plaza-dhaka-airport-inaugurated</link><description>Crowne Plaza Dhaka Airport has officially opened its doors at Centrepoint, marking a significant milestone in Bangladesh’s hospitality landscape.
The inauguration ceremony was held in the presence of distinguished guests, including advisors and directors of United Group, alongside representa</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 16:45:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Who holds which portfolios in Tarique’s cabinet</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tariques-cabinet-a-strategic-mix-of-trusted-veterans-and-new-faces</link><description>After leading his party to a landslide, Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) chief Tarique Rahman has assembled a 50-member cabinet combining a striking number of new faces alongside seasoned leaders.
The new government, sworn in on Tuesday at the South Plaza of parliament, consists of 25 ministers</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 17:00:47 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>