<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 05:31:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Saying no to suicide</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/saying-no-to-suicide</link><description>That 40-41people terminate their lives every day, according to recent police data, in this country should send a chill down the spine. The very word 'suicide' has a story behind and that certainly is not very positive. People by nature are more epicurean than ascetic. But then what pushes one to ta</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 17:43:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Has interim govt been up to public's expectation?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/has-interim-govt-been-up-to-publics-expectation</link><description>Syed Fattahul Alim
 
The interim government inherited the virtual wreckage of a state left by the autocracy toppled in the popular upsurge. The financial sector, especially the banks were in a shambles. The ousted autocracy would like to portray a rosy picture of the economy with the help of</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 17:58:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The urban-rural lending divide</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/the-urban-rural-lending-divide</link><description>Bangladesh is predominantly a rural country, with around 68 per cent of its population living in rural areas. A large segment of this population is deprived of formal banking services due to a lack of bank branches in remote areas. Although agent banking has helped improve financial inclusion over</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 18:13:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Manufacturers fret over Tk120b unsold apparel raw material</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/manufacturers-fret-over-tk120b-unsold-apparel-raw-material</link><description>Millers fret over a stockpile of unsold local yarn worth Tk 120 billion amid massive influx of the cheap-rated clothing raw material, allegedly meant to undercut domestic industry, manufacturers say.



The country's primary textile millers, especially spinners, say yarn imports from India in</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 18:28:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gold hits new record in Bangladesh as price rises for 8th straight time</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/gold-hits-new-record-in-bangladesh-as-price-rises-for-8th-straight-time</link><description>Gold prices in Bangladesh have climbed for the eighth consecutive time, with the price of 22-carat gold reaching a new all-time high of Tk 229,431 per bhori (11.664 grams) on Sunday.
Bangladesh Jewellers Association (BAJUS) announced at night that it has increased the price of gold by Tk 1,575 per</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 18:43:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh Bank issues risk-based supervision framework for banks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladesh-bank-issues-risk-based-supervision-framework-for-banks</link><description>Bangladesh Bank (BB) has issued a detailed framework outlining how banks will shift to risk-based supervision (RBS), with the new supervisory system set to be implemented across the banking sector from January 2026.
Directing all commercial banks to comply with the framework, the central bank issu</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 02:19:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh's UN-defined role as regional hub undermined</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladeshs-un-defined-role-as-regional-hub-undermined</link><description>Bangladesh's UN-mandated role as a regional logistics hub is getting undercut as manifest in the value of its re-exported goods plummeting, according to the first-quarter statistics of this fiscal year.
Official data show the value of re-exported goods from Bangladesh fell sharply in the July-Sept</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 02:35:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hadi Murder: Inquilab Moncho now raises four-point demand seeking justice</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hadi-murder-inquilab-moncho-now-raises-four-point-demand-seeking-justice</link><description>Inuqilab Moncho on Sunday night announced a four-point demand seeking justice for its slain spokesperson, Shaheed Sharif Osman Bin Hadi.
The demands were announced in a post on the organisation’s official Facebook page, UNB reports.
The four-point demands are:
All those involved in the kil</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 02:50:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Climate-resilient digital lifeline planned for remote islands</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/climate-resilient-digital-lifeline-planned-for-remote-islands</link><description>The ICT Division has proposed a $99.84-million project to build climate-resilient digital infrastructure across some of most remote and disaster-prone islands, targeting 77 unions and 701 villages in five coastal districts.
The initiative is expected to benefit more than two million people by expa</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 03:05:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>T-bill yields edge down</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/t-bill-yields-edge-down</link><description>The yields on treasury bills (T-bills) edged down on Sunday as the central bank purchased US$115 million more from three banks on the day to keep the exchange rate stable.
On the day, the government raised Tk 70 billion by issuing three types of T-bills to partially finance its budget deficit.
Th</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 03:20:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Non-life insurers fear loss of business without agents</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/non-life-insurers-fear-loss-of-business-without-agents</link><description>Non-life insurers fear losing business because of the ban on agent commission, while the insurance regulator says it took the action to stop the misuse of the tool to attract premiums in an effort to discipline the sector.
"Our products are invisible. Such products need efforts to sell. We have ha</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 05:06:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Indonesia fire kills 16 people in retirement home</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/indonesia-fire-kills-16-people-in-retirement-home</link><description>A fire at a retirement home in the city of Manado on Indonesia's on Sulawesi island has killed 16 people, a local police official was quoted as saying on Monday by state news agency Antara.
The fire at the Werdha Damai retirement home was finally extinguished late on Sunday and authorities are sti</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 05:21:16 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>