<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 08:25:08 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Chhatra Shakti announces central, DU committees</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/chhatra-shakti-announces-central-du-committees</link><description>Jatiya Chhatra Shakti, the student wing of the National Citizen Party (NCP), has announced its partial central and Dhaka University (DU) committees. The new committees were declared on Friday night.
Zahid Ahsan has taken charge as the president of the central committee with Abu Baker Mojumder as t</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 05:40:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UCB’s CSR initiative opens new horizon for rural students in tech Education</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ucbs-csr-initiative-opens-new-horizon-for-rural-students-in-tech-education</link><description>Madhabpasha, a serene village in Babuganj Upazila of Barishal, is surrounded by rivers and lush greenery. Amidst this quiet landscape stands a nearly century-old educational institution -Madhabpasha Chandradwip High School and College. Every day, around four hundred students come here to weave drea</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 06:10:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Motorcyclist killed in Khagrachari road crash</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/motorcyclist-killed-in-khagrachari-road-crash</link><description>A motorcyclist was killed and another was injured as a mini-truck and their motorcycle collided head-on at Rasul area in Matiranga upazila of Khagrachari on Friday night.
The deceased was identified as Tasib, 17, son of Shamsul Haque of Fatikchhari in Chattogram, reports BSS.
Md Toufiqul Islam, o</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 06:40:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Another missing child found dead in Jamalpur river</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/another-missing-child-found-dead-in-jamalpur-river</link><description>The body of another child who went missing while bathing in the Jhinai River in Madarganj upazila of Jamalpur has been recovered, bringing the death toll to 4.
Another child remains missing, reports bdnews24.com.
Madarganj Fire Service official Delwar Hossain said the body of a child named Kulsum</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 06:55:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fatigue sets in as Bangladesh cricketers struggle through packed calendar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/fatigue-sets-in-as-bangladesh-cricketers-struggle-through-packed-calendar</link><description>Bangladesh captain Litton Das has called for a much-needed break for his players after the team were whitewashed 3-0 by West Indies in the T20I series that ended in Chattogram on Friday.
After a five-wicket defeat in the last T20I, which was the last match of the series against the West Indies, Li</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 07:10:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>China sends its youngest astronaut to space station</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/china-sends-its-youngest-astronaut-to-space-station</link><description>China's Shenzhou-21 space rocket and its crew including the youngest member of its astronaut corps blasted off on Friday atop a Long March-2F rocket from the Jiuquan Satellite Launch Centre in northwest China, Chinese state media reported.
It was the seventh mission to the permanently inhabited Ch</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 07:40:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Eight-month ban on Jatka fishing begins</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/eight-month-ban-on-jatka-fishing-begins</link><description>An eight-month nationwide ban on catching juvenile Hilsa (Jatka) began on Saturday, and it will remain in effect until June 30, 2026, aiming to boost Hilsa production and ensure sustainable conservation.
Supervised by the Ministry of Fisheries and Livestock and implemented by the Department of Fis</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 07:55:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Canada's Carney says he apologised to Trump</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/canadas-carney-says-he-apologised-to-trump-over-reagan-ad</link><description>Canadian Prime Minister Mark Carney said on Saturday he had apologised to US President Donald Trump over an anti-tariff political advertisement and had told Ontario Premier Doug Ford not to run it.
Carney, speaking to reporters after attending an Asia-Pacific summit in South Korea, said he had mad</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 08:25:07 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>