<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 13:10:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Househelp to die for Dhanmondi double murder</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/househelp-sentenced-to-death-for-2019-dhanmondi-double-murder</link><description>A Dhaka court has sentenced domestic worker Shurobhi Akhter Nahid to death for the murder of Afroza Begum and her househelp Diti in the capital’s Dhanmondi in 2019.
However, another accused, housekeeper Bachchu Mia, was acquitted as the charges against him were not proven.
Dhaka’s Sev</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 09:56:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Indian Lok Sabha Speaker, FS attend swearing-in ceremony</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/indian-lok-sabha-speaker-fs-attend-swearing-in-ceremony</link><description>Speaker of the Indian Lok Sabha Om Birla arrived in Dhaka on Tuesday represented the government of India at the swearing-in ceremony of the newly elected government of Bangladesh led by Tarique Rahman, Chairman of Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP).
Indian Foreign Secretary Vikram Misri accompanie</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 10:11:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt approves Nabil Mustafizur Rahman as MD of Sammilito Islami Bank</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/govt-approves-nabil-mustafizur-rahman-as-md-of-sammilito-islami-bank</link><description>The government has approved the appointment of Nabil Mustafizur Rahman as Managing Director (MD) of the state-owned Sammilito Islami Bank PLC, formed through the merger of five Shariah-based banks.
Currently, he is serving as Additional Managing Director (AMD) of United Commercial Bank PLC.
The F</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 10:26:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two oaths, as many readings of the law</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/two-oaths-for-new-lawmakers-trigger-constitutional-debate</link><description>Bangladesh’s newly elected parliament has opened with an unusual split. While BNP lawmakers took the oath as members of parliament, they stopped short of pledging themselves to the proposed Constitutional Reform Council.
In contrast, the Jamaat-e-Islami and the National Citizen Party (NCP) d</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 10:41:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Professor Dr Shamsad Mortuza appointed as Vice Chancellor of ULAB</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/professor-dr-shamsad-mortuza-appointed-as-vice-chancellor-of-ulab</link><description>Professor Dr. Shamsad Mortuza has been appointed as the Vice Chancellor of the University of Liberal Arts Bangladesh (ULAB).
The Secondary and Higher Education Division of the Ministry of Education, Government of the People’s Republic of Bangladesh, issued a gazette notification regarding hi</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 10:56:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Six injured in Magura BNP factional clash</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/six-injured-in-magura-bnp-factional-clash</link><description>Six people were injured in a clash between two factions of BNP over establishing supremacy at Chakdah village in Sreepur upazila of Magura district on Monday night.
Atowar Rahman, inspector of Sreepur Police Station, said former president of no 1 ward of Gayeshpur union unit BNP Panjab Ali and gen</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 11:11:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Finance Minister talks to FE about deregulation and ease of doing business</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/finance-minister-talks-to-fe-about-deregulation-and-ease-of-doing-business</link><description>The Finance and Planning Minister Mr. Amir Khosru Mahmud Chowdhury said on Tuesday that his top priority is to deregulate institutional powers to improve efficiency and restore momentum in the economy.
“My first priority is deregulation,” the finance and planning minister told the Fina</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 11:26:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Qualcomm says UK lawsuit over smartphone chip royalties will be withdrawn</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/qualcomm-says-uk-lawsuit-over-smartphone-chip-royalties-will-be-withdrawn</link><description>Qualcomm (QCOM.O) on Tuesday said a London lawsuit alleging it had abused its dominant position to force Apple and Samsung to pay inflated royalties will be withdrawn.
The British consumers' association called Which? had brought the case on behalf of around 29 million people who bought iPhones or</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 11:41:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP leader’s house torched in Narail</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bnp-leaders-house-torched-in-narail</link><description>Miscreants set the house of a local BNP leader on fire by hurling a petrol bomb at Bildumurtala in Sadar upazila of Narail district early Tuesday.
Witnesses said miscreants hurled a petrol bomb targeting the house of Humayun Molla, president of Habkhali union unit BNP around 1 am.
Family members</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 11:56:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Indian cricket grandees Gavaskar and Kapil join humanitarian appeal for jailed Imran Khan in Pakistan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/indian-cricket-grandees-gavaskar-and-kapil-join-humanitarian-appeal-for-jailed-imran-khan-in-pakistan</link><description>Indian cricket greats Sunil Gavaskar and Kapil Dev joined a dozen other former international captains on Tuesday in demanding better prison treatment for “one of the finest all-rounders” of the game Imran Khan, Pakistan’s former prime minister.
Cricketer-turned-politician Khan, 7</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 12:11:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BB reschedules treasury auctions, repo, and secondary trade timings for Ramadan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bb-reschedules-treasury-auctions-repo-and-secondary-trade-timings-for-ramadan</link><description>Bangladesh Bank (BB) on Tuesday announced a new schedule for treasury instrument auctions, repo operations, and secondary trading, which will be effective during the upcoming holy month of Ramadan.
According to a circular (DMD Circular Letter No-03) issued by the Debt Management Department of the</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 12:26:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ariful breaks into cabinet, rising from ward councillor to minister</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ariful-breaks-into-cabinet-rising-from-ward-councillor-to-minister</link><description>From ward councillor to city mayor, Ariful Haque Chowdhury’s climb through Sylhet’s politics was already steep. Now, in his first term as a member of parliament, he has crossed into national power -- securing a place in Tarique Rahman’s cabinet as the BNP returns to office after t</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 12:41:24 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>