<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 21:22:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Purchase Committee approves purchase of 1.5cr litres of edible oil</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/purchase-committee-approves-purchase-of-15cr-litres-of-edible-oil</link><description>The Advisers Council Committee on Government Purchase on Tuesday approved two major proposals for purchasing 1.50 crore litres of edible oil to strengthen the domestic supply chain and maintain market stability.
The approval came from the 48th meeting of the Advisers Council Committee on Governmen</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 16:15:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Addressing the rising NPL crisis</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/addressing-the-rising-npl-crisis</link><description>The banking sector in Bangladesh is currently grappling with a critical challenge that poses a significant threat to its stability and future growth: the alarming rise in Non-Performing Loans (NPLs). The factors contributing to this crisis are complex and multifaceted, and it is essential to confro</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 16:30:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Duty-free advantage in China: opportunity or illusion?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/duty-free-advantage-in-china-opportunity-or-illusion</link><description>Bangladesh's trade imbalance with China has continued to rise over the past decade, driven mainly by high imports of industrial goods from its single largest source. While Bangladesh's export earnings from China have remained largely stagnant despite enjoying duty-free access for 98 per cent of its</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 16:45:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Striking a balance between growth and job creation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/striking-a-balance-between-growth-and-job-creation</link><description>Over the past one and a half decades, the term Gross Domestic Product or GDP became synonymous with development and the state-owned statistical agency and other official documents would occasionally come up with various data showing how the economy was on an ever-rising growth trajectory. Obviously</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 17:00:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Army, Navy, Air chiefs visit Khaleda at Evercare</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/army-navy-air-chiefs-visit-khaleda-at-evercare</link><description>Chiefs of Army, Navy and Air on Tuesday night visited ailing BNP Chairperson Khaleda Zia at Evercare Hospital in Dhaka.
According to Inter Services Public Relation (ISPR), chief of Army Staff General Waker-Uz-Zaman, chief of Naval Admiral M Nazmul Hassan, chief of Air Marshal Hasan Mahmood Khan vi</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 17:15:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two more foreign specialists' teams set to arrive Wednesday for Khaleda</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/two-more-foreign-specialists-teams-set-to-arrive-wednesday-for-khaleda</link><description>Two specialist medical teams from the UK and China are scheduled to arrive in Dhaka on Wednesday morning to support the medical board formed to ensure treatment of ailing BNP Chairperson Khaleda Zia.
Prof Dr. AZM Zahid Hossain, Khaleda Zia’s personal physician and BNP standing committee memb</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 17:30:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Government secondary school teachers suspend strike</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/government-secondary-school-teachers-suspend-strike</link><description>Government secondary school teachers have suspended their ongoing work stoppage, which was held over four demands including salary scale for ninth grade and the formation of an independent secondary education directorate.
They announced that annual examinations will be held “from Wednesday&amp;r</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 17:45:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Salahuddin commences his campaigning at Chakaria-Pekua</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/salahuddin-commences-his-campaigning-at-chakaria-pekua</link><description>BNP senior leader Salahuddin Ahmed has started electioneering in his constituency Cox’s Bazar-1 (Chakaria-Pekua).
On Tuesday morning, he arrived in Cox’s Bazar on a five-day visit to woo voters in favour of him ahead of the national election, UNB reports. 
On the first day, Salah</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 18:00:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Army officer killed in Natore road accident</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/army-officer-killed-in-natore-road-accident</link><description>An army officer was killed in a road accident in Baraigram, Natore on Tuesday evening.The deceased, Sergeant Mamunur Rashid, was posted at Ramu Cantonment, UNB reports. Inspector Suman Chandra Das, in charge of the Bonpara Police Investigation Center, said that Sergeant Rashid, serving in the</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 18:15:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat chief Shafiqur visits Khaleda at Evercare Hospital</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-chief-shafiqur-visits-khaleda-at-evercare-hospital</link><description>Jamaat-e-Islami chief Shafiqur Rahman has paid a visit to BNP Chairperson Khaleda Zia at Evercare Hospital.
Shafiqur arrived at the hospital around 10pm on Tuesday, bdnews24.com. 
“Everything is in the hands of Allah,” he said. “He can take away the living and give life to</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 18:30:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Polls, MPO allowance hike, new Islamic Bank capital to cost Tk 270b</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/polls-mpo-allowance-hike-new-islamic-bank-capital-to-cost-tk-270b</link><description>Current crunch time comes as a reminder to ministries and divisions concerned to make realistic fund demand from this year's revised budget to help the government avoid higher bank borrowings and interest payments.



The direction comes from finance division while holding consultation with t</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 19:37:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Imran Khan healthy but cut off in jail, sister says as family seeks access</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/imran-khan-healthy-but-cut-off-in-jail-sister-says-as-family-seeks-access</link><description>Imran Khan, Pakistan's jailed former prime minister, is in good physical health but facing isolation and psychological strain, his sister said on Tuesday, after a rare supervised visit following weeks in which his family said access had been blocked.
Uzma Khanum, one of Khan's three sisters, was t</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 19:52:22 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>