<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 15:23:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Guinea junta chief wins presidential election by landslide</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/africa/guinea-junta-chief-wins-presidential-election-by-landslide</link><description>Guinea’s junta chief Gen Mamady Doumbouya has won the presidential election by a landslide, getting 86.7% of the vote, according to provisional results published by the election commission.
The general is hoping to legitimise his rule after seizing power in a coup in 2021, reports BBC.
A ci</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 12:30:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Indian FM, Pakistani speaker meet in Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/indian-fm-jaishankar-pakistani-speaker-ayaz-sadiq-exchange-greetings-during-dhaka-visit</link><description>India’s External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar and Pakistan National Assembly Speaker Sardar Ayaz Sadiq exchanged greetings in Dhaka while visiting the capital to pay their final respects to Khaleda Zia.
The exchange took place ahead of Khaleda’s Janaza, the Chief Advisor’s Offic</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 12:45:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>China imposes curbs on beef imports to protect domestic industry</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/china-imposes-curbs-on-beef-imports-to-protect-domestic-industry</link><description>China will impose an added 55% tariff on beef imports that exceed quota levels from key supplier countries including Brazil, Australia and the U.S. in a move to protect a domestic cattle industry slowly emerging from oversupply.
China’s commerce ministry said on Wednesday the total import qu</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 13:00:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>China remembers Khaleda Zia’s contributions to Dhaka-Beijing ties</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/china-remembers-khaleda-zias-contributions-to-dhaka-beijing-ties</link><description>China has said BNP Chairperson and former Prime Minister Khaleda Zia’s important contributions to promoting Bangladesh-China friendship and the bilateral relationship will forever be remembered.
“Khaleda Zia is an old and dear friend of Chinese people and long committed to China-Bangla</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 13:15:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chief adviser greets countrymen on New Year 2026</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/chief-adviser-greets-countrymen-on-new-year-2026</link><description>Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus has greeted all the Bangladeshis living in the country and abroad at the advent of English New Year 2026'.
In a message on Wednesday, he said the New Year means the introduction of new dreams, new hopes and new possibilities.
“This message of the arriv</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 13:30:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CMP reshuffles OCs at Sadarghat, Chandgaon, Double Mooring stations</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cmp-reshuffles-ocs-at-sadarghat-chandgaon-double-mooring-stations</link><description>Chattogram Metropolitan Police (CMP) has transferred the officers-in-charge (OCs) of three more police stations within a month.
On Wednesday, CMP Commissioner Hasib Aziz issued the transfer orders following directives from the Police Headquarters.
The reshuffle affects Sadarghat, Chandgaon and Do</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 13:00:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh chapter of SAARC Journalist Forum condoles death of ex-PM Khaleda Zia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-chapter-of-saarc-journalist-forum-condoles-death-of-ex-pm-khaleda-zia</link><description>The Bangladesh chapter of the SAARC Journalist Forum (SJF) has expressed its profound sorrow and deep condolences at the demise of Begum Khaleda Zia, former prime minister of Bangladesh and chairperson of the Bangladesh Nationalist Party. 
“As the country’s first woman prime minis</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 13:15:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DU Metro Station closed from evening for 31st night security</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/du-metro-station-closed-from-evening-for-31st-night-security</link><description>The Dhaka University (DU) Metro Rail Station was temporarily closed from 7:00 pm on Wednesday due to security measures ahead of Thirty-first Night celebrations.
The Dhaka Mass Transit Company Limited (DMTCL) said in a statement that the closure was implemented following a special request from Dhak</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 13:30:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Precious metals cash in on record run, stocks bask in year-end glow</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/global/precious-metals-cash-in-on-record-run-stocks-bask-in-year-end-glow</link><description>There was a last-minute selloff in precious metals markets on Wednesday as investors cashed in some of the year's massive gains in gold, silver and platinum, while stocks quietly consolidated their best year since before the COVID pandemic.
Most markets were on end-of-year autopilot after a roller</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 13:45:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khaleda built BNP into a major force: Monju</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/khaleda-zia-made-bnp-a-major-political-force-muzzammil-husain</link><description>Senior journalist Muzzammil Husain Monju has described the leadership of former prime minister Khaleda Zia as “extraordinary”, saying it was under her stewardship that the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) emerged as a major political force.
The political analyst made the remarks whil</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 14:00:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dialogue with journalists on technology-facilitated gender-based violence held</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dialogue-with-journalists-on-technology-facilitated-gender-based-violence-held</link><description>A dialogue with journalists on technology-facilitated gender-based violence (TFGBV), focusing on prevention, response, and the promotion of inclusive digital development, was held in the city on Tuesday.
The programme was organised by the Bangladesh NGOs Network for Radio and Communication (BNNRC)</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 14:15:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Former home minister Mahmudul Hasan passes away</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/former-home-minister-mahmudul-hasan-passes-away</link><description>Former home minister and BNP vice chairman Major General (Retd.) Mahmudul Hasan passed away on Wednesday at the age of 90.
Mahmudul Hasan, former Member of Parliament (MP) from Tangail-5 constituency, breathed his last at 3 pm at his residence in the capital due to old age complications.
Mahmudul</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 14:30:46 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>