<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 09:37:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>‘Want to see transformed media’: Land Secretary Saleh Ahmed</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/want-to-see-transformed-media-land-secretary-saleh-ahmed</link><description>The ability of journalists to work independently is an indicator of a nation's democratic principles, said Senior Secretary of the Ministry of Land A S M Saleh Ahmed.
"So, we want to see a transformed media where journalists can present the truth by delving deep into incidents without pressure fro</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 06:49:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Push for PR system meant to delay election: Fakhrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/push-for-pr-system-meant-to-delay-election-fakhrul</link><description>BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir has said the people of the country will not accept the proportional representation (PR) voting system, as some parties are pushing for it to delay the election and hinder the restoration of democratic order.
Speaking at a memorial discussion, he al</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 07:19:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Egypt urges deploying int'l forces in Gaza</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/egypt-urges-deploying-intl-forces-in-gaza</link><description>Egyptian President Abdel-Fattah al-Sisi stressed Saturday the importance of deploying international forces in Gaza, the Egyptian Presidency said in a statement.
In a phone conversation with Cypriot President Nikos Christodoulides, al-Sisi reviewed all details of the recently-reached Gaza ceasefire</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 07:49:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Police use sound grenades to disperse MPO-listed teachers’ protest</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/police-use-sound-grenades-to-disperse-mpo-listed-teachers-protest</link><description>Police have used sound grenades to disperse a protest by teachers and employees of Monthly Pay Order (MPO)- listed schools, who are pushing for a hike in their housing allowance, in front of the Jatiya Press Club.
Around 2pm on Sunday, the law enforcers charged the protesters. They then threw the</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 08:04:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Arguments begin in crimes against humanity case against Hasina, Kamal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/arguments-begin-in-crimes-against-humanity-case-against-hasina-kamal</link><description>Arguments have started in a case over the Crimes Against Humanity against former Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina, former Home Minister Asaduzzaman Khan Kamal and another accused.
The hearing started on Sunday before the International Crimes Tribunal-1, led by Chairman Justice Md Golam Mortuza Majumde</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 08:19:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pakistan closes border with Afghanistan following exchanges of fire</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/pakistan-closes-border-with-afghanistan-following-exchanges-of-fire</link><description>Pakistan closed border crossings with Afghanistan on Sunday, Pakistani officials said, following exchanges of fire between the forces of the two countries.
Afghan troops opened fire on Pakistani border posts late Saturday, with the country's ministry of defence saying this was in retaliation for P</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 08:49:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ppolitical parties to include RMG workers’ rights in election manifestos</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ppolitical-parties-to-include-rmg-workers-rights-in-election-manifestos</link><description>The RMG Working Group Core Committee has called on all political parties and policymakers to prioritise workers’ rights, welfare, and social protection in their upcoming election manifestos, emphasising that the garment sector’s four million workers deserve stronger legal, social, and e</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 09:19:29 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>