<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 12:52:22 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Moin re-elected DCAB President; Emrul Kayesh new GS</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/moin-re-elected-dcab-president-emrul-kayesh-new-gs</link><description>AKM Moinuddin, Special Correspondent of United News of Bangladesh (UNB), has been re-elected President of the Diplomatic Correspondents Association, Bangladesh (DCAB) for the year 2026.
Abeda Sultana Mukta, Diplomatic Correspondent of Desh TV and Emrul Kayesh, Special Correspondent of Bangla Visio</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 10:56:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US-Venezuela oil deal angers China, pushes prices down</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-venezuela-oil-deal-angers-china-pushes-prices-down</link><description>Global oil prices fell on Wednesday and China denounced the US as a bully after President Donald Trump's administration said it had persuaded Venezuela to divert supplies from Beijing and import up to $2 billion worth of embargoed crude.
The deal was in line with Trump's stated aim of controlling</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 11:11:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>LPG traders threaten nationwide supply suspension</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/lp-gas-traders-threaten-nationwide-supply-suspension</link><description>Liquefied Petroleum Gas (LPG) traders have warned of a nationwide suspension of LPG supply and marketing from Thursday if Bangladesh Energy Regulatory Commission (BERC) does not announce a fresh price adjustment within 24 hours.
LPG Traders Cooperative Society Limited issued the ultimatum from a h</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 11:26:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>JnUCSU polls: Tight race for VP and AGS posts as results trickle in</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jnucsu-polls-tight-race-for-vp-and-ags-posts-as-results-trickle-in</link><description>Initial results from 18 polling centres in the Jagannath University Central Students' Union (JnUCSU) elections show a neck-and-neck battle for several top positions.
Candidates from the Oikkoboddho Nirbhik Jobian panel, backed by Chhatra Dal and Chhatra Odhikar Parishad, are leading for the VP pos</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 11:41:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh raises home-loan cap to Tk 40 million</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladesh-raises-home-loan-cap-to-tk-40-million</link><description>Bangladesh’s central bank has lifted the ceiling on housing loans to Tk 40 million, tying how much banks can lend to the quality of their existing mortgage portfolios as it seeks to balance support for the property market with financial discipline.
Bangladesh Bank said in a circular issued o</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 11:07:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique Rahman to pay respects at Abu Sayed’s grave in Rangpur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-rahman-to-pay-respects-at-abu-sayeds-grave-in-rangpur</link><description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman will visit Rangpur on Jan 12, where he is scheduled to pay respects at the grave of Abu Sayed, the first martyr of the July Uprising.
Around 2pm, the BNP’s acting chairman will visit the grave at Babanpur Jafarpara in Pirgonj Upazila before travelling by ro</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 11:22:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh, Uruguay hold first-ever bilateral political consultations</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-uruguay-hold-first-ever-bilateral-political-consultations</link><description>Bangladesh and Uruguay have held their first bilateral political consultations, marking a new chapter in diplomatic engagement between the two countries more than five decades after formal relations were established.
The consultations took place on Wednesday at the State Guest House Padma in</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 11:37:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Islami Bank holds board meeting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/islami-bank-hold-board-meeting-2</link><description>A meeting of the board of directors of Islami Bank Bangladesh PLC was held on January 7, 2026 Wednesday at the Islami Bank Tower.
Professor Dr. M. Zubaidur Rahman, chairman of the bank, presided over the meeting, according to a press release.
Mohammad Khurshid Wahab, chairman of the executive com</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 11:52:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat alleges discrimination in nomination scrutiny</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-alleges-discrimination-in-nomination-scrutiny-demands-removal-of-partisan-dcs-sps</link><description>Jamaat-e-Islami Nayeb-e-Ameer Dr Syed Abdullah Muhammad Taher on Wednesday alleged that his party faced serious discrimination during the scrutiny of nomination papers and demanded the removal of partisan Deputy Commissioners (DCs) and Superintendents of Police (SPs) from their posts.
“There</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 12:07:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>9th meeting of Shari’ah Supervisory Committee of DBH held</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/9th-meeting-of-shariah-supervisory-committee-of-dbh-held</link><description>DBH Finance PLC (DBH), the country’s largest housing finance institution and the only NBFI (Non-Banking Financial Institution) with exclusive focus on housing finance, recently held its 9th meeting of the Shari’ah Supervisory Committee (SSC) at its Head Office in Gulshan.
The meeting w</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 12:22:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ukraine, US to revisit land, nuclear plant issues in Wednesday talks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/ukraine-us-to-revisit-land-nuclear-plant-issues-in-wednesday-talks</link><description>US and Ukrainian negotiators will revisit the thorny issues of territory and the fate of the occupied Zaporizhzhia nuclear power plant, President Volodymyr Zelenskiy said on Wednesday, the most problematic points in peace talks to end Russia's war.
Kyiv is under US pressure to secure peace in the</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 12:37:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Reza Kibria show-caused over ‘code breach’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-candidate-reza-kibria-show-caused-for-voilating-electoral-code-in-habiganj</link><description>BNP-nominated parliamentary candidate Reza Kibria has been served a show-cause notice over alleged violations of the election code of conduct in Habiganj-1 constituency.
The notice was issued by the election inquiry and judicial committee, asking him to explain his position over the allegations.</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 12:52:22 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>