<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 09:25:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Tarique meets youth ahead of Ctg election rally</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-meets-youth-ahead-of-ctg-election-rally</link><description>BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman has exchanged views with the youth ahead of a planned rally in Chattogram.
The exchange of views, titled “The Plan: Youth Policy Talk with Tarique Rahman”, is being held at the Radisson Blu Hotel in the port city from 10 am on Sunday.
Around 450 students fr</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 06:00:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shakib Al Hasan available for selection, says BCB</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/shakib-al-hasan-available-for-selection-says-bcb</link><description>In a dramatic development coinciding with Bangladesh's official exclusion from the T20 World Cup, the Bangladesh Cricket Board (BCB) has announced that former captain Shakib Al Hasan is once again eligible for national selection.
The decision was made following an eight-hour board meeting on Satur</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 06:35:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two killed in Jatrabari road crash</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/two-killed-in-jatrabari-road-crash</link><description>Two young men were killed after a truck carrying chickens slammed into their motorcycle in Shanir Akhra area of Dhaka’s Jatrabari on Saturday night.
The victims were identified as Khairul Hossain Kamrul, 21, a college student, and his friend Mohammad Yasin, 25, reports BSS.
The accident occ</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 06:50:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Stocks open mixed as DSE falls, CSE rises</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/stocks-open-mixed-as-dse-falls-cse-rises</link><description>Bangladesh's stock market began the week on a mixed note on Sunday, with the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) sliding in early trade while the Chittagong Stock Exchange (CSE) posted gains.
During the first half of the session, the benchmark DSEX index of the DSE shed 10 points.
The Shariah-based DSES i</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 07:05:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Minor earthquake jolts Thakurgaon</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/minor-earthquake-jolts-thakurgaon</link><description>An earthquake shook Thakurgaon and surrounding areas today.
According to the Bangladesh Meteorological Department, the quake was of minor intensity measured 3.4 on the Richter scale and occurred at 8:34:44 am.
The epicenter was located in Atgharia Bazar (Latitude 25.97°N, Longitude. 88.15&amp;deg</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 07:20:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh thrash Maldives to win maiden SAFF Women's Futsal Championship</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/bangladesh-thrash-maldives-to-win-maiden-saff-womens-futsal-championship</link><description>The Maldives were the first to take the lead. But it was to be their only spark of joy in a one-sided thrashing.
Soon enough Sabina Lhatun and Masura Parvin had levelled the score, and the goals began to flow. In the end, the Tigresses etched their names onto the first SAFF Women's Futsal Champion</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 07:35:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No level playing field yet for elections, alleges Nahid</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/no-level-playing-field-yet-for-elections-alleges-nahid</link><description>Jamaat alliance candidate for Dhaka-11 and convener of National Citizen Party (NCP) Nahid Islam on Sunday alleged that a level playing field has yet to be ensured for the upcoming national election.
Speaking during electioneering at different spots in Badda-Satarkul area in the morning, Nahid clai</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 07:50:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Call me ‘Bhaiya’, not ‘sir’: Tarique tells youth in Chittagong</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/call-me-bhaiya-not-sir-tarique-tells-youth-in-chittagong</link><description>BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman has suggested that young people address him as “Bhaiya” (brother) instead of “sir” while interacting with him during an election campaign discussion with students in Chattogram.
The remark came on Sunday morning at the “Youth Policy Talk wi</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 08:05:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump's Greenland ambitions strain MAGA ties with Europe's far-right</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trumps-greenland-ambitions-strain-maga-ties-with-europes-far-right</link><description>Tensions over U.S. President Donald Trump's plans to take control of Greenland have driven a wedge in the once iron-clad link between MAGA and Europe's far-right.
The rift seems to signal that ideological alignment alone may not be enough to temper worries among European nationalists over Trump's</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 08:20:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Elections to be transparent: CEC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/elections-to-be-transparent-cec</link><description>Chief Election Commissioner (CEC) AMM Nasir Uddin on Sunday assured foreign diplomats that the upcoming national election will be held in transparent and credible manners amid foolproof security arrangement, leaving no scope for ‘hide-and-seek’.
“We want a very transparent</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 08:51:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Islamic Foundation rejects ‘9-minute adjustment’ claims in Ramadan Sehri-Iftar schedules</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/islamic-foundation-rejects-9-minute-adjustment-claims-in-ramadan-sehri-iftar-schedules</link><description>The Islamic Foundation has dismissed reports claiming that Sehri and Iftar times for Ramadan should be adjusted by adding or subtracting nine minutes from the Dhaka time, calling such information misleading and baseless.
In a clarification issued on Sunday, the foundation said it has not published</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 09:06:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh economic growth projected at 5pc in 2026</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/bangladesh-economic-growth-projected-at-5pc-in-2026</link><description>Bangladesh’s economic outlook for 2026 reflects a balance between moderate growth potential—estimated at around 5 per cent—and persistent structural challenges, with inflation expected to ease gradually, according to the Economic Update &amp; Outlook (January) published by the Plannin</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 09:21:25 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>