<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 15:25:17 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Mercantile Bank holds training on risk awareness</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/mercantile-bank-holds-training-on-risk-awareness</link><description>Mercantile Bank Training Institute (MBTI) organized a day-long “Training on Risk Awareness” aiming to enhance employees’ understanding of risk management and promote a culture of risk awareness across all levels of the bank on 26 October 2025.
A total of 48 officials from differe</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 12:07:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>More than 40 bodies seen in street after Rio's deadliest police operation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/more-than-40-bodies-seen-in-street-after-rios-deadliest-police-operation</link><description>More than 40 dead bodies were seen on a street in Rio de Janeiro's Penha favela complex early on Wednesday, according to a Reuters witness, a day after the most lethal police operation in the city's history targeting a major gang.
Rio de Janeiro state authorities said on Tuesday that at least 64 p</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 12:22:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>MTB Foundation inaugurates MTB UCEP Skills Training Institute to commemorate bank’s anniversary</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/mtb-foundation-inaugurates-mtb-ucep-skills-training-institute-to-commemorate-banks-anniversary</link><description>To commemorate MTB’s anniversary, MTB Foundation, in partnership with UCEP Bangladesh recently inaugurated the project ‘MTB UCEP Skills Training Institute (MUSTI)’, the flagship project of MTB Foundation under the ‘Education’ sector.
Project MUSTI will provide trainin</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 12:37:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Foreign exchange reserves stand at $32.15 billion</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/foreign-exchange-reserves-stand-at-3215-billion</link><description>Bangladesh’s foreign exchange reserves have stood at $32.15 billion, according to the latest data of the Bangladesh Bank (BB) released on Wednesday.
But, as per the International Monetary Fund (IMF) methodology under the Balance of Payments and International Investment Position Manual (BPM6)</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 13:22:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Meeting of board of directors of IBB PLC held</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/meeting-of-board-of-directors-of-ibb-plc-held</link><description>A meeting of the board of directors of Islami Bank Bangladesh PLC was held on October 29, 2025, Wednesday at Islami Bank Tower.
Professor Dr. M. Zubaidur Rahman, chairman of the bank, presided over the meeting, according to a media release.
Mohammad Khurshid Wahab, chairman of the executive commi</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 13:37:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>174 undocumented Bangladeshi returns from Libya</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/174-undocumented-bangladeshi-returns-from-libya</link><description>A total of 174 irregular Bangladeshi nationals have been repatriated from Libya through a chartered flight of Burak Air under a coordinated initiative supported by the Government of Libya and the International Organization for Migration (IOM).
According to the Ministry of Foreign Affairs, the volu</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 13:52:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Liberation War Ministry cancels gazettes of 128 July fighters</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/liberation-war-ministry-cancels-gazettes-of-128-july-fighters</link><description>The Ministry of Liberation War Affairs has cancelled the gazettes of 128 people from different parts across the country after discrepancies were found during verification of the lists published as injured participants in the July Uprising.
A notification in this regard was issued by the ministry o</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 14:07:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Md Belal Hossain new Chairman of Jamuna Bank</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/md-belal-hossain-new-chairman-of-jamuna-bank</link><description>Mr Md Belal Hossain has been unanimously elected as the new Chairman of Jamuna Bank PLC in accordance with the bank’s regular procedures.
He is one of the founding directors of the bank and a successful entrepreneur of the country, according to a media release.</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 14:22:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NRBC Bank holds its 217th Board Meeting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/nrbc-bank-holds-its-217th-board-meeting</link><description>The 217th meeting of the Board of Directors of NRBC Bank PLC was held on Wednesday, 29 October 2025, at the bank's Head Office.
Mr. Md. Ali Hossain Prodhania, Chairman, NRBC Bank, presided over the meeting, according to a press release.
Mr. Muhammad Emdad Ullah, FCA, Independent Director and Chai</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 14:37:42 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>