<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 12:55:14 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>International plastic, packaging and printing industrial fair to kick off Wednesday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/international-plastic-packaging-and-printing-industrial-fair-to-kick-off-wednesday</link><description>The 18th Bangladesh International Plastic, Packaging and Printing Industrial Fair-2026 (IPF-26) will commence on Wednesday, January 28, 2026, at the International Convention City Bashundhara (ICCB) in Dhaka. 
 
The four-day international industrial fair will continue until Saturday, Jan</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 09:15:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Printing money, not ‘syndicates’, drove up egg and chicken prices</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/printing-money-not-syndicates-drove-up-egg-and-chicken-prices</link><description>The previous government repeatedly accused poultry companies of manipulating the prices of eggs and chicken. What really happened? First, the cost of feed rose sharply after Russia invaded Ukraine. The prices of imported feed ingredients increased. This supply shock was beyond the control of the po</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 09:30:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>If there’s no ‘level playing field’, how are complaints filed? asks EC secy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/if-no-level-playing-field-exists-how-are-complaints-being-filed-asks-ec-secretary</link><description>Despite some unrest, allegations and counter-allegations of irregularities in different parts of the country in the five days since the start of campaigning for the 13th parliamentary election, Election Commission Secretary Akhtar Ahmed says there is “equal opportunity for all”.
Action</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 09:45:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Woman, son among three dead as bus falls into ditch in Bhola</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/woman-son-among-three-dead-as-bus-falls-into-ditch-in-bhola</link><description>At least three people, including a woman and her son, have died when a passenger bus plunged into a roadside ditch in Bhola's Lalmohon.
Another 20 people were injured in the accident that occurred in front of Gazaria College around 12pm on Monday, said Lalmohon Police Station chief (OC) Waliul Isl</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 10:00:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fakhrul urges voters to protect country from 1971 traitors</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fakhrul-urges-voters-to-protect-country-from-1971-traitors</link><description>BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir on Monday urged voters not to ‘destroy the country’ by casting ballots for those who had collaborated with the Pakistani force in 1971 and are now seeking to rule the country again.
“Those who assisted the Pakistani army even at t</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 10:15:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt okays Tk 1b subsidy, 20pc power rebate for fisheries, livestock</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-clears-tk-10-billion-subsidy-20-per-cent-power-rebate-for-fisheries-livestock</link><description>The government has approved a Tk 1.0 billion subsidy and a 20 per cent rebate on electricity bills for marginal-level fish farms, hatcheries and livestock, and poultry farms to reduce production costs and stimulate investment in the sector.
The Ministry of Fisheries and Livestock said on Monday th</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 10:30:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CA for armed forces' role in ensuring free and fair polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ca-for-armed-forces-role-in-ensuring-free-and-fair-polls</link><description>Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus today (Monday) instructed the Armed Forces to perform their duties with professionalism, neutrality, and inter-institutional coordination to ensure participatory, fear-free and fair national elections.
The Chief Adviser gave the instruction at a views exchang</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 10:45:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Former MPs make up 85 of BNP’s 292 election candidates</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/former-mps-make-up-85-of-bnps-292-election-candidates</link><description>The Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) has nominated candidates in 292 constituencies for the upcoming 13th parliamentary election.
Speaking at a media briefing at the BNP’s Gulshan office on Monday, Mahdi Amin, spokesperson for the party’s Election Steering Committee, said 85 of the c</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 11:00:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No official bound to carry out illegal orders: ICT chief prosecutor</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/no-official-required-to-carry-out-illegal-orders-says-ict-chief-prosecutor</link><description>International Crimes Tribunal (ICT) Chief Prosecutor Tajul Islam has said no state official or employee is obligated to obey any unlawful order issued by the government.
He made the remarks on Monday afternoon after the ICT delivered its verdict against eight policemen over the killing of six peop</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 11:15:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DUCSU member Sarba Mitra Chakma announces resignation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/ducsu-member-sarba-mitra-chakma-announces-resignation-as-video-draws-backlash</link><description>In the face of criticism, Sarba Mitra Chakma has announced his resignation from the post of executive member of the Dhaka University Central Students' Union (DUCSU) in a Facebook post.
On Monday afternoon, he wrote: “I have decided to resign. My decision was not taken out of spite or due to</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 11:30:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>United Finance Plc, United Healthcare Services Ltd announce strategic partnership to enhance customer wellbeing</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/united-finance-plc-united-healthcare-services-ltd-announce-strategic-partnership-to-enhance-customer-wellbeing</link><description>United Finance PLC and United Healthcare Services Ltd. have entered into a strategic partnership aimed at enhancing customer wellbeing through a range of value‑added healthcare services, exclusive discounts, and tailored wellness packages.
The agreement was signed by Mohammad Faizur Rahman, Chief</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 11:45:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EU countries give final approval to Russian gas ban</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/eu-countries-give-final-approval-to-russian-gas-ban</link><description>European Union countries on Monday gave their final approval to ban Russian gas imports by late 2027, making their vow to cut ties with their former top supplier legally binding, nearly four years after Moscow's full-scale invasion of Ukraine.
Ministers from EU countries approved the law at a meet</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 12:00:52 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>