<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 16:29:56 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>NRBC Bank holds its 217th Board Meeting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/nrbc-bank-holds-its-217th-board-meeting</link><description>The 217th meeting of the Board of Directors of NRBC Bank PLC was held on Wednesday, 29 October 2025, at the bank's Head Office.
Mr. Md. Ali Hossain Prodhania, Chairman, NRBC Bank, presided over the meeting, according to a press release.
Mr. Muhammad Emdad Ullah, FCA, Independent Director and Chai</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 14:37:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Junior scholarship exam deferred by 7 days, now starts Dec 28</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/junior-scholarship-exam-deferred-by-7-days-now-starts-dec-28</link><description>The junior scholarship examination for eighth graders, originally set to begin on Dec 21, has been deferred by seven days and will now start on Dec 28.
The exam will now start on Dec 28 and continue until Dec 31, according to the revised timetable published on Wednesday by the Board of Intermediat</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 14:07:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Standard Bank Securities holds 51st meeting of the Board of Directors</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/standard-bank-securities-holds-51st-meeting-of-the-board-of-directors</link><description>The 51st meeting of the Board of Directors of Standard Bank Securities Limited was held on Wednesday at Standard Bank Board Room, Head Office, Dhaka. Chairman Ferozur Rahman presided over the meeting, according to a press release.
The meeting was attended by the members of the Board Tazmeem Mostaf</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 14:22:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Capital market reforms to be finished within 2-months</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/capital-market-reforms-to-be-finished-within-2-months</link><description>Bangladesh Securities and Exchange Commission (BSEC) Chairman Khondoker Rashed Maqsood on Wednesday said they are moving forward with significant capital market reforms and assured stakeholders that all key tasks will be completed within the next two months.
The commitment was made during a high-l</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 14:52:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Speakers call for investments in water efficiency</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/speakers-call-for-investments-in-water-efficiency</link><description>Speakers at a seminar on Wednesday stressed the need for responsible water use and shared responsibility of stakeholders, including government, industry, and development partners to integrate water stewardship into Bangladesh’s sustainable industrial development strategy.
They also called fo</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 15:07:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ONE Bank achieves prestigious ISO/IEC 27001:2022 certificate</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/one-bank-achieves-prestigious-iso-iec-270012022-certificate</link><description>ONE Bank has been awarded a prestigious and internationally recognized ISO/IEC 27001:2022 certificate by the French-based certification authority Bureau Veritas (Bangladesh) Pvt. Ltd. for fulfilling the requirements of the ISO 27001:2022 standard.
According to a press release, this is an internati</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 15:37:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP standing committee meeting underway</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-standing-committee-meeting-underway</link><description>A regular meeting of BNP’s standing committee is underway at the BNP chairperson’s office in the Gulshan area in Dhaka on Wednesday night.
BNP’s Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman is presiding over the meeting, joining virtually from London.
Local newspaper reports said the party wo</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 15:52:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Experts urge subsidies &amp; incentives on Organic Fertiliser to Protect Soil Health &amp; Crop Health</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/experts-urge-subsidies-incentives-on-organic-fertiliser-to-protect-soil-health-crop-health</link><description>Agricultural experts and policymakers have emphasised the urgent need for subsidies and incentives to promote the use of organic fertilisers in order to protect soil and crop health.
They urged the government to take concrete measures without delay, according to a press release.
The remarks came</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 16:07:43 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>