<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 11:18:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Pharma industry fears Tk 40 billion lose in Dhaka airport fire</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/pharma-industry-fears-tk-40-billion-lose-in-dhaka-airport-fire</link><description>The Bangladesh Association of Pharmaceutical Industries (BAPI) has said the country's pharmaceutical industry faces a potential financial loss of around Tk 40 billion due to the fire in the Cargo Village at Dhaka's Shahjalal International Airport.
Leaders of the organisation presented the figure</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 08:53:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CAAB chief sidesteps responsibility for Dhaka airport blaze</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/caab-chief-sidesteps-responsibility-for-dhaka-airport-blaze</link><description>Air Vice Marshal Md Mostafa Mahmood Siddiq, chairman of the Civil Aviation Authority of Bangladesh (CAAB), has refused to take the blame for the blaze at the import cargo complex of Dhaka's Shahjalal International Airport.
Although the building belongs to the CAAB, operations inside are conducted</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 09:23:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ECNEC approves 13 projects worth Tk 19.88 billion</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ecnec-approves-13-projects-worth-tk-1988-billion</link><description>The Executive Committee of the National Economic Council (ECNEC) on Tuesday approved 13 development projects involving an estimated total cost of Tk 19.88 billion.
The approval came at an ECNEC meeting chaired by Chief Adviser and ECNEC Chairperson Professor Dr Muhammad Yunus at the NEC Conference</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 08:46:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Bangladesh Bank’s independence key to sustainable economic recovery’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh-banks-independence-key-to-sustainable-economic-recovery-khosru</link><description>Former commerce minister Amir Khosru Mahmud Chowdhury on Tuesday said the independence of Bangladesh Bank is very important for ensuring sustainable economic recovery.
 
The standing committee member of the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) said their party has planned an economic model to</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 09:01:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BIDA invites Korean investors to explore Bangladesh's untapped potential</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bida-invites-korean-investors-to-explore-bangladeshs-untapped-potential</link><description>The Bangladesh Investment Development Authority (BIDA) has called on South Korean investors to capitalize on Bangladesh's dynamic investment landscape, highlighting the country's competitive advantages and ongoing reforms to facilitate foreign direct investment (FDI). At an investment seminar</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 09:31:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>8 arrested as Awami League stages protest marches in 10 locations across Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/8-arrested-as-awami-league-stages-protest-marches-in-10-locations-across-dhaka</link><description>Supporters of the Awami League, whose political activities are banned, have held protest marches in 10 different locations across Dhaka, demanding that the interim government step down and an end to "false cases" against party leaders and activists.
The processions took place between 10:30am and 1</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 09:46:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jobayed’s murder tied to love triangle: Police</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jagannath-university-student-jobayeds-murder-tied-to-love-triangle-police-say</link><description>Claiming to have “unravelled the mystery” behind the killing of Jagannath University Chhatra Dal leader Md Jobayed Hossain, police said the incident stemmed not from politics, but due to a “love triangle”.
According to investigators, 19-year-old Barjis Shabnam Borsha develo</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 10:01:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US-Bangla adds third Airbus A330</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/us-bangla-adds-third-airbus-a330</link><description>Another wide-body airbus has been added to the fleet of the private US-Bangla Airlines, aiming at expanding its operational capacity further.
With this, there are three airbuses for the airlines.
The latest aircraft having capacity of 436 seats landed at Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport in</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 10:16:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Japan elects Sanae Takaichi as first female prime minister</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/japan-elects-sanae-takaichi-as-first-female-prime-minister</link><description>Japan’s parliament on Tuesday elected Sanae Takaichi as the country’s first female prime minister, marking a historic moment in Japanese politics.
The ultraconservative leader of the Liberal Democratic Party (LDP) replaces Shigeru Ishiba, who resigned earlier in the day following his p</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 10:31:46 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>