<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 17:17:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Community Bank signs Participatory Agreement with Bangladesh Bank regarding FICGS</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/community-bank-signs-participatory-agreement-with-bangladesh-bank-regarding-ficgs</link><description>Community Bank Bangladesh PLC. has signed a "Participatory Agreement" with Bangladesh Bank to join the Participation Agreement under Financial Inclusion Credit Guarantee Scheme (FICGS).
This agreement is a key initiative aimed to extend credit facilities to 10/50/100 Tk. Account holder marginal/ l</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 14:22:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique Rahman enquires about Nur’s health</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-rahman-enquires-about-nurs-health</link><description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman today telephoned Nurul Haque Nur, President of Gono Odhikar Parishad, to enquire about his health.
Tarique Rahman called up Nur, President of Gono Odhikar Parishad at about 6:45 pm (BST) to check his well-being, Gono Odhikar Parishad General Secretary Md. Rashed</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 14:37:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>People to reject bids to delay election: Salahuddin</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/people-will-reject-attempts-to-delay-or-obstruct-election-salahuddin</link><description>BNP senior leader Salahuddin Ahmed on Monday said the people of Bangladesh will politically reject those who are trying to delay or obstruct the national election.
“For the last 16 years, we have struggled to restore our democratic and voting rights. But since the election timeline was annou</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 15:22:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BGB urges media to report factually on Khagrachhari tensions</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bgb-urges-media-to-report-factually-on-khagrachhari-tensions-identities-of-3-victims-revealed</link><description>The Border Guard Bangladesh (BGB) has urged journalists to ensure accurate and responsible reporting on the recent violence that broke out in Khagrachhari, warning that misinformation could escalate tensions in the region.
Khagrachhari BGB Sector Commander Colonel Md Abdul Moktakim made the call a</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 15:37:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Railway advises passengers to use official App for ticket purchases</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/railway-advises-passengers-to-use-official-app-for-ticket-purchases</link><description>Bangladesh Railway has advised passengers to purchase train tickets only through its designated mobile application “Rail Sheba” in order to avoid harassment and fraud.
The authority has recently observed that certain fraudulent individuals are assuring ticket sales through various soci</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 15:52:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Brahmanbaria youth dies following alleged mob beating, police torture</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/brahmanbaria-youth-dies-following-alleged-mob-beating-police-torture</link><description>A youth died on Sunday night after alleged mob beating and torture in police custody in Nabinagar upazila of Brahmanbaria.
The victim was identified as Md Abdullah, 23, son of Abul Mia from Baherchar village in Tejkhali union under Bancharampur upazila.
Abdullah succumbed to his injuries while un</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 16:07:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Visa process will ‘normalise’ if situation ‘improves’, says Indian envoy Verma</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/visa-process-will-normalise-if-situation-improves-says-indian-envoy-verma</link><description>Indian High Commissioner to Bangladesh Pranay Verma has said the visa process will return to “normal” if the situation “improves”.
On Monday evening, after attending Durga Puja celebrations at Tangail’s Mirzapur, he said Bangladesh and India share similarities in how</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 16:22:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jatiya Party leader Mamunur Rashid ‘co-conspirator’ to US citizen, police say</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jatiya-party-leader-mamunur-rashid-co-conspirator-to-us-citizen-police-say</link><description>Police have claimed that Kazi Md Mamunur Rashid, secretary general of the Raushon Ershad-led faction of the Jatiya Party, was working as an associate of Enayet Karim Chowdhury, a US citizen of Bangladeshi origin who was detained for “suspicious movement” on Dhaka’s Minto Road.
Ba</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 16:37:24 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>