<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 02:26:54 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>On BNP's pledge to respect fearless, unbiased journalism</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/on-bnps-pledge-to-respect-fearless-unbiased-journalism</link><description>A landslide victory brings with it not only power, but scrutiny. After the Bangladesh Nationalist Party's sweeping win in the 13th parliamentary elections on 12 February, public attention has swiftly shifted from celebration to expectation. Among the most pressing tests facing the incoming governme</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 17:02:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Saving Sundarbans from disintegration</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/saving-sundarbans-from-disintegration</link><description>That a number of environmental organisations have been observing the Sundarbans Day each year on February 14 since 2001 is not widely known. The reason for this is the limited publicity the day's observance receives with the government yet to recognise the day officially. So, the environmental grou</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 17:17:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh moves up 3 spots in Henley Passport Index, ranks 93rd</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-moves-up-3-spots-in-henley-passport-index-ranks-93rd</link><description>Bangladesh has climbed three places in the latest Henley Passport Index, moving up to 93rd position from 96th in the previous ranking.
According to the new list, Singapore remains at the top of the index, retaining its position as the world’s most powerful passport. Japan and South Korea joi</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 17:32:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chief advisor’s principal secretary resigns</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/chief-advisors-principal-secretary-resigns</link><description>The Chief Advisor’s Principal Secretary M Siraz Uddin Miah has resigned.
The chief advisor’s press aide Shafiqul Alam said the Ministry of Public Administration issued a gazette notification about the resignation on Monday.
Two days after the general election, the interim government o</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 17:47:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fire erupts at Karwan Bazar timber market</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fire-erupts-at-karwan-bazar-timber-market</link><description>A fire has broken out at Karwan Bazar timber market.
Fire Service duty officer Shahjahan Hossain said the fire was reported around 10:30pm on Monday.
"Eight units of the Fire Service are currently working to extinguish the flames," he said.
The cause of the fire could not be immediately known. N</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 18:02:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>MP oath hollow without reform council pledge: Asif Mahmud</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/skipping-constitution-reform-council-oath-would-void-mps-mandate-says-asif-mahmud</link><description>Former student advisor Asif Mahmud Shojib Bhuyain has said skipping the oath as a member of the Constitution Reform Council would render a parliamentary oath “meaningless”.
A day before the MP oath, on Monday, he made the remark in a Facebook post.
“The oath of the Constitution</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 18:17:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How much will Tarique earn as PM?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/how-much-will-tarique-earn-as-prime-minister-and-what-perks-come-with-the-office</link><description>If all goes as planned, BNP Chairperson Tarique Rahman is poised to assume office as Bangladesh’s next prime minister, completing a remarkable journey from years of exile to the very centre of state power.
As anticipation builds around his return to government, many are asking a simpler, mor</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 19:03:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Regulator's move for digital bank licensing flops amid protests</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/regulators-move-for-digital-bank-licensing-flops-amid-protests</link><description>A decisive regulatory move for licensing digital banks flops as an emergency board meeting of Bangladesh Bank backtracked following strong protest from officers against such last-minute decision during governmental transition.



Sources said a strong protest from the BB officers' platform upse</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 19:18:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Coppertech's pre-IPO accounts come under fresh regulatory scrutiny</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/coppertechs-pre-ipo-accounts-come-under-fresh-regulatory-scrutiny</link><description>The securities regulator has set out to verify the authenticity of Coppertech Industries' pre-IPO financial statements to uncover any irregularities linked to the controversy surrounding the company's 2019 listing.
A decision to investigate Coppertech Industries was made in November last year, but</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 01:41:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Green Delta earnings flat in 2025 as claim expenses surge</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/green-delta-earnings-flat-in-2025-as-claim-expenses-surge</link><description>Despite higher premium income, Green Delta Insurance's profit remained almost flat at Tk 545 million in 2025 compared to the year before, due to higher expenses on claim settlement and lower income from subsidiaries.
The general insurer's consolidated earnings per share (EPS) stood at Tk 5.44 in 2</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 01:56:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DSE, CSE cut trading hours during Ramadan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/dse-cse-cut-trading-hours-during-ramadan</link><description>The Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) and the Chittagong Stock Exchange (CSE) have reduced trading time by 40 minutes during the holy month of Ramadan.
Trading on the bourses will begin at 10:00am as usual and continue until 1:50pm, including a 10-minute post-closing session, in line with banking hours,</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 02:11:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>People suffer amid LPG shortage, price soars</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/people-suffer-amid-lpg-shortage-price-soars</link><description>Acute shortage of liquefied petroleum gas (LPG) cylinders and its high prices all of a sudden has left Chandpur residents reeling in hardships during food preparation as consumers seen running from one shops to another in vain and food shops, restaurants and hotels suffering losses.
Talking to the</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 02:26:54 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>