<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 14:22:43 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>KSA bars pilgrims with incurable diseases from performing Hajj: Ministry</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ksa-bars-pilgrims-with-incurable-diseases-from-performing-hajj-ministry</link><description>The Saudi government has announced that people suffering from severe health conditions or incurable diseases will not be allowed to perform Hajj, said the Ministry of Religious Affairs.
In a press release on Monday, the ministry said the Saudi Ministry of Hajj and Umrah has instructed all countrie</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 11:34:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New Delhi police detain dozens in anti-pollution protests</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/new-delhi-police-detain-dozens-in-anti-pollution-protests</link><description>Indian police detained dozens of people during a rare protest at the famed India Gate monument in New Delhi demanding action to curb an annual scourge of toxic air swathing the capital and its surrounding region.
Sunday’s protest by crowds of all ages holding banners and chanting slogans bef</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 11:49:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Interim govt will decide on July Charter implementation now: Advisor Rizwana</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/interim-govt-will-decide-on-july-charter-implementation-now-advisor-rizwana</link><description>The government will make a decision on its own regarding the implementation of the July Charter as political parties have not reached a consensus among themselves, says Environment Advisor Syeda Rizwana Hasan.
The advisor made the statement in response to a question while speaking to the media at</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 12:04:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique Rahman calls emergency Standing Committee meeting tonight</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-rahman-calls-emergency-standing-committee-meeting-tonight</link><description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman called an emergency meeting of the party’s Standing Committee tonight. 
BNP Standing Committee Member Dr. Khandaker Mosharraf Hossain said that the meeting will be held tonight at 8:30 pm at the BNP Chairperson’s office in Gulshan, BSS reports.&amp;n</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 11:30:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shariah Bank Merger: BCMIA suspends Bangladesh Bank siege programme</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/shariah-bank-merger-bcmia-suspends-bangladesh-bank-siege-programme</link><description>Bangladesh Capital Market Investors Association (BCMIA) has called off its planned demonstration outside Bangladesh Bank, scheduled for Tuesday, demanding compensation for investors impacted by the merger of five Shariah-based banks.
The decision comes after ongoing discussions with relevant autho</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 11:45:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Outsiders banned from National Eidgah grounds near Supreme Court</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/outsiders-banned-from-national-eidgah-grounds-near-supreme-court</link><description>Outsiders have been barred from entering the National Eidgah grounds adjacent to the Supreme Court in Dhaka amid heightened security surrounding the upcoming verdict in an ICT case against former prime minister Sheikh Hasina.
The restriction was announced in a notice signed by Supreme Court Deputy</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 12:00:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Maj Gen Osman Sarwar made new DG of NTMC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/maj-gen-osman-sarwar-made-new-dg-of-ntmc</link><description>The government has appointed Major General Mohammad Osman Sarwar as the new Director General of the National Telecommunication Monitoring Center (NTMC).
The Ministry of Public Administration issued a notification in this regard on Sunday.
According to the notification, Major General Osman Sarwar</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 12:15:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>City Bank and UNICEF partner to empower marginalized youth with green skills</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/city-bank-and-unicef-partner-to-empower-marginalized-youth-with-green-skills</link><description>City Bank and UNICEF recently announced a new partnership to equip marginalized adolescents and young people, particularly the girls with green and entrepreneurship skills under the pilot project, Skills4Youth.
The partnership was formalized at a signing ceremony held recently in Dhaka, according</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 12:30:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Verdict nears as testimonies conclude in ‘plot graft’ case against Hasina</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/verdict-nears-as-testimonies-conclude-in-plot-graft-case-against-hasina</link><description>Testimonies have concluded in the corruption case filed against former prime minister Sheikh Hasina and 11 others over the alleged illegal allocation of plots.
On Monday, Dhaka Special Judge Mohammad Abdullah Al Mamun set Nov 17 for the defendants to present their statements in self-defence.
Cros</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 12:45:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ex-minister Muktadir ordered to appear before ICT</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/former-minister-obaidul-muktadir-ordered-to-appear-before-ict</link><description>The International Crimes Tribunal (ICT) has ordered former housing and public works minister RAM Obaidul Muktadir Chowdhury to appear before it on Dec 14 over allegations of killings of Hifazat-e Islam leaders in Brahmanbaria.
The directive was issued on Monday by a single-member bench of Tribunal</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 13:00:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC’s decision declared ‘Illegal’, 4 Bagerhat seats restored</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ecs-decision-declared-illegal-4-bagerhat-seats-restored</link><description>The High Court has declared illegal the gazette notification issued by the Election Commission (EC) that reduced Bagerhat's four parliamentary seats to three.
A bench of Justice Sashanka Shekhar Sarkar and Justice Faysal Hasan Arif directed that the previous four seats be reinstated.
The court de</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 13:15:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DMP bans police on duty in Dhaka from using mobile phones</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dmp-bans-police-on-duty-in-dhaka-from-using-mobile-phones</link><description>The Dhaka Metropolitan Police (DMP) has banned the use of mobile phones by on-duty personnel as security measures tighten surrounding programmes announced by the outlawed Awami League.
The directive was issued on Monday by Police Commissioner Sheikh Md Sazzat Ali, Joint Commissioner (Crime) Md Far</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 13:30:45 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>