<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 03:21:44 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Jamaat leader arrested in Sylhet over cheque dishonor cases</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jamaat-leader-arrested-in-sylhet-over-cheque-dishonor-cases</link><description>Police have arrested a local Jamaat-e-Islami leader from Fenchuganj upazila in Sylhet in connection with two cheque dishonor cases.
The arrestee, Shah Mohammad Habibur Rahman (Lipon), a former secretary of Jamaat-e-Islami’s Fenchuganj upazila unit, was detained from his business establishmen</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 16:46:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Detrimental nationalism abuses human rights</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/detrimental-nationalism-abuses-human-rights</link><description>Most unfortunately, because of the changes in the geo-strategic paradigm an osmotic effect is being created in interactive relations between communities and people originating from different countries. Sometimes, an intense dislike or fear of strangers is moving us, according to sociologists toward</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 17:31:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gaza peace plan: reading between the lines</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/reviews/gaza-peace-plan-reading-between-the-lines</link><description>The ceasefire agreement on the war in Gaza, signed on October 10 at Sharm el Sheik, is now two weeks old. It is still holding on, in a manner of speaking. The tongue-in-cheek statement conveys its beleaguered state. No sooner the exchange of Israeli hostages  and Palestinian prisoners was comp</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 17:46:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Close to Nature, Badshahs work wonder</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/close-to-nature-badshahs-work-wonder</link><description>Planting tree is his passion. Badshah is his given name. He deserves the name without any reservation because his heart is as large as any benevolent and legendary badshah ever possessed for showering kindness. Contrary to the grandeur of the name, this Badshah is a day labourer. But the unwavering</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 18:01:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Danger that people's persistent income loss poses</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/danger-that-peoples-persistent-income-loss-poses</link><description>The middle-to-low-income earners, who mostly belong to the fixed income groups in society, are gradually failing to hold on to the socio-economic categories, such as the middle-income groups, they have traditionally been bracketed into.  Such developments have occasionally been the stuff of th</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 18:16:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The mess that is Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/the-mess-that-is-dhaka</link><description>The bustling megacity of Dhaka has long been mired in a series of public nuisance, which earned it the dubious distinction of being one of the least liveable cities in the world. One would expect the government to take determined and effective steps to gradually address this mess, ensuring that liv</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 18:31:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Army finds major arms cache at Airport Railway Station</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/army-seizes-eight-foreign-pistols-explosives-at-airport-railway-station</link><description>The Bangladesh Army has recovered a cache of firearms and explosives from a train compartment during a raid at Dhaka’s Airport Railway Station.
In a statement, the Inter-Services Public Relations (ISPR) said the operation was carried out around 11:15am on Sunday with support from Railway Pol</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 18:46:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US, China talks sketch out rare earths, tariff pause</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-china-talks-sketch-out-rare-earths-tariff-pause-for-trump-and-xi-to-consider</link><description>Top Chinese and US economic officials on Sunday hashed out the framework of a trade deal for US President Donald Trump and Chinese President Xi Jinping to decide on later this week that would pause steeper American tariffs and Chinese rare earths export controls, US officials said.
US Treasury Sec</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 19:01:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New govt pay scale may cost Tk 700b more yearly</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/new-govt-pay-scale-may-cost-tk-700b-more-yearly</link><description>An initial estimate by the National Pay Commission (NPC) suggests the new government pay scale would require around Tk 700 billion more annually, including a hike in pensions, gratuities and medical allowances.



The amount is equivalent to nearly three months of the government's tax revenue c</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 19:16:04 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>