<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 11:18:36 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Commoners facing the brunt of winter vegetable price spiral</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/commoners-facing-the-brunt-of-winter-vegetable-price-spiral</link><description>Unseasonal early-November rainfall has pushed up winter vegetable prices across Rajshahi, and Sylhet districts piling pressure on consumers already battling against the rising living costs.
Our Rajshahi correspondent reports: Untimely downpour in early-November caused extensive damage to winter ve</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 06:38:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gaibandha farmer makes cattle feed out of banana stems</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/gaibandha-farmer-makes-cattle-feed-out-of-banana-stems</link><description>GAIBANDHA, Nov 20: A farmer of remote Hazirhat in Sundarganj has been using banana plant's stems, or portions forming the trunk-like structure, to produce a new processed fodder item for cattle, and addressing feed shortage in the area.
The fodder from banana stalks are as cost effective as it is</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 06:53:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Three DU students injured after leaping from hall buildings amid quake panic</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/three-du-students-injured-after-leaping-from-hall-buildings-amid-quake-panic</link><description>Three students of Dhaka University have been injured after they leapt from the three-storey Hajji Muhammad Mohsin Hall and the four-storey Muktijoddha Ziaur Rahman Hall in panic as a strong quake rattled Bangladesh on Friday.
A student from Muktijoddha Ziaur Rahman Hall is believed to have broken</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 07:08:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>FEAB Foundation holds seminar on food and agribusiness development, innovation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/feab-foundation-holds-seminar-on-food-and-agribusiness-development-innovation</link><description>The FEAB Foundation organised its 7th International Seminar on Thursday (November 20) at the International Convention City Bashundhara (ICCB) in Dhaka to promote food and agribusiness development, safe food production, and technology-driven innovation. The event coincided with the opening of the 13</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 08:30:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Earthquake: Infant dies as wall collapses in Narayanganj</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/earthquake-infant-dies-as-wall-collapses-in-narayanganj</link><description>A 10-month-old infant has been killed after a wall collapsed in a building in Narayanganj’s Rupganj during Friday’s earthquake.
Tariqul Islam, chief of Rupganj Police Station, said two other people, including the child’s mother, have been injured in the incident in the Golakandai</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 09:00:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt closely monitoring earthquake aftermath in Bangladesh: Chief adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-closely-monitoring-earthquake-aftermath-in-bangladesh-chief-adviser</link><description>Chief Adviser Prof Muhammad Yunus has said the government is aware of public concern and panic caused by the earthquake that jolted Dhaka and other parts of Bangladesh on Friday morning.
In a statement, the Chief Adviser said the situation is being closely monitored, and all relevant departments h</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 09:15:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Vietnam leads ASEAN in consumer optimism: UOB</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/global/vietnam-leads-asean-in-consumer-optimism-uob</link><description>Vietnam continues to lead the Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN) in consumer optimism, supported by a positive economic outlook and confidence in personal finances, Vietnam News Agency reported Friday, citing a study by Singapore-based United Overseas Bank (UOB).
Vietnam posted the hig</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 09:30:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Man held over murder of Jubo Dal leader dies in police custody</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/man-held-over-murder-of-jubo-dal-leader-dies-in-police-custody</link><description>A man arrested in connection with the killing of Jubo Dal leader Golam Kibria in Dhaka’s Pallabi has reportedly died while in the custody of the Detective Branch (DB) of police.
The Dhaka Metropolitan Police (DMP) said that 40-year-old Moktar Hossain was declared dead at Dhaka Medical Colleg</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 09:40:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Powerful earthquake leaves five dead, scores injured across Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/powerful-earthquake-leaves-five-dead-scores-injured-across-bangladesh</link><description>At least five people were killed and scores of others, including children and the elderly, were injured when a 5.7-magnitude earthquake struck Dhaka and several other parts of the country on Friday morning.
Thirteen people were injured after the railing of a building collapsed on them in the Kosha</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 09:55:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hand bombs found on metro rail tracks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/unexploded-hand-bombs-recovered-from-dhaka-metro-line</link><description>Police have recovered two unexploded hand bombs from the elevated metro rail track near the Kazipara station in Dhaka.
The objects were discovered on Friday morning on the flat section of track between pillars No. 288 and 289.
Cleaners working in the area spotted the devices around 8:30am on Frid</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 10:10:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CA expresses profound grief over earthquake casualties</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ca-expresses-profound-grief-over-earthquake-casualties</link><description>Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus on Friday expressed profound shock and sorrow at the reports of deaths and injuries in house collapses and other incidents triggered by a powerful earthquake in several districts across the country.
In a condolence message released by his Press Wing this afte</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 10:25:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khaleda to attend Armed Forces Day reception</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/khaleda-to-attend-armed-forces-day-reception</link><description>BNP Chairperson and former Prime Minister Khaleda Zia will attend the Armed Forces Day reception at Senakunja on Friday afternoon.
The BNP chief is scheduled to leave her Gulshan residence for Senakunja around 3pm, said BNP Media Cell member Sayrul Kabir Khan.
He said Khaleda’s medical boar</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 10:40:03 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>