<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 06:38:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>NCP marches towards Indian HC seeking justice for Felani killing</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ncp-marches-towards-indian-hc-seeking-justice-for-felani-killing</link><description>Police have stopped the National Citizens Party's (NCP) 'Anti-Hegemony March' as it advanced toward the Indian High Commission (HC), demanding justice for Felani Khatun, who was killed at the border.
Dhaka Metropolitan North unit of NCP organised the the programme to mark the 15th anniversary of k</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 03:40:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shibir sweeps top three JnUCSU posts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/shibir-sweeps-top-three-jnucsu-posts</link><description>Candidates backed by Islami Chhatra Shibir have captured all three top posts in the Jagannath University Central Students’ Union (JnUCSU), cementing the group’s dominance in campus politics amid a shifting national landscape.
Results declared late on Wednesday night showed Riazul Islam</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 03:55:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Electoral process to be restored with next polls: EC Abul Fazal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/electoral-process-to-be-restored-with-next-polls-ec-abul-fazal</link><description>The upcoming 13th parliamentary election is going to be the beginning of the restoration of the electoral process in the country, Election Commissioner (EC) Abul Fazal Md Sanaullah said on Wednesday.
"If I say metaphorically, it (the 13th national election) is like taking a derailed train back on</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 04:10:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Labour leaders propose 15-point manifesto for workers ahead of polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/labour-leaders-propose-15-point-manifesto-for-workers-ahead-of-polls</link><description>Labour leaders have proposed a 15-point workers' manifesto to political parties, urging them to prioritise workers' rights in their respective election manifestos for the upcoming national election.
They observed that although political change in Bangladesh is often achieved through the sacrifices</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 04:25:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ADSM demands release of Mahdi Hasan, Surabhi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/adsm-demands-release-of-mahdi-hasan-surabhi</link><description>The Anti-Discrimination Student Movement has announced a three-point demand, including unconditional release of its Habiganj district unit Member Secretary Mahdi Hasan and 'July fighter' Tahrima Jannat Surabhi.
The President of the organisation Rifat Rashid made the announced the programmes at a p</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 04:40:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mobile internet subscriptions fall to two-year low</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/mobile-internet-subscriptions-fall-to-two-year-low</link><description>Mobile internet subscriptions in Bangladesh declined to their lowest level in more than two years in November 2025, highlighting a growing disconnect between headline mobile connectivity and actual data usage amid economic stress and regulatory tightening.
Official data from the Bangladesh Telecom</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 04:55:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Australia win Ashes series 4-1 with a five-wicket victory in Sydney</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/australia-win-ashes-series-4-1-with-a-five-wicket-victory-in-sydney</link><description>Mitchell Starc took 31 wickets. Travis Head posted three centuries and tallied 629 runs. Alex Carey completed 28 dismissals.
The bowling, batting and fielding performances feature highly on the all-time lists for Aussies in the Ashes, underscoring Australia’s dominance in the 4-1 series win</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 05:10:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC receives 295 review appeals against nomination decisions</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ec-receives-295-review-appeals-against-nomination-decisions</link><description>A total of 131 appeals seeking review of nomination papers were filed with the Election Commission (EC) on Wednesday.
Of these, 128 challenged decisions against candidates, while three were filed against valid candidates.
With the latest submissions, the total number of appeals has reached 295.</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 05:25:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>JAGANNATHPUR UPAZILA OF SUNAMGANJ: Work on water supply project drags on even after seven years</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/jagannathpur-upazila-of-sunamganj-work-on-water-supply-project-drags-on-even-after-seven-years</link><description>SYLHET, Jan 07: Work on the much-talked about water supply project in Jagannathpur upazila headquarters of Sunamganj district could not be completed even in seven years after its original timeline, causing serious commotion among the town dwellers. The officials concerned also failed to say when it</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 05:40:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Blanket distribution provides warmth to the poor in Manikganj</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/blanket-distribution-provides-warmth-to-the-poor-in-manikganj</link><description>MANIKGANJ, Jan 07: Milon Dashi Sarker, a widowed elderly woman in her eighties of Babur Hati village, barely manages to bear the cost of her living. She is one of the 3,000 impoverished people of Dhulsura Union in Manikganj's Harirampur Upazila, who received a blanket from a business platform to ke</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 05:55:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Man dies ‘while making’ crude bomb in Shariatpur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/man-dies-while-making-crude-bomb-in-shariatpur</link><description>A man has been killed in a crude bomb explosion in Zajira upazila of Shariatpur.
Police believe the man died while making a crude bomb when it exploded early Thursday in the Mulai Beparikandi area of Bilaspur union.
The victim has been identified as Sohan Bepari, 32, son of Delwar Bepari of the n</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 06:10:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Barcelona maul Bilbao 5-0 to reach Spanish Super Cup final</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/barcelona-maul-bilbao-5-0-to-reach-spanish-super-cup-final</link><description>Fermin Lopez scored one goal and laid on two more as Barcelona tore through Athletic Bilbao to record a 5-0 victory in their Spanish Super Cup semi-final played in Jeddah, Saudi Arabia on Wednesday, extending the Catalans’ winning run to nine matches.
Raphinha scored twice while Ferran Torre</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 06:25:53 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>