<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 05:22:05 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Govt to construct 90 cyclone shelters in 12 districts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/govt-to-construct-90-cyclone-shelters-in-12-districts</link><description>The government has taken a move to construct 90 three-storey cyclone shelters in 47 upazilas of  12 districts under the Khulna, Barishal, and Chattogram divisions as part of preparedness for the disaster-prone region. 
Each shelter will have a total floor area of 1,272 square metres and</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 02:37:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump meets Japan's first female prime minister</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-meets-japans-first-female-prime-minister</link><description>US President Donald Trump is meeting with Japan's newly elected, ultraconservative leader in Tokyo during one of the busiest days of his Asia trip, the itinerary of which includes speaking to U.S. troops aboard an aircraft carrier and mingling with business leaders.
Just days after taking office,</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 02:52:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Man commits suicide during video call with expatriate wife</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/man-commits-suicide-during-video-call-with-expatriate-wife</link><description>A man in Thakurgaon committed suicide on Monday while on a video call with his wife, who lives in Italy.
The deceased was identified as Shamim Akhtar, 41, son of Pojir Uddin. He was known in the area as a theatre worker for his acting with a local drama group, reports UNB.
The incident took place</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 03:07:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hurricane Melissa begins lashing Jamaica</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/hurricane-melissa-begins-lashing-jamaica</link><description>Hurricane Melissa began lashing Jamaica with violent gusts on Monday as the US National Hurricane Centre upgraded it to a Category 5 storm packing sustained winds of 165 mph, the largest on record to slam into the Caribbean island.
Cuba, the eastern Bahamas and Turks and Caicos also lie in the exp</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 03:37:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two killed in shootout over land in Rajshahi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/two-killed-in-shootout-over-land-in-rajshahi</link><description>Two people have died and two others suffered injuries after being shot by a rival group during a clash over the occupation of char lands at the Padma River’s confluence in Rajshahi’s Bagha Upazila.
Bagha Police Station Inspector Suprabhat Mandal said that the incident occurred on Monda</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 03:52:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>16 killed after bus plunges off Bolivia mountain road</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/16-killed-after-bus-plunges-off-bolivia-mountain-road</link><description>At least 16 people were killed and 36 others injured on Monday after an interprovincial bus veered off a steep mountain road and fell more than 600 meters in Bolivia's central department of Cochabamba, police said.
The injured, including the 23-year-old driver, were taken to hospitals in Quillacol</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 04:07:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Man dies as lorry crashes into train in Chattogram</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/man-dies-as-lorry-crashes-into-train-in-chattogram</link><description>An elderly man has died after a freight train collided with a lorry in the Sagorika area of Chattogram city.
The accident occurred on the railway line adjacent to the Bir Shrestho Flight Lieutenant Matiur Rahman Cricket Stadium in Pahartali Thana around 4:30 am on Tuesday.
The deceased, identifie</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 04:22:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two killed in underground explosion at Australian silver mine</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/two-killed-in-underground-explosion-at-australian-silver-mine</link><description>Two workers were killed and another injured in an explosion at the recently reopened Polymetals Resources-owned Endeavor silver, zinc and lead mine in Australia on Tuesday, forcing the temporary suspension of operations.
Emergency services were called to the remote mining town of Cobar in the stat</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 04:37:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Here's what happens to your body when clocks 'fall back' an hour</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/heres-what-happens-to-your-body-when-clocks-fall-back-an-hour</link><description>Plan on a glorious extra hour of sleep as most of America “falls back” into standard time. But make sure to get outside for some morning sun, too — it’ll help your body clock reset faster.
Daylight saving time ends at 2 a.m. local time Sunday, which means you should set you</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 05:07:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cyclone ‘Montha’ over Bay likely to intensify, cross Andhra coast by evening</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cyclone-montha-over-bay-likely-to-intensify-cross-andhra-coast-by-evening</link><description>The cyclonic storm ‘Montha’ over the Westcentral Bay and adjoining Southwest Bay of Bengal is likely to move north-northwestwards and intensify further into a severe cyclonic storm.
 
It is expected to cross the Andhra Pradesh coast of India by Tuesday evening or night, said a sp</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 05:22:05 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>