<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 06:35:33 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Sramik Karmachari Oikya Parishad to blockade Ctg port tomorrow</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/sramik-karmachari-oikya-parishad-to-blockade-ctg-port-tomorrow</link><description>CHATTOGRAM, Nov 24: Leaders of the Sramik Karmachari Oikya Parishad (SKOP) will impose a three-hour blockade of the Chittagong Port beginning at 10:00 am tomorrow, as their meeting with officials of Chittagong Port Authority (CPA) failed on Monday.
CPA Secretary Omar Faruk, however, said that the</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 03:56:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>France seeks to boost investment in BD</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/france-seeks-to-boost-investment-in-bd</link><description>France has expressed strong interest in expanding its investment footprint in Bangladesh, particularly in the pharmaceutical and Information and Communication Technology (ICT) sectors.
French Ambassador Jean-Marc Serre-Charlet made the commitment during a meeting with Commerce Adviser Sk Bashir Ud</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 04:11:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>200 sued, but none named, over attack on followers of Baul Abul Sarkar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/200-sued-but-none-named-over-attack-on-followers-of-baul-abul-sarkar</link><description>A case has been filed against 200 unidentified individuals in connection with the attack on followers of Baul artiste Abul Sarkar, police said on Monday evening.
Md Aminul Islam, Inspector (Investigation) of Manikganj Sadar Police Station, said injured Baul artiste Abdul Alim filed the case. The a</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 04:26:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Include water issues in election manifesto</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/include-water-issues-in-election-manifesto</link><description>International Farakka Committee (IFC) Bangladesh called on all the political parties to include the country's most pressing water issues in their election manifestoes.
They made the call at a press briefing in the city on Monday, says a press release.
IFC New York Chairman Sayed Tipu Sultan and I</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 04:41:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>'Only political govt can control commodity prices successfully'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/only-political-govt-can-control-commodity-prices-successfully</link><description>Finance Adviser Dr Salehuddin Ahmed on Monday said controlling commodity prices by engaging administrative officials is difficult while a political government is more successful in this regard.
"You can't resolve these (price controls) by involving administration. This can be done by a political g</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 03:56:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>One-third of Dhaka's street boys sexually exploited, study reveals</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/one-third-of-dhakas-street-boys-sexually-exploited-study-reveals</link><description>Almost a third of street-involved boys in Dhaka are victims of survival-driven sexual exploitation, according to landmark national research released on Monday by The Freedom Fund in collaboration with government agencies, research institutions, and leading child protection organisations.
The findi</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 04:11:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Call for interoperable governance, ethical data practices and people-centred digital shift</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/call-for-interoperable-governance-ethical-data-practices-and-people-centred-digital-shift</link><description>Discussants at a session titled "From Silos to Systems: Rewiring the Global Data Order" stressed the urgent need for interoperable governance, ethical data practices and people-centred digital transformation.
Speaking at the fourth edition of the Bay of Bengal Conversation (BoBC) 2025, held in Dha</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 04:26:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jashore's date sap and molasses: A sweet legacy worth Tk 1.0b</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/jashores-date-sap-and-molasses-a-sweet-legacy-worth-tk-10b</link><description>BENAPOLE, Nov 24: Jashore's century-old heritage of date palm sap and molasses continues to hold strong appeal-both across the country and abroad.
This long-standing reputation has given rise to the popular phrase "Jashorer Jash, Khejur-er Rosh" (Jashore's glory lies in its date palm sap). With th</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 04:41:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Drive for full interoperable payment system sans sops</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/drive-for-full-interoperable-payment-system-sans-sops</link><description>After hiccups on journey for a cashless society, the regulator now signs deal with Gates Foundation for backbone installation to fully implement interoperable payment system.
Under the broader objective, the central bank signed a virtual agreement with the Gates Foundation to have its mojaloop ope</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 04:56:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Manikganj farmers showcase seed bank at Nabanna Festival</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/manikganj-farmers-showcase-seed-bank-at-nabanna-festival</link><description>MANIKGANJ, Nov 24: Farmers showcased their seed bank of traditional seeds during the "Field Day and Nabanna Festival" at Barundi village of Hatipara in Manikganj Sadar Upazila.
With the slogan "Practice Agroecology, Preserve Seed Diversity", the event was organised on Monday afternoon by the Barun</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 05:11:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ICB fund injection drives DSE back above 5,000 after 3 weeks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/icb-fund-injection-drives-dse-back-above-5000-after-3-weeks</link><description>The benchmark equity index of the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) crossed the 5,000-mark threshold after three weeks on Monday, largely supported by the Investment Corporation of Bangladesh (ICB).
The state-run investment bank began injecting funds into the market this week after receiving Tk 10 billio</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 05:26:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Australian far-right senator wears burqa to parliament, sparking outrage</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/australian-far-right-senator-wears-burqa-to-parliament-sparking-outrage</link><description>Australian far-right Senator Pauline Hanson wore a burqa to Parliament on Monday as a political prop in her push to ban the Muslim garment in public, sparking accusations of racism from Muslim senators over the stunt.
Hanson wore the burqa shortly after she was denied permission to introduce a bil</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 05:41:24 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>