<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 04:23:04 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>CEC calls for support of all to ensure level-playing field in election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cec-calls-for-support-of-all-to-ensure-level-playing-field-in-election</link><description>Chief Election Commissioner (CEC) A M M Nasir Uddin has called for cooperation of all the stakeholders, including the media, to ensure a level-playing field in the upcoming election.
"We have to hold a credible national election with the support of all. We want to hold it nationally. It's not poss</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 00:45:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>RUCSU campaigns resume, EC extends deadline by 10 days</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/rucsu-campaigns-resume-ec-extends-deadline-by-10-days</link><description>After a 15-day halt due to protest-initiated shutdown of the university and Durga Puja vacation, candidates of Rajshahi University Central Students' Union (RUCSU) polls restarted their campaign in full throttle once again on Monday for the election scheduled for October 16.
Meanwhile, the election</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 01:00:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CUCSU: Campaigns gain momentum</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/cucsu-campaigns-gain-momentum</link><description>Candidates' campaign for the Chittagong University Central Students' Union (CUCSU) and hall council elections have gained momentum after it was commenced following the publication of the final list of the candidates on September 25.
The candidates from different panels, along with independent cont</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 01:15:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Land ministry's Tk 7.77b ‘Gucchagram-Phase III’ project proposal sent back</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/land-ministrys-tk-777b-gucchagram-phase-iii-project-proposal-sent-back</link><description>The Planning Commission (PC) has sent back the Land Ministry's project proposal on "Gucchagram - Phase III" worth Tk 7.77 billion, attributing reasons to inclusion of unnecessary components, inflated costs for goods and services, and inadequate identification of targeted beneficiaries.
The Develop</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 01:30:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>RU entry tests to begin on Jan 16</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/ru-entry-tests-to-begin-on-jan-16</link><description>The Rajshahi University (RU) authorities have set January 16, 2026, as the starting date for its undergraduate admission tests for the 2025-26 academic session.
For the first time, the admission test will be held simultaneously at public university campuses located in Rajshahi, Dhaka, Chattogram,</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 01:45:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fire at Sadarghat wholesale market</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fire-at-sadarghat-wholesale-market</link><description>An incident of fire happened at a wholesale market in the capital's Sadarghat area on Monday. However, there was no report of casualties.
An official at Fire Service and Civil Defence office said the fire broke out at around 8:05 am. Five units of fire-fighters rushed to the spot and doused the fl</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 02:00:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Homestead cultivation becomes a game changer for womenfolk</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/homestead-cultivation-becomes-a-game-changer-for-womenfolk</link><description>Once an ordinary rural community, Chandopara- a small village under Jahanabad union in Mohanpur upazila of Rajshahi - is now widely known as a "ginger village."
The reason? Almost every homestead in the village is now covered with rows of green ginger plants sprouting from sacks, carefully nurture</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 02:30:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Flash flood triggers woes in five Lalmonirhat upazilas</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/flash-flood-triggers-woes-in-five-lalmonirhat-upazilas</link><description>Flash floods have hit at least 20,000 families residing in the low lying areas of Lalmonirhat's five upazilas due to heavy rainfall and onrush of upstream waters in the Teesta and Dharla rivers.
Road communication were disrupted in many areas due to waterlogging, while croplands, ponds, other wate</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 02:45:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IBC seeks changes in proposed trade union registration rules</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ibc-seeks-changes-in-proposed-trade-union-registration-rules</link><description>IndustriaLL Bangladesh Council (IBC) demanded changes in the proposed trade union registration requirements recommending 10 to 300 workers' representation depending on the size of the factories.
Its other proposals included six months maternity leaves for all establishments, 30 days notice period</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 03:00:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BGMEA to develop AI-enabled ESG compliance framework</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bgmea-to-develop-ai-enabled-esg-compliance-framework</link><description>Bangladesh Garment Manufacturers and Exporters Association (BGMEA) will develop an AI-enabled ESG compliance framework namely 'digital factory passport' to strengthen transparency, accountability, and global competitiveness across country's garment industry.
In this connection, BGMEA and Digital B</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 03:15:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Final list of candidates for CCCI election announced</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/final-list-of-candidates-for-ccci-election-announced</link><description>The final list of the candidates for the election of the Chittagong Chamber of Commerce and Industry (CCCI) board of directors has been announced by the Election Board formed by the Ministry of Commerce (Trade Organisation-1).
According to the final list of valid candidates released on Sunday, six</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 03:30:43 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>