<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 12:40:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Restoration work of 44 ponds, waterbodies begin in Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/restoration-work-of-44-ponds-waterbodies-begin-in-dhaka</link><description>The government on Saturday launched restoration work on 44 ponds(khas) and waterbodies in Dhaka and its outskirts, aiming to rebuild and preserve key waterbodies, protect natural drainage system and strengthen environmental balance.
Environment Adviser Syeda Rizwana Hasan inaugurated the climate r</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 09:05:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A new Bangladesh is aspiration of July Uprising: Rizvi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/a-new-bangladesh-is-aspiration-of-july-uprising-rizvi</link><description>BNP Senior Joint Secretary General Ruhul Kabir Rizvi today (Saturday) said that the aspiration of the July Uprising is a new Bangladesh.
He said, "The self-sacrifice and aspiration of the martyrs in the July Uprising is a new Bangladesh. A new Bangladesh where no fascist will ever be born again, w</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 09:20:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Indonesia landslide kills 6 in Central Java, 17 missing, state media says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/indonesia-landslide-kills-6-in-central-java-17-missing-state-media-says</link><description>A landslide in Indonesia's Central Java killed six people with 17 missing, state news agency Antara reported on Saturday, after prolonged, heavy rains.
The landslide on Thursday in the city of Cilacap buried a dozen houses in Cibeunying village, Antara said, citing disaster official Budi Irawan.</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 09:35:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ISU hosts seminar to enhance textile students’ professional skills</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/isu-hosts-seminar-to-enhance-textile-students-professional-skills</link><description>A seminar titled “Essential Skills for a Successful Textile Engineer” was organized by the ISU Textile Club of International Standard University (ISU) on Thursday afternoon at the university’s Mohakhali campus.
The event aimed to enhance students’ professional competencies</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 09:50:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hero Alam arrested on charges of attempting to murder his former wife</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hero-alam-arrested-on-charges-of-attempting-to-murder-his-former-wife</link><description>Police have arrested popular content creator Hero Alam at his office in Ulon, Hatirjheel, in connection with an attempt to murder case filed by his former wife Ria Monir.
On Saturday, Dhaka Metropolitan Police Tejgaon Deputy Commissioner Ibne Mizan said Alom was sent to court under the warrant, re</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 10:05:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Employers prioritising problem-solving skills over academic achievement: Dr Fouzul Kabir</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/employers-prioritising-problem-solving-skills-over-academic-achievement-dr-fouzul-kabir</link><description>Securing employment based solely on academic results has become increasingly difficult, as employers now prioritise problem-solving abilities, said Dr Muhammad Fouzul Kabir Khan, Adviser to the Interim Government for the Ministries of Road Transport and Bridges, Railways, and Power, Energy and Mine</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 10:20:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>9-day security plan worked out for peaceful national election: Home Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/9-day-security-plan-worked-out-for-peaceful-national-election-home-adviser</link><description>Home Affairs Adviser Lt Gen (retd) Md Jahangir Alam Chowdhury on Saturday said that a special law enforcement and security deployment plan will be in place for nine days over the upcoming national election.
“The plan includes five days prior to the election, one day on the election day, and</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 11:00:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dismembered body: DB contradicts RAB, describes murder as ‘love triangle’ gone wrong</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/dismembered-body-db-contradicts-rab-describes-murder-as-love-triangle-gone-wrong</link><description>Detective Branch officers say the killing of Rangpur businessman Ashraful Haque, whose dismembered body was found stuffed in two blue plastic drums near the High Court, stemmed from a “love-related dispute”, based on the account provided by the key suspect Jarezul Islam.
Their claim di</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 11:15:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prime Bank hosts seminar on Financial Inclusion and Youth Empowerment at BUP</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/prime-bank-hosts-seminar-on-financial-inclusion-and-youth-empowerment-at-bup</link><description>Prime Bank PLC., in collaboration with Bangladesh University of Professionals (BUP), organized a seminar recently titled “Financial Inclusion: Engaging &amp; Inspiring Youth in Banking” under its flagship PrimeAcademia initiative.
With special participation from Lieutenant Colonel S M Zoba</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 11:30:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP to prioritise water-sharing, end ‘Indian hegemony’: Fakhrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-to-prioritise-water-sharing-end-indian-hegemony-fakhrul</link><description>BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir on Saturday said his party will give top priority to resolving longstanding water-sharing disputes and stopping what he described as ‘Indian hegemony’ with Bangladesh.
Talking to reporters after inspecting a rubber dam built on the Maha</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 12:00:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tourist goes missing while bathing at Bandarban’s Nafakhum</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tourist-goes-missing-while-bathing-at-bandarbans-nafakhum</link><description>A tourist has gone missing after reportedly going down to bathe at the Nafakhum waterfall, a restricted and remote tourist spot in Thanchi Upazila of Bandarban, according to police.
The incident occurred on Friday afternoon, according to Thanchi Police Station chief Nasir Uddin. The missing man, I</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 12:15:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Limon placed on five-day remand over judge’s son killing</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/limon-placed-on-five-day-remand-over-judges-son-killing</link><description>A magistrate court in Dhaka on Saturday placed Limon Mian on a five-day remand in the killing of a judge’s son after intruding into the resident at Terakhadia area in the city on Thursday last.
Around 2.30 pm on Saturday, police produced Limon before the Metropolitan Magistrate Court seeking</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 12:30:47 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>