<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 02:47:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>World Bank to back $8.5b 'Blue Network' megaproject</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/world-bank-to-back-85b-blue-network-megaproject</link><description>The World Bank has agreed to lend US$600 million in the first go to support the interim government's flagship 'Blue Network Programme' that seeks to restore to life and protect all rivers, canals and drainage channels in and around Dhaka.
Officials say the initiative aims to create an integrated</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 18:24:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Saif, Saifuddin star in T20 sweep of Afghans</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/saif-and-saifuddin-propel-bangladesh-to-clean-sweep-of-afghanistan-t20-series</link><description>Bangladesh completed a 3-0 sweep of Afghanistan in the T20 series in a 6-wicket rout in the third game, with Saif Hassan blasting a swashbuckling 64* after Saifuddin returned a confining 3-15 in Sharjah.
Opting to bowl first on Sunday, Bangladesh bowlers never allowed Afghan batters to break free</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 20:37:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Parties agree on referendum to implement July Charter</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/parties-agree-on-referendum-to-implement-july-charter</link><description>A major breakthrough comes in the prolonged post-uprising national-consensus-building process with the deadlock over the implementation modality of the July Charter unscrewed as the squabbling politicians agree on referendum.
The political parties and the National Consensus Commission, however, ha</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 23:49:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NBR's field-level tax zones asked to strengthen their IICs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/nbrs-field-level-tax-zones-asked-to-strengthen-their-iics</link><description>The National Board of Revenue (NBR) has instructed its all field-level tax zones to strengthen their Intelligence and Investigation Cells (IICs) for expediting recovery of evaded taxes and enhancing revenue collection by preventing tax evasion.
The directive issued from the office of the Member Mo</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:04:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Remittances hit $2.69b in Sept, 5th-highest monthly inflow</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/remittances-hit-269b-in-sept-5th-highest-monthly-inflow</link><description>Bangladesh received US$2.69 billion in remittances in September, the fifth-highest monthly inflow on record, signalling a rebound in foreign-currency earnings.
The rise in remittance earnings offers a much-needed respite for the economy, which has been grappling with multiple macroeconomic challen</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:19:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Q1 exports rise, offset Sept fall</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/q1-exports-rise-offset-sept-fall</link><description>Bangladesh experiences ups and downs in export performance in the first quarter of the current fiscal year with the three-month earnings posting an overall growth of 5.64 per cent to US$12.31 billion, outweighing a monthly fall in September.
The country's merchandise exports recorded a 4.61-percen</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:34:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ibn Sina posts 5.5pc profit drop, offers record dividend</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/ibn-sina-posts-55pc-profit-drop-offers-record-dividend</link><description>The Ibn Sina Pharmaceutical Industry has declared a record-high 64 per cent cash dividend for the financial year 2025, even as it saw a 5.5 per cent drop in annual profit.
According to a stock exchange filing on Sunday, the listed pharmaceutical company reported a profit of Tk 633 million for FY'2</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:49:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>MJL to invest Tk 2.14b in commercial property</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/mjl-to-invest-tk-214b-in-commercial-property</link><description>MJL Bangladesh PLC, a listed company, in partnership with EC Holdings, is set to invest over Tk 2.14 billion in a commercial property project located on Gulshan Avenue in Dhaka.
The board of directors of MJL Bangladesh, at a meeting held on September 30, approved the investment decision as part of</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 01:04:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>First bilateral chamber with ME countries to be launched tomorrow</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/first-bilateral-chamber-with-me-countries-to-be-launched-tomorrow</link><description>The Saudi Arabia-Bangladesh Chamber of Commerce and Industry (SABCCI) will officially be launched tomorrow (Tuesday). It will be the first bilateral chamber with a Middle Eastern nation.
Already, the newly formed chamber has organised a three-day Saudi Arabia-Bangladesh Business Summit that will b</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 01:19:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Summit challenges LNG deal cancellation in HC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/summit-challenges-lng-deal-cancellation-in-hc</link><description>Summit Oil and Shipping Company Limited (SOSCL), a subsidiary of Summit Group, has filed a writ petition with the High Court (HC) challenging the government's cancellation of its long-term liquefied natural gas (LNG) supply contract.
The petition seeks a rule asking the respondents to explain why</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 01:34:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Palli Sanchay Bank seeks 10-yr tax, VAT exemption</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/palli-sanchay-bank-seeks-10-yr-tax-vat-exemption</link><description>State-owned Palli Sanchay Bank (PSB) has sought a 10-year exemption from income tax and Value Added Tax (VAT) to facilitate investments aimed at socio-economic development of poor rural people.
The bank's Managing Director (MD) Salma Banu recently requested the government to take necessary steps t</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 01:49:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BB issues master circular on outward remittances</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/bb-issues-master-circular-on-outward-remittances</link><description>Bangladesh Bank (BB) has issued a comprehensive master circular on outward remittances, consolidating all existing regulatory instructions into a single reference document.
The circular, released on September 30, will remain effective for one year from the date of issuance.
It aims to simplify an</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 02:04:46 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>