<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 11:16:44 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Govt moves to digitise visa fee payments: BIDA chief</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-moves-to-digitise-visa-fee-payments-bida-chief</link><description>Executive Chairman (State Minister) of the Bangladesh Investment Development Authority (BIDA) Chowdhury Ashik Mahmud Bin Harun, on Wednesday said that the government is undertaking significant efforts to modernise its visa system by digitising fee payments and refining overall visa policy.
"Substa</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 08:00:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>All political parties to sign July Charter, hopes Asif Nazrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/all-political-parties-to-sign-july-charter-hopes-asif-nazrul</link><description>Law Adviser Dr Asif Nazrul on Wednesday said that all political parties participated sincerely in the discussions on the July Charter and are expected to sign the document in the same spirit.
“'I think all political parties have participated in this discussion with dedication. I do not</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 08:30:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCC to hold ‘emergency meeting’ with parties</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/national-consensus-commission-to-hold-emergency-meeting-with-parties</link><description>The National Consensus Commission is holding an emergency meeting with political parties and alliances.
The meeting is scheduled at 6pm at Dhaka’s Foreign Service Academy on Wednesday, a day after it sent a draft of the National July Charter-2025 to the different parties, bdnews24.com report</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 08:45:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hegseth urges allies to boost spending on US weapons for Kyiv</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/hegseth-urges-allies-to-boost-spending-on-us-weapons-for-kyiv</link><description>US Secretary of Defense Pete Hegseth on Wednesday called on NATO allies to increase spending on purchases of US weapons for Ukraine, following a report that highlighted a sharp decline in military support for Kyiv in July and August.
"You get peace when you are strong. Not when you use strong word</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 09:15:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Suspicion might be behind Kalabagan murder: Police</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/suspicion-might-be-behind-kalabagan-murder-police</link><description>Husband’s suspicion over his wife’s alleged extramarital affair might be the reason behind the killing of a woman at Kalabgan in the capital, said police.
Masud Alam, deputy commissioner of Dhaka Metropolitan Police (Ramna Division) said this at a press briefing at DMP media centre aft</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 09:30:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Australian Minister offers further assistance for Bangladesh election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/australian-minister-offers-further-assistance-for-bangladesh-election</link><description>Australian Minister for International Development and Multicultural Affairs Dr Anne Aly on Wednesday pledged her country’s continued support to the Election Commission (EC) ahead of Bangladesh’s 13th parliamentary election.
An Australian delegation, led by Dr Anne Aly, made the proposa</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 09:45:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nvidia CEO Huang welcomes return of employee held in Gaza for two years</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/nvidia-ceo-huang-welcomes-return-of-employee-held-in-gaza-for-two-years</link><description>Nvidia (NVDA.O) CEO Jensen Huang welcomed Avinatan Or from "two unimaginable years in Hamas captivity" in Gaza, saying a number of the chip giant's families had suffered losses during the war.
An electrical engineer at Nvidia in Israel, 32-year-old Or was kidnapped from the Nova music festival on</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 10:00:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Aid trucks roll into Gaza as dispute over hostage bodies is paused</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/aid-trucks-roll-into-gaza-as-dispute-over-hostage-bodies-is-paused</link><description>Russia said on Wednesday that it was closely watching events in Madagascar and hoped that bloodshed would be avoided after the military took power following weeks of youth-led protests.
Demonstrations first erupted in Madagascar on September 25 over water and power shortages and quickly escalated</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 10:15:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fund mobilisation for Rohingyas turns difficult: Shafiqul Alam</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fund-mobilisation-for-rohingyas-turns-difficult-shafiqul-alam</link><description>Highlighting the importance of channeling new funds, Chief Adviser’s Press Secretary Shafiqul Alam has said the required fund mobilisation for the Rohingyas living in Bangladesh has become difficult as many countries are not willing to fund like before.
“Recently, we have seen that fun</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 10:30:27 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>