<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 12:40:41 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Trust Bank organises knowledge sharing &amp; recognition event with BARVIDA</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/trust-bank-organises-knowledge-sharing-recognition-event-with-barvida</link><description>Trust Bank PLC, in collaboration with Bangladesh Reconditioned Vehicles Importers and Dealers Association (BARVIDA), its members, and several brand-new car importers and assemblers, recently organised a Knowledge Sharing and Recognition event.
The event was attended by Trust Bank’s Managing</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 09:44:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Amari Dhaka unveils 'Dhakaiya Dawat'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/amari-dhaka-unveils-dhakaiya-dawat</link><description>Amari Dhaka, one of the city’s leading five-star hotels renowned for its exceptional hospitality and vibrant dining experiences, has announced the launch of its latest culinary promotion — “Dhakaiya Dawat” at Amaya Food Gallery.
 
This exclusive buffet, running from O</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 09:59:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Premier Bank launches revamped website to enhance customer experience</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/premier-bank-launches-revamped-website-to-enhance-customer-experience</link><description>Premier Bank proudly launched its revamped website, aimed at enhancing customer experience and meeting the evolving needs of our clients in the digital age on Wednesday.
The event was graced by Dr. Arifur Rahman, Chairman of the Board of Directors, as the chief guest at the Premier Bank head offic</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 10:29:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pubali Bank launches ‘Banking Products Campaign’ at NU Campus</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/pubali-bank-launches-banking-products-campaign-at-nu-campus</link><description>The ‘Banking Products Campaign’ was held at the National University (NU) Campus under the initiative of the Board Bazar branch of Pubali Bank PLC, the country’s largest private bank.
This campaign was organised to make students aware of modern banking services, digital banking fa</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 10:44:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CA to visit Rome on Oct 12 to join WFP meeting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ca-to-visit-rome-on-oct-12-to-join-wfp-meeting</link><description>Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus will leave for Rome, the capital of Italy, on October 12 to join a global meeting of the World Food Programme (WFP).
Chief Adviser’s Press Secretary Shafiqul Alam disclosed the information at a press conference at the Foreign Service Academy this aftern</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 10:59:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Three Bollywood films to be made in UK from 2026, PM says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/entertainment/three-bollywood-films-to-be-made-in-uk-from-2026-pm-says</link><description>Three new Bollywood films will be made in Britain from next year, Prime Minister Keir Starmer announced during a trip to India on Wednesday.
Yash Raj, India’s leading film production and distribution company, will bring major productions to Britain from early 2026 after an eight-year break f</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 11:14:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt to modernise tax system, prioritise refunds for compliant taxpayers: NBR chairman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/govt-to-modernise-tax-system-prioritise-refunds-for-compliant-taxpayers-nbr-chairman</link><description>National Board of Revenue (NBR) Chairman Md Abdur Rahman on Wednesday said the government is working to make the country’s tax system more transparent, technology-driven and business-friendly, with a special focus on enabling tax refunds for compliant taxpayers.
“Last year, I apologise</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 11:29:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>At least 20 killed in Myanmar junta attack as paramotors widen air war</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/at-least-20-killed-in-myanmar-junta-attack-as-paramotors-widen-air-war</link><description>A 30-year-old protester was taking part in a gathering against Myanmar's ruling junta on a festival day in the central region of Sagaing on Monday when he heard the distinctive noise of fan blades cutting through the air.
Minutes later, explosives were dropped by a motorised paraglider, also known</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 11:59:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CA for resolving visa complexities to expand labour market in Eastern Europe</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ca-for-resolving-visa-complexities-to-expand-labour-market-in-eastern-europe</link><description>Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus on Wednesday emphasised resolving the existing complexities in the visa process as new labour markets of Bangladesh are being created in the Eastern European countries.
As the visa complexities have been persisting since previous governments, the Chief Advise</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 12:14:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Touhid terms Indian foreign secretary’s remark on polls ‘unwarranted’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/touhid-terms-indian-foreign-secretarys-remark-on-polls-unwarranted</link><description>Foreign Affairs Adviser Md Touhid Hossain today (Wednesday) described the recent comment made by Indian Foreign Secretary regarding the upcoming national election of Bangladesh as “completely unwarranted”, saying that it is entirely an internal affair of the country.
“I see that</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 12:29:38 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>