<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 12:47:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Police rescue ‘tortured’ Pakistani woman after 999 call in Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/police-rescue-tortured-pakistani-woman-after-999-call-in-dhaka</link><description>Police rescued a Pakistani woman who was allegedly tortured by her Bangladeshi husband and mother-in-law in Lalkuthi Borobazar area of Darussalam in Dhaka on Sunday after receiving a call through the national emergency helpline 999.
An English-speaking woman called the helpline on Sunday afternoon</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 09:34:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dengue: 6 dead, 983 hospitalised in 24 hours</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dengue-6-dead-983-hospitalised-in-24-hours</link><description>The dengue crisis in Bangladesh continues to deteriorate as six more patients died and 983 were admitted to hospitals across the country in the 24 hours leading up to Monday morning.
With the latest fatalities, the total number of deaths from the mosquito-borne disease in Bangladesh has risen to 2</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 09:49:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Strike closes pharmacies in Brahmanbaria town, patients suffer</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/strike-closes-pharmacies-in-brahmanbaria-town-patients-suffer</link><description>The “Chemist and Druggist Association” has called a strike, closing all pharmacies in Brahmanbaria town indefinitely to protest the decision to evict what it says is a legal commercial establishment allocated a location at the Brahmanbaria Government Women's College Market after declari</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 10:19:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UK-BD partnership to strengthen flood forecasting, early warning in 4 districts: Rizwana</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/uk-bd-partnership-to-strengthen-flood-forecasting-early-warning-in-4-districts-rizwana</link><description>Environment Adviser Syeda Rizwana Hasan has said the EnRICH Project will strengthen flood forecasting and early warning systems in Sylhet, Sunamganj, Cumilla, and Feni from September 2025 to March 2026.
She made the remarks on Monday while addressing a national event titled “UK-Bangladesh Co</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 10:34:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>RU admission process for 2025-26 to begin on November 20</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/ru-admission-process-for-2025-26-to-begin-on-november-20</link><description>The application process for admission to the first-year undergraduate (honours) programs at Rajshahi University (RU) for the 2025–2026 academic session will begin on November 20 and continue until December 6, according to a press release signed by Professor Akhtar Hossain Mazumder, Administra</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 10:49:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Air Chief returns home from Korea</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/air-chief-returns-home-from-korea</link><description>Chief of Air Staff of Bangladesh Air Force Air Chief Marshal Hasan Mahmood Khan returned home on Saturday wrapping up his official visit to Korea.
The chief of air staff attended the Seoul International Aerospace and Defense Exhibition (ADEX)-2025 held in the Republic of Korea, said a release of I</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 11:19:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Writ petition seeks quality check of bearing pads on Metro Rail, flyovers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/writ-petition-seeks-quality-check-of-bearing-pads-on-metro-rail-flyovers</link><description>A writ petition was filed with the High Court on Monday seeking its directives for immediate verification of the quality and safety of bearing pads installed on Dhaka Metro Rail and all flyovers in the capital.
Supreme Court lawyer Barrister Abdullah Al Mamun submitted the public interest litigati</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 12:04:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Teaching students to trade before they graduate</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/youth-and-entrepreneurship/teaching-students-to-trade-before-they-graduate</link><description>Financial literacy remains one of Bangladesh's quiet deficits. Whilst the country produces thousands of business graduates annually, a few understand portfolio construction or market mechanics before entering the workforce. Most learn through expensive mistakes or avoid equity markets entirely, p</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 12:19:28 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>