<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 07:27:30 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Venezuela under Maduro shipped gold worth $5.2 billion to Switzerland</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/venezuela-under-maduro-shipped-gold-worth-52-billion-to-switzerland</link><description>Venezuela transported gold worth almost 4.14 billion Swiss francs ($5.20 billion) to Switzerland during the early years of the leadership of ousted President Nicolas Maduro, customs data shows.
The South American country sent 113 metric tons of the precious metal to Switzerland from 2013 - when Ma</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 04:44:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gas crunch hits fertiliser output</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/gas-crunch-hits-fertiliser-output</link><description>The state-run BCIC has sought an uninterrupted supply of at least 197 million cubic feet of gas per day (MMCFD) to keep four urea fertiliser factories operational for 11 consecutive months.
The Bangladesh Chemical Industries Corporation (BCIC) recently made a proposal to the Ministry of Industries</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 04:59:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Venezuela to export $2b worth of oil to US</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/venezuela-to-export-2b-worth-of-oil-to-us</link><description>Caracas and Washington have reached a deal to export up to $2 billion worth of Venezuelan crude to the United States, US President Donald Trump said on Tuesday, a flagship negotiation that would divert supplies from China while helping Venezuela avoid deeper oil production cuts.
The agreement is a</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 04:15:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Magnitude 6.7 earthquake strikes near Baculin, Philippines</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/magnitude-67-earthquake-strikes-near-baculin-philippines</link><description>A 6.7 magnitude earthquake struck off the Philippines' southern islands on Wednesday, the US Geological Survey (USGS) said, and there were no immediate reports of damage or injuries.
USGS said the quake struck at a depth of 10 km (6 miles) around 68 km (42 miles) east of Baculin, a village in the</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 04:30:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BPC retenders SPM O&amp;M contract</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bpc-retenders-spm-om-contract</link><description>The government has renewed efforts to appoint a contractor for the operation and maintenance (O&amp;amp;M) and marine services of Bangladesh's first single-point mooring (SPM) for a five-year period.
The Tk 80-billion facility, a flagship energy infrastructure project that has remained idle despite being</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 04:45:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Melania hates my dancing: Trump</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/melania-hates-my-dancing-trump</link><description>US President Donald Trump draws cheers from supporters when he dances on stage at his political rallies, but he revealed on Tuesday that first lady Melania Trump is not a fan of dancing Donald.
"My wife hates when I do this," Trump said during a meandering speech to Republican lawmakers in Washing</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 05:00:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Clearing public perception on cybersecurity crucial ahead of polls: Debapriya</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/clearing-public-perception-on-cybersecurity-crucial-ahead-of-polls-debapriya</link><description>Noted economist Dr Debapriya Bhattacharya has called for all political parties to clear public perception on cybersecurity during their election campaigns, warning of massive digital propaganda ahead of the upcoming national elections.
He said neither the government nor the Election Commission cou</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 05:15:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh added to US visa bond scheme requiring payments of up to $15,000</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-added-to-us-visa-bond-scheme-requiring-payments-of-up-to-15000</link><description>Bangladesh has been added to a list of countries whose citizens are required to post a visa bond of up to $15,000 in order to travel to the United States.
Under the policy, applicants from listed countries who are otherwise eligible for B1/B2 visitor visas may be asked to pay a refundable bond bef</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 05:30:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh records season's lowest temperature</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-records-seasons-lowest-temperature</link><description>Bangladesh recorded the lowest temperature of the current winter season on Wednesday.
The season’s lowest temperature of 6.7 degrees Celsius was recorded in Badalgachhi upazila of Naogaon district this morning.
The bone-chilling cold, intensified by icy northern winds, has slowed daily life</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 05:45:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Early results show neck-and-neck race for JnUCSU VP post</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/early-results-show-neck-and-neck-race-for-jnucsu-vp-post</link><description>Preliminary results from seven departments in the Jagannath University Central Students’ Union (JnUCSU) election indicate a closely contested race for the post of vice-president (VP).
Candidates from the Oikkoboddho Nirbhik Jobian panel, backed by Chhatra Dal and Chhatra Odhikar Parishad, ar</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 06:00:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump freezes over $10 billion in childcare, family assistance funds to 5 US states</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-freezes-over-10-billion-in-childcare-family-assistance-funds-to-5-us-states</link><description>US President Donald Trump's administration is freezing more than $10 billion in federal childcare and family assistance funds to California, Colorado, Illinois, Minnesota and New York, the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) said, citing what it called concerns about fraud and misuse.
Th</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 06:15:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NBR launches automated online VAT refund system</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nbr-launches-automated-online-vat-refund-system</link><description>The National Board of Revenue (NBR) on Wednesday launched an automated online Value Added Tax (VAT) refund system, allowing refunds to be transferred directly to taxpayers' bank accounts, a move considered as ending long-standing delays and harassment in the refund process.
NBR Chairman Md Abdur R</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 06:30:40 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>