<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 07:20:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>DU declares closure for 15 days; students asked to leave halls by this evening</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/du-declares-closure-for-15-days-students-asked-to-leave-halls-by-this-evening</link><description>Dhaka University has been declared closed for 15 days due to an emergency situation following a recent earthquake. 
As per the announcement, students have been instructed to leave their residential halls by 5:00 pm of Sunday. The directive was issued in a notice sent on Saturday night by Acti</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 04:24:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>When low confidence overshadows skill</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/article/when-low-confidence-overshadows-skill</link><description>She made a perfect presentation-well-prepared slides, solid facts, proper research and innovative ideas. Still, when she got to the stage, her self-doubt kicked in. "What if I missed something?"-she thought. Her voice trembled; despite having well-researched solutions, she forgot to present them. T</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 04:39:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Why part-time jobs for students matter</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/article/why-part-time-jobs-for-students-matter</link><description>Bangladesh is facing a youth puzzle it has not fully solved. Nearly one-third of the population is between 15 and 29, making it one of the youngest countries in the region. We often call this a big advantage, yet many young people still struggle to find jobs and the jump from school to work takes f</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 04:54:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How AI dependency is eroding critical thinking of youths</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/article/how-ai-dependency-is-eroding-critical-thinking-of-youths</link><description>Since late 2023, the way young people interact with the internet has changed drastically. The shift has moved from seeking information to demanding instant answers. LLM-based AI applications like ChatGPT, Claude, DeepSeek, and Gemini have transformed user behaviou—today's youths no longer wan</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 05:09:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Barriers and opportunities: The role of sustainable private universities in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/analysis/barriers-and-opportunities-the-role-of-sustainable-private-universities-in-bangladesh</link><description>Private universities have become pivotal in expanding access to higher education in Bangladesh, particularly in response to rising demand and the limited capacity of public institutions. This paper examines the barriers and opportunities influencing the transformation of private universities toward</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 05:24:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Midnight clash erupts between two groups at Alia Madrasa in Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/midnight-clash-erupts-between-two-groups-at-alia-madrasa-in-dhaka</link><description>Two factions of students have clashed at the Government-Madrasah-e-Alia in Old Dhaka’s Bakshibazar in several stages.
Several students have reportedly been injured in the incident, which started around midnight on Saturday, according to Sub-Inspector Ashraful Islam of the Chawkbazar Police S</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 05:39:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hilsa prices soar further</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hilsa-prices-soar-further</link><description>Hilsa, the pride of Bangladesh’s rivers and the heart of its culinary culture, has once again slipped beyond the reach of ordinary consumers as prices surged dramatically at the century-old Mir Kadim wholesale fish market in Munshiganj.
Within just 48 hours, hilsa prices have jumped by up to</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 05:54:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DUET students among 10 injured in Gazipur fair clash</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/duet-students-among-10-injured-in-gazipur-fair-clash</link><description>At least 10 people, including students from Dhaka University of Engineering and Technology (DUET), were injured in a clash at a fair in Gazipur on Saturday night.
The incident occurred around 11:00 pm at the Army Pharma grounds of trade and cottage industry fair in Shimultoli area during a concert</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 05:54:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BB halts savings certificate, other citizen services</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/bb-halts-savings-certificate-other-citizen-services</link><description>Bangladesh Bank has suspended all citizen-facing services, including the buying, selling and encashment of national savings certificates, at all of its offices.
The halt also covers prize bond services, the exchange of torn or damaged banknotes, and A-challan transactions, officials said.
The sus</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 06:09:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Three injured as ‘Tawhidi Janata’ attack followers of Baul artiste</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/three-injured-as-tawhidi-janata-attack-followers-of-baul-artiste</link><description>Three supporters of Baul artiste Abul Sarkar have reportedly been injured in an attack by members of the “Tawhidi Janata” -- a loosely defined movement that portrays itself as a defender of Islamic morality.
Abdullah Al Mamun, the additional superintendent of Manikganj police, said tha</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 06:24:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Stocks see downward trend at opening</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/stocks-see-downward-trend-at-opening-15329</link><description>Trading at both the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) and the Chittagong Stock Exchange (CSE) opened on a downward trend on Sunday, with most listed companies seeing a decline in share prices during the first hour.
On the DSE, the benchmark DSEX index slipped by 7 points, while the Shariah-based DSES she</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 06:39:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Commonwealth chief meets CEC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/commonwealth-chief-meets-cec</link><description>Commonwealth Secretary General Shirley Botchwey has held talks with Chief Election Commissioner AMM Nasir Uddin as preparations intensify for Bangladesh's upcoming parliamentary elections and referendum.
The meeting took place at the Election Commission (EC) headquarters in Dhaka’s Agargaon</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 06:54:45 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>