<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 10:27:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Rickshaw Puller Sujon not chosen in NCP’s initial candidate list</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/rickshaw-puller-sujon-not-chosen-in-ncps-initial-candidate-list</link><description>The National Citizen Party (NCP) has announced the first phase of its preliminary list of nominated candidates in 125 constituencies for the upcoming national election.
However, the name of rickshaw-puller Sujan, who rose to fame for his iconic salute during last year's July uprising, is not inclu</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 07:07:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh to see fair, inclusive polls in February: Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-to-see-fair-inclusive-polls-in-february-adviser</link><description>Claiming that the election season is already underway across the country, Religious Affairs Adviser Dr AFM Khalid Hossain on Wednesday said the upcoming national election will be held in a festive, fair and inclusive manner.
He affirmed that the government is actively working to ensure a smooth an</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 07:22:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Is Arka Fashion Week setting the stage for a Bangladeshi fashion renaissance?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/culture/is-arka-fashion-week-setting-the-stage-for-a-bangladeshi-fashion-renaissance</link><description>We can sense a shift in the atmosphere, whether it's a weather effect or a social transformation. Arka Fashion Week, reviving the city with its style and breath of fresh air, is the latest addition to the chain.
The fashion show's triumph was visible as visitors could hardly be kept out of the c</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 07:37:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Only BNP understands what reforms Bangladesh truly need:  Mirza Abbas</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/only-bnp-understands-what-reforms-bangladesh-truly-need-mirza-abbas</link><description>BNP senior leader Mirza Abbas on Wednesday said those who talk about ‘reforms’, except BNP, do not actually know what reforms the country needs, as they are only focused on gaining power.
“Those who still speak about reforms don’t even understand what to reform. They surely</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 07:52:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Global trade to exceed 35 trln USD in 2025: UN report</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/global/global-trade-to-exceed-35-trln-usd-in-2025-un-report</link><description>The United Nations Trade and Development (UNCTAD) said on Tuesday that global trade in goods and services is expected to exceed 35 trillion U.S. dollars in 2025 for the first time.
 
Despite geopolitical tensions, higher costs, and uneven global demand, which slowed growth momentum, global t</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 08:07:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump says to make phone call to stop Thai-Cambodia fighting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/trump-says-to-make-phone-call-to-stop-thai-cambodia-fighting</link><description>Fighting between Thailand and Cambodia extended into a third day on Wednesday as US President Donald Trump said he would make a phone call to stop the conflict, after he had brokered a ceasefire in July to end a five-day battle between the Asian neighbours.
Thailand's foreign minister said in an i</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 08:22:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bagerhat keeps 4 seats, Gazipur retains 5: Appellate Division</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/bagerhat-keeps-4-seats-gazipur-retains-5-appellate-division</link><description>The Appellate Division on Wednesday ruled that Bagerhat district will retain its four parliamentary seats, while Gazipur will continue with five.
The seven-member full bench, headed by Chief Justice Dr Syed Refaat Ahmed, passed the order.
Earlier, on November 10, a High Court (HC) ruling restored</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 08:37:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Urgent reforms needed to curb VAT leakage, expand tax net: Salehuddin</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/urgent-reforms-needed-to-curb-vat-leakage-expand-tax-net-salehuddin</link><description>Finance Adviser Dr Salehuddin Ahmed has underscored the urgent need to curb VAT leakage, widen both VAT and income tax coverage, and modernise Bangladesh’s tax administration.
“Bangladesh’s economic progress depends fundamentally on its ability to mobilise domestic resources rath</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 08:52:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>4,200 kg sodium cyclamate seized at Chattogram Custom House</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/4200-kg-sodium-cyclamate-seized-at-chattogram-custom-house</link><description>An intelligence team in Chattogram Custom House has seized another consignment of prohibited artificial sweetener Sodium Cyclamate weighing 4,200 kilograms.
According to a press release issued by the National Board of Revenue (NBR) on Wednesday, the operation was carried out by the intelligence te</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 09:07:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>If India doesn't extradite Hasina, Dhaka has no real option to bring back: Adviser Touhid</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/if-india-doesnt-extradite-hasina-dhaka-has-no-real-option-to-bring-back-adviser-touhid</link><description>Bangladesh’s interim foreign affairs adviser, Mohammad Touhid Hossain, has said Dhaka has little scope to force the return of former prime minister Sheikh Hasina unless New Delhi agrees to extradite her.
Speaking to reporters at the foreign ministry on Wednesday, Hossain acknowledged Banglad</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 09:22:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CA urges UNO’s to make upcoming election ‘historic and unforgettable’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ca-urges-unos-to-make-upcoming-election-historic-and-unforgettable</link><description>Chief Adviser, Professor Muhammad Yunus, has called on Upazila Nirbahi Officers (UNOs) across the country to ensure that the upcoming national election becomes a defining moment in the nation’s history. 
Describing the post-uprising vote as an opportunity to rebuild Bangladesh, Yunus ur</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 09:37:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Asif Nazrul for safeguarding reforms for next course of advancement</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/asif-nazrul-for-safeguarding-reforms-for-next-course-of-advancement</link><description>Law, Justice and Parliamentary Affairs Adviser Dr Asif Nazrul today (Wednesday) stressed the importance of safeguarding the reforms already introduced by the interim government, saying the next course of advancement must be built on these achievements. "When we talk about reforms, a common fru</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 09:52:36 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>