<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 08:48:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Ctg EPZ factory fire tamed after 17 hours</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ctg-epz-factory-fire-tamed-after-17-hours</link><description>Emergency workers have taken control of a devastating fire that broke out at a factory building in the Chattogram Export Processing Zone (EPZ) area nearly 17 hours after it started.
The blaze, which erupted around 2:00 pm on Thursday, was brought under control around 7:25 am on Friday, according t</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 06:03:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NBR posts record Tk 908.25b revenue collection in Q1</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/nbr-posts-record-tk-90825b-revenue-collection-in-q1</link><description>The National Board of Revenue (NBR) has recorded the highest-ever revenue collection in the first quarter of any fiscal year, collecting Tk 908.25 billion (Tk 90,825 crore) during July–September of FY2025–26.
According to official data, the amount marks a significant 20.21 per cent gro</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 06:18:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India 'already cutting' Russian oil imports by 50pc after US talks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/india-already-cutting-russian-oil-imports-by-50pc-after-us-talks-white-house-official-says</link><description>The United States and India have held productive trade talks, and Indian refiners are already cutting Russian oil imports by 50 per cent, a White House official told Reuters on Thursday.
However, Indian sources said the cut was not visible yet, though it could be reflected in import numbers for De</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 06:33:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Australia may see last of Kohli, Rohit in ODI series</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/australia-may-see-last-of-kohli-rohit-in-odi-series</link><description>Australian cricket fans may have their last chance to see India batting stalwarts Virat Kohli and Rohit Sharma in action when the pair tour in the one-day international series starting in Perth on Sunday.
Boasting almost 600 ODIs between them, both 36-year-old Kohli and 38-year-old Rohit are activ</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 07:33:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka condemns killing of three Bangladeshis by mob in India’s Tripura</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dhaka-condemns-killing-of-three-bangladeshis-by-mob-in-indias-tripura</link><description>Bangladesh has strongly condemned the killing of three of its citizens in India’s north-eastern state of Tripura, calling the incident a “brutal” and “unacceptable” act that violates human rights and the rule of law.
In a statement on Friday, the Ministry of Foreign A</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 08:03:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Police disperse ‘July fighters’ from Parliament plaza ahead of July Charter signing</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/police-disperse-july-fighters-from-parliament-plaza-ahead-of-july-charter-signing</link><description>Police have cracked down on participants of last year's July Uprising near the Parliament's South Plaza, using batons, tear gas, and sound grenades to clear the area after the protesters refused to leave.
The demonstrators had gathered in front of the stage for the signing ceremony of the July Cha</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 08:33:14 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>