<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 22:21:35 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Khosru urges parties to focus on people’s mandate, not debates over consensus</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/khosru-urges-parties-to-focus-on-peoples-mandate-not-debates-over-consensus</link><description>BNP senior leader Amir Khosru Mahmud Chowdhury on Monday urged all political parties to move beyond debates over consensus and focus instead on seeking people's mandate on agreed issues through the upcoming national election.
"The charter has been signed based on whatever level of consensus was re</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 16:18:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UN team seeks roadmap for Bangladesh’s smooth LDC transition</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/un-team-seeks-roadmap-for-bangladeshs-smooth-ldc-transition</link><description>The visiting United Nations assessment team in Dhaka has asked local businesses to prepare a roadmap on the Smooth Transition Strategy (STS) to ensure Bangladesh’s sustainable graduation from the Least Developed Country (LDC) status.
In response, business leaders at a meeting on Sunday infor</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 16:33:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Primary teachers’ movement ends with assurance of 11th-grade pay scale</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/primary-teachers-movement-ends-with-assurance-of-11th-grade-pay-scale</link><description>Assistant teachers from government primary schools, who have been continuing their sit-in at Dhaka’s Central Shaheed Minar for three consecutive days and a nationwide work stoppage for two days, have announced the withdrawal of their movement after being assured of the 11th-grade pay scale.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 16:48:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ACC to submit chargesheet against former IGP Benazir over ‘illicit wealth’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/acc-to-submit-chargesheet-against-former-igp-benazir-over-illicit-wealth</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) has approved a chargesheet against fugitive former inspector general of police (IGP) Benazir Ahmed over Tk 110 million in wealth allegedly beyond his known sources of income.
The ACC Assistant Director for Public Relations Tanzir Ahmed said on Monday that the</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 17:03:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gold price up by Tk 2,507 per bhori in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/gold-price-up-by-tk-2507-per-bhori-in-bangladesh</link><description>The Bangladesh Jewellers Association (BAJUS) has raised the price of gold by Tk 2,507 per bhori, setting the new rate for 22-carat gold at Tk 2,04,283 per bhori.
The new price will take effect from Tuesday, according to a BAJUS press release issued on Monday night.
BAJUS said the price adjustment</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 17:18:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pakistan's army chief to get expanded powers under proposed reform</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/pakistans-army-chief-to-get-expanded-powers-under-proposed-reform</link><description>Pakistan's powerful army chief will be given an expanded role and the remit of the Supreme Court will be curbed under constitutional changes passed by the upper house of parliament on Monday, a move the opposition says will undermine democracy.
Pakistan, historically coup-prone, is seeing its long</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 17:33:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Invest in the base, build the future of Bangladesh cricket</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/invest-in-the-base-build-the-future-of-bangladesh-cricket</link><description>It goes without saying that domestic cricket is the talent pipeline for every cricketing nation. No amount of international coaching or exposure can compensate for a weak domestic structure. The leagues, tournaments, and academies at home are where future stars are shaped long before they wear nati</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 17:48:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AI to reshape the future of business</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/ai-to-reshape-the-future-of-business</link><description>We are living at the dawn of a new era-an age in which artificial intelligence (AI) is a central driver of innovation, strategy, and competitive differentiation. Much like electricity, the internet, or the mobile revolution before it, AI is poised to fundamentally reshape the way businesses operate</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 18:03:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt downsizes current budget by Tk 150b, to ramp up next one</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/govt-downsizes-current-budget-by-tk-150b-to-ramp-up-next-one</link><description>With election and a new government in sight in a couple of months, the interim incumbent seems edgy as it downsizes the current fiscal budget while sets sights high in calculating the next one.



A meeting of the committee for coordination on fiscal, monetary, and currency exchange and resou</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 18:18:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Is an AI therapist dependable?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/is-an-ai-therapist-dependable</link><description>The story of how a 13-year-old adolescent girl, Juliana Paratha, of Colorado in USA, committed suicide  following  long conversations with an AI chatbot, as reported by BBC shocked many. The girl shared her most private emotional experiences with the chatbot. In fact, the chatbot set up a</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 18:33:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Addressing the challenges of new global trading system</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/addressing-the-challenges-of-new-global-trading-system</link><description>The global trading system is undergoing a profound transformation. What was once a relatively predictable, rules-based order -- governed by multilateral disciplines and anchored in the assumption of gradual liberalisation -- has given way to a far more volatile, transactional reality. Tariffs, once</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 18:48:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Exploring AI prospect</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/exploring-ai-prospect</link><description>The dichotomy between the prospect of artificial intelligence (AI) and human resources could not be sharper anywhere save Bangladesh. Given the option for going whole hog for exploring AI prospect, should the country take the chance? Or, can the country afford the luxury of promoting AI at any cost</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 19:03:20 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>