<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 17:21:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Iftekhar Enam Awal promoted to DMD at AB Bank</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/iftekhar-enam-awal-promoted-to-dmd-at-ab-bank</link><description>Mr. Iftekhar Enam Awal has been promoted to Deputy Managing Director of AB Bank PLC.
Mr. Iftekhar started his career with AB Bank PLC as 7th batch Probationary Officer in June 1994 after completing his Post graduation in Finance from the University of Dhaka, according to a press release.
He has p</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 14:32:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sabbir Hossain joins Bank Asia as AMD &amp; COO</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/sabbir-hossain-joins-bank-asia-as-amd-coo</link><description>Md. Sabbir Hossain, a seasoned banker with extensive banking experience, has joined Bank Asia PLC as Additional Managing Director (AMD) and Chief Operating Officer (COO), effective 01 January 2026.
Mr. Hossain brings with him more than three decades of successful banking experience, particularly i</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 14:47:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Modi says Khaleda Zia’s ideals will guide a ‘new journey’ for Bangladesh &amp; India</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/modi-says-khaleda-zias-ideals-will-guide-a-new-journey-for-bangladesh-india</link><description>Indian prime minister Narendra Modi has expressed deep condolences over the death of former Bangladesh prime minister and BNP chairperson Begum Khaleda Zia, saying her political ideals would serve as a “beacon” for a new phase in Bangladesh–India relations under the leadership of</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 14:30:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Petroleum prices cut by Tk 2 per litre for Jan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/petroleum-prices-cut-by-tk-2-per-litre-for-jan</link><description>The government has cut the prices of diesel, kerosene, petrol and octane by Tk 2 per litre each to Tk 102 per litre, Tk 114 per litre, Tk 118 per litre and Tk 122 per litre, respectively for the month of January under the automatic fuel pricing formula.
The previous pump price of diesel, kerosene,</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 14:45:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Arshadur Rouf made interim attorney general</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/arshadur-rouf-assumes-additional-role-as-attorney-general</link><description>Mohammad Arshadur Rouf, serving as additional attorney general, has been entrusted with the additional responsibilities of the attorney general.
The law ministry announced it on Thursday, saying President Mohammed Shahabuddin approved Rouf’s additional charge, effective immediately.
This fo</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 15:00:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh stock market opens New Year with index gains</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh-stock-market-opens-new-year-with-index-gains</link><description>Bangladesh’s stock markets started the first trading day of 2026 on a bullish note as indices rose on both the Dhaka and Chattogram bourses on Thursday, with most listed companies posting gains.
At the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE), the benchmark DSEX index advanced by 45 points. The Shariah-ba</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 15:15:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat, BNP should work together for next five years: Ameer</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-bnp-should-work-together-for-next-five-years-ameer</link><description>Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami Ameer Dr Shafiqur Rahman on Thursday said Jamaat and the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) should work together for the next five years to restore a congenial environment in the interest of national stability.
“We have said that for the sake of our much-loved coun</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 15:30:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Somalia says it killed 29 al-Shabaab militants with international support</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/somalia-says-it-killed-29-al-shabaab-militants-with-international-support</link><description>Somalia’s armed forces have eliminated 29 al-Shabaab militants in the town of Jabad Godane in southeastern Somalia, in coordination with international partners, the Defence Ministry said in a statement on Thursday.
Al-Shabaab has waged an insurgency in Somalia since 2007 in a bid to topple t</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 15:45:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Yemen’s Aden airport shuts as Saudi-UAE rift deepens</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/yemens-aden-airport-shuts-as-saudi-uae-rift-deepens</link><description>Air traffic at Yemen’s Aden international airport was halted on Thursday as tensions persisted between Saudi Arabia and the United Arab Emirates, two Gulf powers whose rivalry is reshaping war-torn Yemen.
The Saudi-backed, internationally recognised Yemeni government ordered new restrictions</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 16:00:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jaishankar’s visit should not be read through political lens: Touhid</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jaishankars-visit-should-not-be-read-through-political-lens-touhid</link><description>Foreign Affairs Adviser Md Touhid Hossain suggested not to interpret Indian External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar’s brief visit to Dhaka through an inter-state or political lens, saying it should be seen primarily as a gesture of courtesy.
He made the remarks on Thursday while speaking to j</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 16:30:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Latifur Rahman’s remarks on AL in Chapainawabganj were personal: Jamaat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/latifur-rahmans-remarks-on-al-in-chapainawabganj-were-personal-jamaat</link><description>Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami on Thursday said that remarks made by Professor Latifur Rahman regarding the Awami League at a courtyard meeting in Chapainawabganj were entirely his personal views and do not reflect the party’s position.
The clarification came in a statement issued by Jamaat&amp;rsqu</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 16:45:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat chief Shafiqur says not everyone gets a farewell like Khaleda’s</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jamaat-chief-shafiqur-says-not-everyone-gets-a-farewell-like-khaledas</link><description>Jamaat-e-Islami chief Shafiqur Rahman has said the outpouring of emotion and respect for former prime minister and BNP chairperson Khaleda Zia was not a farewell that “everyone is fortunate” to receive.
Speaking at the BNP chairperson’s Gulshan office on Thursday evening, he urge</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 17:00:53 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>