<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 12:38:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>NCP agrees on ‘Shapla Koli’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ncp-agrees-on-shapla-koli</link><description>The National Citizen Party, formed by young leaders who spearheaded the July Uprising, has agreed to take ‘Shapla Koli’ as its election symbol -- backing away from its earlier insistence on securing the Shapla logo.
The decision was announced on Sunday after a meeting with the chief el</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 09:20:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jagpa’s registration reinstated with ‘Hookah’ symbol following court order</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jagpas-registration-reinstated-with-hookah-symbol-following-court-order</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has reinstated the registration of Jatiya Ganatantrik Party-Jagpa with its electoral symbol 'Hookah' in line with a High Court order.
"The Jatiya Ganatantrik Party-Jagpa's registration with its party symbol (Registration No-036, 'Hookah' symbol, dated November 20, 2008</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 09:50:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Eight journalists selected for CPRD–TCW Reporting Fellowship 2025</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/eight-journalists-selected-for-cprd-tcw-reporting-fellowship-2025</link><description>The Center for Participatory Research and Development (CPRD) and The Climate Watch (TCW) have announced the selection of eight Bangladeshi journalists for the CPRD–TCW Reporting Fellowship 2025.
The fellowship aims to strengthen climate journalism in Bangladesh by supporting in-depth, eviden</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 10:05:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CA for environment-friendly integrated transport dev plan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ca-for-environment-friendly-integrated-transport-dev-plan</link><description>The Chief Adviser of the Interim Government, Professor Muhammad Yunus, has called for accelerating the integrated development of road, rail, air, and waterways while ensuring that nature, the environment, and rivers remain free from any negative impact.
He made the call on Sunday at an inter-minis</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 10:20:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>British Council announces open calls for ‘WOW – Women of the World’ grants 2025-2026</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/others/british-council-announces-open-calls-for-wow-women-of-the-world-grants-2025-2026</link><description>The British Council invites responses to two open calls for artists and cultural practitioners based either in Bangladesh or in the UK, and arts organisations based in Dhaka, Chattogram, Rajshahi and Sylhet that are working at the intersection of art, culture, gender, and contemporary society to pr</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 10:35:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP, Jamaat equally ‘responsible’ for political ‘discord’: Nahid</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-jamaat-equally-responsible-for-political-discord-nahid</link><description>National Citizen Party (NCP) Convenor Nahid Islam has held both the BNP and Jamaat-e-Islami “equally responsible” for the political discord that has emerged in Bangladesh over state reform, the national election, and the proposed referendum.
Speaking at a press conference at NCP’</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 10:50:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New primary textbooks by November: Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/adviser-bidhan-says-primary-textbooks-will-be-ready-for-distribution-by-november</link><description>All primary school textbooks are expected to reach the government by mid-November, according to Primary and Mass Education Advisor Bidhan Ranjan Roy Poddar.
On Sunday morning at Sunamganj Primary Teacher Training Institute, he said the new textbooks are being printed, have started arriving at ware</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 11:20:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CSOs urge just, inclusive outcomes at COP30</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/csos-urge-just-inclusive-outcomes-at-cop30</link><description>The Climate Justice Alliance, Bangladesh (CJA-B) — a platform of more than 50 national and international organisations — has criticised the slow and inadequate progress of global climate governance under the UNFCCC framework, saying it fails to deliver meaningful national climate action</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 11:35:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UK police says two British men arrested after train attack</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/uk-police-says-two-british-men-arrested-after-train-attack</link><description>British police said on Sunday that a knife attack on a train was not being treated as a terrorist incident and two British men had been arrested on suspicion of attempted murder.
Officer John Loveless said of the nine people who were treated for life-threatening injuries on Saturday, four had been</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 11:50:31 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>