<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 05:04:44 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>13th National Polls: NBR probes discrepancies in candidates' declared income</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/13th-national-polls-nbr-probes-discrepancies-in-candidates-declared-income</link><description>The tax authority has begun investigating discrepancies between reported income and declared assets of candidates of the 13th parliamentary election.
Bank accounts of two candidates have already been frozen, while the tax intelligence team has reopened the past income tax records of another candid</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 02:05:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tight monetary policy to favour cash-rich listed firms</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/tight-monetary-policy-to-favour-cash-rich-listed-firms</link><description>The central bank's continued tight monetary policy stance for the second half of FY26 is expected to benefit listed companies with cash surpluses, as they are likely to keep earning higher interest income.
Equity market participation may improve gradually, as declining yields on government securit</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 02:20:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>City Insurance posts over 10pc profit growth</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/city-insurance-posts-over-10pc-profit-growth</link><description>City Insurance posted a 10.53 per cent year-on-year increase in profit to Tk 231.76 million in 2025.
Its earnings per share (EPS) rose to Tk 3.40 last year from Tk 3.08 in the previous year.
The company reported generating a higher volume of business in 2025 compared to earlier years. It also pai</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 02:35:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP's polling agents asked to be vigilant</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnps-polling-agents-asked-to-be-vigilant</link><description>Polling agents will play the most crucial role in ensuring a fair and successful election, BNP Chairman's adviser Abdus Salam said Tuesday.
"The most important responsibility lies with the polling agents. The election results depend on the polling agents," said Mr. Salam, who is also chief coordin</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 02:50:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Printing presses suffer loss across districts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/printing-presses-suffer-loss-across-districts</link><description>Printing presses across the country have been facing a huge loss on seasonal income due to the ban on posters and restrictions on other campaigning materials ahead of election.
The 13th National Parliamentary Election is set to be held on February 12. According to its code of conduct, candidates a</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 03:05:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Voters largely feel safe to vote: Survey</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/voters-largely-feel-safe-to-vote-survey</link><description>Despite lingering anxieties around the electoral environment, a large majority of voters say they feel safe going to polling stations, according to a nationwide survey released on Tuesday.
Confidence is also relatively high that religious and ethnic minorities will be able to vote without fear.
H</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 03:20:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ten dead after a shooting in Canadian province of British Columbia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/ten-dead-after-a-shooting-in-canadian-province-of-british-columbia</link><description>Ten people, including a suspected shooter, were found dead after a shooting in a town in northeastern British Columbia on Tuesday, Canadian police said.
Six people were found dead inside a high school in Tumbler Ridge, two more people were found dead at a residence believed to be connected to the</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 03:35:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India tightens grip on social media with new three-hour takedown rule</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/india-tightens-grip-on-social-media-with-new-three-hour-takedown-rule</link><description>India's government said social media companies would have to take down unlawful content within three hours of being notified about it, tightening on Tuesday an earlier 36-hour timeline in what could be a compliance challenge for Meta, YouTube and X.
The changes amend India's 2021 IT rules, which h</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 03:50:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>PRAN-RFL to enter motorcycle industry with Tk 5b investment</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/pran-rfl-to-enter-motorcycle-industry-with-tk-5b-investment</link><description>PRAN-RFL Group is set to enter the motorcycle industry with an investment of Tk 5.0 billion in Habiganj, where it will establish a new factory expected to create around 5,000 jobs and boost the local economy.
Giving priority to the young generation, the country's leading business conglomerate is i</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 04:05:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Is gold getting replaced by affordable alternatives?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/is-gold-getting-replaced-by-affordable-alternatives</link><description>"My mother's jewels were stolen a few years back. I wanted to buy at least two to three bhoris of gold for my wedding. But I don't think it's possible anymore," says a bride-to-be from Noakhali anonymously.
The gold market of Bangladesh has been volatile for the past year. But the beginning of 202</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 04:20:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Five-year bond yield steady amid dollar buys</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/five-year-bond-yield-steady-amid-dollar-buys</link><description>The yield on five-year treasury bonds remained broadly unchanged on Tuesday as the central bank purchased a further US$171 million from 11 banks to help stabilise the exchange rate of the US dollar against the local currency.
The cut-off yield, commonly referred to as the interest rate, on Banglad</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 04:35:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Six-tier security plan puts Rangpur on high alert for election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/six-tier-security-plan-puts-rangpur-on-high-alert-for-election</link><description>As Rangpur division prepares for the national election, an unprecedented security operation has turned the region into a tightly guarded zone, with law enforcement agencies rolling out a six-tier security plan to ensure peaceful voting.
From char areas and remote villages to busy city centres, mor</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 04:50:50 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>