<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 17:22:33 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Jamaat to form national govt even if it wins 200 seats: Ameer</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-to-form-national-govt-even-if-it-wins-200-seats-ameer</link><description>Jamaat Ameer Dr Shafiqur Rahman on Monday said his party intends to form a national government if it comes to power, even if it secures 200 parliamentary seats independently, aiming to safeguard national interest and ensure political stability.
He made the remarks while briefing reporters after pa</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 13:30:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>47 Indian fishermen released from Bagerhat jail</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/47-indian-fishermen-released-from-bagerhat-jail</link><description>Forty-seven Indian fishermen released from Bagerhat District Jail will be handed over to the Indian Coast Guard on Tuesday.
Following a court order, jail authorities handed them over to the Bangladesh Coast Guard on Sunday afternoon in the presence of officials from the Indian High Commission, an</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 13:45:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Over 258,000 Bangladeshi expats already registered to vote</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/over-258000-bangladeshi-expats-already-registered-to-vote</link><description>More than 258,000 expatriate Bangladeshi voters from different countries across the world have so far registered through a mobile app, ‘Postal Vote Bd’, since November 19 last to vote in the upcoming national election and the referendum.
The Election Commission (EC) on November 19 open</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 14:00:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shakib hopes to return for a full home series before retirement</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/shakib-hopes-to-return-for-a-full-home-series-before-retirement</link><description>Shakib Al Hasan, who lives out of country after the fall of his political party Awami League from the government facing a mass uprising last year, has said he remains hopeful of playing for Bangladesh again and wants to end his international career with a full series on home soil across all three f</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 14:15:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>2 more die of dengue, 455 hospitalised in 24 hours</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/2-more-die-of-dengue-455-hospitalised-in-24-hours</link><description>Two more deaths were reported from dengue in 24 hours till Monday morning, raising the number of fatalities from the mosquito-borne disease in Bangladesh to 398 this year.
The new fatalities were reported in Dhaka South City Corporation (DSCC), according to the Directorate General of Health Servic</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 14:30:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Eco-industrial parks can cut industries’ climate impact, say experts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/eco-industrial-parks-can-cut-industries-climate-impact-say-experts</link><description>Eco-industrial park (EIP) approaches can help mitigate the climate impact of industries by scaling up resource productivity, minimizing waste, promoting recycling, and improving the economic, environmental and social performance of businesses, speakers said.
They observed that Bangladesh’s i</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 14:45:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Meta to offer choices on personal Facebook and Instagram ads, EU says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/meta-to-offer-choices-on-personal-facebook-and-instagram-ads-eu-says</link><description>Meta has committed to giving Facebook and Instagram users in the European Union a choice when it comes to personalised ads, in line with the EU’s Digital Markets Act, the European Commission said on Monday.
“Meta will give users the effective choice between consenting to share all thei</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 15:00:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Coast Guard rescues hostages, recovers weapons in separate drives in Sundarbans</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/coast-guard-rescues-hostages-recovers-weapons-in-separate-drives-in-sundarbans</link><description>The Bangladesh Coast Guard, in two separate drives, rescued hostages and recovered deer meat, weapons and ammunition from Koira in the Sundarbans and arrested a hunter along with deer meat.
Coast Guard Media Officer Lieutenant Commander Siam-ul-Haq revealed it on Monday evening.
He said based on</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 15:15:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Japan warns of 3-metre high tsunami after magnitude 7.6 earthquake</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/japan-warns-of-3-metre-high-tsunami-after-magnitude-76-earthquake</link><description>A tsunami as high as three metres (10 feet) could hit Japan's northeastern coast after an earthquake with an estimated magnitude of 7.6 occurred offshore on Monday, the Japan Meteorological Agency (JMA) said.
The tsunami warning was issued for the prefectures of Hokkaido, Aomori and Iwate, after t</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 15:30:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jabian Club Limited launched for Jahangirnagar University alumni</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/jabian-club-limited-launched-for-jahangirnagar-university-alumni</link><description>Jabian Club Limited, dedicated to graduates of Jahangirnagar University, was officially launched following its inaugural Executive Committee meeting on 5 December 2025, according to a statement.
Founded through the concerted efforts of former students from multiple graduating classes, the Club was</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 16:01:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Paramount makes $108.4 billion hostile bid for Warner Bros Discovery</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/entertainment/paramount-makes-1084-billion-hostile-bid-for-warner-bros-discovery</link><description>Paramount Skydance on Monday launched a hostile bid worth $108.4 billion for Warner Bros Discovery, in a last-ditch effort to outbid Netflix and create a media powerhouse that would challenge the dominance of the streaming giant.
Netflix had emerged victorious on Friday from a weeks-long bidding w</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 16:16:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No prior condition to hold polls when govt took office: Sakhawat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/no-prior-condition-to-hold-polls-when-govt-took-office-sakhawat</link><description>Labour and Employment Adviser Brigadier General (Retd) M Sakhawat Hossain there was no prior condition to hold elections when the interim government assumed office on 8 August in 2024.
Addressing a press conference at the secretariat on Monday, the adviser said the government itself stated that an</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 16:31:36 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>