<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 14:27:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Ukraine, US to revisit land, nuclear plant issues in Wednesday talks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/ukraine-us-to-revisit-land-nuclear-plant-issues-in-wednesday-talks</link><description>US and Ukrainian negotiators will revisit the thorny issues of territory and the fate of the occupied Zaporizhzhia nuclear power plant, President Volodymyr Zelenskiy said on Wednesday, the most problematic points in peace talks to end Russia's war.
Kyiv is under US pressure to secure peace in the</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 12:37:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Reza Kibria show-caused over ‘code breach’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-candidate-reza-kibria-show-caused-for-voilating-electoral-code-in-habiganj</link><description>BNP-nominated parliamentary candidate Reza Kibria has been served a show-cause notice over alleged violations of the election code of conduct in Habiganj-1 constituency.
The notice was issued by the election inquiry and judicial committee, asking him to explain his position over the allegations.</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 12:52:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Law enforcers to remain in field for 7 days on election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/law-enforcers-to-remain-in-field-for-7-days-on-election</link><description>Law enforcing agencies will be deployed for seven days on the occasion of upcoming parliamentary election and referendum scheduled for February 12.
The deployment will be made to ensure law and order in facilitating a free, fair, impartial, peaceful and festive election.
According to a circular,</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 11:45:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh will not play World Cup in India, Asif Nazrul reiterates</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-will-not-play-world-cup-in-india-asif-nazrul-reiterates</link><description>Sports Adviser Asif Nazrul reaffirmed on Wednesday that Bangladesh will not travel to India for the upcoming T20 World Cup, reiterating the nation’s demand to have their matches relocated to co-host Sri Lanka.
Speaking to the media following a meeting with directors of the Bangladesh Cricket</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 12:00:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>14 senior police officers transferred</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/14-senior-police-officers-transferred</link><description>The government has transferred and given new assignments to 14 senior officials of the Bangladesh Police, including DIGs, Additional DIGs and Superintendents of Police.
The Home Ministry has already issued a notification on Wednesday in this regards.
According to the notification, CID’s DIG</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 12:15:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pakistan eyes defence pact with Bangladesh, sale of JF-17 jets</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/pakistan-eyes-defence-pact-with-bangladesh-sale-of-jf-17-jets</link><description>The air force chiefs of Pakistan and Bangladesh held talks on a potential pact covering the sale of JF-17 Thunder fighter jets to Dhaka, Pakistan's military said, as Islamabad widens its arms supply ambitions and beefs up ties with Bangladesh.
The talks in Islamabad come as Pakistan looks to capit</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 12:30:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UK's Starmer says deployment of troops to Ukraine would be voted by parliament</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/uks-starmer-says-deployment-of-troops-to-ukraine-would-be-voted-by-parliament</link><description>British Prime Minister Keir Starmer said on Wednesday that any deployment of UK forces under a declaration signed with France and Ukraine would be subject to a parliamentary vote.
Starmer, French President Emmanuel Macron and Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelenskiy signed on Tuesday a declaration</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 12:45:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UNDP Bangladesh launches SDG Socialisers Season 2</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/undp-bangladesh-launches-sdg-socialisers-season-2</link><description>The United Nations Development Programme (UNDP) Bangladesh has launched Season 2 of SDG Socialisers, bringing together a new group of content creators who will use their creativity and influence to generate conversations and inspire action on the Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs).
The initiativ</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 13:00:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>'Profitable state-owned enterprises to be floated on capital market'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/profitable-state-owned-enterprises-to-be-floated-on-capital-market-finance-ministry</link><description>The government has agreed in principle to bring profitable state-owned enterprises, including multinational companies with government shareholding to the capital market, aiming to deepen the stock market and restore investor confidence.
Several profitable state-owned companies will be listed throu</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 13:15:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh Bank &amp; NCC Bank sign agreement to Implement BDT 5b Start-up refinance fund</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladesh-bank-ncc-bank-sign-agreement-to-implement-bdt-5b-start-up-refinance-fund</link><description>With the objective of expanding financing in the start-up sector, NCC Bank has signed a participating agreement with Bangladesh Bank.
Under this agreement, NCC Bank will be able to disburse loans to eligible start-up entrepreneurs using refinance funds received from Bangladesh Bank, according to a</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 13:30:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh’s overseas labour migration up 12pc in 2025: RMMRU</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladeshs-overseas-labour-migration-up-12pc-in-2025-rmmru</link><description>Overseas migration of Bangladeshi workers rose by 12 percent in 2025 compared to the previous year, reflecting a continued outbound labour trend amid domestic economic pressures, according to a report released on Wednesday by the Refugee and Migratory Movements Research Unit (RMMRU).
The report, t</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 13:45:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chinese ambassador meets Tarique Rahman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/chinese-ambassador-meets-tarique-rahman</link><description>Chinese Ambassador to Bangladesh Yao Wen on Wednesday held a courtesy meeting with BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman.
The ambassador handed over a bouquet to Tarique Rahman and conveyed his greetings during the meeting held at the BNP Chairperson's political office in Ghulshan this afternoon.
BN</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 14:00:44 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>