<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 06:28:35 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>ADB signs $30m sustainability-linked loan with Envoy Textiles</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/adb-signs-30m-sustainability-linked-loan-with-envoy-textiles</link><description>The Asian Development Bank (ADB) has signed a $30 million sustainability-linked loan facility agreement with Envoy Textiles Limited, marking ADB's first such loan in Bangladesh.
The financing will support the design and construction of a new, automated, and energy-efficient spinning unit at Envoy'</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 03:43:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Depression deepens in Bay of Bengal, ports told to maintain cautionary signal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/depression-deepens-in-bay-of-bengal-ports-told-to-maintain-cautionary-signal</link><description>The depression that formed in the Bay of Bengal has intensified into a deep depression, the Bangladesh Meteorological Department (BMD) says.
In a special weather bulletin issued on Thursday morning, the Met Office said the depression over the west-central Bay of Bengal and adjacent areas has moved</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 03:58:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka’s air turns ‘moderate’ Thursday morning</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dhakas-air-turns-moderate-thursday-morning</link><description>Dhaka, the overcrowded capital city of Bangladesh, has ranked 12th on the list of cities with the worst air quality with an AQI score of 87 at 11 am on Thursday.
Dhaka's air was classified as 'moderate,' referring to a light health threat, according to the AQI index. However, the air quality was m</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 04:13:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Wildlife advocate and primate expert Jane Goodall dies at 91</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/wildlife-advocate-and-primate-expert-jane-goodall-dies-at-91</link><description>Scientist and global activist Jane Goodall, who turned her childhood love of primates into a lifelong quest for protecting the environment, has died at the age of 91, the institute she founded said on Wednesday.
Goodall died of natural causes while in California on a speaking tour, the Jane Goodal</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 04:28:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Four of a family suffer burn injuries in Noakhali</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/four-of-a-family-suffer-burn-injuries-in-noakhali</link><description>Four members of a family, including two children, sustained burn injuries in a fire at their flat in Basurhat Municipality of Companiganj upazila, Noakhali, on Wednesday night.
One of the victims was later shifted to Dhaka, reports UNB.
Kumod Chandranath, father of the children and a pharmaceutic</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 04:43:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CA condoles death of his friend world renowned zoologist Dr Jane</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ca-condoles-death-of-his-friend-world-renowned-zoologist-dr-jane</link><description>Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus has expressed deep sorrow at the death of his friend Dr Jane Goodall, a world-renowned zoologist, primatologist, anthropologist, and conservationist.
“I am deeply saddened by the passing of my dear friend Dr Jane Goodall, a world renowned zoologist, pri</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 04:58:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Typhoon Bualoi leaves 34 dead in Vietnam</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/typhoon-bualoi-leaves-34-dead-in-vietnam</link><description>Typhoon Bualoi and subsequent floods and landslides have left 34 people dead, 20 missing, and 140 others injured, with estimated economic losses of 8.78 trillion Vietnamese dong (about 356 million US dollars), Vietnam News Agency reported Wednesday.
The typhoon caused severe damage to infrastructu</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 05:13:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Apple halts Vision Pro overhaul to focus on AI glasses</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/apple-halts-vision-pro-overhaul-to-focus-on-ai-glasses</link><description>Apple has halted a planned overhaul of its Vision Pro mixed-reality headset to shift resources to smart glasses that would rival products from Meta Platforms, Bloomberg News reported on Wednesday, citing people familiar with the matter.
The iPhone maker had been preparing a cheaper, lighter varian</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 05:28:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pakistan says 13 militants killed in operations in Balochistan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/pakistan-says-13-militants-killed-in-operations-in-balochistan</link><description>Thirteen terrorists were killed during two intelligence-based operations in Pakistan's southwest Balochistan province, the Inter-Services Public Relations (ISPR) said on Wednesday.
The operations were conducted on Sept. 30 and Oct. 1 in Quetta and Kech districts, the ISPR, the media wing of the Pa</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 05:58:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>26 killed in Nigeria boat accident</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/africa/26-killed-in-nigeria-boat-accident</link><description>At least 26 bodies have been recovered during a rescue operation after a fully loaded boat capsized in Nigeria's central state of Kogi, local authorities said Wednesday.
The boat, conveying mostly traders travelling from the Ibaji local government area of Kogi to the Ilushi market in the southern</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 06:13:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>30 killed in Ethiopia scaffolding collapse</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/africa/30-killed-in-ethiopia-scaffolding-collapse</link><description>At least 30 people were killed on Wednesday when a wooden scaffolding collapsed in Ethiopia's Amhara Region, state media reported.
The makeshift structure, set up for the construction of a church in the town of Arerti, collapsed in the early hours of the morning, killing more than 30 worshipers an</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 06:28:35 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>