<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 16:41:54 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>HSIA cargo village fire under control partially</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hsia-cargo-village-fire-under-control-partially</link><description>The fire that broke out at the Cargo Village of Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport (HSIA) in Dhaka was brought under control partially, with the blaze remaining confined to the cargo area, officials said on Saturday evening.
Confirming the development, the airport’s Executive Director&amp;rs</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 13:46:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>25 Ansar members injured in Dhaka airport fire</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/25-ansar-members-injured-in-dhaka-airport-fire</link><description>At least 25 members of the Ansar force have been injured in the fire that erupted at the import cargo complex of Dhaka’s Shahjalal International Airport.
The injured were taken to the Combined Military Hospital (CMH) and Kurmitola General Hospital, said Ansar’s North Zone Commander Md</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 14:01:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Airport fire damages imported goods worth millions</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/airport-fire-damages-imported-goods-worth-millions</link><description>A catastrophic fire ripped through the imported goods section of the cargo village at Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport on Saturday afternoon, causing extensive damage worth millions and forcing the suspension of flight operations at the country's busiest airport.
The blaze, which broke out a</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 14:16:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>All-out efforts underway to resume flight operations at HSIA: Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/all-out-efforts-underway-to-resume-flight-operations-at-hsia-adviser</link><description>Civil Aviation and Tourism Adviser Sheikh Bashir Uddin this evening visited the site of the fire that broke out at the Cargo Village of Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport (HSIA) in Dhaka, assuring that all-out efforts are underway to resume flight operations as soon as possible.
“We will</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 14:31:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Security services investigate each fire incident thoroughly: CA Press Wing</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/security-services-investigate-each-fire-incident-thoroughly-ca-press-wing</link><description>The government, in a statement on Saturday, said that the security services are investigating each fire incident thoroughly and protecting lives and property with utmost vigilance.
"The Interim Government is aware of public concern regarding some major fires in several locations across the country</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 15:01:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique Rahman expresses concern over HSIA fire incident</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-rahman-expresses-concern-over-hsia-fire-incident</link><description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman on Saturday expressed concern over the incident of fire at the Cargo Village of Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport (HSIA) in the city.
In his verified Facebook page, Tarique Rahman said, "I am deeply concerned at the fire that broke out at the Cargo Village o</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 15:16:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rishad’s 6-35 spins Bangladesh to 74-run win over West Indies in first ODI</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/cricket/rishads-6-35-spins-bangladesh-to-74-run-win-over-west-indies-in-first-odi</link><description>Leg-spinner Rishad Hossain produced a brilliant spell of 6 for 35 as Bangladesh thrashed the West Indies by 74 runs in the first ODI to take a 1–0 lead in the three-match series.
Defending a paltry 207, Rishad ripped through the West Indian middle and lower order after the pacers set the ton</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 15:21:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>HSIA fire fully under control, flight resumes</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hsia-fire-fully-under-control-flight-resumes</link><description>The blaze that broke out at the Cargo Village of Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport (HSIA) on Saturday afternoon was fully brought under control after more than seven hours, according to the civil aviation and tourism ministry.  
Flight operations also resumed with the landing of a flight</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 15:36:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nahid asks BNP’s Salahuddin to apologise for comment on July activists</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/nahid-asks-bnps-salahuddin-to-apologise-for-comment-on-july-activists</link><description>National Citizen Party (NCP) Convener Nahid Islam has asked BNP leader Salahuddin Ahmed to apologise for calling July activists -- who had gathered at the venue of the July Charter signing ceremony -- the “fascist army” of the Awami League.
He made the call at a press conference on Sat</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 16:06:37 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>