<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 10:20:11 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>‘Why the delay?’: Jamaat’s Taher on July Charter implementation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/why-the-delay-jamaats-taher-on-july-charter-implementation</link><description>Senior Jamaat-e-Islami leader Syed Abdullah Mohammad Taher has questioned the delay in implementing the July National Charter, saying the interim government must act quickly to carry out agreed reforms ahead of the general election slated for February.
Speaking to reporters at Hazrat Shahjalal Int</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 07:10:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>In Bangladesh’s flooded plains, schools in boats keep learning afloat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/in-bangladeshs-flooded-plains-schools-in-boats-keep-learning-afloat</link><description>In flood-prone regions of Bangladesh, solar-powered “floating schools” ensure children do not miss class when rising waters cut off roads and villages.
One of them is 10-year-old Safikul Islam.
Each morning, he waits on the edge of his flooded village in Bhangura, western Bangladesh,</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 07:40:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat chief Shafiqur Rahman meets UN official Gwyn Lewis</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jamaat-chief-shafiqur-rahman-meets-un-official-gwyn-lewis</link><description>Gwyn Lewis, the United Nations resident coordinator in Bangladesh, has met with Shafiqur Rahman, the chief of Jamaat-e-Islami.
The meeting took place at Rahman’s office in Dhaka’s Bashundhara at 9am on Tuesday.
Lewis was accompanied by Huma Khan, the human rights advisor to the UN res</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 08:25:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh pace attack tops T20 economy charts as batters make big hitting gains</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/bangladesh-pace-attack-tops-t20-economy-charts-as-batters-make-big-hitting-gains</link><description>Bangladesh's fast bowlers have quietly built one of the sharpest records in T20 cricket this year - and their batters aren't far behind either.
Once known as a spin-heavy team, Bangladesh have turned their pace attack into a consistent force. So far in 2025, Bangladeshi pacers have been the most e</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 08:40:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Airbus A320 ousts Boeing 737 as most-delivered jet in history</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/airbus-a320-ousts-boeing-737-as-most-delivered-jet-in-history</link><description>Europe's Airbus broke a major commercial barrier on Tuesday when its A320 family of planes overtook the Boeing 737 to become the most-delivered jetliner in history. Boeing's decades-old record fell as a jet was delivered overnight to Saudi carrier Flynas, bringing deliveries to 12,260 since the A32</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 09:40:48 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>