<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 20:35:50 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>From 'buy America' to 'bye America', Wall Street exodus gathers pace</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/from-buy-america-to-bye-america-wall-street-exodus-gathers-pace</link><description>US investors are pulling money out of their own stock market at the fastest pace in at least 16 years as Big Tech returns fade and better-performing overseas markets look more attractive.
In the last six months, US-domiciled investors have pulled some $75 billion from US equity products, with $52</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 16:49:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Woman arrested after child’s body found stuffed in plastic drum</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/woman-arrested-after-childs-body-found-stuffed-in-plastic-drum</link><description>Police have arrested a woman for allegedly killing a 7-year-old boy and dumping his body in a plastic drum at a rubbish heap in Dhaka’s Gendaria.
The suspect, identified as 45-year-old Maya Begum alias Laboni, was arrested following the recovery of the child’s body on Wednesday, accord</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 17:04:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Narsingdi lawmaker warns traders against price manipulation during Ramadan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/narsingdi-lawmaker-warns-traders-against-price-manipulation-during-ramadan</link><description>Khairul Kabir Khokon, Member of Parliament for Narsingdi-1 (Sadar) and BNP Joint Secretary General, has warned unscrupulous traders against creating artificial shortages or hiking prices during Ramadan. He said strict action will be taken against anyone found violating these rules.
Speaking to rep</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 17:49:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP leader’s kin accused as extortion threats shut down Bauphal shops</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bnp-leaders-kin-accused-as-extortion-threats-shut-down-bauphal-shops</link><description>Business leaders in Bauphal upazila shut shops on Friday after alleged extortionists threatened to kill them for refusing to pay regular tolls.
The president of the Kalaiya Daspara Construction Materials Owners Association, Mostafizur Rahman Chowdhury, was first threatened on Thursday.
Traders la</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 18:04:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Why quantity theory of money fails in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/why-quantity-theory-of-money-fails-in-bangladesh</link><description>In economic policy debates, some ideas endure not because they explain reality well, but because they sound reassuringly simple. One such idea is the belief that inflation can be understood-and managed-by tracking how much money exists and how quickly it circulates through the economy. In Banglades</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 17:20:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Coordinated policies, disciplined finance</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/coordinated-policies-disciplined-finance</link><description>Bangladesh is not short of ambition; it is short of coordination.
Over the past decades, the country has demonstrated remarkable economic resilience. Export-led growth, remittance inflows, infrastructure expansion, and demographic strength have powered steady progress. Yet today, inflation remains</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 17:35:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Studying the history of language movement</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/studying-the-history-of-language-movement</link><description>Today marks the 74th anniversary of the language movement. February 21, commonly known as Amar Ekushey, reflects the eternal spirit of a historical moment. It was on this day in 1952 at least eight people sacrificed their lives to secure Bangla as a state language in the then Pakistan. The movement</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 17:50:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The book fair and lost readers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/the-book-fair-and-lost-readers</link><description>The Amar Ekushey Book Fair kicks off today, keeping alive a cherished annual tradition that celebrates new books and the world of print. For the thousands who visit each year, buying books is only one part of the experience. The fair has grown into a cultural ritual that connects them to language,</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 18:05:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Remembering the courage of Ekushey</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/remembering-the-courage-of-ekushey</link><description>The 21st of February is a powerful reminder of the unyielding will of the Bengali people who refused to let their identity be destroyed by the repressive machinery of the state. On this day in 1952, students and ordinary people stepped forward to demand recognition of Bangla as a state language, an</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 18:20:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>PM pays homage to language heroes</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/pm-pays-homage-to-language-heroes</link><description>Prime Minister Tarique Rahman has paid rich tributes to the martyrs of the 1952 Language Movement, marking the great Martyrs' Day and the International Mother Language Day.
He paid homage by placing a wreath at the Central Shaheed Minar in the city at 12:08 am on Saturday.
The premier arrived on</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 18:35:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>President Shahabuddin pays tribute at Shaheed Minar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/president-shahabuddin-pays-tribute-to-language-movement-martyrs-at-shaheed-minar</link><description>President Mohammed Shahabuddin on Saturday paid tribute to the martyrs of the Language Movement by placing wreaths at the Central Shaheed Minar to mark International Mother Language Day and Martyrs' Day .
President Shahabuddin arrived at the Shaheed Minar exactly at 11:59pm on Friday and placed a</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 18:50:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh formally seeks three-year deferral of LDC graduation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh-formally-seeks-three-year-deferral-of-ldc-graduation</link><description>Bangladesh's newly elected government has formally requested a three-year extension of preparatory period for graduation from the least-developed country (LDC) category, citing transition-plan upsets for prolonged global shocks, domestic economic strains and political upheavals.



Sources say</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 19:05:02 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>