<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 15:26:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Conservation must be given priority in St. Martin’s Island master plan: Rizwana</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/conservation-must-be-given-priority-in-st-martins-island-master-plan-rizwana</link><description>Environment, Forest and Climate Change and Water Resources Adviser Syeda Rizwana Hasan on Tuesday stressed giving priority to conservation in the proposed “Master Plan of Saint Martin’s Island”. 
Saint Martin’s Island has been declared an ecologically critical area, an</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 12:45:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Celebration of English New Year by NRBC Bank</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/celebration-of-english-new-year-by-nrbc-bank</link><description>NRBC Bank has celebrated the arrival of the English New Year 2026 with a modest ceremony at the bank's headquarters.
The chief guest for the occasion was Md. Ali Hossain Prodhania, Chairman of the Board of Directors. Dr. Md. Touhidul Alam Khan, Managing Director &amp; CEO, Mohammad Abdul Qaium Khan, D</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 13:00:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>SBAC Bank signs agreement to participate in Bangladesh Bank's Start-up Fund</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/sbac-bank-signs-agreement-to-participate-in-bangladesh-banks-start-up-fund</link><description>SBAC Bank PLC has signed an agreement to participate an agreement in the Bangladesh Bank Start-up Refinance Fund of Tk 500 crore to facilitate innovation and the development of new entrepreneurs.
In the presence of Nurun Nahar, Deputy Governor of Bangladesh Bank, S. M. Mainul Kabir, Managing Direc</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 13:15:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IFIC Bank, Shopping Bag Supermarket sign MoU to offer exclusive benefits for customers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ific-bank-shopping-bag-supermarket-sign-mou-to-offer-exclusive-benefits-for-customers</link><description>A Memorandum of Understanding (MoU) has been signed between IFIC Bank PLC and Shopping Bag Supermarket, one of the premier retail destinations in Chattogram, according to a press release.
The signing ceremony was held on Monday at the corporate office of Shopping Bag Supermarket in the presence of</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 13:30:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Lutfey Siddiqi suggests modern, demand-driven curricula at NSDA</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/lutfey-siddiqi-suggests-modern-demand-driven-curricula-at-nsda</link><description>Chief Adviser’s Special Envoy on International Affairs Lutfey Siddiqi visited the National Skills Development Authority (NSDA) and underscored the importance of modern, demand-driven, and regularly updated curricula to ensure workforce competitiveness in a rapidly changing global economy.
He</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 13:01:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>VIP protocol for party chiefs undermines level playing field: Islami Andolan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/vip-protocol-for-party-chiefs-undermines-level-playing-field-islami-andolan</link><description>Islami Andolan Bangladesh (IAB) on Tuesday alleged that the leaders of one or two political parties are receiving VVIP treatment, creating hurdles to a level playing field ahead of the national election and referendum scheduled for February 12.
“We told the Election Commission that some poli</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 13:16:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Midland Bank employees, dependents to get insurance coverage from MetLife Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/midland-bank-employees-dependents-to-get-insurance-coverage-from-metlife-bangladesh</link><description>Midland Bank PLC has signed an agreement with MetLife Bangladesh to provide insurance coverage for its employees and their dependents.
According to a press release, this partnership will ensure that nearly 600 permanent employees of Midland Bank are protected against accidents, disabilities, and l</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 13:31:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Young and old in Barishal join contract broiler farming</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/young-and-old-in-barishal-join-contract-broiler-farming</link><description>Many broiler chicken farmers sustained losses while buying feed on credit from dealers, and have now become contract farmers of poultry companies. Many young and elderly people who could not manage jobs, and who lacked capital to start a business, have also become contract farmers.
Farmers said co</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 13:46:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Applications for private MPO teachers open on Saturday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ntrca-invites-applications-for-67000-mpo-teachers-from-saturday</link><description>The Non-Government Teachers’ Registration and Certification Authority (NTRCA) has announced a major recruitment drive to appoint 67,208 teachers and lecturers to MPO-listed private educational institutions across Bangladesh.
Applications will open on Saturday and remain available until midni</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 14:01:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Uttara Bank introduces TakaPay Debit Card</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/uttara-bank-introduces-takapay-debit-card</link><description>Mr. Md. Abul Hashem, Managing Director and CEO of Uttara Bank PLC. has inaugurated the “TakaPay Debit Card” of the bank on Monday.
According to a press release, this card can be used to withdraw cash at all ATMs and make payment through POS machines within the country. Additional Manag</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 14:16:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Vote counting begins after JnU’s first polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/vote-counting-under-way-after-jagannath-universitys-first-student-council-election</link><description>After two decades of transformation, Jagannath University students have cast their ballots for the first-ever election of the central student council (JnUCSU).
Following a peaceful voting process, counting of votes began at 6:30pm at the Department of Geography and Environment on Tuesday.
Polling</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 14:31:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Over 15.33 lakh register for postal voting: Shafiqul Alam</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/over-1533-lakh-register-for-postal-voting-shafiqul-alam</link><description>Chief Adviser’s Press Secretary Shafiqul Alam on Tuesday said that a total of 15,33,682 voters have registered for casting their votes through postal ballots as registration for postal vote ended on Monday.
“A total of 15,33,682 voters have registered for casting their votes through po</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 14:46:17 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>