<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 03:33:44 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Three reasons why IMF cuts Bangladesh's growth forecast</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/three-reasons-why-imf-cuts-bangladeshs-growth-forecast</link><description>The International Monetary Fund (IMF) has cited three major reasons for downward revision of Bangladesh's GDP-growth prospect for this fiscal year, including a pass-through ambience of uncertainty.
"I think there are three reasons, one of course is the policy mix has been tighter, the second tarif</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 19:24:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh Bank to form ‘Shariah Advisory Board’ for Islami banking governance</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladesh-bank-to-form-shariah-advisory-board-for-islami-banking-governance</link><description>Bangladesh Bank has initiated measures to ensure good governance, transparency, and the proper application of Shariah principles in the Islamic banking sector.
In this regard, the central bank has recently approved a policy for the formation of its own Shariah Advisory Board (SAB), a senior offici</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 02:14:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Stage set for July Charter signing today amid political rift</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/stage-set-for-july-charter-signing-today-amid-political-rift</link><description>The National Consensus Commission (NCC) gets another extension of tenure as the interim government is all set to hold the July Charter-signing ceremony today (Friday) amid political differences, including demand for an official order executing the firman.
The Cabinet Division in a circular extende</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 02:29:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Business climate stagnates as firms grapple with inflation, policy gaps</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/business-climate-stagnates-as-firms-grapple-with-inflation-policy-gaps</link><description>Bangladesh's business environment has shown little sign of progress over the past year, with several key areas even deteriorating, according to the latest Business Climate Index (BBX) for FY2024-25 released on Thursday.
The index highlights persistent structural challenges, from access to regulato</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 01:33:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Taka seen overvalued as dollar gap widens</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/taka-seen-overvalued-as-dollar-gap-widens</link><description>The local currency, Taka, appears increasingly overvalued as sluggish import demand, weak private-sector credit growth, and robust remittance inflows continue to shape foreign exchange dynamics.
Bangladesh Bank's latest data show the real effective exchange rate (REER) climbed to 104.51 in Septemb</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 01:48:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh Bank's strict LC rules hinder import of foodstuffs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladesh-banks-strict-lc-rules-hinder-import-of-foodstuffs</link><description>A good number of imported food items, including the nutritious ones for babies and elderly people, are gradually disappearing from the market due to Bangladesh Bank's stringent rules on opening Letters of Credit (L/Cs).
Importers said they find themselves in a difficult situation to import product</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 02:03:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Online Gambling, Pornography: Government declares zero tolerance</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/online-gambling-pornography-government-declares-zero-tolerance</link><description>The government has taken a hard line against the growing prevalence of gambling, betting, and pornography-related content in the country's digital space, declaring a "zero-tolerance" policy to protect cyberspace from unethical and harmful activities.
The move aims to create a safer, more disciplin</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 02:18:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Broiler prices surge amid declining beef consumption over anthrax fears</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/broiler-prices-surge-amid-declining-beef-consumption-over-anthrax-fears</link><description>The prices of broiler chicken, edible oil, and vegetables moved up again this week, further increasing burden on consumers.
Broiler chicken prices went up by Tk 10 per kilogram in city markets, reaching Tk 190-195 per kg on Thursday, a weekly increase of Tk 10-15 per kg.
Sonali and Pakistani chic</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 02:33:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UGC warns against fake foreign university branches in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/ugc-warns-against-fake-foreign-university-branches-in-bangladesh</link><description>The University Grants Commission (UGC) of Bangladesh has identified three fake foreign university branch campuses operating in the country and warned students against enrolling in them.
The universities are America World University (USA), Trinity University (USA), and the Spiritual Institute of Ne</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 02:48:42 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>