<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 04:08:35 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Deadlock over CCCI election drags on</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/deadlock-over-ccci-election-drags-on</link><description>CHATTOGRAM, Dec 27: Uncertainty continues to surround the biennial election of the Chittagong Chamber of Commerce and Industry (CCCI), the oldest trade body of the country, as fresh legal moves have again stalled the process despite recent court directives.
Although a High Court order had cleared</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 23:38:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>30 duty-free cars imported by ex-MPs handed over to govt transport pool</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/30-duty-free-cars-imported-by-ex-mps-handed-over-to-govt-transport-pool</link><description>CHATTOGRAM, Dec 27: Thirty duty-free luxury vehicles imported by members of the 12th Jatiya Sangsad during Sheikh Hasina government's last tenure were handed over to the government transport pool under the Vehicle Directorate of the Ministry of Public Administration yesterday (Friday).
Sharif Al A</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 23:53:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>GPH Ispat honours meritorious students of Sitakunda</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/gph-ispat-honours-meritorious-students-of-sitakunda</link><description>CHATTOGRAM, Dec 27: GPH Ispat organised a grand reception titled "GPH Shining Stars Recognition-2025" on Saturday to appreciate the talents of students from the Sitakunda region who achieved GPA-5 in the HSC and Alim examinations.
The event was held on the GPH Ispat plant premises in Kumira. Spe</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 00:08:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Why being good at your job doesn't guarantee career growth</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/article/why-being-good-at-your-job-doesnt-guarantee-career-growth</link><description>Farah had exceeded every sales target for three consecutive years at a multinational bank in Dhaka. Her quarterly reviews were flawless. When the regional manager position opened, she assumed it was hers. It went to Kamal, who had missed targets twice but happened to play golf with the division hea</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 00:23:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Vitalizers 3.0 sets new benchmark for national business case competitions</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/article/vitalizers-30-sets-new-benchmark-for-national-business-case-competitions</link><description>The BRAC University Business &amp; Economics Forum concluded its flagship national business case competition, Vitalizers 3.0 at the BRAC University Auditorium recently, reinforcing the event's position as a premier platform for aspiring business leaders across Bangladesh.
Presented by X Ceramics, co</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 00:38:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>When 'learning opportunities' become free labour</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/article/when-learning-opportunities-become-free-labour</link><description>The promise is alluring: a foot in the door, a chance to learn, a line on a CV that might open up a future career. For thousands of students, graduates, and even post-graduates across Bangladesh, this promise comes in the form of an internship. The reality, however, is often a starkly different pic</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 00:53:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique Rahman to contest polls from Bogura-6,  Dhaka-17</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-rahman-to-contest-polls-from-bogura-6-dhaka-17</link><description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman will contest the 13th parliamentary election billed for February 12 next year from two constituencies--Bogura-6 and Dhaka-17.
BNP Standing Committee member Salahuddin Ahmed confirmed the decision while speaking to UNB on Saturday night.
“Our party’s</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 01:08:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Inqilab Moncho announces all-out blockade on Sunday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/inqilab-moncho-announces-all-out-blockade-on-sunday</link><description>Inqilab Moncho has announced an all-out blockade in divisional cities across the country from 2pm on Sunday, demanding the swift arrest and trial of those responsible for the killing of martyr Sharif Osman bin Hadi.
In a Facebook post on Saturday night, the platform urged people to observe the blo</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 01:23:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khaleda in critical condition, undergoing challenging treatment phase: Dr Zahid</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/khaleda-in-critical-condition-undergoing-challenging-treatment-phase-dr-zahid</link><description>BNP Chairperson and former Prime Minister Begum Khaleda Zia remains in a critical condition and is passing through a very challenging phase of her treatment, her personal physician Dr AZM Zahid Hossain said on Saturday night.
“Her condition is extremely complex, and she is now going through</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 01:38:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mohiuddin Roni to run from Dhaka-18 as independent candidate</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/mohiuddin-roni-to-run-from-dhaka-18-as-independent-candidate</link><description>Mohiuddin Roni, a key figure of July Uprising, is going to contest from Dhaka-18 constituency in the 13th parliamentary election as an independent candidate.
In a video message posted on his verified Facebook account, Roni said he wants to work for the people by establishing a just state free from</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 01:53:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Charge sheet in Hadi murder case by Jan 7: DMP chief</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/charge-sheet-in-hadi-murder-case-by-jan-7-dmp-chief</link><description>The charge sheet in the murder case of Sharif Osman bin Hadi, spokesperson of Inqilab Moncho, will be submitted by January 7, said Dhaka Metropolitan Police (DMP) Commissioner Md Sajjat Ali on Saturday night.
“We have already arrested 10 suspects involved in the Hadi murder and are working t</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 02:08:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Keraniganj blast: Madrasa head, previously accused of extremism, named key suspect</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/keraniganj-blast-madrasa-head-previously-accused-of-extremism-named-key-suspect</link><description>Reactions between chemicals stored in large quantities led to the explosion that blew away the walls of a madrasa and caused cracks in its roof and columns on the outskirts of Dhaka on Friday.
Police say the chemicals found stored in the building are commonly used to make explosives, adding that t</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 02:23:17 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>