<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 08:27:20 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Farmer shot dead in Kushtia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/farmer-shot-dead-in-kushtia</link><description>A farmer has been shot dead and another man was wounded by gunfire in Bheramara upazila of Kushtia district.
The incident took place around 8:30 pm on Friday in the Rayta Notunpara area of Bahadurpur Union, according to Bheramara Police Station chief Abdur Rouf Talukder.
The dead man was identifi</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 04:56:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ukraine faces 'difficult choice' as Trump demands acceptance of peace plan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/ukraine-faces-difficult-choice-as-trump-demands-acceptance-of-peace-plan</link><description>President Volodymyr Zelenskiy warned on Friday that Ukraine risked losing its dignity and freedom — or Washington's backing — over a US peace plan that endorses key Russian demands, a proposal Donald Trump said Kyiv should accept within a week.
The US president told Fox News Radio he b</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 05:11:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Armanitola building owner asked to submit design</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/armanitola-building-owner-asked-to-submit-design</link><description>Rajdhani Unnayan Kartripakkha (Rajuk) has warned that the earthquake-damaged building at Kasaituli in Dhaka’s Armanitola will be sealed if the owner fails to submit its design and approval papers within seven days.
It will disconnect the gas, electricity and WASA lines on the eighth day, fol</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 05:41:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US warns airlines of potential hazards when flying over Venezuela</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-warns-airlines-of-potential-hazards-when-flying-over-venezuela</link><description>The US Federal Aviation Administration warned major airlines on Friday of a "potentially hazardous situation" when flying over Venezuela and urged them to exercise caution.
The FAA notice cited,  the "worsening security situation and heightened military activity in or around Venezuela" and sa</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 05:56:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt moves to modernise BSTI labs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/govt-moves-to-modernise-bsti-labs</link><description>The government has taken up a Tk 8.51 billion project to expand and modernise the physical and chemical laboratories of Bangladesh Standards and Testing Institution (BSTI) to improve product testing, strengthen consumer protection and ensure better quality control in local and imported goods.
Offi</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 06:11:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>3.3 magnitude tremor jolts Baipail</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/33-magnitude-tremor-jolts-baipail</link><description>A mild earthquake was felt in the Baipayl area of Ashulia, on the outskirts of Savar upazila of Dhaka, on Saturday morning.
According to the Bangladesh Meteorological Department (BMD), the tremor was recorded at 10:36:12 am today.
Nizamuddin Ahmed, the duty officer at the BMD, said the quake meas</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 06:29:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Indonesia's biggest Islamic group asks chief to resign over invitation to pro-Israeli speaker</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/indonesias-biggest-islamic-group-asks-chief-to-resign-over-invitation-to-pro-israeli-speaker</link><description>Indonesia's biggest Islamic organisation, Nahdlatul Ulama, has asked its chief to resign for inviting a US scholar known for his support of Israel during the Gaza war to an internal event in August, according to meeting minutes reviewed by Reuters.
The leadership of NU, which is also the world's b</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 06:44:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Over 200 Catholic students kidnapped in Nigeria</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/africa/over-200-catholic-students-kidnapped-in-nigeria</link><description>Gunmen in Nigeria kidnapped at least 227 students and teachers at a Catholic school in the northwest on Friday, the Christian Association of Nigeria (CAN) said, the latest in a spate of school attacks this week that has forced the government to shut 47 colleges.
Friday's incident in Niger state wa</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 06:59:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Income tax return deadline likely to be extended to December 31</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/income-tax-return-deadline-likely-to-be-extended-to-december-31</link><description>The government is likely to extend the deadline for submitting individual income tax returns until December 31, according to senior officials familiar with matter. The current deadline is set to expire on November 30.
Officials at the National Board of Revenue (NBR) said the proposal is under acti</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 07:14:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BBC board member Banerji resigns after Trump documentary edit</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/bbc-board-member-banerji-resigns-after-trump-documentary-edit</link><description>An independent director on the BBC's board, Shumeet Banerji, has quit on Friday in the wake of what the public broadcaster said was an incorrect edit of a speech by President Donald Trump and which has prompted the threat of a $5 billion lawsuit.
Banerji, who also serves on the board of Indian con</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 07:46:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Lilly reaches $1 trillion market value</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/lilly-reaches-1-trillion-market-value</link><description>Eli Lilly hit $1 trillion in market value on Friday, making it the first drugmaker to enter the exclusive club dominated by tech giants and underscoring its rise as a weight-loss powerhouse.
A more than 35 per cent rally in the company's stock this year has largely been driven by the explosive gro</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 08:01:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bhutanese PM pays homage to Liberation War martyrs in Savar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bhutanese-pm-pays-homage-to-liberation-war-martyrs-in-savar</link><description>Bhutanese Prime Minister Tshering Tobgay paid tribute to the Liberation War martyrs by placing a wreath at the National Memorial in Savar, on the outskirts of Dhaka, shortly after his arrival for a two-day state visit on Saturday.
After placing the wreath at the memorial’s altar, he stood in</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 08:16:06 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>