<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 21:20:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Gold prices hit record high in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/gold-prices-hit-record-high-in-bangladesh</link><description>Gold prices in Bangladesh climbed to an all-time high on Sunday, with the price of 22-carat gold rising to Tk 218,117 per bhori following a fresh hike announced by the Bangladesh Jewellers Association (BAJUS).
BAJUS raised the price of 22-carat gold by Tk 1,050 per bhori, setting the new rat</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 17:05:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Indian visa application centre in Ctg suspends operations</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/indian-visa-application-centre-in-ctg-suspends-operations</link><description>India on Sunday suspended operations at the Visa Application Centre (IVAC) in Chattogram, the commercial capital of Bangladesh, until further notice.
“Due to the recent security incident at AHCI Chittagong, Indian visa operations at IVAC Chittagong will remain suspended from 21/12/2025 until</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 17:20:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US pursuing third oil tanker near Venezuela, officials say</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-pursuing-third-oil-tanker-near-venezuela-officials-say</link><description>The US Coast Guard is pursuing an oil tanker in international waters near Venezuela, officials told Reuters on Sunday, in what would be the second such operation this weekend and the third in less than a week if successful.
“The United States Guard is in active pursuit of a sanctioned dark f</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 17:35:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BPL tickets go on sale as Sylhet gears up for opening phase</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/bpl-tickets-go-on-sale-as-sylhet-gears-up-for-opening-phase</link><description>Ticket sales for the Sylhet phase of the Bangladesh Premier League (BPL) will begin on Sunday, December 21.
Fans are now able to purchase seats exclusively through an online platform, the Bangladesh Cricket Board (BCB) has announced.
The tickets, which go on sale from 4:00 pm, will be avail</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 16:36:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>RTI key to ensuring human rights, good governance</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/rti-key-to-ensuring-human-rights-good-governance</link><description>We have recently celebrated Human Rights Day in Bangladesh. In this context, several legal analysts as well as social icons have underlined the importance and significance of transparency, culpability and accountability. There have also been references throughout the world pertaining to free speech</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 16:51:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Attacks on media and cultural institute</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/attacks-on-media-and-cultural-institute</link><description>The ransacking and torching of the Prothom Alo and The Daily Star office buildings in Dhaka add a new dimension to the mobocracy. Similar acts of vandalism and arson in the Chhayanaut building exposes a gross volte-face of the movement. These are not the heady days immediately after the fall of Has</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 17:06:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Lowering data price to widen internet use</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/lowering-data-price-to-widen-internet-use</link><description>The latest survey by the Bangladesh Bureau of Statistics (BBS) shows an impressive rate (98.9 per cent) of penetration of mobile phones at the household level in Bangladesh in the first quarter of the current fiscal year (2025-26). In comparison, the rate of Smartphone use is over 72 per cent. So f</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 17:21:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ending the plight of female migrant workers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/ending-the-plight-of-female-migrant-workers</link><description>The sufferings of the Bangladeshi female migrant workers abroad, and the social isolation and depression many face on their return home, often hit the headlines and evoke widespread public concern.  Driven by the hope of entering the workforce, improving their economic condition, many poor wom</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 17:36:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AL leader dies after falling ill at Kashimpur prison gate</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/al-leader-dies-after-falling-ill-at-kashimpur-prison-gate</link><description>Awami League leader Wasikur Rahman Babu died on Sunday after suddenly falling ill at the gate of Kashimpur Central Jail-2, jail authorities said.
Confirming the incident, Superintendent of Kashimpur Jail-2 Al Mamun said Wasikur collapsed while being handed over to police custody.
Wasikur, a forme</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 17:51:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladeshi tourists in Sri Lanka urged to take precautions</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladeshi-tourists-in-sri-lanka-advised-to-take-precautions-amid-landslide-warnings</link><description>The Bangladesh High Commission in Sri Lanka has urged Bangladeshi tourists to remain vigilant and follow safety instructions after the Disaster Management Centre (DMC) of Sri Lanka issued a Level 03 (Red) Landslide Early Warning—the highest alert—for parts of Kandy and Nuwara Eliya for</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 18:06:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladeshi faces US charges over “selling fake documents”</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladeshi-man-faces-charges-in-us-for-running-fake-id-marketplaces-online</link><description>A Bangladeshi national has been accused in a US court of allegedly operating online platforms that sold fake templates of identity documents, including passports, social security cards and driving licences.
Zahid Hasan, 29, from Dhaka, faces nine charges, Montana District Attorney Kurt Alme said.</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 18:21:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Revised budget, new one's outline going for CA's perusal today</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/revised-budget-new-ones-outline-going-for-cas-perusal-today</link><description>A pared-down draft revised budget for the current fiscal year and an outline of the next one are being placed before Chief Adviser Muhammad Yunus today to seek his advice and directions, officials say.



An upscale Tk 8.5-trillion budget for next fiscal year is likely to be framed by the inter</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 18:36:49 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>