<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 15:22:56 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>India’s economy surges ahead of full US tariff hit</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/indias-economy-surges-ahead-of-full-us-tariff-hit</link><description>India’s economic growth accelerated to 8.2 percent year-on-year in the July-September period, boosted by strong consumer spending and a front-loading of production ahead of local festivals and punitive US tariffs.
Economists polled by Reuters had forecast a 7.3 percent expansion for the quar</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 12:40:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DU VC meets IDDEF President in city</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/du-vc-meets-iddef-president-in-city</link><description>Dhaka University (DU) Vice-Chancellor (VC) Professor Niaz Ahmed Khan has held a meeting with Mehmet Turan, president of Turkey-based non-profit Islamic organisation IDDEF.
IDDEF stands for ‘Insana Deger Veren Dernekler Federasyonu’ or ‘The Federation of Associations That Value Hu</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 12:55:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sonali Life wins South Asian Business Excellence Award for the fifth time</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/sonali-life-wins-south-asian-business-excellence-award-for-the-fifth-time</link><description>Sonali Life Insurance Company Limited has won the prestigious South Asian Business Excellence Award for the fifth consecutive year.
The award ceremony was held on 27 November in Colombo, Sri Lanka, where the company received recognition in four categories.
Sonali Life’s business partners&amp;md</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 13:10:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Zelensky's 'man for all seasons' ensnared in corruption probe</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/zelenskys-man-for-all-seasons-ensnared-in-corruption-probe</link><description>Ask Ukrainians who the country's most powerful figure is after the president and many will say Andriy Yermak, his chief of staff and a key negotiator during four years of war when Western financial and military aid has kept Kyiv in the fight.
Yermak, a friend of President Volodymyr Zelensky and hi</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 13:25:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘July Mancha’ disrupts Baul protest at Shahbagh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/july-mancha-disrupts-baul-protest-at-shahbagh</link><description>A protest demanding justice for attacks on Baul singers and the release of detained artiste Abul Sarkar had been disrupted in Shahbagh after a confrontation with a group identifying themselves as members of “July Mancha”.
The scuffle broke out around 5pm on Friday outside the Shahbagh</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 13:40:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh U17s power past Bahrain to make it four wins from four</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/bangladesh-u17s-power-past-bahrain-to-make-it-four-wins-from-four</link><description>Bangladesh have moved a step closer to the AFC U17 Asian Cup finals with a hard-earned 2–1 win over Bahrain, extending their perfect run to four victories from four matches in the qualifiers.
Playing on Friday at the Tongliang Long Stadium in China, Golam Rabbani Choton’s side delivere</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 13:30:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Airfare on Sylhet-Dhaka route revised following public outcry</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/airfare-on-sylhet-dhaka-route-revised-following-public-outcry</link><description>In response to widespread public criticism over high airfares on the Sylhet-Dhaka route, authorities have announced a revised fare structure, officials said on Friday.
According to a statement from the Sylhet Deputy Commissioner’s media cell, the revision aims to improve passenger services w</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 13:45:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Israeli raid in southern Syria leaves 13 dead</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/israeli-raid-in-southern-syria-leaves-13-dead-syrian-state-media-report</link><description>Thirteen people were killed in an Israeli raid in southern Syria on Friday, Syrian state media reported, with Damascus accusing Israel of a "criminal attack" in a village where Israel said its troops came under fire during an operation to arrest militants.
The Israeli military said six soldiers we</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 14:00:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fakhrul urges govt not to pass police, NGO laws hurriedly</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/fakhrul-urges-govt-not-to-pass-police-ngo-laws-hurriedly</link><description>BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir on Friday urged the interim government not to hurriedly pass two major laws, warning that such moves by a non-elected administration can obstruct the country’s democratic process.
In a statement, he said, “We have learned from reliable</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 14:15:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chief Adviser seeks prayers for Khaleda Zia’s recovery</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/chief-adviser-seeks-prayers-for-khaleda-zias-recovery</link><description>Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus has expressed deep concern over the current health condition of former Prime Minister and BNP Chairperson Begum Khaleda Zia and sought prayers from the nation for her quick recovery.
Professor Yunus has been regularly monitoring Khaleda Zia’s health upd</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 14:30:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two killed as bus hits truck on Dhaka-Chattogram highway</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/two-killed-as-bus-hits-truck-on-dhaka-chattogram-highway</link><description>Two people were killed and two others seriously injured Friday afternoon when a passenger bus collided with a truck carrying bricks on the Dhaka-Chattogram Highway in Daudkandi, Cumilla police said.
The accident occurred in the Hugulia area of Daudkandi while a Starline bus traveling toward Chatto</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 14:45:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Belarus leader visits Myanmar ahead of disputed election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/belarus-leader-visits-myanmar-ahead-of-disputed-election</link><description>Belarusian President Alexander Lukashenko arrived in Myanmar on a goodwill visit, state media reported Friday, becoming only the second foreign leader to set foot in the country since the military seized power in 2021.
The trip comes weeks before a national election widely dismissed by critics as</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 15:00:52 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>