<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 04:56:16 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>LDCs' key challenges decoded</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/ldcs-key-challenges-decoded</link><description>Though the services sector has become a leading source of growth and employment in the least developed countries (LDCs), it has yet to provide adequate, productive, and formal jobs. Instead, service-centric jobs in these countries are clustered in low-productivity and informal sectors, leading to l</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 18:15:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Unity, economic reforms, rule of law main goals</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/unity-economic-reforms-rule-of-law-main-goals</link><description>Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) and prime minister-apparent Tarique Rahman prioritizes national unity, economic reforms and the rule of law under is upcoming government.
He explains that national unity is the collective strength of the country and both the government and the opposition must wor</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 18:30:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New leadership and the quest for liveability</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/new-leadership-and-the-quest-for-liveability</link><description>The long awaited national election, held 17 years after the last genuinely contested vote, has brought with it a wave of public expectation. For many residents of Dhaka, some of those expectations are surprisingly simple, though no less reasonable for it. People in the megacity want a clean and ord</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 18:45:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mamata sends sweets, flowers to Tarique Rahman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/mamata-sends-sweets-flowers-to-tarique-rahman</link><description>West Bengal Chief Minister Mamata Banerjee on Saturday sent floral greetings and sweets to BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman following the party's landslide victory in the 13th national election.
BNP Media Cell member Atiqur Rahman Ruman received the flowers and sweets in the evening at the party chairm</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 19:00:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat to seek recount in 30 constituencies</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-to-seek-recount-in-30-constituencies</link><description>Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami (BJI) will move to the Election Commission (EC) for recounting the ballots of 30 constituencies and demand announcement of fresh results.
It also called for suspension of gazette and oath-taking.
The party also alleged widespread vote rigging, intimidation of agents, an</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 02:09:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CA greets Tarique on landslide victory</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ca-greets-tarique-on-landslide-victory</link><description>Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus congratulates Tarique Rahman, chair of the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP), on securing an absolute majority in the general election that yielded results he describes as a "historic milestone" in Bangladesh's democratic transition.
In a message of greeting</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 02:24:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Foreign observers term polls as credible, peaceful</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/foreign-observers-term-polls-as-credible-peacefuln</link><description>Foreign observers in their separate observations have termed the Feb 12 national election as peaceful and credible.
The European Union's chief election observer has described Bangladesh's 13th parliamentary elections as "credible and competently managed", calling them a pivotal step towards restor</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 02:12:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique to visit rivals today in unity gesture</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-to-visit-rivals-today-in-unity-gesture</link><description>In a move party leaders describe as a message of unity and democratic maturity, Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) Chairman Tarique Rahman is set to visit the residences of key political rivals this (Sunday) evening.
The planned courtesy calls on Shafiqur Rahman, Ameer of Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islam</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 02:27:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC publishes gazette on JS polls, referendum</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-publishes-gazette-on-js-polls-referendum</link><description>The Election Commission has published the gazette notification of the Members of Parliament elected in the 13th National Parliamentary Election.
The gazette was issued on Friday night by Election Commission (EC) Senior Secretary Akhtar Ahmed.
The gazette contains the names of the elected Members</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 02:42:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nagorik Coalition decries post-poll violence surge</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nagorik-coalition-decries-post-poll-violence-surge</link><description>Expressing "deep concern" over post-election violence, the Nagorik Coalition has urged the interim government to ensure citizens' safety and bring those responsible to justice.
In a statement issued to the media on Saturday, the platform said that, apart from a few isolated incidents, the parliame</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 02:57:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt to scrutinise Myanmar's global trade ties amid refugee crisis</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-to-scrutinise-myanmars-global-trade-ties-amid-refugee-crisis</link><description>In a move to bolster data-driven policymaking, the Ministry of Foreign Affairs (MoFA) has asked the Ministry of Commerce (MoC) to compile and submit a comprehensive report on Myanmar's trade relations with Bangladesh and other major global economies.
An official said MoFA recently requested the da</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 03:12:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Recent market rallies echo August 2024 optimism, with a twist</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/recent-market-rallies-echo-august-2024-optimism-with-a-twist</link><description>The Dhaka bourse witnessed a 3.77 per cent leap in its broad index to 5,426 points on August 3, 2024, as investor enthusiasm ran high over anticipated market reforms following the ouster of the previous regime.
That marked the biggest single-day gain in more than 43 months, resulting in a whopping</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 03:27:15 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>