<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 11:21:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Police arrest Ataur Rahman Bikrompuri in Narsingdi operation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/police-arrest-ataur-rahman-bikrompuri-in-narsingdi-operation</link><description>The Dhaka Metropolitan Police (DMP) have arrested Ataur Rahman Bikrompuri, a religious speaker and political commentator who drew the spotlight following recent incidents.
According to the DMP, Ataur Rahman was apprehended in Narsingdi following a coordinated operation by Gazipur Metropolitan Poli</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 08:33:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP strikes election deal with 7 more partners, reserves 8 seats</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-strikes-election-deal-with-7-more-partners-reserves-8-seats</link><description>BNP has reached an electoral understanding with seven more alliance partners of the anti-fascist movement, leaving eight parliamentary seats for them for the upcoming national election.
BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir announced the list at a press conference at the party Chairper</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 08:49:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Woman, granddaughter die as house catches fire in Ctg</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/woman-granddaughter-die-as-house-catches-fire-in-ctg</link><description>A woman and her granddaughter were killed after a fire broke out at their house at Kaderia Para village in Rangunia upazila of Chattogram district on Wednesday.
The deceased were identified as Rumi Akhtar, 55, wife of Ruhul Amin, and her five-year-old granddaughter Jannat Akhtar, residents of the</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 09:04:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Redwan Ahmed joins BNP from LDP, set to run for Cumilla-7</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/redwan-ahmed-joins-bnp-from-ldp-set-to-run-for-cumilla-7</link><description>Redwan Ahmed has resigned as secretary general of the Liberal Democratic Party (LDP) and officially joined the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP).
On Wednesday afternoon, he joined the BNP at the chairperson’s Gulshan office -- welcomed into the party by BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul I</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 09:19:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jasas leader stabbed dead in Gazipur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/jasas-leader-stabbed-dead-in-gazipur</link><description>A leader of Jatiyatabadi Samajik Sangskritik Sangstha (Jasas) was stabbed to death by unidentified miscreants at Latifpur village in Sreepur upazila of Gazipur district early Wednesday.
The deceased was identified as Farid Sarkar, joint secretary of Gosinga union unit of Jasas.
Nasir Ahmed, Offic</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 09:34:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Myanmar junta's shift from battlefield to ballots faces long odds</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/myanmar-juntas-shift-from-battlefield-to-ballots-faces-long-odds</link><description>From inside a military base last week, Myanmar’s junta chief Min Aung Hlaing announced who he wanted voters to pick in Sunday’s general election, nearly five years after seizing power in a coup.
“He suggested that during the upcoming election period, voters should choose candidat</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 09:06:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt welcomes Tarique Rahman’s return, assures full cooperation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-welcomes-tarique-rahmans-return-assures-full-cooperation</link><description>Chief Adviser’s Press Secretary Shafiqul Alam on Wednesday said the government welcomes BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman’s scheduled homecoming on Thursday morning, affirming that all cooperation sought by his party is being extended with necessary security measures in place.
"We wel</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 09:21:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chankharpul killings: ICT-1 sets January 20 for delivering judgment</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/chankharpul-killings-ict-1-sets-january-20-for-delivering-judgment</link><description>The International Crimes Tribunal-1 on Wednesday fixed January 20 for delivering its judgment in the case filed over the killing of six students during July-August movement in Dhaka's Chankharpul area.
A three-member ICT bench led by its chairman Justice Golam Martuza Majumdar passed the order aft</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 09:36:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ukrainian troops withdraw from eastern town of Siversk</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/ukrainian-troops-withdraw-from-eastern-town-of-siversk</link><description>Ukrainian forces have pulled out of the embattled eastern town of Siversk, Kyiv's military said on Tuesday, as Russian troops wage a battlefield offensive aimed at threatening key cities critical to Ukraine's defences in the east.
The fall of Siversk comes with Ukraine under US pressure to quickly</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 09:51:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BSEC extends deadline for provisioning of 6 market intermediaries</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bsec-extends-deadline-for-provisioning-of-6-market-intermediaries</link><description>The Bangladesh Securities and Exchange Commission (BSEC), the country’s capital market regulator, has decided to conditionally extend the deadline for provision conservation and adjustment for six additional intermediary institutions.
This decision aims to provide relief to firms struggling</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 10:06:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>February polls must not be postponed, NCP tells EC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/february-polls-must-not-be-postponed-ncp-tells-election-commission</link><description>The National Citizen Party (NCP) has demanded the parliamentary elections and the referendum be held on the scheduled date without any postponement.
NCP Chief Coordinator Nasiruddin Patwary spoke about it on Wednesday after meeting with Chief Election Commissioner AMM Nasir Uddin at the Nirbachan</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 10:21:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Airport area elevated expressway toll plaza to be toll-free for 4 hours Thursday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/airport-area-elevated-expressway-toll-plaza-to-be-toll-free-for-4-hours-thursday</link><description>The toll plaza of the elevated expressway in the airport area will remain toll-free for the general people for two hours on Thursday.
Vehicles entering Dhaka city through the airport area elevated expressway will not have to pay any toll from 11 am to 3 pm, according to the Chief Adviser’s p</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 10:36:14 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>