<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 11:23:33 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Unidentified man found dead in Chuadanga</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/unidentified-man-found-dead-in-chuadanga</link><description>Police recovered the body of an unidentified man from a corn field at Kayetpara in Alamdanga upazila of Chuadanga district on Thursday.
Local people first spotted the body of the man, aged about 38–40, wearing trousers and a navy-blue jacket, in the field around 9:00 am and informed the poli</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 08:27:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No election code violation in Tarique’s northern region tour: Salahuddin</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/no-election-code-violation-in-tariques-northern-region-tour-salahuddin</link><description>BNP senior leader Salahuddin Ahmed on Thursday said the upcoming four-day tour of the northern region by party Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman will not violate the election code of conduct, as it is meant to pay homage to the martyrs of the July mass uprising.
"Some people may be viewing this tour</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 08:58:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh issues Forest and Tree Conservation Ordinance 2026 with Tk 100,000 fine</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-issues-forest-and-tree-conservation-ordinance-2026-with-tk-100000-fine</link><description>The Bangladesh government has issued the Forest and Tree Ordinance 2026 with the aim of preventing the occupation of forest land, regulating the use of forest land for non-forest purposes, ensuring proper conservation of forests and forest land, preventing the reduction of forest areas, and protect</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 09:13:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Teenager killed in Madaripur road crash</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/teenager-killed-in-madaripur-road-crash</link><description>A teenager was killed and another injured in a road accident at Rajoir upazila of Madaripur district on Wednesday night.
The deceased was identified as Osman, 19, son of Billal Howlader of Uttaripara village under Rangabali Police Station in Patuakhali district. He was a student of Baitul Noor Cad</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 09:28:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Israel hits Gaza launch site following failed rocket fire</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/israeli-military-says-it-hit-gaza-launch-site-following-failed-rocket-fire</link><description>The Israeli military said that it identified a failed rocket launch from near Gaza City on Thursday and subsequently struck the launch site.
A Hamas source said the group was checking the Israeli allegation.</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 08:45:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Eastern Bank hosts month-long Entrepreneur Development Training under SICIP</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/eastern-bank-hosts-month-long-entrepreneur-development-training-under-sicip</link><description>Eastern Bank PLC (EBL) has launched a month-long Entrepreneur Development Training Program as part of its ongoing efforts to support entrepreneurship in Bangladesh.
The program is being implemented under the Skills for Industry Competitiveness and Innovation Program (SICIP), led by the Ministry of</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 09:00:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pakistan, Saudi in talks on JF-17 jets-for-loans deal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/pakistan-saudi-in-talks-on-jf-17-jets-for-loans-deal-sources-say</link><description>Pakistan and Saudi Arabia are in talks to convert about $2 billion of Saudi loans into a JF-17 fighter jet deal, two Pakistani sources said, deepening military cooperation months after the two nations signed a mutual defence pact last year.
The talks underscore how the two allies are moving to ope</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 09:15:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Illegal iPhone assembly factory busted in Dhaka; 3 Chinese nationals held</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/illegal-iphone-assembly-factory-busted-in-dhaka-3-chinese-nationals-held</link><description>Police have uncovered an illegal iPhone assembly factory operated by some Chinese nationals and arrested three of them from separate areas in the capital.
Detective Branch Mirpur Division Deputy Commissioner Mahiuddin Mahmud Sohel disclosed the information on at a press briefing at the DMP media c</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 09:30:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nasiruddin Patwary aims to spend Tk 2.7m on campaign</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/nasiruddin-patwary-aims-to-spend-tk-27m-on-campaign-will-provide-tk-100000-himself</link><description>Jatiya Nagorik Committee Chief Convenor Mohammad Nasiruddin Patwary plans to spend Tk 2.7 million in his campaign for the Dhaka-8 parliamentary seat in the upcoming general election, but plans to only contribute Tk 100,000 of his own money to the war chest.
In an affidavit submitted to the Electio</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 09:45:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A familiar refrain as China and Japan, uneasy neighbors in East Asia, begin 2026 at odds again</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/a-familiar-refrain-as-china-and-japan-uneasy-neighbors-in-east-asia-begin-2026-at-odds-again</link><description>They’re at it again.
China and Japan — frenemies, trading partners and uneasy neighbors with a tortured, bloody history they still struggle to navigate — are freshly at each other’s rhetorical throats as 2026 begins. And it’s over the same sticking points that have ke</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 10:00:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Energy ministry proposes VAT cut to below 10pc on LPG imports</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/energy-ministry-proposes-vat-cut-to-below-10pc-on-lpg-imports</link><description>The Ministry of Power, Energy and Mineral Resources has recommended cutting value-added tax (VAT) on liquefied petroleum gas (LPG) imports to below 10 percent by reinstating a 15 percent VAT exemption at the import stage. 
"To maintain normal supply of LP gas in the market, the advisory counc</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 10:15:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ICT Division's white paper published</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ict-divisions-white-paper-published</link><description>The Information and Communication Technology (ICT) Division on Tuesday published the white paper prepared by a task force formed to investigate irregularities and mismanagement in ICT-related initiatives undertaken during the previous government.
The white paper, now available on the ICT Division&amp;</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 10:30:42 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>