<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 05:20:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Government tightens grip on financial rules</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/government-tightens-grip-on-financial-rules</link><description>In a fresh push to restore fiscal discipline across public offices, the government has reminded all ministries and agencies that no financial directive can be issued without the Finance Division's consent.
The warning comes amid growing concern over ministries and divisions issuing revenue-related</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 02:01:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt plans to trim foreign project aid</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/govt-plans-to-trim-foreign-project-aid</link><description>The government is preparing to reduce foreign project aid in the current fiscal year's Annual Development Programme (ADP) as ministries and divisions continue to lag behind in project execution.
Officials said consultations will begin next week to reassess how much of the Tk 860 billion project ai</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 02:16:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BD less exposed to AI risks: Report</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bd-less-exposed-to-ai-risks-report</link><description>Bangladesh's job market remains among the least exposed to the rapid rise of artificial intelligence (AI) compared to other emerging economies, according to a new World Bank report.
Only 1.44 per cent of total jobs in Bangladesh are related to AI, far below 7.29 per cent in Sri Lanka and 5.8 per c</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 02:31:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CAAB mulls operating HSIA's third terminal on its own</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/caab-mulls-operating-hsias-third-terminal-on-its-own</link><description>The Civil Aviation Authority of Bangladesh (CAAB) is considering operating the newly built third terminal of Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport (HSIA) with its own manpower and expertise, as negotiations with a Japanese consortium over its operation and maintenance have hit a stalemate.
Talks</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 02:46:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Regulator tightens margin lending to cleanse market of negative equity</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/regulator-tightens-margin-lending-to-cleanse-market-of-negative-equity</link><description>The new margin rules awaiting gazette notification are meant to keep both lenders and borrowers out of the negative equity trap.
Some vested quarters opposed them, but the regulator has stayed firm in its position to bring necessary changes in loan facilities for investment in the secondary market</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 03:01:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>MTB fast-tracks digital shift, eyes 'voice banking' for tech-savvy clients</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/mtb-fast-tracks-digital-shift-eyes-voice-banking-for-tech-savvy-clients</link><description>Mutual Trust Bank (MTB) PLC has intensified its focus on digital transformation to meet the banking needs of the rapidly expanding, technologically adept population more conveniently.
As part of the bank's 'physital' (physical and digital) banking approach, the bank has been partnering with fintec</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 03:31:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>First US wheat shipment arrives at Ctg port</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/first-us-wheat-shipment-arrives-at-ctg-port</link><description>A vessel carrying around 57,000 tonnes of wheat from the United States has docked at Chattogram Port, marking the start of US wheat imports under a government-to-government (G2G) agreement between Bangladesh and the US.
The vessel, MV Norse Stride, anchored at the port to deliver 56,959 tonnes of</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 03:46:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ERF Institute hosts first training course</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/others/Erf-institute-hosts-first-training-course</link><description>The ERF Institute, run by the Economic Reporters Forum (ERF), launched its first-ever training course on Saturday, aiming to enhance the skills of economic journalists.
The daylong session, focused on data journalism, was held at the ERF auditorium in Paltan Tower in Dhaka.
A total of 20 particip</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 04:01:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Beximco Pharma provides access to affordable version</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/beximco-pharma-provides-access-to-affordable-version</link><description>The Beximco Pharmaceuticals will make available 'Triko', its brand medicine for generic version of Trikafta used to treat Cystic fibrosis (CF), at an affordable cost from spring 2026. CF is a life-threatening genetic disorder with very low life expectancy, says a press release.
Triko will cost US$</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 04:16:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Students prepare for Tech Fusion Fest 2025</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/article/students-prepare-for-tech-fusion-fest-2025</link><description>Excitement builds at the Bangladesh University of Business and Technology (BUBT) as students gear up for Tech Fusion Fest 2025. This highly anticipated technology festival, organised by the BASIS Students' Forum of BUBT Chapter, will take place on November 17, 18, and 19 this year. The entire campu</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 04:31:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Opportunities to save and invest for young people</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/article/opportunities-to-save-and-invest-for-young-people</link><description>Think about this: whilst one person scrolls through social media for an hour, someone their age somewhere else just earned enough returns to buy three months of groceries. The difference isn't luck. It's a matter of where money was positioned last year.
Bangladesh stands at a peculiar crossroads.</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 04:46:17 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>