<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 05:31:13 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>India to relocate families of diplomats from Bangladesh citing 'safety risks': Report</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/india-plans-to-relocate-families-of-diplomats-from-bangladesh-citing-safety-risks-report</link><description>India has reportedly decided to make Bangladesh a 'non-family' posting for its diplomats, advising the families of officials stationed in the country to return home citing security concerns.
The Hindustan Times, citing sources familiar with the matter, said all five Indian missions in Bangladesh w</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 02:00:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Islami Andolan set to contest 259 seats</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/islami-andolan-set-to-contest-259-seats-after-jamaat-allaince-exit</link><description>Islami Andolan Bangladesh will contest the election in 259 constituencies, down from an earlier plan to field candidates in 268 seats, following its withdrawal from the Jamaat-e-Islami-led 11-party alliance.
The Islamist party announced earlier this month that it would run independently after brea</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 02:15:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>After Trump salvo, Macron says: we don't give in to bullies</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/after-trump-salvo-macron-says-we-dont-give-in-to-bullies</link><description>French President Emmanuel Macron on Tuesday said Europe would not give in to bullies or be intimidated, in a scathing criticism of US President Donald Trump's threat to impose steep tariffs if Europe does not let him take over Greenland.
While other European leaders have tried to keep a measured t</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 02:30:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Beijing's GDP surpasses 5 trillion yuan mark</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/global/beijings-gdp-surpasses-5-trillion-yuan-mark</link><description>Chinese capital Beijing's GDP exceeded 5.207 trillion yuan (about 743.79 billion U.S. dollars) in 2025, up 5.4 per cent year on year, surpassing the 5 trillion yuan mark for the first time, according to the municipal statistics bureau.</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 02:45:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US to cut roughly 200 NATO positions</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-to-cut-roughly-200-nato-positions</link><description>The United States plans to reduce the number of personnel it has stationed within several key NATO command centers, a move that could intensify concerns in Europe about Washington's commitment to the alliance, three sources familiar with the matter said this week.
As part of the move, which the Tr</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 03:00:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>National election: Symbol allocation today, campaign kickoff tomorrow</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/symbol-allocation-today-campaign-kickoff-tomorrow</link><description>A most-watched election process picks into its culmination as symbols to parties and independent contenders will be allocated today before campaign trails kick off tomorrow.
The Election Commission (EC) will allocate the voting symbols today as the deadline for candidature withdrawal was over Tues</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 03:00:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ACI's growth paradox: A profitable parent, bleeding subsidiaries</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/acis-growth-paradox-a-profitable-parent-bleeding-subsidiaries</link><description>ACI has continued expanding into new territories despite its already launched subsidiaries and associate companies weighing heavily on its business and pushing it into the red.
In FY25, ACI's standalone profit stood at about Tk 3.99 billion, up 19 per cent from the previous year. However, the comp</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 03:15:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>2025 -- a year of rebound for UCB, says its MD</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/2025-a-year-of-rebound-for-ucb-says-its-md</link><description>The significant turnaround of the United Commercial Bank (UCB) from a prolonged liquidity crisis will be a key topic of discussion in the coming days as far as transformation in the banking industry is concerned, said the bank's Managing Director and CEO Mohammad Mamdudur Rashid.
In an exclusive i</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 03:30:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Olympic Industries to acquire stake in proposed firm, buy land in Narayanganj</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/olympic-industries-to-acquire-stake-in-proposed-firm-buy-land-in-narayanganj</link><description>Leading biscuit maker Olympic Industries has decided to buy land to expand its operations and make a new investment of Tk 2 million in a proposed company.
According to a disclosure, the investment will be made in Tripti Industries (proposed) in exchange for 200,000 ordinary shares at a face value</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 03:45:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Onus of pay-hike burden left to oncoming govt</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/onus-of-pay-hike-burden-left-to-oncoming-govt</link><description>An additional Tk 800 billion may be needed in fully implementing the proposed new pay scale for public employees, officials say as the Pay Commission is set to submit its report today.
Finance Adviser Dr Salehuddin Ahmed explains the modus operandi of executing the pay scale with salary hikes, lea</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 04:00:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Next polls a ‘hard test’ for country's future: Fakhrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/next-polls-a-hard-test-for-countrys-future-fakhrul</link><description>BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir on Tuesday described the next national elections as a "hard test" for the country's future.
"The election will decide whether Bangladesh remains under liberal democracy or falls into the hands of extremist and anti-state forces," he said at a discu</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 04:51:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>H1 tax revenue posts double-digit growth</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/h1-tax-revenue-posts-double-digit-growth</link><description>The tax revenue collection posted double-digit growth, more than 14 per cent, in the first half of the current fiscal year (H1), but the gains were not enough to offset a widening gap against official targets.
Provisional figures show that while domestic revenue mobilisation improved year on year,</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 05:06:41 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>