<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 12:50:43 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>In JD Vance case, US Supreme Court may again chip away campaign finance limits</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/in-jd-vance-case-us-supreme-court-may-again-chip-away-campaign-finance-limits</link><description>The US Supreme Court for decades has chipped away at campaign finance laws, deciding they suppress political speech in violation of constitutional protections. A case involving US Vice President JD Vance being argued next week gives the court and its conservative majority a chance to amplify this t</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 10:46:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Did the US military commit a war crime in boat attack off Venezuela?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/did-the-us-military-commit-a-war-crime-in-boat-attack-off-venezuela</link><description>Members of Congress have said they will investigate whether the US military broke the law by allegedly killing two survivors of a strike on a suspected drug trafficking vessel in the Caribbean. The White House has defended the strike as lawful.
Below is a look at the potential legal violations in</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 11:01:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt set to implement Tk 40.62 billion project to strengthen reproductive health</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/govt-set-to-implement-tk-4062-billion-project-to-strengthen-reproductive-health</link><description>The government is set to strengthen reproductive health and family planning services across the country with the introduction of a major new initiative titled "Climate Responsive Reproductive Health and Population Services Improvement and System Strengthening Project for Result." 
The project</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 11:16:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh's economic policy not dictated by IMF or WB: BB Governor</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/bangladeshs-economic-policy-not-dictated-by-imf-or-wb-bb-governor</link><description>Bangladesh Bank Governor Dr Ahsan H Mansur on Thursday said the country's economic policy is independently formulated and not dictated by the International Monetary Fund (IMF) or the World Bank.
"If we follow their prescriptions blindly, the exchange rate could surge to around Tk 170-180 per US do</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 10:30:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EU launches antitrust probe into Meta over use of AI in WhatsApp</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/eu-launches-antitrust-probe-into-meta-over-use-of-ai-in-whatsapp</link><description>Brussels has opened a new antitrust investigation into Meta Platforms (META.O) over its rollout of artificial intelligence features in WhatsApp, the European Commission said on Thursday, reflecting rising scrutiny of Big Tech's use of generative AI.
The move, reported earlier by Reuters and the Fi</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 10:45:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UK energy bills to rise after $37bn grid upgrade</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/uk-consumers-face-higher-energy-bills-after-regulator-approves-37-billion-grid-upgrade</link><description>British energy regulator has approved a 28 billion pound ($37.33 billion) investment over the next five years to ensure a safe and reliable energy system in the future, part of an upgrade plan that will add 108 pounds to consumer bills by 2031.
The investment is higher than a provisional assessmen</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 11:00:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Putin vows to seize all of Donbas ‘militarily or otherwise’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/putin-says-russia-will-take-all-of-ukraines-donbas-region-militarily-or-otherwise</link><description>President Vladimir Putin said in an interview published on Thursday that Russia would take full control of Ukraine's Donbas region by force unless Ukrainian forces withdraw, something Kyiv has flatly rejected.
Putin sent tens of thousands of troops into Ukraine in February 2022 after eight years o</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 11:15:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Panama's Copa suspends flights to Venezuela, citing signal problem</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/panamas-copa-suspends-flights-to-venezuela-citing-signal-problem</link><description>Panamanian carrier Copa Airlines has suspended Thursday and Friday flights to and from Venezuela's capital Caracas, citing a navigation signal issue reported by its pilots.
The issue did not compromise flight safety, the company added in a statement published late Wednesday.
WHY IT MATTERS
&amp;bull</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 11:30:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khaleda Zia only VVIP entitled to prescribed state facilities: Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/khaleda-zia-only-vvip-entitled-to-prescribed-state-facilities-adviser</link><description>Environment Adviser Syeda Rizwana Hasan on Thursday said only former Prime Minister and BNP Chairperson Khaleda Zia, as of now, is entitled to receive the prescribed facilities designated for a ‘very, very important person’ (VVIP) of the State.
The government has declared Khaleda Zia a</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 11:45:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Engage Toolkit’ will play a significant role in developing children’s creativity and intelligence: Speakers at BRAC IED event</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/engage-toolkit-will-play-a-significant-role-in-developing-childrens-creativity-and-intelligence-speakers-at-brac-ied-event</link><description>Teachers in traditional education settings often prioritise academic curricula and plan classroom activities based on their own preferences. In contrast, the Engage Toolkit places greater emphasis on children’s abilities, interests and choices, speakers said at an event in Cox’s Bazar t</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 12:00:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Turkey told Russia, Ukraine to keep energy infrastructure out of war, minister says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/turkey-told-russia-ukraine-to-keep-energy-infrastructure-out-of-war-minister-says</link><description>Turkey is telling Russia, Ukraine, and all other parties to keep energy infrastructure out of their conflict and wants energy flows to continue uninterrupted, Energy Minister Alparslan Bayraktar said after a series of attacks off Turkey's Black Sea coast.
Ukraine, which is targeting Russia's oil e</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 12:15:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khaleda to be flown to UK for advanced treatment: Fakhrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/khaleda-to-be-flown-to-uk-for-advanced-treatment-fakhrul</link><description>BNP Chairperson Begum Khaleda Zia may be flown to the United Kingdom early Friday for advanced treatment by a royal air ambulance provided by the Emir of Qatar, said party Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir on Thursday.
“You have already heard that we have received a highly advanc</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 12:30:43 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>