<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 17:38:17 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Pakistan says its air strikes hit 22 Afghan military targets, killing 274</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/pakistan-says-its-air-strikes-hit-22-afghan-military-targets-killing-274</link><description>Pakistani air strikes hit 22 Afghan military targets, Pakistan's military spokesperson said on Friday, after heavy fighting between the South Asian neighbours that began overnight.
At least 12 Pakistani soldiers were killed and 274 Taliban officials and militants were killed since Thursday night,</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 13:48:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Investment drive key to economic uplift: Khosru</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/local-and-foreign-investment-vital-for-jobs-economic-transition-says-finance-minister</link><description>Finance and Planning Minister Amir Khosru Mahmud Chowdhury has stressed the importance of domestic and foreign investment for Bangladesh’s economic recovery.
Speaking on Friday during a visit to a proposed hospital site at Patenga Marine Drive in Chattogram, he said boosting investment is &amp;l</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 14:03:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Iran stored highly enriched uranium at underground site, IAEA report says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/iran-stored-highly-enriched-uranium-at-underground-site-iaea-report-says</link><description>Some of Iran's most highly enriched uranium, close to weapons grade, was stored in an underground area of its nuclear site in Isfahan, the UN nuclear watchdog said in a confidential report sent to member states on Friday and seen by Reuters.
It is the first time the International Atomic Energy Age</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 14:18:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Passengers detained at Dhaka airport with foreign currencies worth over Tk 38 million</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/passengers-detained-at-dhaka-airport-with-foreign-currencies-worth-over-tk-38-million</link><description>Two passengers have been detained at Shahjalal International Airport with foreign currencies worth over Tk 38 million, according to the Customs Intelligence and Investigation Directorate.
On Friday, the agency said in a media statement that the seized currencies from the detainees include Saudi ri</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 14:33:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Children enchanted by puppet show at Ekushey Book Fair</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/children-enchanted-by-puppet-show-at-ekushey-book-fair</link><description>Children watched the puppet show with wide-eyed fascination as the second day of the Amar Ekushey Book Fair began in a lively atmosphere amid their cheerful presence.
The fairgrounds gained a different level of vibrancy from the morning, with a strong presence of young visitors on the weekly holid</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 15:03:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>PM exchanges warm greetings with children after Jumu'ah prayers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/pm-exchanges-warm-greetings-with-children-after-jumuah-prayers</link><description>Prime Minister Tarique Rahman exchanged warm greetings with children after offering the Jumu'ah prayers at a mosque in the city on Friday.
"Prime Minister Tarique Rahman offered Jumu'ah prayers at the Naval Headquarters mosque here. After the prayers, he met children gathered outside the mosque an</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 15:18:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BRAC Bank hosts ‘TARA Uddokta Mela 2026’ to showcase all-women entrepreneur products</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/brac-bank-hosts-tara-uddokta-mela-2026-to-showcase-all-women-entrepreneur-products</link><description>BRAC Bank has hosted ‘TARA Uddokta Mela 2026’, a three-day fair to promote locally made products by women entrepreneurs and create a market for them, according to a press release.
Inaugurated 27 February 2026, the fair will remain open to the public until March 1, 2026, every day from</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 15:33:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Afghan Taliban open to talks after Pakistan bombs Kabul, Kandahar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/afghan-taliban-open-to-talks-after-pakistan-bombs-kabul-kandahar</link><description>Afghanistan's Taliban rulers said on Friday they were willing to negotiate after Pakistan bombed its forces in major cities and dozens of troops were killed in the most serious clashes between the allies-turned-foes.
The strikes by Pakistan were the first time it had directly targeted its former a</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 16:34:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UK withdraws staff from Iran temporarily</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/uk-withdraws-staff-from-iran-temporarily</link><description>Britain said on Friday it had temporarily withdrawn its staff from Iran citing the security situation in the region.
US President Donald Trump briefly laid out his case for a possible attack on Iran in his State of the Union speech on Tuesday, underlining that while he preferred a diplomatic solut</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 16:53:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DSCC warns contractors over extra waste charges</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/waste-collectors-charging-above-tk-100-will-face-action-says-dscc-administrator</link><description>Dhaka South City Corporation (DSCC) Administrator Abdus Salam has warned that contractors will face consequences if they charge more than Tk 100 for collecting household waste.
At an Iftar event on Friday, he said any contractor found demanding more than the fixed amount would have their primary c</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 17:08:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Family blame loan shark for man’s death</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/family-allege-murder-over-loan-interest-as-man-found-hanging-in-madaripur</link><description>The family of a man whose body was found hanging from a tree near his house in Madaripur has alleged he was murdered after he failed to pay loan interest.
Relatives and local residents held a human chain and protest in Shibchar Upazila on Friday, demanding a fair investigation and the arrest of th</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 17:23:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt bans fishing in Padma-Meghna for 2 months to protect jatka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-bans-fishing-in-padma-meghna-for-2-months-to-protect-jatka</link><description>The government has imposed a two-month ban on catching all types of fish, including hilsa, in the Padma River and Meghna River from Saturday midnight to boost hilsa production and conserve jatka.
The restriction will remain in force from March 1 to April 30, during which fishing, sale, transport a</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 17:38:17 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>