<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 17:20:54 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Shut down University Teachers’ Network: RUCSU GS</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rucsu-gs-ammar-calls-for-university-teachers-network-to-be-shut-down</link><description>Rajshahi University Central Student Union General Secretary Salahuddin Ammar has called for the University Teachers’ Network to be shut down.
He made this call in response to a statement made by the platform on Sunday titled “Stop the unauthorised activities of student representatives</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 14:59:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Stocks extend losses for second day at DSE</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/stocks-extend-losses-for-second-day-at-dse</link><description>Bangladesh’s stock market continued its downward trend for the second consecutive session on Monday, with key indices falling at the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) and losses also recorded at the Chittagong Stock Exchange (CSE).
At the DSE, the benchmark DSEX index shed 7 points, while the Shari</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 15:14:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>JnUCSU election on Tuesday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/jnucsu-election-on-tuesday</link><description>The Jagannath University Central Students’ Union (JnUCSU) and Hall Students’ Union elections will be held on Tuesday.
Voting will start at 9:00 am and continue until 3:00 pm without any break.
A total of 16,500 students are expected to exercise their voting rights at 178 booths across</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 15:29:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>39 candidates file nominations in Gopalganj</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/39-candidates-file-nominations-in-gopalganj</link><description>A total of 39 candidates submitted nomination papers for three parliamentary seats in Gopalganj till Monday, the final day for filing nominations for the 13th national election.
Despite a cold wave, the offices of the district commissioner and returning officer, as well as the election office, saw</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 15:44:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Health protection scheme launched for urban sanitation workers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/health-protection-scheme-launched-for-urban-sanitation-workers</link><description>The Dhaka North City Corporation (DNCC), in collaboration with SAJIDA Foundation and Harpic, on Sunday launched Shasthya Nirapotta Scheme (SNS), a health insurance policy, for its sanitation workers, aiming to improve their access to healthcare services.
Under the scheme, sanitation workers will b</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 15:59:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Manju backs out of election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jatiya-partys-anwar-hossain-manju-withdraws-from-election</link><description>Jatiya Party (JP) Chairman Anwar Hossain Manju has withdrawn from the parliamentary elections, choosing not to submit his nomination papers.
He had collected nomination papers for the Pirojpur-2 constituency but ultimately decided against contesting.
Speaking on Monday, the last day of submission</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 15:30:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Russian army chief tells Putin Moscow's troops are advancing, Ukraine is on the defensive</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/russian-army-chief-tells-putin-moscows-troops-are-advancing-ukraine-is-on-the-defensive</link><description>General Valery Gerasimov, the chief of Russia's General Staff, said on Monday that Moscow's forces were advancing in Ukraine along the entire front line, while Kyiv's forces were by contrast focused on defence and attempting to counter attack.
In a televised meeting with President Vladimir Putin a</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 15:45:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Iraq parliament elects Halbousi as speaker in first post-election session</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/iraq-parliament-elects-halbousi-as-speaker-in-first-post-election-session</link><description>Iraq's parliament elected Sunni Muslim lawmaker Haibat al-Halbousi as speaker at its opening session on Monday following November's national election, launching a process to form a new government that often takes months.
A parliamentary statement said Halbousi secured 208 out of a total of 283 vot</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 16:00:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chinese researchers establish new model to predict human organ aging</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/chinese-researchers-establish-new-model-to-predict-human-organ-aging</link><description>A team of Chinese researchers has recently developed a model to predict the aging of 13 human organs, including the brain, enabling precise assessment of organ aging levels, the China Science Daily reported on Monday.
Previous research focused mainly on the common features of overall aging or expl</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 16:15:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hamas confirms death of spokesman of its military wing</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/hamas-confirms-death-of-spokesman-of-its-military-wing</link><description>Hamas' armed wing, the Al-Qassam Brigades, announced on Monday that its military spokesperson Abu Obeida had been killed during the Israeli offensive on the Gaza Strip.
The announcement was made by a newly-appointed spokesperson, who assumed the same nom de guerre, Abu Obeida, during a televised p</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 16:30:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Joint effort needed for quality telecom services: Taiyeb</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/joint-effort-needed-for-quality-telecom-services-taiyeb</link><description>Chief Adviser's Special Assistant for the Ministry of Posts, Telecommunications and Information Technology Faiz Ahmad Taiyeb on Monday urged the concerned authorities to work together to ensure uninterrupted and improved telecommunication services.
He made the call while inspecting the Third Subma</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 16:45:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>2,582 candidates submitted nomination papers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/2582-candidates-submitted-nomination-papers</link><description>A total of 2,582 candidates have submitted nomination papers to contest from the country’s 300 constituencies in the 13th general election slated for February 12, 2026.
As many as 3,407 aspirants collected nomination papers, but 2,582 ones filed nomination papers, according to the statistics</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 17:00:56 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>