<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 04:31:17 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Italian PM to focus on migration, trade during Dhaka visit</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/italian-pm-to-focus-on-migration-trade-during-dhaka-visit</link><description>Migration and trade will top the agenda during the Italian Prime Minister's upcoming visit to Dhaka, scheduled for late December, Italian Ambassador to Bangladesh Antonio Alessandro said on Sunday.
Speaking to reporters after a meeting at the Ministry of Foreign Affairs, the envoy noted that the h</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 01:10:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NBR rejects claims of restrictions on Benapole land port operation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nbr-rejects-claims-of-restrictions-on-benapole-land-port-operation</link><description>The National Board of Revenue (NBR) on Sunday dismissed media reports claiming that customs authorities had imposed restrictions on import and export operations through the Benapole land port after 6:00 pm.
In a clarification, the NBR said no new order or restrictions had been imposed by the custo</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 01:25:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Moscow seeks consent to opening Sberbank liaison office in BD</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/moscow-seeks-consent-to-opening-sberbank-liaison-office-in-bd</link><description>Russia is pressing Bangladesh for allowing its Sberbank to establish a liaison or branch office for helping resolve multi-million dollar outstanding payments for the Rooppur Nuclear Power Plant (NPP) and defense equipment.
The proposal was made during recent high-level meetings in Moscow between t</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 01:40:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Grameenphone Q3 profit dips slightly despite higher revenue</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/grameenphone-q3-profit-dips-slightly-despite-higher-revenue</link><description>Despite higher revenue, Grameenphone's profit dropped slightly by 0.52 per cent year-on-year to Tk 7.51 billion in July-September this year, due to higher energy costs and operating expenses.
The leading telecom operator's revenue stood at Tk 40.10 billion for July-September this year, registering</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 01:55:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tick size cut to keep ‘penny stocks’ tradable</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/tick-size-cut-to-keep-penny-stocks-tradable</link><description>With some stocks trading around Tk 1 per share, the prime bourse has reduced the smallest allowable price deviation in each transaction for such securities to Tk 0.01 from the existing Tk 0.10.
The decision will come into effect on October 29, according to a stock exchange filing on Sunday, aimed</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 02:10:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Kohinoor Chemical to pay record dividends for FY25, boosted by record profits</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/kohinoor-chemical-to-pay-record-dividends-for-fy25-boosted-by-record-profits</link><description>Kohinoor Chemical posted a record profit of Tk 632 million in FY25, driven by higher sales and a reduction in raw material prices.
With that, the company registered more than 24 per cent year-on-year profit growth for the year through June, according to price-sensitive information published on Sun</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 02:25:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BSEC forms 9-member Shariah advisory council</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/bsec-forms-9-member-shariah-advisory-council</link><description>The securities regulator has formed a nine-member Shariah advisory council to facilitate the issuance of Shariah-compliant securities and promote the development of an Islamic capital market.
The Bangladesh Securities and Exchange Commission (BSEC) on Sunday announced the names of the council memb</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 02:40:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Credit card spending climbs 35pc in Aug amid digital shift</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/credit-card-spending-climbs-35pc-in-aug-amid-digital-shift</link><description>Credit card usage in Bangladesh has surged sharply over the past year, reflecting stronger consumer confidence and an uptick in retail activity in the domestic market.
According to the latest data from Bangladesh Bank (BB), domestic credit card transactions increased by 34.84 per cent between Augu</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 02:55:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>HC issues rule on ex-CJ Khairul Haque's bail</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/hc-issues-rule-on-ex-cj-khairul-haques-bail</link><description>The High Court on Sunday issued a rule asking the respondents to explain in two weeks as to why former Chief Justice Khairul Haque should not be granted bail in five cases filed against him.
The High Court bench of Justice A S M Abdul Mobin and Justice Md Sagir Hossain passed the order, after hear</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 03:10:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Global financial, technical support crucial to ensure climate justice: Rizwana</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/global-financial-technical-support-crucial-to-ensure-climate-justice-rizwana</link><description>Global financial and technical support is crucial to ensure climate justice in Bangladesh, said Ministry of Environment, Forest and Climate Change Advisor Syeda Rizwana Hasan.
She noted that it is vital to enhance research, policy formulation, and action planning within the administration to stren</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 03:25:23 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>