<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 10:49:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Excessive use of fertilisers and pesticides has become a threat: Food Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/excessive-use-of-fertilisers-and-pesticides-has-become-a-threat-food-adviser</link><description>Food and Land Adviser Ali Imam Majumder on Monday said the excessive use of fertilisers and pesticides to boost crop production has become a serious threat to food safety.
He said artificial fertilisers and pesticides were not used in agriculture in the past. Later, agricultural officials encourag</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 07:29:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Political violence claims 158 lives, injures thousands in 17 months: TIB</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/political-violence-claims-158-lives-injures-thousands-in-17-months-tib</link><description>At least 158 political activists were killed and 7,082 others injured in 600 incidents of political violence across the country over 17 months, according to a study by Transparency International Bangladesh (TIB).
The findings were disclosed on Monday at a press conference at TIB’s office in</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 07:44:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Economic challenges await next elected government: Finance adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/economic-challenges-await-next-elected-government-finance-adviser-says</link><description>Finance Adviser Salehuddin Ahmed has cautioned that major economic challenges lie ahead for the next elected government, noting that while the interim administration has managed to bring relative stability to the economy, further reforms are needed.
He made the remarks on Monday while speaking at</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 07:59:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DMP opens dedicated hotline for election complaints</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dmp-opens-dedicated-hotline-for-election-complaints</link><description>The Dhaka Metropolitan Police (DMP) has launched a dedicated hotline to receive information or complaints related to the upcoming parliamentary election and referendum.
In a statement on Sunday, the DMP said the hotline numbers will allow the public to report election-related grievances “qui</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 08:14:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique urges women to decide how to respond to parties that 'insult' them</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-urges-women-to-decide-how-to-respond-to-parties-that-insult-them</link><description>BNP chief Tarique Rahman has urged women to decide how to respond to political parties that "disrespect" them, warning that a country cannot be “safe” in the hands of those who lack respect for people’s dignity.
Speaking at an election rally in Khulna on Monday, he said: “T</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 08:29:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gaza border reopening long awaited by stranded Palestinians</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/gaza-border-reopening-long-awaited-by-stranded-palestinians</link><description>Cut off from family or urgently requiring hospital care, Palestinians stranded on each side of Gaza's Rafah crossing waited with growing desperation for Monday's reopening of the border as a delayed part of October's ceasefire deal.
How fully crossings to and from Egypt will resume, and under what</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 08:44:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh to restore examinations for Class 1 and Class 2</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-to-restore-examinations-for-class-1-and-class-2</link><description>Students in the primary grades of Class 1 and Class 2 will once again face regular examinations, reports bdnews24.com.
The two classes had previously discontinued exams in 2023 following the implementation of a new curriculum formulated by the previous government.
However, after three years, the</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 08:59:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Travel ban on former Petrobangla director Rafiqul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/travel-ban-on-former-petrobangla-director-rafiqul</link><description>A Dhaka court today (Monday) imposed a travel ban on former director of Bangladesh Oil, Gas and Mineral Corporation (Petrobangla) Rafiqul Islam over corruption charges.
Dhaka Metropolitan Senior Special Judge Md Sabbir Faiz passed the order, allowing a plea of the Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC),</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 09:14:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh beat India 2-0 in SAFF U-19 Women's Championship</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/bangladesh-beat-india-2-0-in-saff-u-19-womens-championship</link><description>Bangladesh under-19 women’s national football team on way to the final of SAFF U-19 Women’s Championship as they beat India by 2-0 goals in their second match held at Pokhara Rangasala Stadium in Pokhara, Nepal on Monday.
With this win, Bangladesh women are now one step away from the f</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 09:29:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gavaskar predicts potential ‘U-turn’ from Pakistan despite boycott announcement</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/cricket/gavaskar-predicts-potential-u-turn-from-pakistan-despite-boycott-announcement</link><description>Indian cricket legends Sunil Gavaskar and Madan Lal have strongly criticised Pakistan’s decision to boycott their T20 World Cup group-stage match against India, warning that the move will ultimately cause more harm to Pakistan cricket than to the tournament organisers.
The reaction comes a d</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 09:44:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No approval for artificial hilsa farming: govt</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-rules-out-artificial-hilsa-farming-without-policy-approval</link><description>The interim government has not granted approval for hilsa cultivation through artificial or controlled means, according to the Ministry of Fisheries and Livestock.
The ministry issued a press release on Monday clarifying that no individual or organisation has received permission to farm hilsa or c</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 09:59:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>LPG, autogas prices raised for February</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/lpg-autogas-prices-raised-for-february</link><description>The Bangladesh Energy Regulatory Commission (BERC) has announced new retail prices for liquefied petroleum gas (LPG), raising the cost of a 12-kg cylinder by Tk 50 for February.
According to the new pricing, the retail price of a 12-kg LPG cylinder has been fixed at Tk 1,356, up from Tk 1,306. The</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 10:14:03 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>