<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 03:22:06 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Austerity and its uneven burden on revised ADP</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/austerity-and-its-uneven-burden-on-revised-adp</link><description>The scale and composition of the Revised Annual Development Programme (RADP) for the current fiscal year reveal a far larger contraction than many had anticipated, particularly in sectors that underpin human development. While some degree of rationalisation was inevitable amid tight fiscal space, r</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 18:15:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Post-July 2024 efforts at revamping judiciary</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/post-july-2024-efforts-at-revamping-judiciary</link><description>Bangladesh's judicial system has faced many challenges since the country's in dependence. The 1972 Constitution, for instance, established a Supreme Court and formally adopted the principle of the separation of the judiciary from the executive organs of the state. The development of the judiciary h</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 18:30:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>15 hurt in BNP-Jamaat scuffle in Bhola</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bnp-jamaat-scuffle-leaves-15-people-injured-in-bhola-on-victory-day</link><description>At least 15 people have been injured in a scuffle between the activists of the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) and Jamaat-e-Islami during a Victory Day event in Bhola’s Daulatkhan.
Daulatkhan Police chief Saiful Islam Shikder said the incident occurred at the Ghaznavi Stadium on Tuesday.</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 18:45:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>'Spare us more humiliation': war heroine pleads</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/spare-us-more-humiliation-war-heroine-pleads</link><description>Since the Liberation War, "Birangona" or war heroine Sheikh Fatema Ali has found no respite from humiliation.
The wartime rape victim has been continuously neglected and subjected to slander and social stigma.
The war crimes survivor has never found peace, nor even a chance to heal the wounds inf</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 19:00:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>1,104 infiltration attempts from Bangladesh: India</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/1104-infiltration-attempts-from-bangladesh-in-11-months-2556-arrested-says-india</link><description>India logged 1,104 infiltration attempts from Bangladesh between January and November this year, leading to the arrest of 2,556 people, Junior Home Minister Nityanand Rai has told parliament.
Rai also said during the full year of 2024, authorities detected 977 infiltration attempts along the Bangl</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 19:15:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hadi attack probe: Key suspect’s father held</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hadi-attack-prime-suspects-father-detained-as-rab-widens-investigation</link><description>The Rapid Action Battalion (RAB) has detained the father of Faisal Karim Masud, the key suspect in the attack on Inqilab Moncho leader Sharif Osman bin Hadi, as the investigation into the attempted killing intensifies.
After the detention, the RAB said it had recovered two firearms from Narsingdi</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 19:30:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Healthcare in Dhaka inadequate, services shabby</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/healthcare-in-dhaka-inadequate-services-shabby</link><description>An unchecked influx of people into Dhaka from insufficiently served countryside demographically elevates the Bangladesh capital to world's second-densely-populated city but downgrades its basic civic services - healthcare, in particular, left in disarray.
According to a recent UN report, Dhaka is</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 01:40:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sharif Osman's health condition stable after slight deterioration</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/sharif-osmans-health-condition-stable-after-slight-deterioration</link><description>The health condition of Inqilab Mancha spokesman Sharif Osman Hadi was stated to be stable on Tuesday after slight deterioration following initial medical tests in Singapore, according to his family sources.
In a Facebook post on Tuesday, quoting Sharif Osman Hadi's brother, the Inqilab Mancha sai</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 01:55:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt to host Global Sourcing Expo twice a year from 2026</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/govt-to-host-global-sourcing-expo-twice-a-year-from-2026</link><description>The government is set to organise the Global Sourcing Expo twice a year to showcase Bangladesh's strengths to international buyers and diversify its export basket, according to sources at the Ministry of Commerce.
Officials said the decision follows positive responses from exhibitors, global buyer</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 02:10:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt spending on DAEE project may jump 78pc</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-spending-on-daee-project-may-jump-78pc</link><description>Government spending on the Dhaka-Ashulia Elevated Expressway (DAEE) project is likely to rise by 78 per cent as the Bangladesh Bridge Authority (BBA) has finalised a revised cost estimate of Tk 272.33 billion.
The government's contribution to the DAEE project was Tk 59.51 billion, which increased</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 02:25:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tk 2.39b skill dev projects proposed for Rohingya host communities</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tk-239b-skill-dev-projects-proposed-for-rohingya-host-communities</link><description>The Ministry of Youth and Sports has proposed two skill-development projects worth Tk 2.39 billion with support from the New Development Bank (NDB) of the BRICS countries, aiming to generate employment for youths from Rohingya host communities in Cox's Bazar and across the Chattogram division, offi</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 02:40:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>20 pc of Bangladeshi Hajj pilgrims to go to KSA via Madinah next year</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/20-pc-of-bangladeshi-hajj-pilgrims-to-go-to-ksa-via-madinah-next-year</link><description>Twenty per cent of Bangladeshi Hajj pilgrims must travel to Saudi Arabia via Madinah next year and 30 per cent will return through the same route.
A high official of the Religious Affairs Ministry told the FE that they had sent a letter to all lead Hajj agencies informing the 2026 Hajj agreement b</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 02:55:49 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>