<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 04:25:54 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>LafargeHolcim defies industry slump with 36pc profit surge in Q3</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/lafargeholcim-defies-industry-slump-with-36pc-profit-surge-in-q3</link><description>LafargeHolcim posted a 36 per cent year-on-year profit growth to Tk 1.20 billion in July-September - a remarkable feat at a time when the construction industry is reeling from sharp cuts in both public and private investment.
The success was achieved due to higher sales of premium products and agg</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 01:40:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>LR Global CEO banned for life, must recover investment in 30 days</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/lr-global-ceo-banned-for-life-must-recover-investment-in-30-days</link><description>The stock market regulator has ordered LR Global Bangladesh Asset Management Company to recover the investment it made in Padma Printers &amp; Colour three years ago in breach of securities rules.
The Bangladesh Securities and Exchange Commission (BSEC) at the same time has imposed fines on six top of</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 01:55:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sena Insurance Q3 profit drops on higher claims, costs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/sena-insurance-q3-profit-drops-on-higher-claims-costs</link><description>Sena Kalyan Insurance saw its third-quarter profit slump by 16.7 per cent year-on-year to Tk 32.40 million, as revenue from its core underwriting business fell sharply while management expenses continued to climb.
The army-run general insurer saw a 67 per cent year-on-year decline in profit from i</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 02:10:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ICT orders 15 army officers to be sent to jail</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ict-orders-15-army-officers-to-be-sent-to-jail</link><description>The International Crimes Tribunal (ICT) on Wednesday ordered that 15 army officers accused in three separate cases over enforced disappearances, killings, and other crimes against humanity allegedly committed during the Awami League regime be sent to jail after being shown arrested.
A three-member</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 02:40:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BD seeks Korean investments in textiles, electronics, renewables</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/bd-seeks-korean-investments-in-textiles-electronics-renewables</link><description>The Bangladesh Investment Development Authority (BIDA) has urged Korean investors to leverage Bangladesh's dynamic investment landscape, highlighting the country's strategic advantages and ongoing pro-business reforms aimed at facilitating foreign direct investment (FDI).
At an investment seminar</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 02:55:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>SC begins hearing appeal on caretaker govt</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/sc-begins-hearing-appeal-on-caretaker-govt</link><description>Appearing before the Appellate Division during the hearing on the caretaker government system, Advocate Dr Sharif Bhuiyan on Tuesday argued that scrapping the system from the Constitution was a completely "wrong-headed" decision.
During his submission, he further argued that there are established</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 03:10:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC to set up central cell to counter AI misuse in next polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ec-to-set-up-central-cell-to-counter-ai-misuse-in-next-polls</link><description>Chief Election Commissioner (CEC) AMM Nasir Uddin on Tuesday said the Election Commission (EC) will set up a central cell to tackle rumours surrounding the upcoming national elections in the wake of artificial intelligence (AI).
"The misuse of AI has become a pressing global concern. We have plann</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 03:25:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BD sees 116,726 deaths, 165,021 injuries in past 12 years: BJKS</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bd-sees-116726-deaths-165021-injuries-in-past-12-years-bjks</link><description>Bangladesh has witnessed a total of 116,726 deaths and 165,021 injuries in 67,890 road accidents over the past 12 years, according to the Bangladesh Jatri Kalyan Samiti (BJKS).
The organisation blamed widespread corruption, policy failures, and mismanagement in the transport sector for what it ter</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 03:40:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Children launch six-point manifesto for next polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/children-launch-six-point-manifesto-for-next-polls</link><description>Ahead of the upcoming national elections, more than 200 children on Tuesday issued a six-point manifesto urging stakeholders, including the government and political parties, to prioritise child protection in their agendas.
The manifesto calls for quality education, healthcare protection, inclusion</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 03:55:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Broken bridge over Ichamati River becomes a nightmar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/broken-bridge-over-ichamati-river-becomes-a-nightmar</link><description>A dilapidated bridge over the Ichamati River at Kusta Purbo Para in Ghior upazila of the district has become a daily nightmare for thousands of people.
Built in 2002 at a cost of around Tk1.8 million by the Local Government Engineering Department (LGED), the bridge lost one of its approaches to th</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 04:10:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Implement IFRS 9 effectively to restore trust in banking sector</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/implement-ifrs-9-effectively-to-restore-trust-in-banking-sector</link><description>The country's accounting professionals have called for adoption and effective implementation of International Financial Reporting Standard (IFRS) 9, citing its critical role in restoring public trust and ensuring greater transparency in the country's banking sector.
They also underscored the need</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 04:25:54 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>