<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 14:17:31 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Powerful quake hits off Japan’s northern coast, tsunami advisory issued</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/powerful-quake-strikes-off-the-coast-of-japan-tsunami-advisory-lifted-after-3-hours</link><description>A powerful magnitude 6.9 earthquake struck off the coast of Iwate Prefecture in northern Japan on Sunday evening, prompting a tsunami advisory and warnings of possible aftershocks, the Japan Meteorological Agency (JMA) said.
The quake, which occurred at 5:03 p.m. local time at a depth of about 16</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 11:50:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt to decide shareholders’ fate in 5 Shariah banks proposed for merger: Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-to-decide-shareholders-fate-in-5-shariah-banks-proposed-for-merger-adviser</link><description>The government will make the final decision on the status of shareholders of the five Shariah-based banks proposed for merger, said Finance Adviser Dr Salehuddin Ahmed on Sunday.
The Bangladesh Bank governor’s statement is not final as the government will look into the matter, Dr Salehuddin</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 12:05:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Army deployment to remain unchanged: Jahangir</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/army-deployment-to-remain-unchanged-jahangir</link><description>Home Advisor Jahangir Alam Chowdhury has said the government’s plan to withdraw 50 percent of Army personnel deployed with executive magistracy powers from the field will not be implemented.
After a meeting of the core committee on law and order at the Secretariat on Sunday, Jahangir was ask</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 12:20:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Walton cables get approval from Maldives' Utility Regulatory Authority for electrical installations</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/walton-cables-get-approval-from-maldives-utility-regulatory-authority-for-electrical-installations</link><description>Bangladeshi electronics giant Walton has accomplished another milestone in its export business in the latest move of its global presence, since it started exporting locally made power cables to Maldives upon receiving the approval certificate from Male Utility Regulatory Authority.
Walton Cables&amp;r</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 12:35:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Migrant vessel sinks off Malaysia-Thailand border, hundreds missing</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/migrant-vessel-sinks-off-malaysia-thailand-border-hundreds-missing</link><description>Hundreds were missing on Sunday after a boat sank near the Thailand-Malaysia border, as 10 survivors and one body were recovered, the Malaysian maritime authority said.
More victims might still be found at sea some three days after the sinking of the vessel, which left Buthidaung, Myanmar, with ab</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 11:50:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>80pc of strokes preventable through lifestyle modification: Experts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/80pc-of-strokes-preventable-through-lifestyle-modification-experts</link><description>Nearly 80 per cent of strokes are preventable through lifestyle modifications and controlling high blood pressure, quitting smoking, avoiding unhealthy diets and staying physically active, said experts.
The experts said this at the International Stroke Conference 2025 held on Sunday at Bangladesh</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 12:05:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>At least two dead as Super Typhoon Fung-wong nears landfall in the Philippines</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/at-least-two-dead-as-super-typhoon-fung-wong-nears-landfall-in-the-philippines</link><description>At least two people died in the Philippines as Super Typhoon Fung-wong lashed central and eastern parts of the country, with heavy rains and strong winds cutting power in large areas of the Bicol region ahead of its expected landfall in northern Luzon.
More than a million people have evacuated vul</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 12:20:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>71 Madrasah teachers, 2 faculty members become British Council-trained teacher educators for English</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/71-madrasah-teachers-2-faculty-members-become-british-council-trained-teacher-educators-for-english</link><description>The British Council, in collaboration with the Bangladesh Madrasah Teachers’ Training Institute (BMTTI) and Technical and Madrasah Education Division (TMED), has completed an intensive six-day residential Training of Trainers (ToT) programme.
Delivered over 28 sessions by nine top English La</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 12:35:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Asif Mahmud plans to stand in February election as an independent</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/asif-mahmud-plans-to-stand-in-february-election-as-an-independent</link><description>Local Government Advisor Asif Mahmud Shojib Bhuyain has said he intends to contest in the next parliamentary polls as an independent candidate.
On Sunday afternoon, he said, though he has not yet decided from where he will stand, he hopes, “It will be from Dhaka, God willing,” accordin</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 12:50:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Four school students drown in Meherpur lake</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/four-school-students-drown-in-meherpur-lake</link><description>Four school students have died while picking water lilies from a lake in Meherpur Sadar.
Meherpur Sadar Upazila administrator (UNO) Khairul Islam said, “The accident occurred around 5:15 pm on Sunday at Mominpur Beel.”</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 13:05:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>6 more die of dengue; 1,195 hospitalised in 24 hours</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/6-more-die-of-dengue-1195-hospitalised-in-24-hours</link><description>The dengue situation in Bangladesh continues to worsen, with six more deaths and 1,195 new hospitalisations recorded across the country in the 24 hours till Sunday morning.
According to the Directorate General of Health Services (DGHS), the latest figures bring this year’s total death toll f</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 13:20:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Expand Bangladesh-South Korea cooperation: Seminar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/expand-bangladesh-south-korea-cooperation-seminar</link><description>Speakers at a seminar on Sunday highlighted the importance of expanding cooperation between Bangladesh and South Korea in advanced manufacturing and infrastructure projects in a changing global environment.
They talked about roads, ports and power sector projects, strengthening collaboration in di</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 13:35:32 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>