<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 10:42:11 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Pakistan PM congratulates Tarique Rahman, pledges closer ties</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/pakistan-pm-congratulates-tarique-rahman-on-election-win-pledges-closer-ties</link><description>Pakistan's Prime Minister Shehbaz Sharif has congratulated Tarique Rahman on "leading the BNP to a resounding victory" in the elections.
"I look forward to working closely with the new Bangladesh leadership to further strengthen our historic, brotherly multifaceted bilateral relations and advance</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 06:30:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Use of chemical fertilisers deteriorates soil quality in Pabna</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/use-of-chemical-fertilisers-deteriorates-soil-quality-in-pabna</link><description>PABNA, Feb 12: The quality of soil in Pabna's arable land has been deteriorating due to the use of chemical fertilisers and the resulting situation include abnormal rise of phosphorus and reduction of pH and organic matter in the soil, among other technical factors, according to soil researchers.</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 06:45:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Houses built for homeless get stolen in Gaibandha</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/houses-built-for-homeless-get-stolen-in-gaibandha</link><description>GAIBANDHA, Feb 12: Some 76 vacant houses out of the 110 built to shelter the homeless and the landless in Chandipur village of Gaibandha's Gobindaganj were stolen, leaving only concrete-made poles behind.
The houses, built under the former government's Guchchagram project, featured tin roofs and</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 07:00:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP sweeps Sheikh Hasina’s stronghold of Gopalganj</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-sweeps-sheikh-hasinas-stronghold-of-gopalganj</link><description>The BNP has swept Gopalganj, winning all three parliamentary constituencies in Sheikh Hasina’s home district.
The results mark a dramatic shift in a region long regarded as an Awami League fortress.
Returning Officer and Deputy Commissioner Md Arif-uz-Zaman announced the final results at 2:</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 07:49:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP claims landslide victory in country’s first election since 2024 uprising</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bnp-claims-landslide-victory-in-countrys-first-election-since-2024-uprising</link><description>The Bangladesh Nationalist Party has claimed victory in the country’s first election since the 2024 uprising, positioning itself to form the next government and potentially reshape Bangladesh’s political landscape after years of intense rivalry and disputed polls.
The party’s med</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 08:04:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pakistan's jailed Imran Khan loses 85% vision in right eye, lawyer says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/pakistans-jailed-imran-khan-loses-85-vision-in-right-eye-lawyer-says</link><description>Pakistan's jailed former Prime Minister Imran Khan has lost 85% of the sight in his ‌right eye, his lawyer told the Supreme Court, an ordeal that ‌adds to legal and political challenges the leader is already battling.
Khan, 73, has been in ​jail since August 2023, serving a 14-year sente</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 08:39:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mamata congratulates Tarique Rahman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/mamata-congratulates-tarique-rahman</link><description>West Bengal Chief Minister Mamata Banerjee on Friday extended her congratulations to BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman for guiding his party to victory in Bangladesh’s national election.
Taking to X, the West Bengal Chief Minister wrote, “My hearty congratulations, shubhonandan, to all my br</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 08:54:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP says election accusers must prove allegations</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-says-election-accusers-must-prove-allegations</link><description>BNP senior leader Nazrul Islam Khan on Friday said that those raising allegations over Thursday’s parliamentary elections must provide evidence to support their claims.
Talking to journalists at the Election Commission, Nazrul Islam responded to allegations made by Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 09:09:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh sees nearly 60pc turnout in general election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-sees-nearly-60pc-turnout-in-general-election</link><description>Voter turnout in the Feb 12 election and referendum stood at 59.44 per cent, according to the Election Commission (EC).
The vote was held on Thursday, with 127,711,793 registered voters eligible to cast ballots.
A total of 2,028 candidates from 50 political parties, along with independents, conte</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 09:24:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP’s Tulee alleges ‘poll fraud’, urges results suspension and re-vote</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnps-tulee-alleges-poll-fraud-urges-results-suspension-and-re-vote</link><description>BNP candidate Sanjida Islam Tulee has alleged widespread rigging in Dhaka-14 and called for the suspension of results.
Speaking at a press conference on Friday afternoon at a building on Mirpur Zoo Road, she levelled accusations of ballot snatching, fake voting, voter intimidation and the forced r</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 09:39:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Yes’ wins referendum on July Charter, turnout at 60.26 per cent</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/yes-wins-referendum-on-july-charter-turnout-at-6026-per-cent</link><description>The referendum on the July National Charter has passed with a resounding 68.06 per cent of votes going to “Yes”.
The fourth referendum in the country’s history had a turnout of 60.26 per cent.
A total of 48,074,429 (68.05 percent) votes were cast for “Yes”, while 22,</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 09:54:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC suspends poll results in 3 constituencies over legal disputes</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-suspends-poll-results-in-3-constituencies-over-legal-disputes</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has withheld results of the Chattogram-2 and Chattogram-4 races and suspended the election in Sherpur-2, pending Supreme Court rulings on legal challenges.
On Thursday, the commission issued three separate letters directing returning officers to keep the outcomes on ho</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 10:09:39 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>