<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 05:39:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Google to invest $10 billion in data centre and AI project in India</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/google-to-invest-10-billion-in-data-centre-and-ai-project-in-india</link><description>Alphabet Inc's Google will invest $10 billion to set up a massive data centre and artificial intelligence hub in Andhra Pradesh, officials from the southern Indian state said, marking its biggest such investment in the South Asian nation.
Google will build a 1-gigawatt data centre campus in the po</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 02:52:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US, China to roll out tit-for-tat port fees</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/us-china-to-roll-out-tit-for-tat-port-fees-threatening-more-turmoil-at-sea</link><description>The United States and China on Tuesday will begin charging additional port fees on ocean shipping firms that move everything from holiday toys to crude oil, making the high seas a key front in the trade war between the world's two largest economies.
China said it had started to collect the special</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 03:07:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>SpaceX completes 11th Starship test before debuting upgraded prototype</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/spacex-completes-11th-starship-test-before-debuting-upgraded-prototype</link><description>Elon Musk's SpaceX launched its 11th Starship rocket from Texas on Monday and landed it in the Indian Ocean, the last flight before the company begins test-launching a new version of the giant rocket outfitted with more features for moon and Mars missions.
Starship, which includes the Starship upp</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 03:22:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Brazil President Lula plans visit to Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/brazil-president-lula-plans-visit-to-bangladesh</link><description>Brazilian President Luiz Inácio Lula da Silva has expressed his interest in visiting Bangladesh in the coming months, hoping the visit would strengthen ties between the two nations.
President Lula made the announcement during a meeting with Bangladesh's Chief Adviser, Professor Muhammad Yun</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 03:52:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Djibouti PM meets CA, seeks advice on microfinance</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/djibouti-pm-meets-ca-seeks-advice-on-microfinance</link><description>Prime Minister of Djibouti Abdoulkader Kamil Mohamed met Chief Adviser Prof Muhammad Yunus on Monday on the sidelines of the World Food Forum at the FAO headquarters.
During the meeting, the two leaders discussed a wide range of issues, including enhancing bilateral trade and investment, replicati</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 04:22:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>JMI Hospital Requisite injects fresh funds into Apollo-partnered hospital</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/jmi-hospital-requisite-injects-fresh-funds-into-apollo-partnered-hospital</link><description>JMI Hospital Requisite Manufacturing has approved a further investment of Tk 115 million in its newly inaugurated subsidiary - JMI Specialized Hospital.
The leading medical device manufacturer and flagship company of JMI Group will purchase machinery and provide working capital to the hospital.
C</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 04:37:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt assurance raises hopes of general shareholders in Islamic bank merger</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/govt-assurance-raises-hopes-of-general-shareholders-in-islamic-bank-merger</link><description>A government announcement concerning shareholders of the five troubled Islamic banks being merged has raised hopes among general shareholders.
"The matter of protecting investors' interests is being carefully examined in the merger process," reads an official statement issued by the Ministry of Fi</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 04:52:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BD Lamps cuts quarterly loss by 79pc on higher sales</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/bd-lamps-cuts-quarterly-loss-by-79pc-on-higher-sales</link><description>Bangladesh Lamps, widely known as BD Lamps, cut its losses by 79 per cent year-on-year to Tk 12.5 million in the first quarter through September, driven by higher sales.
The electric bulb and energy-saving light manufacturer saw its overall sales rise around 16 per cent year-on-year to Tk 488 mill</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 05:07:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DU, Dhaka College students clash over setting up of tea stall</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/du-dhaka-college-students-clash-over-setting-up-of-tea-stall</link><description>A clash broke out between the students of Dhaka University (DU) and Dhaka College in front of a residential hall over setting up of a tea stall in the early hours of Monday.
The clash erupted around 1:30 am following an argument in which DU students at the Shahnewaz Hall opposed Dhaka College stud</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 05:37:20 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>