<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 10:32:30 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>10-year bond yield slides on dollar buys</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/10-year-bond-yield-slides-on-dollar-buys</link><description>The yield on 10-year treasury bonds declined on Tuesday as the central bank purchased an additional US$45 million from two banks in a bid to stabilise the exchange rate of the US dollar against the local currency.
According to auction results, the cut-off yield, generally regarded as the interest</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 07:47:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Interoperability among NBR wings: Project kicks off to boost revenue mobilisation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/interoperability-among-nbr-wings-project-kicks-off-to-boost-revenue-mobilisation</link><description>A first-of-its-kind initiative aimed at strengthening domestic revenue mobilisation by ensuring interoperability among different wings of the National Board of Revenue (NBR) has started operations.
The government has already signed a financing agreement with the World Bank on this, and the project</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 08:02:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Netanyahu to join Trump’s Board of Peace</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/netanyahu-to-join-trumps-board-of-peace</link><description>Israel Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said Wednesday he had agreed to join US President Donald Trump’s Board of Peace, after his office earlier criticised the makeup of the board’s executive committee.
The board, chaired by Trump, was originally envisioned as a small group of world</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 08:17:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Expatriate voters to cast postal ballots from today</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/expatriate-voters-to-cast-postal-ballots-from-today</link><description>Expatriate voters registered through the 'Postal Vote BD' app will be able to cast their ballots for the upcoming 13th Jatiya Sangsad (JS) elections and referendum from 5:00 pm today (Wednesday).
The Election Commission (EC) has instructed voters to follow the prescribed procedure available on its</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 08:32:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Babar’s wife withdraws candidacy from Netrokona-4</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/babars-wife-withdraws-candidacy-from-netrokona-4</link><description>Tahmina Zaman Sraboni, wife of BNP-nominated candidate and former state minister for home affairs Lutfozzaman Babar, has withdrawn her candidacy along with two other contenders in Netrokona.
Tahmina had stood as an independent candidate in the Netrokona-4 constituency covering Madan, Mohonganj and</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 08:47:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Milestone jet crash: Last survivor returns home</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/milestone-jet-crash-last-survivor-returns-home</link><description>The final surviving patient of the tragic Milestone School and College fighter jet crash was discharged on Wednesday from the National Institute of Burn and Plastic Surgery (NIBPS).
Resident Surgeon of NIBPS, Dr Shawon Bin Rahman, confirmed that the patient was released.
The patient, Abidur Rahim</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 09:02:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Why is EC silent on Tarique’s ‘breach of conduct’ in promising flats?’ asks Patwary</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/why-is-ec-silent-on-tariques-breach-of-conduct-in-promising-flats-asks-patwary</link><description>NCP Chief Coordinator Nasiruddin Patwary has demanded to know why the Election Commission has remained silent after BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman “directly violated” election laws and regulations by promising to provide flats to Korail slum residents.
Patwary, who is contesting in the Dh</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 09:17:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP warns ‘rebel’ candidates they will face disciplinary action</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bnp-warns-rebel-candidates-they-will-face-disciplinary-action</link><description>The BNP has warned of disciplinary action against “rebel” candidates who stay in the contest for the parliamentary election in spite of the party’s decisions.
On Wednesday, Mahdi Amin, spokesperson of the party’s Central Election Steering Committee, said at a media briefing</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 09:32:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Abu Sayed murder suspect escapes as police launch raid in Rangpur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/abu-sayed-murder-suspect-escapes-as-police-launch-raid-in-rangpur</link><description>A murder suspect in the case of Abu Sayed, who was killed in Rangpur’s Pirgachha Upazila during the July Uprising, has fled after noting the police's presence during a raid.
The suspect, Nahid Hasan Liton, is the organisational secretary of the district Jubo League.
Pirgachha police chief A</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 09:47:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Arrest warrant issued against Transcom’s Simeen Rahman, 2 others</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/arrest-warrant-issued-against-transcoms-simeen-rahman-2-others</link><description>A Dhaka court has issued arrest warrants against three people, including Transcom Group Chief Executive Officer (CEO) Simeen Rahman, in a case over embezzlement of the company’s shares.
Dhaka Additional Chief Metropolitan Magistrate Md Sefatullah issued the warrants on Wednesday after taking</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 10:02:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gazette notification issued for Mosque Management Policy-2025</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/gazette-notification-issued-for-mosque-management-policy-2025</link><description>The government has issued a gazette notification for the Mosque Management Policy-2025 to ensure efficient, transparent and time-befitting management of mosques across the country.
The notification was signed on January 19 by Md. Kamal Uddin, Secretary of the Ministry of Religious Affairs, an offi</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 10:17:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gaza families ordered to relocate in first truce evacuation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/israel-orders-gaza-families-to-move-in-first-forced-evacuation-since-ceasefire</link><description>Israeli forces ordered dozens of Palestinian families in the southern Gaza Strip to leave their homes in the first forced evacuation since October's ceasefire, as residents and Hamas said on Tuesday the military was expanding the area it controls.
Residents of Bani Suhaila, east of Khan Younis, sa</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 10:32:29 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>