<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 11:36:49 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Four bodies recovered from Mirpur Bihari camp</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/four-bodies-recovered-from-mirpur-bihari-camp</link><description>Police have recovered the bodies of four members of the same family from Mirpur 11’s Wapda Bihari Camp in Dhaka’s Pallabi Thana.
AKM Alamgir Jahan, chief of Pallabi Police Station, said police went to a home and recovered the bodies after they were reported around 11am.
The bodies w</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 09:19:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AB Party candidate’s election office vandalised in Feni</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ab-party-candidates-election-office-vandalised-in-feni</link><description>Miscreants vandalised the election office of AB Party chairman Mujibur Rahman Manjur, the Eagle-symbol candidate of the 11-party alliance, at Izzatpur in Feni Sadar late Wednesday night.
Local sources said the office, located on Daiyabibi Bazar Road at Izzatpur, was inaugurated by party leaders an</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 09:34:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Former Biman MD, wife seek bail over ‘abusing’ domestic child worker, hearing on Sunday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/former-biman-md-wife-seek-bail-over-abusing-domestic-child-worker-hearing-on-sunday</link><description>Former Biman Bangladesh Airlines managing director and chief executive officer Shafiqur Rahman and his wife Bithi have sought bail in a case over the abuse of a child domestic worker.
Lawyer Zakir Hossain filed the bail petition on their behalf on Thursday at the court of Dhaka Chief Metropolitan</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 09:49:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nasser Hussain backs Bangladesh and Pakistan stance on T20 World Cup</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/nasser-hussain-backs-bangladesh-and-pakistan-stance-on-t20-world-cup</link><description>Former England captain Nasser Hussain has thrown his weight behind Bangladesh and Pakistan in the ongoing T20 World Cup crisis, asserting that it is high time to halt the intrusion of politics into the sport.
Speaking on the Sky Cricket Podcast with fellow commentator Mike Atherton, Hussain praise</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 10:04:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat Ameer vows to ensure security, rights of all, women safety</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-ameer-vows-to-ensure-security-rights-of-all-women-safety</link><description>Jamaat Ameer Dr Shafiqur Rahman on Thursday pledged to ensure the security and rights of people of all religions and communities, while promising strict measures to protect women from harassment and threats.
Speaking at an election rally organised by the Naogaon district Jamaat at Atim ground in N</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 10:19:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>President meets Judicial Service Pay Commission delegation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/president-meets-judicial-service-pay-commission-delegation</link><description>A delegation of the Bangladesh Judicial Service Pay Commission met President Mohammed Shahabuddin at Bangabhaban on Thursday.
Shabbir Ahmed Akunjee, Private Secretary to the Public Division Secretary at the President’s Office, shared the information with the media.
Justice S M Emdadul Hoque</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 09:50:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh urges global action against illicit financial flows</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-urges-global-action-against-illicit-financial-flows</link><description>Bangladesh has called for stronger international cooperation to curb illicit financial flows and ensure the return of stolen assets, saying recovered funds are vital for development, public welfare and rebuilding trust in public institutions.
Speaking at the ECOSOC Special Meeting on Financial Int</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 10:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fakhrul slams Jamaat’s role in 1971 Liberation War</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/fakhrul-slams-jamaats-role-in-1971-liberation-war</link><description>BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir on Thursday criticised Jamaat-e-Islami over its role during Bangladesh’s 1971 Liberation War, saying the party must clarify its position on the country’s independence.
“Jamaat leaders are currently making statements in television</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 10:20:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh Election: Over 273,000 expats yet to vote</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-election-over-273000-expats-yet-to-vote</link><description>More than 273,000 Bangladeshi expatriates are yet to cast their postal ballots, with six days left before the February-12 national election and referendum, officials said.
The Election Commission has sent the ballots to 767,188 registrant expatriates staying in 123 foreign countries through the po</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 10:35:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique to tour northern districts Saturday in 2nd-phase campaign</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-to-tour-northern-districts-saturday-in-2nd-phase-campaign</link><description>BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman will visit the northern districts on Saturday as part of the second phase of his election campaign in the region.
According to the party’s media cell, Tarique Rahman will leave Dhaka by air at 10:00am for Saidpur Airport and address three election rallies during t</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 10:50:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt fixes Ramadan office timing</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-fixes-ramadan-office-timing</link><description>All offices of the government, semi-government, autonomous and semi-autonomous bodies will function from 9:00 am to 3:30 pm during the upcoming month of holy Ramadan.
The decision was taken at the weekly meeting of the Council of Advisers at the Chief Adviser's Office (CAO) on Thursday, with Chief</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 11:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Babita, Ayub Bachchu, Shafik Rehman to get Ekushey Padak</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/babita-ayub-bachchu-shafik-rehman-to-get-ekushey-padak</link><description>The Ministry of Cultural Affairs has decided to award this year’s Ekushey Padak to nine individuals and a band.
The awardees were selected at a meeting chaired by Cultural Affairs Adviser Mostafa Sarwar Farooki on Thursday.
The names were announced by the Chief Advisor’s Press Secreta</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 11:20:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>