<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 09:26:37 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>One spouse is enough, Vatican tells world's Catholics</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/others/one-spouse-is-enough-vatican-tells-worlds-catholics</link><description>Happily ever after doesn't require any complicated maths, the Vatican said on Tuesday -- for Catholics, one spouse is enough.
In a new decree approved by Pope Leo, the Vatican's top doctrinal office told the world's 1.4 billion Catholics they should seek to marry one spouse for life and should not</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 06:07:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>With 36.6m residents, Dhaka now world's second-largest city: UN report</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/with-366m-residents-dhaka-now-worlds-second-largest-city-un-report</link><description>A new United Nations report has found that Indonesia’s capital Jakarta is the world’s largest city with 41.9 million people living there, followed by Dhaka in Bangladesh, which is home to 36.6 million, Al Jazeera reports.
A low-lying coastal city located in the west of the densely popu</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 07:26:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fire at BMU under control</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/fire-at-bmu-under-control</link><description>A fire that broke out at Bangladesh Medical University (BMU) at Shahbagh intersection of Dhaka, was brought under control within a short time on Wednesday morning.
Rashed Bin Khalid, duty officer (media cell) at Fire Service and Civil Defence (FSCD) headquarters, said the fire erupted on the fourt</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 07:41:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Everything will be fine before the voting day: CEC on law and order</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/everything-will-be-fine-before-the-voting-day-cec-on-law-and-order</link><description>Chief Election Commissioner (CEC) AMM Nasir Uddin on Wednesday said the law and order situation will continue to improve and everything will be in order before the voting day.
“It will improve gradually. As the polling day approaches, you will see everything will fall in line. Everything wil</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 07:56:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>64 districts get SPs through lottery: Home adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/64-districts-get-sps-through-lottery-home-adviser</link><description>The government has appointed Superintendents of Police (SPs) for 64 districts across the country through a lottery system ahead of the national election slated for the first half of February next year.
According to a gazette notification signed by Md Mahbubur Rahman, deputy secretary at the Minist</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 08:11:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>South Africa beat India by 408 runs to sweep series</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/south-africa-beat-india-by-408-runs-to-sweep-series</link><description>South Africa beat India by 408 runs in the second test in Guwahati to complete a 2-0 series sweep on Wednesday.
Chasing an improbable target of 549, India were all out for 140 on the final day of the contest.
Ravindra Jadeja (54) topped the score for the hosts, who once again struggled against th</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 07:41:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Low pressure over Southwest Bay of Bengal intensifies into well-marked low</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/low-pressure-over-southwest-bay-of-bengal-intensifies-into-well-marked-low</link><description>The low-pressure area over the southwest Bay of Bengal and adjoining Sri Lanka coast intensified into a well-marked low over the same area at 6:00 am on Wednesday, according to the Bangladesh Meteorological Department (BMD).
It is likely to move north-northwesterly direction and intensify further,</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 07:56:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Vast trove of medieval Jewish records opened up by AI</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/vast-trove-of-medieval-jewish-records-opened-up-by-ai</link><description>Researchers in Israel are hoping to make new discoveries about Jewish history by loading a digital database of manuscripts stretching back a thousand years into a new transcription tool that uses artificial intelligence.
The Cairo Geniza, the biggest collection of medieval Jewish documents in the</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 08:11:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Navy College student shines in Notun Kuri-2025</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/others/navy-college-student-shines-in-notun-kuri-2025</link><description>Navy College’s seventh-grade student Somriddhi Suchona Swarg has secured the second position in the ‘Kha’ category of the storytelling segment in the final round of BTv-organised Notun Kuri-2025, the country’s largest talent hunt competition for children and teenagers.
The</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 08:26:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Classified loans reach all-time high at Tk 6.44 trillion in September</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/classified-loans-reach-all-time-high-at-tk-644-trillion-in-september</link><description>The classified loans in the country’s banking sector hit an all-time high at Tk 6.44 trillion in September 2025, accounting for 35.73 per cent of the entire loans worth Tk 18.04 trillion disbursed by all scheduled banks.
The volume of non-performing loans (NPLs) rose to Tk 6.44 trillion as o</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 08:41:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt appoints SPs for 64 districts through lottery</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-appoints-sps-for-64-districts-through-lottery</link><description>The interim government today issued an order regarding the appointments of Superintendents of Police (SPs) for all 64 districts
The appointment was finalized through a lottery system ahead of the upcoming 13th national parliament elections on Monday at the residence of the Chief Adviser, Jamuna, r</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 08:56:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gravity Shift: Is Google's new 'Antigravity' IDE 'Cursor-killer'?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/gravity-shift-is-googles-new-antigravity-ide-cursor-killer</link><description>If you've spent any time on "Tech Twitter" over the last six months, you know the drill: Cursor is the vibe-coding king. The AI-native editor has eaten VS Code's lunch, becoming the go-to for everyone from indie hackers to enterprise architects. We've settled comfortably into the era of 'Vibe Codin</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 09:11:54 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>