<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 16:06:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>EU seeks early measures to remove NTBs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/eu-seeks-early-measures-to-remove-ntbs</link><description>The European Union (EU) has sought quick measures to remove non-tariff barriers (NTBs), promoting business confidence and ensuring non-discrimination.
“We look for early measures to remove NTBs, promote business confidence, and ensure non-discrimination,” said the EU Embassy on Wednesd</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 13:40:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DSCC wants professionalism to deliver PM’s ‘Green City–Clean City’ vision</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dscc-administrator-wants-professionalism-to-implement-pms-green-city-clean-city-vision</link><description>Acting on the directives of Prime Minister Tarique Rahman, the newly-appointed administrator of Dhaka South City Corporation (DSCC) on Wednesday instructed officials to work with the highest level of professionalism and dedication to transform Dhaka into a modern ‘Green City and Clean City.&amp;r</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 13:55:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Renu Begum of Shariatpur wins motorcycle on cash remittance</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/renu-begum-of-shariatpur-wins-motorcycle-on-cash-remittance</link><description>Renu Begum, a client of the Naria branch in Shariatpur, won the fourth motorcycle in the Cash Remittance Festival by receiving remittance through Ria Money Transfer at Islami Bank Bangladesh PLC.
She wins this prize against a remittance of Tk. 85,300 sent by Masum Hossain, an expatriate in Italy,</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 14:10:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pragati Insurance holds 340th board meeting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/pragati-insurance-holds-340th-board-meeting</link><description>The 340th meeting of the Board of  Directors of  Pragati Insurance PLC was held on  24 February 2026 at the Head Office of the company.
Syed M. Altaf Hussain, Chairman of the company, presided over the meeting, according to a press release. 
Besides, Director Alhaj Khalilur Ra</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 14:25:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The election was the easy part, now comes the reckoning</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/the-election-was-the-easy-part-now-comes-the-reckoning</link><description>On 12 February 2026, Bangladesh did something important. Nearly 60% of its citizens voted. Polling day was largely calm. The Election Commission under the interim administration managed a process that was orderly and participatory. In a country where elections have too often carried fear in their w</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 14:40:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>State ministers Habibur, Rajib assigned portfolios in road transport, rail, shipping</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/state-ministers-habibur-rajib-assigned-portfolios-in-road-transport-rail-shipping</link><description>The portfolios of two state ministers assigned to the ministries of road transport and bridges, railways, and shipping have been allocated.
Among them, Habibur Rashid will oversee the Road Transport and Highways Division and the Ministry of Railways, bdnews24.com reports. 
Md Rajib Ahsan wil</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 14:11:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BRAC Bank brings exclusive offers at more than 1,400 outlets this Eid</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/brac-bank-brings-exclusive-offers-at-more-than-1400-outlets-this-eid</link><description>BRAC Bankis enhancing the Ramadan and Eid-ul-Fitr experience with savings of up to 50 per cent at more than 1,400 partner outletsnationwide, enabling customers to celebrate with greater flexibility, confidence and value.
From premium Iftar experiences at leading five-star hotels to attractive airf</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 14:26:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mitsui &amp; Co. Asia Pacific signs strategic partnership with ACI Logistics (Shwapno)</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/mitsui-co-asia-pacific-signs-strategic-partnership-with-aci-logistics-shwapno</link><description>Mitsui &amp; Co., Ltd. ("Mitsui"), one of Japan’s leading global trading and investment companies, has agreed to partner with ACI Logistics Limited (ACIL) by providing a foreign currency-denominated convertible loan to ACIL, in accordance with the relevant regulatory approvals through its Singapo</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 14:41:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>PM to confer Ekushey Padak 2026 tomorrow</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/pm-to-confer-ekushey-padak-2026-tomorrow</link><description>Prime Minister Tarique Rahman is expected to distribute Ekushey Padak 2026 at a ceremony at Osmani Memorial Auditorium here at 11 am tomorrow.
 Earlier, the government announced the names of nine eminent citizens and one music band for the country's second-highest civilian award Ekushey Padak</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 14:56:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rajshahi DIG issues ‘special order’ for AL leaders</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/rajshahi-dig-issues-special-order-for-al-leaders</link><description>The deputy inspector general (DIG) of Rajshahi Range has ordered police to show Awami League leaders and activists who are “capable of reorganising the party” after securing bail as “arrested” in other cases.
DIG Mohammad Shahjahan issued the “special” directive</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 15:11:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Man shot dead in public after ‘tiff’ at Raozan market</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/man-shot-dead-in-public-after-tiff-at-raozan-market</link><description>An elderly man has been shot dead in public over a “tiff” at a market in Chattogram’s Raozan.
The incident occurred at Oli Mia’s Hat in the Purba Guzra Union around 7:15pm on Wednesday, according to police.</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 15:26:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh to examine trade deal with US: Commerce minister</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladesh-to-examine-trade-deal-with-us-commerce-minister</link><description>Commerce Minister Khandaker Abdul Muktadir has said Bangladesh will carefully weigh the potential benefits and drawbacks before deciding whether to pursue a trade agreement with the United States.
Speaking to reporters on Wednesday after a meeting with business leaders, he said it was “too e</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 15:41:30 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>