<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 16:30:47 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Khaleda created unique public-private synergy in economy: Moyeen Khan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/khaleda-created-unique-public-private-synergy-in-economy-moyeen-khan</link><description>Former Prime Minister Khaleda Zia created a unique combination between the public and private sectors in Bangladesh’s business and economic landscape, said BNP Standing Committee member Abdul Moyeen Khan on Monday.
He made the remarks while speaking at a doa and remembrance programme organis</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 13:36:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Obaidul Quader placed on ventilator support in Kolkata</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/obaidul-quader-placed-on-ventilator-support-in-kolkata</link><description>Obaidul Quader, general secretary of the Awami League, whose activities were banned following the July movement, is reported to be in a critical condition and receiving treatment on ventilator support in Kolkata.
Hospital and related sources said he is undergoing treatment in the intensive care un</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 13:51:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UCB posts landmark achievement in deposit mobilisation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ucb-posts-landmark-achievement-in-deposit-mobilisation</link><description>United Commercial Bank PLC (UCB) posted a landmark achievement in deposit mobilization, setting a new standard in Bangladesh’s banking industry at a time when the sector has been navigating significant economic and financial challenges.
In 2025, UCB recorded an exceptional deposit growth of</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 14:06:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Denmark PM urges Trump to stop threats to take over Greenland</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/denmark-pm-urges-trump-to-stop-threats-to-take-over-greenland</link><description>The leaders of Denmark and Greenland on Sunday urged U.S. President Donald Trump to stop threatening to take over Greenland, after he reiterated his wish to do so in an interview with The Atlantic magazine.
“It makes absolutely no sense to talk about the U.S. needing to take over Greenland.</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 14:21:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>911th Executive Committee meeting of Shahjalal Islami Bank held</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/911th-executive-committee-meeting-of-shahjalal-islami-bank-held</link><description>The 911th meeting of the Executive Committee (EC) of Shahjalal Islami Bank PLC (SJIB PLC) was held recently at the Corporate Head Office of the bank, according to a press release.
The meeting was presided over by Mr. Akkas Uddin Mollah, the Chairman of the Executive Committee (EC) of the bank. The</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 14:36:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Man shot dead in public in Jashore</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/man-shot-dead-in-public-in-jashore</link><description>Assailants have gunned down a young man in public in Monirampur Upazila, Jashore.
The incident occurred around 5:45 pm at Kapalia Bazaar on Monday, according to Additional Police Superintendent Abul Basar, bdnews24.com reports.</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 14:51:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Witkoff, Kushner to represent US at Ukraine talks, says White House</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/witkoff-kushner-to-represent-us-at-ukraine-talks-says-white-house</link><description>President Donald Trump's special envoy Steve Witkoff and his son-in-law Jared Kushner will represent the United States at talks on Ukraine in Paris this week, a White House official said on Monday.</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 14:45:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CA office debunks false claims over cancellations of holidays</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ca-office-debunks-false-claims-over-cancellations-of-holidays</link><description>The Chief Adviser’s (CA) Office on Monday dismissed a media report that the government has cancelled the holidays of the educational institutions on a number of religious and national days.
CA Press Wing Facts in a post on its official Facebook page said misinformation is being spread on the</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 15:00:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>National Bank holds training workshop on risk-based internal audit</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/national-bank-holds-training-workshop-on-risk-based-internal-audit</link><description>A day-long training workshop titled ‘Risk Based Internal Audit (RBIA) and Team Building &amp; Brainstorming’ was successfully organized on Sunday jointly by the National Bank Training Institute (NBTI) and the Internal Control &amp; Compliance Division (ICCD) of National Bank PLC.
According to</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 15:15:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EASD poll: 70pc of voters want to vote for BNP</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/easd-survey-finds-70pc-of-voters-intend-to-support-bnp-in-parliamentary-polls</link><description>A public opinion poll has found that 70 percent of the electorate across the country intends to vote for the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) in the parliamentary elections.
A private organisation named Eminence Associates for Social Development (EASD) conducted the survey.
On Monday, the organ</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 15:30:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Leaders of BNP-allied parties hold meetings with Tarique Rahman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/leaders-of-bnp-allied-parties-hold-meetings-with-tarique-rahman</link><description>Leaders of five political parties allied with the BNP in the simultaneous movement against the Awami League government held separate meetings with BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman on Monday.
The meetings took place in the afternoon at the BNP Chairperson’s Gulshan office.
During the discu</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 15:45:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique Rahman to visit Bogura, Rangpur on Jan 11</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-rahman-to-visit-bogura-rangpur-on-jan-11</link><description>BNP leaders and activists say Acting Chairperson Tarique Rahman is preparing to visit Bogura on January 11.
The decision was taken at a meeting initiated by the Bogura district committee on Monday, said Kalam Azad, BNP spokesperson in charge of Rajshahi and Rangpur Divisions.
In addition to the d</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 16:00:53 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>