<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 04:42:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Advisory Council to nod amended NBR ordinances today</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/advisory-council-to-nod-amended-nbr-ordinances-today</link><description>The Advisory Council may approve amended ordinances for income tax, customs, and Value-Added Tax (VAT) today (Thursday), paving the way for the bifurcation of revenue administration and policy.
Three separate ordinances for each wing of the National Board of Revenue (NBR) have already been approve</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 01:48:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jet fuel price raised for October</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/jet-fuel-price-raised-for-october</link><description>The Bangladesh Energy Regulatory Commission (BERC) has raised the price of aviation fuel for both domestic and international flights in October, marking the fifth consecutive monthly adjustment.
The increase is expected to make air travel costlier for passengers.
The price of jet A-1 fuel has bee</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 02:18:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tri-national JV investing $120m to run countrywide retail outlets</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/tri-national-jv-investing-120m-to-run-countrywide-retail-outlets</link><description>A tri-national joint venture is investing US$120 million to build and run countrywide retail outlets in Bangladesh with the local firm's two foreign partners bringing in most modern marketing know-how.
Indonesia's retail-giant Alfamart has announced its entry into Bangladesh with the joint venture</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 02:33:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gold price hits historic high at Tk 209,101 per bhori</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/gold-price-hits-historic-high-at-tk-209101-per-bhori</link><description>Gold prices in Bangladesh have soared to a new historic high, reaching Tk 209,101 per bhori (approximately 11.664 grams), breaking the record set just a day earlier.
The new rate, which reflects an increase of Tk 6,905 per bhori of 22-carat, comes into effect on today (Thursday), as announced by t</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 02:48:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Three killed in Ctg motorcycle accidents</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/three-killed-in-ctg-motorcycle-accidents</link><description>Three people, including two motorcyclists and a pedestrian, were killed in separate road accidents in Chattogram on Wednesday night.
Police said the accidents occurred in the Halishahar area of the Faujdarhat–Port Link Road and near Akmal Ali Point in the city’s port area.
The decease</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 03:03:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BD to ratify 3 ILO conventions</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bd-to-ratify-3-ilo-conventions</link><description>The government has decided to ratify three International Labour Organization (ILO) conventions related to occupational safety and health, its promotional framework, and the elimination of violence and harassment at work.
Among them, Conventions 155 and 187 deal with occupational safety and health</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 03:18:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>'Pattern shifting from govt initiatives to pvt sector, social business'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/global/pattern-shifting-from-govt-initiatives-to-pvt-sector-social-business</link><description>International development funding pattern is now shifting from the government-centred initiatives to the private sector, social business, and other models of finance, according to David Engerman, a Professor of History at Yale University, USA.
"My active conclusion is that the era of development i</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 03:33:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UN to slash 25pc of global peacekeeping force</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/un-to-slash-25pc-of-its-global-peacekeeping-force</link><description>The United Nations will begin slashing its peacekeeping force and operations, forcing thousands of soldiers in the next several months to evacuate far-flung global hotspots as a result of the latest US funding cuts to the world body, a senior UN official said.
The official, who spoke on the condit</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 03:48:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>JCD, Shibir trade barbs over breaching code of conduct</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jcd-shibir-trade-barbs-over-breaching-code-of-conduct</link><description>After the long Durga Puja vacation, the Rajshahi University (RU) campus has once again become vibrant with the return of students and renewed electioneering for the upcoming Rajshahi University Central Students' Union (RUCSU) polls.
However, allegations of breaching electoral code of conduct have</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 04:03:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Snails, clams being collected from Narail wetlands indiscriminately</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/snails-clams-being-collected-from-narail-wetlands-indiscriminately</link><description>BENAPOLE, Oct 08: Snails and clams are being collected indiscriminately from canals, wetlands, and waterbodies across Narail district, ignoring restrictions imposed by the Department of Environment (DoE).
The snails and clams gathered are being supplied to shrimp enclosures in Narail and other dis</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 04:33:41 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>