<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 09:35:18 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Air ambulance lands in Dhaka to take bullet-hit Hadi to Singapore</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/air-ambulance-lands-in-dhaka-to-take-bullet-hit-hadi-to-singapore</link><description>An air ambulance, equipped with all emergency facilities for a critical patient, has landed at Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport to take bullet-hit Dhaka-8 aspiring independent candidate Sharif Osman Hadi to Singapore for advanced treatment.
The ambulance landed at 11:22 am, the airport autho</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 06:30:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Farmers busy preparing Boro seedbeds in Sylhet</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/farmers-busy-preparing-boro-seedbeds-in-sylhet</link><description>Farmers across four districts in Sylhet division are racing against time to prepare seedbeds as the window for Boro rice cultivation rapidly closes.
With the target for Boro farming this season set at 497,683 hectares, officials and farmers are working hard to meet the deadline.
The target for Bo</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 06:45:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Clothing trader shot dead in Khulna</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/clothing-trader-shot-dead-in-khulna</link><description>A clothing trader has been shot dead in Rupsha upazila of Khulna.
The killing took place around 10:30 pm on Sunday near the eastern end of the Rupsha Bridge in front of the Jabusa Autogas Filling Station, according to police.
The victim was identified as 30-year-old Sagar Sheikh, a resident of th</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 07:00:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Three more held over gun attack of Osman Hadi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/three-more-held-over-gun-attack-of-osman-hadi</link><description>Members of the Rapid Action Battalion (RAB) have arrested three more people in connection with the gun attack on Sharif Osman Hadi, an independent candidate for the Dhaka-8 constituency.
The arrestees are suspected shooter Faisal’s wife Begum Samia, his brother-in-law Shipu, and Begum Maria.</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 07:15:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Metro services to be suspended for 40 minutes on Tuesday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/metro-services-to-be-suspended-for-40-minutes-on-tuesday</link><description>Metro rail services will be suspended for 40 minutes on Tuesday to ensure the safety of paratroopers during Victory Day celebrations.
Dhaka Mass Transit Company Limited (DMTCL) announced on Monday that the suspension will be from 11:50 am to 12:30 pm.
A para jump is scheduled at Tejgaon Puratan A</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 07:30:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BGB says it's 'unclear' whether Hadi attackers crossed into India</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bgb-says-its-unclear-whether-hadi-attackers-crossed-into-india</link><description>The Border Guard Bangladesh (BGB) says it is not yet clear whether those involved in the shooting of Inqilab Moncho Convenor Sharif Osman Hadi in Dhaka had escaped to neighbouring India through the Mymensingh border.
Speaking to reporters at the Khagdohar BGB camp in Mymensingh on Monday, Col Sark</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 07:45:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Complaint filed against journo Anis, actress Shaon, model Maria</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/complaint-filed-against-journo-anis-actress-shaon-model-maria</link><description>Journalist Anis Alamgir, actress Meher Afroz Shaon, model Maria Kispotta and three others have been named in a complaint filed at Uttara West Police Station, accusing them of conspiring to destabilise the state and inciting a banned organisation.
The complaint was filed on Sunday night by Aryan Ah</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 08:00:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Student group blocks Shahbagh intersection demanding home advisor’s resignation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/student-group-blocks-shahbagh-intersection-demanding-home-advisors-resignation</link><description>The Jatiya Chhatra Shakti, the student wing of the National Citizen Party (NCP), has blocked the Shahbagh intersection in Dhaka, demanding the resignation of the home affairs advisor following the shooting of Inqilab Moncho Convenor Osman Sharif Hadi, according to bdnews24.com.
Leaders and activis</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 08:03:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt to bear overseas treatment costs for Hadi, says advisor</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-to-bear-overseas-treatment-costs-for-hadi-says-advisor</link><description>Finance Advisor Salehuddin Ahmed says the government will bear the cost of overseas treatment for Inqilab Moncho Convenor Sharif Osman bin Hadi.
Speaking to journalists after a meeting of the Advisory Council Committee on Government Procurement at the Secretariat on Monday, Salehuddin said the fin</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 08:18:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No uncertainty over national election, reaffirms CEC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/no-uncertainty-over-national-election-reaffirms-cec</link><description>Chief Election Commissioner AMM Nasir Uddin on Monday reaffirmed that there is no uncertainty over the upcoming national election as it will be held in free, fair and competitive manners on time, reports UNB.
 
"InshaAllah, rest assured-- we will rightly see a fair, nice and competitive elec</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 08:33:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh needs strong diplomatic engagement to delay LDC graduation, says RAPID chief</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/bangladesh-needs-strong-diplomatic-engagement-to-delay-ldc-graduation-says-rapid-chief</link><description>Bangladesh needs strong diplomatic engagement to delay its graduation from the Least Developed Country (LDC) category, as the country is likely to face multiple post-graduation challenges without adequate preparation, said Dr Mohammad Abdur Razzaque, chairman of the Research and Policy Integration</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 08:48:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bullet-hit Hadi airlifted to Singapore</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bullet-hit-hadi-airlifted-to-singapore</link><description>The air ambulance, equipped with all emergency facilities for a critical patient, departed Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport carrying bullet-hit Dhaka-8 aspiring independent candidate Sharif Osman Hadi to Singapore for advanced treatment on Monday.
The ambulance, operated by Aspro Aviation, t</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 09:03:05 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>