<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 12:39:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>8 dead, 778 hospitalised as Bangladesh fails to curb dengue</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/8-dead-778-hospitalised-as-bangladesh-fails-to-curb-dengue</link><description>The dengue situation in Bangladesh continues to deteriorate as eight more deaths were reported from dengue in 24 hours till Sunday morning, raising the number of fatalities from the mosquito-borne disease in Bangladesh to 364 this year.
During the same period, 778 new patients were admitted to hos</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 11:14:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gas price for fertiliser factories hiked by 83pc</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-raises-gas-price-for-fertiliser-factories-by-83-per-cent</link><description>Bangladesh has increased the price of gas supplied to fertiliser factories by 83 percent per cubic metre.
In a statement on Sunday, the Bangladesh Energy Regulatory Commission (BERC) said that the price per cubic metre would rise from Tk 16 to Tk 29.25.
The new rate will take effect on Dec 1.
Th</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 11:29:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ICC Bangladesh organizes workshop for SMEs, women entrepreneurs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/icc-bangladesh-organizes-workshop-for-smes-women-entrepreneurs</link><description>International Chamber of Commerce (ICC) Bangladesh organized a day-long workshop on ‘Capacity building of MSMEs and Women Entrepreneurs’ for using ICC Rules in International Trade on Saturday in a city hotel, Chattogram.
The workshop has been designed for the benefits of MSMEs and Wome</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 10:15:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bhutanese PM hails Kurigram SEZ as crucial G2G project</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bhutanese-pm-hails-kurigram-sez-as-crucial-g2g-project</link><description>Bhutanese Prime Minister Tshering Tobgay on Sunday described the Kurigram Special Economic Zone (SEZ), which is currently being constructed under a Government-to-Government (G2G) partnership, as an important project.
“This zone in Bangladesh would connect with Bhutan’s forthcoming spec</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 10:30:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Well driiling and seismic survey in gas fields suspeneded</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/well-driiling-and-seismic-survey-in-gas-fields-suspeneded</link><description>All types of drilling and seismic survey operations of state-run gas exploration companies have been suspended for 48 hours until 8 am on November 25 as a precautionary measure due to earthquake concerns.
State-run Petrobangla announced on Sunday the suspension of exploration activities to ensure</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 10:45:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prof Yunus, Bhutan’s PM, pledges stronger collaboration across SAARC, BIMSTEC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/prof-yunus-bhutans-pm-pledges-stronger-collaboration-across-saarc-bimstec</link><description>Chief Adviser Prof Muhammad Yunus and visiting Bhutanese Prime Minister Tshering Tobgay have reaffirmed their commitment and cooperation at the international, regional and sub-regional platforms, like SAARC and BIMSTEC based on the principles of shared values, mutual respect, understanding, coopera</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 11:00:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US to launch new phase of Venezuela operations, sources say</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-to-launch-new-phase-of-venezuela-operations-sources-say</link><description>The United States is poised to launch a new phase of Venezuela-related operations in the coming days, four US officials told Reuters, as the Trump administration escalates pressure on President Nicolas Maduro's government.
Reuters was not able to establish the exact timing or scope of the new oper</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 11:15:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khaleda to go to hospital for health check-up shortly</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/khaleda-to-go-to-hospital-for-health-check-up-shortly</link><description>BNP Chairperson and former Prime Minister Khaleda Zia will go to Evercare Hospital in the capital on Sunday evening for a health check-up.
“Madam (Khaleda) will be taken to Evercare Hospital for a health check-up as advised by her medical board,” said BNP Media Cell member Sayrul Kabir</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 11:30:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EBL partners with SSCL to launch advanced supply chain finance platform</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ebl-partners-with-sscl-to-launch-advanced-supply-chain-finance-platform</link><description>Eastern Bank PLC. (EBL) has signed an agreement with Spectrum Software and Consulting (Pvt.) Ltd. (SSCL) to implement OptiFin, a flagship Supply Chain Finance solution by SSLC.
Riad Mahmud Chowdhury, Deputy Managing Director and Head of Corporate Banking at EBL, and Mushfiqur Rahman, Managing Dire</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 11:45:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Election candidates must disclose domestic, foreign assets: ACC chairman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/election-candidates-must-disclose-domestic-foreign-assets-acc-chairman</link><description>Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) Chairman Dr Mohammad Abdul Momen on Sunday said contestants in the upcoming election must declare their foreign assets along with domestic ones while submitting election affidavits.
He made the remarks after laying the foundation stone of the ACC’s Sylhet Div</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 12:00:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DOGE 'doesn't exist' with eight months left on its charter</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/doge-doesnt-exist-with-eight-months-left-on-its-charter</link><description>US President Donald Trump's Department of Government Efficiency has disbanded with eight months left to its mandate, ending an initiative launched with fanfare as a symbol of Trump's pledge to slash the government's size but which critics say delivered few measurable savings.
"That doesn't exist,"</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 12:15:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh sends fresh letter to India seeking Hasina’s return</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-sends-fresh-letter-to-india-seeking-hasinas-return</link><description>The interim government has sent another letter to India seeking the return of Sheikh Hasina, who was sentenced to death for crimes against humanity during the July Uprising.
On Sunday, Foreign Advisor Touhid Hossain said the letter was dispatched on Friday.
On Monday, the International Crimes Tri</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 12:30:43 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>