<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 13:35:13 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>EC urges equal media coverage for all candidates</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-urges-equal-media-coverage-for-all-candidates</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has called for equal opportunities for all candidates in election coverage on Bangladesh Television and private TV channels.
Creating a congenial environment is crucial for free, fair, and credible elections, said an EC statement signed by Md Ruhul Amin Mollick, direct</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 12:06:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP forms reception committee ahead of Tarique’s return</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-forms-reception-committee-ahead-of-tariques-return</link><description>BNP has formed a reception committee ahead of the return of its Acting Chairman, Tarique Rahman to Bangladesh on December 25.
The committee was formed on Monday with BNP Standing Committee Member Salahuddin Ahmed as the convener and BNP Senior Joint Secretary General Ruhul Kabir Rizvi as the membe</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 10:53:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IIDFC holds 24th AGM; Janata Bank’s DMD Md Fayaz Alam elected as IIDFC Chairman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/iidfc-holds-24th-agm-janata-banks-dmd-md-fayaz-alam-elected-as-iidfc-chairman</link><description>Mr. Md Fayaz Alam, Deputy Managing Director of Janata Bank PLC., has been elected as the new Chairman of IIDFC PLC.
The Board of Directors elected him during the company’s 24th Annual General Meeting (AGM), held on Wednesday, December 10, at IIDFC’s Head Office, according to a media re</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 11:08:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ayesha ‘confesses’ to Mohammadpur murders</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/household-aide-ayesha-confesses-to-mohammadpur-double-murder</link><description>Domestic aide Ayesha Akhter has given a confessional statement to the court in connection with the murder of a mother and her teenage daughter in Dhaka’s Mohammadpur, after her husband confessed earlier.
Dhaka Additional Chief Metropolitan Magistrate Jashita Islam recorded her confessional s</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 11:23:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Standard Chartered partners with Friendship</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/standard-chartered-partners-with-friendship</link><description>Standard Chartered Bangladesh, in partnership with Friendship, has launched projects to bring critical healthcare and education support to some of Bangladesh’s most isolated char communities, in Bangladesh.
The integrated programme is set to positively impact nearly 100,000 people across rem</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 11:38:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bank Asia Partners with Incepta Pharmaceuticals for integrated cash management solution</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bank-asia-partners-with-incepta-pharmaceuticals-for-integrated-cash-management-solution</link><description>Bank Asia PLC and Incepta Pharmaceuticals Limited have signed a strategic agreement to introduce an integrated cash management solution and strengthening the partnership between the two organisations.
The signing ceremony was held on 11 December 2025 at the Head office of Incepta Pharmaceuticals L</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 11:53:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Run for the Earth 2025’ to champion environmental protection and healthy living</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/run-for-the-earth-2025-to-champion-environmental-protection-and-healthy-living</link><description>With a strong message of environmental protection and sustainable living, ‘Infinity Run for the Earth 2025’ is set to take place at Hatirjheel in Dhaka city on December 19 under the initiative of The Athlete X.
The marathon is expected to attract more than 2,500 registered runners from</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 12:08:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>25th AGM of CDBL held</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/25th-agm-of-cdbl-held</link><description>25th Annual General Meeting (AGM) of Central Depository Bangladesh Limited (CDBL) held on Wednesday, (17th December 2025) at DSE Multi-Purpose Hall.
The meeting was presided over by Mr. AKM Habibur Rahman, Director of CDBL, according to a press release.
22 per cent Cash Dividend was approved in t</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 12:23:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Warner Bros Discovery board rejects rival bid from Paramount</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/entertainment/warner-bros-discovery-board-rejects-rival-bid-from-paramount</link><description>Warner Bros Discovery's (WBD.O) board rejected Paramount Skydance's (PSKY.O) $108.4 billion hostile bid on Wednesday, saying it failed to provide adequate financing assurances.
In a letter to shareholders, disclosed in a regulatory filing, the board wrote that Paramount had "consistently misled" W</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 12:38:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>icddr,b study finds high rates of early marriage, intimate partner violence among newlyweds</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/icddrb-study-finds-high-rates-of-early-marriage-intimate-partner-violence-among-newlyweds</link><description>An icddr,b study revealed on Wednesday an alarming picture of early marriage, intimate partner violence and high rates of mistimed pregnancies among newlywed couples in informal settlements of Bangladesh.
The two-year cohort study conducted by AdSEARCH of icddr,b revealed that among the participat</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 12:53:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shahjalal Islami Bank won Gold Award at 12th ICSB National Award-2024</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/shahjalal-islami-bank-won-gold-award-at-12th-icsb-national-award-2024</link><description>Shahjalal Islami Bank PLC has won the Gold Award in the Islamic Banking category at the 12th ICSB National Award-2024 in recognition of its excellence in corporate governance and establishing transparency and accountability in overall management.
The Institute of Chartered Secretaries of Banglades</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 13:08:07 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>