<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 15:24:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Khalilur Rahman discusses bilateral issues in meeting with Ajit Doval</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/khalilur-rahman-discusses-bilateral-issues-in-meeting-with-ajit-doval</link><description>Amid Dhaka’s renewed call for former Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina’s extradition, National Security Adviser (NSA) and High Representative for the Rohingya Issue Dr Khalilur Rahman on Wednesday met National Security Adviser of India Ajit Doval in New Delhi.
“They discussed work of</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 13:30:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dengue: 6 die, 788 hospitalised</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dengue-6-die-788-hospitalised</link><description>Six more people have died of dengue fever in Bangladesh, while 788 new patients have been admitted to hospitals with the disease in the past 24 hours.
The total number of hospitalisations from the Aedes mosquito-borne illness this year has reached 87,712, with 17,450 patients admitted in November</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 13:45:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>National footballers made every Bangladeshi proud: Prof Yunus</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/national-footballers-made-every-bangladeshi-proud-prof-yunus</link><description>Chief Adviser Prof Muhammad Yunus has congratulated the Bangladesh national football team on their impressive 1-0 win over India in the AFC Asian Cup qualifiers, noting that the victory has made every Bangladeshi proud.
“This victory has made every Bangladeshi proud of. This is not just a vi</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 14:00:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Police arrest three in Patiya, recover arms again in Raozan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/police-arrest-three-in-patiya-recover-arms-again-in-raozan</link><description>Police have recovered illegal arms again in Raozan, acting on information obtained from a suspect arrested two days ago in Chattogram.
Detectives recovered the firearms along with cartridges following a raid in Chowdhuryrhat on Tuesday.
Raozan police also arrested three people with foreign pistol</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 13:24:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Armed Forces Day to be celebrated on Nov 21 amid festivity, enthusiasm</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/armed-forces-day-to-be-celebrated-on-nov-21-amid-festivity-enthusiasm</link><description>The Armed Forces Day will be celebrated through various programmes on November 21 amid festivity and enthusiasm, marking the establishment of army, navy and air force during the 1971 Liberation War.
The day's programmes will begin with offering of special prayers after Fajr prayers at all mosques</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 13:39:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pakistan envoy meets youth and sports adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/pakistan-envoy-meets-youth-and-sports-adviser</link><description>Pakistan High Commissioner to Bangladesh Imran Haider on Wednesday paid a courtesy call on Local Government, Rural Development and Cooperatives and Youth and Sports Adviser Asif Mahmud Shojib Bhuyain at the letter’s office at the Bangladesh Secretariat.
During the meeting, various priority i</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 13:54:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Spain to investigate Meta for alleged Android privacy breaches</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/spain-to-investigate-meta-for-alleged-android-privacy-breaches</link><description>Spain’s parliament will investigate Meta for possible privacy violations of its Facebook and Instagram users, Spanish Prime Minister Pedro Sanchez said on Wednesday.
“In Spain, the law is above any algorithm or any large technology platform. And anyone who violates our rights will pay</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 14:09:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Israeli military strikes southern Lebanon after evacuation warning</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/israeli-military-strikes-southern-lebanon-after-evacuation-warning</link><description>The Israeli military carried out powerful airstrikes in two villages in southern Lebanon on Wednesday, witnesses said, pressing a campaign of near-daily attacks in the border region where Israel says it is targeting Iran-backed Hezbollah.
The Israeli military said it was striking "several Hezbolla</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 14:24:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IFIC Bank customers, employees to get special discounts at Japan Bangladesh Friendship Hospital</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ific-bank-customers-employees-to-get-special-discounts-at-japan-bangladesh-friendship-hospital</link><description>IFIC Bank PLC has signed a Memorandum of Understanding (MoU) with Japan Bangladesh Friendship Medical Services Limited to provide exclusive healthcare benefits to its customers, employees, and their family members.
The agreement was signed on Wednesday (19 November 2025) at a ceremony held at IFIC</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 14:39:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>SC verdict on caretaker govt system on Thursday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/sc-verdict-on-caretaker-govt-system-on-thursday</link><description>The Appellate Division of the Supreme Court will deliver its judgment on Thursday on an appeal challenging its earlier verdict that abolished the caretaker government system for conducting national elections.
A seven-member bench led by Chief Justice Dr Syed Refaat Ahmed is scheduled to announce t</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 14:54:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Saudi crown prince heads to a friendlier US Congress</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/saudi-crown-prince-heads-to-a-friendlier-us-congress</link><description>Lawmakers are set to meet with Saudi Crown Prince Mohammed bin Salman at the US Capitol on Wednesday on the second day of a visit to the United States that has aimed to tout stronger-than-ever economic and security ties with Washington while brushing off scrutiny of his human rights record.
Presid</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 15:09:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hartal called in Rangamati over ‘quota bias’ in primary teacher recruitment</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hartal-called-in-rangamati-over-quota-bias-in-primary-teacher-recruitment</link><description>A group of jobseekers has announced a hartal in Rangamati from 6am Thursday to 6pm Friday, alleging quota discrimination in the district council’s recruitment of primary assistant teachers.
The call came at a press conference on Wednesday afternoon at a restaurant in Banorupa under the banne</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 15:24:25 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>