<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 07:18:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Louvre transfers jewels to Bank of France</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/others/louvre-transfers-jewels-to-bank-of-france</link><description>The Louvre has transferred some of its most precious jewels to the Bank of France, according to French radio RTL, after an audacious daylight heist last week exposed the famed museum's security vulnerability.
The transfer of some precious items from the museum's Apollo gallery, home to the French</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 05:47:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DU eviction drives: Leftist groups protest drive, Ducsu counters</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/du-eviction-drives-leftist-groups-protest-drive-ducsu-counters</link><description>Several leftist student fronts allegedly joined evicted vendors to stage a protest on the Dhaka University (DU) campus on Saturday evening, a day after illegal makeshift shops, vagabonds and outsiders were evicted from the premises.
In protest against the move, several representatives from the Dha</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 04:19:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Japan launches new cargo spacecraft to ISS</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/japan-launches-new-cargo-spacecraft-to-iss</link><description>Japan's space agency on Sunday successfully launched its new flagship H3 rocket carrying an unmanned cargo spacecraft for its first mission to deliver supplies to the International Space Station.
The Japan Aerospace Exploration Agency said the HTV-X1 spacecraft successfully lifted off at</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 04:34:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh’s banking crisis deepens; audit uncovers Tk 1.55 lakh crore shortfall</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladeshs-banking-crisis-deepens-audit-uncovers-tk-155-lakh-crore-shortfall</link><description>Bangladesh’s banking sector is struggling with a deepening crisis, as the latest independent audit for the June quarter exposes a collective capital shortfall exceeding Tk 1.55 lakh crore.
Experts warn that restoring stability and achieving a standardised balance will require significant tim</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 04:49:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Weather may remain mainly dry today: BMD</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/weather-may-remain-mainly-dry-today-bmd</link><description>The weather may remain mainly dry with temporary partly cloudy sky over the country, beginning at 9:00 am today.
“The weather may remain mainly dry with temporary partly cloudy conditions over the country,” according to a Bangladesh Meteorological Department (BMD) bulletin here this mo</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 05:19:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Thai, Cambodia leaders sign expanded ceasefire deal with Trump present</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/thai-cambodia-leaders-sign-expanded-ceasefire-deal-with-trump-present</link><description>The leaders of Thailand and Cambodia signed an enhanced ceasefire deal on Sunday in the presence of US President Donald Trump, who intervened in July to bring an end to their deadly five-day border conflict.
The agreement was signed soon after Trump's arrival at a summit of the Association of Sout</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 05:34:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Japan successfully launches new cargo spacecraft to deliver supplies to International Space Station</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/japan-successfully-launches-new-cargo-spacecraft-to-deliver-supplies-to-international-space-station</link><description>Japan's space agency on Sunday successfully launched its new flagship H3 rocket carrying an unmanned cargo spacecraft for its first mission to deliver supplies to the International Space Station.
The Japan Aerospace Exploration Agency said the HTV-X1 spacecraft successfully lifted off atop the No.</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 05:49:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Woman hacked to death by father-in-law in Jhenaidah</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/woman-hacked-to-death-by-father-in-law-in-jhenaidah</link><description>A woman was hacked to death allegedly by her father-in-law at Purbapaikpara village under Manoharpur Union in Shailkupa upazila of Jhenaidah district on Sunday.
The deceased was identified as Lima Khatun, 25, wife of Abdur Rob and a mother of two children of the same village, reports BSS. 
T</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 06:04:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Coach detachment disrupts train service on Dhaka–Mymensingh route</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/coach-detachment-disrupts-train-service-on-dhaka-mymensingh-route</link><description>Train movement on the Dhaka–Mymensingh route was disrupted for nearly half an hour on Saturday night after a coach of the Jamalpur Express got detached while running through Gafargaon upazila in Mymensingh district.
Sub-inspector Golam Kibria, in charge of the Gafargaon Railway outpost, said</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 06:19:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fire guts 13 shops in Bandarban</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/fire-guts-13-shops-in-bandarban</link><description>A fire has ripped through a market in Bandarban’s Thanchi Upazila, burning down at least 13 shops.
The fire broke out in the early hours of Sunday in Bolipara Union's Bolibazar, according to Peer Mohammad, chief of the Thanchi Thana Fire Station.
"We left for Bolibazar immediately after rec</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 06:49:21 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>