<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 09:31:05 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Export cash incentives to continue till June 2026</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/export-cash-incentives-to-continue-till-june-2026</link><description>The government will continue to provide cash incentive facilities for exporters for an additional six months in order to support them during ongoing global economic challenges.
According to a notification issued by the Finance Division of the Ministry of Finance on Wednesday, the government has ex</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 06:15:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Peasants upset as wintry weather extensively damaging seedbeds</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/peasants-upset-as-wintry-weather-extensively-damaging-seedbeds</link><description>Extremely chilly weather marked by dense fog is taking a heavy toll on seedbeds of different crops, especially of Boro paddy, in Pabna and Sylhet causing an extremely worrying situation for the farmers in the districts.
Our Pabna correspondent says: Under the impact of the persisting cold wave ass</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 06:30:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Three Chinese nationals arrested in capital for running fake iPhone factory</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/three-chinese-nationals-arrested-in-capital-for-running-fake-iphone-factory</link><description>Police arrested three Chinese nationals for their involvement in running a fake iPhone assembling factory in the capital. The arrestees were identified as Tan Jian, Wu Jun, and Dong Hongwei.
Mahiuddin Mahmud Sohel, Deputy Commissioner (DC) of Mirpur Division of Dhaka Metropolitan Police (DMP) Dete</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 06:45:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt issues decree for return of vehicles of completed dev projects</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-issues-decree-for-return-of-vehicles-of-completed-dev-projects</link><description>The government has issued a directive for the immediate return of all vehicles used in the completed development projects to the central transport pool, aiming to ensure fiscal discipline and prevent unauthorised use of public assets, sources said.
The Ministry of Public Administration (MoPA) has</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 07:00:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP demands justice for Musabbir killing</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-demands-justice-for-musabbir-killing</link><description>The Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) on Thursday strongly condemned the killing of Swechchhasebak Dal leader Azizur Rahman Musabbir and demanded immediate arrest and exemplary punishment of those responsible, warning that such incidents are part of a broader attempt to destabilise the country ami</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 07:15:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Debt spiral clouds microcredit's success</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/debt-spiral-clouds-microcredits-success</link><description>Concerns over overlapping loans and rising debt burdens are increasingly overshadowing the achievements of microcredit sector, prompting calls for deeper research and policy intervention.
Officials and experts warn that many borrowers are becoming trapped in a "debt spiral", taking on new loans to</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 07:30:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh seeks US tariff cut as USTR agrees to consider proposal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladesh-seeks-us-tariff-cut-as-ustr-agrees-to-consider-proposal</link><description>National Security Adviser Dr Khalilur Rahman has proposed that the Office of the United States Trade Representative (USTR) reduce the reciprocal tariff from the current 20 per cent.
US Trade Representative Ambassador Jamieson Greer has agreed to consider the proposal positively.
He also agreed to</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 07:45:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fakhrul expresses concern over law and order ahead of polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/fakhrul-expresses-concern-over-law-and-order-ahead-of-polls</link><description>BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir on Friday expressed concerns over the law and order situation in the country ahead of national elections, saying he is not satisfied with the performance of law enforcement agencies.
"The rate at which political leaders are being killed, particular</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 08:00:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Proposed 'Insurance Resolution Ordinance' awaits MoF review</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/proposed-insurance-resolution-ordinance-awaits-mof-review</link><description>The insurance regulator-IDRA--has submitted its much-hyped draft ordinance to the Ministry of Finance, seeking sweeping new powers to intervene in the governance of troubled insurers.
The proposed ordinance is to empower the IDRA (Insurance Development and Regulatory Authority) to set into any com</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 08:15:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>One dead, 38 missing after garbage mound collapses in Philippines</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/one-dead-38-missing-after-garbage-mound-collapses-in-philippines</link><description>A 22-year-old woman has been killed and at least 38 people remain missing after a large mound of waste collapsed at a landfill in the central Philippines, according to authorities.
The incident occurred on Thursday at the Binaliw landfill in Cebu City, where rescue teams have so far pulled 12 inju</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 08:30:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Four burnt bodies found after three-way road crash in Cumilla</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/four-burnt-bodies-found-after-three-way-road-crash-in-cumilla</link><description>Police say they have recovered the burnt bodies of four people after a road accident involving a bus, an autorickshaw, and a motorcycle in Cumilla’s Daudkandi Upazila.
The accident occurred on Friday afternoon on the Dhaka-Chattogram highway in the Baniapara area, according to Iqbal Bahar Mo</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 09:15:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Iran's Supreme Leader to give speech about protests in a few minutes, state TV</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/irans-supreme-leader-to-give-speech-about-protests-in-a-few-minutes-state-tv</link><description>Iran's Supreme Leader Ali Khamenei will give a speech in a few minutes on "the terrorist actions" in the country, Iranian state TV reported on Friday, as protests over economic hardships continued around the country.</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 09:30:43 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>