<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 11:23:47 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>BB allows 270-day credit for LPG imports</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bb-allows-270-day-credit-for-lpg-imports</link><description>Bangladesh Bank (BB) has relaxed import rules for liquefied petroleum gas, permitting importers to use credit facilities of up to 270 days, a move aimed at easing dollar liquidity pressure and ensuring steady LPG supplies in the domestic market.
Under the new arrangement, LPG imports will now be t</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 08:30:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Youth loses leg in landmine blast along Teknaf Border</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/youth-loses-leg-in-landmine-blast-along-teknaf-border</link><description>A young man lost his right leg in a landmine explosion along the Teknaf border in Cox’s Bazar on Monday.
The incident occurred around 10:30 am in the Hauserdip area of the Hoikkhong Lombabil border under Teknaf upazila, police said.
The victim was identified as Mohammad Hanif, 22, son of Md</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 09:05:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Home Adviser warns Ansar against unethical conduct during election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/home-adviser-warns-ansar-against-unethical-conduct-during-election</link><description>Home Affairs Adviser Lt Genl (retd) Md Jahangir Alam Chowdhury on Tuesday issued a firm warning to members of the Bangladesh Ansar and Village Defence Party (VDP), directing them to stay away from any unethical, partisan or duty-breaching activities that could undermine the credibility of the natio</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 09:20:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EBL, Moner Bondhu partner to launch mental wellness program for rural students</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ebl-moner-bondhu-partner-to-launch-mental-wellness-program-for-rural-students</link><description>Eastern Bank PLC (EBL) has partnered with Moner Bondhu to implement a comprehensive mental health and life skills development program for 5,000 students across 10 schools in remote and underserved rural communities of Bangladesh.
The partnership was formalized at a ceremony held recently at EBL&amp;rs</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 09:35:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Interim govt surrendered to bureaucracy: TIB</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/interim-govt-surrendered-to-bureaucracy-tib</link><description>Transparency International Bangladesh (TIB) has raised questions regarding eight ordinances enacted by the interim government as part of the reform process.The organization's Executive Director, Dr. Iftekharuzzaman, said, "Whatever initiatives have been taken in the name of reform, the interim gove</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 09:02:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>5 years in jail for ex-mayor Nurul Absar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/former-coxs-bazar-mayor-nurul-absar-gets-5-years-in-jail-over-embezzlement</link><description>A Chattogram court has sentenced former Cox’s Bazar municipality mayor Nurul Absar to five years’ rigorous imprisonment over “misappropriation of public funds”.
Judge Md Mizanur Rahman of the Chattogram Divisional Special Judges Court delivered the verdict on Monday.
Court</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 09:17:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Malaysia, Indonesia block Musk’s Grok over sexualised AI images</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/malaysia-indonesia-block-musks-grok-over-sexualised-ai-images</link><description>Malaysia and Indonesia have become the first countries to block Grok, the artificial intelligence chatbot developed by Elon Musk’s xAI, citing its misuse to generate sexually explicit and non-consensual images.
Authorities in both Southeast Asian nations said existing safeguards failed to pr</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 09:32:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>45 crude bombs recovered in Shariatpur: 4 held</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/45-crude-bombs-recovered-in-shariatpur-4-held</link><description>Law enforcers in a joint drive have recovered 45 crude bombs and bomb-making materials from a bamboo grove in Jajira upazila of Shariatpur district on Monday.
Tipped off, a joint force team conducted a drive in the area with a dog squad and recovered huge bomb-making materials and 45 crude bombs f</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 09:47:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Inqilab Moncho activists throw eggs at Palak’s prison van</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/inqilab-moncho-activists-throw-eggs-at-ex-minister-palaks-prison-van</link><description>Activists from the Inqilab Moncho have thrown eggs at the prison van carrying former ICT state minister Zunaid Ahmed Palak during.
The incident occurred in front of the Dhaka Chief Metropolitan Magistrate’s court on Monday afternoon.
The leaders and activists of the group chanted anti-Awami</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 10:02:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NEC cuts ADP by Tk 300 billion</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/nec-cuts-adp-by-tk-300-billion</link><description>The National Economic Council (NEC) on Monday approved Revised Annual Development Programme(ADP) for the fiscal year 2025–26 with a total size of Tk 2.08935 trillion, marking a reduction from the original allocation amid resource constraints and macroeconomic considerations.
The decision was</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 10:17:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Seat-sharing announcement within days: Jamaat Ameer</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/seat-sharing-announcement-within-days-jamaat-ameer</link><description>Jamaat-e-Islami Ameer Dr Shafiqur Rahman on Monday said the alliance is expected to make a final announcement on seat-sharing either on Tuesday or Wednesday.  He made the remarks while speaking to reporters after meeting a three-member delegation led by Ivars Ijabs, chief observer of the Europ</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 10:32:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chinese envoy meets Jamaat Ameer</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/chinese-envoy-meets-jamaat-ameer</link><description>Chinese Ambassador to Bangladesh Yao Wen meets Ameer of Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami Dr Shafiqur Rahman on Monday and discussed ways to strengthen party-to-party exchanges.
The two sides had in-depth discussions on China-Bangladesh relations, party-to-party exchanges and other issues of common inter</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 10:47:08 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>