<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 15:25:32 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Inflation to fall below 7pc by mid-2026 amid tightening policies: Govt</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/inflation-to-fall-below-7-per-cent-by-mid-2026-amid-tightening-policies-expects-govt</link><description>Bangladesh’s interim government believes inflation could fall below 7 per cent by June 2026, buoyed by contractionary monetary policy, fiscal restraint and improving balance across key economic indicators, officials said after a high-level meeting chaired by the chief adviser, Muhammad Yunus.</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 13:28:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Netanyahu government moves to shut down Israel's Army Radio station</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/netanyahu-government-moves-to-shut-down-israels-army-radio-station</link><description>Israel's cabinet voted on Monday to shut down a popular national radio station, one in a series of measures by Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu's right-wing coalition that critics see as blows to democracy.
Defence Minister Israel Katz had proposed that Army Radio, broadcasting since the early da</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 13:26:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Voting is constitutional right, not anyone’s charity: Prof Yunus</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/voting-is-constitutional-right-not-anyones-charity-prof-yunus</link><description>Chief Adviser Prof Muhammad Yunus on Monday said voting right is not anyone’s charity as it is people’s constitutional right.
“By exercising this right we decide which path our future will take. Ensuring a free, fair and participatory election is not only the responsibility of th</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 13:41:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Crown Cement declares 21pc cash dividend</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/crown-cement-declares-21pc-cash-dividend</link><description>The shareholders of Crown Cement have approved 21 per cent cash dividend for the year ended 30 June 2025, as recommended by the board of directors.
The approval was given during the 31st Annual General Meeting (AGM) of the company, which was held through digital platform on Monday (December 22), a</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 13:56:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DU halls ‘safe’ after earthquake, authorities say</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/du-halls-safe-after-earthquake-authorities-say</link><description>Following November’s earthquake, Dhaka University has assessed its residential halls and determined that “no building is structurally at risk”, university authorities confirmed.
On Monday, Treasurer and Chair of the Post-Earthquake Building Inspection Committee Prof M Jahangir Al</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 14:11:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Travel ban on Chandpur BNP candidate Jalal, family</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/court-bars-bnps-chandpur-2-candidate-jalal-uddin-his-family-from-leaving-bangladesh</link><description>A Dhaka court has imposed a travel ban on BNP’s Chandpur-2 (Matlab) candidate Jalal Uddin and his wife and children amid a corruption investigation.
The order was issued on Monday by Vacation Judge Mohammad Abdullah Al Mamun of Dhaka Metropolitan Senior Special Judges’ Court, following</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 13:43:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Asif Mahmud collects nomination form for Dhaka-10 constituency</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/asif-mahmud-collects-nomination-form-for-dhaka-10-constituency</link><description>Former adviser of the interim government and a frontline leader of July Uprising Asif Mahmud Shojib Bhuyain today collected the nomination form to contest the upcoming national election from the Dhaka-10 constituency comprising Dhanmondi, Kalabagan, New Market and Hazaribagh areas.
He collected th</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 13:58:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nagad wins award at Eastern Bank Digital Excellence Awards 2025</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/nagad-wins-award-at-eastern-bank-digital-excellence-awards-2025</link><description>Nagad has received the Excellence in Business Payout award from Eastern Bank Limited (EBL), one of the country’s leading private commercial banks, according to a press release.
Under this initiative, the bank honored 40 partner merchant organisations for their significant contributions to th</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 14:13:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump appoints envoy to Greenland, stirs backlash</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/trump-appoints-envoy-to-greenland-stirs-backlash</link><description>US President Donald Trump named Louisiana Governor Jeff Landry on Sunday as his special envoy to Greenland, drawing renewed criticism from Denmark and Greenland over Washington’s interest in the mineral-rich Arctic island.
Trump has advocated for Greenland, a self-governing Danish territory,</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 14:28:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Petrobangla, BMTF sign deal to digitally monitor industrial gas supply</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/petrobangla-bmtf-sign-deal-to-digitally-monitor-industrial-gas-supply</link><description>In a major step toward digitising the nation’s energy infrastructure, Petrobangla, the state carbohydron agency, and the Bangladesh Machine Tools Factory Limited (BMTF) signed a contract on Monday to implement a sophisticated GPS-based monitoring system for gas metering stations.
The contrac</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 14:43:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mob violence is a threat to democracy: Rizvi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/mob-violence-is-a-threat-to-democracy-rizvi</link><description>Expressing grave concern over the continued incidents of mob violence across the country, BNP Senior Joint Secretary General Ruhul Kabir Rizvi today said that the attacks being carried out by unruly mobs pose a serious threat to humanity and democratic values. He made these remarks while talki</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 14:58:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh ‘suspends’ visa services at Delhi, Agartala missions</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-suspends-visa-services-at-delhi-agartala-missions</link><description>Bangladesh has reportedly suspended visa services at its missions in India.
On Monday, the foreign ministry officials, who declined to be named, said notices about the suspension have been affixed at the Bangladesh High Commission in Delhi and the Assistant High Commission in Agartala, Tripura.</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 15:13:25 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>