<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 15:26:33 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>2 construction workers die after falling from Chattogram building</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/2-construction-workers-die-after-falling-from-chattogram-building</link><description>Two construction workers died after falling from an under-construction building in Anwara upazila of Chattogram district on Sunday.
The deceased were identified as Siam, 19 of Kushtia district and Anis, 25 of Rajshahi district.
The accident occurred in the afternoon in the Gundhipara area when th</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 13:45:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Work underway to bring relief in city dwellers life: DNCC Administrator</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/work-underway-to-bring-relief-in-city-dwellers-life-dncc-administrator</link><description>Administrator of Dhaka North City Corporation (DNCC) Shafiqul Islam Khan has said they are ready to work round the clock to restore comfort and relief of the city dwellers.
Talking to the reporters after visiting Korail slum this afternoon, he said, “From our position we are continuously wor</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 14:00:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Price of Dhaka WASA Water ATM water triples in two years</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/price-of-dhaka-wasa-water-atm-water-triples-in-two-years</link><description>The price of drinking water supplied through Water ATM booths in the capital has been tripled within the last two years, raising concerns among city residents already struggling with the cost of living.
Due to the failure of the Dhaka Water Supply and Sewerage Authority (Dhaka WASA) to ensure safe</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 12:56:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DSCC launches month-long mosquito control drive with four-tier monitoring</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dscc-launches-month-long-mosquito-control-drive-with-four-tier-monitoring</link><description>Amid a recent surge in mosquito infestation, Dhaka South City Corporation (DSCC) has launched a month-long special cleanliness and mosquito control “crash programme,” featuring a four-tier monitoring mechanism to ensure transparency and effectiveness.
The programme was inaugurated on S</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 13:11:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hundreds of ships drop anchor in Middle East Gulf, data shows</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/hundreds-of-ships-drop-anchor-in-middle-east-gulf-data-shows</link><description>At least 150 tankers, including crude and LNG vessels, dropped anchor in open Gulf waters beyond the Strait of Hormuz and dozens more were stationary on the other side of the chokepoint, shipping data showed on Sunday, after US and Israeli strikes on Iran plunged the region into turmoil.
The tanke</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 13:26:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>American-Bangladeshi alleges assault, death threats in Gazipur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/american-bangladeshi-alleges-assault-death-threats-in-gazipur</link><description>A non-resident Bangladeshi has filed a police complaint in Gazipur, alleging he was assaulted and threatened with death by the sons of a local BNP leader over a dispute regarding a utility connection.
The victim, Akram Hossain, a Bangladeshi origin US citizen, is staying at his ancestral residence</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 13:41:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh has extensive engagements with India: Salahuddin</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-has-extensive-engagements-with-india-as-neighbours-says-home-minister</link><description>Home Minister Salahuddin Ahmed has said Bangladesh has extensive engagements with India and expects to resolve outstanding issues through regular communication.
He made the remarks to reporters on Sunday after a courtesy call by Indian High Commissioner Pranay Verma at the Secretariat.
“As</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 13:56:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladeshi killed in Iranian drone strike on UAE</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/one-bangladeshi-dead-others-injured-as-uae-intercepts-over-500-drones-from-iran</link><description>A Bangladeshi national is among three individuals killed in the United Arab Emirates following a wave of retaliatory drone strikes launched by Iran, the UAE Ministry of Defence has confirmed.
In a statement posted on social media platform X on Sunday, the ministry detailed the scale of the Iranian</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 14:11:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Civil aviation minister’s mother passes away at 83</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/civil-aviation-ministers-mother-passes-away-at-83</link><description>Hurun Nahar Rashid, mother of Civil Aviation and Tourism Minister Afroza Khanam Rita, passed away early Sunday at the age of 83 (Inna Lillahi wa Inna Ilaihi Raji'un).
She breathed her last at 4:30 am at Evercare Hospital in the capital, where she had been undergoing treatment.
Hurun Nahar Rashid</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 14:26:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP to take country forward under Tarique’s leadership: Moyeen Khan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-to-take-country-forward-under-tariques-leadership-moyeen-khan</link><description>BNP Standing Committee member Dr Abdul Moyeen Khan on Sunday said the current government will move the country forward in a united manner under the leadership of Prime Minister Tarique Rahman.
“BNP has repeatedly been elected by people’s votes because it is a people-based political par</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 14:41:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Month-long awareness campaign on road safety begins</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/month-long-awareness-campaign-on-road-safety-begins</link><description>A month-long road safety awareness campaign has begun in Dhaka to increase public awareness and thus prevent road accidents and reduce the number of accidental casualties. 
The campaign is being conducted by Swift Solution, a private organisation that has been working on road safety for a lon</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 14:56:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladeshi among 3 killed, 58 injured in UAE as Iranian attacks continue</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladeshi-among-3-killed-58-injured-in-uae-as-iranian-attacks-continue</link><description>Three people, including a Bangladeshi national, were killed and 58 others injured in the United Arab Emirates since the launch of Iranian attacks on February 28, the UAE Ministry of Defence said.
The casualties include individuals of Emirati, Egyptian, Ethiopian, Filipino, Pakistani, Iranian, Indi</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 15:11:19 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>