<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 12:48:08 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Superintendents of police picked by lottery in all 64 districts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/superintendents-of-police-picked-by-lottery-in-all-64-districts</link><description>Superintendents of police (SPs) have been selected for all 64 districts through a lottery ahead of the upcoming parliamentary elections next year.
The lottery was held at the State Guest House Jamuna, the official residence of Chief Advisor Muhammad Yunus, on Monday, according to several police</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 09:32:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Plot graft: Verdict in case against British MP Tulip on Dec 1</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/plot-graft-verdict-in-case-against-british-mp-tulip-on-dec-1</link><description>A Dhaka court has fixed Dec 1 to deliver its verdict in an Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) case against ousted prime minister Sheikh Hasina, her sister Sheikh Rehana, Rehana's daughter and British MP Tulip Siddiq, and 17 others on charges of fraud in allocating plots under the Purbachal New Town P</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 09:47:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Stronger registration law essential to protecting women’s rights: Speakers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/stronger-registration-law-essential-to-protecting-womens-rights-speakers</link><description>Speakers at a webinar on Tuesday said a strong birth and death registration law is particularly important for safeguarding women’s fundamental rights, including access to education, healthcare, social protection and justice.
The webinar titled “Stronger Registration Laws to Protect Wom</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 09:48:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DMP files 1,590 cases against traffic rules violators</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dmp-files-1590-cases-against-traffic-rules-violators</link><description>Traffic Division of Dhaka Metropolitan Police (DMP) filed a total of 1,590 cases against motor vehicles and drivers for violating traffic rules in the capital over the past day.
The DMP has been conducting drives against traffic rule violations in the city to bring the traffic management system un</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 10:03:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>365,472 financial units excluded from Economic Census count: Survey</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/365472-financial-units-excluded-from-economic-census-count-survey</link><description>A total of 365,472 financial units were excluded from the count of the Economic Census, according to a survey. 
The Economic Census, conducted in 2024, had recorded over 11.88 million financial establishments, but a later Post Enumeration Check (PEC) revealed that the national Net Coverage Er</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 10:18:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two to die in Cumilla murder case</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/two-to-die-in-cumilla-murder-case</link><description>A court on Tuesday sentenced two people to death and five others to life term imprisonment in a murder case in Chauddagram upazila of the district in 2013.
Judge of Additional Sessions Judge's Court-3 Sabrina Nargis delivered the verdict on Tuesday afternoon. 
The death-row convicts are Zia</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 10:33:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt finalizes SPs for 64 districts through lottery</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-finalizes-sps-for-64-districts-through-lottery</link><description>The interim government has finalized the appointments of Superintendents of Police (SPs) for all 64 districts through a lottery system ahead of the upcoming 13th national parliament elections.
The lottery was conducted on Monday at the residence of the Chief Adviser, Jamuna, in the presence of Act</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 10:48:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Four pc street boys face commercial sexual exploitation, study reveals</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/four-pc-street-boys-face-commercial-sexual-exploitation-study-reveals</link><description>Almost 4 per cent of the street-involved boys in Dhaka are victims of commercial sexual exploitation, according to new national research launched on Monday by The Freedom Fund with government agencies, research partners, and national child protection organisations. 
 
The findings, from</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 10:49:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt to promote 800 judicial officials</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-to-promote-800-judicial-officials</link><description>The government is set to promote around 800 officials of the Bangladesh Judicial Service, with 250 being elevated to the rank of district judge — the highest number ever promoted at one time, according to sources at the Ministry of Law, Justice and Parliamentary Affairs.
The mass promotion</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 11:04:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>28 rescued in Teknaf from attempted trafficking to Malaysia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/28-rescued-in-teknaf-from-attempted-trafficking-to-malaysia</link><description>Twenty-eight people, including women and children, were rescued early Monday from an attempted trafficking journey to Malaysia during a joint operation by the Coast Guard and police in Teknaf’s Baharchhara area.
Coast Guard Media Officer Lt Commander Siam-ul-Hoque said on Tuesday that the op</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 11:19:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Top criminal’ Chhoto Sajjad transferred to Rajshahi jail, wife moved to Feni</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/top-criminal-chhoto-sajjad-transferred-to-rajshahi-jail-wife-moved-to-feni</link><description>Sajjad Hossain alias Chhoto Sajjad, a “top-listed” criminal currently behind bars, and his wife have been transferred from Chattogram Central Jail.
Sajjad has been moved to Rajshahi Central Jail, and his wife Sharmin Akter Tamanna to Feni District Jail, Chattogram Senior Jail Super Iqb</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 11:34:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Job creation key to equality, faster poverty reduction in Bangladesh: World Bank</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/job-creation-key-to-equality-faster-poverty-reduction-in-bangladesh-world-bank</link><description>Bangladesh reduced poverty significantly between 2010-2022, lifting 25 million people out of poverty and another 9 million people out of extreme poverty while improving living standards and access to essential services like electricity, education, and sanitation, but since 2016, the pace of poverty</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 11:49:22 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>