<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 14:23:59 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>MJL Bangladesh holds 27th Annual General Meeting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/mjl-bangladesh-holds-27th-annual-general-meeting</link><description>The 27th Annual General Meeting (AGM) of MJL Bangladesh PLC (MJLBPLC) was held on Monday, December 22, 2025, at 11:00 a.m. through virtual conferencing.
The meeting was presided over by Mr. Abdul-Muyeed Chowdhury, Chairman of MJLBPLC, according to a press release.
Managing Director of MJLBPLC Mr.</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 11:26:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Israeli military says it is examining killing of Palestinian teen in West Bank</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/israeli-military-says-it-is-examining-killing-of-palestinian-teen-in-west-bank</link><description>The Israeli military said it was reviewing an incident in the occupied West Bank in which soldiers shot dead a 16-year-old Palestinian who they said had thrown a brick at them, after CCTV footage appeared to show he was not doing so when shot.
Asked about the video, an Israeli military spokesperso</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 11:41:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Iran holds missile drills in various cities, state media say</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/iran-holds-missile-drills-in-various-cities-state-media-say</link><description>Iran held missile drills in various cities on Monday, state media reported, citing unnamed sources and witnesses, in what was the second such reported exercise in a month.
NBC News reported on Saturday that US President Donald Trump was to be briefed by Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu th</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 11:56:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prime Bank signs Payroll Banking agreement with Bauwerk Limited</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/prime-bank-signs-payroll-banking-agreement-with-bauwerk-limited</link><description>Prime Bank PLC has recently signed a Payroll Banking agreement with Bauwerk Limited, a global leader in providing technology- leading products, systems and services to the worldwide construction industry to offer comprehensive Payroll Banking services.
The signing ceremony took place at the bank&amp;r</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 12:11:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Midland Bank signs MoU with Marco Polo Dhaka Hotel</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/midland-bank-signs-mou-with-marco-polo-dhaka-hotel</link><description>Midland Bank PLC. signed a Memorandum of Understanding (MoU) with Marco Polo Dhaka Hotel on 15 December 2025. 
The MoU signing ceremony was held at Midland Bank PLC’s Head Office in Gulshan-2, Dhaka, according to a media release. 
Mr. Md. Nazmul Huda Sarkar, Chief Technology Offic</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 12:26:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>bKash hosts seminar on Cyber Space Compliance for its AML, CFT officials</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bkash-hosts-seminar-on-cyber-space-compliance-for-its-aml-cft-officials</link><description>bKash has organised a two-day long seminar to boost skills of all employees engaged in Anti Money Laundering and Combating the Financing of Terrorism (AML&amp;amp;CFT) compliance functions.
According to a press release, the theme of this half-yearly seminar was “Strengthening AML&amp;amp;CFT Frameworks in C</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 12:41:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Attack on Prothom Alo office: 15 sent to jail</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/attack-on-prothom-alo-office-15-sent-to-jail</link><description>A Dhaka court has ordered 15 people, arrested under the Anti-Terrorism Act in connection with the attack on the office of the daily Prothom Alo, to be sent to jail.
The accused are Md. Naim Islam, 25; Md. Sagar Islam, 37; Md. Ahad Sheikh, 20; Md. Biplob, 20; Md. Nazrul Islam alias Minhaj, 20; Md.</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 12:56:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Inflation to fall below 7 per cent by mid-2026 amid tightening policies, expects govt</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/inflation-to-fall-below-7-per-cent-by-mid-2026-amid-tightening-policies-expects-govt</link><description>Bangladesh’s interim government believes inflation could fall below 7 per cent by June 2026, buoyed by contractionary monetary policy, fiscal restraint and improving balance across key economic indicators, officials said after a high-level meeting chaired by the chief adviser, Muhammad Yunus.</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 13:11:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Netanyahu government moves to shut down Israel's Army Radio station</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/netanyahu-government-moves-to-shut-down-israels-army-radio-station</link><description>Israel's cabinet voted on Monday to shut down a popular national radio station, one in a series of measures by Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu's right-wing coalition that critics see as blows to democracy.
Defence Minister Israel Katz had proposed that Army Radio, broadcasting since the early da</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 13:26:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Voting is constitutional right, not anyone’s charity: Prof Yunus</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/voting-is-constitutional-right-not-anyones-charity-prof-yunus</link><description>Chief Adviser Prof Muhammad Yunus on Monday said voting right is not anyone’s charity as it is people’s constitutional right.
“By exercising this right we decide which path our future will take. Ensuring a free, fair and participatory election is not only the responsibility of th</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 13:41:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Crown Cement declares 21pc cash dividend</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/crown-cement-declares-21pc-cash-dividend</link><description>The shareholders of Crown Cement have approved 21 per cent cash dividend for the year ended 30 June 2025, as recommended by the board of directors.
The approval was given during the 31st Annual General Meeting (AGM) of the company, which was held through digital platform on Monday (December 22), a</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 13:56:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DU halls ‘safe’ after earthquake, authorities say</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/du-halls-safe-after-earthquake-authorities-say</link><description>Following November’s earthquake, Dhaka University has assessed its residential halls and determined that “no building is structurally at risk”, university authorities confirmed.
On Monday, Treasurer and Chair of the Post-Earthquake Building Inspection Committee Prof M Jahangir Al</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 14:11:49 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>