<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 07:30:51 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Trump says Denmark cannot protect Greenland</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-says-denmark-cannot-protect-greenland</link><description>US President Donald Trump on Monday said the United States would talk about acquiring Greenland at this week's Davos World Economic Forum because Denmark cannot protect the country.
"We have to have it. They have to have this done. They can't protect it, Denmark, they're wonderful people," Trump t</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 05:30:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tribunal defers verdict in Chankharpul crimes against humanity case to Jan 26</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tribunal-defers-verdict-in-chankharpul-crimes-against-humanity-case-to-jan-26</link><description>The International Crimes Tribunal has deferred the verdict in a crimes against humanity case filed over the six murders in Dhaka’s Chankharpul during the July Uprising to Jan 26.
The fate of eight suspects, including former Dhaka Metropolitan Police commissioner Habibur Rahman, will now rema</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 05:45:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Canada could send small contingent of troops to Greenland</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/canada-could-send-small-contingent-of-troops-to-greenland</link><description>Canada is considering whether to send a small contingent of troops to Greenland to take part in NATO military exercises, a source directly familiar with the matter said on Monday.
The news was first reported by the CBC News and the Globe and Mail newspaper.
Military officials have presented plans</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 06:00:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump ties his stance on Greenland to not getting Nobel Peace Prize</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-ties-his-stance-on-greenland-to-not-getting-nobel-peace-prize</link><description>US President Donald Trump linked his aggressive stance on Greenland to last year’s decision not to award him the Nobel Peace Prize, telling Norway’s prime minister that he no longer felt “an obligation to think purely of Peace,” in a text message released Monday.
Trump's me</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 06:15:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chile wildfires kill 19 amid extreme heat; scores evacuated</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/chile-wildfires-kill-19-amid-extreme-heat-scores-evacuated</link><description>Wildfires in Chile have killed at least 19 people, authorities said on Monday, as the government carried out mass evacuations and fought over 30 blazes exacerbated by intense heat and high winds.
While weather conditions overnight helped control some fires, the largest were still active, with adve</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 06:30:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Stocks open mixed as DSE rises, CSE falls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/stocks-open-mixed-as-dse-rises-cse-falls</link><description>Trading at the country’s stock markets began on a mixed note on Tuesday, the third working day of the week, with indices rising at the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) while the Chittagong Stock Exchange (CSE) edged lower.
In the first half of the session, the DSE’s benchmark index gained 12</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 06:00:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Syria says 120 IS detainees escaped prison; Kurdish website said 1,500 escaped</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/syria-says-120-is-detainees-escaped-prison-kurdish-website-said-1500-escaped</link><description>Syria's Interior Ministry said on Tuesday that about 120 Islamic State detainees escaped from Shaddadi prison, after the Kurdish website Rudaw reported that a spokesperson for the Kurdish-led Syrian Democratic Forces, Farhad Shami, said around 1,500 Islamic State members had escaped.
The Syrian mi</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 06:15:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bulgarian President Radev resigns</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/bulgarian-president-radev-resigns-amid-speculation-he-will-form-his-own-party</link><description>Bulgarian President Rumen Radev said on Monday he will resign, fuelling speculation that he will form his own political party to run in upcoming parliamentary elections after the previous government quit last month.
Radev, who was due to hold the largely ceremonial post until January 2027, said he</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 06:30:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC constituency demarcation prevails for Cumilla-2</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-constituency-demarcation-prevails-for-cumilla-2</link><description>The Appellate Division has upheld the constituency boundaries for Cumilla-2 as redrawn by the Election Commission ahead of the 13th parliamentary election.
A three-member appellate bench led by Chief Justice Zubayer Rahman Chowdhury passed the order on Tuesday, bdnews24.com reports.
During the 12</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 06:45:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>JG Healthcare to represent Sunway Medical Centre in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/jg-healthcare-to-represent-sunway-medical-centre-in-bangladesh</link><description>JG Healthcare Limited has been appointed the authorised representative and local patient referral office of Sunway Medical Centre Sdn Bhd, Malaysia, under a newly signed service agreement.
The agreement enables Bangladeshi patients to access verified medical information, consultation coordination,</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 07:00:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Evaly's Rassel, Shamima arrested again</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/evalys-rassel-shamima-arrested-again</link><description>Detectives have arrested Evaly Managing Director Mohammad Rassel and its Chairperson Shamima Nasrin in Dhaka.
A team of the Detective Branch (DB) detained them in the city’s Dhanmondi area early Tuesday, said Saiful Islam, officer-in-charge of Dhanmondi Police Station.
He said a total of 39</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 07:15:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Coordinated bid underway to manipulate election results, says Abbas</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/coordinated-bid-underway-to-manipulate-election-results-says-abbas</link><description>BNP Standing Committee member Mirza Abbas has alleged that a major party and a small one are making coordinated attempts to influence the outcome of the national election in several constituencies.
Speaking at a discussion meeting on Tuesday at the Diploma Engineers’ Institute in the capital</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 07:30:48 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>