<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 23:19:59 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Watchman dies in railing collapse during quake</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/security-guard-struck-by-falling-railing-during-quake-dies-in-dhaka</link><description>A security guard has died in Dhaka’s Mugda after a railing from the roof of an under-construction building collapsed during the earthquake.
The guard, identified with a single name Maksud, was critically injured when the 5.7 magnitude earthquake struck on Friday.
He was taken to Mugda Gener</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 15:47:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Frustration deepens in BNP allies as seat-sharing talks stall ahead of election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/frustration-deepens-in-bnp-allies-as-seat-sharing-talks-stall-ahead-of-election</link><description>Almost three weeks after the BNP unveiled its list of potential contenders for 236 constituencies, a quiet unease is spreading among the party’s allies.
What began as hopeful indications for a unified electoral strategy has now turned into growing frustration, as the long-expected seat-shari</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 15:18:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Zelenskiy say he won't betray Ukrainian interests in US-led peace process</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/zelenskiy-say-he-wont-betray-ukrainian-interests-in-us-led-peace-process</link><description>President Volodymyr Zelenskiy said on Friday he would not betray Ukraine's interests in a US-led peace process, warning that Kyiv faces a choice between losing a key partner and its national dignity at one of the most perilous moments in its history.
The 28-point plan that the United States has pr</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 15:33:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fintech revolution &amp; financial inclusion</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/fintech-revolution-financial-inclusion</link><description>In South Asia, more specifically in Bangladesh, the most significant financial innovation of this decade has neither been an opening of bank branches, an expansion in banks, nor an increased governmental regulation of finance. Rather, innovation has been brought by the mobile phone, which is increa</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 15:48:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Toilet success, sewer failure</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/toilet-success-sewer-failure</link><description>Last Wednesday, countries observed the World Toilet Day with three key messages: we'll always need the toilet, toilets are under pressure and we need toilets fit for the future. The significance of these messages cannot be overstated. UN-Water, the UN's coordination mechanism on water and sanitatio</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 16:03:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Rohingya's path to self determination</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/the-rohingyas-path-to-self-determination</link><description>During last Ramadan, standing beside UN Secretary General Antonio Guterres in a refugee camp, Professor Muhammad Yunus expressed his hope that the Rohingya community would be able to offer their next Eid prayers in their homeland of Arakan. His words kindled a fragile expectation among a persecuted</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 16:18:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Earthquake and the risk to Dhaka residents</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/earthquake-and-the-risk-to-dhaka-residents</link><description>Earthquakes seldom announce themselves before they strike yet their consequences reflect years of choices made about how cities grow and how safety is enforced. The tremor that rippled through Dhaka and nearby districts on Friday morning was a moderate event by global standards, but even so it made</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 16:33:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>400 hurt in Gazipur as buildings crack from quake</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/earthquake-injures-400-in-gazipur-as-buildings-crack-control-rooms-opened</link><description>At least 400 people have been injured in Gazipur after rushing out of buildings during an earthquake, most of them reported to be workers.
The tremor occurred at 10:38am on Friday, with its epicentre in Narshingdi’s Madhabdi, said Bangladesh Meteorological Department’s Seismology Centr</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 16:48:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Earthquake: Japan stands in solidarity with Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/earthquake-japan-stands-in-solidarity-with-bangladesh</link><description>Ambassador of Japan to Bangladesh Saida Shinichi on Friday said that Japan, as an earthquake-prone nation, stands in solidarity with Bangladesh during this challenging time.
As a testament to the enduring solidarity between Bangladesh and Japan, the Ambassador extended his deepest condolences and</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 17:34:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh earthquake death toll rises to 10; scores injured</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-earthquake-death-toll-rises-to-10-scores-injured</link><description>The death toll from the 5.7-magnitude earthquake that struck Dhaka and several other parts of the country on Friday morning rose to 10.
Of them, four were killed in Dhaka, five in Narsingdi district, the epic centre of the earthquake, and one in Narayanganj.
Thirteen people were injured after the</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 17:49:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pahartali railway workshop: Where trains are reborn</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/pahartali-railway-workshop-where-trains-are-reborn</link><description>On a sunny July morning, with white clouds scattered across the light blue sky, I take an autorickshaw from the busy Tiger Pass Circle in the heart of Chattogram. My destination is the Pahartali Carriage and Wagon Repair Workshop of Bangladesh Railway (BR). It is a short and pleasant ride down the</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 18:35:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Earthquake leaves dozen dead, scores injured</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/earthquake-leaves-dozen-dead-scores-injured</link><description>Buildings rocked massively and residents made panic exit in Dhaka and nearby as a major earthquake shook Bangladesh on Friday morning that left around a dozen people dead and scores injured.
A large number of buildings in the crammed capital city, Dhaka, developed cracks or tilted, sending down de</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 18:50:39 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>