<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 11:21:20 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Trump says to make phone call to stop Thai-Cambodia fighting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/trump-says-to-make-phone-call-to-stop-thai-cambodia-fighting</link><description>Fighting between Thailand and Cambodia extended into a third day on Wednesday as US President Donald Trump said he would make a phone call to stop the conflict, after he had brokered a ceasefire in July to end a five-day battle between the Asian neighbours.
Thailand's foreign minister said in an i</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 08:22:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bagerhat keeps 4 seats, Gazipur retains 5: Appellate Division</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/bagerhat-keeps-4-seats-gazipur-retains-5-appellate-division</link><description>The Appellate Division on Wednesday ruled that Bagerhat district will retain its four parliamentary seats, while Gazipur will continue with five.
The seven-member full bench, headed by Chief Justice Dr Syed Refaat Ahmed, passed the order.
Earlier, on November 10, a High Court (HC) ruling restored</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 08:37:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Urgent reforms needed to curb VAT leakage, expand tax net: Salehuddin</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/urgent-reforms-needed-to-curb-vat-leakage-expand-tax-net-salehuddin</link><description>Finance Adviser Dr Salehuddin Ahmed has underscored the urgent need to curb VAT leakage, widen both VAT and income tax coverage, and modernise Bangladesh’s tax administration.
“Bangladesh’s economic progress depends fundamentally on its ability to mobilise domestic resources rath</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 08:52:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>4,200 kg sodium cyclamate seized at Chattogram Custom House</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/4200-kg-sodium-cyclamate-seized-at-chattogram-custom-house</link><description>An intelligence team in Chattogram Custom House has seized another consignment of prohibited artificial sweetener Sodium Cyclamate weighing 4,200 kilograms.
According to a press release issued by the National Board of Revenue (NBR) on Wednesday, the operation was carried out by the intelligence te</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 09:07:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>If India doesn't extradite Hasina, Dhaka has no real option to bring back: Adviser Touhid</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/if-india-doesnt-extradite-hasina-dhaka-has-no-real-option-to-bring-back-adviser-touhid</link><description>Bangladesh’s interim foreign affairs adviser, Mohammad Touhid Hossain, has said Dhaka has little scope to force the return of former prime minister Sheikh Hasina unless New Delhi agrees to extradite her.
Speaking to reporters at the foreign ministry on Wednesday, Hossain acknowledged Banglad</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 09:22:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CA urges UNO’s to make upcoming election ‘historic and unforgettable’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ca-urges-unos-to-make-upcoming-election-historic-and-unforgettable</link><description>Chief Adviser, Professor Muhammad Yunus, has called on Upazila Nirbahi Officers (UNOs) across the country to ensure that the upcoming national election becomes a defining moment in the nation’s history. 
Describing the post-uprising vote as an opportunity to rebuild Bangladesh, Yunus ur</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 09:37:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Asif Nazrul for safeguarding reforms for next course of advancement</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/asif-nazrul-for-safeguarding-reforms-for-next-course-of-advancement</link><description>Law, Justice and Parliamentary Affairs Adviser Dr Asif Nazrul today (Wednesday) stressed the importance of safeguarding the reforms already introduced by the interim government, saying the next course of advancement must be built on these achievements. "When we talk about reforms, a common fru</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 09:52:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CEC to record speech on election schedule</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cec-to-record-speech-on-election-schedule</link><description>The Election Commission (EC), led by AMM Nasir Uddin, is finalising preparations to announce the schedule for the upcoming general election and referendum following a meeting with the president.
The address is scheduled to be recorded at the Election Building on Wednesday afternoon, bdnews24.com r</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 10:00:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Private off-docks go on undeclared strike, export sector worries</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/private-off-docks-go-on-undeclared-strike-export-sector-worries</link><description>After failing to collect their expected excise and duties, private off-docks have opted for an undeclared strike from Thursday. As part of the programme, they will refrain from handling export containers and empty containers.
Those concerned worry that the export sector in the country will face lo</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 10:15:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Budget-friendly places to do Yoga in Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/others/budget-friendly-places-to-do-yoga-in-dhaka</link><description>Have you ever thought of having a stress-free, relaxed life after a busy day? We have our everyday struggles. Hustling here and there for our livelihoods or juggling academic pressure and personal expectations, leaving no room for mental peace. So, repetitive conditions like these make us think of</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 10:30:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>President expresses satisfaction over EC’s preparations for polls, referendum</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/president-expresses-satisfaction-over-ecs-preparations-for-polls-referendum</link><description>President Mohammed Shahabuddin expressed satisfaction over the preparations undertaken by the Election Commission (EC) ahead of the upcoming 13th parliamentary election and the national referendum, EC Senior Secretary Akhtar Ahmed said on Wednesday.
“The President expressed satisfaction afte</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 10:45:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UK finance minister Reeves says budget leaks were frustrating and unacceptable</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/uk-finance-minister-reeves-says-budget-leaks-were-frustrating-and-unacceptable</link><description>British finance minister Rachel Reeves said on Wednesday that she was frustrated with leaks about her budget before her November 26 tax and spending statement, including media reports about possible income tax rises.
Reeves had appeared to pave the way for an income tax rate hike - which would hav</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 11:00:49 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>