<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 09:29:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Past projects taking toll on state coffer</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/past-projects-taking-toll-on-state-coffer</link><description>State bank borrowing is swelling for having to fund the development projects undertaken by the fallen regime, as the interim government is in a double bind because ditching those will amount to twofold losses.
Finance Adviser of the post-uprising government Dr Salehuddin Ahmed Monday struck such d</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 04:15:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Health ministry’s poor show drags execution</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/health-ministrys-poor-show-drags-execution</link><description>Despite being the third-largest budget-holder, the Ministry of Health and Family Welfare has recorded the lowest project- implementation rate, affecting overall development progress and potentially slowing Bangladesh’s economic growth, officials said on Monday.
The slow performance has also</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 04:30:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Renata’s debt-reduction strategy may spur new entrants to secondary market</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/renatas-debt-reduction-strategy-may-spur-new-entrants-to-secondary-market</link><description>Renata’s listed preference shares, offering a 15 per cent return, may serve as an example for other companies seeking to reduce debt burdens while strengthening investor confidence.
To replace high-cost short-term loans with lower-cost, long-term funding, the drug manufacturer issued prefere</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 04:45:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bondi gunmen were inspired by Islamic State, had travelled to the Philippines, Australia police say</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/bondi-gunmen-were-inspired-by-islamic-state-had-travelled-to-the-philippines-australia-police-say</link><description>Two alleged gunmen who attacked a Hanukkah event at Sydney’s Bondi Beach had travelled to the Philippines before the assault which killed 15 people and appeared to be inspired by Islamic State, police said on Tuesday.
The attack on Sunday was Australia’s worst mass shooting in nearly 3</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 05:00:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump sues the BBC for defamation over editing of Jan 6 speech, seeks up to $10 billion in damages</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-sues-the-bbc-for-defamation-over-editing-of-jan-6-speech-seeks-up-to-10-billion-in-damages</link><description>President Donald Trump sued the BBC on Monday for defamation over edited clips of a speech that made it appear he directed supporters to storm the US Capitol, opening an international front in his fight against media coverage he deems untrue or unfair.
Trump accused Britain’s publicly owned</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 06:44:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fines imposed, illegal brick kilns shut in nationwide anti-pollution drive</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fines-imposed-illegal-brick-kilns-shut-in-nationwide-anti-pollution-drive</link><description>The Department of Environment (DoE) has carried out a coordinated nationwide enforcement drive against air pollution, illegal brick kilns, the use of banned polythene and industrial units operating without environmental clearance.
During the drives on Monday, mobile courts imposed fines, shut down</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 06:59:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Home Adviser, IGP pay tributes to martyred police members on Victory Day</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/home-adviser-igp-pay-tributes-to-martyred-police-members-on-victory-day</link><description>Home Adviser Lt Gen (retd) Md Jahangir Alam Chowdhury and Inspector General of Police (IGP) Baharul Alam on Tuesday paid tribute to the martyred police members of the Liberation War on the occasion of the Victory Day at the Rajarbagh Police Lines memorial.
They placed wreaths at the memorial at ar</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 07:14:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BGB DG pays tribute to Liberation War martyrs on Victory Day</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bgb-dg-pays-tribute-to-liberation-war-martyrs-on-victory-day</link><description>Border Guard Bangladesh (BGB) Director General Major General Mohammad Ashrafuzzaman Siddiqui on Tuesday morning paid homage to the martyrs of the Liberation War by placing a wreath at ‘Simanta Gaurab’ at the BGB Headquarters in Pilkhana, Dhaka.
On the occasion, a smartly turned-out con</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 07:29:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Anti-independence forces trying to resurface on Victory Day: Fakhrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/anti-independence-forces-trying-to-resurface-on-victory-day-fakhrul</link><description>BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir on Tuesday said the forces that opposed Bangladesh’s independence in 1971 are once again trying to raise their heads.
“Those who stood against Bangladesh’s independence in 1971 are now trying to raise their heads again. But the pe</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 07:44:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Injustice, discriminations led people to revolt in 1971: Jamaat Ameer</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/injustice-discriminations-led-people-to-revolt-in-1971-jamaat-ameer</link><description>Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami Ameer Dr Shafiqur Rahman on Tuesday the people of the then East Pakistan rose in revolt as the Pakistani ruling elite perpetrated injustice and created discriminations against them.
He made the remarks while speaking as the chief guest at the inauguration of a youth mara</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 07:59:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Victory Day tributes overshadowed by 'electioneering' at National Memorial</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/election-code-under-scrutiny-as-national-memorial-becomes-campaign-stage-on-victory-day</link><description>Supporters of several political leaders have been accused of breaching the electoral code of conduct by chanting slogans and displaying campaign material while paying tribute at Savar’s National Martyrs’ Memorial on Victory Day.
The incidents occurred just days after the Election Commi</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 08:14:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CJ, judges pay tribute to martyrs at National Memorial</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/chief-justice-sc-judges-pay-tribute-to-liberation-war-martyrs-at-national-memorial</link><description>Chief Justice Syed Refaat Ahmed has led the judges of the Supreme Court in paying tribute to the martyrs of Bangladesh’s 1971 Liberation War at the National Martyrs’ Memorial in Savar.
The head of the judiciary and fellow judges laid wreaths at the memorial at 7:05am on Tuesday, markin</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 08:29:37 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>