<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 13:31:58 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Japan scrambles jets after nuclear-capable Russian bombers fly nearby</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/japan-scrambles-jets-after-nuclear-capable-russian-bombers-fly-nearby</link><description>Japan said it scrambled jets on Friday to monitor Russian warplanes, including strategic bombers capable of carrying nuclear weapons, which had flown along the edge of Japanese airspace up its coast.
Russia's Defence Ministry, in a statement reported by state-owned RIA news agency, confirmed that</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 10:29:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two killed after truck crashes into bus in Faridpur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/two-killed-after-truck-crashes-into-bus-in-faridpur</link><description>Two people have been killed and several others injured after a truck ploughed into a bus that had just been involved in a collision with another truck in Faridpur’s Bhanga Upazila.
The accident occurred on the Dhaka-Khulna highway near the Tarail bus stand area around 2:45am on Friday, said</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 10:44:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>At least 14 dead after migrant boat sinks off western Turkey</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/at-least-14-dead-after-migrant-boat-sinks-off-western-turkey</link><description>At least 14 people drowned when a rubber boat carrying migrants sank off Turkey's western province of Mugla on Friday, the local governor's office said, adding that a search and rescue operation was underway for possible survivors.
In a statement, the Mugla Governor's Office said an Afghan man who</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 10:59:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Missing freedom fighter found dead in Habiganj</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/missing-freedom-fighter-found-dead-in-habiganj</link><description>Police have recovered the body of a freedom fighter a day after he went missing in Nabiganj Upazila of Habiganj.
Manik Lal Das, 75, was found floating in a waterbody of Shaulagor Haor at Chargaon in Boro Bhakoir (West) Union on Thursday evening, said Nabiganj Police chief Sheikh Mohammad Kamruzzam</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 11:14:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh reiterates support for Palestinian statehood</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-reiterates-support-for-palestinian-statehood</link><description>Bangladesh on Friday reiterated its unwavering support for the inalienable rights of the Palestinian people, including their right to self-determination and the establishment of an independent and sovereign State of Palestine based on the pre-1967 borders, with East Jerusalem as its capital.
The g</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 11:29:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EU accuses Meta and TikTok of breaching transparency rules</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/eu-accuses-meta-and-tiktok-of-breaching-transparency-rules</link><description>The European Union on Friday said Meta and TitTok had breached their transparency obligations after an investigation that could result in billions of dollars in fines.
The inquiry found both companies had violated the Digital Services Act, the EU’s trailblazing digital rule book that imposes</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 11:59:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>468 patients hospitalised with dengue in 24 hours</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/468-patients-hospitalised-with-dengue-in-24-hours</link><description>A total of 468 new dengue patients were hospitalized across the country in the past 24 hours, according to a press release issued by the Directorate General of Health Services (DGHS) on Friday.
Of them, 73 were admitted to hospitals in Barishal division(outside City Corporation), 87 in Chattogram</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 12:14:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique Rahman will return by November, Salahuddin expects</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-rahman-will-return-by-november-salahuddin-expects</link><description>BNP Standing Committee Member Salahuddin Ahmed said on Friday he expects the party’s acting chairman Tarique Rahman to return home by November.
“It is expected that BNP’s acting chairman Tarique Rahman will return home by November,” he told reporters at his residence in Gul</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 12:29:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Diversion planned for routine maintenance of Karnaphuli Tunnel</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/diversion-planned-for-routine-maintenance-of-karnaphuli-tunnel</link><description>The Bangladesh Bridge Authority (BBA) has announced an overnight traffic diversion at the Karnaphuli Tunnel to carry out scheduled maintenance work.
The maintenance will begin tomorrow and continue until October 30, according to a press release issued by the BBA.
The diversions will be in effect</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 12:44:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Roadside bombing kills 3 police officers in northwest Pakistan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/roadside-bombing-kills-3-police-officers-in-northwest-pakistan</link><description>A powerful roadside bomb struck a police vehicle Friday in a former stronghold of the Pakistani Taliban in the country’s northwest near the Afghan border, killing a city police chief and two junior officers, officials said.
The bombing took place in the city of Hangu in Khyber Pakhtunkhwa pr</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 13:14:11 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>