<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 09:21:13 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Freedom fighter, wife killed in Rangpur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/freedom-fighter-wife-killed-in-rangpur</link><description>A freedom fighter and his wife were found dead with their throats slit at their home in Taraganj upazila of Rangpur early Sunday.
The deceased were identified as freedom fighter Jogesh Chandra Roy, 75, a retired headteacher of a local government primary school, and his wife Surbonna Roy, 60, resid</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 06:30:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Malaysia seeks deeper tourism ties with Bangladesh: envoy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/malaysia-seeks-deeper-tourism-ties-with-bangladesh-envoy</link><description>Malaysian High Commissioner Mohd Shuhada Othman has said Malaysia is committed to strengthening tourism, cultural and people-to-people ties with Bangladesh as both nations continue to deepen friendship built on trust, mutual respect and shared aspirations.
"Over the decades, our relationship has g</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 07:00:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Three killed in Faridpur road crash</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/three-killed-in-faridpur-road-crash</link><description>Three people were killed as an unidentified vehicle crashed into a motorbike in Bhanga upazila of Faridpur early Sunday.
The deceased were two brothers, Sumon, 25, and Imon, 22, sons of Karim Mondol from Sadhki Mohammadpur in Kumarkhali upazila of Kushtia, and Ashik Molla, 22, reports UNB.
The sp</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 07:15:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Volunteers remove nearly 2 tonnes of waste from St Martin</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/volunteers-remove-nearly-2-tonnes-of-waste-from-st-martin</link><description>Volunteers have removed nearly two tonnes of waste from St Martin’s beaches as Unilever Bangladesh and Kewkradong Bangladesh led the International Coastal Cleanup 2025 on the ecologically sensitive island, mobilising hundreds of youth and local residents to protect its fragile coastline.
A t</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 07:30:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Zubaida back at Evercare as medical board meets over Khaleda's care</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/zubaida-back-at-evercare-as-medical-board-meets-over-khaledas-care</link><description>After spending the night at her parents' home in Dhanmondi, Zubaida Rahman has returned to Evercare Hospital, where her ailing mother-in-law and BNP chief Khaleda Zia has been receiving critical care for the last two weeks.
She arrived at the hospital around 11:30am on Sunday and was with Khaleda</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 07:02:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DSE opens higher, CSE sees early decline</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/dse-opens-higher-cse-sees-early-decline</link><description>Trading at the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) began on a positive note on Thursday, while the Chittagong Stock Exchange (CSE) opened lower.
During the first hour, DSE's key index, DSEX, gained 7 points, as per a UNB report.
The Shariah-based DSES also edged up by 2 points, while the blue-chip DS30 in</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 07:17:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khaleda will recover with 'divine blessings', hopes Fakhrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/khaleda-will-recover-with-divine-blessings-hopes-fakhrul</link><description>BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir on Sunday expressed the hope that their critically ill party chairperson Khaleda Zia will recover with 'divine blessings'.
"People all over the country are praying for her, regardless of their political affiliation. We have faith in Allah, and we b</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 07:32:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New three-party alliance to emerge ahead of 13th National Election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/new-three-party-alliance-to-emerge-ahead-of-13th-national-election</link><description>A new political alliance comprising three parties, including the National Citizens Party (NCP), is set to be launched ahead of the upcoming 13th National Parliamentary Election. The other two parties in the coalition are the Rashtra Sangskar Andolon (Movement for State Reform) and the Amar Banglade</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 07:47:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mobile traders block road outside BTRC to protest phone registration rules</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/mobile-traders-block-road-outside-btrc-to-protest-phone-registration-rules</link><description>Mobile phone traders have blocked the road in front of the Bangladesh Telecommunication Regulatory Commission (BTRC) headquarters in Dhaka to protest the government’s decision to deactivate unregistered handsets.
Several hundred traders and their employees gathered outside the BTRC buildin</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 08:02:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Quality of democracy cannot improve without behavioural change: Planning Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/quality-of-democracy-cannot-improve-without-behavioural-change-planning-adviser</link><description>Planning Adviser Dr Wahiduddin Mahmud on Sunday said democratic institutions alone cannot guarantee the quality of democracy unless political behaviour and political culture change.
"A parliament elected by people, a government accountable to that parliament, and independent watchdog institutions</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 08:17:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India's Goa state orders probe after nightclub fire kills 25</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/indias-goa-state-orders-probe-after-nightclub-fire-kills-25</link><description>Indian authorities ordered an investigation and offered compensation to victims on Sunday after a fire ripped through a nightclub in the western state of Goa, killing 25.
"I have ordered a magisterial inquiry into the entire incident to identify the cause and fix responsibility" for the fire in th</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 08:32:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mass shooting at a South African bar leaves 12 dead, including 3 children</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/africa/mass-shooting-at-a-south-african-bar-leaves-12-dead-including-3-children</link><description>A mass shooting carried out Saturday by multiple suspects in an unlicensed bar near the South African capital left at least 12 people dead, police said. The victims included three children aged 3, 12 and 16.
Another 13 people were wounded and being treated in the hospital. Police didn’</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 08:47:33 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>