<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 14:27:44 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Sammilito Islami Bank draws Tk 440m deposits in two days</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/sammilito-islami-bank-attracts-tk-440m-in-deposits-in-first-two-days-of-operations</link><description>Sammilito Islami Bank received deposits amounting to Tk 440 million in the first two days of its operation.
BB Governor Dr Ahsan H. Mansur disclosed this at a press briefing on Monday at the BB headquarters, where the newborn Islamic bank’s Chairman Dr Ayub Miah, administrators of the five</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 12:15:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>449th Board Meeting of Al-Arafah Islami Bank held</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/449th-board-meeting-of-al-arafah-islami-bank-held</link><description>The 449th Board meeting of Al-Arafah Islami Bank PLC. was held on Sunday, January 4, 2026, at the bank’s Head Office.
Chairman of the Board of Directors Khwaja Shahriar presided over the meeting, according to a media release. 
The overall business performance of the bank was reviewed a</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 12:30:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Russia warns citizens against travel to Venezuela</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/russia-warns-citizens-against-travel-to-venezuela</link><description>Russia on Monday advised its citizens against travelling to Venezuela.
The warning came after US President Donald Trump announced that the United States had carried out a strike on Venezuela and captured President Nicolas Maduro and his wife.
Both the Russian Embassy in Caracas and the Economy Mi</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 11:27:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BRAC Bank’s Board engages with BFIU to strengthen AML-CFT oversight</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/brac-banks-board-engages-with-bfiu-to-strengthen-aml-cft-oversight</link><description>BRAC Bank has organised an Anti-Money Laundering (AML) and Combating the Financing of Terrorism (CFT) awareness session for its Board of Directors and senior management, reiterating the bank’s commitment to strong regulatory oversight and compliance at the highest level.
Md. Mofizur Rahman K</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 11:42:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Three-day AHCAB International Expo begins Jan 8</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/three-day-ahcab-international-expo-begins-jan-8</link><description>The Animal Health Companies Association of Bangladesh (AHCAB) is organising the sixth AHCAB International Expo to promote innovation, investment, and sustainable growth in Bangladesh’s animal health, fisheries, and livestock sectors.
The three-day expo will be held from January 8 to 10 at an</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 11:57:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Samsung to double mobile devices this year</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/samsung-to-double-mobile-devices-this-year</link><description>Samsung Electronics plans to double this year the number of its mobile devices with AI features powered by Google's Gemini, its co-CEO said, which would give the U.S. firm an edge over rivals as the global race in artificial intelligence hots up.
The South Korean company, which had rolled out Gemi</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 12:12:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Eighteen business bodies recall Khaleda Zia’s economic, democratic legacy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/eighteen-business-bodies-recall-khaleda-zias-economic-democratic-legacy</link><description>Leaders of 18 leading business bodies on Monday paid glowing tributes to former Prime Minister and BNP Chairperson Khaleda Zia, recalling her decisive role in strengthening democracy and steering Bangladesh towards economic progress.
The remarks came from a memorial and doa mehfil titled ‘Me</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 12:27:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>One of two children found on Chattogram roadside dies</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/one-of-two-children-found-on-chattogram-roadside-dies</link><description>One of the two children rescued from a roadside in Chattogram’s Anwara has died.
After nine days of treatment, 14-month-old Morshed, identified with a single name, passed away on Monday in the Neonatal Intensive Care Unit (NICU) of Chattogram Medical College Hospital, according to Anwara Upa</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 12:42:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP to strengthen business bodies to cut red tape, boost economy: Khosru</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/bnp-to-strengthen-business-bodies-to-cut-red-tape-boost-economy-khosru</link><description>BNP Standing Committee Member Amir Khosru Mahmud Chowdhury on Monday said their party would work to further strengthen Bangladesh’s business organisations to overcome bureaucratic complexities and revitalise the economy.
“From my experience as a former commerce minister, I learned that</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 12:57:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ABB’s AGM held; Mashrur Arefin elected Chairman and Ahsan Zaman Chowdhury Secretary General</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/abbs-agm-held-mashrur-arefin-elected-chairman-and-ahsan-zaman-chowdhury-secretary-general</link><description>Mashrur Arefin, Managing Director &amp; CEO of City Bank PLC, has been elected Chairman of the Association of Bankers, Bangladesh (ABB), the apex body of the country’s commercial bank executives.
Ahsan Zaman Chowdhury, Managing Director &amp; CEO of Trust Bank PLC, has been elected Secretary General</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 13:12:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Climate Danger: Bangladesh among countries least equipped to manage risks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/climate-danger-bangladesh-among-countries-least-equipped-to-manage-risks</link><description>A new report has identified a stark disparity in climate vulnerability and financial capacity; and countries highly exposed to climate effects, including Bangladesh, Bhutan, India, Myanmar, Nepal and Pakistan are the least equipped to manage these risks.
The report, ’Climate Finance Synthesi</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 13:27:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Zelensky to replace Ukraine security chief Maliuk</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/head-of-ukraines-security-service-maliuk-to-be-replaced-zelensky-says</link><description>Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky said on Monday that he planned to replace the head of the country's SBU security service, Vasyl Maliuk, as part of a wider reshuffle that has also seen a new presidential chief of staff.
Maliuk was appointed SBU chief in Feb 2023, having already served as act</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 13:42:24 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>