<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 13:10:11 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>7 dead, 350 hurt in post-poll violence: MSF</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/post-poll-violence-leaves-7-dead-350-injured-across-bangladesh-says-msf</link><description>At least seven people have been killed and 350 others injured in a wave of post-election violence that has swept across 26 districts since the results were announced, according to rights group Manabadhikar Shongskriti Foundation (MSF).
In a statement issued on Monday, three days after the election</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 11:00:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Interim head Yunus bids farewell to staff</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ca-yunus-bids-farewell-to-staff-as-interim-rule-ends</link><description>As the curtain falls on the interim administration that governed Bangladesh for the past 18 months, Chief Advisor Muhammad Yunus has reached the final days of his tenure.
State news agency Bangladesh Sangbad Sangstha reported that Yunus delivered a farewell address on Monday to officers and employ</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 11:15:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mirza Fakhrul visits Dr Rafiqul Islam at BMU</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/mirza-fakhrul-visits-dr-rafiqul-islam-at-bmu</link><description>BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir on Monday visited Health Affairs Secretary of the party Dr. Mohammad Rafiqul Islam, who is currently undergoing treatment at Bangladesh Medical University (BMU).
During the visit, he met with the attending physicians and enquired about Dr. Rafiqul</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 11:30:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique Rahman quits Bogura-6, keeping Dhaka-17: EC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-rahman-quits-bogura-6-keeping-dhaka-17-ec</link><description>BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman has left Bogura-6 seat for by-election as he is set to take oath as a member of parliament from Dhaka-17 constituency on Tuesday.
“We’ve received a letter that BNP chairman Tarique Rahman quits Bogura-6 constituency,” Election Commission Senior Secreta</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 11:45:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>RMG worker killed in Dhaka road crash</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rmg-worker-killed-in-dhaka-road-crash</link><description>A female garment worker was killed when a bus knocked her down in the Mugda area of the capital early Monday.
The deceased was identified as Noyon Moni, 44, the wife of Abdul Hamid of Shariatpur district. She used to live in Mugda area with her husband.
The accident occurred at night when the bus</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 12:00:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Germany says talks with France on nuclear deterrence are at an early stage</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/germany-says-talks-with-france-on-nuclear-deterrence-are-at-an-early-stage</link><description>Talks between German Chancellor Friedrich Merz and French President Emmanuel Macron over creating a joint European nuclear deterrent are at an early stage and not aimed at diminishing the role of the United States, a German government spokesperson said on Monday.
"The aim of the talks is to explor</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 11:30:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DMP issues traffic curbs, diversions for swearing-in of MPs, ministers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dmp-issues-traffic-curbs-diversions-for-swearing-in-of-mps-ministers</link><description>The Dhaka Metropolitan Police (DMP) has put traffic measures in place around parliament ahead of the oath-taking ceremony of newly elected MPs and cabinet ministers at the South Plaza.
The move aims to handle the large crowds expected in the area and ensure smooth movement during the event.
The D</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 11:45:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>34 Australians released from Syrian camp holding IS-affiliated families</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/34-australians-released-from-syrian-camp-holding-is-affiliated-families</link><description>Syrian Kurdish forces on Monday released 34 Australians who were detained in a camp holding families of suspected Islamic State militants in northern Syria, saying they would be flown to Australia from Damascus.
Hukmiya Mohamed, a co-director of Roj camp, told Reuters that the 34 Australians had b</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 12:00:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rashid Khan creates history with 700 T20 wickets</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/rashid-khan-creates-history-with-700-t20-wickets</link><description>Afghanistan captain Rashid Khan has etched his name in history by becoming the first bowler to claim 700 wickets in recognized T20 cricket.
The leg-spinner achieved the monumental milestone during Afghanistan’s T20 World Cup match against the United Arab Emirates at the Arun Jaitley Stadium</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 12:15:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Amari Dhaka offers Mughal elegance in dining, stays and takeaway this Ramadan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/amari-dhaka-offers-mughal-elegance-in-dining-stays-and-takeaway-this-ramadan</link><description>Amari Dhaka has announced a range of Mughlai-themed dining, takeaway and stay offerings for the upcoming Ramadan, inviting guests to experience royal culinary traditions throughout the holy month.
Renowned chefs from different countries have arrived at the hotel to present culinary masterpieces in</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 12:30:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>This national election a ‘role model’ in Bangladesh history: Home Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/this-national-election-a-role-model-in-bangladesh-history-home-adviser</link><description>Bangladesh’s 13th parliamentary election will be remembered as a ‘role model’ in the country’s electoral history, said Home Affairs Adviser Lt Gen (retd) Md Jahangir Alam Chowdhury on Monday.
Speaking at a farewell reception at the Police Headquarters, he praised the role o</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 12:45:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hasina’s stay in India no barrier to Bangladesh ties, says Fakhrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/hasinas-stay-in-india-no-barrier-to-bangladesh-ties-says-fakhrul</link><description>As Bangladesh stands on the brink of a political transition, senior BNP leader Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir has sought to decouple bilateral diplomacy from domestic reckoning, saying India-Bangladesh relations will not be “held hostage” by the presence of Sheikh Hasina in New Delhi.
He</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 13:00:49 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>