<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 17:19:50 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Tourist dies due to excessive alcohol consumption in Cox’s Bazar, five held</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/tourist-dies-due-to-excessive-alcohol-consumption-in-coxs-bazar-five-held</link><description>A tourist has died allegedly due to excessive alcohol consumption at a hotel in Cox’s Bazar’s Kolatoli area, leading police to detain five people for questioning.
The incident occurred on Wednesday morning in room 407 of the “Hypherion White Palace” hotel located in the cit</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 13:52:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Call for bridging education-employment divide</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/call-for-bridging-education-employment-divide</link><description>Participants at a roundtable discussion on Wednesday called for collective action to bridge the education-to-employment divide to ensure more productive workforce, higher economic growth, and improved individual well-being.
They suggested forging strategic partnerships and offering innovation fund</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 14:07:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BRAC Bank hosts Agent Meet 2025 for Dhaka Region</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/brac-bank-hosts-agent-meet-2025-for-dhaka-region</link><description>BRAC Bank has organised the Agent Meet 2025 for the Dhaka Region to strengthen field-level engagement and accelerate financial inclusion, according to a press release.
The Agent Meet took place in Cox’s Bazar on October 10, 2025, bringing together esteemed agent partners from 116 Agent Banki</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 14:22:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>At least 40 migrants die as boat sinks off Tunisia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/at-least-40-migrants-die-as-boat-sinks-off-tunisia</link><description>At least 40 migrants from sub-Saharan African countries have died after their boat sank off the coast of Tunisia on Wednesday, in one of the deadliest maritime tragedies in the region this year, an official said.
The boat, carrying about 70 migrants, sank near the coastal city of Mahdia, the offic</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 14:52:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nahid says no room for caretaker govt until July Charter is implemented</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/nahid-says-no-room-for-caretaker-government-until-july-charter-is-implemented</link><description>The formation of a caretaker government before the implementation of the July Charter is not feasible, the National Citizen Party Convenor Nahid Islam.
On Wednesday, following a meeting with Chief Advisor Muhammad Yunus, he said if anyone intends to implement the Charter before a public referendum</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 15:07:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rare Test win for Zimbabwe in easy defeat of Afghanistan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rare-test-win-for-zimbabwe-in-easy-defeat-of-afghanistan</link><description>Zimbabwe quick Richard Ngarava took five wickets to skittle Afghanistan out for 159 in their second innings and win their one-off Test by an innings and 73 runs midway through the third day on Wednesday.
Zimbabwe, who had only won one of their previous 17 Tests, had dismissed the Afghanis for 127</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 15:37:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh signs three ILO conventions on occupational safety</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-signs-three-ilo-conventions-on-occupational-safety</link><description>The interim government has signed three conventions of the International Labour Organization (ILO).
Labour and Employment Advisor Sakhawat Hussain signed the conventions on Wednesday at the State Guest House Jamuna.
The conventions include ILO Convention No. 155 on Occupational Safety and Health,</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 16:07:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gold price sees year's steepest drop after 8 consecutive hikes</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/gold-price-sees-years-steepest-drop-after-8-consecutive-hikes</link><description>After eight consecutive price hikes, the Bangladesh Jewellers Association (BAJUS) has slashed gold prices by over Tk 8,000 per bhori, marking the steepest single-day drop of the year.
According to a BAJUS press release issued Wednesday night, the price of 22-carat gold has been reduced by Tk 8,386</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 16:22:30 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>