<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 11:52:05 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Unaware of ministerial offer, may return to academia: Salehuddin</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/unaware-of-ministerial-offer-may-return-to-academia-salehuddin</link><description>Finance Adviser Dr Salehuddin Ahmed on Tuesday said he is unaware of any proposal for him to join a future political government as a minister.
 “I do not know anything about this,” he said, responding to questions from reporters after a meeting of the Cabinet Committee on Governme</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 09:35:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IGP doesn’t rule out militant attack risk during election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/igp-doesnt-rule-out-militant-attack-risk-during-election</link><description>Although the risk of militant attacks during the election campaign has eased, it still cannot be ruled out ahead of the 13th parliamentary election, says Inspector General of Police (IGP) Baharul Alam.
He shared his perspective at a press conference at the Police Headquarters’ Media Centre o</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 09:50:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Compensation planned for shareholders of five merged banks: Salehuddin</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/compensation-planned-for-shareholders-of-five-merged-banks-salehuddin</link><description>The interim government has moved towards arranging compensation for shareholders affected by the merger of five Shariah-based banks, with Finance Advisor Salehuddin Ahmed indicating that the process will be “complex” and carried out in phases.
Speaking at the Secretariat after a meetin</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 10:05:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Voters can take mobiles to polling centres</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/voters-can-take-mobiles-to-polling-centres-but-cannot-use-them-in-secret-booths</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has withdrawn its decision to ban mobile phones inside polling stations amid criticism.
According to the new decision, voters can take mobile phones to polling stations, but they cannot be used in secret booths (where votes are cast).
Orders in this regard, signed by</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 09:08:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DU VC announces plan to step down</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/du-vc-announces-plan-to-step-down</link><description>Dhaka University Vice-Chancellor Dr Niaz Ahmed Khan has said he took charge of the university during a time of crisis, which no longer exists, and therefore wishes to step down from his post.
“I assumed the responsibility of vice-chancellor during an emergency situation. That emergency perio</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 09:23:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Finance Advisor Salehuddin gives his tenure 70 out of 100</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/finance-advisor-salehuddin-gives-his-tenure-70-out-of-100</link><description>Finance Advisor Salehuddin Ahmed has rated himself 70 out of 100 points in assessing his performance in the post, acknowledging limitations in implementing economic reforms and policy initiatives.
He said, “Although many initiatives were taken, it was not possible to complete everything. Sti</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 09:38:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt approves procurement of 55,000 tonnes of fertiliser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-approves-procurement-of-55000-tonnes-of-fertiliser</link><description>The Advisers Council Committee on Government Purchase on Tuesday approved separate proposals for the procurement of 55,000 tonnes of fertiliser.
The approval came at a meeting of the committee at the Cabinet Division conference room at the Bangladesh Secretariat with Finance Adviser Dr Salehuddin</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 09:53:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shafiqul Alam says his properties unchanged, bank deposit up slightly</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/shafiqul-alam-says-his-properties-unchanged-bank-deposit-up-slightly</link><description>Chief Adviser’s Press Secretary Shafiqul Alam on Tuesday said there has been no change in his properties, though his bank deposit has increased slightly.
“Today may be my last working day. As I leave this public office, I declare that there has been no change in our properties,”</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 10:08:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Indonesia says proposed Gaza peacekeeping force could total 20,000 troops</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/indonesia-says-proposed-gaza-peacekeeping-force-could-total-20000-troops</link><description>A proposed multinational peacekeeping force for Gaza could total about 20,000 troops, with Indonesia estimating it could contribute up to 8,000, President Prabowo Subianto’s spokesman said on Tuesday.
The spokesman said, however, that no deployment terms or areas of operation had been agreed</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 10:23:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US deal to allow zero duty on 86pc of Bangladesh exports: Bashir</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/commerce-advisor-bashir-claims-86-per-cent-of-bangladesh-exports-get-duty-free-access-under-us-reciprocal-trade-deal</link><description>Commerce Advisor Sheikh Bashir Uddin has said Bangladesh will receive duty free access for 85 to 86 per cent of its exports under the reciprocal trade agreement with the United States.
He made the remarks on Tuesday afternoon at a press conference at the Secretariat to brief the media on the recip</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 10:38:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No scope for ‘election engineering’ this time, warns Fakhrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/no-scope-for-election-engineering-this-time-warns-fakhrul</link><description>BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir on Tuesday said there is no scope for ‘engineering’ in the national election as government officials and employees are expected to discharge their duties properly to ensure free, fair and credible voting.
“We have finally regained</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 10:53:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CA to address the nation on Tuesday evening</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ca-to-address-the-nation-on-tuesday-evening</link><description>Chief Advisor Muhammad Yunus will address the nation at 7pm on Tuesday.
The Chief Advisor’s Office said the speech will be delivered ahead of the 13th parliamentary elections and July National Charter referendum vote on Feb 12.
The speech will be broadcast live on Bangladesh Television (BTV</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 11:08:50 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>