<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 14:22:14 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Cooperatives can help build an equal and self-reliant Bangladesh: Prof Yunus</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cooperatives-can-help-build-an-equal-and-self-reliant-bangladesh-prof-yunus</link><description>Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus has called for strengthening the cooperative movement to build an inclusive, equitable and self-reliant Bangladesh.
He made the call marking the ‘54th National Co-operative Day’ to be observed on November 1.
In a message issued on Friday, Pr</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 11:47:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>27 police officers hurt in Ctg police lines accident</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/27-police-officers-injured-as-bus-overturns-in-chattogram-police-lines</link><description>At least 27 female police personnel have been injured after a bus overturned inside the Dampara Police Lines in Chattogram.
The accident occurred on Friday afternoon while the vehicle was descending a slope within the compound, police said.
Of the injured, 12 were taken to Chittagong Medical Coll</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 12:17:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pound heads for worst monthly performance since July</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/pound-heads-for-worst-monthly-performance-since-july</link><description>The pound headed for its worst performance against the dollar since July on Friday, while also wallowing at 2-1/2-year lows against the euro, reflecting growing investor nervousness about the outlook for UK government finances.
Sterling GBP, which has fallen 2.3 percent in October, set for its big</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 12:01:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dengue: 506 more cases detected in 24 hours</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dengue-506-more-cases-detected-in-24-hours</link><description>Bangladesh reported no deaths from the dengue in 24 hours till Friday morning (October 31, 2025).
Meanwhile, five hundred and six more new dengue cases were reported during the same period, bringing the total number of cases to 69, 862 this year.
According to the Directorate General of Health Ser</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 12:16:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>High Court acquits DSE Director Emon in DSA case</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/high-court-acquits-dse-director-emon-in-dsa-case</link><description>The High Court has granted the appeal of Minhaz Mannan Emon, director of the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE), acquitting him of charges filed under the Digital Security Act (DSA).
A High Court bench comprising Justice ASM Abdul Mobin and Justice Md Jabid Hossain delivered the verdict on Thursday, overt</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 12:31:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>20 cops injured as bus loses control inside CMP headquarters</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/20-cops-injured-as-bus-loses-control-inside-cmp-headquarters</link><description>At least 20 policemen, including female members of the force, were injured when a bus carrying the law enforcers lost control inside Chattogram Metropolitan Police (CMP) headquarters in the Dampara area on Friday afternoon.
The police team was on its way to Bir Sreshtho Shaheed Flight Lt Matiur Ra</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 12:46:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh takes part in first-ever UN session on biodiversity convention</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/bangladesh-takes-part-in-first-ever-un-session-on-biodiversity-convention</link><description>Bangladesh participated in the first-ever meeting of the Subsidiary Body on Article 8(j) and Related Provisions (SB8j-1) under the UN Convention on Biological Diversity (CBD), held from October 27 to 30 in Panama City.
The meeting marked a historic step to formally recognise the rights of Indigeno</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 13:01:45 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>