<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 08:30:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>BNP delegation meets with CEC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-delegation-meets-with-cec</link><description>A BNP delegation is meeting with Chief Election Commissioner AMM Nasir Uddin ahead of the 13th national parliamentary elections.
The meeting began at 11:45 am on Thursday at the Nirbachan Bhaban, reports bdnews24.com.
The delegation is led by BNP National Standing Committee member Abdul Moyeen Kh</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 06:06:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Auto-rickshaw driver killed in Mymensingh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/auto-rickshaw-driver-killed-in-mymensingh</link><description>A 38-year-old auto-rickshaw driver was killed and his vehicle snatched by miscreants in Mymensingh on Wednesday night.
The deceased was identified as Masud Mia, son of Khorshed Ali of Bhalukjan area under Fulbaria municipality in the district, reports UNB.
According to police and locals, Masud to</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 06:21:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>July Uprising: Three reasons given for actor Iresh Zaker’s exemption from case</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/july-uprising-three-reasons-given-for-actor-iresh-zakers-exemption-from-case</link><description>A petition has been filed seeking the discharge of actor Iresh Zaker from the murder case of BNP activist Mahfuz Alam Sraban, who was killed during the July Uprising.
On Oct 9, the investigating officer, Inspector Sajjad Roman of Mirpur Model Police Station, submitted an interim report to the cour</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 06:51:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Students of Govt Science College block Farmgate</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/students-of-govt-science-college-block-farmgate</link><description>Students of Government Science College have blocked roads in the Farmgate area to protest against illegal parking outside the institution, the reckless parking of various vehicles including auto rickshaws, and the death of a student in a road accident nearby.
Traffic was brought to a standstill fr</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 07:45:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh Railway sets sights on new locomotives to revamp services: Sheikh Moinuddin</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-railway-sets-sights-on-new-locomotives-to-revamp-services-sheikh-moinuddin</link><description>The government is taking steps to purchase a new fleet of modern locomotives to make Bangladesh's rail services more efficient and profitable, said Sheikh Moinuddin, Special Assistant to the Chief Adviser on Road Transport, Bridges and Railways.
"We expect to complete the tender process within a m</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 08:15:24 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>