<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 07:20:05 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Bangladesh builds South-South semiconductor bridge through Penang Roadshow</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladesh-builds-south-south-semiconductor-bridge-through-penang-roadshow</link><description>The Bangladesh Semiconductor Industry Association (BSIA) has completed a three-day Malaysia Semiconductor Roadshow in Penang from November 11–13, aimed at promoting Bangladesh as an emerging partner in the global semiconductor supply chain and exploring prospects for a South-South Silicon Cor</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 05:49:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh demands survival-focused climate support at COP30</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-demands-survival-focused-climate-support-at-cop30</link><description>Bangladesh called on global leaders at the COP30 climate summit to deliver survival-centered, justice-driven climate finance for the Least Developed Countries (LDCs), warning that millions already face irreversible losses from a crisis they did not cause.
​Farida Akhter, Adviser for Fisheries and</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 06:04:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rab, DB present differing motives behind killing</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rab-db-present-differing-motives-behind-killing</link><description>Law-enforcement agencies on Saturday presented differing narratives over the gruesome killing of Rangpur-based trader Ashraful Haque, whose dismembered body was discovered in two plastic drums near the High Court in Dhaka on Thursday last.
The Rapid Action Battalion (Rab) and the Dhaka Metropolita</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 04:51:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nabanna Utsab to be held at DU today</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nabanna-utsab-to-be-held-at-du-today</link><description>To present the heritage of the ancient Bengali New Year to the new generation, the Dhaka University Central Students' Union (DUCSU) is organising a special Nabanna Utsab this time.
The event will take place today (Sunday --1st Agrahayan, 16 November), from 10 am to 10 pm on the Dhaka University ca</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 05:06:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Election becoming an inevitable process in country: Debapriya</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/election-becoming-an-inevitable-process-in-country-debapriya</link><description>RAJSHAHI, Nov 15: Distinguished Fellow at the Centre for Policy Dialogue (CPD) Dr Debapriya Bhattacharya has said that national elections in Bangladesh are gradually becoming an inevitable process.
"The upcoming polls will be timely, participatory and credible, ultimately contributing to the count</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 05:21:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BRAC University launches 'Vitalizers 3.0' to cultivate next generation of business leaders</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/article/brac-university-launches-vitalizers-30-to-cultivate-next-generation-of-business-leaders</link><description>The BRAC University Business &amp; Economics Forum (BUBeF) has officially announced the launch of its flagship event, X Ceramics presents Vitalizers 3.0 - A National Business Case Competition. Co-sponsored by Neo Aluminium and in association with Berger Paints Bangladesh Limited, the 2025 edition is se</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 05:36:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Are our univs producing graduates with enough English language skills?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/article/are-our-univs-producing-graduates-with-enough-english-language-skills</link><description>Bangladesh's ambition to become a globally competitive economy rests heavily on its university graduates. For these young professionals, English is not just another subject; it is the essential tool for accessing international research, securing high-value jobs, and pursuing higher education abroad</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 05:51:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Who're monitoring the consultancies sending students abroad?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/article/whore-monitoring-the-consultancies-sending-students-abroad</link><description>Ratul spent two years and nearly Tk 5.0 million at a private university in Malaysia his consultancy recommended. The firm never mentioned the institution lacked proper accreditation. When he returned to Dhaka with his degree, employers refused to recognise it. He remains unemployed. His consultancy</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 06:06:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Climate Debt Risk Index 2025: Loan-heavy climate finance is pushing frontline nations toward a debt trap, new analysis</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/climate-debt-risk-index-2025-loan-heavy-climate-finance-is-pushing-frontline-nations-toward-a-debt-trap-new-analysis</link><description>Change Initiative disseminated the Climate Debt Risk Index 2025 (CDRI’25) jointly with Young Power in Social Action (YPSA), finding that loan-dominant climate finance, slow cash delivery, and high exposure to climate shocks are combining to raise debt risks across dozens of low-income and cli</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 06:21:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh Election: CEC urges stakeholders to help ensure voter safety</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-election-cec-urges-stakeholders-to-help-ensure-voter-safety</link><description>Chief Election Commissioner AMM Nasir Uddin on Sunday sought cooperation from political parties to create a safe environment for voters during the national election to be held in early February 2026.
“We need your support in bringing voters to the polling stations and creating a safe environ</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 06:36:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh’s C-section delivery rate climbs to 51.8pc in 2025: Survey</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/bangladeshs-c-section-delivery-rate-climbs-to-518pc-in-2025-survey</link><description>The rate of caesarean section deliveries in Bangladesh has risen to 51.8 per cent this year (2025), up sharply from 36 per cent in 2019, according to the latest Multiple Indicator Cluster Survey (MICS) of the Bangladesh Bureau of Statistics (BBS).
The report’s preliminary findings, released</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 06:51:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>44 AL activists arrested for ‘flash procession, sabotage’ attempts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/44-al-activists-arrested-for-flash-procession-sabotage-attempts</link><description>Police have arrested 44 leaders and activists of the Awami League, a party banned from holding any activities, and its affiliates in various places in Cumilla.
They were arrested between 6:00 am and 8:00 am on Sunday, Cumilla Police Superintendent Mohammad Nazir Ahmed Khan said.
He said that base</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 07:06:47 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>