<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 15:26:33 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>1m people die annually in south Asia due to air pollution: WB</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/1m-people-die-annually-in-south-asia-including-bangladesh-due-to-air-pollution-wb</link><description>As many as one million people die annually in South Asia, including in Bangladesh, due to air pollution, while clean air can improve the lives of nearly one billion people across the region, according to a recent report of the World Bank.
The report said air pollution across the parts of South Asi</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 11:54:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Islami Bank holds board meeting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/islami-bak-holds-board-meeting-1</link><description>A meeting of the board of directors of Islami Bank Bangladesh PLC was held on December 18, 2025 Thursday at the Islami Bank Tower.
Professor Dr. M. Zubaidur Rahman, chairman of the bank, presided over the meeting, according to a press release.
Mohammad Khurshid Wahab, chairman of the executive co</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 12:09:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Loans over $200m to be audited: Governor</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh-bank-to-verify-all-loans-above-200-million-to-restore-governance-accountability</link><description>Bangladesh Bank Governor Ahsan H Mansur has announced an initiative to verify all loans exceeding $200 million as part of efforts to “restore governance and public confidence” in the banking sector.
Speaking at a seminar in Dhaka on Thursday, he said the banking sector is “gradua</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 12:24:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ILO chief praises Bangladesh’s labour reforms as ‘historic’ shift from past inertia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ilo-chief-praises-bangladeshs-labour-reforms-as-historic-shift-from-past-inertia</link><description>The head of the International Labour Organisation (ILO) has praised Bangladesh for undertaking what he described as a wide-ranging and potentially transformative programme of labour reforms, signalling growing international confidence in the country’s efforts to strengthen workers’ righ</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 12:39:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Home advisor’s effigy burnt at Dhaka University</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/home-advisors-effigy-burnt-at-dhaka-university</link><description>The Chhatra Shakti has demanded the resignation of Home Advisor Jahangir Alam Chowdhury over the failure to arrest the attackers of Inqilab Moncho Convenor Sharif Osman bin Hadi amid what it says is “deterioration of public security”.
They took out the rally from the Shahbagh intersect</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 12:54:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ECB holds rates steady and turns more positive on the economy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/global/ecb-holds-rates-steady-and-turns-more-positive-on-the-economy</link><description>The European Central Bank kept its policy rates steady on Thursday and took a more positive view on a euro zone economy that has shown resilience to global trade shocks.
The central bank for the 20 countries that share the euro raised several of its growth and inflation projections for the bloc, i</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 13:09:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Play-based learning vital for children’s development: Speakers at BRAC event</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/play-based-learning-vital-for-childrens-development-speakers-at-brac-event</link><description>An information and experience-sharing event on play-based learning, inclusive education, and children’s psychosocial development was organised by the BRAC Education Programme.
The event took place on Thursday, 18 December, at the BRAC Centre in Dhaka, bringing together government policymaker</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 13:24:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Italy raids illegal tobacco factory, seizes 27 tonnes of cigarettes</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/italy-raids-illegal-tobacco-factory-seizes-27-tonnes-of-cigarettes</link><description>An illegal tobacco factory that produced four million counterfeit cigarettes per day, evading millions of euros in taxes and duties, has been uncovered and seized near Rome, Italian and European Union authorities said on Thursday.
The site in Pomezia, around 30 kilometres (19 miles) south of Rome,</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 13:39:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>'Govt moves to formulate action plan to eliminate child labour by 2030'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-moves-to-formulate-action-plan-to-eliminate-child-labour-by-2030</link><description>The government has initiated a move to formulate a national action plan to eliminate child labour from the country by 2030, Labour Secretary Sanwar Jahan Bhuiyan said on Thursday.
Eradication of child labour requires coordinated interventions—particularly in hazardous sectors—alongside</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 13:54:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Billion in irregularities’: Kamal faces graft charges</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/chargesheet-imminent-as-acc-probes-tk-1b-irregularities-claims-against-ex-minister-kamal</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) is set to submit a chargesheet against former home minister Asaduzzaman Khan Kamal over alleged irregularities involving more than Tk 1 billion in illegal assets and suspicious financial transactions.
ACC Director General Akhtar Hossain said on Thursday that th</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 14:09:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC seeks police for RO, ARO offices ahead of Bangladesh polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-seeks-police-for-ro-aro-offices-ahead-of-bangladesh-polls</link><description>The Election Commission on Thursday asked the Home Ministry to deploy a necessary number of police personnel to ensure the security of the offices of Returning Officers (ROs) and Assistant Returning Officers (AROs) ahead of the upcoming national election and the referendum, scheduled for February 1</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 14:24:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nuzhat Anwar new DSE managing director</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/nuzhat-anwar-new-dse-managing-director</link><description>Ms. Nuzhat Anwar has been appointed as the new Managing Director of Dhaka Stock Exchange PLC, who has over two decades of experience in financial markets, banking, and development finance.
The Bangladesh Securities and Exchange Commission (BSEC) on Thursday approved her appointment, says a press r</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 14:39:51 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>