<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 02:40:36 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>2 arrested in Jhenaidah for allegedly selling madrasa student</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/2-arrested-in-jhenaidah-for-allegedly-selling-madrasa-student</link><description>Police arrested two people in Jhenaidah’s Harinakundu upazila on allegations of abducting a madrasa student and selling him to a hijra community in Bhola district.
The arrestees are Sumon, son of Shariful Islam of Mandartala village, and his wife Shyamoli Khatun.
According to police sources</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 17:44:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt cuts fuel prices by Tk 2 per litre for February</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/govt-cuts-fuel-prices-by-tk-2-per-litre-for-february</link><description>The government has announced a Tk 2 per litre reduction in the prices of diesel, octane, petrol, and kerosene for February 2026, aiming to provide fuel at a relatively affordable price to consumers.
Under the revised rates, diesel will now sell at Tk 100 per litre, down from Tk 102; octane at Tk 1</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 17:59:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sink or swim</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/sink-or-swim</link><description>Bangladesh has a troubled relationship with corruption. Since independence, it has been an enduring feature of public life-shaping institutions, distorting economic outcomes, and steadily eroding public trust. While corruption has long been widespread, systematic evidence from both domestic and int</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 18:14:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The changing global economic order</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/reviews/the-changing-global-economic-order</link><description>The global economic order is undergoing a massive long-term shift away from free trade towards a more fragmented or more precisely a patchwork structure. This new emerging global economic system is largely influenced by rising protectionism, geo-political tensions and structural risks.
The post WW</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 18:29:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The silent crisis of drug abuse</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/the-silent-crisis-of-drug-abuse</link><description>There has been little success in the drive against drugs, even in relative terms. By all indications, the menace is expanding, assuming newer forms and greater intensity with the influx of new substances. The findings of the latest nationwide survey conducted by Bangladesh Medical University (BMU)</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 18:44:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Lenders stare at Tk 6.46b loss after bank merger</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/lenders-stare-at-tk-646b-loss-after-bank-merger</link><description>At least five financial institutions risk losing assets following the recent bank merger, as shares held as collateral for loans they disbursed have been valued at zero.
IFIC Bank, Dutch-Bangla Bank, Shahjalal Islami Bank, Southeast Bank and National Housing Finance together face losses exceeding</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 18:59:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>GDP growth in  election years</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/gdp-growth-in-election-years</link><description>The current fiscal year is an election year, with polls scheduled for February 12. A key question is how the economy will respond to the election in terms of Gross Domestic Product (GDP) growth. As the economy has entered the Political Business Cycle (PBC), the impact of this cycle on growth needs</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 19:14:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Designing tax reform that works</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/designing-tax-reform-that-works</link><description>Tax policy in Bangladesh has long been driven by what is easiest to collect rather than what is fair or efficient. High trade taxes and transaction-based levies have filled revenue gaps left by weak income assessment and limited information. This has created a system where compliance is often more</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 19:29:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ctg port moves four as strike over NCT deal hits activities</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ctg-port-moves-four-as-strike-over-nct-deal-hits-activities</link><description>Following a work stoppage at the Chittagong Port, four employees who led protests against the leasing of the New Mooring Container Terminal (NCT) to foreign operators transferred to the Pangaon Inland Container Terminal in Dhaka's Keraniganj.
An office order on Saturday instructed them to report t</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 01:50:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Lenders stare at Tk 6.46b loss after bank merger</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/lenders-stare-at-tk-646b-loss-after-bank-merger-1</link><description>At least five financial institutions risk losing assets following the recent bank merger, as shares held as collateral for loans they disbursed have been valued at zero.
IFIC Bank, Dutch-Bangla Bank, Shahjalal Islami Bank, Southeast Bank and National Housing Finance together face losses exceeding</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 02:05:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Some 330 int’l election observers confirmed</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/some-330-intl-election-observers-confirmed</link><description>Six renowned international organisations, including the Organisation of Islamic Cooperation (OIC), have agreed to deploy at least 63 observers to oversee Bangladesh's 13th general election and referendum on the July National Charter on February 12, in addition to a host more.
They will join observ</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 02:20:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BD economic growth modest 4.7pc in FY26, no better luck next</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/bd-economic-growth-modest-47pc-in-fy26-no-better-luck-next</link><description>Bangladesh's economic growth may stay stymied to 4.7 per cent in the current fiscal year for elevated inflationary pressure and delays in financial and fiscal reforms, and there's no better luck next.
The International Monetary Fund (IMF) has come up with such observations after a protracted spot</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 02:35:38 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>