<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 09:24:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Three die from electrocution in Gopalganj</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/three-die-from-electrocution-in-gopalganj</link><description>Three people, including a grandmother and her grandson, died from electrocution in Kashiani upazila of Gopalganj district last night.
The incident occurred around 8:30 pm at Tetulia village under Rajpat union of the upazila.
The deceased were identified as Rahela Begum, 50, wife of Mosarraf Shikd</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 05:49:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Demand to reinstate Biman’s Manchester–Sylhet route debated in British parliament</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/demand-to-reinstate-bimans-manchester-sylhet-route-debated-in-british-parliament</link><description>A demand to reconsider Biman Bangladesh Airlines’ decision to suspend regular flights on the Manchester–Sylhet route has been raised in the British parliament, as concerns grow over higher travel costs and disrupted links between the UK and Bangladesh.
Speaking in the House of Common</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 06:04:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Purbachal plot graft: Verdict against Hasina, Tulip, Bobby on Feb 2</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/purbachal-plot-graft-verdict-against-hasina-tulip-bobby-on-feb-2</link><description>A Dhaka court will deliver its verdict in a case over corruption in the allocation of plots in Purbachal against Radwan Mujib Siddiq Bobby, the nephew of ousted prime minister Sheikh Hasina, on Feb 2.
A total of 18 suspects, including Hasina and her niece and British MP Tulip Siddiq, are accused i</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 06:19:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Iran restores limited internet</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/iran-restores-limited-internet</link><description>Some citizens in Iran have been provided with access to the Internet after several days of nationwide blackout, the semi-official Mehr news agency reported on Saturday, without giving more details.
Also on Saturday, the country restored short message service (SMS), reports Xinhua.
Iran imposed se</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 06:30:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rapid growth gives impetus to financial inclusion: BB report</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/rapid-growth-gives-impetus-to-financial-inclusion-bb-report</link><description>Bangladesh has made significant progress in expanding financial inclusion, driven largely by rapid growth in digital financial services, agent banking and microfinance, according to a Bangladesh Bank report.
In its review of the country's financial inclusion landscape up to December 2024, the Bang</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 06:45:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>45 more contestants regain candidacies on eighth day of hearings</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/45-more-contestants-regain-candidacies-on-eighth-day-of-hearings</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) on Saturday approved 45 more appeals on the eighth day of hearings on challenges against returning officers' decisions on the scrutiny of nomination papers for the 13th National Parliamentary Election.
A total of 112 review appeal applications were taken up for hearing</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 07:00:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chhatra Dal protests outside Nirbachan Bhaban over EC’s role ahead of Feb polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/chhatra-dal-protests-outside-nirbachan-bhaban-over-ecs-role-ahead-of-feb-polls</link><description>Jatiyatabadi Chhatra Dal (JCD), the student wing of the BNP, on Sunday continued its demonstration in front of Nirbachan Bhaban, protesting the Election Commission’s “biased and controversial” role ahead of the upcoming national election slated for February 12 next.
JCD activists</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 07:15:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Why Bangladesh needs a mentoring culture to forge its future leaders</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/youth-and-entrepreneurship/why-bangladesh-needs-a-mentoring-culture-to-forge-its-future-leaders</link><description>Every year, hundreds of thousands of graduates leave Bangladesh's universities with their degrees in hand. They've spent years studying, earned their qualifications, and they're ready to contribute to the country's economy. For most of them, though, the jump from university to a real career is conf</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 07:30:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Patients suffer as intern doctors continue work stoppage at Osmani Hospital</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/patients-suffer-as-intern-doctors-continue-work-stoppage-at-osmani-hospital</link><description>Patients at Sylhet MAG Osmani Medical College Hospital are facing severe difficulties as intern doctors continue a work stoppage following an attack on a female intern doctor.
Intern doctors at the hospital have been on strike for 24 consecutive hours after failing to reach an agreement with the a</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 07:45:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka University Cultural Society welcomes new 'Oitri' batch</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/dhaka-university-cultural-society-welcomes-new-oitri-batch</link><description>The Dhaka University Cultural Society held its annual reception programme 'Oitri Baran' on Thursday at the TSC Auditorium, welcoming its newest batch of members with an evening of performances that stretched from 2 pm well into the night.
The event brought together students, faculty, and notable c</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 08:00:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BUET Entrepreneurs Network launches BUETEN Summit 2026</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/buet-entrepreneurs-network-launches-bueten-summit-2026</link><description>The BUET Entrepreneurs Network (BUETEN) has announced its flagship event, the BUETEN Summit 2026, to be held on January 23 and 24 at the Bangladesh University of Engineering and Technology (BUET) campus in Dhaka. Organised under the tagline "Connect. Innovate. Lead.", the summit will bring together</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 08:15:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two killed in Tangail road accident</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/two-killed-in-tangail-road-accident-1214</link><description>Two people were killed and two others injured in a road accident at Basail upazila of Tangail district last evening.
The deceased were identified as Milon, 24, son of Mintu Mia of Gosai Joyair area under Tangail Sadar upazila, and Arfan Khan, 75, son of late Moksed Khan of Chakpara area under Basa</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 08:30:27 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>