<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 09:22:54 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Suryakumar says champions India 'denied' the trophy after Asia Cup win</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/suryakumar-says-champions-india-denied-the-trophy-after-asia-cup-win</link><description>India captain Suryakumar Yadav said his side had been denied the chance to hoist the Asia Cup trophy on Sunday after it was removed from the presentation ceremony following their refusal to accept it from Pakistan's interior minister Mohsin Naqvi.
India beat Pakistan by five wickets in the final a</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 07:05:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Vessel with 52, 500 tonnes of Russian wheat arrives in Kutubdia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/vessel-with-52-500-tonnes-of-russian-wheat-arrives-in-kutubdia</link><description>A vessel carrying around 52, 500 tonnes of wheat from Russia has arrived at Kutubdia outer anchorage in the Bay of Bengal.
The vessel 'MV PERTH I', carrying the consignment imported under a cash purchase agreement, docked at Kutubdia in Kutubdia, according to a media release sent from the Ministry</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 07:20:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BB extends transaction hours for instant fund transfers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bb-extends-transaction-hours-for-instant-fund-transfers</link><description>Bangladesh Bank has revised the transaction hours for the Real-Time Gross Settlement (BD-RTGS) system, aiming to expand access to instant electronic payments in response to growing demand.
The new timetable will take effect on Oct 5, the central bank said on Sunday, according to bdnews24.com.
Und</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 06:29:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Former Snapchat CSO meets Prof Yunus, keen to invest in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/former-snapchat-cso-meets-prof-yunus-keen-to-invest-in-bangladesh</link><description>Imran Khan, a prominent American investor of Bangladeshi origin, met Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus in New York on Saturday (local time) and expressed his interest in investing in Bangladesh.
Khan, 48, moved to the United States at the age of 18 to pursue higher studies and later gained pr</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 06:44:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>One-third of farm produce lost before reaching consumers, experts warn</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/one-third-of-farm-produce-lost-before-reaching-consumers-experts-warn</link><description>Bangladesh loses about 34 per cent of its farm produce before it reaches consumers—an amount equivalent to 4.0 per cent of the country’s GDP.
Experts warn that such massive losses undermine food security, drive up prices, and damage the environment.
The figures were revealed on Monday</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 06:59:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CID file money laundering case against Noor Ali, 13 others</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/cid-file-money-laundering-case-against-noor-ali-13-others</link><description>The Criminal Investigation Department (CID) have filed a money laundering case against Unique Eastern Private Limited owner Noor Ali and 13 others for organised extortion of over Tk 400 million.
Bdnews24.com, citing a press statement issued on Monday, stated that initial evidence of fraud amountin</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 07:44:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UK reaffirms support for free, fair and credible elections in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/uk-supports-free-fair-and-credible-elections-in-bangladesh-next-year-sarah-cooke</link><description>British High Commissioner to Bangladesh Sarah Cooke on Monday reaffirmed the United Kingdom’s support for free, fair, credible, and peaceful elections in Bangladesh in 2026.
“I reaffirmed the UK's support for free, fair, credible and peaceful elections here in Bangladesh next year,&amp;rdq</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 08:14:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New York Mayor Eric Adams drops re-election bid</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/new-york-mayor-eric-adams-drops-re-election-bid</link><description>Embattled New York City Mayor Eric Adams, who has faced a federal bribery indictment and stunningly low approval ratings as the leader of the nation's largest city, dropped his bid on Sunday for a second term.
His departure from the race, a little more than a month before Election Day, leaves the</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 08:29:31 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>