<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 18:31:30 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Bank Asia partners with Heidelberg Materials Bangladesh on integrated cash management</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bank-asia-partners-with-heidelberg-materials-bangladesh-on-integrated-cash-management</link><description>Bank Asia PLC and Heidelberg Materials Bangladesh PLC have entered into a strategic partnership to introduce an integrated cash management solution for further strengthening the collaboration between the two organisations, according to a press release.
The agreement was formally signed by Mr. Soha</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 14:49:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat-e-Islami backs Inqilab Moncho’s 24-hour ultimatum for Hadi killers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-e-islami-backs-inqilab-monchos-24-hour-ultimatum-for-hadi-killers</link><description>Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami has expressed solidarity with the 24-hour ultimatum issued by Inqilab Moncho, demanding the immediate arrest of those responsible for the killing of Sharif Osman Hadi.
Jamaat-e-Islami Secretary General Mia Golam Parwar, urged the government to clarify its position and sw</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 15:04:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Kazi Farms Kitchen crowned number one frozen food brand for 4th consecutive year</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/kazi-farms-kitchen-crowned-number-one-frozen-food-brand-for-4th-consecutive-year</link><description>Kazi Farms Kitchen has once again been recognised as the number one frozen food brand in Bangladesh at the prestigious 17th Best Brand Award 2025, marking an exceptional 4th consecutive win in this category.
The award ceremony, organised by Bangladesh Brand Forum, was held on Saturday at the Grand</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 15:19:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hadi murder: CID finds Tk 1.27 billion abnormal transactions linked to Faisal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/hadi-murder-cid-finds-tk-127-billion-abnormal-transactions-linked-to-faisal</link><description>The Criminal Investigation Department (CID) has uncovered evidence of “suspicious transactions” worth Tk 1.27 billion in bank accounts linked to Faisal Karim Masud, key suspect in the murder of Sharif Osman bin Hadi, and his associates.
In a Sunday press note, the CID said it has launc</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 15:34:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Daylong protests force six pro-Awami League deans at Rajshahi University to resign</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/daylong-protests-force-six-pro-awami-league-deans-at-rajshahi-university-to-resign</link><description>In the face of a daylong student protest, six pro-Awami League deans at Rajshahi University have resigned.
Registrar Professor Iftikharul Alam Masud confirmed the resignations on Sunday night.
The students staged demonstrations throughout the day, including the locking of dean chambers and confin</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 15:49:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Urgent, inclusive, localised action suggested to address lightning risks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/urgent-inclusive-localised-action-suggested-to-address-lightning-risks</link><description>A new study has called for urgent, inclusive, and localised action to address lightning risks, one of the country’s fastest-growing climate-related hazards.
The study highlighted that lightning strikes claimed nearly 2,000 lives and injured more than 1,300 people between 2009 and 2024, dispr</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 16:04:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique Rahman urges vigilance against efforts to ‘cause anarchy’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-rahman-urges-vigilance-against-efforts-to-cause-anarchy</link><description>Acting BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman has warned that some elements are attempting to create “anarchy” across the country and urged party activists to remain vigilant.
Attending an inauguration of a digital memorial for those slain in the July Uprising in Bogura, he said the coming days w</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 16:19:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No sign of ‘locked’ door in Lakshmipur fire: police</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/police-find-no-evidence-of-locked-door-before-bnp-leaders-home-set-ablaze</link><description>Police claim they have found no evidence of the BNP leader’s house in Lakshmipur being locked before it was set on fire with petrol, despite allegations.
The fire broke out at the house of Belal Hossain, the co-organising secretary of BNP’s Bhabaniganj Union in Sadar Upazila, on Friday</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 16:35:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh to celebrate Shab-e-Meraj on Jan 16</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-to-celebrate-shab-e-meraj-on-jan-16</link><description>Bangladesh will observe Shab-e-Meraj on the Jan 16 night following the sighting of the moon.
The National Moon Sighting Committee confirmed the date on Sunday during a meeting chaired by Religious Affairs Advisor AFM Khalid Hossain, held in the conference room of the Islamic Foundation.
The found</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 16:50:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gold prices hit record high in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/gold-prices-hit-record-high-in-bangladesh</link><description>Gold prices in Bangladesh climbed to an all-time high on Sunday, with the price of 22-carat gold rising to Tk 218,117 per bhori following a fresh hike announced by the Bangladesh Jewellers Association (BAJUS).
BAJUS raised the price of 22-carat gold by Tk 1,050 per bhori, setting the new rat</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 17:05:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Indian visa application centre in Ctg suspends operations</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/indian-visa-application-centre-in-ctg-suspends-operations</link><description>India on Sunday suspended operations at the Visa Application Centre (IVAC) in Chattogram, the commercial capital of Bangladesh, until further notice.
“Due to the recent security incident at AHCI Chittagong, Indian visa operations at IVAC Chittagong will remain suspended from 21/12/2025 until</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 17:20:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US pursuing third oil tanker near Venezuela, officials say</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-pursuing-third-oil-tanker-near-venezuela-officials-say</link><description>The US Coast Guard is pursuing an oil tanker in international waters near Venezuela, officials told Reuters on Sunday, in what would be the second such operation this weekend and the third in less than a week if successful.
“The United States Guard is in active pursuit of a sanctioned dark f</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 17:35:41 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>