<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 07:24:46 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Amnesty calls for release of Anis Alamgir</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/amnesty-calls-for-release-of-anis-alamgir</link><description>Amnesty International has called for the release of journalist Anis Alamgir, who has been arrested in a case under the Anti-Terrorism Act.
“Anis Alamgir’s arrest continues an alarming trend of individuals being targeted for being perceived to support activities of the now banned Awami</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 06:02:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two killed in Sylhet motorcycle collision</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/two-killed-in-sylhet-motorcycle-collision</link><description>Two people were killed and two others injured in a collision between two motorcycles in Golapganj upazila of Sylhet district on Wednesday night.
The deceased were identified as Abdul Ahad, 42, and Sabbir Ahmad, 21, of Goashpur and Ranaping Chatrish villages respectively under the Golapganj upazila</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 04:33:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>12 killed in Nigeria mining site attack</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/africa/12-killed-in-nigeria-mining-site-attack</link><description>At least 12 people were killed, and three others abducted when gunmen attacked a mining site in Atoso village in Nigeria's restive Plateau state, a local group leader said on Wednesday.
Dalyop Solomon Mwantiri, who heads the Berom Youth Moulders-Association (BYM) said the attackers, who locals ide</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 04:48:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Saudi Arabia lifts expatriate fees to boost industrial sector</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/saudi-arabia-lifts-expatriate-fees-to-boost-industrial-sector</link><description>Saudi Arabia has abolished the “expatriate fees” imposed on foreign workers employed in industrial establishments registered under industrial licences.
The decision was taken at a cabinet meeting chaired by the crown prince and Prime Minister Mohammed bin Salman, following a recommenda</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 05:03:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ICDDR,B STUDY ON INFORMAL SETTLEMENTS: 43pc rural, 65pc urban women married before 18</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/icddrb-study-on-informal-settlements-43pc-rural-65pc-urban-women-married-before-18</link><description>A latest study of icddr,b has found an alarming picture of early marriage, intimate partner violence, and high rates of mistimed pregnancies among newlywed couples in informal settlements of Bangladesh.
The two-year cohort study, conducted by AdSEARCH of icddr,b, revealed on Wednesday that among t</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 05:18:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DMP sets up addl checkposts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dmp-sets-up-addl-checkposts</link><description>The Dhaka Metropolitan Police (DMP) has set up additional checkpoints in different areas across the capital for monitoring suspicious movements, verifying vehicles and individuals, and preventing any untoward incidents.
The DMP has also urged the residents to cooperate with police during the check</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 05:33:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Reinforce legal framework against human trafficking, speakers suggest at a city seminar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/reinforce-legal-framework-against-human-trafficking-speakers-suggest-at-a-city-seminar</link><description>Speakers on Wednesday emphasised the importance of fostering a victim-centred, trauma-informed, and gender-responsive approach among law students by strengthening their foundational knowledge and practical understanding.
They said this approach aimed to reinforce Bangladesh's legal framework again</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 05:48:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>RU holds 12th convocation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/ru-holds-12th-convocation</link><description>Rajshahi University (RU) held its 12th convocation on Wednesday, after uncertainty in the last five years. The ceremony took place at the central stadium amid a festive atmosphere across the campus.
From early morning, the university premises buzzed with excitement as graduates reunited with frien</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 06:03:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Indian visa centre in Dhaka now open</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/indian-visa-centre-in-dhaka-now-open</link><description>After assessing the security situation on Thursday morning, Indian Visa Application Centre (IVAC) in Dhaka is now operational and functioning as normal.
"We do understand the difficulties faced by applicants," said an official. 
Based on evolving security situation, there will be a reassessm</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 06:18:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Another Bangladeshi peacekeeper injured in Sudan drone attack</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/another-bangladeshi-peacekeeper-injured-in-sudan-drone-attack</link><description>Another Bangladeshi peacekeeper has been injured in a drone attack by separatist forces in Sudan, raising the total number of wounded Bangladesh Army personnel serving in the UN mission to nine.
According to a media release from the Inter-Services Public Relations (ISPR), eight Bangladeshi peaceke</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 06:33:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCP activist Jannat Ara Rumi found dead in Hazaribagh hostel</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ncp-activist-jannat-ara-rumi-found-dead-in-hazaribagh-hostel</link><description>Police have recovered the hanging body of a young woman, identified as Jannat Ara Rumi (30), from a female hostel in the Hazaribagh area of Dhaka
She was involved in politics with the National Citizen Party (NCP), though it has not yet been confirmed whether she held any official post in the party</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 06:48:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DSE, CSE down in early trading</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/dse-cse-down-in-early-trading</link><description>Trading at both the Dhaka and Chattogram stock exchanges began on a negative note on Thursday, with key indices falling in the first hour amid declines in most company prices.
The benchmark DSEX at the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) shed 17 points.
The Shariah-based DSES fell by 5 points, while the b</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 07:03:15 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>