<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 15:26:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Biting cold to stay put for 2 more days</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/intense-cold-to-linger-for-two-more-days-with-patchy-drizzle</link><description>The Bangladesh Meteorological Department (BMD) says the biting cold gripping the country is set to persist through Wednesday, as dense fog continues to block sunlight across large swathes of Bangladesh.
After a brief easing, temperatures could dip again, the BMD warned, raising the prospect of ano</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 14:00:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Banks to remain closed on Wednesday following death of Khaleda Zia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/banks-to-remain-closed-on-wednesday-following-death-of-khaleda-zia</link><description>All scheduled banks operating in Bangladesh will remain closed on Wednesday (December 31), following the government’s declaration of a public holiday in honour of the late former Prime Minister and BNP Chairperson, Begum Khaleda Zia.
The Department of Off-site Supervision (DOS) of Bangladesh</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 12:45:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Southeast Bank opens its 137th branch at Gouripur in Cumilla</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/southeast-bank-opens-its-137th-branch-at-gouripur-in-cumilla</link><description>Southeast Bank PLC has inaugurated its 137th ‘Gouripur Branch’ at Jinnot Ali Complex, Homna Road, Gouripur Bazar, Daudkandi, Cumilla with the aim of expanding the scope of modern banking services.
Md. Sekander-E-Azam, Deputy Managing Director of Southeast Bank PLC, formally inaugurated</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 13:00:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>International media highlight Khaleda Zia’s death</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/international-media-highlight-khaleda-zias-death</link><description>The death of BNP Chairperson and former Prime Minister Khaleda Zia has been widely covered by leading international media outlets, reflecting her long-standing influence on Bangladesh’s politics and her stature on the global stage.
Major international news organisations—including Reute</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 13:15:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pakistan deputy PM to attend Khaleda Zia’s funeral prayer</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/pakistan-deputy-pm-to-attend-khaleda-zias-funeral-prayer</link><description>Pakistan’s Deputy Prime Minister and Foreign Minister Mohammad Ishaq Dar is scheduled to attend the funeral prayer (namaj-e-janaza) of former prime minister and BNP chairperson Begum Khaleda Zia.
Ishaq Dar is scheduled to arrive in Dhaka on a special flight on Wednesday morning, the Pakistan</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 13:30:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Vehicular movement to be restricted while Khaleda Zia’s body transported in city</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/vehicular-movement-to-be-restricted-while-khaleda-zias-body-transported-in-city</link><description>Traffic will remain restricted on several roads in the capital on Wednesday due to the movement of the convoy carrying the body of former Prime Minister and BNP Chairperson Begum Khaleda Zia, according to Dhaka Metropolitan Police (DMP).
The funeral prayer (Namaj-e-Janaja) of Begum Khaleda Zia is</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 13:45:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fireworks, open-air events banned on New Year’s Eve in Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fireworks-open-air-events-banned-on-new-years-eve-in-dhaka</link><description>Police have banned fireworks, crackers, and open-space events on the night of Dec 31, marking the final day of the Gregorian calendar.
The government has declared three days of state mourning following the death of former prime minister and BNP chairperson Khaleda Zia, along with a one-day general</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 14:00:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fireworks, gatherings banned on New Year's Eve in Ctg</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/chattogram-police-bans-fireworks-lanterns-and-gatherings-in-chattogram-on-new-years-eve</link><description>Burning fireworks, firecrackers and flying lanterns have been prohibited in Chattogram city on the last day of the Gregorian calendar.
Chattogram Metropolitan Police (CMP) Commissioner Hasib Aziz has issued six instructions imposing strict restrictions on public movement and gatherings, particular</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 14:15:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>MTB Foundation commemorates 26th anniversary by distributing bicycles in Chattogram</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/mtb-foundation-commemorates-26th-anniversary-by-distributing-bicycles-in-chattogram</link><description>To commemorate the bank’s 26th Anniversary, MTB Foundation distributed free bicycles to the underprivileged female meritorious students of different schools in the Chattogram region under its ‘Swapno Sarathi’ (The Dream Chariot) program.
The motto of the campaign, ‘schoole</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 14:30:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EBL opens a sub-branch at Kansat, Chapainawabganj</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ebl-opens-a-sub-branch-at-kansat-chapainawabganj</link><description>Eastern Bank (EBL) has expanded its retail footprint with opening of its sub-branch at Al Hajj Mohammad Abdul Kayum Market, Kansat, Chapainawabganj, according to a press release.
EBL Deputy Managing Director and Head of Retail and SME Banking M. Khorshed Anowar along with Acting Branch Area Head -</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 14:45:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Power failure halts Channel Tunnel rail traffic, causing travel mayhem</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/power-failure-halts-channel-tunnel-rail-traffic-causing-travel-mayhem</link><description>Train services through the Channel Tunnel linking Britain and continental Europe were suspended on Tuesday following a power supply failure, disrupting peak winter holiday travel.
A spokesperson for Eurostar, which operates high-speed trains linking London to Paris, Brussels, Amsterdam and Disneyl</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 15:00:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bank Asia launches ten Islamic Banking Windows simultaneously</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bank-asia-launches-ten-islamic-banking-windows-simultaneously</link><description>Bank Asia PLC has inaugurated ten Islamic Banking Windows simultaneously across the country on the occasion of the 17th anniversary of its Islamic Banking Services, according to a press release.
The inauguration ceremony was held on 24 December 2025 at Bank Asia Tower, Karwan Bazar, Dhaka. Deputy</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 15:15:56 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>