<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 15:01:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Armed forces allowed inside polling stations: Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/armed-forces-allowed-inside-polling-stations-adviser</link><description>Home Affairs Adviser Lt Gen Md Jahangir Alam Chowdhury on Tuesday said any kind of chaos at polling stations will be dealt with strictly, as armed forces members are being allowed inside polling stations for the first time.
“Any disruption at polling centers will be dealt with strictly. Ther</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 12:46:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique reviews ground situation after campaign</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-chief-tarique-assesses-constituency-level-situation-from-party-office-after-campaign</link><description>After spending several days travelling across the country for election campaigning, BNP Chairperson Tarique Rahman is now working from his office in Gulshan.
From there, he has been speaking with party leaders, activists, and candidates across the country, seeking updates from candidates on the si</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 13:01:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mild earthquake jolts Sylhet; epicentre in Gowainghat upazila</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/mild-earthquake-jolts-sylhet-epicentre-in-gowainghat-upazila</link><description>A mild tremor shook Sylhet and its adjacent areas on Tuesday.
According to the Bangladesh Meteorological Department (BMD), the tremor was recorded at 5:32 pm with a magnitude of 4.0 on the Richter scale.
The epicentre of the earthquake was Gowainghat upazila of Sylhet division, 214 km North-East</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 13:16:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BB buys $171m through dollar auction</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bb-buys-171m-through-dollar-auction</link><description>Bangladesh Bank (BB) on Tuesday purchased US$171 million from 11 commercial banks through multiple auction methods as part of its ongoing strategy to curb the depreciation of the US dollar against the Taka and revitalise the remittance and export sectors.
According to central bank data, it bought</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 12:18:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Key in your hands, use it wisely: Yunus to voters</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/key-in-your-hands-use-it-wisely-prof-yunus-tells-voters</link><description>Chief Adviser Prof Muhammad Yunus on Tuesday urged the electorate to make the February-12 election day the ‘birthday of a new Bangladesh’, saying that voters themselves will write the history of the country’s glorious future.
“Your vote will write the history of Bangladesh&amp;</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 12:33:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Israeli strikes kill five in Gaza, health officials say</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/israeli-strikes-kill-five-in-gaza-health-officials-say</link><description>Israeli airstrikes and gunfire killed five Palestinians in Gaza on Tuesday, health officials said, the latest violence to undermine a four-month-old, U.S.-brokered truce in the enclave.
In Deir Al-Balah in central Gaza, an airstrike killed two people who were riding an electric bike, medics said.</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 12:48:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Court orders arrest of Hero Alom over ‘rape’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/court-orders-arrest-of-hero-alom-over-rape</link><description>A Bogura court has ordered the arrest of popular content creator Ashraful Hossen Alom, widely known as Hero Alom, over ‘soliciting sexual relationship with promises of marriage’.
The arrest warrant was issued by Judge Anwarul Haque of the Women and Children Repression Prevention Tribun</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 13:03:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>JnU hosts seminar on parental involvement in students’ academic motivation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/jnu-hosts-seminar-on-parental-involvement-in-students-academic-motivation</link><description>The Department of Psychology of Jagannath University (JnU) organised a seminar titled “Student–Parent Motivation: A Community Outreach Programme” as part of the University Grants Commission (UGC)–funded HEAT (Higher Education Acceleration and Transformation) Sub-Project (PIN</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 13:18:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP leader Rizvi hospitalised</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-leader-rizvi-hospitalised</link><description>BNP Senior Joint Secretary General Advocate Ruhul Kabir Rizvi was admitted to Square Hospital in the capital on Tuesday.
His personal assistant Arifur Rahman Tushar said the BNP leader was taken to the hospital around 3:00 pm due to breathing difficulties, UNB reports. 
He said Rizvi has bee</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 13:33:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique keeps up momentum, spends busy day with party work</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-keeps-up-momentum-spends-busy-day-with-party-work</link><description>BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman spent a busy Tuesday after wrapping up his election campaigning by remaining engaged in organisational and coordination activities.
Throughout the day, Tarique spoke over the phone with party leaders, activists and candidates across the country to take updates on the ov</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 13:48:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>2,028 candidates participating in the Feb 12 polls: EC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/2028-candidates-participating-in-the-feb-12-polls-ec</link><description>A total of 2,028 candidates of 50 political parties and independent candidates are participating in 299 constituencies in the 13th national parliamentary elections scheduled for February 12.
Of those, 81 are women candidates, said Election Commissioner (EC) Brigadier General (retd) Abul Fazal Muha</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 14:03:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Standard Bank rebranded as ‘Standard Islami Bank’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/standard-bank-rebranded-as-standard-islami-bank</link><description>Bangladesh Bank has officially announced the renaming of Standard Bank PLC to ‘Standard Islami Bank PLC’ effective February 10, 2026.
The change follows the bank's full conversion into a Shariah-compliant financial institution.
The transition reflects the continued expansion of the Is</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 14:18:50 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>