<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 13:30:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Political stability crucial for economic recovery before election: DCCI</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/political-stability-crucial-for-economic-recovery-before-election-dcci</link><description>Dhaka Chamber of Commerce &amp; Industry (DCCI) has warned that political uncertainty ahead of Bangladesh’s national election could threaten economic recovery, urging timely and effective policy measures to sustain growth and bolster investor confidence in 2026.
In a media release on Saturday, t</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 11:32:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nominations of BNP's Babar, wife cleared for Netrokona-4 constituency</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/nominations-of-bnps-babar-wife-cleared-for-netrokona-4-constituency</link><description>The Election Commission has declared the nominations of former state minister Lutfozzaman Babar and his wife Tahmina Zaman Sraboni valid.
The couple has now entered the election race for the Netrokona-4 constituency, which covers Mohanganj, Madan, and Khaliajuri.
Tahmina is running as an independ</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 11:47:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>17 nominations validated in Thakurgaon, Fakhrul among candidates</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/17-nominations-validated-in-thakurgaon-fakhrul-among-candidates</link><description>The nomination papers of 17 candidates across three constituencies in Thakurgaon, including that of BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir, have been declared valid by the Returning Officer for the 13th national election.
The announcement was made on Saturday morning at the office of th</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 12:02:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CAB seeks govt action to rein in LPG, sugar, edible oil prices</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cab-seeks-govt-action-to-rein-in-lpg-sugar-edible-oil-prices</link><description>Consumers Association of Bangladesh (CAB) has issued a seven-point demand to the government, warning of widespread consumer frustration amid what it calls abnormal and sustained price hikes in sugar, liquefied petroleum gas (LPG) and edible oils.
In a statement on Saturday, CAB accused an influent</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 12:17:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A real election to take place after many years: Rizwana Hasan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/a-real-election-to-take-place-after-many-years-rizwana-hasan</link><description>Information and Broadcasting Adviser Syeda Rizwana Hasan today (Saturday) said that a real election will be held in the country after many years where the government has no partisan role.
She made the remarks while inaugurating a training workshop on ‘Election-Time Journalism’, organiz</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 11:33:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shariatpur trader, who was stabbed and set ablaze, dies</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/shariatpur-trader-who-was-stabbed-and-set-ablaze-dies</link><description>A small-town trader in Shariatpur has died after being stabbed and set on fire with petrol in a gruesome attack, prompting calls for exemplary punishment for those responsible.
Khokon Chandra Das, 50, succumbed to his injuries around 8am on Saturday while undergoing treatment at the National Insti</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 11:48:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Fake phones’ to stay active for now</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/millions-of-cloned-handsets-to-remain-active-in-bangladesh-despite-neir-rollout</link><description>The interim government has released what it describes as alarming data on fake or “cloned mobile phones” following the rollout of the National Equipment Identity Register (NEIR).
In an official statement on Saturday, authorities said millions of handsets using duplicate or fake IMEI nu</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 12:03:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘We burnt Baniachong Police Station, SI Santosh’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/we-burnt-baniachong-police-station-si-santosh</link><description>A senior district leader of the Students Against Discrimination has sparked controversy after allegedly threatening police officers at Shayestaganj Police Station in Habiganj.
He allegedly invoked past violence, claiming responsibility for the burning of another police station and the killing of a</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 12:18:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BRAC Bank coworkers spread warmth in Bandarban hill tracts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/brac-bank-coworkers-spread-warmth-in-bandarban-hill-tracts</link><description>BRAC Bank coworkers have concluded a week-long winter clothing drive that collected over 400 essential winter items for hill communities in Bandarban. 
The initiative, called "Khushi Chhorai Ushnotay" (Spreading Joy Through Warmth), was conducted in partnership with Jhilimili, a youth volunte</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 12:33:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCP secures nomination validity in four Dhaka seats</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ncp-secures-nomination-validity-in-four-dhaka-seats</link><description>The district returning officer on Saturday declared valid the nomination papers of four candidates of National Citizen Party (NCP), a partner of the Jamaat-e-Islami-led 10-party alliance, in four Dhaka constituencies.
Dhaka's Deputy Commissioner and District Returning Officer Md Rezaul Karim appro</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 12:48:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>66 benches formed in High Court after vacation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/66-benches-formed-in-high-court-after-vacation</link><description>After the December vacation, a total of 66 benches have been formed on Saturday to conduct judicial proceedings in the High Court Division of the Supreme Court.
The list of the 66 benches, formed under the directive of Chief Justice Zubayer Rahman Chowdhury, was published on the Supreme Court&amp;rsqu</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 13:03:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jatiya Party’s Anisul raises concern over ‘fair’ election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jatiya-partys-anisul-raises-concern-over-fair-election</link><description>Anisul Islam Mahmud, chairman of a breakaway faction of the Jatiya Party, has raised concerns about a “fair” election, alleging that two of his proposers and supporters were kidnapped in broad daylight.
He made the allegation at an emergency press briefing held at his Gulshan residence</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 13:18:21 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>