<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 06:35:39 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Govt urges nationwide special prayers for Khaleda Zia on Friday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-urges-nationwide-special-prayers-for-khaleda-zia-on-friday</link><description>The interim government on Thursday called for special prayers across the country seeking the speedy recovery of the former prime minister and BNP chairperson Khaleda Zia.
Muslims have been requested to offer du'a after Juma prayers on Friday at all mosques, while temples, churches and pagodas have</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 02:59:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>2 shareholder-directors elected unopposed to DSE board</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/2-shareholder-directors-elected-unopposed-to-dse-board</link><description>Md Hanif Bhuiya and Md Sajedul Islam have been elected uncontested as shareholder-directors of the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) for the next three years.
They will replace Md Shakil Rizvi, managing director of Shakil Rizvi Stock, and Mohammad Shahjahan, managing director of Jahan Securities.
This y</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 03:14:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Regulator launches action against DBBL over related-party building purchase</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/regulator-launches-action-against-dbbl-over-related-party-building-purchase</link><description>The securities regulator has initiated enforcement action against Dutch-Bangla Bank Ltd. (DBBL) over what it described as a conflict of interest linked to a plan to purchase a multi-storied building.
On August 26, the bank's board of directors decided to acquire a 21-storey commercial building in</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 03:29:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Top court rejects appeal, affirms legality of interim government</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/top-court-rejects-appeal-affirms-legality-of-interim-government</link><description>Bangladesh's top court has dismissed an appeal challenging the High Court's decision upholding the formation of the interim government and reaffirming its legal validity.
As a result, no further legal questions remain concerning the validity of the oaths taken by the interim administration led by</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 03:44:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tender floated for Jan spot cargo</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/tender-floated-for-jan-spot-cargo</link><description>Bangladesh is preparing to bring in its first spot liquefied natural gas cargo of 2026 as it seeks to manage rising demand amid tight domestic supply.
The state-run Rupantarita Prakritik Gas Company Ltd (RPGCL), a subsidiary of Petrobangla, has issued an international tender for a January 3-4 deli</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 03:59:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Teachers launch 'full' shutdown, schools closed across country</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/teachers-launch-full-shutdown-schools-closed-across-country</link><description>Assistant teachers of government primary schools announced that they launched a complete shutdown across the country on Wednesday until further notice to realise their three-point demand.
As part of the move, they have padlocked numerous schools, hampering ongoing annual examinations.
They also h</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 04:14:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DU regular classes to resume Dec 28</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/du-regular-classes-to-resume-dec-28</link><description>The Dhaka University (DU) has decided to reopen its residential halls and resume regular in-person classes from 28 December, following a technical assessment conducted after the recent earthquakes. To minimise the academic gap during the emergency closure, ongoing online classes will continue until</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 04:29:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Another Chinese medical team joins Khaleda’s treatment</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/another-chinese-medical-team-joins-khaledas-treatment</link><description>Another team of specialist doctors from China has arrived in Dhaka to assist in the treatment of BNP Chairperson Begum Khaleda Zia, who is undergoing treatment at Evercare Hospital in the capital.
The four-member team arrived at Evercare Hospital at 10:10 pm on Wednesday, said BNP media cell membe</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 04:44:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Editors' Council new exec body holds first meeting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/editors-council-new-exec-body-holds-first-meeting</link><description>First meeting of the newly-elected executive committee of the Editors' Council was held on Tuesday last (December 02), the apex platform of the editors in media outlets informed through a press release.
New Age Editor Nurul Kabir officially took the responsibility of president of the new committee</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 04:59:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BTRC conducts public hearing via Convay</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/btrc-conducts-public-hearing-via-convay</link><description>The Bangladesh Telecommunication Regulatory Commission (BTRC) has, for the first time, conducted its national public hearing entirely through Convay, a locally developed video-conferencing platform, marking a new milestone for domestic technology adoption in key government processes.
The sixth ann</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 05:14:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka may see shift in crime patterns ahead of national election: DB</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/dhaka-may-see-shift-in-crime-patterns-ahead-of-national-election-db</link><description>Dhaka may witness a shift in its crime patterns in the coming weeks ahead of the national election, as intelligence agencies fear a rise in sabotage, arson attacks, and politically driven violence.
In recent weeks, parts of the capital have experienced scattered incidents of crude bomb explosions,</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 05:29:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt revises school age rules</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-revises-school-age-rules</link><description>The government has revised age-related rules for student admission from first to ninth grade in public schools.
While the minimum age for first-grade admission remains five to seven years, the new policy removes the previous requirement that students entering higher classes must follow the same ag</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 05:44:57 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>