<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 12:49:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Tarique Rahman seeks ‘doa’ for his mother as millions join funeral</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-rahman-seeks-doa-for-his-mother-as-millions-join-funeral</link><description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman sought doa (supplication) for eternal peace of the departed soul of his mother Begum Khaleda Zia, three-time former Prime Minister and the party’s chairperson, prior to her Namaz-e-Janaza at Manik Mia Avenue this afternoon. 
“I am Tarique Rahman,</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 09:45:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jatiya Party postpones 40th founding anniversary programmes</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jatiya-party-postpones-40th-founding-anniversary-programmes</link><description>All programmes marking the 40th founding anniversary of the Jatiya Party have been postponed following the declaration of state mourning over the death of BNP Chairperson and former prime minister Khaleda Zia.
The decision was announced in a statement issued on Wednesday.
The party’s foundi</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 10:00:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>11 lakh voters register to vote by post</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/11-lakh-voters-register-to-vote-by-post</link><description>A total of 1,125,263 voters have registered so far to cast postal votes in the 13th National Parliament Election and Referendum.
In addition to expatriate Bangladeshis, officials and employees assigned to election duties and government employees stationed outside their localities are registering t</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 10:15:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DITF plays vital role to promote domestic products, expand exports: CA</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ditf-plays-vital-role-to-promote-domestic-products-expand-exports-ca</link><description>Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus on Wednesday called upon all participating countries and institutions at the Dhaka International Trade Fair (DITF) to work together in a spirit of mutual cooperation and partnership.
“The interim government has remained firmly committed to safeguarding</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 10:30:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Interim govt advisers meet foreign dignitaries, express gratitude</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/interim-govt-advisers-meet-foreign-dignitaries-express-gratitude</link><description>Law Adviser Dr Asif Nazrul and National Security Adviser Dr Khalilur Rahman on Wednesday met visiting Indian External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar, Speaker of the Pakistan National Assembly Sardar Ayaz Sadiq, Nepal’s Foreign Minister Bala Nanda Sharma and Bhutan’s Foreign Minister DN D</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 10:45:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Thieves drill into German bank vault and make off with millions</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/thieves-drill-into-german-bank-vault-and-make-off-with-millions</link><description>Thieves used the quiet Christmas period to drill their way into the vault of a German retail bank and make off with at least 10 million euros' worth of money and valuables from customers' deposit boxes, police said on Tuesday.
The perpetrators drilled through a thick concrete wall at a branch of S</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 11:00:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Finland suspects ship of causing undersea cable damage, president says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/finland-suspects-ship-of-causing-undersea-cable-damage-president-says</link><description>Finnish authorities have inspected a vessel suspected of causing undersea cable damage in the Gulf of Finland, President Alexander Stubb said on Wednesday.
Baltic Sea nations have been on high alert after a string of outages of power cables, telecom links and gas pipelines since Russia invaded Ukr</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 11:15:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>From battleships to buildings: Trump's name is everywhere</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/from-battleships-to-buildings-trumps-name-is-everywhere</link><description>As a New York businessman, President Donald Trump put his name on real estate, golf courses, vodka, steaks, bottled water and his own university.
As president in his second term, he is merging his personal brand with national institutions and government programs, an unusual assertion of power by a</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 11:30:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rooted in Feni: The neem tree that bears Khaleda’s memory</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/rooted-in-feni-the-neem-tree-that-bears-khaledas-memory</link><description>At the gate of Majumdar Bari in Fulgazi, Feni, a neem tree planted decades ago by BNP Chairperson Khaleda Zia still stands, quietly preserving a living memory of her ties to the ancestral home.
Back in 2008, during a visit to her ancestral house, Majumdar Bari at Shreepur village of Fulgazi Upazil</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 11:45:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Myanmar junta says voter turnout at 52pc in first phase of election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/myanmar-junta-says-voter-turnout-at-52pc-in-first-phase-of-election</link><description>Myanmar's junta said slightly more than half of eligible voters cast their ballot in the first phase of a three-stage national election at the weekend, a figure that was markedly lower than the previous two elections.
The election is the first since a 2021 coup and is taking place during a civil w</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 12:00:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Drugmakers raise US prices on 350 medicines despite pressure from Trump</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/drugmakers-raise-us-prices-on-350-medicines-despite-pressure-from-trump</link><description>Drugmakers plan to raise US prices on at least 350 branded medications including vaccines against COVID, RSV and shingles and blockbuster cancer treatment Ibrance, even as the Trump administration pressures them for cuts, according to data provided exclusively by healthcare research firm 3 Axis Adv</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 12:15:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP vows to walk Khaleda’s path</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/in-death-khaleda-zia-sets-bnps-course-as-it-pledges-to-carry-her-legacy-forward</link><description>Millions stood shoulder to shoulder beneath an open winter sky as Bangladesh bid farewell to Khaleda Zia—a leader whose political life was defined by defiance, endurance and unyielding belief in democracy.
Moments before her funeral prayers, the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) pledged to</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 12:30:41 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>