<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 05:24:35 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Govt activities to continue despite poll schedule: Salehuddin</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-activities-to-continue-despite-poll-schedule-salehuddin</link><description>Finance Adviser Dr Salehuddin Ahmed on Tuesday said that government operations will continue as usual despite the announcement of the national election schedule.
"All government activities will continue as long as they do not directly influence the election," he said, adding that only decisions af</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 04:00:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jet fuel price hiked by up to 4.36pc for December</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/jet-fuel-price-hiked-by-up-to-436pc-for-december</link><description>The energy regulator has raised the prices of jet A-1 fuel, known as aviation fuel, by 4.10 per cent to 4.36 per cent for international and domestic flights respectively for this month (December).
With the upward adjustments, the price of jet A-1 fuel has been fixed at US$0.6875 per litre for inte</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 02:30:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Employees won't get incentive bonuses: BB</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/employees-wont-get-incentive-bonuses-bb</link><description>Bangladesh Bank on Tuesday directed that commercial banks having capital shortfall or provision shortfall would not be able to pay incentives to their employees.
Banks previously used to disburse such type of bonuses even if they had deficits.
The central bank issued this directive in order to en</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 02:45:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rokeya Day observed in Rangpur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rokeya-day-observed-in-rangpur</link><description>Rangpur district administration, BRUR and different socio-cultural organisations observed Rokeya Day 2025 on Tuesday.
A tribute was paid at the memorial plaque of Begum Rokeya at her birthplace in Pairaband, Mithapukur in the morning. A discussion meeting was held at noon, followed by drawing and</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 03:00:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Aamra Networks faces BSEC probe over use of rights issue funds</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/aamra-networks-faces-bsec-probe-over-use-of-rights-issue-funds</link><description>The market watchdog has ordered a full inquiry into the utilization of rights-offer proceeds by Aamra Networks after an on-the-spot inspection raised doubts over the company's claimed investments.
Aamra Networks raised Tk 929.79 million through rights shares in May last year and claimed to have ut</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 03:15:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Doreen Power exits gas-fired power, sells final plant as scrap</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/doreen-power-exits-gas-fired-power-sells-final-plant-as-scrap</link><description>Doreen Power has decided to sell its last gas-based power plant as scrap, effectively shutting down its electricity generation operations from natural gas.
It will continue generating revenue and profits from its subsidiaries, which are heavy fuel oil-based power plants, until 2037.
"We will have</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 03:30:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>State-run sugar mills face crisis as BSFIC fails to secure funds for farmers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/state-run-sugar-mills-face-crisis-as-bsfic-fails-to-secure-funds-for-farmers</link><description>The financial stability of eight state-run sugar mills is under threat as the Bangladesh Sugar and Food Industries Corporation (BSFIC) struggles to secure adequate funds to pay sugarcane farmers in the ongoing 2025-26 crushing season.
Despite having a staggering outstanding claim of Tk 80.80 billi</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 03:45:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>World Bank team reviews Bay Terminal project</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/world-bank-team-reviews-bay-terminal-project</link><description>CHATTOGRAM, Dec 09: A World Bank (WB) delegation on Tuesday wrapped up a three-day visit to Chittagong port, where they reviewed the Bay Terminal mega project, which is set to significantly enhance the port's capacity and operational efficiency.
The visit focused on discussions with Chittagong Por</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 04:00:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Experts urge govt to execute anti-torture commitments</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/experts-urge-govt-to-execute-anti-torture-commitments</link><description>Human rights experts, government officials, and international partners have called for swift and substantive implementation of Bangladesh's new obligations under the Optional Protocol to the Convention against Torture (OPCAT), opining that its ratification must now be translated into real accountab</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 04:15:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Australia begins enforcing world-first teen social media ban</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/australia-begins-enforcing-world-first-teen-social-media-ban</link><description>Australia on Wednesday became the first country to ban social media for children under 16, blocking access in a move welcomed by many parents and child advocates but criticised by major technology companies and free-speech advocates.
Starting at midnight (1300 GMT on Tuesday), 10 of the largest pl</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 04:30:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US trade deal with Indonesia at risk of collapse, US official says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/us-trade-deal-with-indonesia-at-risk-of-collapse-us-official-says</link><description>A US trade agreement reached with Indonesia in July is at risk of collapsing because Jakarta has backtracked on several commitments it made as part of the deal, a US official said on Tuesday.
"They're reneging on what we agreed to in July," said the official, who spoke on condition of anonymity, g</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 04:45:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cambodia vows fierce fight against Thailand in their escalating border conflict</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/cambodia-vows-fierce-fight-against-thailand-in-their-escalating-border-conflict</link><description>Cambodia’s Senate President Hun Sen vowed a fierce fight against Thailand as a second day of widespread renewed combat between the nations Tuesday drove tens of thousands of people to flee border areas.
The fighting following a skirmish Sunday that injured two Thai soldiers and derailed a ce</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 05:00:54 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>