<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 17:39:49 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>49 Puja pandals targeted in sabotage attempts: RAB</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rabs-chief-says-19-arrested-over-attempts-to-disrupt-puja-festivities-at-49-pandals</link><description>At least 49 out of 35,000 Puja pavilions across the country were targeted for sabotage, but these attempts were successfully thwarted, Rapid Action Battalion Director-General AKM Shahidur Rahman has said.
After inspecting the Ramakrishna Mission Ashrama in Narayanganj on Wednesday, Shahidur said,</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 14:51:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Daughter bids last goodbye to father at zero line</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/daughter-bids-last-goodbye-to-father-at-zero-line</link><description>A woman married in Bangladesh has rushed to the border after receiving news of her father’s death in India, but barbed wire fencing stood in the way as she had no travel documents.
Later, after the matter was raised with border authorities, troops from both sides held a flag meeting to allow</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 15:06:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rock samples show moon's farside interior is cooler than the nearside</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/rock-samples-show-moons-farside-interior-is-cooler-than-the-nearside</link><description>The moon is sometimes called "two-faced" because the surface of its side perpetually facing away from Earth looks so different than its side always facing our planet. And the differences run deeper than that, as shown by an analysis of rock and soil retrieved in 2024 by China's Chang'e-6 robotic lu</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 15:51:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BSF detains man from no-man’s land, BGB opens negotiations</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bsf-detains-man-from-no-mans-land-bgb-opens-negotiations</link><description>India’s Border Security Force has detained a Bangladeshi man from the Jibannagar border in Chuadanga.
The incident occurred around 10am on Wednesday near Benipur village along the frontier, according to Lt Col Md Rafiqul Alam, commander of Maheshpur-58 Border Guard Bangladesh (BGB) Battalion</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 16:06:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>260 members of Moroccan security forces reported hurt as youth protests turn violent</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/africa/260-members-of-moroccan-security-forces-reported-hurt-as-youth-protests-turn-violent</link><description>Youth protests in cities across Morocco turned far more violent on the fourth night of unrest, authorities said on Wednesday, reporting 263 members of the security forces and 23 civilians injured as demonstrators torched cars and ransacked shops.
Protestsbegan on Saturday and have accelerated over</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 16:21:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Indonesia earthquake slows efforts to rescue those trapped by school collapse</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/indonesia-earthquake-slows-efforts-to-rescue-those-trapped-by-school-collapse</link><description>Rescuers battling to extricate students from the rubble of an Islamic school under construction that collapsed and killed at least six in Indonesia's province of East Java faced a harder task on Wednesday, a day after an earthquake packed the debris tighter.
The magnitude 6.5 quake complicated the</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 16:36:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Advisor Khalid slates depiction of Yunus as demon in India</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/religious-affairs-advisor-khalid-calls-depiction-of-yunus-as-demon-indecent-disrespectful</link><description>Religious Affairs Advisor AFM Khalid Hossain has condemned the depiction of Muhammad Yunus with the face of a demon at a Durga Puja pavilion in India’s West Bengal.
Speaking after a seminar in Brahmanbaria on Wednesday afternoon, he said such a portrayal of a government leader in another cou</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 16:51:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Climate change's hidden toll</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/climate-changes-hidden-toll</link><description>Bangladesh is often celebrated as a global leader in climate adaptation. From its cyclone preparedness programmes to community-based resilience strategies, the country has built an international reputation for confronting one of the gravest existential challenges of our time. Yet beneath this celeb</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 17:06:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Caring for the elderly</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/caring-for-the-elderly</link><description>The International Day of Older Persons was observed on October 1 with the theme, "Older Persons Driving Local and Global Action: Our Aspirations, Our Well-Being and Our Rights." The theme highlights that older persons, far from being passive beneficiaries, can play a transformative role in building</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 17:21:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Animation industry, its growth potential</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/animation-industry-its-growth-potential</link><description>That animation has developed as a global industry within the media and entertainment sector is not widely known. However, its application to feature films, television cartoon series and video games has kept the entertainment world moving. The virtual world thus created becomes an edition of the rea</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 17:36:29 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>