<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 07:26:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Country's fruit production sees huge boost over years</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/countrys-fruit-production-sees-huge-boost-over-years</link><description>The country's fruit production has experienced a big boost over the recent years, as yields of some non-traditional varieties have ballooned significantly, official statistics showed.
Bangladesh's fruit sector has demonstrated a remarkable growth and resilience in the last fiscal year (FY), 2024-2</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 03:41:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two-day int'l conf'ce on Bhashani begins at DU today</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/two-day-intl-confce-on-bhashani-begins-at-du-today</link><description>An international conference titled 'Decolonization and Maulana Bhashani' is set to begin at Dhaka University (DU) today (December 23). The two-day conference is organised by the Center for Advanced Research in Arts and Social Sciences (CARASS) to discuss the life, thoughts, and legacy of Maulana Ab</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 03:56:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Inqilab Moncho presses for Hadi killing trial, backed by FBI, Scotland Yard</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/inqilab-moncho-presses-for-hadi-killing-trial-backed-by-fbi-scotland-yard</link><description>Inqilab Moncho staged a protest rally on Monday demanding justice for the killing of its spokesperson Sharif Osman Hadi and the trial of all those involved in the murder.
The platform also called for conducting investigation of the killing through formation of a judicial tribunal, also taking assi</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 04:11:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>RAJSHAHI AND RANGPUR DIVISIONS: Fertiliser scarcity holds back potato cultivation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/rajshahi-and-rangpur-divisions-fertiliser-scarcity-holds-back-potato-cultivation</link><description>RAJSHAHI, Dec 22: At the very outset of the potato farming season, farmers in the sixteen districts under Rajshahi and Rangpur divisions have become increasingly worried as they are not getting fertilisers as per their needs, causing disruptions in field preparation and early planting.
They allege</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 04:26:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rights groups warn of shrinking democratic space in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rights-groups-warn-of-shrinking-democratic-space-in-bangladesh</link><description>Global human rights organisations have expressed concern that the targeting of politicians, activists, major media outlets and cultural institutions in Bangladesh, amid heightened political tensions ahead of the 2026 national election, signals a troubling erosion of the rule of law and a shrinking</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 04:41:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cyberattack disrupts France's postal service and banking during Christmas rush</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/cyberattack-disrupts-frances-postal-service-and-banking-during-christmas-rush</link><description>With just three days to go before Christmas, a cyberattack knocked France’s national postal service offline Monday, blocking and delaying package deliveries and online payments.
The timing was miserable for millions of people at the height of the Christmas season, as frazzled postal workers</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 04:56:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Singapore to raise age limit for first-time blood donors to 65</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/singapore-to-raise-age-limit-for-first-time-blood-donors-to-65</link><description>Singapore will raise the upper age limit for first-time blood donors to 65 from 60, effective Jan. 2 next year, the Health Sciences Authority (HSA) said.
Under the new rules, first-time donors will be allowed to give blood up to one day before their 66th birthday, while repeat donors may continue</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 05:11:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fire at high-rise building in Babubazar under control</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fire-at-high-rise-building-in-babubazar-under-control</link><description>A fire that broke out early this morning at Haji Tower, a 14-storey commercial cum residential building in the Babubazar area of Armanitola in Old Dhaka, was brought under control.
Nine firefighting units rushed to the scene within five minutes after the fire originated on the sixth floor of the b</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 05:26:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump says US needs Greenland for security</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-says-us-needs-greenland-for-security</link><description>US President Donald Trump reasserted on Monday that the United States needs Greenland for its national security and said a special envoy he appointed to the Arctic island would "lead the charge."
Trump named Louisiana Governor Jeff Landry on Sunday as his special envoy to Greenland, drawing renewe</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 05:41:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>If you don’t work properly, I lose sleep: CEC to election officials</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/if-you-dont-work-properly-i-lose-sleep-cec-to-election-officials</link><description>Chief Election Commissioner AMM Nasir Uddin has directed field administration officials, including returning officers, to carry out their duties strictly in line with the law and election regulations ahead of the 13th parliamentary elections and referendum.
He urged officials to perform their duti</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 06:14:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ten houses gutted in Gazipur fire</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/ten-houses-gutted-in-gazipur-fire</link><description>At least ten houses were gutted in a fire that broke out at Abdar village in Sreepur upazila of Gazipur district on Tuesday.
Md Nurul Karim, inspector of Sreepur Fire Service and Civil Defence, said the fire broke out at a tin-shed house in the morning and engulfed the adjoining houses, reports UN</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 06:29:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Body of abducted businessman found after six hours</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/body-of-abducted-businessman-found-after-six-hours</link><description>A businessman who was abducted at gunpoint from his showroom in Dupchanchia upazila of Bogura was found dead about six hours later, police said.
The deceased was identified as Pintu Akand, 35, a resident of Lohachura village in Raninagar upazila of Naogaon district.
He was the owner of a ‘L</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 06:44:02 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>