<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 10:28:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Govt plans to expand advanced laparoscopic surgery to district level</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/govt-plans-to-expand-advanced-laparoscopic-surgery-to-district-level</link><description>Despite the advent of expensive robotic surgery, laparoscopic and minimally invasive procedures done without opening the abdomen are highly popular in urological treatment.
The government has undertaken a plan to deliver these advanced, affordable services to people’s doorsteps across the co</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 06:15:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh's PMI rises by 0.2 points in December</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/bangladeshs-pmi-rises-by-02-points-in-december</link><description>Bangladesh’s overall Purchasing Managers’ Index (PMI) rose slightly in December, indicating a faster pace of economic expansion, driven mainly by continued growth in agriculture, manufacturing and services, according to the latest PMI report.
PMI increased by 0.2 points in December fro</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 06:30:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nepal city under curfew following Mosque vandalism</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/southern-nepal-border-city-under-curfew-following-mosque-vandalism</link><description>A curfew was imposed on a key border city in southern Nepal after Hindu and Muslim groups began protesting against each other following the vandalism of a mosque over the weekend, officials said Tuesday.
The curfew orders issued by the Parsa District Administration said that no one will be allowed</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 06:45:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Asked Xi to play a mediating role on North Korea</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/asked-xi-to-play-a-mediating-role-on-north-korea</link><description>South Korean President Lee Jae Myung said on Wednesday that much progress had been made in restoring trust with Beijing, and that he had asked Chinese President Xi Jinping to play a role in mediating Seoul's efforts to engage North Korea.
Lee, who held talks with Xi this week, said the Chinese lea</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 07:00:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ongoing cold wave to persist for three to four more days: Met office</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/ongoing-cold-wave-to-persist-for-three-to-four-more-days-met-office</link><description>The current cold wave sweeping parts of the country will continue for three to four more days until January 11, according to the Bangladesh Meteorological Department.
According to the Met Office’s regular bulletin, a mild to moderate cold wave is sweeping over Rajshahi, Rangpur, Khulna and B</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 07:15:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh receives first US corn shipment since 2018</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladesh-receives-first-us-corn-shipment-since-2018</link><description>Bangladesh has received its first consignment of corn from the United States since 2018.
The process of unloading the shipment started at 11:20 am on Wednesday at a jetty on the Karnaphuli River in Chattogram, near the Chittagong Port Authority’s water transport licensing office.
An event m</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 07:30:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India’s top court denies bail to 2 Muslim activists after 5 years in jail without trial</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/indias-top-court-denies-bail-to-2-muslim-activists-after-5-years-in-jail-without-trial</link><description>India’s Supreme Court on Monday denied bail to two Muslim student activists who have spent years in detention without trial over a conspiracy case linked to one of the country’s deadliest outbreaks of religious violence.
Umar Khalid and Sharjeel Imam were arrested five years ago under</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 08:30:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Exploring Bangladesh's 'overlooked' historical sites</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/others/exploring-bangladeshs-overlooked-historical-sites</link><description>It is not necessarily the case that Bangladesh's history will fade away in dramatic failure. More often, it fades quietly. The urban and rural areas are scattered with historical sites left standing but not maintained. These sites characterise the stratification of the country's history: colonialis</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 08:31:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>197 appeals filed so far against nomination decisions</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/197-appeals-filed-so-far-against-nomination-decisions</link><description>A total of 197 appeals have been filed with the Election Commission (EC) so far against returning officers’ decisions on the acceptance and rejection of nomination papers for the upcoming 13th Jatiya Sangsad election, officials said today (Wednesday).
On the third day, the filing of appeals</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 08:46:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rampal power plant tops national electricity generation for second month</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rampal-power-plant-tops-national-electricity-generation-for-second-month</link><description>Rampal Maitree Super Thermal Power Plant has secured the top position in electricity generation in December, the second consecutive month, according to a press release issued by the plant authorities.
The Bangladesh-India joint venture power plant generated 640 million units of electricity in Dece</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 09:01:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Are environmental crimes acknowledged enough?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/are-environmental-crimes-acknowledged-enough</link><description>When we think of crime, we mostly picture handcuffs, courtrooms, and crime scenes splashed with police tape. Rarely do we imagine a river slowly turning black, a forest vanishing overnight, or children breathing toxic air as victims of crime. Think about something- when a m</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 09:16:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BCB rebuffs reports of ICC ultimatum over T20 WC matches in India</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/bcb-rebuffs-reports-of-icc-ultimatum-over-t20-wc-matches-in-india</link><description>The Bangladesh Cricket Board (BCB) has rejected reports that it was issued an ultimatum by the International Cricket Council (ICC) over the upcoming T20 World Cup, calling the claims "false and baseless".
Media reports had suggested the ICC told Bangladesh it must travel to India for the tournamen</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 09:31:02 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>