<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 22:36:52 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Falgun: Time for rebellion and love</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/falgun-time-for-rebellion-and-love</link><description>Spring, Basanta, starts today in Bangladesh as winter recedes, leaving a modest touch of Nature, reminding poet Subhash Mukhopadhyay's famous stanzas: "Phool Phutuk, Na Phutuk/Aj Bosonto" ( It is spring today, no matter if flowers bloom or not). In the urban life, it requires calendar to know the c</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 17:39:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The ups and downs of gold price</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/the-ups-and-downs-of-gold-price</link><description>Why is the price of gold swinging so sharply in Bangladesh? The most common explanation is both simple and unsatisfying. Prices move because the global market moves. Since Bangladesh neither sets nor significantly influences international prices, its domestic market ends up following what happens a</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 17:54:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP pledges to fulfil people’s mandate: Dr Moyeen Khan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-pledges-to-fulfil-peoples-mandate-dr-moyeen-khan</link><description>BNP Standing Committee Member and newly elected MP from Narsingdi-2 Palash constituency, Dr. Abdul Moyeen Khan, on Friday pledged to fulfil the responsibilities entrusted to his party by the people over the next five years.
Speaking to journalists after visiting his parents’ graves in his na</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 18:09:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A new dawn of hope breaks over Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/a-new-dawn-of-hope-breaks-over-bangladesh</link><description>The people of Bangladesh, who practically remained disenfranchised for more than one and a half decades under the ruthlessly autocratic regime of Sheikh Hasina, could finally cast their ballots last Thursday (February 12, 2026) to elect the 13th Jatiya Sangsad (legislature). Notably, Sheikh Hasina</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 18:24:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat warns of street protests over 'rigged' polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-warns-of-street-protests-over-rigged-polls</link><description>Jamaat-e-Islami chief Shafiqur Rahman has threatened to take to the streets if steps are not taken immediately to address allegations of vote rigging and stop post-election attacks on party activists.
He spoke at a press conference on Friday night after an hour-long meeting with leaders of the 11-</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 18:39:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP set to form govt with absolute majority in parliament</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-set-to-form-govt-with-absolute-majority-in-parliament</link><description>Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) begins spadework to form the government after securing a commanding two-thirds majority in a general election widely seen as a turning point in the country's turbulent political history.



Official results announced on Friday showed the BNP won 209 of the 297</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 18:54:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>MFS, internet banking services back to normal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/mfs-internet-banking-services-back-to-normal</link><description>Mobile Financial Services (MFS) such as bKash, Nagad, and Rocket, along with internet banking platforms, have resumed full operations across Bangladesh starting on Friday.
The lifting of restrictions follows 96 hours of limited service aimed at preventing the misuse of funds during the 13th Nation</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 19:09:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Global leaders greet Tarique Rahman on BNP's victory</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/global-leaders-greet-tarique-rahman-on-bnps-victory</link><description>Global leaders and diplomatic missions stationed in Dhaka have been quick to congratulate Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) Chairman Tarique Rahman on his party’s significant election victory and are signalling a willingness to work closely with Bangladesh under his leadership.
India, China</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 19:24:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Post-election violence: Youth beated to death in Munshiganj</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/post-election-violence-youth-beated-to-death-in-munshiganj</link><description>A man was killed and 12 others injured in post-election violence in Char Abdullah village in Munshiganj Sadar on Friday.
The deceased Jashim Uddin, 30, was a supporter of independent candidate Mohammad Mohiuddin, who contested the election with the football symbol after being denied the BNP nomina</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 19:39:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>After Gen Z uprising, Bangladesh vote shows limits of youth power: Reuters</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/after-gen-z-uprising-bangladesh-vote-shows-limits-of-youth-power-reuters</link><description>In an election triggered by a Gen Z–led uprising in Bangladesh, a youth-driven party secured only six seats in the 300-member parliament, showing the challenge of turning street momentum into votes.
When it came to it, results showed on Friday that voters overwhelmingly chose the long-establ</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 19:54:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nine-year-old boy beaten to death over betel nut theft</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nine-year-old-boy-beaten-to-death-over-betel-nut-theft</link><description>A nine-year-old boy was beaten to death over allegations of stealing betel nuts in Haluaghat in Mymensingh on Friday afternoon.
The victim, Imon Mia, was the son of Dulal Mia of Bausha village in Swadeshi Union.
According to police and local sources, Imon had allegedly stolen betel nuts from his</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 20:55:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>T20 World Cup: USA beat Netherlands by 93 runs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/cricket/t20-world-cup-usa-beat-netherlands-by-93-runs</link><description>The United States thrashed Netherlands by 93 runs in their Group A encounter on Friday to claim their first victory at the 2026 Twenty20 World Cup, thanks to Saiteja Mukkamalla's knock of 79 and Harmeet Singh's devastating four-wicket haul.
With the victory, the US moved up to third in the group b</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 21:59:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>