<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 17:59:41 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>State ministers Habibur, Rajib assigned portfolios in road transport, rail, shipping</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/state-ministers-habibur-rajib-assigned-portfolios-in-road-transport-rail-shipping</link><description>The portfolios of two state ministers assigned to the ministries of road transport and bridges, railways, and shipping have been allocated.
Among them, Habibur Rashid will oversee the Road Transport and Highways Division and the Ministry of Railways, bdnews24.com reports. 
Md Rajib Ahsan wil</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 14:11:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BRAC Bank brings exclusive offers at more than 1,400 outlets this Eid</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/brac-bank-brings-exclusive-offers-at-more-than-1400-outlets-this-eid</link><description>BRAC Bankis enhancing the Ramadan and Eid-ul-Fitr experience with savings of up to 50 per cent at more than 1,400 partner outletsnationwide, enabling customers to celebrate with greater flexibility, confidence and value.
From premium Iftar experiences at leading five-star hotels to attractive airf</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 14:26:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mitsui &amp; Co. Asia Pacific signs strategic partnership with ACI Logistics (Shwapno)</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/mitsui-co-asia-pacific-signs-strategic-partnership-with-aci-logistics-shwapno</link><description>Mitsui &amp; Co., Ltd. ("Mitsui"), one of Japan’s leading global trading and investment companies, has agreed to partner with ACI Logistics Limited (ACIL) by providing a foreign currency-denominated convertible loan to ACIL, in accordance with the relevant regulatory approvals through its Singapo</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 14:41:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>PM to confer Ekushey Padak 2026 tomorrow</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/pm-to-confer-ekushey-padak-2026-tomorrow</link><description>Prime Minister Tarique Rahman is expected to distribute Ekushey Padak 2026 at a ceremony at Osmani Memorial Auditorium here at 11 am tomorrow.
 Earlier, the government announced the names of nine eminent citizens and one music band for the country's second-highest civilian award Ekushey Padak</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 14:56:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rajshahi DIG issues ‘special order’ for AL leaders</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/rajshahi-dig-issues-special-order-for-al-leaders</link><description>The deputy inspector general (DIG) of Rajshahi Range has ordered police to show Awami League leaders and activists who are “capable of reorganising the party” after securing bail as “arrested” in other cases.
DIG Mohammad Shahjahan issued the “special” directive</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 15:11:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Man shot dead in public after ‘tiff’ at Raozan market</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/man-shot-dead-in-public-after-tiff-at-raozan-market</link><description>An elderly man has been shot dead in public over a “tiff” at a market in Chattogram’s Raozan.
The incident occurred at Oli Mia’s Hat in the Purba Guzra Union around 7:15pm on Wednesday, according to police.</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 15:26:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh to examine trade deal with US: Commerce minister</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladesh-to-examine-trade-deal-with-us-commerce-minister</link><description>Commerce Minister Khandaker Abdul Muktadir has said Bangladesh will carefully weigh the potential benefits and drawbacks before deciding whether to pursue a trade agreement with the United States.
Speaking to reporters on Wednesday after a meeting with business leaders, he said it was “too e</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 15:41:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh Bank shuffles top officials following leadership change</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/bangladesh-bank-shuffles-top-officials-following-leadership-change</link><description>Bangladesh Bank has announced the immediate transfer and reassignment of five senior officials in the wake of Wednesday’s leadership change, according to an official directive.
The central bank’s official directive, signed by Director (HRD-1) Md Tarikul Islam, shuffled four directors a</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 16:42:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Parliament should impeach President Shahabuddin, says Nahid</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/parliament-should-impeach-president-shahabuddin-says-opposition-leader-nahid</link><description>Opposition Chief Whip Nahid Islam has demanded the impeachment and arrest of President Mohammed Shahabuddin.
He made the remarks on Wednesday afternoon after visiting the graves of those killed in the BDR mutiny at the Banani Military Graveyard on National Martyred Army Day.
Nahid, also National</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 16:59:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ekushey Book Fair 2026: Dhaka’s literary heartbeat returns</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/after-delays-and-disputes-ekushey-book-fair-opens-thursday-with-bangla-academy-awards</link><description>Bookworms are ready to welcome back the beloved literary festival as the Amar Ekushey Book Fair 2026 opens Thursday afternoon after repeated postponements.
Publishers rush to complete their stalls, while Bangla Academy prepares to host the official ceremony that will mark the start of a month-long</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 17:14:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DGFI gets a battle-tested chief</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/dgfi-gets-a-battle-tested-chief</link><description>Whenever a powerful appointment drops in Bangladesh, one question pops up like clockwork: Was this about merit or was this about quota?
The appointment of Major General Kaiser Rashid as the Director General of Directorate General of Forces Intelligence (DGFI) lands squarely in that debate. But a l</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 17:29:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Action taken over Barishal courtroom chaos: SC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/action-taken-over-barishal-courtroom-chaos-sc</link><description>The Supreme Court has said that necessary legal action has been taken over the disorderly incident during a session at the Barishal Additional Chief Metropolitan Court on Tuesday.
In a statement on Wednesday, the Appellate Division of the Supreme Court said that on February 24, a group of lawyers</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 17:44:24 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>