<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 11:37:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>No approval for artificial hilsa farming: govt</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-rules-out-artificial-hilsa-farming-without-policy-approval</link><description>The interim government has not granted approval for hilsa cultivation through artificial or controlled means, according to the Ministry of Fisheries and Livestock.
The ministry issued a press release on Monday clarifying that no individual or organisation has received permission to farm hilsa or c</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 09:59:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>LPG, autogas prices raised for February</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/lpg-autogas-prices-raised-for-february</link><description>The Bangladesh Energy Regulatory Commission (BERC) has announced new retail prices for liquefied petroleum gas (LPG), raising the cost of a 12-kg cylinder by Tk 50 for February.
According to the new pricing, the retail price of a 12-kg LPG cylinder has been fixed at Tk 1,356, up from Tk 1,306. The</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 10:14:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Travel ban on four close aides of PK Haldar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/travel-ban-on-four-close-aides-of-pk-haldar</link><description>A Dhaka court on Monday imposed a travel ban on four close aides of former managing director of NRB Global Bank and Reliance Finance Limited, Prashanta Kumar Haldar alias PK Haldar.
The restrained individuals are Mahbubul Haque, chairman of International Leasing and Financial Services Limited; Man</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 09:03:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IMF chief says global inflation to fall, trade integration is needed</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/global/imf-chief-says-global-inflation-to-fall-trade-integration-is-needed</link><description>Global inflation is expected to fall to 3.8 per cent this year and to 3.4 per cent in 2027, helped by softer demand and lower energy prices, the IMF chief said on Monday.
Managing Director Kristalina Georgieva said in a speech in the Annual Arab Fiscal Forum in Dubai that global growth has held up</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 09:18:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>SSC form fill-up reopened with penalty</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/dhaka-board-reopens-ssc-form-fill-up-window-with-late-fee</link><description>The Board of Intermediate and Secondary Education, Dhaka is allowing students to submit forms for this year’s Secondary School Certificate (SSC) examinations for an extended period.
Students under this board can now complete the registration process and pay the required fees with a late pena</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 09:33:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Man killed in clash over land dispute in Narail</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/man-killed-in-clash-over-land-dispute-in-narail</link><description>A 36-year-old man was killed, and two others were injured in a clash between two groups of villagers over a land dispute at Beledanga village in Naragati upazila of Narail district on Monday.
The deceased was identified as Yusuf Molla, 36, son of Moniruzzaman Molla of Beledanga village in the upaz</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 09:48:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>China criticizes decision to award a Grammy to the Dalai Lama</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/china-criticizes-decision-to-award-a-grammy-to-the-dalai-lama</link><description>Beijing on Monday criticized the Dalai Lama ’s first Grammy win, describing the music industry award for an audiobook, narration and storytelling as “a tool for anti-China political manipulation.”
The Tibetan Buddhist spiritual leader, who lives in exile in India, took the award</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 10:03:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Extra forces to guard risky polling centres: Home Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/extra-forces-drones-cctv-to-guard-risky-polling-centres-home-adviser</link><description>The government will deploy additional security forces along with drones, CCTV cameras and dog squads, at sensitive polling centres to ensure a peaceful national election, Home Adviser Lieutenant General (retd) Jahangir Alam Chowdhury said on Monday.
Body-worn cameras and round-the-clock monitoring</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 10:18:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pakistani security forces hunt militants behind weekend attacks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/pakistani-security-forces-hunt-militants-behind-weekend-attacks</link><description>Pakistani soldiers were hunting down separatist militants on Monday who stormed schools, banks, and security installations, killing nearly 50 people, in a series of coordinated attacks across southwestern Balochistan province, the military said.
The attacks at the weekend brought Pakistan’s</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 10:33:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Zubaida inaugurates ‘free heart camp’ at Korail slum</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/zubaida-inaugurates-free-heart-camp-at-mohakhalis-korail-slum</link><description>Zubaida Rahman, a cardiologist and the wife of BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman, has inaugurated a free heart health camp in the Korail slum area of Dhaka’s Mohakhali on Monday.
The health camp and medicine distribution programme at the Ansar Camp ground was organised by the Doctors’ Associ</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 10:48:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India-Bangladesh ties should move beyond Sheikh Hasina: BNP’s Fakhrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/india-bangladesh-ties-should-move-beyond-sheikh-hasina-bnps-fakhrul</link><description>Relations between India and Bangladesh can and should move beyond the issue of Sheikh Hasina, BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir has told Indian news magazine The Week, reports bdnews24.com.
In response to a question on the ousted prime minister during an interview published onlin</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 11:03:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A section of publishers calls for Ekushey Book Fair to be held after Eid-ul-Fitr</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/a-section-of-publishers-calls-for-ekushey-book-fair-to-be-held-after-eid-ul-fitr</link><description>A section of publishers on Monday urged authorities to reschedule the Amar Ekushey Book Fair 2026 by February 5 until after Eid-ul-Fitr, warning that staging the country’s largest literary event during Ramadan could deal a severe blow to Bangladesh’s already struggling creative publishi</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 11:18:29 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>