<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 07:16:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nine years on, Smart NID yet to reach all Bangladeshis</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nine-years-on-smart-nid-yet-to-reach-all-bangladeshis</link><description>Nine years after Bangladesh launched the Smart National Identity Card project, the Election Commission (EC) is still far from delivering cards to all citizens.
When the Smart NID distribution began, the target was to reach every citizen within just over a year. Nearly eight years after that deadli</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 04:53:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The first supermoon of the year is approaching. Here's what to know</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/the-first-supermoon-of-the-year-is-approaching-heres-what-to-know</link><description>The moon will appear slightly larger and brighter Monday night during what's known as a supermoon.
October's supermoon is the first of three this year. It happens when a full moon is closer to Earth in its orbit. That makes the moon look up to 14% bigger and 30% brighter than the faintest moon of</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 05:08:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka’s air continues to be ‘moderate’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dhakas-air-continues-to-be-moderate-1</link><description>Dhaka has ranked 31st on the list of cities with the worst air quality, with an AQI score of 66 at 9:30 am Sunday morning (October 5, 2025).
Dhaka's air was classified as 'moderate,' referring to a light health threat, according to the AQI index. Such air quality has continued for the past few day</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 05:38:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Activists allege Greta Thunberg mistreated as flotilla detainees arrive in Turkey</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/activists-allege-greta-thunberg-mistreated-as-flotilla-detainees-arrive-in-turkey</link><description>Some 137 activists detained by Israel for taking part in a flotilla seeking to deliver aid to Gaza arrived in Turkey on Saturday after being deported, with two alleging that Swedish campaigner Greta Thunberg was mistreated during her detention.
Israel did not immediately comment on the new allegat</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 05:00:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Indonesia school collapse death toll rises to 36, search for bodies continues</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/indonesia-school-collapse-death-toll-rises-to-36-search-for-bodies-continues</link><description>The number of students confirmed dead after the collapse of an Islamic boarding school building in Indonesia rose to 36, from 16 a day earlier, the country's disaster mitigation agency said on Sunday.
Efforts continued for a seventh day to search for the bodies of 27 students still declared miss</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 05:30:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh, US officials discuss regional political, security issues</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-us-officials-discuss-regional-political-security-issues</link><description>National Security Adviser and High Representative for the Rohingya issue Dr Khalilur Rahman has met senior US officials in Washington and discussed regional political and security issues.
Bangladesh's new Ambassador to the United States, Tareq M Ariful Islam, was present at the separate meetings,</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 05:45:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Heavy rains kill at least 22 in Nepal, block roads</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/heavy-rains-kill-at-least-22-in-nepal-block-roads</link><description>Heavy rains triggered landslides and flash floods, blocking roads, washing away bridges and killing at least 22 people in the last 36 hours in Nepal, officials said on Sunday.
Eighteen people were killed in separate landslides in the Ilam district in the east bordering India, police spokesperson B</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 06:00:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fire guts 19 shops in Khagrachhari’s Guimara</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/fire-guts-19-shops-in-khagrachharis-guimara</link><description>At least 19 shops have been destroyed after a fire ripped through a market in Khagrachhari’s Guimara Upazila.
The fire broke out around 1:45 am on Sunday at the "Hajji Ismail Market" in the Jaliapara area, according to Md Enamul Haque Chowdhury, chief of Guimara Police Station.
Witnesses sa</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 06:30:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Indices up in early trading at Dhaka, Chattogram bourses</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/indices-up-in-early-trading-at-dhaka-chattogram-bourses</link><description>Indices at both the Dhaka and Chattogram stock exchanges witnessed an upward trend in the first hour of trading on Sunday, the first working day of the week, as most companies saw gains in their share prices.
At the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE), the benchmark DSEX index rose by 43 points, while the</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 06:45:30 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>