<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 17:34:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>NCC Bank launches Automated Environmental and Social Risk Management System</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ncc-bank-launches-automated-environmental-and-social-risk-management-system</link><description>NCC Bank has officially launched an advanced Automated Environmental and Social Risk Management (ESRM) system in line with its testament to eco-friendly financing and sustainable banking.
This technology-driven platform will embark an innovative shift in the bank's credit process, making Environme</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 14:59:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>MTB Foundation commemorates International Day of Education 2026</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/mtb-foundation-commemorates-international-day-of-education-2026</link><description>To commemorate the International Day of Education 2026, MTB Foundation celebrated this year's theme ‘The Power of Youth in Co-Creating Education’ by distributing free bicycles to the female underprivileged meritorious students of different schools in Mathbaria, Barishal under its &amp;lsquo</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 15:14:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Home Adviser Jahangir Alam pledges credible polls on Feb 12</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/home-adviser-jahangir-alam-pledges-credible-polls-on-feb-12</link><description>Home Affairs Adviser Lt Gen (retd) Md Jahangir Alam Chowdhury on Wednesday reaffirmed that all stakeholders are committed to ensuring a transparent, fair, and widely accepted election.
“There is no political bias among those involved in the election. There is no such thing as an Awami League</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 15:29:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique to launch 3-day northern region electioneering Thursday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-to-launch-3-day-northern-region-electioneering-thursday</link><description>BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman will kick off a three-day election campaign in the northern region starting on Thursday, aiming to rally support ahead of the polls.
Tarique will leave for Rajshahi at noon by air to formally launch the tour, BNP Media Cell member Sayrul Kabir Khan said on Wednesday.
H</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 15:44:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BGB to deploy 38 platoons in Dhaka sector ahead of national election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bgb-to-deploy-38-platoons-in-dhaka-sector-ahead-of-national-election</link><description>Border Guard Bangladesh (BGB) will deploy 38 platoons across 14 parliamentary constituencies under Dhaka Battalion (5 BGB) to maintain law and order, safeguard voters’ rights and ensure a peaceful environment during the upcoming national election.
According to BGB headquarters sources, 11 pl</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 15:59:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Party support, not lineage, drew me back to Bangladesh’, Tarique tells Time Magazine</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/party-support-not-lineage-drew-me-back-to-bangladesh-tarique-tells-time-magazine</link><description>BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman has said he is the right person to heal Bangladesh’s divisions, insisting his return is driven by party supporters rather than family lineage.
“It’s not because I’m the son of my father and mother,” he told the Time Magazine in his first ex</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 16:14:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chinese fossils show marine animals thriving half a billion years ago</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/chinese-fossils-show-marine-animals-thriving-half-a-billion-years-ago</link><description>Scientists have unearthed in southern China fossils of a multitude of marine creatures dating to more than a half billion years ago, showing a deep-water ecosystem thriving in the aftermath of the first mass extinction of the animal world.
The Cambrian Period fossils, about 512 million years old,</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 16:08:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC estimates Tk 31 billion cost for Feb-12 election, referendum</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-estimates-tk-31-billion-cost-for-feb-12-election-referendum</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has estimated the overall expenditures for the upcoming referendum and the 13th national parliamentary election at some Tk 31 billion.
The Commission on Wednesday approved the budget, estimating the total cost of Tk 31 billion to conduct the referendum and general elec</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 16:23:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Voting in Bangladesh to be held through 42,779 polling stations</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/voting-in-bangladesh-to-be-held-through-42779-polling-stations</link><description>The balloting will be held through 42,779 polling stations in the 300 constituencies throughout the country in the referendum and national election scheduled for February 12 next.
“The final number of polling stations is 42,779 and that of polling booths is 247,482 in the referendum and 13th</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 16:38:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Why Phillips Curve fails in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/why-phillips-curve-fails-in-bangladesh</link><description>In simple terms, the Phillips Curve proposes a trade-off: when an economy grows rapidly and jobs become plentiful, prices tend to rise faster; when unemployment is high, inflation tends to slow. In other words, a country may tolerate some inflation to achieve more employment or accept higher unempl</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 16:53:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>When laws fail to protect children</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/when-laws-fail-to-protect-children</link><description>That the corporal punishment of children is banned is nothing new. But the fact is there are few schools or madrasahs countrywide that are following this rule. The issue has once again come into focus and triggered public outrage after two recent incidents of violence against children surfaced on s</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 17:08:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tradable savings certificate on bond market</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/tradable-savings-certificate-on-bond-market</link><description>The liquidity crisis in banks stemming mainly from non-performing loans (NPLs) has long stoked the compulsion of exploring alternative sources of sustainable fund. Since foreign investment is hard to come by, the search for such alternative sources has become even more compelling. Now the Banglades</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 17:23:40 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>