<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 10:23:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Physical work unlikely to start despite feasibility study, DPP</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/physical-work-unlikely-to-start-despite-feasibility-study-dpp</link><description>Physical work of electric traction on the rail-track from Narayanganj to Joydebpur is unlikely to start soon despite completion of its feasibility study and preparation of development project proposal (DPP), estimating the cost at Tk 39.33 billion.
Sources said approval of the DPP of the Dhaka-Joy</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 05:23:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DUCSU holds conf’ce with elected reps from 18 halls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ducsu-holds-confce-with-elected-reps-from-18-halls</link><description>The Dhaka University Central Students' Union (DUCSU) organised a special conference with elected representatives from 18 residential halls of the university.
The event was held on Wednesday night at the Nawab Nabab Ali Chowdhury Senate Building on the university campus.
The conference was chaired</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 05:38:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt cracks down on unauthorised interior works in Secretariat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-cracks-down-on-unauthorised-interior-works-in-secretariat</link><description>The government has issued strict directives to curb interior decoration and unauthorised repair works inside the Bangladesh Secretariat in Dhaka, aiming to strengthen fire safety and prevent future accidents, sources said.
The move follows an investigation that found unregulated "beautification" a</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 05:53:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Three pedestrians die as quake causes railing collapse in Bangshal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/three-pedestrians-die-as-quake-causes-railing-collapse-in-bangshal</link><description>Three pedestrians have been killed after an earthquake caused a railing to collapse from a five-storey building on KP Ghosh Street in Dhaka’s Bangshal.
Rafiqul Islam, chief of Bangshal Police Station, said: “A railing from a five-storey building collapsed and fell amid the earthquake.&amp;</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 06:08:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Australia launches jt campaign to combat visa fraud</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/australia-launches-jt-campaign-to-combat-visa-fraud</link><description>Australia has joined its international partners in a coordinated campaign to raise awareness about visa scams as part of International Fraud Awareness Week, warning that fraudulent agents are increasingly targeting would-be migrants across South Asia, said a spokesman of the Australian High Commiss</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 06:23:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Commoners facing the brunt of winter vegetable price spiral</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/commoners-facing-the-brunt-of-winter-vegetable-price-spiral</link><description>Unseasonal early-November rainfall has pushed up winter vegetable prices across Rajshahi, and Sylhet districts piling pressure on consumers already battling against the rising living costs.
Our Rajshahi correspondent reports: Untimely downpour in early-November caused extensive damage to winter ve</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 06:38:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gaibandha farmer makes cattle feed out of banana stems</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/gaibandha-farmer-makes-cattle-feed-out-of-banana-stems</link><description>GAIBANDHA, Nov 20: A farmer of remote Hazirhat in Sundarganj has been using banana plant's stems, or portions forming the trunk-like structure, to produce a new processed fodder item for cattle, and addressing feed shortage in the area.
The fodder from banana stalks are as cost effective as it is</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 06:53:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Three DU students injured after leaping from hall buildings amid quake panic</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/three-du-students-injured-after-leaping-from-hall-buildings-amid-quake-panic</link><description>Three students of Dhaka University have been injured after they leapt from the three-storey Hajji Muhammad Mohsin Hall and the four-storey Muktijoddha Ziaur Rahman Hall in panic as a strong quake rattled Bangladesh on Friday.
A student from Muktijoddha Ziaur Rahman Hall is believed to have broken</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 07:08:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>FEAB Foundation holds seminar on food and agribusiness development, innovation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/feab-foundation-holds-seminar-on-food-and-agribusiness-development-innovation</link><description>The FEAB Foundation organised its 7th International Seminar on Thursday (November 20) at the International Convention City Bashundhara (ICCB) in Dhaka to promote food and agribusiness development, safe food production, and technology-driven innovation. The event coincided with the opening of the 13</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 08:30:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Earthquake: Infant dies as wall collapses in Narayanganj</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/earthquake-infant-dies-as-wall-collapses-in-narayanganj</link><description>A 10-month-old infant has been killed after a wall collapsed in a building in Narayanganj’s Rupganj during Friday’s earthquake.
Tariqul Islam, chief of Rupganj Police Station, said two other people, including the child’s mother, have been injured in the incident in the Golakandai</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 09:00:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt closely monitoring earthquake aftermath in Bangladesh: Chief adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-closely-monitoring-earthquake-aftermath-in-bangladesh-chief-adviser</link><description>Chief Adviser Prof Muhammad Yunus has said the government is aware of public concern and panic caused by the earthquake that jolted Dhaka and other parts of Bangladesh on Friday morning.
In a statement, the Chief Adviser said the situation is being closely monitored, and all relevant departments h</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 09:15:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Vietnam leads ASEAN in consumer optimism: UOB</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/global/vietnam-leads-asean-in-consumer-optimism-uob</link><description>Vietnam continues to lead the Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN) in consumer optimism, supported by a positive economic outlook and confidence in personal finances, Vietnam News Agency reported Friday, citing a study by Singapore-based United Overseas Bank (UOB).
Vietnam posted the hig</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 09:30:47 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>