<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 12:48:44 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Chief advisor’s address ‘violated’ July Charter: Salahuddin</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/chief-advisors-address-violated-july-charter-salahuddin</link><description>Senior BNP leader Salahuddin Ahmed has alleged that Chief Advisor Muhammad Yunus “violated” the July National Charter in his televised address to the nation on Thursday.
“In his speech, the chief advisor breached the signed July National Charter,” the Standing Committee mem</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 10:35:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>WTO affirms support for Bangladesh’s trade transition post-LDC graduation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/wto-affirms-support-for-bangladeshs-trade-transition-post-ldc-graduation</link><description>The World Trade Organization (WTO), a Geneva based intergovernmental organization that regulates and facilitates international trade, has affirmed its commitment to providing robust support for Bangladesh as the nation approaches its scheduled graduation from Least Developed Country (LDC) status in</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 10:50:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BSEC issues gazette on ‘Mutual Fund Regulations 2025’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bsec-issues-gazette-on-mutual-fund-regulations-2025</link><description>The Bangladesh Securities and Exchange Commission (BSEC), the country’s capital market regulator, has issued a gazette on ‘Bangladesh Securities and Exchange Commission (Mutual Fund) Regulations 2025’.
The new regulation became effective immediately upon its publication, said a p</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 11:05:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Inspirational seminar on peace and nonviolence held at ISU</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/inspirational-seminar-on-peace-and-nonviolence-held-at-isu</link><description>An inspiring seminar titled “Peace and Nonviolence: Inspiring Positive Change in Individuals and Society” was held at International Standard University (ISU) on Wednesday afternoon.
The event aimed to promote the values of peace, empathy, and nonviolence as essential tools for building</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 11:20:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC to sit with 12 more political parties on Sunday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-to-sit-with-12-more-political-parties-on-sunday</link><description>The Election Commission will sit with 12 more political parties on Sunday as part of its ongoing electoral dialogue ahead of the next general election.
The Commission will exchange views with six parties in the morning session and with another six parties in the afternoon session on November 16, s</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 10:37:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC decision after reviewing Yunus’s plan for simultaneous election, referendum</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-decision-after-reviewing-yunuss-plan-for-simultaneous-election-referendum</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) is going to hold internal discussions before forming an opinion on the proposal to hold the next parliamentary election and the referendum on implementing the July Charter on the same day in February
On Thursday, Chief Election Commissioner (CEC) AMM Nasir Uddin made t</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 10:52:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>July Charter falls short of public hopes Jamaat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/july-charter-implementation-decision-betrays-peoples-aspirations-says-jamaat</link><description>The interim government’s decision to hold the referendum on the July National Charter on the same day as the national parliamentary election “does not meet the people’s aspirations”, says Jamaat-e-Islami.
Secretary General Mia Golam Porwar gave the instant reaction at 3:30p</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 11:07:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IPDC and BRAC University partner on affordable, sustainable housing initiative</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ipdc-and-brac-university-partner-on-affordable-sustainable-housing-initiative</link><description>As part of its ongoing CSR and sustainability commitments, IPDC Finance PLC, the first non-bank financial institution (NBFI) in Bangladesh, has partnered with the School of Architecture and Design, BRAC University, to launch the “Affordable &amp; Sustainable Housing Design Project”
This jo</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 11:22:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Government decides to exempt excise duty on air tickets for 2026 Hajj pilgrims</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/government-decides-to-exempt-excise-duty-on-air-tickets-for-2026-hajj-pilgrims</link><description>The Advisory Council of the interim government, on Thursday, approved a proposal to exempt excise duty on air tickets for Bangladeshi pilgrims travelling to Saudi Arabia to perform Hajj in 2026, aiming to reduce the overall cost of pilgrimage.
 
According to official sources, the Ministry of</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 11:37:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Woman held in Dhanmondi 32</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/woman-arrested-in-dhanmondi-32-during-awami-league-lockdown</link><description>Police have arrested a woman in Dhanmondi 32 amid the “lockdown” called by the Awami League, whose activities are banned by the interim government.
Masud Alam, deputy commissioner of Dhaka Metropolitan Police’s Ramna Division, said on Thursday afternoon that the woman, identified</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 11:52:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Germany envoy terms Bangladesh’s 2026 polls ‘world’s largest democratic election’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/germany-envoy-terms-bangladeshs-2026-polls-worlds-largest-democratic-election</link><description>Germany’s ambassador to Bangladesh, Dr Rüdiger Lotz, has expressed optimism that Bangladesh will soon rejoin the ranks of vibrant democracies as it prepares for what he described as “the world’s largest democratic election” in 2026, when more than 127 million citizens a</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 12:07:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>32 ‘petrol bombs’ recovered in Faridpur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/police-have-recovered-32-petrol-bombs-in-abandoned-suitcase-in-faridpur</link><description>Police have recovered 32 petrol bomb-like explosives in a suitcase found abandoned by the highway in Faridpur’s Bhanga.
Bhanga Police Chief Ahsraf Hossain said the explosives were recovered on the Dhaka-Barishal Highway at 1pm on Thursday.
Acting on a tip-off over some preparing to carry ou</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 12:22:27 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>