<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 03:26:26 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Discovering the wonders of Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/discovering-the-wonders-of-bangladesh</link><description>Vacationing is no longer a luxury enjoyed by a select few but an increasingly routine part of contemporary life. That tourism has expanded so rapidly, aided by rising incomes and widespread digital connectivity, indicates required means and mindset of a growing number of people for travel. This tra</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 18:45:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Meeting fertiliser needs of Boro farmers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/meeting-fertiliser-needs-of-boro-farmers</link><description>Chronic shortage of natural gas has been hampering fertiliser production especially at the five urea fertiliser-producing plants operated by the state-owned Bangladesh Chemical Industries Corporation (BCIC). But Boro being the country's major dry season rice crop (January-February its peak planting</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 19:00:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DSEX extends gains riding on banking shares</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/dsex-extends-gains-riding-on-banking-shares</link><description>The benchmark index of the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) closed the first week of the New Year high, extending gains for a third straight week.
The market rally is driven by renewed buying interest in heavyweight banking stocks, as investors grew optimistic about the outlook for political stability a</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 00:15:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rice, veggies, sugar, edible oil get costlier</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/rice-veggies-sugar-edible-oil-get-costlier</link><description>After remaining static for about a month, prices of rice, winter vegetables, sugar and edible oil have increased in the city markets over the past week, adding pressure on household budgets of the commoners.
Prices of almost all winter vegetables rose by Tk 10-20 per kilogramme/piece last week, ev</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 00:30:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt issues two new ordinances to protect biodiversity, wildlife</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/govt-issues-two-new-ordinances-to-protect-biodiversity-wildlife</link><description>The interim government issued two ordinances related to the Ministry of Environment, Forest and Climate Change for the protection of the country's biodiversity and wildlife.
The ordinance, Wildlife (Conservation and Protection) Ordinance, 2026, was published in the form of a gazette on Wednesday o</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 00:45:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Major industrial groups seek Tk 165.5b bailout funds</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/major-industrial-groups-seek-tk-1655b-bailout-funds</link><description>Constrained by stated severe liquidity crunch in the country's industrial sector, eleven conglomerates seek some Tk 165.5 billion in interest-free loans from the government to sustain operations and meet staff-payment obligations, sources say.
The SOS (save our soul) appeal comes from Noman Group,</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 01:00:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Foreign fund flow into Bangladesh corporates falls to $9.80b until Nov</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/foreign-fund-flow-into-bangladesh-corporates-falls-to-980b-until-nov</link><description>Corporate external borrowing drops as persisting economic sluggishness dampens businesses' appetite for funds with the short-term overseas debt stock having declined to $9.80 billion until November.
Officials and money-market analysts see such unrelenting contraction in private-sector foreign debt</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 01:15:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Migratory birds throng Ctg seashore, riverbanks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/migratory-birds-throng-ctg-seashore-riverbanks</link><description>The weather has been chilly in the port-city for the last several days. A number of migratory and guest birds have now gathered in the seashore areas as well as on the banks of rivers including Karnaphuli, Sangu and Halda.
Bird-lovers are going to the areas along the banks of Karnaphuli River to w</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 01:30:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Temp dips to 6.8°C in Panchagarh as cold spell prevails</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/temp-dips-to-68c-in-panchagarh-as-cold-spell-prevails</link><description>The cold wave and dense fog are likely to persist for several more days across the country, according to the Bangladesh Meteorological Department (BMD).
The overall weather situation would remain dry with a temporary partly cloudy sky during the next 24 hours, commencing from 9:00am Friday, said t</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 01:45:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two-day photo exhibition on Khaleda Zia in capital</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/two-day-photo-exhibition-on-khaleda-zia-in-capital</link><description>A two-day photo exhibition focusing on the eventful and struggling life of BNP Chairperson and former prime minister Begum Khaleda Zia began at Zia Udyan in the capital on Friday.Political Biography Book
BNP Standing Committee Member Nazrul Islam Khan inaugurated the exhibition, organised by Bogur</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 02:00:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>12th Commencement Ceremony of AUW today</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/12th-commencement-ceremony-of-auw-today</link><description>The 12th Commencement Ceremony of the Asian University for Women (AUW) will be held at Radisson Blu Hotel in the port-city today (Saturday) with its Chancellor Cherie Blair in the chair. Professor Irene Tracey, Vice Chancellor of the University of Oxford, UK, will attend the function as the speaker</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 02:15:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DU holds int'l conference on Islamic Finance, Banking</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/du-holds-intl-conference-on-islamic-finance-banking</link><description>The Dhaka University (DU) has organised a two-day international conference on Islamic Finance and Banking under the theme 'Islamic Finance for Sustainable Economic Development'.
The event is jointly organised by the DU Department of Finance and the Central Shariah Board for Islamic Banks of Bangla</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 02:30:47 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>