<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 18:32:46 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Investors demand resignation of Finance Adviser, BB Governor over bank merger</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/investors-demand-resignation-of-finance-adviser-bb-governor-over-bank-merger</link><description>Stock market investors under the banner of ‘Bangladesh Pujibazar Oikya Parishad’ on Thursday demanded the resignation of Finance Adviser Dr Salehuddin Ahmed and Bangladesh Bank Governor Dr Ahsan H Mansur, alleging that the recent merger of five Shariah-based banks was decided without co</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 14:22:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shareholders of 5 troubled banks to get compensations: BB</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/shareholders-of-5-troubled-banks-to-get-compensations-bb</link><description>Bangladesh Bank (BB) today (Thursday) said that shareholders of five troubled banks will get compensation under the Bank Resolution Ordinance, 2025 (BRO 2025). “According to Section 40 of the BRO, 2025, if a scheduled bank under resolution is ultimately liquidated, and shareholders suffe</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 14:10:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>United Group brings global recognition to Bangladesh at the Asian Innovation Excellence Awards 2025</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/united-group-brings-global-recognition-to-bangladesh-at-the-asian-innovation-excellence-awards-2025</link><description>United Group has brought global recognition to Bangladesh by winning the “Bangladesh Operational Innovation of the Year - Energy” award at the Asian Innovation Excellence Awards 2025, held at the Marina Bay Sands Expo &amp; Convention Centre, Singapore.
The award recognises United Power Ge</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 14:25:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCP begins nomination form sale</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ncp-begins-nomination-form-sale</link><description>The National Citizen Party (NCP) has started selling nomination forms for aspiring candidates ahead of the 13th national election, with each form priced at Tk 10,000.
Announcing the initiative at a press briefing on Thursday evening, NCP Chief Coordinator Nasiruddin Patwary said that freedom</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 14:40:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Community Bank Bangladesh PLC achieves ISO 27001:2022 Certification</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/community-bank-bangladesh-plc-achieves-iso-270012022-certification</link><description>Community Bank Bangladesh PLC has recently achieved the internationally recognized ISO 27001:2022 certificate. ISO 27001:2022 is the latest iteration of the globally recognized standard for information security management systems (ISMS).
The recertification audit was conducted by Intertek Banglade</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 14:55:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Avenue Sangma shares insights on modern marketing</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/avenue-sangma-shares-insights-on-modern-marketing</link><description>Digital marketing is no longer a niche strategy but the central nervous system for business growth in the 21st century. To understand its evolving landscape, we sat down with Avenue Sangma, a respected voice in the digital marketing sphere as a digital marketer in global space.
In this exclusive i</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 15:10:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>1,681 candidates get job recommendations in 44th BCS</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/1681-candidates-get-job-recommendations-in-44th-bcs</link><description>The Public Service Commission (PSC) has released the supplementary results of the 44th Bangladesh Civil Service (BCS) exams with final nominations for the appointment of a total of 1,681 candidates.
The commission issued a notification releasing the results on Thursday, reports bdnews24.com.
PSC</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 16:16:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP expresses solidarity with Tarek’s hunger strike over his party's registration</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-expresses-solidarity-with-tareks-hunger-strike-over-his-partys-registration</link><description>BNP on Thursday expressed solidarity with Tarek Rahman, who has been observing a hunger strike in front of the Election Commission, demanding registration for his political party.
"The political party he formed definitely deserves registration. And for this just cause, he has been on hunger strike</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 16:31:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>JnUCSU Election:16,365 students enlisted as voter</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jnucsu-election16365-students-enlisted-as-voter</link><description>The Election Commission of Jagannath University (JnU) has published the draft voter list for the Jagannath University Central Students’ Union (JnUCSU) and hall union elections 2025.
The draft was published on Thursday evening on the official JnUCSU election website, reports UNB.
According t</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 16:46:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BGMEA secures special healthcare benefits for members</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bgmea-secures-special-healthcare-benefits-for-members</link><description>The Bangladesh Garment Manufacturers and Exporters Association (BGMEA) has taken a significant step to encourage its members, officials, staff, and their families to seek quality health and diagnostic services domestically instead of traveling abroad for treatment.
To this end, the BGMEA on Thursd</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 17:01:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC registers 66 local election observer organisations</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ec-registers-66-local-election-observer-organisations</link><description>The Election Commission has registered 66 organisations as local election observers as well as identified 16 more firms as eligible for registration as local election observers ahead of the upcoming 13th parliamentary election to be held in early February 2026.
“The 66 organisations have giv</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 17:16:54 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>