<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 06:28:54 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>UN cybercrime treaty to be signed in Hanoi to tackle global offences</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/un-cybercrime-treaty-to-be-signed-in-hanoi-to-tackle-global-offences</link><description>A landmark UN cybercrime treaty, aimed at tackling offences that cost the global economy trillions of dollars annually, is set to be signed in Vietnam's capital Hanoi by around 60 countries over the weekend.
The convention, which will take effect after it is ratified by 40 nations, is expected to</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 04:54:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US sanctions Colombia's president, accuses him of allowing expansion of drug trade</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/us-sanctions-colombias-president-accuses-him-of-allowing-expansion-of-drug-trade</link><description>The US on Friday imposed sanctions on Colombian President Gustavo Petro, as President Donald Trump sharply escalated a feud with Washington's longtime Latin American ally over accusations that Petro has refused to stop the flow of cocaine into the United States.
Tensions between Washington and man</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 05:09:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US to escalate military presence in South America with aircraft carrier group</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/us-to-escalate-military-presence-in-south-america-with-aircraft-carrier-group</link><description>President Donald Trump’s administration escalated a US military buildup in the Caribbean on Friday by announcing the deployment of the Gerald Ford aircraft carrier group to Latin America — a show of force far beyond any past counter-narcotics effort and Washington’s most assertive</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 05:24:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US, China seek to avoid trade war escalation, salvage Trump-Xi meeting in Malaysia talks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/us-china-seek-to-avoid-trade-war-escalation-salvage-trump-xi-meeting-in-malaysia-talks</link><description>Top economic officials from the US and China will face off in Kuala Lumpur on Saturday to try to avert an escalation of their trade war and ensure that a meeting happens next week between US President Donald Trump and Chinese President Xi Jinping.
The talks on the sidelines of the Association of S</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 05:26:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Thailand's Queen Mother Sirikit, influential style icon, dies at 93</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/thailands-queen-mother-sirikit-influential-style-icon-dies-at-93</link><description>Thailand's Queen Mother Sirikit, who brought glamour and elegance to a postwar revival in the country's monarchy and who, in later years, would occasionally wade into politics, has died aged 93, the Thai Royal Household Bureau said on Saturday.
Sirikit had been out of the public eye since a stroke</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 05:41:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hilsa fishing ban ends: Fishermen in Chandpur set to return to rivers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/hilsa-fishing-ban-ends-fishermen-in-chandpur-set-to-return-to-rivers</link><description>After a 22-day government ban, the Meghna and Padma rivers are set to come alive once again with the sound of boats and nets being cast, as nearly 43,000 fishermen in Chandpur prepare to resume hilsa fishing from Saturday midnight.
 
The annual restriction on catching, selling and tran</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 05:56:18 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>