<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 13:17:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>No risk for voters, only for election saboteurs: RAB DG</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/no-risk-for-voters-only-for-election-saboteurs-rab-dg</link><description>Rapid Action Battalion (RAB) Director General Additional IGP AKM Shahidur Rahman on Wednesday said there is no risk for general voters in Thursday’s national election, warning that those attempting to disrupt the polls will face the music.
“The risk in this election is for those who wa</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 11:49:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>China should support AI advancement with power, computing resources, premier says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/china-should-support-ai-advancement-with-power-computing-resources-premier-says</link><description>China should better coordinate power and computing resources to advance artificial intelligence, China's second-ranking official, Premier Li Qiang, said on Wednesday.
The country should push for the "scaled and commercialised application of artificial intelligence," Li said, according to state bro</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 12:04:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Truck–autorickshaw collision kills election official, woman in Sherpur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/truck-autorickshaw-collision-kills-election-official-woman-in-sherpur</link><description>An assistant presiding officer, who was on the way to his assigned polling station, has been killed in a road accident involving a truck and an autorickshaw in Sherpur.
The officer was travelling in the autorickshaw, which collided with the truck in Sherpur Sadar. The accident also left another wo</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 10:52:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Take lead again tomorrow’, Jamaat Ameer to Gen-Z</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/take-lead-again-tomorrow-jamaat-ameer-to-gen-z</link><description>Jamaat Ameer Dr Shafiqur Rahman on Wednesday called on the Generation Z (Gen-Z) to once again take the lead on the election day, recalling their role during the July movement.
In a Facebook post in the afternoon, he wrote, “Dear Gen-Z, you are the heroes of the July revolution. Through your</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 11:07:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP expresses concern over Jamaat’s alleged money distribution before election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-expresses-concern-over-jamaats-alleged-money-distribution-before-election</link><description>The Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) on Wednesday expressed serious concern over what it called a violation of election rules by its key rival, Jamaat-e-Islami, through alleged distribution of money ahead of the election.
Speaking at a press briefing at the BNP election office in Gulshan, BNP sp</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 11:22:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US troops to Nigeria will avoid combat, focus on training, military says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/africa/us-troops-to-nigeria-will-avoid-combat-focus-on-training-military-says</link><description>Nigeria's military said on Wednesday that about 200 US troops due to arrive in the coming weeks would not take part in combat action and that Nigerian forces would retain full control over all security decisions.
This followed comments from a US official on Tuesday that the Pentagon planned to dep</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 11:37:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Voice For Justice Observers’ team meets Chief Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/voice-for-justice-observers-team-meets-chief-adviser</link><description>An election observation delegation from the Voice For Justice Observers’ team on Wednesday paid a courtesy call on Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus.
The four-member delegation, led by Prof Hasanat M Husain MBE, Convenor, Voice for Justice World Forum and Consultant, UK Ministry of Educ</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 11:52:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat leader held at airport with Tk 7.4 million: police</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/police-count-tk-74-million-recovered-from-bag-of-jamaat-leader-held-at-saidpur-airport</link><description>Police have counted Tk 7.4 million recovered from the bag of a Thakurgaon district Jamaat-e-Islami leader detained at Saidpur Airport in Nilphamari.
Authorities are set to brief the media on Wednesday evening.
Saidpur Police chief Rezaul Karim said the details would be shared at a press conferenc</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 12:07:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No cap on cash for domestic flights: HSIA</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/no-cap-on-cash-for-domestic-flights-hsia</link><description>Executive Director of Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport (HSIA) Group Captain SM Ragib Samad on Wednesday said there is no restriction or maximum ceiling on carrying cash on domestic air routes.
“There is no restriction on carrying cash on domestic routes. No maximum ceiling has been set</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 12:22:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique thanks top Islamic scholars for supporting BNP</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-thanks-top-islamic-scholars-for-supporting-bnp</link><description>BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman on Wednesday expressed heartfelt thanks and gratitude to the country’s respected pirs, mashayekhs, Islamic scholars, ulema, imams and khatibs for their reported support for his party.
In a statement reacting to news published in various newspapers and media outlet</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 12:37:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BGB DG asks for stern action against sabotage, chaos during election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bgb-dg-asks-for-stern-action-against-sabotage-chaos-during-election</link><description>Border Guard Bangladesh (BGB) Director General Major General Mohammad Ashrafuzzaman Siddiqui on Tuesday asked the BGB members to firmly thwart any attempt to carry out sabotage, violence or create chaos during the election.
The BGB DG came up with the instruction while exchanging views with BGB pe</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 12:52:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>S Africa survive double Super Over drama against Afghanistan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/s-africa-survive-double-super-over-drama-against-afghanistan</link><description>South Africa survived Kagiso Rabada’s final-over meltdown against Afghanistan and then a double Super Over drama before prevailing in a heart-stopping Group D match of the Twenty20 World Cup on Wednesday.
In a remarkable match of fluctuating fortunes, South Africa appeared to be in the box s</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 13:07:58 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>