<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 07:20:26 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Dhaka to get state-of-the-art special needs school</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dhaka-to-get-state-of-the-art-special-needs-school</link><description>The government is set to establish a modern and fully equipped school for children with special needs in Dhaka, aiming to ease the acute shortage of quality education and therapy services for children with neurodevelopmental disorders (NDD) and other disabilities in the capital.
The new institutio</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 05:16:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Adani seeks up to $5 billion investment in Google data centre to join AI boom</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/indias-adani-seeks-up-to-5-billion-investment-in-google-data-centre-to-join-ai-boom</link><description>India's Adani Group plans to invest up to $5 billion in Alphabet-owned Google's India AI data centre project, an executive said on Friday, as it seeks to cash in on booming demand for data capacity in the world's most populous nation.
In October, Google said it would invest $15 billion over five y</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 05:31:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sammilito Islami bank to be launched next week: BB Governor</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/sammilito-islami-bank-to-be-launched-next-week-bb-governor</link><description>Bangladesh Bank (BB) governor Dr Ahsan H Mansur said the much-talked-about proposed Sammilito Islami Bank will be launched next week.
Speaking as the chief guest at the 4th Bangladesh Economic Conference on Saturday, the central bank governor said they have almost completed all the formalities to</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 05:46:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US FDA memo links 10 child deaths to COVID vaccines, New York Times reports</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/us-fda-memo-links-10-child-deaths-to-covid-vaccines-new-york-times-reports</link><description>The US Food and Drug Administration said in an internal memo that at least 10 children had likely died "because of" COVID-19 vaccinations, citing myocarditis, or heart inflammation, as a possible cause, the New York Times reported on Friday.
The Department of Health and Human Services, which inclu</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 06:01:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>11 Bangladeshis arrested in Singapore anti-drug raid</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/11-bangladeshis-arrested-in-singapore-anti-drug-raid</link><description>Singapore’s Central Narcotics Bureau (CNB) has arrested 11 Bangladeshis and one Myanmar national in a coordinated anti-drug operation in a Woodlands dormitory.
The raid was conducted from late Thursday night until early Friday morning amid heavy rain, with support from multiple government bo</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 06:16:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Millions pushed into risky migration in Asia as livelihoods collapse: OHCHR</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/millions-pushed-into-risky-migration-in-asia-as-livelihoods-collapse-ohchr</link><description>The UN human rights office has warned that soaring inflation, weak job markets, and shrinking access to basic services are forcing millions of people in South and South-East Asia to migrate out of desperation.
In a new assessment, the office said people across the region are increasingly moving &amp;l</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 05:50:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>'Political realities prevent my return', says Tarique</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/political-realities-prevent-my-return-says-tarique-as-he-seeks-prayers-for-khaleda</link><description>Urging everyone to continue praying for the recovery of his critically ill mother, Khaleda Zia, BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman has said that although he strongly wishes to return home and be by her side, he is unable to do so freely due to the current political realities.
In a Facebook post on</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 06:05:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nepal issues new Rs 100 note showing ‘Indian territories’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/nepal-issues-new-rs-100-note-showing-indian-territories</link><description>Nepal’s central bank on Thursday unveiled new Rs 100 currency notes featuring a revised national map that includes the disputed Kalapani, Lipulekh, and Limpiyadhura regions, territories India has long maintained are its own, reports The Times of India.
The move revives a years-long boundary</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 06:20:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khasru says BNP will replicate RMG model in other export sectors if elected</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/khasru-says-bnp-will-replicate-rmg-model-in-other-export-sectors-if-elected</link><description>BNP standing committee member Amir Khasru Mahmud Chowdhury has said they will replicate the successful RMG model in other export-oriented industries if they come to power.
Speaking at the 4th Bangladesh Economic Conference on Saturday, he said they will open facilities such as bonded warehouses an</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 06:35:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two workers burnt in Gazipur factory explosion</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/two-workers-burnt-in-gazipur-factory-explosion</link><description>Two workers have been burnt in a fire sparked by a machine explosion at a factory in Kaliakair upazila of Gazipur district.
The incident occurred on Friday evening at Madina Polymer Industries Ltd's unit in the Upazila's Board Mill area, according to Monir Hossain, a firefighter from the Kaliakair</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 06:50:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Election schedule to be declared in second week of Dec: CEC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/election-schedule-to-be-declared-in-second-week-of-dec-cec</link><description>Chief Election Commissioner AMM Nasir Uddin has said the Election Commission will announce the schedule for the next general election in the second week of December. 
“Hopefully, what we expect is that it will be declared in the second week of December. When the schedule is announced, t</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 07:05:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mock voting drill under way in Dhaka ahead of national election, referendum</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/mock-voting-drill-under-way-in-dhaka-ahead-of-national-election-referendum</link><description>A mock voting exercise is being held in Dhaka as the Election Commission (EC) tests its preparations for the upcoming 13th national election and a nationwide referendum, both scheduled to take place on the same day in February next year.
The drill began at 8:00 am on Saturday at the Sher-e-Bangla</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 07:20:26 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>