<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 07:18:58 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Kulaura-Shahbajpur rail rehab project sees only 60pc progress</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/kulaura-shahbajpur-rail-rehab-project-sees-only-60pc-progress</link><description>The 6th time extension for completion of the much-talked about rehabilitation of the Kulaura-Shahbajpur rail section ended on 30 June this year while the progress is only 60 percent yet.
However, the Bangladesh Railway (BR) extended the timeline up to December 2026 with another year in test period</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 03:53:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BINA paddy variety brings smile to Magura growers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/bina-paddy-variety-brings-smile-to-magura-growers</link><description>Early bumper production of the high-yielding Aman crop BINA paddy 26 (BINA dhan26) on 50 hectares in two villages of Magura Sadar Upazila has brought smiles to growers.
Sources at the Department of Agricultural Extension, Magura, said this is the first time the cultivation of the paddy variety has</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 04:08:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh struggles to lure foreign visitors despite natural wonders</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladesh-struggles-to-lure-foreign-visitors-despite-natural-wonders</link><description>Bangladesh's natural diversity, from the world's longest sea beach to the largest mangrove forest, offers all the makings of a thriving tourism economy. Yet, the country remains far from realising its potential as a global travel destination.
Industry insiders say that despite its unique attractio</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 04:38:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pakistan flags pest issues in pineapple</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/pakistan-flags-pest-issues-in-pineapple</link><description>Bangladesh and Pakistan have initiated a process to expand bilateral trade in fruits, sources say.
As part of the move, a meeting was recently held between the Plant Quarantine Wing, Ministry of Agriculture, Bangladesh, and the Department of Plant Protection (DPP) under Pakistan's Ministry of Nati</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 04:53:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gold prices hit new record</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/gold-prices-hit-new-record</link><description>Gold notched a new high above $4,300 an ounce on Friday and was poised for its best week in five years, as signs of weakness in US regional banks, global trade frictions and expectations of more rate cuts sent investors flocking to the safe-haven metal.
Spot gold was up 0.3 per cent at $4,336.18 p</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 05:08:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientists move closer to confirming existence of dark matter</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/scientists-move-closer-to-confirming-existence-of-dark-matter</link><description>Scientists may be coming closer to confirming the existence of dark matter - the invisible stuff thought to make up more than a quarter of the cosmos - as they study a diffuse glow of gamma rays near the center of our galaxy.
Everything visible in the universe is made of ordinary matter - from sta</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 05:38:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Three flats of BSB Global’s Bashar seized</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/three-flats-of-bsb-globals-bashar-seized</link><description>The Criminal Investigation Department has seized three flats belonging to MK Khairul Bashar, chairman of BSB Global Network, who was arrested in a money laundering case.
The Dhaka Metropolitan Senior Special Judges’ Court issued the order on Thursday following a petition filed by the CID, th</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 05:53:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Microsoft: Russia, China increasingly using AI to escalate cyberattacks on the US</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/microsoft-russia-china-increasingly-using-ai-to-escalate-cyberattacks-on-the-us</link><description>Russia, China, Iran and North Korea have sharply increased their use of artificial intelligence to deceive people online and mount cyberattacks against the United States, according to new research from Microsoft.
This July, the company identified more than 200 instances of foreign adversarie</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 06:08:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pacific Group shuts 8 Ctg factories amid worker protests</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/pacific-group-shuts-8-ctg-factories-amid-worker-protests</link><description>Eight factories operated by Pacific Group in the Chattogram EPZ have been declared closed indefinitely following worker protests.
On Thursday night, the owners said the factories had been closed under Section 12(2) of the EPZ Labour Act 2019.
The factories closed are Pacific Jeans-1, Pacific Jean</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 06:23:24 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>