<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 15:42:39 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Tension erupts in Rangpur-6 after recovery of six ballot papers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tension-erupts-in-a-polling-station-in-rangpur-6-after-recovery-of-six-ballot-papers</link><description>Tension flared on Monday morning after six tampered ballot papers and two seals were recovered from a polling station in Pirganj Upazila of the Rangpur-6 constituency.
The incident occurred at Hasarpara Government Primary School polling station in Madankhali Union.
Locals said some students who a</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 12:29:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Italy says it stands ready to train police in Gaza</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/italy-says-it-stands-ready-to-train-police-in-gaza</link><description>Italy stands ready to help train police forces in Gaza and elsewhere in the Palestinian territories, its foreign minister said on Monday, as Rome aims to play a role in stabilising the Middle East.
“We are ready to train a new Gaza police force, and we are also ready to train a Palestinian p</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 12:44:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Uttara Bank opens its 50th sub branch in Moulvibazar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/uttara-bank-opens-its-50th-sub-branch-in-moulvibazar</link><description>Uttara Bank PLC has inaugurated the 50th sub branch of the bank at Shamshernagar in Kamolganj in Moulvibazar district, according to a press release.
Mr. Khandaker Ali Samnoon, Deputy Managing Director of Uttara Bank PLC, inaugurated the ‘Shamshernagar Sub Branch’ at a function on Monda</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 12:59:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Amid criticism, Law Adviser lists ministry’s steps since taking charge</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/amid-criticism-law-adviser-lists-ministrys-steps-since-taking-charge</link><description>Law Adviser Dr. Asif Nazrul has outlined a wide range of legal and institutional reforms carried out by the Ministry of Law, Justice and Parliamentary Affairs since the July mass uprising, amid criticism over his role.
In a Facebook post, he said while the work was done collectively by the ministr</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 13:14:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prime Bank holds ‘Empowering Youth’ seminar at Gazipur Agricultural University</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/prime-bank-holds-empowering-youth-seminar-at-gazipur-agricultural-university</link><description>Under the initiative of its flagship platform PrimeAcademia, Prime Bank PLC recently organized a seminar titled “Empowering Youth” at Gazipur Agricultural University (GAU), in collaboration with GAU and the GAU Career Club.
According to a press release, the initiative reaffirmed the Ba</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 13:29:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>459 temporary CCC employees granted permanent status</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/459-temporary-ccc-employees-granted-permanent-status</link><description>A total of 459 temporary employees of Chattogram City Corporation (CCC) have been granted permanent status.
Mayor Dr Shahadat Hossain announced the decision while addressing a meeting with the employees at the corporation’s head office in Tiger Pass .
The employees, who had been working on</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 13:44:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ONE Bank outlines strategic priorities for 2026</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/one-bank-outlines-strategic-priorities-for-2026</link><description>ONE Bank PLC has outlined its strategic priorities for the year 2026 at a Strategic Leadership Meet held recently at the Radisson Blu Water Garden Hotel, Dhaka.
According to a press release, the day-long session brought together around 80 members of the bank’s Strategic Leadership Team to al</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 13:59:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NRBC Bank rewards 66 branches and sub branches for achieving over 100pc in CASA drive</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/nrbc-bank-rewards-66-branches-and-sub-branches-for-achieving-over-100pc-in-casa-drive</link><description>NRBC Bank Awards 66 Branches for achieving more than 100 per cent of their targets in collecting Current and Savings Accounts (CASA), which are low- and no-cost deposits.
According to a press release, the certificates were handed over to the Heads of branch and sub-branch by the Chairman of the ba</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 14:14:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh’s newly elected MPs to take oath on Tuesday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladeshs-newly-elected-mps-to-take-oath-on-tuesday</link><description>Newly elected MPs are set to take oath as members of the 13th parliament and also the Constitution Reform Council on Tuesday.
Chief Election Commissioner AMM Nasir Uddin will administer the oath in line with the Constitution as the posts of Speaker and Deputy Speaker of the 12th Parliament are cur</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 14:29:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Al-Arafah Islami Bank signs deal with Seamax Ltd</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/al-arafah-islami-bank-signs-deal-with-seamax-ltd</link><description>Al-Arafah Islami Bank PLC, the country’s one of the leading Shariah-based banks, has signed a Memorandum of Understanding with Seamax Limited, according to a press release.
Under this agreement, both organisations will jointly contribute to the agricultural and rural development of the count</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 14:44:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>SC stays HC order on Ramadan school closure</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/sc-stays-hc-order-on-ramadan-school-closure</link><description>The Appellate Division of the Supreme Court (SC) on Monday stayed a High Court (HC) order that had directed to close the government and non-government secondary and lower secondary schools from February 18 in observance of the Holy month of Ramadan.
The Appellate Division Chamber Judge Court passe</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 14:59:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCP signs July National Charter, CA extends thanks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ncp-signs-july-national-charter-ca-extends-thanks</link><description>National Citizen Party (NCP) has signed the July National Charter, giving it compete shape on the aspects of approval of all stakeholders.
The charter was endorsed by most of the stakeholders of the Consensus Commission of the Interim Government but the NCP remained absent from signing the instrum</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 15:14:04 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>