<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 17:36:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Teachers hold nighttime protest at Shaheed Minar over allowance demands</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/teachers-hold-nighttime-protest-at-shaheed-minar-over-allowance-demands</link><description>As part of their “uninterrupted sit-in” demanding house rent allowance at 20 percent of base salary, MPO-registered teachers and staff are holding a nighttime sit-in at the Central Shahid Minar.
In response to police attacks on teachers, they decided to start uninterrupted work stoppag</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 14:51:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Wife poisons Rangamati farmer to death after he learns of her 'affair’: police</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/wife-poisons-rangamati-farmer-to-death-after-he-learns-of-her-affair-police</link><description>The Police Bureau of Investigation (PBI) has unveiled the cause behind a farmer’s death in Rangamati, five months after he went missing.
The PBI Chattogram shared the details of the incident on Sunday.
According to the PBI, the farmer’s wife Kohinur Akhter killed Didarul Alam by suffo</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 15:21:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Envoy Textiles holds meeting with ADB delegation after $30m financing approval</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/envoy-textiles-holds-meeting-with-adb-delegation-after-30m-financing-approval</link><description>Envoy Textiles Limited on Sunday hosted a high-level courtesy meeting with a delegation from the Asian Development Bank (ADB) at its Corporate Office in Dhaka's Panthpath. The meeting was convened following the recent approval of a USD 30 million financing package from ADB to support the company's</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 15:36:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EU begins gradual rollout of digital border system</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/eu-begins-gradual-rollout-of-digital-border-system</link><description>European Union member countries began rolling out a new entry and exit system on Sunday at the bloc’s external borders, electronically registering non-EU nationals' data.
The Entry/Exit System (EES), an automated system that requires travellers to register at the border by scanning their pas</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 15:51:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Transport workers call off strike in Mymensingh, four districts after talks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/transport-workers-call-off-strike-in-mymensingh-four-districts-after-talks</link><description>Transport workers have withdrawn their strike in five districts of Mymensingh Division, calling in protest against the arrest of a worker accused of harassing a July Uprising protester and the suspension of 16 United Service buses.
As a result, buses will resume operations from Monday morning.
On</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 16:06:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ensuring accountability &amp; human rights</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/ensuring-accountability-human-rights</link><description>This year's International Day for Universal Access to Information (IDUAI) dawned at a grim moment for Bangladesh. It, however, helped to open many windows.
The Information Commission-the very body entrusted since 2010 with upholding citizens' access to public information-has been essentially inact</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 16:36:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Child marriage and sexual violence against girls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/child-marriage-and-sexual-violence-against-girls</link><description>Much as the nation strives to bring an end to child marriage, the unlawful matrimony continues in this country. The consequences of such premature marriage for underage girls with adult youths or men are devastating. It is the brides who pay the heaviest price. The girls given off to such marriage</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 16:51:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How reliable are methods of measuring poverty?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/how-reliable-are-methods-of-measuring-poverty</link><description>Poverty has occupied the central stage of development thinking. In fact, development is about improvement in the income level and basic living standards of the common people. It should focus first and foremost on addressing poverty among the masses. It is because of this, the World Bank (WB), the m</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 17:06:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>MDCF-2: A breakthrough in fight against child malnutrition</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/mdcf-2-a-breakthrough-in-fight-against-child-malnutrition</link><description>Just as the oral rehydration solution (ORS) developed by the icddr,b revolutionised the fight against diarrhoea worldwide, this breakthrough has the potential to make a lasting impact on malnutrition
 
It is heartening that a food supplement for undernourished children, developed by the Inte</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 17:21:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BGB soldier loses leg in landmine explosion on Bangladesh-Myanmar border</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bgb-soldier-loses-leg-in-landmine-explosion-on-bangladesh-myanmar-border</link><description>A Border Guard Bangladesh (BGB) soldier lost his leg in a landmine explosion along the Naikhongchhari border on Saturday morning.
The incident occurred around 10:50am while a BGB patrol team was operating in the Tumbru border area of Naikhongchhari upazila.
Nayek Mohammad Akhtar Hossain of</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 17:36:42 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>