<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 16:33:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Turkey told Russia, Ukraine to keep energy infrastructure out of war, minister says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/turkey-told-russia-ukraine-to-keep-energy-infrastructure-out-of-war-minister-says</link><description>Turkey is telling Russia, Ukraine, and all other parties to keep energy infrastructure out of their conflict and wants energy flows to continue uninterrupted, Energy Minister Alparslan Bayraktar said after a series of attacks off Turkey's Black Sea coast.
Ukraine, which is targeting Russia's oil e</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 12:15:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khaleda to be flown to UK for advanced treatment: Fakhrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/khaleda-to-be-flown-to-uk-for-advanced-treatment-fakhrul</link><description>BNP Chairperson Begum Khaleda Zia may be flown to the United Kingdom early Friday for advanced treatment by a royal air ambulance provided by the Emir of Qatar, said party Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir on Thursday.
“You have already heard that we have received a highly advanc</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 12:30:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Advisers’ Council approves Police Commission Ordinance, clears amendments to RPO</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/advisers-council-approves-police-commission-ordinance-clears-amendments-to-rpo</link><description>The Council of Advisers, on Thursday, approved the long-anticipated Police Commission Ordinance, paving the way for the formation of an independent five-member commission aimed at making policing in Bangladesh more public-centred, accountable and rights-sensitive.
Environment Adviser Syeda Ri</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 13:30:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>50 police station chiefs reshuffled in Dhaka through lotteries</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/50-police-station-chiefs-reshuffled-in-dhaka-through-lotteries</link><description>Ahead of the national election, the list of new officers-in-charge (OCs) for 50 police stations under the Dhaka Metropolitan Police (DMP) has been published after a lottery-based selection process involving 527 stations nationwide.
In an order signed on Thursday by DMP Commissioner Sheikh Md Sazza</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 13:45:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Russia, India aim to increase and diversify trade</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/russia-india-aim-to-increase-and-diversify-trade</link><description>India and Russia want to boost their trade and expand the variety of items in transactions, both said on Thursday as Russian President Vladimir Putin headed to New Delhito start a two-day state visit.
Putin's first visit to India in four yearsaims toincrease sales of Russian oil, missile systems a</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 14:00:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NSU hosts a seminar on contemporary compensation strategies in the banking sector of Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/nsu-hosts-a-seminar-on-contemporary-compensation-strategies-in-the-banking-sector-of-bangladesh</link><description>North South University's (NSU) Department of Management organised a seminar titled "Contemporary Compensation Strategies in the Banking Sector of Bangladesh: An HR Perspective" on Thursday at NSU.
The session was graced by the presence of Dr AKM Waresul Karim, Professor and Dean of the School of B</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 14:15:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Russia warns Faroe Islands over ‘spy ship’ sanctions</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/russia-warns-faroe-islands-of-potential-retaliation-over-sanctions-related-to-alleged-spy-ships</link><description>Russia is considering retaliatory measures against the Faroe Islands after the Faroese parliament passed a law giving the government the authority to bar Russian fishing companies from its waters, the Russian Foreign Ministry said on Thursday.
The Faroese public broadcaster said on Wednesday that</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 14:30:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Italian police probe 13 fashion firms over labour abuse</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/italian-police-seek-governance-documents-from-13-fashion-firms-in-labour-abuse-probe</link><description>Italian police on Wednesday visited the headquarters of 13 high-end fashion firms, asking them to hand over documents on governance and supply-chain controls as part of an investigation into alleged worker abuse at fashion subcontractors, judicial documents showed.
The brands that received documen</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 14:45:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Forthcoming national election will be free, fair: Salahuddin Ahmed</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/forthcoming-national-election-will-be-free-fair-salahuddin-ahmed</link><description>BNP Standing Committee member Salahuddin Ahmed today (Thursday) said the upcoming national election will be a decisive one for the country’s history. 
“After 17 long years of democratic movement, struggle and sacrifice, the people will finally be able to exercise their right of vo</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 15:00:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Economists double down on December Fed cut despite policymaker divide</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/global/economists-double-down-on-december-fed-cut-despite-policymaker-divide</link><description>The US Federal Reserve will reduce its key interest rate by a quarter-percentage point at the December 9-10 policy meeting to support a cooling labour market, according to a majority of over 100 economists surveyed by Reuters.
That strong consensus broadly mirrored a November poll and the near-85</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 15:15:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Qatar air ambulance for Khaleda Zia delayed, Zubaida flying in</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/qatar-air-ambulance-for-khaleda-zia-delayed-zubaida-flying-in</link><description>The special air ambulance provided by the Emir of Qatar to transport BNP Chairperson Khaleda Zia to London is expected to be delayed after a “technical issue”, raising the possibility that her departure could slip past 10 am on Friday.
Zubaida Rahman, wife of Khaleda’s son Tariqu</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 15:30:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC clears two new political parties for registration, including Aam Jonotar Dal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ec-clears-two-new-political-parties-for-registration-including-aam-jonotar-dal</link><description>The Election Commission has decided to register two new parties, including the Aam Jonotar Dal, whose general secretary had made headlines in early November by staging a hunger strike demanding his party’s registration.
The second party selected for registration is Jonotar Dal, bdnews24.com</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 15:45:38 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>