<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 17:38:18 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>NCP clarifies position on pressing for ‘Shapla’ election symbol</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ncp-continues-pressing-for-shapla-as-election-symbol-disputes-ecs-decision</link><description>The National Citizen Party (NCP) has again demanded the “Shapla” as its electoral symbol, rejecting the Election Commission’s (EC) stance that the flower cannot be allocated due to its place in the national emblem.
In a statement on Friday, NCP Convenor Nahid Islam explained why</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 15:19:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Singapore looks forward to 'working closely' with Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/singapore-looks-forward-to-working-closely-with-bangladesh</link><description>Singapore’s Foreign Minister Dr Vivian Balakrishnan has said his country looks forward to working closely with Bangladesh as it pursues its next phase of growth and development.
“With a young and hardworking population, Bangladesh has immense potential,” he said, as he met Specia</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 15:23:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chevron's Los Angeles refinery down after large fire erupts in jet fuel unit</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/chevrons-los-angeles-refinery-down-after-large-fire-erupts-in-jet-fuel-unit</link><description>Chevron’s 285,000-barrel-per-day El Segundo refinery in Southern California was mostly down on Friday after a large fire erupted in a jet fuel production unit, disrupting supply in the Golden State’s isolated energy market.
The El Segundo refinery is the second-largest refinery in Cali</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 15:38:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>4 injured in armed clash between locals in Munshiganj</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/4-injured-in-armed-clash-between-locals-in-munshiganj</link><description>At least four people were injured, including three who were shot, in a clash between two local groups over establishing supremacy in Munshiganj Sadar on Friday, said police.
Besides, several houses were vandalised during the clash. Police recovered 14 fresh grenades and nine bullet casings from th</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 15:53:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fewer foreign students, fewer dollars: US colleges feel the pinch</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/fewer-foreign-students-fewer-dollars-us-colleges-feel-the-pinch</link><description>DePaul University has told faculty it will immediately reduce spending following a 30 per cent decline in international enrollment this fall. The move is the latest by US colleges to cope with the disruptive education and immigration policies of President Donald Trump.
The amount of the reduction</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 16:23:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>20 injured as Jamaat, BNP clash in Chandpur over ‘edited' Facebook photo</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/20-injured-as-jamaat-bnp-clash-in-chandpur-over-edited-facebook-photo</link><description>At least 20 people have been injured in a clash between leaders and activists of the BNP and Jamaat-e-Islami in Chandpur’s Hajiganj Upazila, triggered by a Facebook post containing “distorted” images of BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman and party leader Rumin Farhana.
Hajiganj</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 16:47:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India set to receive first Afghan Taliban minister</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/india-set-to-receive-first-afghan-taliban-minister</link><description>The UN Security Council Committee has temporarily lifted a travel ban on the Afghan Taliban foreign minister, which would allow him to visit India between Oct 9 and 16, India's foreign ministry said on Friday.
If confirmed, it would be the first visit to India by a senior leader of the Taliban-run</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 17:02:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump gives Hamas until Sunday night to reach Gaza deal or 'all HELL' will break out</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-gives-hamas-until-sunday-night-to-reach-gaza-deal-or-all-hell-will-break-out</link><description>US President Donald Trump gave Palestinian Hamas militants until Sunday evening to accept his proposal to end the nearly two-year-old war with US ally Israel in the Gaza Strip, or "all HELL" would break out.
"An agreement must be reached with Hamas by Sunday Evening at SIX (6)pm, Washington, DC ti</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 17:17:43 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>