<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 05:25:38 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>House help Ayesha arrested from Jhalakathi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/house-help-ayesha-arrested-from-jhalakathi</link><description>Police on Wednesday arrested the domestic help, Ayesha, a prime suspect in the Mohammadpur double-murder case, from Nalchity of Jhalakhati district.
The arrestee, identified as Ayesha, confessed to her involvement in the killings during questioning, police said
Police recovered six bhoris of gold</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 01:25:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Finance Adviser hemmed in for hours</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/finance-adviser-hemmed-in-for-hours</link><description>Bangladesh Secretariat employees kept Finance Adviser Dr Salehuddin Ahmed confined to his office for five and a half hours on Wednesday, demanding a 20 per cent "secretariat allowance".
The agitated employees said the National Press Club and the Bangladesh Secretariat area was the centre of almost</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 01:40:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ACC sues 60 recruiting cos on charge of embezzling Tk 45b</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/acc-sues-60-recruiting-cos-on-charge-of-embezzling-tk-45b</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) on Wednesday filed separate cases against the owners, chairmen, managing directors, directors and others of 60 overseas recruiting companies on charge of embezzling Tk 45 billion.
They are accused of misappropriating the money by overcharging Malaysia-bound Ban</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 01:55:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>VAT paid by public often fails to reach treasury</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/vat-paid-by-public-often-fails-to-reach-treasury</link><description>Finance Adviser Dr Salehuddin Ahmed has noted with concern that VAT paid by the public often fails to reach the government treasury.
He has described this as "unfortunate" and stressed the need to simplify procedures to ensure that VAT is properly deposited.

"VAT is a modern and powerful mechan</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 02:10:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CA advises field officials to make upcoming election historic, unforgettable</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ca-advises-field-officials-to-make-upcoming-election-historic-unforgettable</link><description>Chief Adviser Prof Muhammad Yunus advises Upazila Nirbahi Officers (UNOs) across Bangladesh to get down to preparing forthwith to ensure that the upcoming general election stands out as a defining moment in the nation's history.
Describing the post-uprising twin-vote as an opportunity to rebuild B</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 02:25:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NBR in dilemma over tax benefit on edible oil import</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/nbr-in-dilemma-over-tax-benefit-on-edible-oil-import</link><description>The National Board of Revenue (NBR) is in a dilemma over offering a fresh tax benefit on import of edible oils considering revenue impact.
A proposal from the Ministry of Commerce (MoC) to consider tax benefits on the essential commodity for Ramadan is under review in the tax authority now.
A sen</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 02:40:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nothing doing if India doesn't extradite Hasina</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nothing-doing-if-india-doesnt-extradite-hasina</link><description>Bangladesh's interim foreign affairs adviser, Mohammad Touhid Hossain, has said Dhaka has little scope to force the return of deposed former prime minister Sheikh Hasina unless New Delhi agrees to extradite her.
Speaking to reporters at the foreign ministry on Wednesday, Hossain acknowledged Bangl</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 02:55:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Disasters displace 5.0m internally</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/disasters-displace-50m-internally</link><description>Bangladesh is home to almost five million people living in internal displacement due to natural hazards, according to the first nationwide estimate released by the International Organisation for Migration (IOM) in the city on Wednesday.
The assessment marks the most comprehensive attempt to quanti</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 03:10:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ACC sues Bashundhara chairman, sons, 13 NBL officials</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/acc-sues-bashundhara-chairman-sons-13-nbl-officials</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) on Wednesday filed a case against 16 persons, including Bashundhara Group Chairman Ahmed Akbar Sobhan, his two sons and 13 officials of National Bank PLC (NBL), on charges of embezzlement and money laundering involving a bank loan of about Tk 6.0 billion.
ACC D</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 03:45:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>T-bill yields rise as govt borrows more</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/t-bill-yields-rise-as-govt-borrows-more</link><description>The government borrowed Tk 50 billion through a special auction of 91-day treasury bills (T-bills) on Wednesday to partially finance its budget deficit.
The cut-off yield, commonly referred to as the interest rate, on the 91-day T-bills rose to 10.55 per cent, up from 10.26 per cent at the previou</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 04:00:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Atlas expects profit by FY27 after 11 years of losses</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/atlas-expects-profit-by-fy27-after-11-years-of-losses</link><description>State-owned Atlas Bangladesh expects to break its cycle of losses after 11 years-by FY27-emboldened by what it claims are profitable partnerships and the launch of its own brand of electric two-wheelers.
Its Managing Director Md Ajibor Rahman said the company revised its business strategy after th</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 04:15:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka stocks snap out of two-day recovery streak</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/dhaka-stocks-snap-out-of-two-day-recovery-streak</link><description>The Dhaka bourse closed Wednesday's session with a marginal loss after two previous recovery sessions following a price correction experienced by market leaders such as Grameenphone and Square Pharmaceuticals.
On the day, the majority of blue-chip stocks closed in the red, while junk stocks domina</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 04:30:43 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>