<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 07:24:41 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Warner Bros fight heats up with $108 billion hostile bid from Paramount</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/warner-bros-fight-heats-up-with-108-billion-hostile-bid-from-paramount</link><description>Paramount Skydance on Monday launched a hostile bid worth $108.4 billion for Warner Bros Discovery in a last-ditch effort to outbid Netflix and create a media powerhouse that would challenge the dominance of the streaming giant.
Netflix had emerged victorious on Friday from a weeks-long bidding wa</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 03:51:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Global leaders commit $1.9 billion to eradicate polio amid funding cuts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/global-leaders-commit-19-billion-to-eradicate-polio-amid-funding-cuts</link><description>Global leaders pledged $1.9 billion to advance polio eradication on Monday, accelerating efforts to protect 370 million children from polio each year amid significant funding cuts.
The budget of the Global Polio Eradication Initiative, a partnership that includes the World Health Organization and</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 04:06:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Japan threatening us militarily, China foreign minister tells German counterpart</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/japan-threatening-us-militarily-china-foreign-minister-tells-german-counterpart</link><description>Japan is threatening China militarily which is "completely unacceptable", Chinese Foreign Minister Wang Yi told his German counterpart, after Japan said that Chinese fighter jets had aimed their radar at Japanese military aircraft.
Japan has denounced the encounter as a dangerous act, though China</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 04:21:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Thailand-Cambodia fighting spreads along contested border</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/thailand-cambodia-fighting-spreads-along-contested-border</link><description>Thailand said it was taking action to expel Cambodian forces from its territory on Tuesday, as renewed fighting between the two Southeast Asian neighbours spread along the disputed border.
Each side has blamed the other for the clashes, which have derailed a fragile ceasefire brokered by US Presid</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 04:36:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New committee elected at India-Bangladesh Chamber with six returning members</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/new-committee-elected-at-india-bangladesh-chamber-with-six-returning-members</link><description>The India-Bangladesh Chamber of Commerce and Industries (IBCCI) has installed its new committee, retaining only one Bangladeshi and five Indian members from the outgoing panel.
Moshiur Rahman, owner of Rahman Shipping Lines, assumed the presidency of the chamber, overseeing business relations betw</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 04:51:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US prepared to open up exports of Nvidia H200 chips to China</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/us-prepared-to-open-up-exports-of-nvidia-h200-chips-to-china</link><description>The US Commerce Department is prepared to allow Nvidia's H200 chip to be exported to China, a person familiar with the matter told Reuters.
Nvidia shares rose 2.2 percent immediately after Semafor earlier reported the development.
Allowing the shipments could signal a friendlier approach to China</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 05:06:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BB chief says voting for ‘symbols’, not candidates, creates autocrats</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bb-chief-says-voting-for-symbols-not-candidates-creates-autocrats</link><description>Bangladesh Bank Governor Ahsan H Mansur has criticised the tendency to vote for “symbols” rather than carefully evaluating candidates in elections.
“In that case we are obviously creating conditions for an autocrat to emerge,” said Mansur
The culture of voting by “</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 05:21:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>16,000 fossil footprints in central Bolivia reveal dinosaur behavior</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/16000-fossil-footprints-in-central-bolivia-reveal-dinosaur-behavior</link><description>Legend once had it that the huge, three-toed footprints scattered across the central highlands of Bolivia came from supernaturally strong monsters — capable of sinking their claws even into solid stone.
 
Then scientists came here in the 1960s and dispelled children's fears, determinin</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 05:36:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh’s betel nut exports snarl as 150 trucks sit idle at Benapole</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladeshs-betel-nut-exports-snarl-as-150-trucks-sit-idle-at-benapole</link><description>A deepening bottleneck at the Benapole-Petrapole trade gateway has stranded about 150 export-bound trucks loaded with betel nuts worth an estimated Tk 100 crore, exposing Bangladesh’s second-largest betel-nut industry to mounting financial risk as delays stretch into a second month.
Exporter</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 05:51:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Australia social media ban set to take effect, sparking a global crackdown</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/australia-social-media-ban-set-to-take-effect-sparking-a-global-crackdown</link><description>Australia is set to become the first country to implement a minimum age for social media use on Wednesday, with platforms like Instagram, TikTok and YouTube forced to block more than a million accounts, marking the beginning of an expected global wave of regulation.
From midnight (1300 GMT), 10 of</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 06:06:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Robi launches eco-friendly ‘Super Bikes’ for field staff</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/robi-launches-eco-friendly-super-bikes-for-field-staff</link><description>Robi Axiata PLC has introduced eco-friendly Robi Super Bikes for its field staff to support sustainable mobility and strengthen digital service delivery across rural Bangladesh.
The electric bikes, designed for the company’s field staff, aim to ensure faster, greener, and more efficient cust</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 06:21:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP ready to lead fresh drive against corruption: Tarique</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-ready-to-lead-fresh-drive-against-corruption-tarique</link><description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman on Tuesday said his party is ready to lead a fresh strong and comprehensive drive against corruption if voted to power as graft has become deeply rooted in Bangladesh and continues to disrupt the daily lives of millions of people.
 “Fighting corruption</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 06:36:15 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>