<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 12:50:41 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Voters take an average of 3:52 mins to cast 2 ballots in mock voting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/voters-take-an-average-of-352-minutes-to-cast-two-ballots-in-mock-voting</link><description>It has taken an average of 1.5 minutes for a voter to enter a hall at a polling centre to cast their two ballots in the parliamentary election and referendum during a mock vote, Election Commissioner Abul Fazal Md Sanaullah says.
At the inauguration of a training programme for journalists at the E</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 10:15:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Winter break to continue at DU with 15 days of holidays</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/winter-break-to-continue-at-du-with-15-days-of-holidays-halls-to-remain-closed</link><description>In consideration of students' fears about earthquakes, the authorities at Dhaka University have decided to announce a continuation of winter break with 15 days of holidays.
Moreover, two more days of holidays will be added to the break, extending the holidays up to Dec 24.
In consideration of Chr</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 10:30:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India revokes state-run security app order for smartphones after outcry</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/india-revokes-state-run-security-app-order-for-smartphones-after-outcry</link><description>India revoked its order to smartphone makers on Wednesday to preload a state-run cybersecurity app days after the plan triggered a major backlash from Prime Minister Narendra Modi's opponents and privacy activists over surveillance fears.
The Indian government had confidentially ordered comp</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 10:45:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dengue: Death toll reaches 396 this year</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/dengue-death-toll-reaches-396-this-year</link><description>Five more deaths were reported from dengue in 24 hours till Wednesday morning, raising the number of fatalities from the mosquito-borne disease in Bangladesh to 396 this year.
The recent fatalities occurred in the Dhaka South City Corporation (DSCC), Dhaka North City Corporation (DNCC) and Mymensi</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 11:00:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Awami League was right fit for Jamaat: Mirza Abbas</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/awami-league-was-right-fit-for-jamaat-mirza-abbas</link><description>BNP Standing Committee member Mirza Abbas on Wednesday said Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami was never able to practise civil politics and that Awami League had always been a better match for the party.
“Awami League is an indecent party and Jamaat is an uncivilised one. To keep Jamaat in check, A</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 11:15:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EPB plans to hold sourcing expos on a regular basis</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/epb-plans-to-hold-sourcing-expos-on-a-regular-basis-in-future</link><description>The three-day Global Sourcing Expo 2025 Dhaka, the first of its kind in Bangladesh, concluded today (Wednesday) at the Bangladesh–China Friendship Exhibition Centre (Big Wave) in Purbachal, on the outskirts of the capital.
Mohammad Hassan Arif, Vice Chairman and Chief Executive of the Export</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 11:30:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ZI Khan Panna seeks unconditional apology</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/zi-khan-panna-seeks-unconditional-apology</link><description>Senior lawyer ZI Khan Panna sought an unconditional apology for his inability to represent as defence lawyer of ousted Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina in two separate cases filed for crimes against humanity including enforced disappearances.
Replacing ZI Khan, the International Crimes Tribunal-1, led</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 11:21:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hasina responsible for Khaleda Zia’s critical condition: Rizvi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/hasina-responsible-for-khaleda-zias-critical-condition-rizvi</link><description>BNP Senior Joint Secretary General Ruhul Kabir Rizvi has alleged that BNP Chairperson and former Prime Minister Khaleda Zia’s deteriorating health is largely the result of actions taken by Awami League President and deposed Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina.
Rizvi said, “Begum Khaleda Zia i</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 11:36:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trust Bank signs MoU with CG Runner BD Limited</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/trust-bank-signs-mou-with-cg-runner-bd-limited</link><description>Trust Bank PLC. and CG Runner BD Limited, the official distributor of BYD Bangladesh recently signed an agreement at CG Runner BD Limited corporate office.
Under this agreement, BYD customers could avail Trust Bank Auto Loans at a special rate and waived processing fee along with other special val</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 11:51:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prime Bank hosts Annual Risk Conference 2025 to strengthen proactive risk culture</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/prime-bank-hosts-annual-risk-conference-2025-to-strengthen-proactive-risk-culture</link><description>Prime Bank successfully hosted its Annual Risk Conference 2025, reaffirming its commitment to fostering a proactive risk culture and ensuring sustainable growth in alignment with regulatory standards.
The conference took place recently at the Marina Yasmin Chowdhury Conference Hall at Prime Tower</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 12:21:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rafah crossing to open soon to let Gazans cross into Egypt, Israel says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/rafah-crossing-to-open-soon-to-let-gazans-cross-into-egypt-israel-says</link><description>Gaza's main gateway will open in the next few days, Israel said on Wednesday, allowing thousands of Palestinians who are in need of medical care to leave the war-ravaged enclave through Egypt.
COGAT, the Israeli military arm that oversees humanitarian matters, said the opening of the Rafah crossin</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 12:36:50 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>