<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 05:23:34 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Beyond demolition of vulnerable buildings</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/beyond-demolition-of-vulnerable-buildings</link><description>The deployment of eight teams by the Rajdhani Unnayan Kartipakkha (RAJUK) following the Friday's powerful quake and three more tremors the next day to assess the vulnerabilities of buildings in Dhaka is a welcome move. It has identified 300 buildings out of 3,252 already assessed at quake risks. Th</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 18:23:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>45th BCS results released after three years, 1,807 cleared for hiring</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/45th-bcs-results-released-after-three-years-1807-cleared-for-hiring</link><description>The Public Service Commission (PSC) has released the final results of the 45th BCS, nearly three years after the circular was issued, recommending 1,807 candidates for cadre posts.
The PSC published the results at 11pm on Wednesday, said spokesperson SM Matiur Rahman, with details now available on</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 19:23:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Policy gaps hinder Bangladesh’s growth in global toy export market</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/policy-gaps-hinder-bangladeshs-export-growth-in-multi-billion-dollar-global-toy-industry</link><description>Bangladeshi entrepreneurs are facing a series of policy-related challenges that hinder their ability to grab the growing opportunities in the global toy market, though the interim government aims to diversify the country's export basket.
Exporters say they are taking significant risks to explore i</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 02:00:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Electric bus in Dhaka: Rollout hits snag amid approval backlog</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/electric-bus-in-dhaka-rollout-hits-snag-amid-approval-backlog</link><description>The rollout of electric buses under the Bangladesh Clean Air Project (BCAP) is set to be delayed indefinitely, as the required project approvals could not be obtained during the interim government's tenure.
Officials said that although the World Bank (WB) approved US$290 million for the project in</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 02:15:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Businesses call for pre-listing inspections of IPO aspirants to ensure fair valuation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/businesses-call-for-pre-listing-inspections-of-ipo-aspirants-to-ensure-fair-valuation</link><description>Business enterprises have suggested on-the-spot inspections of companies willing to go public to assess whether their financial and operational strength is sufficient to protect shareholders' interests.
The proposal came at a meeting held on Wednesday at the Bangladesh Securities and Exchange Comm</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 02:30:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Death toll rises to 36 in Hong Kong residential block fire</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/death-toll-rises-to-36-in-hong-kong-residential-block-fire</link><description>At least 36 people were killed and 279 were missing on Wednesday after Hong Kong's deadliest fire in three decades ripped through high-rise residential towers sheathed in flammable bamboo scaffolding, authorities said.
More than 10 hours after the fire started in the northern Tai Po district, flam</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 02:45:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>TIB calls for full disclosure of agreements with foreign cos on Laldia, Pangaon terminals</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tib-calls-for-full-disclosure-of-agreements-with-foreign-cos-on-laldia-pangaon-terminals</link><description>Transparency International Bangladesh (TIB) has said that while foreign investment in the development of Chattogram Port may bring positive outcomes for the country, the government must fully disclose all information, conditions, and procedures related to recently signed terminal agreements to ensu</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 03:00:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BRAC Bank to maintain its financial profile amid tough operating conditions: S&amp;P</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/brac-bank-to-maintain-its-financial-profile-amid-tough-operating-conditions-sp</link><description>BRAC Bank’s ratings of B+/B have been affirmed by global rating agency S&amp;amp;P.
“We estimate its risk-adjusted capital (RAC) ratio will be in the range of 4%–5% over the next two years,” the agency said on Thursday.
This ratio was 3.3 per cent at the end of December 2024, down</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 04:04:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CSE joins digital disclosure submission platform</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/cse-joins-digital-disclosure-submission-platform</link><description>The Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) has launched the second phase of its smart submission system (SSS), incorporating the port city bourse, to speed up and create a hassle-free disclosure submission process through a single digital platform.
By eliminating manual submissions of hard-copy documents, the</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 04:19:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Verdict in three plot scam cases against Hasina, Joy, Putul today</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/verdict-in-three-plot-scam-cases-against-hasina-joy-putul-today</link><description>A Dhaka court is set to deliver its verdict today (Thursday) in three cases filed against 47 individuals—including ousted prime minister Sheikh Hasina, her son Sajeeb Wazed Joy, and daughter Saima Wazed Putul—over alleged irregularities in RAJUK plot allocations.
Public prosecutor for</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 04:34:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BGB deployed in court area ahead of Hasina plot-scam verdict</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bgb-deployed-in-court-area-ahead-of-hasina-plot-scam-verdict</link><description>Border Guard Bangladesh (BGB) personnel have been deployed in Dhaka's lower court area ahead of the verdict in three plot-scam cases filed against 47 individuals, including ousted prime minister Sheikh Hasina, her son Sajeeb Wazed Joy, and daughter Saima Wazed Putul.
Police presence has also been</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 04:49:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hong Kong police arrest three as apartment fire death toll rises to 44</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/hong-kong-police-arrest-three-as-apartment-fire-death-toll-rises-to-44</link><description>A huge fire still burning in a Hong Kong apartment complex that has killed at least 44 people and left almost 300 missing may have been spread by unsafe scaffolding and foam materials used during maintenance work, police said on Thursday.
Working through the night, firefighters were struggling to</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 05:04:35 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>