<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 07:37:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Japan's LDP, Ishin agree to form coalition government, Kyodo says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/japans-ldp-ishin-agree-to-form-coalition-government-kyodo-says</link><description>Japan's Liberal Democratic Party and the Japan Innovation Party have broadly agreed to form a coalition government, setting the stage for the country's first female prime minister, Kyodo news agency reported on Sunday.
Sanae Takaichi, leader of the conservative LDP, and Hirofumi Yoshimura, head of</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 05:26:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The world is heading to add 57 superhot days a year, but study indicates it could have been worse</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/the-world-is-heading-to-add-57-superhot-days-a-year-but-study-indicates-it-could-have-been-worse</link><description>The world is on track to add nearly two months of dangerous superhot days each year by the end of the century, with poorer small nations hit far more often than the biggest carbon-polluting countries, a study released Thursday found.
But efforts to curb emissions of heat-trapping gases that starte</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 05:41:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Shapla’ can't be allotted as it's not on official list: EC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/shapla-cant-be-allotted-as-its-not-on-official-list-ec</link><description>Election Commissioner Md Anwarul Islam Sarker on Sunday said that the National Citizens Party (NCP) cannot be allotted ‘Shapla’ (water lily) as it is not included in the official list of symbols under the constitutional law and election rules.
He made the remark while talking to report</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 06:26:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>17 shops gutted in Faridpur fire</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/17-shops-gutted-in-faridpur-fire</link><description>A fire has ravaged at least 17 shops at Boalmari upazila of Faridpur.
The incident took place at Kadirdi market around 10:15 pm on Saturday, according to Khalek Sheikh, station leader at Boalmari Fire Service and Civil Defence.
The affected shops include a beauty salon, medicine shop, tailor shop</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 06:37:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fund shortfall forces major cuts to UN peacekeeping missions</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fund-shortfall-forces-major-cuts-to-un-peacekeeping-missions</link><description>A severe funding gap is threatening to undermine UN peacekeeping operations globally, with the Organization warning that delayed payments from Member States could force it to scale back patrols, close field offices, and repatriate thousands of ‘blue helmets.’
The crisis, which UN peace</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 06:52:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Stocks start week with losses at DSE, CSE</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/stocks-start-week-with-losses-at-dse-cse</link><description>Trading on the country’s two major stock exchanges began the week with losses on Sunday, as key indices and most share prices declined.
At the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE), the benchmark index DSEX dropped by 12 points, while the Shariah-based DSES and the blue-chip DS30 indices each fell by 7</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 07:07:02 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>