<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 07:10:05 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Israeli strikes kill 24 in Gaza</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/israeli-strikes-kill-24-in-gaza</link><description>Israeli tank shelling and airstrikes killed 24 Palestinians including seven children in Gaza on Wednesday, health officials said, the latest violence to undermine the nearly four-month-old ceasefire in the enclave.
Among the dead was a medic who rushed to help victims of a strike in the southern c</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 02:56:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Experts push for overhaul of tax system to boost investment</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/experts-push-for-overhaul-of-tax-system-to-boost-investment</link><description>Experts and economists have raised concerns over the complexities and inefficiencies within the supplementary duty (SD) and excise framework, calling for urgent business-friendly reforms to modernise the tax system and improve domestic resource mobilisation.
Speaking at a workshop on Tuesday, the</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 03:11:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Strong institutions key amid economic uncertainties’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/strong-institutions-key-amid-economic-uncertainties</link><description>Bangladesh urgently needs competent and resilient institutions to navigate mounting global and domestic pressures, including geopolitical tensions and the imminent challenges of graduating from least developed country (LDC) status, prominent businessman Mahbubur Rahman has said.
At a time of heigh</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 03:26:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>RU holds Div Youth Startup Summit</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ru-holds-div-youth-startup-summit</link><description>‘Rajshahi Divisional Youth Startup Summit 2026’ was held at the Rajshahi University (RU) to promote innovative thinking among young entrepreneurs and strengthen startup culture.
The day-long event was jointly organised by YOUReach and DEIED.
Held at Kazi Nazrul Islam Auditorium on the</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 03:41:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Survey signals high turnout, shifting votes</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/survey-signals-high-turnout-shifting-votes</link><description>With the 13th national parliamentary election approaching, a new nationwide survey suggests that voters are not only paying close attention but are also prepared to turn out in large numbers.
Nearly nine in ten respondents said they intend to cast their ballots, reflecting a level of enthusiasm th</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 03:56:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>July Charter written in blood: Ali Riaz</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/july-charter-written-in-blood-ali-riaz</link><description>Prof Ali Riaz, special assistant to the Chief Adviser, said although the printed copies appear in black ink, every letter of the July National Charter was written with the blood of the people of Bangladesh.
He made the remarks while speaking at a discussion titled "Public Awareness Campaign on the</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 04:11:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NASA's Juno finds Jupiter is a tiny bit smaller than previously thought</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/nasas-juno-finds-jupiter-is-a-tiny-bit-smaller-than-previously-thought</link><description>Jupiter, without a doubt, is the biggest planet in our solar system. But it turns out that it is not quite as large - by ever so small an amount - as scientists had previously thought.
Using new data obtained by NASA's robotic Juno spacecraft, scientists have obtained the most precise measurements</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 04:58:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Postal ballots of 380,000 expatriates reach Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/postal-ballots-of-380000-expatriates-reach-bangladesh</link><description>Nearly 380,000 postal ballots cast by expatriate Bangladeshis have reached the country so far.
Salim Ahmad Khan, team leader of the Election Commission’s Out of Country Voting (OCV) System Development and Implementation (SDI) Project, said that 379,924 postal ballots had arrived as of 9:30am</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 05:13:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pakistan PM says India boycott is a ‘thoughtful decision’ to support Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/pakistan-pm-breaks-silence-saying-india-boycott-is-a-thoughtful-decision-to-support-bangladesh</link><description>Pakistan Prime Minister Shehbaz Sharif has officially confirmed that their national cricket team will not take the field against India in the upcoming T20 World Cup, stating the decision was made to stand in solidarity with Bangladesh.
Addressing cabinet members in Islamabad on Wednesday, Sharif d</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 05:28:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Treasury bond yields slide as liquidity rises</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/treasury-bond-yields-slide-as-liquidity-rises</link><description>The yield on two-year treasury bonds fell further on Tuesday as the central bank purchased an additional US$171 million from 16 banks, aiming to keep the exchange rate of the US dollar against the local currency stable.
The cut-off yield, generally referred to as the interest rate, on Bangladesh G</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 05:43:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Seven injured as Jamaat campaign comes under ‘attack’ in Noakhali-3</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/seven-injured-as-jamaat-campaign-comes-under-attack-in-noakhali-3</link><description>At least seven people have been injured during an alleged attack on a door-to-door campaign event for Jamaat-e-Islami-backed candidate Borhan Uddin in Noakhali’s Begumganj. Rival activists traded blame over the incident.
The incident took place on Wednesday afternoon in Aleyapur Union, where</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 05:58:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Iran unveils new underground missile base</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/iran-unveils-new-underground-missile-base</link><description>Iran's Islamic Revolution Guards Corps (IRGC) on Wednesday unveiled a new underground missile base amid tensions with the United States, the semi-official Fars news agency reported.
The base was unveiled during a visit by Chief of Staff of the Iranian Armed Forces Abdolrahim Mousavi and Seyed Maji</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 06:13:53 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>