<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 20:25:16 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Fish hospital opens in Khulna to treat diseased fish</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/fish-hospital-opens-in-khulna-to-treat-diseased-fish</link><description>Usually people visit hospitals when sick, now fish in Khulna can also receive medical care. A specialised fish hospital, ‘Fish Square Fisheries Hospital,’ was inaugurated in Dumuria of Khulna on Friday afternoon, to provide treatment and advice for fish diseases and aquaculture issues.</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 15:58:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>2 Chinese nationals taken into custody over ‘unauthorised travel’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/2-chinese-nationals-taken-into-custody-over-unauthorised-travel</link><description>Police in Khagrachhari’s Ramgarh have taken two Chinese nationals into custody, saying they travelled to the hill district “without permission”.
Police seized laptops and several other electronic devices from the duo—Jiang Chengtong and Teng Tonggui.
Ramgarh Police Chief M</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 16:13:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DUCSU announces Bengali New Year celebration in Agrahayan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ducsu-strays-from-boishakh-announces-bengali-new-year-celebrations-in-agrahayan</link><description>The Dhaka University Central Students’ Union (DUCSU) has announced that it will celebrate Bengali New Year at the start of Agrahayan rather than on the traditional first day of Boishakh.
The newly elected DUCSU leadership intends to organise the event on Sunday, the first day of the Bengali</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 16:28:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt plans to develop economic zone in Bhola</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/govt-plans-to-develop-economic-zone-in-bhola</link><description>The government has a plan to develop an economic zone at the gas-rich Bhola district as many reputed companies have expressed their desire to set up industries in Bhola.
Power, Energy and Mineral Resources Adviser Muhammad Fouzul Kabir Khan, Industries Adviser Adilur Rahman Khan and Commerce Advis</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 16:51:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Auto driver beaten to death in Brahmanbaria</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/auto-driver-beaten-to-death-in-brahmanbaria</link><description>An autorickshaw driver was beaten to death on Friday in Bijoynagar upazila of Brahmanbaria district after his vehicle allegedly hit a motorcycle.
The deceased was identified as Mohammad Delwar Hossain, 45, also known as Dilu Mia of Chanpur village in Paharpur union under the same upazila and son o</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 17:06:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Man killed in Jhenaidah road crash</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/man-killed-in-jhenaidah-road-crash123</link><description>A youth was killed and two others were injured in a head-on collision between two motorcycles in Kaliganj upazila of Jhenaidah on Friday evening.
The deceased was identified as Suman Hossain, 22, son of Abdul Mannan of Baliadanga village in Kaliganj. The injured are Toukir Ahmed of Bhutiarghati vi</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 17:21:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fish hospital opens in Khulna to treat diseased fish</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fish-hospital-opens-in-khulna-to-treat-diseased-fish-1</link><description>Usually people visit hospitals when sick, now fish in Khulna can also receive medical care. A specialised fish hospital, ‘Fish Square Fisheries Hospital,’ was inaugurated in Dumuria of Khulna on Friday afternoon, to provide treatment and advice for fish diseases and aquaculture issues.</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 17:36:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Unleashing the youth dividend in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/unleashing-the-youth-dividend-in-bangladesh</link><description>Despite these challenges, it is clear that this is a momentous point in Bangladeshi history. This is because it is a country which is situated at a critical point in its national journey. Indeed, with a significant percentage, which is nearly 65 per cent of its population aged below 35, it is one o</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 18:04:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ensuring smooth walking for pedestrians</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/ensuring-smooth-walking-for-pedestrians</link><description>Around two-fifths of the daily commuters in Dhaka walk to reach their destinations, whereas the ratio was one-fifth two decades ago. The data are impressive, no doubt, especially since the city is not particularly conducive to smooth walking. There is a lack of safe, accessible and efficient infras</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 18:19:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>When climate crisis meets corruption</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/when-climate-crisis-meets-corruption</link><description>Bangladesh stands among the world's most climate-vulnerable nations, not only in statistical rankings but in the lived experience of millions. The country has entered an era in which the scale and frequency of natural disasters can no longer be predicted within familiar seasonal or geographical pat</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 18:34:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Poverty rising, jobs squeezing, social parameters worsening</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/poverty-rising-jobs-squeezing-social-parameters-worsening</link><description>Poverty is rising, employment shrinking and key social indicators in Bangladesh are deteriorating, says a presentation at an international meet in Dhaka about a setback on the national economic front and its spillovers.



Despite these negative trends, however, people of Bangladesh have not</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 18:49:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Stimulating investment in blue economy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/stimulating-investment-in-blue-economy</link><description>The size of the investment that the formal lending institutions, that is, banks, have already made or are willing to make in a particular sector of the economy is indicative of the particular sector's importance in the economy. From that perspective, the blue economy does not seem to play a substan</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 19:04:18 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>