<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 12:44:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>UN human rights experts urge Bangladesh, Malaysia to intensify efforts to protect migrant workers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/un-human-rights-experts-urge-bangladesh-malaysia-to-intensify-efforts-to-protect-migrant-workers</link><description>UN human rights experts on Friday urged both governments of Bangladesh and Malaysia to intensify their efforts to ensure that migrant workers are not criminalised or re-victimised and that fraudulent recruitment agencies and other responsible actors are held accountable.
The experts expressed rene</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 10:41:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Indian combat aircraft crashes during a demonstration at the Dubai Air Show</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/indian-combat-aircraft-crashes-during-a-demonstration-at-the-dubai-air-show</link><description>A combat plane crashed Friday during a demonstration at the Dubai Air Show.
The Indian HAL Tejas, a combat aircraft used in the Indian Air Force, crashed around 2:10 p.m. local time while flying a demonstration flight for a crowd.
It wasn’t immediately clear if the pilot ejected, or if anyo</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 10:56:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>2.1mn Dhaka buildings need immediate inspection: Ansary</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dhakas-57-quake-warrants-immediate-check-of-its-21mn-buildings-buets-ansary</link><description>The 5.7 magnitude earthquake that rattled Bangladesh on Friday should serve as a wake-up call for authorities to brace for an even stronger quake in future, says Mehedi Ahmed Ansary, who teaches civil engineering at Bangladesh University of Engineering and Technology (BUET).
“Buildings need</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 11:11:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Friday’s quake strongest in years: geologist</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-hasnt-seen-a-quake-as-strong-as-this-in-years-says-geologist</link><description>Geologist Dr Syed Humayun Akhter has described the earthquake that jolted Dhaka and other parts of Bangladesh on Friday as the strongest to strike the country in recent years.
The 5.7-magnitude tremor was centred in Narsingdi's Madhabdi, around 13km from Dhaka, at a depth of 10km. The shaking last</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 11:26:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Top Ukraine security official denies accepting terms of Trump's peace plan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/top-ukraine-security-official-denies-accepting-terms-of-trumps-peace-plan</link><description>Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelenskiy's top security official denied on Friday he had agreed to the outline of a Trump administration peace plan, after U.S. officials said he had accepted most of its terms.
Washington has presented Kyiv with a 28-point plan that would endorse many of Russia's ma</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 11:41:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Red Cross to shed nearly 3,000 jobs, scale back budget amid donor fatigue</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/red-cross-to-shed-nearly-3000-jobs-scale-back-budget-amid-donor-fatigue</link><description>The International Committee of the Red Cross will reduce its 2026 budget by 17 per cent to 1.8 billion Swiss francs ($2.23 billion)and cut 2,900 jobs, it said in a statement on Friday.
Aid budgets are facing an unprecedented shortfall as donors shift their focus towards defence, forcing humanitari</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 11:11:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump officials prepare for potential shakeup after one-year mark, CNN reports</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/trump-officials-prepare-for-potential-shakeup-after-one-year-mark-cnn-reports</link><description>The White House is preparing for possible turnover in the cabinet after US President Donald Trump reaches the one-year mark of his term, potentially shaking up his otherwise stable team of secretaries, CNN reported on Friday, citing multiple people familiar with the discussions.
Reuters could not</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 11:26:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khaleda, Yunus exchange greetings at Senakunja</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/khaleda-yunus-sit-side-by-side-exchange-greetings-at-senakunja</link><description>BNP Chairperson Khaleda Zia has attended the Armed Forces Day reception at Senakunja after a year, sitting next to interim government Chief Advisor Muhammad Yunus.
She arrived at the venue around 4pm on Friday and was welcomed by Army Chief General Waker-Uz-Zaman, Navy Chief Admiral M Nazmul Hassa</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 11:41:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>COP30 climate summit set for last-gasp showdown over fossil fuels and finance</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/cop30-climate-summit-set-for-last-gasp-showdown-over-fossil-fuels-and-finance</link><description>The COP30 climate summit was headed for a showdown on Friday over the future of fossil fuels after hosts Brazil dropped efforts to develop a global plan to shift away from oil, gas and coal from its proposed deal.
A draft text for a deal for this year's UN climate summit, released before dawn on F</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 11:56:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Indian Tejas fighter jet crashes, killing pilot</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/indian-tejas-fighter-jet-crashes-killing-pilot</link><description>An Indian home-produced Tejas fighter jet crashed at the Dubai Air Show during an aerial display on Friday, killing its pilot, the Indian Air Force said.
The fighter was flying at a low altitude at around 2:15pm (1015 GMT) before coming down in a ball of fire, according to a witness. Footage from</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 12:11:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two British teens plead not guilty to London transport cyberattack charges</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/two-british-teens-plead-not-guilty-to-london-transport-cyberattack-charges</link><description>Two teenagers pleaded not guilty on Friday to hacking charges over a 2024 cyberattack on London’s public transport body, with one of them also denying charges related to two health systems in the United States.
Transport for London (TfL), which operates the British capital’s tube and b</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 12:26:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Australia adds Amazon's Twitch to teen social media ban, spares Pinterest</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/australia-adds-amazons-twitch-to-teen-social-media-ban-spares-pinterest</link><description>Australia's internet watchdog on Friday said it would include Amazon-owned live streaming service Twitch in its upcoming teen social media ban, but will not add image-sharing platform Pinterest to the list.
From Dec 10, Australia will become the world's first country to bar people aged 16 years an</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 12:41:54 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>