<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 23:22:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Probe opens into 'hill-cutting' at Ramgarh Port</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/probe-opens-after-allegations-of-hill-cutting-infill-at-ramgarh-land-port</link><description>The Ministry of Shipping has launched an investigation into allegations that hills were cut to fill land for the development of Ramgarh Land Port in Khagrachhari.
The probe team visited several sites in Ramgarh where soil had reportedly been excavated from hills and used to fill areas of the port.</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 16:17:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>8 hurt in cement factory blast</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/8-workers-injured-as-boiler-explodes-at-narayanganj-akij-cement-factory</link><description>At least eight workers have been injured as a boiler exploded at an Akij Cement plant in Bandar Upazila of Narayanganj.
They have been taken to the National Burn and Plastic Surgery Institute in Dhaka.
The incident occurred on Saturday evening in Kadamrosul, said Bandar Police chief Golam Muktar</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 16:32:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Magnitude 6.8 earthquake strikes off Indonesia, GFZ says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/magnitude-68-earthquake-strikes-off-indonesias-talaud-islands-gfz-says</link><description>An earthquake of magnitude 6.8 struck off the coast of Indonesia's Talaud Islands on Saturday, the German Research Center for Geosciences (GFZ) said.
The quake was at a depth of 77 km (47.85 miles), GFZ said.
The Indonesian geophysics agency BMKG reported 7.1 magnitude reading, at 17 km depth. It</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 16:47:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique calls on media to ensure accountability</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-rahman-urges-news-outlets-to-support-democratic-oversight</link><description>Tarique Rahman has outlined the Bangladesh Nationalist Party’s (BNP) roadmap for serving the people and called on journalists to work towards ensuring accountability, stressing that constructive criticism is vital to solving Bangladesh’s challenges.
The BNP chairman spoke at a Dhaka ho</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 17:02:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Man killed, another injured in Chattogram shooting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/man-killed-another-injured-in-chattogram-shooting</link><description>A man has been killed and another injured in yet another attack, this time in Fatikchhari, Chattogram.
The incident took place at Lelang Union of the Upazila around 7:30pm on Saturday, police said.
The dead, Jamal Uddin, 38, was a resident of the area.
The injured, Nasir Uddin, 35, has been admi</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 17:17:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BD may get further tariff cuts, reciprocal free market access</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bd-may-get-further-tariff-cuts-reciprocal-free-market-access</link><description>Bangladesh advances towards strengthening its mutually beneficial trade relationship with the United States, opening the door to greater market access and new opportunities for its vital textile and apparel sector.
A spokesperson for the interim government's Chief Adviser Office  Saturday bro</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 17:32:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>GESI as a development framework</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/gesi-as-a-development-framework</link><description>Gender Equality and Social Inclusion, more commonly referred to as GESI, has increasingly become a defining lens through which development practitioners, policymakers, and international organisations assess and plan interventions. Yet, despite its widespread use in project proposals, policy documen</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 17:47:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>From financial inclusion to systemic risk</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/reviews/from-financial-inclusion-to-systemic-risk</link><description>Bangladesh's microcredit sector is not a conventional financial industry; it is the outcome of decades of social mobilisation, institutional innovation, and an integrated development philosophy that blends finance with health, education, disaster response, and livelihood support. The draft ordinanc</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 18:02:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Less about ideas, more about institutions</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/analysis/less-about-ideas-more-about-institutions</link><description>For much of the past decade, development debates have been dominated by ideas rather than institutions. Grand visions, national strategies, technology roadmaps, and long-term plans have proliferated across emerging and developing economies. Artificial intelligence, clean energy, digital finance, an</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 18:17:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>LPG crisis exposes regulatory gaps</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/lpg-crisis-exposes-regulatory-gaps</link><description>Liquefied petroleum gas (LPG) is no longer a luxury; it has become an essential cooking fuel for millions of households across the country. As domestic natural gas reserves dwindle, authorities have for years encouraged domestic use of LPG as an alternative. New residential gas connection has remai</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 18:32:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Global economic prospects and Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/global-economic-prospects-and-bangladesh</link><description>Forecasting or projecting the world economic conditions for the near future is a regular exercise of a number of international bodies or organisations. The projections are primarily linked to a number of 'ifs' and 'buts', which minimises the scope for blaming organisations for wrong forecasts. The</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 18:47:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Making essential drugs affordable</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/making-essential-drugs-affordable</link><description>The government's decision to expand the list of essential medicines to 295 and bring all of them under price regulation comes at a time when the cost of basic treatment is increasingly outpacing the ability of ordinary families to pay. In this context, regulating prices offers a practical means of</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 19:02:24 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>