<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 14:19:18 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Aminul urges BNP activists to avoid crowding outside hospital</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/aminul-urges-bnp-activists-to-avoid-crowding-outside-hospital</link><description>Convener of Dhaka North City unit BNP, Aminul Haque on Saturday urged party leaders and activists not to gather at the entrance of Evercare Hospital, where BNP Chairperson and former Prime Minister Begum Khaleda Zia is receiving treatment.
Addressing the crowd this afternoon via a microphone outsi</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 12:12:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fakhrul calls for policies to revive industries; make looters accountable</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/fakhrul-calls-for-policies-to-revive-industries-make-looters-accountable</link><description>BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir on Saturday emphasised the urgent need for reopening factories and industries closed over the past 15 years, reminding that their shutdown has left 1.4 million people unemployed.
Speaking at the ‘4th Bangladesh Economic Summit 2025’ in</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 12:27:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khaleda not fit to travel abroad now: Fakhrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/khaleda-not-fit-to-travel-abroad-now-fakhrul</link><description>BNP Chairperson Khaleda Zia, currently receiving treatment in a Dhaka hospital, is not in a condition to be sent abroad at this moment, Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir has said.
The BNP secretary general provided the update on Khaleda’s condition at a press conference on Saturday afternoon at he</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 12:42:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ukraine hit two 'shadow fleet' tankers with drones in Black Sea, security official says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/ukraine-hit-two-shadow-fleet-tankers-with-drones-in-black-sea-security-official-says</link><description>Ukraine hit two tankers used by Russia to export oil while skirting Western sanctions with marine drones in the Black Sea, an official from the SBU security service said on Saturday.
The joint operation to hit the so-called 'shadow fleet' vessels was run by the SBU and Ukraine's navy, the official</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 12:00:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Indonesia flood death toll climbs to 303 amid cyclone devastation, disaster agency says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/indonesia-flood-death-toll-climbs-to-303-amid-cyclone-devastation-disaster-agency-says</link><description>The death toll from floods and landslides following cyclonic rains in the Indonesian island of Sumatra has risen to 303, the head of the country's disaster mitigation agency said on Saturday, up from a previous figure of 174 dead.
Large parts of Indonesia, Malaysia and Thailand have been stricken</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 12:15:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cooperatives key to ecological farming, youth engagement, say experts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cooperatives-key-to-ecological-farming-youth-engagement-says-experts</link><description>A national wrap-up workshop organised by COAST Foundation on Saturday advocated for the critical role of farmers’ cooperatives in promoting ecological agriculture, boosting rural economies, and strengthening food security across Bangladesh.
The event, held at a city hotel, marked the conclus</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 12:30:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ukrainian delegation heads to US for peace talks after lead negotiator's exit</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/ukrainian-delegation-heads-to-us-for-peace-talks-after-lead-negotiators-exit</link><description>Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky said on Saturday that a delegation headed by security council secretary Rustem Umerov was on its way to the United States to continue talks on an agreement to end Russia's war.
Umerov has been put in charge of the Ukrainian delegation after the previous lead</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 12:45:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh struggles to woo foreign investors who cite ‘instability’: Jamaat chief</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bangladesh-struggles-to-woo-foreign-investors-who-cite-instability-jamaat-chief</link><description>Shafiqur Rahman, chief of the Jamaat-e-Islami, has said many foreign investors are reluctant to invest in Bangladesh due to political “instability and corruption”.
On Saturday, he said, despite independence, Bangladesh has yet to create the “desired comfort and facilities for dom</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 13:00:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two job candidates caught with hidden devices during exam in Rangpur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/two-job-candidates-caught-with-hidden-devices-during-exam-in-rangpur</link><description>Two candidates were detained at an examination centre in Rangpur after being caught with electronic devices during a recruitment test for the post of ‘Assistant Sub-Food Inspector’ under the Directorate General of Food, on Saturday afternoon.
They were subsequently sentenced to 20 days</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 13:15:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Global airlines affected by major Airbus A320 recall</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/global-airlines-affected-by-major-airbus-a320-recall</link><description>Europe's Airbus ordered immediate repairs to 6,000 of its widely used A320 jets in a sweeping recall affecting more than half the global fleet, threatening upheaval during the busiest travel weekend of the year in the US and sparking disruption worldwide.
The fix mainly involves reverting to earli</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 13:30:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>87,000 Bangladeshi expats registered so far to vote</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/87000-bangladeshi-expats-registered-so-far-to-vote</link><description>Nearly 87,000 expatriate Bangladeshi voters from different countries across the world have so far registered through a mobile app, ‘Postal Vote Bd’, in the past 10 days to vote in the upcoming national election and the referendum.
The Election Commission (EC) on November 19 opened the</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 13:45:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>1.4 million now jobless due to stalled industrialisation: A.K. Azad at economic conference</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/14-million-now-jobless-due-to-stalled-industrialisation-ak-azad-at-economic-conference</link><description>Industrial stagnation and shrinking private investment have caused 1.4 million (14 lakh) people to lose jobs, leaving them “wandering on the streets without employment,” Ha-Meem Group Managing Director and former FBCCI president A.K. Azad said on Saturday.
Speaking at the opening sessi</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 14:00:41 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>