<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 07:23:57 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Metro rail strike averted, still uncertainty persists</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/metro-rail-strike-averted-still-uncertainty-persists</link><description>The metro-rail operator has narrowly averted a fresh strike after its board approved long-pending service rules last week, easing immediate tensions with agitating staff.
However, officials and employees alike fear that delays in making the rules effective could once again destabilise operations.</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 03:00:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cold wave approaches as winter peaks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/cold-wave-approaches-as-winter-peaks</link><description>The feeling of cold has intensified across Bangladesh over the last five days, mainly due to a slump in day temperature, up to 8°C, as the country approaches its coldest winter month -- January.
The Bangladesh Meteorological Department said the temperature drop was driven by dense fog restrict</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 04:13:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Non-life insurers barred from using agents as IDRA scraps commissions</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/non-life-insurers-barred-from-using-agents-as-idra-scraps-commissions</link><description>The Insurance Development and Regulatory Authority (IDRA) has imposed a complete ban on agent commissions in the non-life insurance sector, introducing stricter rules on salary and benefit payments to employees.
According to a notification issued by the regulator, non-life insurance companies will</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 04:28:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Election aspirants to get e-return filing services on holidays</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/election-aspirants-to-get-e-return-filing-services-on-holidays</link><description>The National Board of Revenue (NBR) has opened a special helpdesk to facilitate submission of online income-tax returns on holidays by individuals intending to contest the upcoming national parliamentary elections.
The initiative will allow prospective candidates to file their e-returns even on we</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 04:43:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Transport services may face disruption due to thick fog: Met office</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/transport-services-may-face-disruption-due-to-thick-fog-met-office</link><description>Moderate to thick fog may temporarily disrupt air navigation, inland river transport and road communication in different parts of the country, according to the Bangladesh Meteorological Department (BMD).
In its regular bulletin, the BMD said moderate to thick fog may occur at places across the cou</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 04:58:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US says it struck IS militants in northwest Nigeria</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-says-it-struck-is-militants-in-northwest-nigeria</link><description>The United States carried out a strike against Islamic State militants in northwest Nigeria at the request of Nigeria's government, President Donald Trump and the US military said on Thursday, claiming the group had been targeting Christians in the region.
"Tonight, at my direction as Commander in</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 05:13:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Japan's cabinet approves record $785 billion budget</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/japans-cabinet-approves-record-785-billion-budget</link><description>Japanese Prime Minister Sanae Takaichi's cabinet on Friday approved a record $785 billion budget for the next fiscal year, aiming to strike a balance between her proactive fiscal policy and debt blowout concerns by limiting new bond issuance.
Faced with rising government bond yields and a weak yen</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 05:30:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Abhaynagar Upazila of Jashore: Charcoal kilns widely harming environment and public health</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/abhaynagar-upazila-of-jashore-charcoal-kilns-widely-harming-environment-and-public-health</link><description>BENAPOLE: The unchecked operation of unauthorised charcoal kilns in Abhaynagar upazila of Jashore has pushed the local environment and public health to the brink of disaster.
Toxic black smoke spewing continuously from the kilns is severely polluting the air, destroying forest resources and causin</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 05:45:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hundreds of 'Death Wells' scattered across Barind fields</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/hundreds-of-death-wells-scattered-across-barind-fields</link><description>The water crisis in the Barind region has no end in sight, but now, poorly planned well drilling is rapidly turning into a serious humanitarian risk. Across vast tracts of farmland in Rajshahi, Naogaon and Chapainawabganj, hundreds of abandoned deep tube wells and test bores lie exposed, silently t</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 06:00:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Four die as launches collide on Meghna River amid dense fog</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/four-die-as-launches-collide-on-meghna-river-amid-dense-fog</link><description>Four people have been killed in a head-on collision between two passenger launches on the Meghna River in Chandpur amid dense fog.
The collision occurred around 2:00 am on Thursday in the Harinaghat area of Chandpur Sadar Upazila, according to BIWTA Chandpur Port Officer Babu Lal Baidya.
Dhaka Di</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 06:47:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BGMEA sets new membership criteria to ensure factory safety, operational standards</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bgmea-sets-new-membership-criteria-to-ensure-factory-safety-operational-standards</link><description>The apex body of the country's apparel sector has introduced a set of new criteria for granting membership, including minimum factory space and machinery requirements, aiming to ensure basic operational and safety standards.
The Bangladesh Garment Manufacturers and Exporters Association (BGMEA) sa</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 07:02:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Textile, cottage industries fair begins in Rajshahi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/textile-cottage-industries-fair-begins-in-rajshahi</link><description>A month-long handloom, textile and cottage industries fair opened in Rajshahi on Thursday.
Organised by the Women Entrepreneurs' Association of Bangladesh (WEAB), Rajshahi chapter, the fair is being held on the northern side of the Rajshahi Central Botanical Garden and Zoo to mark the organisation</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 07:17:12 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>