<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 10:38:58 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Prisoner dies at DMCH</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/prisoner-dies-at-dmch</link><description>An inmate of Dhaka Central Jail died at Dhaka Medical College Hospital (DMCH) on Saturday.
The deceased was identified as Miaz Uddin, 60, son of Binod Ali, reports UNB.
Inspector Md Faruk, in charge of DMCH police camp, said Miaz Uddin fell sick at the jail on Friday night and he was taken to the</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 08:48:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nobel Prize in Physics marks 100 years of Quantum wonders</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/nobel-prize-in-physics-marks-100-years-of-quantum-wonders</link><description>It's been a hundred years since scientists opened the mysterious box of quantum theory. The questions have only grown stranger. This year, the Nobel Prize in Physics goes to three researchers—John Clark, Michelle Deere, and John Martinez—for their groundbreaking work on quantum tunnelli</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 09:03:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Security beefed up at Ctg airport, port amid fears of cyber attack</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/security-beefed-up-at-ctg-airport-port-amid-fears-of-cyber-attack</link><description>Authorities have strengthened security in and around Shah Amanat International Airport and the seaport amid fears of possible cyberattacks.
To prevent any untoward incidents, the airport and police authorities have taken joint precautionary measures including setting up a four-tier security cordon</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 09:18:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Duelling protests sparked by July fighter's 'harassment' paralyses Dhaka-Mymensingh traffic</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/duelling-protests-sparked-by-july-fighters-harassment-paralyses-dhaka-mymensingh-traffic</link><description>Road communication between Dhaka and Mymensingh has been disrupted following duelling protests by students and transport workers after a gazetted July fighter was allegedly harassed on a United Service bus.
Members of the Students Against Discrimination and transport workers staged counter demonst</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 09:38:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Battle lines drawn over Confederate tribute at Georgia's Stone Mountain</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/battle-lines-drawn-over-confederate-tribute-at-georgias-stone-mountain</link><description>The heroic images of three Confederate leaders carved into the granite face of Georgia's Stone Mountain have towered over the countryside outside Atlanta since the 1970s, paying silent homage to the Southern cause in the US Civil War.
Its supporters say the monument - often compared with Mou</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 09:53:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP's Moyeen Khan rejects proportional representation system</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnps-moyeen-khan-rejects-proportional-representation-system</link><description>Strongly opposing the introduction of a proportional representation (PR) system, BNP senior leader Dr Abdul Moyeen Khan on Saturday said it would only strengthen political parties while weakening the link between people and their elected representatives, ultimately causing suffering for the public.</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 10:08:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Elections and referendum on same day? Consensus panel to ask government to decide</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/elections-and-referendum-on-same-day-consensus-panel-to-ask-government-to-decide</link><description>The National Consensus Commission will propose that the government decide whether to hold the national election and the referendum at the same time, panel member Badiul Alam Majumdar has said.
He made the remarks on Saturday while speaking at a “Shadow Parliament” organised by Debate f</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 10:38:58 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>