<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 10:25:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Denmark eyes new law to protect citizens from AI deepfakes</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/denmark-eyes-new-law-to-protect-citizens-from-ai-deepfakes</link><description>In 2021, Danish video game live-streamer Marie Watson received an image of herself from an unknown Instagram account.
She instantly recognised the holiday snap from her Instagram account, but something was different: Her clothing had been digitally removed to make her appear naked. It was a deepfa</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 07:40:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat warns of tougher programmes to secure pre-election referendum</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-warns-of-tougher-programmes-to-secure-pre-election-referendum</link><description>Jamaat-e-Islami has warned that the party will resort to a tougher action if necessary to secure a referendum before the national election.
Speaking at a brief rally at Paltan intersection shortly before 11:45 am on Thursday, the party’s deputy chief Syed Abdullah Mohammad Taher said the mov</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 07:55:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Former Exim Bank MD Feroz Hossain arrested in Tk 8.57b embezzlement case</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/former-exim-bank-md-feroz-hossain-arrested-in-tk-857b-embezzlement-case</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) on Thursday arrested former Exim Bank MD and CEO Mohammad Feroz Hossain over embezzlement of Tk 8.57 billion.
A team led by ACC Assistant Director Shahjahan Miraj apprehended him from the Segunbagicha area of the capital around midday on November 6. He is expec</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 08:25:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ex-minister Abdul Latif Siddique secures HC bail</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ex-minister-abdul-latif-siddique-secures-hc-bail</link><description>The High Court on Thursday granted bail to former minister Abdul Latif Siddique in a case filed under the Anti-Terrorism Act.
The HC bench of Justice ASM Abdul Mobin and Justice Md Sagir Hossain passed the order after hearing a petition seeking bail for him.
The court also granted bail to journal</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 09:10:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt plans ordinance to punish airline ticket syndicates in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/govt-plans-ordinance-to-punish-airline-ticket-syndicates-in-bangladesh</link><description>The government is set to promulgate an ordinance amending the Civil Aviation Act, 2017, to curb the activities of airline ticket syndicates.
The Ministry of Civil Aviation and Tourism has drafted the Civil Aviation (Amendment) Ordinance, 2025, in this regard, according to sources at the ministry.</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 09:25:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP’s Mosharraf calls on people to unite for fair Feb election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnps-mosharraf-calls-on-people-to-unite-for-fair-feb-election</link><description>BNP senior leader Khandaker Mosharraf Hossain on Thursday urged people from all walks of life to extend their cooperation in holding the next national election in February next year, foiling all conspiracies to derail it.
“It seems to us that there is no scope for deferring the election from</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 09:55:52 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>