<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 06:37:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>15 years of investment, little modal shift</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/15-years-of-investment-little-modal-shift</link><description>An enormous amount of money had been invested in developing Bangladesh's communications system over the past 15 years but modal transport share remained heavily skewed toward overburdened roads for no significant shift to rail, water, or air transport.
A baseline study carried out under the Nation</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 02:36:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nearly 200 BNP leaders file as independents, defying party decision</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/nearly-200-bnp-leaders-file-as-independents-defying-party-decision</link><description>After seven years off the ballot, hundreds of Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) leaders sought the party’s "sheaf of paddy" symbol – and many were refused. Now, in open defiance of the high command, just under 200 of them have filed nomination papers to run against BNP’s own cand</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 03:36:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP announces seven days of mourning</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/khaleda-zias-death-bnp-announces-seven-days-of-mourning</link><description>The Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) has announced seven days of mourning following the death of its chairperson and former prime minister Khaleda Zia.
The party’s Senior Joint Secretary General Ruhul Kabir Rizvi announced the decision on Tuesday at Dhaka’s Evercare Hospital, bdnews2</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 04:37:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prof Yunus mourns death of former Prime Minister Khaleda Zia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/prof-yunus-mourns-death-of-former-prime-minister-khaleda-zia</link><description>Chief Adviser Prof Muhammad Yunus on Tuesday expressed profound sorrow at the death of three-time former Prime Minister and BNP Chairperson Begum Khaleda Zia, describing her as a towering figure in the country’s democratic movement.
“With the sad demise of Begum Khaleda Zia, the nation</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 03:38:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat Ameer mourns Khaleda Zia’s death</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-ameer-mourns-khaleda-zias-death</link><description>Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami Ameer Dr Shafiqur Rahman has expressed profound sorrow over the death of former Prime Minister Khaleda Zia.
In a post shared on the social media platform Facebook on Tuesday morning, the Jamaat Ameer prayed for Khaleda Zia, UNB reports.
In his message, the Jamaat Ameer</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 03:53:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chief Adviser calls Council of Advisers to discuss Khaleda Zia’s burial: Fakhrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/chief-adviser-calls-council-of-advisers-to-discuss-khaleda-zias-burial-fakhrul</link><description>Chief Adviser Prof Muhammad Yunus has called BNP leaders to inform them that the Council of Advisers will discuss issues, including state honour and burial arrangements for former Prime Minister and BNP Chairperson Begum Khaleda Zia, BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir said on Tuesday</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 04:08:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khaleda Zia embodied Bangladesh’s democratic aspirations: Chinese envoy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/khaleda-zia-embodied-bangladeshs-democratic-aspirations-chinese-envoy</link><description>Extending his deepest condolences, Chinese Ambassador to Bangladesh Yao Wen on Tuesday said BNP Chairperson and former Prime Minister Begum Khaleda Zia has long embodied Bangladesh’s democratic aspirations and stood as a steadfast champion of freedom.
"With profound sorrow and a heavy heart,</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 04:23:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CA to address nation around 12 noon</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ca-to-address-nation-around-12-noon</link><description>Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus will address the nation around 12:00 noon today (Tuesday).
Bangladesh Television (BTV) and Bangladesh Betar will broadcast the address simultaneously, the Chief Adviser's Press Wing said.</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 04:38:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pakistan leaders convey condolences on Khaleda Zia’s death</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/pakistan-leaders-convey-condolences-on-khaleda-zias-death</link><description>Pakistan has expressed deep grief over the death of former Bangladesh prime minister and Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) chairperson Begum Khaleda Zia, who passed away early Tuesday at 6:00 am.
In separate statements posted on X, President Asif Ali Zardari, Prime Minister Shehbaz Sharif, and De</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 04:53:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Modi condoles death of Begum Khaleda Zia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/modi-condoles-death-of-begum-khaleda-zia</link><description>Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi today expressed deep sorrow at the death of former Bangladesh Prime Minister and BNP Chairperson Begum Khaleda Zia, recalling her contributions to Bangladesh and bilateral relations.
In a condolence message, Modi said, "Deeply saddened to learn about the passing</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 05:08:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Supradip Chakma mourns death of Khaleda Zia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/supradip-chakma-mourns-death-of-khaleda-zia</link><description>Chittagong Hill Tracts Affairs Adviser Supradip Chakma today expressed deep shock and sorrow at the death of former Prime Minister and Chairperson of Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) Begum Khaleda Zia.
In a condolence message, Supradip Chakma said Begum Khaleda Zia was a three-time elected prime</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 05:23:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India's domination of global rice trade stokes looming water crisis</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/indias-domination-of-global-rice-trade-stokes-looming-water-crisis</link><description>When India overtook China as the world's largest producer of rice this year, the country's politicians and agriculture lobby marked the moment by praising resilient farmers and innovative government policy.
India has nearly doubled the amount of rice it exported over the past decade, with shipment</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 05:38:17 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>