<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 12:48:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Bangladesh undergoing major transformation ahead of historic election: CA</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-undergoing-major-transformation-ahead-of-historic-election-ca</link><description>Chief Adviser Prof Muhammad Yunus on Wednesday conveyed to a visiting Canadian parliamentary delegation that Bangladesh is now preparing for the national election, which will be a historic moment for the nation.
“You’ve come at a time when Bangladesh is undergoing a significant transfo</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 10:00:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pay scale process involves multiple commissions, layers of approval: Salehuddin</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/pay-scale-process-involves-multiple-commissions-layers-of-approval-salehuddin</link><description>Finance Adviser Dr Salehuddin Ahmed on Wednesday said the process of pay scale implementation involves several independent commissions and multiple layers of administrative approval.
“The work of the Pay Commission is highly complex and independent. There is no government role in determining</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 10:15:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EU wants election to succeed: Khosru</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/eu-wants-to-see-successful-election-in-bangladesh-says-bnps-khosru</link><description>The European Union is closely monitoring Bangladesh’s next general election and aims to see it held successfully, senior BNP leader Amir Khosru Mahmud Chowdhury has said.
The BNP National Standing Committee member made the statement at a news briefing after a meeting between the EU ambassado</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 10:30:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dense fog, cold winds sweep through Panchagarh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/panchagarh-shivers-at-126c-as-fog-thickens-across-northern-district</link><description>Winter has begun to set in across Panchagarh, Bangladesh’s northernmost border district, as temperatures continue to dip each day.
The chill in the air deepens with the thickening fog, cold mornings, evening breezes, and dew settling over the fields.
The lowest temperature of the season was</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 09:54:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AL leader held over Mymensingh ‘bus torching’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/mymensingh-awami-league-leader-arrested-over-bus-torching</link><description>A case has been filed over the killing of driver Julhas Mia after the torching of a parked bus in Mymensingh’s Fulbaria. Police have arrested an Awami League leader in connection with the incident.
A man named Anowar Hossain was arrested from the Adarsha Bazar area of the Fulbaria Municipali</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 10:09:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Career Compass 2025’ workshop by JCI Manikganj held at IUB</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/career-compass-2025-workshop-by-jci-manikganj-held-at-iub</link><description>To prepare the young generation for future career challenges and help them build confidence for professional life, JCI Manikganj organized a unique workshop titled “Career Compass 2025 – Guiding the Next Generation” with the participation of university students.
The event took pl</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 10:24:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt to decide on body camera purchase for police within days: Finance Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-to-decide-on-body-camera-purchase-for-police-within-days-finance-adviser</link><description>The government is set to make a decision on purchasing body cameras for law enforcement agencies within the next few days, Finance Adviser Dr Salehuddin Ahmed said on Wednesday.
“We will take a decision on the purchase of body cameras after completing a few pending tasks. Hopefully, the matt</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 10:39:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt approves short-term LNG purchase from Singaporean company</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/govt-approves-short-term-lng-purchase-from-singaporean-company</link><description>The government on Wednesday approved in principle a proposal to procure liquefied natural gas (LNG) from Aramco Trading Singapore Pte Ltd on a short-term basis under a Government-to-Government (G2G) arrangement.
The decision was taken at a meeting of Advisers Council Committee on Economic Affairs</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 10:54:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Denmark’s APM Terminals to make record $550m investment in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/denmarks-apm-terminals-to-make-record-550m-investment-in-bangladesh</link><description>Bangladesh is set to receive a record $550 million in foreign direct investment (FDI) from Denmark’s global terminal operator APM Terminals, marking the largest European investment in the country’s history, according to the Public Private Partnership Authority (PPPA).
Speaking at a pre</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 11:09:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>All shops &amp; shopping malls to remain open on Thursday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/all-shops-shopping-malls-to-remain-open-on-thursday-despite-awami-leagues-lockdown-call</link><description>All shops and shopping malls across the country, including those in the capital, will remain open on Thursday as usual, despite the Awami League’s announced ‘lockdown’ programme on the day (November 13).
However, shops in areas that observe a weekly holiday on Thursdays will rema</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 11:24:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Emerging markets including Bangladesh face USD 3.7 trillion annual ESG funding gap: Study</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/emerging-markets-including-bangladesh-face-usd-37-trillion-annual-esg-funding-gap-study</link><description>Emerging economies are grappling with an annual shortfall of USD 3.7 trillion in Environmental, Social, and Governance (ESG) finance required to meet the United Nations Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs) by 2030, according to a new report by Dun &amp; Bradstreet titled “ESG Funding in Emerging</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 11:39:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IMF delegation meets Jamaat representatives</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/imf-delegation-meets-jamaat-representatives</link><description>A delegation from the International Monetary Fund (IMF) on Wednesday held a meeting with representatives of Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami in the afternoon at the party’s central office.
Adviser to the IMF Mission Chief for Bangladesh, Chris Papageorgiou led the IMF delegation, reports BSS.
The</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 11:54:13 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>