<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 03:14:47 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Buddhists highest religious leader Dr Jnanasree Mahathero passes away</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/buddhists-highest-religious-leader-dr-jnanasree-mahathero-passes-away</link><description>Highest religious leader of Bangladeshi Buddhists and Ekushey Award winner, the Supreme Patriarch of Sangha Council of Bangladesh (monastic order) Aggamahapandita Dr Jnanasree Mahathero passed away at a city hospital on Thursday.
He was around 101, hospital and monastery, sources said</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 17:15:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>100,000 yaba sseized from abandoned private car in Ctg</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/100000-yaba-sseized-from-abandoned-private-car-in-ctg</link><description>Police in Chittagong have recovered about 100,000 yaba tablets worth an estimated Tk 30 million from an abandoned private car in the Firingi Bazar area under Kotwali police station.
The operation took place on Thursday around 6:30 p.m. near the old Fishery Ghat area, according to OC Abdul Karim of</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 17:30:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP thanks CA for reaffirming Feb election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-thanks-ca-for-reaffirming-feb-election</link><description>BNP on Thursday thanked the Chief Adviser for reaffirming that the next national election will be held in the first half of February and for announcing that a referendum will take place on the same day.
“The BNP Standing Committee, chaired by Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman, thanked the Chief</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 17:45:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt appoints new DCs in 23 more districts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-appoints-new-dcs-in-23-more-districts</link><description>The government on Thursday night appointed new deputy commissioners (DCs) in 23 districts.
The Ministry of Public Administration issued two separate gazette notifications—one covering 9 districts and the other 14, reports UNB.
The districts include Chattogram, Lakshmipur, Munshiganj, Netrok</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 17:45:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>From newsroom to newsfeed</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/from-newsroom-to-newsfeed</link><description>There was a time when newsrooms set the rhythm of public life. The editor decided what mattered, the reporter chased the facts, and the printing press or the evening bulletin carried the collective heartbeat of a society. But that order has collapsed. Today, the news no longer waits for deadlines;</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 18:00:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Empathy missing from healthcare</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/empathy-missing-from-healthcare</link><description>Tens of thousands of Bangladeshis fly abroad every year not for leisure or business, but for treatment. From India to Thailand or Singapore or even the United States, hospitals have become familiar destinations for Bangladeshi patients seeking quality healthcare. For the affluent, a check-up or sur</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 18:15:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>LDC graduation no guarantee for socio-economic justice</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/ldc-graduation-no-guarantee-for-socio-economic-justice</link><description>Bangladesh's graduation from its least developed country (LDC) status to a developing nation has become highly contentious. While the interim government is in favour of maintaining the timeline for the graduation scheduled for November, 2026, the private sector opposes such a move arguing that the</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 18:30:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>National election, referendum on same day in early Feb: CA</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/national-election-referendum-on-same-day-in-early-feb-ca</link><description>Next national parliamentary election and referendum on constitutional reforms will be held concurrently the same day in early February 2026, Chief Adviser Prof Muhammad Yunus announced Thursday to break a political standoff.



In a televised address to the nation in the afternoon, the head of</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 18:45:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Need for a unified agro-processing regulatory body</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/need-for-a-unified-agro-processing-regulatory-body</link><description>That Bangladesh's agro-processing industry remains mired in layers of regulatory hurdles is no secret. The sector, despite its immense potential to drive export growth, rural employment, and value addition to agricultural produce, continues to struggle with a host of compliance challenges. Exporter</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 19:00:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chief Adviser violates July Charter he signed</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/chief-adviser-violates-july-charter-he-signed</link><description>BNP Standing Committee member Salahuddin Ahmed Thursday said Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus violated the July National Charter which he himself signed.
He said the Chief Adviser had broken the promises made in the charter that was signed at the South Plaza of the National Parliament on Oct</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 02:30:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Polls, referendum on same day against people's will, says Jamaat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/polls-referendum-on-same-day-against-peoples-will-says-jamaat</link><description>Jamaat-e-Islami Secretary-General Mia Golam Porwar said on Thursday that the government announced the national elections and referendum for the same day ignoring the will and demands of the people.
"Chief adviser's announcement has not fulfilled the aspirations of the public," he told the media at</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 02:45:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Finance goes tightfisted, trims ADP down to Tk 2.0t</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/finance-goes-tightfisted-trims-adp-down-to-tk-20t</link><description>Government's finance authority gets further tightfisted with the current development budget downsized by Tk 300 billion to Tk 2.0 trillion, officials say, citing hard times on the economic front in the interim period.
The Finance Division has slashed Annual Development Programme (ADP) outlay for t</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 03:00:50 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>