<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 07:54:33 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Voters will thwart any conspiracy: Tarique</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/voters-will-thwart-any-conspiracy-tarique</link><description>After casting his vote in the parliamentary election and referendum, BNP chief Tarique Rahman has said voters will thwart any “conspiracy” through the ballot box.
He arrived at the Gulshan Model High School polling centre with his wife Zubaida Rahman and daughter Zaima Rahman at 9:35am</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 05:09:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Serial mismatch causes minor hassle at Suritola Centre ; voting continues smoothly</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/serial-mismatch-causes-minor-hassle-at-suritola-centre-voting-continues-smoothly-1</link><description>Voting at Suritola Government Primary School, a polling centre in Dhaka 6 constituency,  witnessed minor disruptions due to serial mismatches in voter lists, but polling officials said the issues were resolved promptly.
Humayun Kabir, the presiding officer at Lutfur Rahman Lane centre, said s</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 05:24:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Election official falls ill, dies at polling centre in Brahmanbaria</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/election-official-falls-ill-dies-at-polling-centre-in-brahmanbaria</link><description>An election official has died while on duty at a polling centre in Brahmanbaria’s Sarail Upazila.
Md Mujahidul Islam, 48, was working at the Nazrul Islam Auditorium Centre (Polling Centre No. 51) when he suddenly fell ill.
His colleagues rescued him and took him to the Sarail Upazila Health</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 05:39:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tasnim Jara alleges polling agents barred from centres in Dhaka-9</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tasnim-jara-alleges-polling-agents-barred-from-centres-in-dhaka-9</link><description>Tasnim Jara, an independent candidate in Dhaka-9, has alleged that her polling agents were forced out of voting centres on various pretexts, raising questions about the fairness of the election.
She made the claims while speaking to reporters at the Khilgaon Model College polling centre on Thursda</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 05:54:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Voter turnout picks up at BAF Ashraf Ali Shaheen School centre in Shewrapara</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/voter-turnout-picks-up-at-baf-ashraf-ali-shaheen-school-centre-in-shewrapara</link><description>A total of 412 voters had cast their ballots at the BAF Ashraf Ali Shaheen School polling centre in Shewrapara as of 11:30 am on Thursday, accounting for 21 per cent of the centre’s 1,907 registered voters.
SM Samiul Islam, presiding officer of the centre, said the turnout was initially low,</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 06:09:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Three presiding officers withdrawn in Faridpur, Jhenaidah</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/three-presiding-officers-withdrawn-in-faridpur-jhenaidah</link><description>Three presiding officers have been withdrawn in Faridpur and Jhenaidah districts over allegations of irregularities while a presiding officer was physically assaulted at a polling centre in Sylhet.
In Faridpur, two presiding officers were withdrawn from separate constituencies over allegations of</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 06:24:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Child, two Ansar members hurt in blast at Gopalganj voting centre</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/child-two-ansar-members-hurt-in-blast-at-gopalganj-voting-centre</link><description>Three people, including a 13-year-old girl, have been injured in an alleged hand bomb attack at a polling station in Gopalganj.
The blast occurred around 9:00 am on Thursday at the Reshma International School centre at Nichupara.
Two members of the Ansar, a paramilitary auxiliary force responsibl</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 06:39:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Come out and vote without fear: Army Chief Waker</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/come-out-and-vote-without-fear-army-chief-waker</link><description>Chief of Army Staff General Waker-Uz-Zaman on Thursday urged voters to come out and cast their ballots without fear, expressing optimism that the election would be free and fair.
"Please come out of your homes without fear, go to the polling stations and cast your votes. This is a very important d</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 06:43:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Steady turnout recorded at Gendaria Mohila Samity School in Dhaka-6</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/steady-turnout-recorded-at-gendaria-mohila-samity-school-in-dhaka-6</link><description>Voter turnout remained steady at the Gendaria Mohila Samity Government Primary School polling centre in the Dhaka-6 constituency as voting continued peacefully on Thursday morning.
Md Tusher, presiding officer of the centre, told The Financial Express that a significant number of voters had cast t</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 06:58:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCP calls emergency press conference at 2:00pm</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ncp-calls-emergency-press-conference-at-200pm</link><description>The National Citizens Party (NCP) has called an emergency press conference at 2:00pm today regarding the overall situation of the ongoing 13th National Parliament elections and referendum across the country and allegations of irregularities in voting.
The party's Central Election Steering Committe</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 07:13:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Women flock to Dhaka polling centres as voting progresses</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/women-flock-to-dhaka-polling-centres-as-voting-progresses</link><description>The number of women voters rose remarkably at polling centres across the capital as voting for Thursday's national election progressed.
Although turnout of female voters was relatively low in the morning, visits to polling centres in Dhaka-5, Dhaka-6, Dhaka-8, Dhaka-9 and Dhaka-11 constituencies s</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 07:28:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Let’s play the full 90 minutes’: NCP’s Patwary to BNP</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/lets-play-the-full-90-minutes-ncps-patwary-to-bnp</link><description>NCP’s Nasiruddin Patwary has told the BNP to “play the full 90 minutes” after his polling agent was delayed and barred from working for three hours at the Mirza Abbas Mohila College centre.
He alleged that party-backed musclemen interfered, preventing proper monitoring, and descr</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 07:43:50 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>