<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 11:18:41 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>India won't rush into trade deals, rejects restrictive conditions: trade min</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/india-wont-rush-into-trade-deals-rejects-restrictive-conditions-trade-minister-says</link><description>India will not rush into signing any trade agreements and will reject conditions from partner countries that restrict its trading choices, Trade Minister Piyush Goyal said on Friday.
The country is negotiating a long-pending free trade agreement with the European Union, with differences remaining</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 09:41:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hobbled by US tariffs, carpet weavers in India's Kashmir struggle to stay afloat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/hobbled-by-us-tariffs-carpet-weavers-in-indias-kashmir-struggle-to-stay-afloat</link><description>Gulzar Ahmad Bhat, a former carpet weaver in India's Jammu and Kashmir region, now sells tea on the shores of the scenic Dal Lake, abandoning his craft of 35 years after increased US tariffs left him unable to afford his children's school fees and medicine for his family of six.
Thousands of India</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 09:56:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump says talks with Canada off after ad invokes Reagan as free-trader</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-says-talks-with-canada-off-after-ad-invokes-reagan-as-free-trader</link><description>US President Donald Trump said on Thursday trade talks with Canada were terminated after a Canadian political advertisement used the recorded voice of late president Ronald Reagan saying tariffs cause trade wars and economic disaster.
Trump, who imposed import tariffs on Canadian steel, aluminum a</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 10:11:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ASEAN Summits in Malaysia should focus on human rights: HRW</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/asean-summits-in-malaysia-should-focus-on-human-rights-hrw</link><description>Governments attending upcoming regional summits in Malaysia should reject the Myanmar military junta's plans to hold "elections" in December 2025, Human Rights Watch said in a letter to all countries sending delegates.
The Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN) and ASEAN partner Summits wi</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 09:27:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Toddler drowns in Bhola pond</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/toddler-drowns-in-bhola-pond</link><description>A two-year-old boy drowned in a pond in isolated island Monpura upazila of Bhola on Friday morning.
The deceased was identified as Md Anmad, son of Md Mosleuddin of Sikdarhat village in ward No-8 of Uttar Sakuchia union.
According to family members, the child was playing near the house and accide</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 09:57:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Reagan 1987 address was defence of free but fair trade</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/reagan-1987-address-was-defence-of-free-but-fair-trade</link><description>The 1987 radio address by the late former US President Ronald Reagan at the centre of a new US-Canada row was a defence of free but fair trade in which he explained his decision to put duties on Japanese goods in a trade dispute.
US President Donald Trump said on Thursday that all trade talks with</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 10:12:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prisoner transfer to new Khulna Jail to begin Sunday: Jailer</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/prisoner-transfer-to-new-khulna-jail-to-begin-sunday-jailer</link><description>The process of transferring prisoners to the newly constructed Khulna District Jail is set to begin on Sunday.
Jailer Munir Hossain said that if any complications arise, the transfer might be delayed by a day or two.
In the first phase, he said, 100 inmates will be moved, with the remaining priso</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 10:27:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No pressure to bring AL into polls: Press Secretary</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/no-pressure-to-bring-al-into-polls-press-secretary</link><description>There is no local or international pressure on the government to bring the ousted Awami League (AL) into the electoral race, Chief Adviser’s Press Secretary Shafiqul Alam said on Friday.
Talking to reporters after placing a wreath at the July Memorial along the banks of the Nabaganga River i</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 10:42:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Partial collapse of Bailey bridge snaps Langadu-Khagrachhari road link</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/partial-collapse-of-bailey-bridge-snaps-langadu-khagrachhari-road-link</link><description>The Bailey bridge in Khagrachhari’s Dighinala has partially collapsed, stranding a covered van along the way and halting passenger bus service from Rangamati’s Langadu to Khagrachhari and the rest of the country.
The accident occurred in the Betchari area of the Dighinala-Langadu road</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 11:12:01 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>