<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 10:47:54 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>HC petition challenges July Charter</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hc-petition-challenges-july-charter</link><description>A writ petition has been filed with the High Court challenging the legality of the July National Charter 2025, a sweeping reform agenda introduced by the now-dissolved interim government led by Prof Dr Muhammad Yunus.
The petitioner argues that key provisions of the Charter, including proposals fo</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 04:37:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>TIB calls for annual asset disclosure by MPs, public officials</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tib-calls-for-annual-asset-disclosure-by-mps-public-officials</link><description>Transparency International Bangladesh (TIB) has called for mandatory annual disclosure of income, expenditure and asset statements by members of parliament and all public office holders to ensure transparency and accountability in governance.
It also urged the formulation and adoption of an integr</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 04:22:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Stocks slide at DSE, CSE in early trading</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/stocks-slide-at-dse-cse-in-early-trading</link><description>Trading at the country’s two bourses witnessed a downward trend in the first half on Thursday, the last working day of the week, with key indices slipping amid a majority of issues closing lower.
At the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE), the benchmark DSEX lost 8 points during the first half</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 09:11:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>PM meets Army, Navy and Air Force chiefs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/pm-meets-army-navy-and-air-force-chiefs</link><description>Prime Minister Tarique Rahman has met with the three service chiefs -- Army Chief Gen Waker-Uz-Zaman, Navy Chief Admiral Mohammad Nazmul Hassan, and Chief of Air Force Chief Marshal Hasan Mahmood Khan.
The meeting took place on Thursday at the Secretariat, Prime Minister’s Additional Press S</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 09:26:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Poor dairy farmers fall in debt in Pabna due to 'Dadan trap'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/poor-dairy-farmers-fall-in-debt-in-pabna-due-to-dadan-trap</link><description>PABNA, FEB 18: Impoverished dairy farmers in Pabna's Bera Char said they have been sustaining serious losses and falling in debt due to cattle traders' conditions on milk selling after the traders' provided them investment to buy and raise dairy cows.
Farmers said they have been considering changi</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 05:22:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Million taka growth centre defunct for 18 years in Sunamganj</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/million-taka-growth-centre-defunct-for-18-years-in-sunamganj</link><description>SYLHET, Feb 18: Sunamganj's Dowarabazar Upazila growth centre, built to be used as the commercial hub for the sale and marketing of kitchen and other items, remained non-operational for nearly two decades.
Sources said "over unknown reasons", the authorities had failed to launch operations at the</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 05:37:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two dead as Army truck, bus collide head-on in Mymensingh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/two-dead-as-army-truck-bus-collide-head-on-in-mymensingh</link><description>Two people have been killed and at least 12 others injured in a head-on collision between an Army truck and a bus in Mymensingh’s Phulpur upazila.
The accident occurred around 10:45am on Wednesday at the Balia intersection on the Sherpur–Mymensingh regional highway, according to Rashed</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 03:37:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Assistant High Commissioner Aniruddha Das says all Indian visa services will be restored ‘soon’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/assistant-high-commissioner-aniruddha-das-says-all-indian-visa-services-will-be-restored-soon</link><description>Aniruddha Das, India’s senior consular official in Sylhet, has said steps are under way to fully restore all visa services.
On Thursday, the Indian assistant high commissioner in Sylhet also assured maximum cooperation to strengthen bilateral ties through visa facilitation.
“Medical a</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 09:41:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Family Card’ to be launched on pilot basis before Eid: Minister Mintoo</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/family-card-to-be-launched-on-pilot-basis-before-eid-minister-mintoo</link><description>The government has planned to introduce ‘Family Card’ on a pilot basis before the upcoming Eid-ul-Fitr, said Environment, Forest and Climate Change Minister Abdul Awal Mintoo on Thursday.
“As far as I know, the Prime Minister wants to begin it as a pilot project before Eid,&amp;rdquo</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 09:56:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Issues with countries to be resolved at bilateral, multilateral forums: Shama Obaed</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/issues-with-countries-to-be-resolved-at-bilateral-multilateral-forums-shama-obaed</link><description>State Minister for Foreign Affairs Shama Obaed on Thursday said Bangladesh has issues and challenges with each country, which will be addressed through discussions at bilateral, regional and multilateral platforms.
Speaking to reporters at the Ministry of Foreign Affairs, she said the current admi</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 10:11:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sherpur-1 BNP candidate Priyanka to challenge election result in court</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/sherpur-1-bnp-candidate-priyanka-to-challenge-election-result-in-court</link><description>BNP candidate Sunsila Jabrin Priyanka has announced plans to move to court, raising objections to the results of the Sherpur-1 (Sadar) constituency in the elections.
On Thursday, she demanded a re-election, reports bdnews24.com.
She lost to Jamaat-e-Islami candidate and former central president o</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 10:26:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘We will defend national interest inch by inch’: Khalilur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/we-will-defend-national-interest-inch-by-inch-khalilur</link><description>Foreign Minister Khalilur Rahman has said the new government will conduct its foreign policy by firmly defending Bangladesh’s national interest, guided by five “core principles”.
Those principles, he said, are sovereign equality, respect for mutual independence, non-interference</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 10:41:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>