<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 12:46:57 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>ICT prosecutors seek charges against Joy, Palak</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ict-prosecutors-seek-charges-against-joy-palak</link><description>Prosecutors at the International Crimes Tribunal have applied for the framing of charges against Sajeeb Wazed Joy, the son of ousted prime minister Sheikh Hasina, and former ICT state minister Zunaid Ahmed Palak, accusing them of involvement in crimes against humanity by shutting down internet se</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 11:19:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BRAC opens applications for BRIDGE Returnship Programme</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/brac-opens-applications-for-bridge-returnship-programme</link><description>BRAC has announced the start of a new application cycle for its BRIDGE Returnship Programme, an initiative supporting women who are looking to return to professional life after a career break.
Through structured opportunities and targeted support, the programme seeks to ease the transition back in</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 09:53:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Confronting protests, Iran vows to strike back if US attacks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/confronting-protests-iran-vows-to-strike-back-if-us-attacks</link><description>Tehran threatened on Sunday to retaliate against Israel and US military bases in the event of US strikes on Iran, issuing the warning as Israeli sources said Israel was on high alert for the possibility of any US intervention.
With Iran's clerical establishment facing the biggest anti-government p</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 10:08:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC distributes leaflets on referendum, National Election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-distributes-leaflets-on-referendum-national-election</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has taken measures to widely distribute banners and leaflets prepared for the upcoming referendum and the 13th National Parliament Election 2026 to be held on February 12.
To create awareness among the public on the occasion of the referendum, 15,000 eco-friendly banne</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 10:23:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt. implementing reforms to foster liberalised economic environment: Bashir</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/govt-implementing-reforms-to-foster-liberalised-economic-environment-bashir</link><description>Commerce Adviser Sk Bashir Uddin said that the government is implementing comprehensive reforms to trade policies and commercial laws to foster a more liberalised, inclusive, and justice-based economic environment on Sunday.
The government is currently finalising changes to the Import Policy Order</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 10:38:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Teknaf child in ICU after being shot across border</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/teknaf-child-in-icu-after-being-shot-across-border</link><description>Huzaifa Afnan, a child wounded by a bullet fired from Myanmar, is in intensive care in Chattogram.
She was admitted to Chattogram Medical College Hospital after the incident earlier on Sunday, bdnews24.com reports.
The ambulance carrying him reached the hospital at 4:30pm, Medical Police Outpost</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 10:53:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ezazul Islam appointed DG of BIBM</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ezazul-islam-appointed-dg-of-bibm</link><description>Dr Md Ezazul Islam has been appointed as Director General (DG) of the Bangladesh Institute of Bank Management (BIBM).
Before taking up this role, Dr. Islam served as Executive Director (Grade-1) in charge of the Monetary Policy Department at Bangladesh Bank and was an active member of the Monetary</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 11:08:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prof Yunus to work on healthcare, youth development, ‘Three Zero’ agenda after polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/prof-yunus-to-work-on-healthcare-youth-development-three-zero-agenda-after-polls</link><description>Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus on Sunday said that his post-election work would focus primarily on three areas - digital healthcare development, youth development and “Three Zero” agenda.
He revealed it as Akie Abe, head of Foundation for Encouragement of Social Contribution, s</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 11:23:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sharp fall in indices drags down trading at DSE, CSE</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/sharp-fall-in-indices-drags-down-trading-at-dse-cse</link><description>Trading at both the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) and the Chittagong Stock Exchange (CSE) ended on a bearish note on Monday as key indices suffered sharp losses, with most stocks closing lower and turnover declining.  On the second trading day of the week, the DSE's benchmark index DSEX drop</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 11:38:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>WH Smith draws up plans to find a new chairman, Sky News reports</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/wh-smith-draws-up-plans-to-find-a-new-chairman-sky-news-reports</link><description>Travel retail group WH Smith is drawing up plans to find a new chairman amid a battle to restore investors' faith in the company, Sky News reported on Sunday.
The search for two new non-executive directors is expected to lead to the recruitment of a candidate capable of replacing Annette Court wit</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 11:53:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>German foreign minister puts emphasis on close ties before US trip</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/german-foreign-minister-puts-emphasis-on-close-ties-before-us-trip</link><description>German Foreign Minister Johann Wadephul emphasised the importance of transatlantic relations on Sunday as he left for a trip to Washington that takes place at a delicate time due to tensions over U.S. interests in Greenland and Venezuela.
“Never before has it been so crucial to invest in the</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 12:08:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh standoff 'a litmus test' for ICC chair Jay Shah, reports NDTV</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/bangladesh-standoff-a-litmus-test-for-icc-chair-jay-shah-reports-ndtv</link><description>The escalating standoff regarding Bangladesh's refusal to travel to India for the T20 World Cup has placed ICC Chairman Jay Shah under severe pressure, according to a report by an Indian media outlet.  The report by NDTV suggests that Shah faces a "stern test" as he attempts to broker a s</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 12:23:31 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>