<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 06:35:05 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Dhaka sees mercury drop to 13.5°C</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dhaka-sees-mercury-drop-to-135c</link><description>The capital on Friday experienced a fall in the mercury, while a mild cold wave swept over some parts of the country, according to the Bangladesh Meteorological Department.
As temperatures fell in Dhaka, people thronged shopping malls and makeshift roadside stalls to buy warm clothes.
The elderly</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 01:49:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sub-regional connectivity subdued by highway land hassles, cost swells</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/sub-regional-connectivity-subdued-by-highway-land-hassles-cost-swells</link><description>A Dhaka-Tamabil highway project for sub-regional connectivity remains subdued as nine years got lost in land-acquisition hassles, thus raising the overall cost to Tk 284.016 billion, officials say.
Roads and Highways Department (RHD) couldn't complete acquiring land during this long time and so th</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 02:04:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Veg, onion, potato prices fall further</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/veg-onion-potato-prices-fall-further</link><description>The prices of vegetables, potatoes, and onions declined more over the past week, while those of chicken and eggs saw a small increase.
Most other commodities remained static at their previous highs, according to market sources.
Newly harvested seed onions (murikata) were sold at Tk 60-80 per kg,</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 02:19:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique Rahman's presence triggers euphoria</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-rahmans-presence-triggers-euphoria</link><description>Tarique Rahman, the acting chairman of the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP), has emerged as a galvanising figure in the political arena after his return to the country on Thursday following 17 years in exile, drawing vast jubilant crowds wherever he has made appearances.
From the moment he set f</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 02:34:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Large-scale manufacturing down 0.78pc in Oct</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/large-scale-manufacturing-down-078pc-in-oct</link><description>The large-scale manufacturing (LSM) sector contracted by 0.78 per cent in October year on year due to a sharp slowdown in the garment industry, according to the latest Bangladesh Bureau of Statistics (BBS) data. LSM, which accounts for about 11 per cent of the gross domestic product (GDP), was drag</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 02:49:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Weekly Market Review: Stocks gain amid major political developments</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/weekly-market-review-stocks-gain-amid-major-political-developments</link><description>The benchmark equity index of Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) rebounded this week, driven by a wave of optimism among investors following growing political clarity surrounding the upcoming national elections.
Market analysts said the investors' optimism over evolving political developments offered some</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 04:20:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Some 767,591 expats, individuals register for postal voting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/some-767591-expats-individuals-register-for-postal-voting</link><description>A total of 767,591 individuals have registered with the 'Postal Vote BD' system to exercise their voting rights remotely for Bangladesh's parliamentary election scheduled for 12 February 2026.
Of the total, 5,42,942 are Bangladeshis living abroad (NRB) while the remaining 2,24,649 are individuals</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 04:35:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>St Martin’s-bound vessel in Cox’s Bazar catches fire</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/st-martins-bound-vessel-in-coxs-bazar-catches-fire</link><description>A fire broke out on a passenger vessel bound for St Martin’s Island in Cox’s Bazar on Saturday morning.
Hossain Islam Bahadur, general secretary of the Sea Cruise Operator Owners' Association of Bangladesh (SCOAB), said the fire broke out on The Atlantic Cruise around 7:00 am while it</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 04:50:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Man dies in fire on St Martin’s-bound vessel in Cox’s Bazar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/man-dies-in-fire-on-st-martins-bound-vessel-in-coxs-bazar</link><description>A man has been killed after a fire broke out on a St Martin's Island-bound vessel anchored in Cox’s Bazar.
The fire started around 6:30 am on Saturday on the Atlantic Cruise ship while it was anchored on the Bakkhali River near the Nunia Chhara BIWTA jetty, according to Syed Muhammad Morshed</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 05:07:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Inquilab Moncho clears Shahbagh for Tarique Rahman’s visit to Osman Hadi’s grave</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/inquilab-moncho-shifts-shahbagh-blockade-for-tarique-rahmans-visit-to-osman-hadis-grave</link><description>Inquilab Moncho on Saturday moved its blockade from Shahbagh to in front of Aziz Super Market ahead of the arrival of BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman.
The platform withdrew the blockade from Shahbagh around 8:30 am and took position near Aziz Super Market.
In a post on its official Facebook pa</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 05:22:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Myanmar goes to the polls amid civil war and humanitarian crisis</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/myanmar-goes-to-the-polls-amid-civil-war-and-humanitarian-crisis</link><description>Myanmar heads to the polls on Sunday as it battles a civil war that has ravaged parts of the country as well as one of Asia's worst humanitarian crises.
Already one of Southeast Asia's poorest countries, Myanmar has been hammered by a conflict triggered by a 2021 coup in which the military ousted</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 05:37:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Zelenskiy to hold talks with Trump on Sunday on ending Ukraine war</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/zelenskiy-to-hold-talks-with-trump-on-sunday-on-ending-ukraine-war</link><description>Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelenskiy wants to discuss territorial issues, the main stumbling block in talks to end the war, with US President Donald Trump in Florida on Sunday, as a 20-point peace framework and a security guarantee deal near completion.
Announcing the meeting, Zelenskiy said "a</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 05:52:31 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>