<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 19:18:18 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>N’ganj child killed for screaming during ‘attempted rape’: Police</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/three-in-narayanganj-kill-child-for-screaming-during-attempted-rape-say-police</link><description>A fifth-grader in Narayanganj’s Bandar Upazila has been abducted and strangled to death after she screamed while resisting an attempted rape, police say.
Bandar Police chief Golam Muktar Ashraf said one of the three arrested suspects gave a confessional statement under Section 164 on Wednesd</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 15:57:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AB Bank opens its sub-branch at Kankirhat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ab-bank-opens-its-sub-branch-at-kankirhat</link><description>AB Bank PLC inaugurated its Kankirhat sub-branch on December 24, 2025, as the 60th sub-branch of the bank. The sub-branch is located at Bhuiyan Market, Birkot, Kesharpar, Senbug, Noakhali, according to a press release.
Mr. Reazul Islam, Managing Director and CEO (Acting), AB Bank inaugurated the s</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 16:12:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Democrats urge Trump to reverse mass ambassador recalls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/democrats-urge-trump-to-reverse-mass-ambassador-recalls</link><description>Democratic senators urged President Donald Trump on Wednesday to reverse a recall of nearly 30 career ambassadors, warning the move leaves a dangerous leadership vacuum that allows adversaries like Russia and China to expand their reach.
The Trump administration in recent days has ordered more tha</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 15:57:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Between giants: Bangladesh's strategy in the Indo-Pacific</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/between-giants-bangladeshs-strategy-in-the-indo-pacific</link><description>Bangladesh is presently at a crucial juncture-it is in a transition period and undergoing a visionary shift in its foreign policy. It is a fact that the pragmatic doctrine of "friendship to all, and malice towards none" has enabled Bangladesh to keep itself intact for the past several decades. Howe</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 16:12:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Vietnam's apparel export strategy lesson for BD</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/vietnams-apparel-export-strategy-lesson-for-bd</link><description>Bangladesh and Vietnam are often presented as close rivals in the global apparel industry, with export figures suggesting a neck-and-neck race for a larger share of global apparel market. In 2024, Bangladesh exported garments worth USD 38.48 billion, accounting for 6.9 per cent of the global market</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 16:27:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fruit production is on a roll</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/fruit-production-is-on-a-roll</link><description>A quiet revolution is taking place in the country's agriculture sector. Gone are the days when an overwhelming emphasis was put on production of cereals. At least a segment of farmers are getting smarter to opt for cultivation of cash crops, mainly fruits. Apart from traditional fruit cultivation,</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 16:42:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Postal vote registration until Dec 31</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-extends-postal-vote-registration-deadline-to-dec-31</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has extended the deadline for voter registration through the Postal Vote BD app until Dec 31 for the parliamentary elections and referendum.
EC Secretary Akhtar Ahmed announced the decision at a briefing at the Nirbachan Bhabsn on Wednesday.
The deadline was originall</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 16:57:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Netanyahu coalition pushes Oct 7 attack probe</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/netanyahu-coalition-pushes-contentious-oct-7-attack-probe-families-call-for-justice</link><description>Israel's parliament gave the initial go-ahead on Wednesday for a government-empowered inquiry into the surprise Oct 7, 2023 attack by Hamas on southern Israel rather than the expected independent investigation demanded by families of the victims.
Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu has resisted call</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 17:12:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique arrives at Heathrow en route home</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-rahman-arrives-at-heathrow-airport-en-route-to-bangladesh</link><description>After 17 years in exile, BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman has arrived at Heathrow Airport in London as he prepares to return to Bangladesh.
He was accompanied by his wife Zubaida Rahman and their daughter Zaima Rahman.
They reached the airport around 10:30pm Bangladesh time on Wednesday.
Leade</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 17:44:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique Rahman’s return: Barishal BNP heads to Dhaka in festive procession</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-rahmans-return-barishal-bnp-sets-off-for-dhaka-with-festive-launch-procession</link><description>Leaders and activists of Barishal BNP set off for Dhaka on Wednesday night in a fleet of launches, celebrating Tarique Rahman’s return with fireworks and traditional drums.
The launch convoy began departing the ghats one after another after 9:30 pm, carrying party members from across the dis</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 17:59:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique Rahman’s return: Chhatra Dal leader beaten dead en route to Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-rahmans-return-chhatra-dal-leader-killed-en-route-to-dhaka-event</link><description>A union-level Chhatra Dal leader in Bhola was stabbed to death Wednesday evening while traveling to Dhaka to attend the homecoming event of BNP acting chairman Tarique Rahman.
The incident occurred in the Closer Bazar area, reportedly stemming from a longstanding personal feud.
The deceased, Rezw</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 19:01:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt ignores majority opinion about good governance</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-ignores-majority-opinion-about-good-governance</link><description>The government does not take into cognizance the opinion of nearly 73 per cent of the population about establishing good governance, an official survey shows, which indicates roots of graft and recurrent political crisis.
If political interference is added, the rate of indifference rises to 78 per</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 19:16:47 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>