<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 05:59:06 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Battery sector minimum wage proposed at Tk 13,275</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/battery-sector-minimum-wage-proposed-at-tk-13275</link><description>The Minimum Wage Board has proposed a new minimum monthly wage of Tk 13,275 for workers in the battery manufacturing sector.
Under the proposal, workers would also receive a 5.0 per cent annual wage increment, along with a risk allowance for those directly engaged in the sector.
The Board under t</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 02:15:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh-Algeria Business Forum hosts Iftar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladesh-algeria-business-forum-hosts-iftar</link><description>The Embassy of the People's Democratic Republic of Algeria in Dhaka and the Bangladesh-Algeria Business Forum jointly hosted an Iftar gathering on Wednesday, bringing together distinguished guests from various sectors in Bangladesh.
The event reflected the growing friendship and cooperation betwee</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 02:30:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Amid efforts to save nature, economic uncertainty grips St Martin's Island</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/amid-efforts-to-save-nature-economic-uncertainty-grips-st-martins-island</link><description>COX'S BAZAR, Feb 25: As the holy month of Ramadan starts, residents of St Martin's Island, Bangladesh's only coral island, are facing mounting economic hardship. With tourism suspended for nine consecutive months effective from February 1, thousands of fishermen, labourers and small business owners</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 02:45:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt moves to revive Ati Khal in Keraniganj</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-moves-to-revive-ati-khal-in-keraniganj</link><description>The government has taken an initiative to recover and rejuvenate Ati Khal, a canal locally known as a "dead stretch" of the Buriganga River, in Keraniganj, on the outskirts of the capital.
The move aims to restore drainage capacity, revive inland navigation, and improve the local environment throu</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 03:00:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Withdraw 'false' cases against journalists for press freedom, Editors' Council urges govt</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/withdraw-false-cases-against-journalists-for-press-freedom-editors-council-urges-govt</link><description>The Editors' Council has urged the newly-elected government to withdraw 'false and harassment' cases filed against journalists to ensure press freedom.
Through a media statement on Wednesday, the Council said many false murder cases as well as a number of harassment cases have been filed against j</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 03:15:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt steps up mosquito extermination efforts in city: Health minister</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-steps-up-mosquito-extermination-efforts-in-city-health-minister</link><description>Health and Family Welfare Minister Sardar Md Sakhawat Hossain on Wednesday said the government has launched several initiatives to relieve city dwellers from the nuisance of mosquitoes.
He made the remarks while inspecting the mosquito extermination programme run by Dhaka South City Corporation (D</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 03:30:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BR to sell advance Eid tickets March 3-9</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/br-to-sell-advance-eid-tickets-march-3-9</link><description>The Bangladesh Railway (BR) will start selling advance train tickets for the upcoming Eid journey from March 3, and the sale will continue until March 9. Return journey tickets will be available from March 13 to March 18.
The decision was taken at a preparatory meeting for the upcoming Eid-ul-Fitr</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 03:45:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh’s first drought-resistant soybean brings hope to char areas</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/bangladeshs-first-drought-resistant-soybean-brings-hope-to-char-areas</link><description>In a groundbreaking development for Bangladesh’s agriculture, Gazipur Agricultural University (GAU) has successfully developed the country’s first high drought-tolerant soybean hybrid, named ‘GAU Soybean’.
The achievement comes under the leadership of the distinguishe</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 04:00:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mild earthquake jolts parts of Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/mild-earthquake-jolts-parts-of-bangladesh</link><description>A mild earthquake was felt in Sylhet district and nearby areas on Wednesday night.
The tremor, measuring 5.1 on the Richter scale, was recorded at 10:53 pm, according to the European-Mediterranean Seismological Centre (EMSC).
The EMSC said the epicentre was located in Myanmar. It was about 112 ki</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 04:15:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>British High Commissioner acknowledges Sylhet's 'special relationship' with UK</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/british-high-commissioner-acknowledges-sylhets-special-relationship-with-uk</link><description>British High Commissioner to Bangladesh Sarah Cook has said that the United Kingdom (UK) shares a deep and special relationship with Sylhet.
“Sylhet’s relationship with the UK is very close because around 90 percent of Bangladeshis living in the UK are from Sylhet. Bangladesh&amp;rsq</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 04:30:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ministry of Social Welfare warns public about fake website in its name</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ministry-of-social-welfare-warns-public-about-fake-website-in-its-name</link><description>The government has identified a fake website operating in the name of the Ministry of Social Welfare and warned citizens to remain cautious to avoid possible fraud.
In a statement on Wednesday, the ministry said its official website — www.msw.gov.bd — is functioning normally and</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 04:45:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt forms Cabinet Committees on Law and Order, National Awards</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-forms-cabinet-committees-on-law-and-order-national-awards</link><description>The government has formed a Cabinet Committee on Law and Order and a Cabinet Committee on National Awards.
The Cabinet Division issued a notification in this regard on Wednesday.
Home Minister Salahuddin Ahmed has been named convener of the 10-member Cabinet Committee on Law and Order.
Other mem</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 05:00:54 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>