<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 23:37:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nazrul Islam Khan falls sick, hospitalised</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nazrul-islam-khan-falls-sick-hospitalised</link><description>BNP Standing Committee member Nazrul Islam Khan on Tuesday admitted to United Hospital in the capital’s Gulshan area on Wednesday night due to gallbladder complications.
BNP Standing Committee member Professor AZM Zahid Hossain said Nazrul was hospitalised after doctors found stones in his g</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 17:01:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt committee approves over 55m copies of school textbooks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-committee-approves-over-55m-copies-of-school-textbooks</link><description>A government committee on Tuesday gave approval of a proposal for printing, binding and supplying some 55 million (5.54 crore) copies of textbooks free of cost for secondary-level students for the 2026 academic year.
The textbooks will be distributed among students of class 9, Dakhil class 9, SSC</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 17:16:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Woman found dead in travel bag in Narayanganj</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/woman-found-dead-in-travel-bag-in-narayanganj</link><description>Police have recovered the body of a young woman from inside a travel bag in Sonargaon upazila of Narayanganj.
Sonargaon Police chief Rashedul Hasan Khan said the body was found in Mograpara Union around 6:00 pm on Tuesday.
Police said the woman appeared to be around 20 years old, reports bdnews24</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 17:31:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bending NTBs must to unlock BD-EU trade bonanza</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bending-ntbs-must-to-unlock-bd-eu-trade-bonanza</link><description>On a note of readiness to expand trade and investment with Bangladesh, the European Union (EU) has listed out 60 types of non-tariff barriers (NTBs) as major hindrances and sought remedies.  
The 27-nation economic bloc has outlined such barriers under 13 categories in a document compile</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 17:47:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gold price soars to new record, jumps by Tk 2,613 per bhori</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/gold-price-soars-to-new-record-jumps-by-tk-2613-per-bhori</link><description>The Bangladesh Jewellers Association (BAJUS) has once again raised gold prices by Tk 2,613 per bhori (11.664 grams), setting a new record high in the domestic market, just a day after the previous hike.
With the latest adjustment, the price of 22-carat gold now stands at Tk 216,332 per bhori, effe</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 18:02:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prof Yunus to return home Wednesday morning from Italy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/prof-yunus-to-return-home-wednesday-morning-from-italy</link><description>Chief Adviser Prof Muhammad Yunus is scheduled to return home on Wednesday morning as he wrapped up his two-day visit in Italy with a series of meetings.
He left Rome for Dhaka at 7:20pm (Italian Time) concluding his two-day visit to the Italian capital, Chief Adviser’s Deputy Press Secretar</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 18:17:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh at the Crossroads</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/bangladesh-at-the-crossroads</link><description>Bangladesh finds itself at a watershed moment in its economic life today. Previously regarded with disdain, as a frontier economy beset by inherent problems, Bangladesh has registered tangible gains in its efforts to eliminate obstacles that had discouragingly deterred investment across its borders</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 18:32:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Empowering rural women beyond donor dependency</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/empowering-rural-women-beyond-donor-dependency</link><description>Every year, International Rural Women's Day reminds us of the indispensable role rural women play in ensuring food security, sustaining families, and driving the local economy. Yet, behind this celebration lies an uncomfortable truth: many of the initiatives that have improved the lives of rural wo</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 18:47:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Unlocking the stalled potential of CMSMEs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/unlocking-the-stalled-potential-of-cmsmes</link><description>Cottage, Micro, Small and Medium Enterprises (CMSMEs) are often described as the backbone of Bangladesh's economy. They account for nearly 85 per cent of the country's industrial base, employ around 11.8 million people and contribute close to 28 per cent of GDP. Yet, despite their importance, CMSME</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 19:33:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Law to ensure data security, privacy of citizens</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/law-to-ensure-data-security-privacy-of-citizens</link><description>In this data-driven digital age, the challenge of safeguarding personal information from unauthorized access and use is daunting. Reports of data breach leading to loss of sensitive data on financial transactions, medical history, biometric information, to name but a few, abound. Against this backd</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 19:48:13 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>