<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 12:53:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>9 more cos relegated to Z category</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/9-more-cos-relegated-to-z-category</link><description>Nine more companies were downgraded to the Z category on the Dhaka bourse with effect from Sunday, as they failed to hold annual general meetings (AGMs) within the stipulated timeframe.
Among the firms, Alif Industries, Best Holdings, Gemini Sea Food, First Securities Islami Bank, and Beach Hatche</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 09:45:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump warns of ‘very strong’ action against Iran after Venezuela operation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-warns-of-very-strong-action-against-iran-after-venezuela-operation</link><description>US President Donald Trump has warned of direct military action against Iran following a recent US operation in Venezuela, saying Washington would respond with “very strong force” if protesters are killed again amid ongoing unrest in the country.
Speaking to reporters aboard Air Force O</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 10:00:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Inflation rises in December</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/inflation-rises-in-december</link><description>Inflation increased in December on a point-to-point basis, driven by higher prices of both food and non-food items, according to the latest data from the Bangladesh Bureau of Statistics (BBS).Overall inflation stood at 8.49 per cent in December, up from 8.29 per cent in November.
Food inflation wa</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 10:15:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Manchester United sack manager Amorim</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/manchester-united-sack-manager-amorim</link><description>Manchester United have sacked head coach Ruben Amorim, the Premier League club said on Monday, a day after they were held to a draw by relegation-threatened Leeds United.
"With Manchester United sitting sixth in the Premier League, the club’s leadership has reluctantly made the decision that</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 10:30:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Postal voting: Registration ends at midnight</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/postal-voting-registration-ends-at-midnight</link><description>The deadline for voter registration through the Postal Vote BD app will end at midnight.
The registration started on Nov 19 to enable Bangladeshi expatriates and certain groups of citizens inside the country to vote in the parliamentary polls and referendum scheduled to be held on Feb 12.
The Ele</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 10:45:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CA’s condolence message on Khaleda’s death handed over to Tarique</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cas-condolence-message-on-khaledas-death-handed-over-to-tarique</link><description>A condolence message sent by Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus over the death of BNP Chairperson and three-time former Prime Minister Begum Khaleda Zia was handed over to BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman on Monday.
Chief Adviser’s Private Secretary Shazeeb M Khairul Islam delivered th</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 11:00:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Third terminal cannot be opened during interim govt's tenure: Bashir</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/third-terminal-cannot-be-opened-during-interim-govts-tenure-bashir</link><description>Civil Aviation and Tourism Adviser Sheikh Bashir Uddin today (Monday) said the third terminal of Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport (HSIA) cannot be inaugurated during the tenure of the interim government.
He made the remarks while responding to a question at a press conference held at the Sec</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 11:15:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Woman assaulted after robbery allegation in Rangpur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/woman-tied-to-pole-assaulted-by-mob-after-robbery-allegation-in-rangpur</link><description>A woman has been tied to an electric pole and assaulted in Rangpur city after being accused of robbery.
Footage of the incident has since gone viral on social media.
Rangpur Kotwali Police chief (OC) Shajahan said that the incident took place near Medical Mor in the city on Monday afternoon.
&amp;ld</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 11:30:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jara appeals EC decision, vows legal fight</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tasnim-jara-challenges-ec-rejection-vows-legal-fight-for-dhaka-9-race-as-independent</link><description>Former NCP leader Tasnim Jara has filed an appeal with the Election Commission (EC), announcing she will pursue legal action to contest in the Dhaka-9 seat as an independent candidate.
Speaking to journalists at the EC office on Monday after submitting her appeal, Jara said she would continue the</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 11:45:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Lawyer sends legal notice seeking school closure in Ramadan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/sc-lawyer-sends-legal-notice-seeking-month-long-school-closure-for-ramadan</link><description>A Supreme Court lawyer has served a legal notice to the government, seeking closure of all educational institutions for the entire month of Ramadan.
Advocate Md Elyas Ali Mondal sent the notice in public interest on Monday, challenging a recent notification issued by the education ministry to keep</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 12:00:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sammilito Islami Bank draws Tk 440m deposits in two days</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/sammilito-islami-bank-attracts-tk-440m-in-deposits-in-first-two-days-of-operations</link><description>Sammilito Islami Bank received deposits amounting to Tk 440 million in the first two days of its operation.
BB Governor Dr Ahsan H. Mansur disclosed this at a press briefing on Monday at the BB headquarters, where the newborn Islamic bank’s Chairman Dr Ayub Miah, administrators of the five</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 12:15:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>449th Board Meeting of Al-Arafah Islami Bank held</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/449th-board-meeting-of-al-arafah-islami-bank-held</link><description>The 449th Board meeting of Al-Arafah Islami Bank PLC. was held on Sunday, January 4, 2026, at the bank’s Head Office.
Chairman of the Board of Directors Khwaja Shahriar presided over the meeting, according to a media release. 
The overall business performance of the bank was reviewed a</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 12:30:53 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>