<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 14:27:18 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Remittance inflow increases by 19.5pc in February</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/remittance-inflow-increases-by-195pc-in-february</link><description>Expatriate Bangladeshis sent US$3.02 billion remittances in February, which was around 19.5 percent higher than the corresponding month of the previous year.
Expatriates sent home $2.53 billion in the same month the previous year, according to the latest data from the Bangladesh Bank, BSS reports.</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 12:00:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Global reaction to the killing of Iran’s Khamenei</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/global-reaction-to-the-killing-of-irans-khamenei</link><description>Iran’s Supreme Leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei was killed in US and Israeli strikes, state media confirmed as another wave of attacks hit the country on Sunday.
Below is international reaction to his death.
EUROPEAN UNION FOREIGN POLICY CHIEF KAJA KALLAS
“The death of Ali Khamenei is a</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 12:15:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Where US and Israeli forces struck Iran</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/where-us-and-israeli-forces-struck-iran</link><description>The United States and Israel launched their most ambitious attacks on Iran in decades on Saturday in an operation that killed Supreme Leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei.
The biggest foreign-policy gamble of US President Donald Trump’s presidency comes after he campaigned for reelection as a &amp;ldqu</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 12:30:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Afghanistan says it thwarted a Pakistani airstrike attempt on Bagram Air Base</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/afghanistan-says-it-thwarted-a-pakistani-airstrike-attempt-on-bagram-air-base</link><description>Afghanistan said Sunday it had thwarted attempted airstrikes on Bagram Air Base, the former US military base north of Kabul, while cross-border fighting between Pakistan and Afghanistan stretched into a fourth day.
The fighting has been the most severe between the neighbors for years, with Pakista</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 12:45:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>PM orders urgent measures for safety of Bangladeshis in Middle East</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/pm-orders-urgent-measures-for-safety-of-bangladeshis-in-middle-east</link><description>Prime Minister Tarique Rahman has ordered urgent measures to ensure the safety of Bangladeshi nationals in Iran and across the Middle East amid escalating regional conflict, as flight cancellations and fears of rising fuel prices add to mounting concern.
After arriving at his office at the se</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 13:00:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Oil jumps 10pc on Iran conflict and could spike to $100 a barrel, analysts say</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/oil-jumps-10pc-on-iran-conflict-and-could-spike-to-100-a-barrel-analysts-say</link><description>Brent crude jumped 10 percent to about $80 a barrel over the counter on Sunday, oil traders said, while analysts predicted that prices could climb as high as $100 after US and Israeli strikes on Iran plunged the Middle East into a new war.
“While the military attacks are themselves supportiv</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 12:30:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Six people killed after missile strike on Israeli town of Beit Shemesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/six-people-killed-after-missile-strike-on-israeli-town-of-beit-shemesh-ambulance-service-says</link><description>Six people were killed after a missile strike on the Israeli town of Beit Shemesh, the Israeli ambulance service said on Sunday.</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 12:45:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh keeps fuel prices steady for March</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladesh-keeps-fuel-prices-steady-for-march</link><description>The government has kept the retail prices of all major fuel oils unchanged for March.
The existing rates for diesel, octane, petrol and kerosene would remain in force under the revised automatic fuel pricing guideline, the Ministry of Power, Energy, and Mineral Resources said in a gazette notifica</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 13:00:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DSE index drops 138 points amid Middle East tensions</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/dse-index-drops-138-points-amid-middle-east-tensions</link><description>The benchmark index of the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) lost more than 138.56 points on Sunday as investors dumped their holdings, fearing a further fall amid the intensified Middle East crisis.
US-Israel jointly launched a strike on Iran on Saturday that killed Iranian Supreme Leader Ayatollah Ali</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 13:15:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Five DCs removed</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/five-dcs-removed</link><description>Amid a major administrative reshuffle, the government has removed five deputy commissioners (DCs) from districts across the country.
The Ministry of Public Administration issued a notification in this regard on Sunday.
According to the notification, the DCs of Gazipur, Panchagarh, Kushtia, Netrok</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 13:30:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>2 construction workers die after falling from Chattogram building</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/2-construction-workers-die-after-falling-from-chattogram-building</link><description>Two construction workers died after falling from an under-construction building in Anwara upazila of Chattogram district on Sunday.
The deceased were identified as Siam, 19 of Kushtia district and Anis, 25 of Rajshahi district.
The accident occurred in the afternoon in the Gundhipara area when th</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 13:45:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Work underway to bring relief in city dwellers life: DNCC Administrator</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/work-underway-to-bring-relief-in-city-dwellers-life-dncc-administrator</link><description>Administrator of Dhaka North City Corporation (DNCC) Shafiqul Islam Khan has said they are ready to work round the clock to restore comfort and relief of the city dwellers.
Talking to the reporters after visiting Korail slum this afternoon, he said, “From our position we are continuously wor</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 14:00:46 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>