<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 23:20:36 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Guinea-Bissau army officers take control after disputed vote, RFI reports</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/guinea-bissau-army-officers-take-control-after-disputed-vote-rfi-reports</link><description>A group of senior army officers announced on Wednesday that they have seized control of Guinea-Bissau "until further notice," following the West African nation's disputed presidential election, French radio RFI reported.</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 16:19:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BB revises criteria for bank MD, CEO appointments</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bb-revises-criteria-for-bank-md-ceo-appointments</link><description>Bangladesh Bank has revised the requirements for appointing managing directors (MDs) and chief executive officers (CEOs) of bank companies.
The central bank’s Banking Regulation and Policy Department (BRPD) announced the revision in a circular on Wednesday. 
The circular amends Section</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 16:08:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ex-BCL leader expelled, stripped of DUCSU post</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/dhaka-university-cancels-former-chhatra-league-leader-rabbanis-studentship-ducsu-seat</link><description>Dhaka University administration has struck former Bangladesh Chhatra League general secretary Golam Rabbani off the roll, while also annulling his position as general secretary of the central students’ union (DUCSU).
He was elected as DUCSU general secretary in 2019.
Proctor Associate Prof</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 16:23:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>166 Upazilas get new UNOs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/government-appoints-166-new-upazila-administrators-ahead-of-elections</link><description>The interim government has transferred and appointed 166 new Upazila administrators (UNOs) in a single-day administrative reshuffle ahead of the general elections.
On Wednesday, the public administration ministry issued notifications assigning senior assistant secretary-level officers to the new p</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 16:38:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Clash breaks out at Khulna rally over demand to release Baul artiste</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/clash-breaks-out-at-khulna-rally-over-demand-to-release-baul-artiste</link><description>A rally in Khulna protesting the nationwide attacks on shrines and Sufi sites -- and demanding the release of Baul Abul Sarkar -- has been attacked, leaving several activists of the left-leaning Democratic Students’ Alliance injured.
The incident unfolded around 5pm at Shibbari Mor, said Kab</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 16:53:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ICT releases full verdict on Hasina, Kamal’s death penalty</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ict-releases-full-verdict-on-hasina-kamals-death-penalty</link><description>The International Crimes Tribunal (ICT)-1 on Wednesday released the full text of its 453-page judgment that convicted and sentenced ousted prime minister Sheikh Hasina and former home minister Asaduzzaman Khan Kamal to death for crimes against humanity committed during last year’s July Mass U</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 17:08:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Banks’ NPL balloons to  Tk 6.44t in Sept count</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/banks-npl-balloons-to-tk-644t-in-sept-count</link><description>Banks in Bangladesh gasp under a burden of bad loans as the aggregate volume makes a quantum leap by over Tk 2.24 trillion in just six months to a record high until September.
As per latest-available data until last September, with the fast rise in non-performing loans (NPLs), the outstanding of t</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 17:23:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khaleda Zia’s breathing improves, says BNP</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/khaleda-zias-breathing-improves-says-bnp</link><description>BNP Chairperson Khaleda Zia’s breathing difficulty has eased after an infection in her heart and lungs, the party’s health affairs secretary has said. 
A medical board is providing necessary treatment while she remains in a cabin under intense observation, Dr Rafiqul Islam said, &amp;</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 17:38:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>International liner trade of Bangladesh--partnering with leading terminal operators</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/international-liner-trade-of-bangladesh-partnering-with-leading-terminal-operators</link><description>The recent initiatives of the interim government of Bangladesh in the terminal operations of Chittagong port, awarding two terminals to global operators, as well as the operations of Pangaon inland terminal have raised controversies. Reading the reports and submissions at the apex court and argumen</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 17:53:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Antimicrobial resistance threat looms large</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/antimicrobial-resistance-threat-looms-large</link><description>Antimicrobial Resistance (AMR), a growing global public health threat, is severely affecting the management of infectious diseases. Microorganisms are increasingly developing the ability to resist the killing effects of antimicrobials (AMs), rendering these drugs less effective or even completely u</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 18:08:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Beyond demolition of vulnerable buildings</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/beyond-demolition-of-vulnerable-buildings</link><description>The deployment of eight teams by the Rajdhani Unnayan Kartipakkha (RAJUK) following the Friday's powerful quake and three more tremors the next day to assess the vulnerabilities of buildings in Dhaka is a welcome move. It has identified 300 buildings out of 3,252 already assessed at quake risks. Th</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 18:23:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>45th BCS results released after three years, 1,807 cleared for hiring</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/45th-bcs-results-released-after-three-years-1807-cleared-for-hiring</link><description>The Public Service Commission (PSC) has released the final results of the 45th BCS, nearly three years after the circular was issued, recommending 1,807 candidates for cadre posts.
The PSC published the results at 11pm on Wednesday, said spokesperson SM Matiur Rahman, with details now available on</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 19:23:04 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>