<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 17:20:17 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Bangladesh Polls: Nomination paper submission closes Monday; 99pc yet to file</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-polls-nomination-paper-submission-closes-monday-99pc-yet-to-file</link><description>With the deadline for submitting nomination papers for the upcoming national election falling on Monday, nearly 99 percent of aspirants who collected the forms have yet to file them as they are waiting for the last day.
“A total of 2,780 nomination papers were collected to contest the electi</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 14:38:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique signs nomination papers for Dhaka-17, Bogura-6 polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-signs-nomination-papers-for-dhaka-17-bogura-6-polls</link><description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman on Sunday signed his nomination papers to contest the 13th national parliamentary election from Dhaka-17 and Bogura-6 constituencies with the party’s electoral symbol, the Sheaf of Paddy.
Tarique signed the nomination papers in the evening at the BNP C</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 14:10:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NRB Global Convention 2025 to be held on Tuesday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nrb-global-convention-2025-to-be-held-on-tuesday</link><description>A day-long NRB Global Convention 2025 will be held on Tuesday to highlight the contributions of NRBs in various sectors, celebrate their impact on Bangladesh’s growth and strengthen ties between Bangladesh and its international partners.
Non-resident Bangladeshis (NRBs) from about 25 countri</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 14:25:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Many textile mills about to shut down due to faulty policy: BTMA</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/many-textile-mills-about-to-shut-down-due-to-faulty-policy-btma</link><description>The Bangladesh Textile Mills Association (BTMA) on Sunday warned that many textile mills are about to shut down due to faulty policy and economic meltdown.
The BTMA issued the warning from a press conference held at the Gulshan Club in Dhaka on Sunday. Speaking at the event, BTMA’s present a</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 14:40:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCP allied with Jamaat to cross electoral bridge: Nahid</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ncp-allied-with-jamaat-to-cross-electoral-bridge-nahid</link><description>National Citizen Party (NCP) Convenor Nahid Islam has formally announced an “electoral understanding” with Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami as the country approaches the parliamentary elections.
Speaking at a media briefing at their Bangla Motor office in Dhaka on Sunday night, Nahid said th</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 14:55:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khaelda files nomination for Dinajpur-3</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/former-pm-khaleda-zia-submits-nomination-papers-from-dinajpur-3</link><description>BNP Chairperson Khaleda Zia’s nomination papers have been submitted for the Dinajpur-3 constituency in the parliamentary polls.
Local BNP leaders and activists submitted the nomination papers on behalf of the former prime minister at 4pm on Sunday.
BNP’s central leader Syed Jahangir A</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 15:10:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Providing dependents’ income tax info in nomination form optional: EC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/providing-dependents-income-tax-info-in-nomination-form-optional-ec</link><description>Hours after a demand for clarification from BNP, the Election Commission on Sunday said providing the income tax information of an aspirant's spouse, children and dependents in the nomination form would be considered as optional.
The EC issued the clarification in a letter sent to 69 returning off</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 15:25:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>China welcomes Thailand-Cambodia truce ahead of trilateral talks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/china-welcomes-thailand-cambodia-truce-ahead-of-trilateral-talks</link><description>China on Sunday congratulated Cambodia on reaching a ceasefire with Thailand after weeks of deadly border fighting, as officials from the three countries prepared to open a two-day meeting in southwestern China.
Thailand and Cambodia on Saturday ended weeks of fierce border clashes that killed at</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 15:40:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mahfuj prioritises long-standing stance over Jamaat-NCP election ticket</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/mahfuj-prioritises-long-standing-stance-over-jamaat-ncp-election-ticket</link><description>Former interim government adviser and frontline July uprising leader Mahfuj Alam said that maintaining his long-standing political position is more important than contesting an election as a Jamaat-NCP alliance candidate in any Dhaka constituency.
"Rather than becoming a Jamaat-NCP alliance candid</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 15:55:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP’s Khairul Kabir Khokon submits nomination for Narsingdi-1</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnps-khairul-kabir-khokon-submits-nomination-for-narsingdi-1</link><description>BNP-nominated candidate for the Narsingdi-1 (Sadar) constituency and BNP Joint Secretary General Khairul Kabir Khokon on Sunday submitted his nomination papers to contest the 13th Jatiya Sangsad election.
He submitted the nomination to Deputy Commissioner and District Returning Officer Mohammad An</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 16:10:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh-Pakistan trade up 20pc: envoy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/pakistans-trade-volume-with-bangladesh-increased-by-20-per-cent-says-its-high-commissioner</link><description>Bangladesh and Pakistan’s businesses are exploring new avenues for investment, Pakistan’s High Commissioner to Bangladesh Imran Haider has said, noting that bilateral trade grew by 20 per cent in the last fiscal year.
He made the remarks during a meeting with Chief Advisor Muhammad Yun</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 16:25:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>More Israeli tech staff seek relocation abroad</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/israels-tech-sector-says-more-staff-seek-relocation-abroad-report</link><description>Requests to relocate abroad by Israelis working at multinational companies operating in Israel rose in the past year in reaction to Israel's two-year war against Palestinian militant group Hamas, a report showed on Sunday.
The Israel Advanced Technology Industries Association (IATI) found that 53</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 16:40:56 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>