<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 17:14:36 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>UN says Israel's action widens unlawful blockade</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/un-says-israels-action-widens-unlawful-blockade</link><description>Israel's interception in international waters of civilian aid vessels bound for Gaza widens its unlawful blockade of the strip, the U.N. rights office said on Thursday.
"As the occupying power, Israel must ensure food and medical supplies for the population to the fullest extent of the means avail</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 13:34:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Israel blocks the main road to Gaza City</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/israel-blocks-the-main-road-to-gaza-city</link><description>Israeli tanks blocked the main road to Gaza City on Thursday, preventing those who have left the besieged city from returning.
Defence Minister Israel Katz said it was now the last chance for hundreds of thousands of people still inside to escape. 
Israel has told the entire million-strong p</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 13:49:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh student group expresses solidarity with Sumud flotilla</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-student-group-expresses-solidarity-with-sumud-flotilla</link><description>The Bangladesh Ganatantrik Chhatra Sansad (BAGCHAS) held a rally at Dhaka University on Thursday afternoon to express solidarity with the Global Sumud Flotilla, which was mostly intercepted by Israel.
Titled ‘Sumud: Steadfast,’ the program emphasized Palestinians’ right to self-d</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 14:04:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gas pressure disruption hits Gazipur factories</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/gas-pressure-disruption-hits-gazipur-factories</link><description>Gas pressure has dropped in parts of the Gazipur zone under Titas Gas Transmission and Distribution Company Limited, disrupting production at garment factories and textile mills, industry insiders said.
Titas officials said a fire broke out in a gas line near Chandra intersection on the Dhaka&amp;ndas</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 14:34:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nagorik Oikya’s Manna promises not to object if NCP secures ‘Shapla’ symbol</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/nagorik-oikyas-manna-promises-not-to-object-if-ncp-secures-shapla-symbol</link><description>Nagorik Oikya Convenor Mahmudur Rahman Manna has promised not to object if the Election Commission allocates the “Shapla” symbol to the National Citizen Party.
Both the Nagorik Oikya and NCP sought the Shapla symbol during their registration process. But the EC has refused, saying Shap</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 14:49:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC rules out ‘Water Lily’ for NCP, asks it to pick from 50 electoral symbols</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-rules-out-water-lily-for-ncp-asks-it-to-pick-from-50-electoral-symbols</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has sent a letter to the National Citizen Party (NCP) attaching a list of 50 electoral symbols, asking the party to pick one from the list instead of its desired ‘Water Lily’ symbol.
“The National Citizen Party-NCP in its application mentioned ‘</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 15:04:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shah Rukh Khan joins billionaire elite, tops Bollywood rich list</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/entertainment/shah-rukh-khan-joins-billionaire-elite-tops-bollywood-rich-list</link><description>With a career glittering over three decades marked by soaring triumphs, blockbuster hits, and a vast international fanbase, Bollywood’s “King Khan” Shah Rukh Khan has now entered the rarified ranks of global billionaires.
According to Hindustan Times, the Hurun India Rich List 20</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 15:38:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India and China to resume direct flights after five-year freeze</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/india-and-china-to-resume-direct-flights-after-five-year-freeze</link><description>India and China will restart direct flights between designated cities this month, ending a suspension of more than five years, in a move that signals a cautious easing of bilateral tensions, India's foreign ministry said on Thursday.
There have been no direct flights between China and India since</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 15:53:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Digital payment: a catalyst for cashless economy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/digital-payment-a-catalyst-for-cashless-economy</link><description>With the proliferation of smartphones, mobile apps, and online platforms, peoples have countless options at their fingertips for conducting payments, transfers, and purchases. This transformation in the payment landscape has not only modernised transaction processes but also impacted consumer behav</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 16:23:54 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>