<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 20:34:43 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Tarique heads to Shah Paran's shrine to launch election campaign in Sylhet</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-heads-to-shah-parans-shrine-to-launch-election-campaign-in-sylhet</link><description>BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman has started for Sufi saint Hazrat Shah Paran's shrine after praying at Hazrat Shahjalal’s resting place in Sylhet in keeping with party tradition to officially begin his election campaign.
He departed from Sylhet’s Osmani International Airport by road shortl</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 16:01:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ACC to charge 21 over BCS appointments under freedom fighter quota</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/acc-to-prosecute-21-over-bcs-recruitments-under-freedom-fighter-quota-without-application</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) has decided to file six cases against 21 individuals over appointing six officers through the 29th Bangladesh Civil Service (BCS) exam under the freedom fighter quota.
ACC Director General Md Akhtar Hossain informed journalists about the decision to prosecute t</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 16:16:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ex-caretaker advisor Hafizuddin Khan dies</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/former-caretaker-government-advisor-hafizuddin-khan-dies-at-89</link><description>Former advisor to a caretaker government and civil servant M Hafizuddin Khan has died at the age of 89.
He died at his residence in Uttara’s Sector 1 on Wednesday at 7pm due to natural causes, according to his maternal cousin Liaquat Ali.
Hafizuddin served as secretary of the posts and tele</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 16:31:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique Rahman visits Shahjalal shrine, offers prayers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-rahman-visits-shahjalal-shrine-offers-prayers</link><description>BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman visited the shrine of Hazrat Shahjalal (RA) in Sylhet on Wednesday night.
He later performed Nafl prayers at 9:05pm, said BNP Media Cell member Sayrul Kabir Khan.
At 9:30pm, Tarique Rahman also visited the grave of late General (retired) M. A. G. Osmani, the first Comm</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 16:46:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gold price tops Tk 250,000 per bhori, sets new all-time high in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/gold-price-tops-tk-250000-per-bhori-sets-new-all-time-high-in-bangladesh</link><description>Gold prices in Bangladesh have surged past the Tk 250,000 mark per bhori on Wednesday, hitting an all-time high in the domestic market.
The Bangladesh Jewellers Association (BAJUS) raised the price of 22-carat gold by Tk 8,339 per bhori (11.664 grams), setting the new rate at Tk 252,467, the highe</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 17:01:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jatiya Party begins election campaign amid concerns</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jatiya-party-launches-election-campaign-amid-worries-over-fairness-level-playing-field</link><description>The Jatiya Party is heading into the campaign in 196 constituencies, raising concerns that include possible “election engineering”.
Secretary General Shameem Haider Patwary said there is anxiety among candidates over potential obstacles to campaigning and the absence of a “level</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 17:36:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New US Ambassador to Bangladesh raises concern over China</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/new-us-ambassador-to-bangladesh-raises-concern-over-chinas-regional-influence</link><description>Newly appointed US Ambassador to Bangladesh Brent T Christensen on Wednesday said he is concerned about broader Chinese influence in South Asia, stressing that they have a host of options available to try to help their partner militaries meet their capability needs.
‘You know, as I sai</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 17:31:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>'The Ugly American'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/the-ugly-american</link><description>A novel with the eponymous title was written in the sixties by two Americans, Eugene Burdick and William Lederer, that was later made into a Hollywood movie. The book was a critique of the scatter-brained foreign policy pursued by American administration in the sixties' cold war era, particularly i</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 17:51:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Addressing the youth job challenge</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/reviews/addressing-the-youth-job-challenge</link><description>The July 2024 Mass Movement brought to the fore the long-standing unaddressed development challenges of rising inequalities in wealth, income, and economic opportunities. A particularly concerning reflection of these inequalities is the growing incidence of youth unemployment. Addressing this matte</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 18:06:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Loan defaulters should be in jail, not parliament</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/loan-defaulters-should-be-in-jail-not-parliament</link><description>The remark of an election commissioner that the loan-defaulting candidates were being validated ‘with a heavy heart’ speaks volumes for the Commission’s predicament in the absence of a robust legal mechanism and decisive political backing, writes Atiqul Kabir Tuhin
Non-performing</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 18:21:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Draft Money Loan Court Act comes to nought</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/draft-money-loan-court-act-comes-to-nought</link><description>The Ministry of Law's refusal to endorse the draft of the Artha Rin Adalat Ain (Money Loan Court Act) and its suggestion, instead, to amend the existing laws renders the whole exercise redundant. An unceremonious rejection, this MoL decision smacks of highhandedness at its best and undue sympathy f</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 18:36:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt employees' salary proposed to be jacked up by max 142pc</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-employees-salary-proposed-to-be-jacked-up-by-max-142pc</link><description>Government employees' pay is recommended to be ramped up by 142 per cent to Tk 160,000 at the highest and Tk 20,000 lowest, generating dismay among economists.



The Pay Commission submitted its report to Chief Adviser of the interim government Prof Muhammad Yunus on Wednesday, recommending su</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 18:51:38 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>