<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 03:11:34 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Forest officer injured in poacher attack in Sundarban; 3 detained</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/forest-officer-injured-in-poacher-attack-in-sundarban-3-detained</link><description>A forest officer was injured Monday in the Sundarbans, when a group of poachers hunting deer attacked him.
The incident took place at Dimer Char in the Sarankhola range of the Sundarbans East Division in Bagerhat.
The injured officer, Rana Dev, received first aid at the temporary Dublarchar Healt</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 18:11:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Unregulated battery recycling plants</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/unregulated-battery-recycling-plants</link><description>Lead poisoning has been a serious public health issue in Bangladesh since early 1990s affecting mostly children. Suspecting that burning of leaded-gasoline was a source of lead pollution in the environment, in 1999, the government of the time banned the use of leaded gasoline. Now, informal lead-ba</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 18:26:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Safety measures must to restore confidence in metro rail</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/safety-measures-must-to-restore-confidence-in-metro-rail</link><description>It was a bright afternoon on October 26, 2025, when tragedy struck once again in Dhaka's Farmgate area. A bearing pad from the city's metro rail infrastructure fell from above, fatally hitting a young man named Abul Kalam Azad. He died on the spot-leaving behind a grieving mother, a devastated wife</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 18:41:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How much flawed is Dhaka's metro rail?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/how-much-flawed-is-dhakas-metro-rail</link><description>For tens of thousands of people, Dhaka City's iconic infrastructure as well as service is the metro rail. In the context of long tailbacks on the city's roads and streets, the service metro rail renders is refreshing and this is despite the occasional irregularities caused by technical malfunctions</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 18:56:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IMF sceptical about 35pc-higher revenue target, bank overhauls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/imf-sceptical-about-35pc-higher-revenue-target-bank-overhauls</link><description>International Monetary Fund creditworthiness-review mission appears unsatisfied with Bangladesh finance officials' explanation over ramped-up revenue target handed to the revenue board for the current fiscal year, and the means of mobilisation.



Finance Division sources said the visiting IMF</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 19:57:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Only 32.9pc of Bangladeshis fully food secure, BBS survey shows</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/only-329pc-of-bangladeshis-fully-food-secure-bbs-survey-shows</link><description>Only 32.9 per cent of Bangladesh's population is fully food secure in terms of daily intake, with millions facing vulnerability in their everyday nutrition, according to a new survey by the Bangladesh Bureau of Statistics (BBS).
The survey, titled "Food Security Situation and Coping Mechanism in B</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 01:34:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>'Fast transition to elected govt will restore investor trust'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/fast-transition-to-elected-govt-will-restore-investor-trust</link><description>Experts have underscored more major reforms to remove the existing hurdles and enable Bangladesh to tap the emerging business opportunities, calling for faster democratic transition to accelerate the system-recast process.
Speaking at a roundtable Monday in Dhaka, they also said reforms aligned wi</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 01:49:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Future of megaprojects funded by JICA remains clouded</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/future-of-megaprojects-funded-by-jica-remains-clouded</link><description>Six major infrastructure projects involving an investment worth nearly Tk 1.94 trillion--- 76 per cent of which is funded by the Japan International Cooperation Agency (JICA)--- are now encountering problems of varied nature.
Behind the glossy images of progress surrounding these projects lie disp</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 02:04:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh Bank allows taka-foreign currency swap for exporters</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladesh-bank-allows-taka-foreign-currency-swap-for-exporters</link><description>The Bangladesh Bank has allowed exporters to obtain Taka liquidity by swapping their foreign currency funds with commercial banks.
In a circular issued on Monday, it allowed the authorised dealer (AD) banks to enter into Taka-foreign currency swap arrangements with exporters against balances held</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 02:19:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh logs 19.13pc FDI growth in FY 2024-25</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladesh-logs-1913pc-fdi-growth-in-fy-2024-25</link><description>Bangladesh has logged 19.13 per cent growth in attracting foreign direct investment (FDI) in the last fiscal year 2024-25.
The country reported FDI worth $1686.24 million in the fiscal year (FY) 2024-25 which was $1415.46 million in the previous FY.
Bangladesh Investment Development Authority (BI</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 02:34:55 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>