<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 22:18:04 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Govt promotes 80 police inspectors as ASPs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-promotes-80-police-inspectors-as-asps</link><description>The government has promoted 80 police inspectors to the post of assistant superintendents of police (ASPs). 
The promotions were given in three separate notifications signed by Deputy Secretary of the Home Affairs Ministry Md Mahbubur Rahman, according to a handout issued on Tuesday.
Accordi</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 16:29:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Woman killed in Meherpur road accident</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/woman-killed-in-meherpur-road-accident</link><description>A woman was killed and three of her family members were injured when a truck hit a CNG-run auto-rickshaw in Gangni upazila of Meherpur on Tuesday.
The deceased was identified as Sumi Khatun, 30, wife of Ariful Islam Gani from Badiyapara village in Gangni upazila, reports UNB.
The accident occurre</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 16:59:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BSEC imposes lifetime ban, heavy fines on LR Global CEO Reaz Islam</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/bsec-imposes-lifetime-ban-heavy-fines-on-lr-global-ceo-reaz-islam</link><description>The Bangladesh Securities and Exchange Commission (BSEC) has imposed a lifetime ban on Reaz Islam, chief executive officer (CEO) and chief investment officer of LR Global Bangladesh Asset Management Company Limited, barring him from all activities in the capital market. 
The BSEC has also ban</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 17:14:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladeshis’ Qatar visa restriction claim baseless: Ministry</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladeshis-qatar-visa-restriction-claim-baseless-ministry</link><description>The Ministry of Expatriates' Welfare and Overseas Employment has dismissed as baseless and misleading the recent social media posts claiming that Qatar has stopped issuing visas for Bangladeshi workers.
In a statement issued Tuesday night, the ministry said it has noticed several online posts and</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 17:45:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>On the validity of CTG port tariff revision</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/on-the-validity-of-ctg-port-tariff-revision</link><description>I have recently delivered a paper at a seminar organised by the Centre for Bay of Bengal Studies (CBoBS) at Independent University, Bangladesh, where I concluded that there is a severe deficit in maritime education. There is no alternate to knowledge, and until we establish a knowledge-based societ</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 18:00:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Reassessing social safety net programmes</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/reassessing-social-safety-net-programmes</link><description>In the absence of studies on the performance of the social safety net programmes (SSNPs), there's a common belief that despite their inherent challenges, they play a significant role in preventing a general decline in poverty rates and supporting specific sectoral activities.
Introduction of SSNPs</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 18:15:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Creating unified regulatory authority for auditors</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/creating-unified-regulatory-authority-for-auditors</link><description>The function of any regulator is to ensure that the stakeholders concerned follow the set of rules that guides their activities and does not fall afoul of it. Also, it holds those breaking the rules to account and, at the same time, ensures the overall quality of the professional output. But if the</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 18:30:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Most cargos charred in HSIA fire unlikely to be compensated</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/most-cargos-charred-in-hsia-fire-unlikely-to-be-compensated</link><description>All insured goods incinerated in the import-cargo-village fire at Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport (HSIA) may not be compensated as most consignees had 'Air Risk Only' insurance coverage.



This insurance policy covers only four specific risks: air crash, hijacking, forced landing, and o</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 19:15:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pharma sector stares at big loss from fire</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/pharma-sector-stares-at-big-loss-from-fire</link><description>The devastating fire at the cargo village of Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport (HSIA) has dealt a severe blow to Bangladesh's pharmaceutical industry, with an estimated economic impact of more than Tk 40 billion.



Industry leaders fear the blaze could disrupt the production of life-savin</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 19:30:46 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>