<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 14:22:56 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Walton Digital Campaign Season-23 kicks off</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/walton-digital-campaign-season-23-kicks-off</link><description>Centring the winter season, the country's superbrand Walton has started the 'Digital Campaign Season-23' nationwide. Like the previous campaign, there are special offers for the buyers of Walton products, including fridge, TV, air conditioner, washing machine and BLDC fan, this season.
Under the '</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 12:05:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Council of Advisers approves draft of Referendum Ordinance</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/council-of-advisers-approves-draft-of-referendum-ordinance</link><description>The Council of Advisers on Tuesday in principle approved the draft of the ‘Referendum Ordinance, 2025’ outlining how the referendum will be conducted.
“We hope the relevant gazette will be issued by today or tomorrow,” Law Adviser Dr Asif Nazrul told reporters at the Foreig</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 12:20:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US and Russia hold peace talks in Abu Dhabi as missiles pound Kyiv</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-and-russia-hold-peace-talks-in-abu-dhabi-as-missiles-pound-kyiv</link><description>U.S. Army Secretary Dan Driscoll held talks on late on Monday and Tuesday with Russian officials in Abu Dhabi as part of an intense new push by President Donald Trump's administration to end the war in Ukraine, Driscoll's spokesperson said.
U.S. and Ukrainian officials are trying to narrow the gap</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 12:35:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bag on metro line halts trains</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dhaka-metro-services-disrupted-for-20-minutes-after-bag-falls-on-track</link><description>Train services on the metro line were suspended for 20 minutes after a bag was found on the track between Secretariat and Motijheel stations.
Md Ahsan Ullah, deputy project director (Public Relations) of Dhaka Metro Rail, said the service resumed once the bag was removed.
Operations had been halt</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 12:50:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>SIBL administrator team meets branch managers, sub-branch in-charges</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/sibl-administrator-team-meets-branch-managers-sub-branch-in-charges</link><description>The Administrator Team of Social Islami Bank PLC (SIBL) held an exchange meeting with Branch Managers and Sub-Branch In-charges on 24 November 2025 to discuss measures for ensuring smooth and uninterrupted banking operations.
Conducted via Zoom from the Bank’s Head Office, the session focuse</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 12:06:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shimanto Bank inks MoU with Force Support Wing of Border Guard Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/shimanto-bank-inks-mou-with-force-support-wing-of-border-guard-bangladesh</link><description>Shimanto Bank has recently signed a Memorandum of Understanding (MoU) with the Force Support Wing of Border Guard Bangladesh at Pilkhana, Dhaka, according to a press release.
As part of this agreement, BGB members who use their Shimanto Bank Credit Cards for monthly purchases at the BGB Exclusive</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 12:21:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Electrical short circuit triggered cargo village fire at Dhaka airport, probe finds</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/electrical-short-circuit-triggered-cargo-village-fire-at-dhaka-airport-probe-finds</link><description>A devastating fire that tore through the cargo village of Dhaka’s Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport last month was caused by an electrical short circuit, an official investigation has concluded.
The report which exposing years of neglect, dangerous storage practices and the absence of b</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 12:36:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prime Bank launches Bangladesh’s first AI-powered digital LC platform ‘Prime Banijjo’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/prime-bank-launches-bangladeshs-first-ai-powered-digital-lc-platform-prime-banijjo</link><description>Prime Bank PLC has recently launched Prime Banijjo, the country’s first AI-powered digital LC management platform, marking a major milestone in Bangladesh’s trade digitisation journey, according to a press release.
The launch event featured an interactive experience session where corpo</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 12:51:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cox’s Bazar NGOs left out of UNHCR’s 2026–29 ‘Rohingya Response’ partnership</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/coxs-bazar-ngos-left-out-of-unhcrs-2026-29-rohingya-response-partnership</link><description>Local NGOs in Cox’s Bazar, who have long worked on Rohingya issues, said on Tuesday that UNHCR has stopped all partnerships with Cox’s Bazar–based NGOs.
Instead, UNHCR has given the partnerships to international NGOs and organisations based outside the district.
They said this g</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 13:06:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pragati Insurance settles its first non-life car insurance claim under Bancassurance partnership of Midland Bank</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/pragati-insurance-settles-its-first-non-life-car-insurance-claim-under-bancassurance-partnership-of-midland-bank</link><description>Pragati Insurance Limited, the Bancassurance partner of Midland Bank PLC, has successfully settled its first non-life motor car insurance claim.
To mark the occasion, a brief ceremony was organised at the bank’s Gulshan branch. During the event, a cheque was handed over to the customer, Mr.</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 13:21:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mahtab Osmani joins Bank Asia as deputy managing director</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/mahtab-osmani-joins-bank-asia-as-deputy-managing-director</link><description>Mr. Mahtab Osmani has joined Bank Asia PLC. as Deputy Managing Director &amp; Head of Corporate Business, International Banking, and Export Finance, effective 25 November 2025.
Mr. Osmani brings 24 years of distinguished experience from Standard Chartered Bank, where he progressed from an analyst role</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 13:36:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Allow expats to register with only passports: BNP to EC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/allow-expats-to-register-with-only-passports-bnp-to-ec</link><description>BNP on Tuesday urged the Election Commission to extend the registration time for out of country voting (OCV) and include the eligible expatriates who do not have national identity (NID) cards but hold valid Bangladeshi passports in the voter lists ahead of the upcoming national election.
“Ma</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 13:51:08 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>