<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 15:28:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Pubali Bank holds 1st Business Conference-2026 of Regional and Corporate Branch Managers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/pubali-bank-holds-1st-business-conference-2026-of-regional-and-corporate-branch-managers</link><description>Pubali Bank PLC’s 1st Business Conference-2026 of Regional and Corporate Branch Managers held at Bank’s Head Office Auditorium on Thursday.
Monzurur Rahman, Chairman of the Board of Directors of Pubali Bank, was present as Chief Guest with the participation of all Regional Managers, Co</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 12:27:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DU bus vandalised amid blockade by 7 colleges’ students</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/du-bus-vandalised-amid-blockade-by-7-colleges-students</link><description>A bus of Dhaka University was vandalised at the Science Lab intersection in the capital on Thursday during a blockade enforced by students of seven government colleges, leaving at least two students injured.
The incident occurred around 2:30 pm when a Dhaka University bus was halted due to the blo</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 12:42:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ACC questions Chief Heat Officer Bushra</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/acc-questions-chief-heat-officer-bushra-afreen-over-fathers-corruption</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) has questioned Asia’s first Chief Heat Officer Bushra Afreen, daughter of former Dhaka North City Corporation (DNCC) mayor Atiqul Islam, as part of an ongoing corruption investigation.
She was interrogated at the ACC headquarters on Thursday morning for a</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 12:57:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Iran protests expose opposition splits</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/iran-protests-show-bitter-schism-among-exiled-opposition-factions</link><description>Huge protests in Iran have galvanised exiled foes of the authorities but despite their hatred of the ruling clerics, a bitter schism dating to before the 1979 Islamic Revolution still afflicts the leading opposition factions.
That split, between monarchists supporting Reza Pahlavi, son of the oust</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 13:12:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique Rahman at Jamuna with family to meet Prof Yunus</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-rahman-at-jamuna-with-family-to-meet-prof-yunus</link><description>BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman on Thursday evening entered the state guest house Jamuna with his family to pay a courtesy call on Chief Adviser Prof Muhammad Yunus.
Tarique arrived at Jamuna at around 7:30pm.
Earlier, he left the BNP chairperson’s office in Gulshan at 6:42pm and went to his re</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 13:27:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CU Chhatra Dal gives VC 48 hours to quit</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cu-chhatra-dal-demands-resignation-of-vc-pro-vc-in-48-hours-over-nepotistic-appointments</link><description>Chittagong University unit of the Jatiyatabadi Chhatra Dal has demanded the resignation of the vice-chancellor and pro-vice-chancellor, setting a 48-hour deadline over allegations of irregular and nepotistic appointments.
The demand came on Thursday after students staged a six-hour sit-in from 10a</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 13:42:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique Rahman meets CA Yunus at Jamuna</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-rahman-meets-ca-yunus-at-jamuna</link><description>Tarique Rahman has met Chief Advisor Muhammad Yunus in Dhaka, his first family visit to the advisor’s residence since returning to Bangladesh last month.
At 7:28pm on Thursday, the BNP chairman’s flag-bearing car entered the State Guest House Jamuna, accompanied by his wife Zubaida Rah</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 13:57:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Canada’s Carney hails warmer ties with China, Xi’s leadership</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/canadas-carney-hails-warmer-ties-with-china-xis-leadership</link><description>Prime Minister Mark Carney hailed on Thursday Canada’s improving ties with China as well as the leadership of President Xi Jinping, declaring that their nations were charting a new course in cooperation at a time of global division and disorder.
The four-day visit to China was the first by a</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 14:12:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Southeast Bank provides financial assistance to Noakhali Science and Technology University</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/southeast-bank-provides-financial-assistance-to-noakhali-science-and-technology-university</link><description>As part of its Special Corporate Social Responsibility (SCSR), Southeast Bank PLC. has extended special financial support under its “Special CSR Fund” to Noakhali Science and Technology University for conducting agricultural research activities. 
M.A. Kashem, Chairman of Southeast</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 14:27:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump sees Iranian crackdown easing, Tehran denies man to be executed</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-sees-iranian-crackdown-easing-tehran-denies-man-to-be-executed</link><description>U.S. President Donald Trump said he had been told that killings in Iran’s crackdown on protests were easing and that he believed there was no current plan for large-scale executions, adopting a wait‑and‑see posture after earlier threatening intervention.
After Iran’s foreign minister s</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 14:58:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>hosting.com launches operations in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/hostingcom-officially-launches-operations-in-bangladesh</link><description>Global web hosting service provider hosting.com has officially commenced its business operations in Bangladesh.
The formal launch ceremony was held on Wednesday (14 January) at Hotel Sheraton in Dhaka, with Faiz Ahmed Taiyeb, Special Assistant to the Chief Adviser of the Ministry of Posts, Telecom</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 15:13:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>40th FOBANA Convention 2026 set for September 4–6 in Orlando, Florida</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/40th-fobana-convention-2026-set-for-september-4-6-in-orlando-florida</link><description>The 40th FOBANA Convention 2026 is scheduled to take place from September 4 to 6, 2026, at the Holiday Inn Resort, Orlando, Florida, USA. The announcement was made at a press conference held in Dhaka.
Organizers stated that the 40th FOBANA Convention, marking four decades of the Federation of Bang</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 15:28:55 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>