<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:30:57 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Shahjalal Islami Bank opens its’ Airport Road Branch in Banani</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/shahjalal-islami-bank-opens-its-airport-road-branch-in-banani</link><description>In order to provide modern technology based banking services to all classes of people of the society, Shahjalal Islami Bank PLC inaugurated its Airport Road Branch (142nd Branch) at Banani (Road No.-11, Tower B-11, 1st&amp; 2nd floor, House No-43, Block-F, Banani, Dhaka) in the capital city Dhaka.
Vic</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 13:15:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UK to give default 'yes' to new homes around railway stations</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/uk-to-give-default-yes-to-new-homes-around-railway-stations</link><description>Britain said planning applications for new homes near railway stations would receive a default 'yes' in future if they meet certain rules as it steps up efforts to encourage house building by reducing obstacles.
The government wants to build 1.5 million homes before the next election, due in 2029,</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 13:30:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pubali Bank holds Managers’ Conference</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/pubali-bank-holds-managers-conference</link><description>Pubali Bank PLC holds 'Managers' Conference-2025' with the participation of all branches, sub-branches and Islamic Banking Window Managers of Dhaka Central, North and South regions and Corporate Branch Heads of the Bank at the auditorium of head office, according to a press release.
Managing Direc</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 13:45:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cloudflare outage cuts access to X, ChatGPT, other web platforms for thousands</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/cloudflare-outage-cuts-access-to-x-chatgpt-other-web-platforms-for-thousands</link><description>Major internet platforms, including X and ChatGPT, were inaccessible for thousands of users globally on Tuesday as web-infrastructure firm Cloudflare was hit by an outage, disrupting internet services.
Cloudflare, whose network handles around a fifth of web traffic, said it started to investigate</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 14:00:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Islami Bank hosts orientation for newly recruited security guards</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/islami-bank-hosts-orientation-for-newly-recruited-security-guards</link><description>Islami Bank Bangladesh PLC organized a professional skills development, training and orientation program for newly recruited security guards on 17 November 2025, Monday at the Islami Bank Tower, according to a press release.
Md. Omar Faruk Khan, Managing Director, was present as the chief guest. D</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 14:15:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BRAC Bank launches ‘PRANTIK’, its in-house agent banking system</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/brac-bank-launches-prantik-its-in-house-agent-banking-system</link><description>BRAC Bank has launched ‘PRANTIK’, an in-house developed agent banking system that will deliver seamless and secure banking services to customers across the most remote corners of Bangladesh, according to a press release.
Designed and built entirely by BRAC Bank’s Technology Divis</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 14:30:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Five minutes away from one-party dictatorship’: Georgia’s U-turn from Western path</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/five-minutes-away-from-one-party-dictatorship-georgias-u-turn-from-western-path</link><description>Just over a year ago, a diverse array of opposition coalitions jockeyed for votes in Georgia’s parliament, with four of them winning seats. Today, of their eight main leaders, all but one are in jail, in exile or facing criminal charges. The ruling party aims to ban the three main opposition</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 14:45:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rickshaw garage catches fire at Dhaka’s Koratoli Bazar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rickshaw-garage-catches-fire-at-dhakas-koratoli-bazar</link><description>A fire broke out at a rickshaw garage adjacent to the 300-feet road by Koratoli Bazar of Dhaka on Tuesday night.
According to the Fire Service and Civil Defence (FSCD) control room, the blaze started around 7:38 pm.
Rafi Al Faruk, duty officer at the FSCD control room, said on information four fi</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 15:00:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BFUJ, DUJ express concern over cyber case against journalist Mujtaba</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bfuj-duj-express-concern-over-cyber-case-against-journalist-mujtaba</link><description>Bangladesh Federal Union of Journalists (BFUJ) and Dhaka Union of Journalists (DUJ) on Tuesday expressed deep concern over a cybercrime case filed against NTV Joint News Editor Mujtaba Khandakar and called for its immediate withdrawal.
In a joint statement, BFUJ acting President Obaidur Rahman Sha</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 15:15:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NSA Khalilur Rahman to attend Security Conclave in New Delhi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nsa-khalilur-rahman-to-attend-security-conclave-in-new-delhi</link><description>Amid Dhaka’s renewed call for former Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina’s extradition, National Security Adviser (NSA) and High Representative for the Rohingya Issue Dr Khalilur Rahman will attend the Colombo Security Conclave (CSC) which will be held in New Delhi on November 19-20.
National</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 15:30:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP urges leaders to skip celebrations for Tarique’s birthday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-urges-leaders-to-skip-celebrations-for-tariques-birthday</link><description>BNP has instructed its leaders and activists not to hold any event or festival this year to celebrate the 60th birthday of party Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman, which falls on November 20.
BNP Senior Joint Secretary General Ruhul Kabir Rizvi issued the instruction in a press release on Tuesday.
&amp;</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 15:45:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh facing a state of instability, warns Fakhrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bangladesh-facing-a-state-of-instability-warns-fakhrul</link><description>BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir on Tuesday bemoaned that Bangladesh is currently experiencing a state of instability.
“At this moment, we truly needed people like Barrister Moudud Ahmed. Because, we are living in a state of instability. Barrister Moudud was undoubtedly one</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:00:42 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>