<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 15:21:18 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Anis Alamgir lands in jail after interrogation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/journalist-anis-alamgir-sent-to-jail-after-interrogation</link><description>Journalist Anis Alamgir has been sent to jail after interrogation concluded in an Anti-Terrorism Act case filed with Uttara West Police Station in Dhaka.
The order was issued on Saturday by Dhaka Metropolitan Magistrate Md Hasan Shahadat, confirmed Prosecution Sub-Inspector Shamim Hossain.
After</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 13:15:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh writes to Meta for strict content monitoring until election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-writes-to-meta-for-strict-content-monitoring-until-election</link><description>The National Cyber Security Agency (NCSA) has urged Meta to closely monitor social media content, citing concerns that platforms are being used to incite violence amid Bangladesh’s ongoing political crisis.
The NCSA sent a letter to the American multinational technology company on Friday.
T</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 13:30:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>3 to be questioned again over Hadi shooting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hadi-shooting-faisals-wife-brother-in-law-friend-to-face-interrogation</link><description>A Dhaka court has granted four days for questioning the wife, brother-in-law, and a close friend of Faisal Karim Masud, the key suspect in the shooting death of Inqilab Moncho Convenor Sharif Osman bin Hadi.
Dhaka Metropolitan Magistrate Md Siddique Azad issued the order on Saturday, the day of Ha</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 12:42:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Russia hits ports, bridge in escalating strikes on Ukraine's Odesa region</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/russia-hits-ports-bridge-in-escalating-strikes-on-ukraines-odesa-region</link><description>Russia attacked the southern Ukrainian port of Pivdennyi on Saturday, Ukrainian officials said, as it ramped up strikes on the Odesa region along the Black Sea including energy facilities and a critical route to the Moldova border.
Russia has unleashed an almost continuous drone and missile campai</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 12:57:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Activities in Shilpakala Academy to resume from Dec 21</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/entertainment/activities-in-shilpakala-academy-to-resume-from-dec-21</link><description>Following the state mourning on the death of Shaheed Sharif Osman Bin Hadi, all activities including programs and exhibitions at Bangladesh Shilpakala Academy will resume from December 21.
Bangladesh Shilpakala Academy confirmed it in a press release.
Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus announ</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 13:12:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>JU Admission Test begins Sunday with ‘C’ unit exam</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/ju-admission-test-begins-sunday-with-c-unit-exam</link><description>The undergraduate (Honours) first-year admission test of Jahangirnagar University (JU) for the 2025–26 academic session will begin on Sunday with the examination of ‘C’ unit.
The university authorities have issued nine important instructions for candidates appearing in the admiss</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 13:27:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Army, navy, air force chiefs to meet CEC on Sunday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/army-navy-air-force-chiefs-to-meet-cec-on-sunday</link><description>The chiefs of three services – Bangladesh Army, Bangladesh Navy and Air Force– will meet Chief Election Commissioner AMM Nasir Uddin on Sunday.
“The meeting will be held at 12:00 pm at Nirbachan Bhaban,” said EC Director (PR) Ruhul Amin Mollik on Saturday.
Due to the meeti</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 13:42:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Online Editors Alliance denounces attacks on Prothom Alo, Daily Star</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/online-editors-alliance-denounces-attacks-on-prothom-alo-daily-star</link><description>The Online Editors Alliance has condemned the recent attacks on the offices of Prothom Alo and The Daily Star, two of Bangladesh’s leading newspapers.
In a joint statement, the organisation expressed deep concern over the safety of journalists and the environment for carrying out duties inde</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 13:57:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Plot’ to derail vote will be foiled: BNP</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-vows-to-thwart-orchestrated-conspiracy-to-derail-election</link><description>The BNP has accused “certain political groups” of working through a planned design to strip people of their democratic rights, warning that any attempts to disrupt the election will be firmly opposed.
Calling for vigilance, senior leader Mirza Abbas said attempts to create instability</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 14:12:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UN chief Guterres urges Bangladesh to ‘exercise restraint’ over Hadi’s killing</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/un-chief-guterres-urges-bangladesh-to-exercise-restraint-over-hadis-killing</link><description>The UN Secretary-General António Guterres has urged all parties in Bangladesh to “exercise restraint” over the death of Inqilab Moncho Convenor Sharif Osman bin Hadi.
UN spokesperson Stéphane Dujarric relayed the call at a briefing in New York, according to a UN statement</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 14:27:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Citizens Bank opens its Tejgaon Link Road Branch</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/citizens-bank-opens-its-tejgaon-link-road-branch</link><description>Citizens Bank PLC recently opened the Tejgaon Link Road Branch at Gulshan Tejgaon Link Road, Dhaka, according to a press release.
Mr. Chowdhury Mohammed Hanif Shoeb, Chairman, Citizens Bank PLC., formally inaugurated the Branch as Chief Guest in the presence of Independent Directors Mr. N K A Mobi</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 14:42:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prime Bank Partners with JBS Holdings to offer exclusive discounts on flat purchases</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/prime-bank-partners-with-jbs-holdings-to-offer-exclusive-discounts-on-flat-purchases</link><description>Prime Bank PLC has entered into a strategic partnership with JBS Holdings Limited, one of Bangladesh’s most reputed real estate developers, to offer exclusive discounts on flat purchases for its valued customers.
A formal signing ceremony marking this collaboration was recently held at JBS H</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 14:57:05 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>