<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 14:19:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>CPD for independent parliamentary commission to ensure stronger democratic practices</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cpd-for-independent-parliamentary-commission-to-ensure-stronger-democratic-practices</link><description>The Centre for Policy Dialogue (CPD) has said that an independent commission should be established in Bangladesh that can provide both pre-legislative and post-legislative support to ensure the desirable state of impartial scrutiny, stronger accountability, and more democratic practices.
The think</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 11:00:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Times Higher Edu Ranking: Dhaka University climbs 200 places</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/times-higher-edu-ranking-dhaka-university-climbs-200-places</link><description>Dhaka University (DU) has advanced 200 places to fall within the 801–1000 range in the Times Higher Education (THE) World University Ranking 2026.
Last year, the university was ranked within the 1001–1200 bracket, UNB reports. 
The UK-based renowned educational magazine published</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 11:15:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NBR member Belal Hossain made OSD two days after ACC lawsuit</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nbr-member-belal-hossain-made-osd-two-days-after-acc-lawsuit</link><description>Mohammad Belal Hossain Chowdhury, a member of the National Board of Revenue, has been made an officer on special duty two days after the Anti-Corruption Commission brought charges of accumulating illegal assets and concealing information against him. 
On Thursday, the Internal Revenue Divisio</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 11:30:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Indian police arrest owner of cough syrup company linked to deaths of 19 children</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/indian-police-arrest-owner-of-cough-syrup-company-linked-to-deaths-of-19-children</link><description>Indian police have arrested the owner of Sresan Pharmaceutical Manufacturer, the cough syrup company linked to the deaths of at least 19 children in the central state of Madhya Pradesh, a senior police officer told Reuters on Thursday.
The children, all under five years of age, died in the past mo</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 11:45:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BRAC Bank cardholders to get exclusive dining privileges at Thai Express and Saffron Dine</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/brac-bank-cardholders-to-get-exclusive-dining-privileges-at-thai-express-and-saffron-dine</link><description>BRAC Bank has entered into a partnership with two premier fine dining destinations, Thai Express and Saffron Dine, to offer exclusive privileges to its valued cardholders.
As part of this partnership, all BRAC Bank debit and credit cardholders will receive a flat 15% discount on all food items at</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 12:00:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>904th Executive Committee meeting of Shahjalal Islami Bank held</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/904th-executive-committee-meeting-of-shahjalal-islami-bank-held</link><description>The 904th meeting of the Executive Committee (EC) of Shahjalal Islami Bank PLC (SJIB PLC) was held on 8 October 2025 at Corporate Head Office of the bank.
The meeting was presided over by Mr. Akkas Uddin Mollah, the Chairman of Executive Committee (EC) of the bank, according to a press release.&amp;nb</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 12:15:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Country’s GDP grows 3.69pc in FY25</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/countrys-gdp-grows-369pc-in-fy25</link><description>Bangladesh’s economy grew by 3.69 percent in the last fiscal year (FY25), driven by moderate performances by the agriculture, industry and services sectors.
According to the latest data by the Bangladesh Bureau of Statistics (BBS), the GDP growth rate during the 4th or the April to June quar</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 12:30:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Remittance inflow witnesses 14.4pc growth till Oct 8</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/remittance-inflow-witnesses-144pc-growth-till-oct-8</link><description>Inflow of remittances witnessed 14.4 percent (pc) growth, reaching US$8,390 million during the period from July 1 to October 8, 2025 which was $7,332 million during the same period of the previous fiscal year.
According to the latest data of Bangladesh Bank (BB) issued, expatriates sent remittance</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 12:45:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>HSC, equivalent exam results likely on Oct 16</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hsc-equivalent-exam-results-likely-on-oct-16</link><description>The chiefs of nine Boards of Intermediate and Secondary Education have announced Oct 16 as the possible date for the publication of the HSC and equivalent examinations’ results.
Bangladesh Madrasah Education Board Chairman Mian Md Nurul Haq said the decision was reached during a meeting of t</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 13:00:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Modi and Starmer tout India-UK trade deal as new Indian investment unveiled</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/modi-and-starmer-tout-india-uk-trade-deal-as-new-indian-investment-unveiled</link><description>Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi and British counterpart Keir Starmer hailed the potential on Thursday of their months-old trade deal to transform commercial links, as London unveiled new Indian investment in Britain and said "this is just the start".
Starmer is in the financial capital of Mumb</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 13:30:30 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>