<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 07:23:28 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Potato prices reach bottom rock in already-glutted Bogura market</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/potato-prices-reach-bottom-rock-in-already-glutted-bogura-market</link><description>Prices of newly-harvested potatoes in Bogura have hit all-time lowest as large volumes of old stock remain unsold in the market, widening losses for farmers already struggling after a difficult previous season.
Farmers are selling new potatoes at rock-bottom prices, despite returns remaining well</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 05:00:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Iran authorities signal intensified crackdown as unrest grows</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/iran-authorities-signal-intensified-crackdown-as-unrest-grows</link><description>Iran's authorities indicated on Saturday they could intensify their crackdown on the biggest anti-government demonstrations in years, with the Revolutionary Guards blaming unrest on terrorists and vowing to safeguard the governing system.
US President Donald Trump, who has repeatedly threatened to</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 05:15:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mushroom cultivation gains popularity in Gopalganj</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/mushroom-cultivation-gains-popularity-in-gopalganj</link><description>Government initiatives to popularise oyster mushroom cultivation in two upazilas of Gopalganj has been bringing good income to farmers, as more of them have been showing interest in growing the nutritious vegetable.
In FY25, the Department of Agricultural Extension (DAE) provided mushroom cultivat</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 05:30:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Industrial term loan disbursement grows 11.86pc in Q1 FY26</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/industrial-term-loan-disbursement-grows-1186pc-in-q1-fy26</link><description>Industrial term loan disbursement posted significant year-on-year growth in the July-September quarter of fiscal year (FY) 2025-26, reflecting cautious investment appetite amid ongoing economic adjustments, according to Bangladesh Bank (BB) data.
Disbursement of industrial loans stood at Tk 247.71</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 04:36:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How to fix Bangladesh's broken promise</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/how-to-fix-bangladeshs-broken-promise</link><description>Higher education in Bangladesh has long been equated with upward social mobility, economic security, and national progress. A university degree was generally seen as a ticket to employment and stability, thus worth the sacrifices imposed upon both families and students. That view shaped public poli</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 04:51:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Challenges and priorities for the next elected government</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/challenges-and-priorities-for-the-next-elected-government</link><description>Like millions of ordinary citizens, I am hopeful that in February 2026, our beloved motherland Bangladesh will once again witness a free, fair, and peaceful general election through which democratic governance will be restored and citizens will regain their democratic rights.
Having been deeply in</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 05:06:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Second day of appeal hearings underway at EC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/second-day-of-appeal-hearings-underway-at-ec</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) on Sunday commenced the second day of hearings on appeals lodged against the decisions of returning officers regarding the acceptance and rejection of nomination papers for the 13th Jatiya Sangsad election.
The hearings began at 10:00 am at the auditorium of the Electi</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 05:21:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NSU confers degrees on over 3,000 graduates at 26th convocation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/nsu-confers-degrees-on-over-3000-graduates-at-26th-convocation</link><description>North South University (NSU) held its 26th convocation ceremony on January 07 at its campus, awarding degrees to more than 3,000 undergraduate and postgraduate students.
Professor Dr Chowdhury Rafiqul Abrar, adviser to the Ministry of Education, chaired the convocation, whilst Professor Dr SMA Fai</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 05:36:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>large-value tax payment: NBR launches bKash-enabled services</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/large-value-tax-payment-nbr-launches-bkash-enabled-services</link><description>The National Board of Revenue (NBR) is going to launch the payment of large amounts of tax through mobile financial services (MFS) to simplify tax payments by corporates.
The country's largest MFS provider, bKash's online merchant wallet, will be used to facilitate tax payments.
The new facility</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 05:51:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>RSTP proposes 3 more metro rail corridors</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/rstp-proposes-3-more-metro-rail-corridors</link><description>Development of three more metro rail corridors has been proposed in the Revised Strategic Transport Plan (RSTP), of which updating is now at the final stage.
However, officials said the new corridors would be working as the bus priority corridors in the next two decades.
The RTSP proposed total s</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 06:06:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP candidate Shama Obaid reports lower income, higher assets</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-candidate-shama-obaid-reports-lower-income-higher-assets</link><description>BNP candidate Shama Obaid's annual income has dropped over the past seven years, even as the value of her assets has grown significantly.
Shama, who is contesting the Faridpur-2 constituency covering Saltha and Nagarkanda, disclosed the figures in documents submitted to the Election Commission a</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 06:21:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Israel on high alert for possibility of US intervention in Iran</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/israel-on-high-alert-for-possibility-of-us-intervention-in-iran</link><description>Israel is on high alert for the possibility of any US intervention in Iran as authorities there confront the biggest anti-government protests in years, according to three Israeli sources with knowledge of the matter.
President Donald Trump has repeatedly threatened to intervene in recent days and</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 06:36:04 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>