<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 10:20:38 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>EU backs Bangladesh's democratic transition efforts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/eu-backs-bangladeshs-democratic-transition-efforts</link><description>The European Union (EU) has expressed support for Bangladesh's ongoing transition under the interim government, reaffirming its confidence in the country's leadership and encouraging political parties to participate constructively in the electoral process, reports BSS.
In a Facebook post, the EU s</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 07:25:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC to hold talks with 12 parties, including Jamaat, on Monday ahead of general election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ec-to-hold-talks-with-12-parties-including-jamaat-on-monday-ahead-of-general-election</link><description>The Election Commission is going to hold talks with 12 political parties, including the Jamaat-e-Islami, on Monday for its third day of dialogue with political stakeholders ahead of the parliamentary elections.
On Saturday, EC’s Public Relations Assistant Director, Md Ashadul Haque said the</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 07:40:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The lost magic of watching TV shows together</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/entertainment/the-lost-magic-of-watching-tv-shows-together</link><description>Television first arrived in Bangladesh in the 1960s; it was a wonder to the Bangalees. In those early days, owning a television was a privilege. 
My grandparents have told us that when someone in the neighbourhood had a TV set, people from nearby houses would gather to watch whatever was being bro</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 08:22:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>RAB CO tells how Jarez orchestrated trader Ashraful’s murder</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/rab-co-tells-how-jarez-orchestrated-trader-ashrafuls-murder</link><description>Rangpur trader Ashraful Haque was allegedly lured to his death by his friend Jarez, who then killed and dismembered him in a planned manner, said Lt Col Fayezul Arefin, commanding officer of RAB-3.
"The brutal killing was the result of a calculated plot carried out under the guise of friendship,"</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 08:37:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh introduces new police uniform in phased distribution</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-introduces-new-police-uniform-in-phased-distribution</link><description>Bangladesh Police have begun distributing new uniforms, initially to a limited number of personnel, according to bdnews24.com.
Dhaka Metropolitan Police spokesperson Talebur Rahman said the uniform rollout began on Saturday and will be distributed to all members in phases.
Metropolitan police m</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 08:52:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The city we're forgetting: Dhaka's vanishing heritage</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/culture/the-city-were-forgetting-dhakas-vanishing-heritage</link><description>Dhaka is changing faster than it can remember itself. The city's skyline now tells two very different stories. One is written in the fading terracotta of old buildings and the shade of age-old trees. The other is spelt out in the reflective glass of new towers that define its growing ambition. 
Th</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 09:07:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Restoration work of 44 ponds, waterbodies begin in Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/restoration-work-of-44-ponds-waterbodies-begin-in-dhaka</link><description>The government on Saturday launched restoration work on 44 ponds(khas) and waterbodies in Dhaka and its outskirts, aiming to rebuild and preserve key waterbodies, protect natural drainage system and strengthen environmental balance.
Environment Adviser Syeda Rizwana Hasan inaugurated the climate r</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 09:05:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A new Bangladesh is aspiration of July Uprising: Rizvi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/a-new-bangladesh-is-aspiration-of-july-uprising-rizvi</link><description>BNP Senior Joint Secretary General Ruhul Kabir Rizvi today (Saturday) said that the aspiration of the July Uprising is a new Bangladesh.
He said, "The self-sacrifice and aspiration of the martyrs in the July Uprising is a new Bangladesh. A new Bangladesh where no fascist will ever be born again, w</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 09:20:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Indonesia landslide kills 6 in Central Java, 17 missing, state media says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/indonesia-landslide-kills-6-in-central-java-17-missing-state-media-says</link><description>A landslide in Indonesia's Central Java killed six people with 17 missing, state news agency Antara reported on Saturday, after prolonged, heavy rains.
The landslide on Thursday in the city of Cilacap buried a dozen houses in Cibeunying village, Antara said, citing disaster official Budi Irawan.</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 09:35:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ISU hosts seminar to enhance textile students’ professional skills</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/isu-hosts-seminar-to-enhance-textile-students-professional-skills</link><description>A seminar titled “Essential Skills for a Successful Textile Engineer” was organized by the ISU Textile Club of International Standard University (ISU) on Thursday afternoon at the university’s Mohakhali campus.
The event aimed to enhance students’ professional competencies</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 09:50:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hero Alam arrested on charges of attempting to murder his former wife</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hero-alam-arrested-on-charges-of-attempting-to-murder-his-former-wife</link><description>Police have arrested popular content creator Hero Alam at his office in Ulon, Hatirjheel, in connection with an attempt to murder case filed by his former wife Ria Monir.
On Saturday, Dhaka Metropolitan Police Tejgaon Deputy Commissioner Ibne Mizan said Alom was sent to court under the warrant, re</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 10:05:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Employers prioritising problem-solving skills over academic achievement: Dr Fouzul Kabir</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/employers-prioritising-problem-solving-skills-over-academic-achievement-dr-fouzul-kabir</link><description>Securing employment based solely on academic results has become increasingly difficult, as employers now prioritise problem-solving abilities, said Dr Muhammad Fouzul Kabir Khan, Adviser to the Interim Government for the Ministries of Road Transport and Bridges, Railways, and Power, Energy and Mine</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 10:20:38 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>