<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 08:27:47 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Women to get legal rights soon to take children to workplaces: Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/women-to-get-legal-rights-soon-to-take-children-to-workplaces-adviser</link><description>Dr Wahiduddin Mahmud, Adviser to the Ministry of Planning, said women would soon have the legal rights to take their children to workplaces, as the interim government is working to establish a provision in this regard.
He said women are not only carrying the lion's share of unpaid household work,</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 06:00:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UN chief pledges full support for Bangladesh’s democratic transition</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/un-chief-pledges-full-support-for-bangladeshs-democratic-transition</link><description>United Nations Secretary-General António Guterres has expressed his full support and solidarity with Bangladesh’s ongoing democratic transition and reform initiatives.
He made the remarks during a meeting with Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus at the UN Headquarters in New York o</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 06:15:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NU makes ICT course mandatory at UG level</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/nu-makes-ict-course-mandatory-at-ug-level</link><description>With technical assistance from the ICT Division's Aspire to Innovate (a2i) programme and UNICEF, the National University (NU) has, for the first time, introduced a mandatory four-credit Information and Communication Technology (ICT) course at the undergraduate (UG) level.
The initiative aims to tr</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 06:30:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>FE senior reporter Jubair Hasan wins Silk Road Global News Award</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fe-senior-reporter-jubair-hasan-wins-silk-road-global-news-award</link><description>Senior reporter of The Financial Express (FE) Mohammad Jubair Hasan has clinched the 2nd Silk Road Global News Award 2025, initiated by China under its flagship Belt and Road Initiative (BRI) project.
At a recent event in Kunming of southwest China's Yunnan province, he received the prestigious gl</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 05:38:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Stocks rise at DSE, CSE as indices gain</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/stocks-rise-at-dse-cse-as-indices-gain</link><description>Trading at Bangladesh's two stock exchanges opened on a positive note on Tuesday, with major indices climbing and most shares posting gains.
On the third working day of the week, the key DSEX index at the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) rose 43 points within the first hour of trading.
The other two in</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 05:53:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Government ‘neutral’ on religious festivals: Farooki</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/government-neutral-on-religious-festivals-farooki</link><description>Cultural Affairs Adviser Mostofa Sarwar Farooki has outlined the government's "neutral cultural policy" on religious festivals as it strives to uphold communal harmony.
Speaking at the World Cultural Policy Forum in Barcelona, Farooki highlighted Bangladesh’s “Ananda Shobhajatra”</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 06:23:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka court freezes Sikder family's investments in Thailand</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dhaka-court-freezes-sikder-familys-investments-in-thailand</link><description>In two separate cases, a Dhaka court has ordered the freezing of Tk1.33 billion worth of investments belonging to the Sikder family in Thai companies, as well as 114 accounts in local banks that belong to the former personal secretary of a former minister.
The first order was issued Monday after t</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 06:53:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Women in Gaza say they were offered food, money, or work for 'sexual favours'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/women-in-gaza-say-they-were-promised-food-money-or-work-in-exchange-for-sexual-interactions</link><description>After weeks of scraping by to feed her six children in Gaza, the 38-year-old woman thought she’d found a lifeline.
At a shelter, a friend told her about a man who could help with food, aid, maybe even a job. The woman — separated from her husband, and forced to shutter the business tha</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 07:08:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Temporary market makes a comeback in Sylhet city</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/temporary-market-makes-a-comeback-in-sylhet-city</link><description>Lighting, water, sanitation and security arrangements have been ensured at the Laldighirpar field (market) in Sylhet city, so that street vendors can continue their trade operations there, clearing all the busy footpaths and streets of the city - but very few were seen relocating on Monday.
Vendor</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 07:38:35 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>