<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 10:24:50 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Swiss face arduous task of identifying victims of deadly bar fire</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/swiss-face-arduous-task-of-identifying-victims-of-deadly-bar-fire</link><description>Investigators on Friday set about the painful task of identifying the burned bodies of a blaze that engulfed a crowded bar and killed around 40 people at a New Year's Eve party in the upscale Swiss ski resort of Crans-Montana.
So severe were the burns suffered by the mostly young crowd of reveller</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 07:15:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>World reacts to fatal fire at Swiss ski resort bar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/world-reacts-to-fatal-fire-at-swiss-ski-resort-bar</link><description>World leaders reacted to a fatal fire that tore through a crowded bar during a New Year's Eve party in the upscale Swiss ski resort of Crans-Montana. Here are some of their comments:
SWISS FEDERAL PRESIDENT GUY PARMELIN:
"The fire that broke out last night in a bar in Crans-Montana is one of the</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 07:30:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>China's Xi to host South Korea's Lee in New Year amid Japan tensions</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/chinas-xi-to-host-south-koreas-lee-in-new-year-amid-japan-tensions</link><description>Chinese President Xi Jinping will host South Korean President Lee Jae Myung on a state visit starting on Sunday, signalling Beijing's intent to strengthen ties with Seoul amidst strained relations with Japan over Taiwan.
The visit marks the second meeting between Xi and Lee in just two months, an</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 07:45:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Record 17,387 containers handled at Mongla Port in six months</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/record-17387-containers-handled-at-mongla-port-in-six-months</link><description>Mongla Port, the country’s second-largest seaport, handled a record 17,387 TEUs of containers by 28 container vessels during the first six months of the current fiscal year (FY 2025–26).
The port also recorded the anchoring of a record 440 overseas commercial vessels during the July&amp;nd</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 08:00:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Several reported killed in Iran protests over economic hardships</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/several-reported-killed-in-iran-protests-over-economic-hardships</link><description>Several people were killed during unrest in Iran, Iranian media and rights groups said on Thursday, as the biggest protests to hit the Islamic Republic for three years over worsening economic conditions sparked violence in several provinces.
The semi-official Fars news agency reported that three p</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 08:15:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Contaminated water kills nine and hospitalises 200 in India's Indore city</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/contaminated-water-kills-nine-and-hospitalises-200-in-indias-indore-city</link><description>At least nine people have died, and more than 200 have been hospitalised in the central Indian city of Indore after a diarrhoea outbreak that officials said was linked to contaminated drinking water, according to a lawmaker and local health authorities.
Kailash Vijayvargiya, a lawmaker, said nine</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 08:30:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two killed after truck rams motorcycle in Gaibandha</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/two-killed-after-truck-rams-motorcycle-in-gaibandha</link><description>Two people have been killed and another injured after a truck ploughed into a motorcycle in Gaibandha’s Gobindaganj Upazila.
The crash occurred around 11pm on Thursday on the Rangpur–Dhaka highway near the BRAC office at Fashitola Bazar, according to police.
The two men who died were</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 08:45:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Condolence book opened in Tokyo in memory of Khaleda Zia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/condolence-book-opened-in-tokyo-in-memory-of-khaleda-zia</link><description>A condolence book was opened on Friday at the Embassy of Bangladesh in Tokyo following the demise of Khaleda Zia, a three-time former Prime Minister of the government of Bangladesh and Chairperson of Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP).
Representatives from various foreign diplomatic missions based</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 09:00:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Zaima, family members offer prayers at Khaleda’s grave amid tight security</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/zaima-family-members-offer-prayers-at-khaledas-grave-amid-tight-security</link><description>Family members of BNP chairperson and former prime minister Khaleda Zia have paid their respects at her grave, offering prayers.
Khaleda’s granddaughter Zaima Rahman, along with other family members, visited the grave around 9:30am on Friday.
She was accompanied by Syeda Sharmila Rahman, wi</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 09:15:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Old artillery shell recovered in Kushtia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/old-artillery-shell-recovered-in-kushtia</link><description>Police have recovered an old artillery shell from a village in Daulatpur upazila of Kushtia district.
The shell was found on Thursday evening at the house of late Asmat Ullah, a retired senior warrant officer of the Bangladesh Army, in Daulatkhali village under the upazila headquarters.
After spo</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 09:30:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Inquilab Moncho stages protests demanding justice for Hadi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/inquilab-moncho-stages-protests-demanding-justice-for-hadi</link><description>Inquilab Moncho on Friday staged a demonstration demanding justice for its slain spokesperson Sharif Osman Bin Hadi, with a large number of protesters in attendance.
They brought out a procession from the central mosque premises of Dhaka University after Jumu'a prayers.
During the demonstration,</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 09:45:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BGB trooper dies from gunshot wound in Kurigram; police suspect suicide</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bgb-trooper-dies-from-gunshot-wound-in-kurigram-police-suspect-suicide</link><description>A member of the Border Guard Bangladesh (BGB) has died from gunfire at a BGB camp in Kurigram's Phulbari Upazila in what police suspect is a case of suicide.
The incident occurred around 1:30 am on Friday at the Gangarhat Border Outpost (BOP), according to Phulbari Police Station chief (OC) Mahmud</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 10:00:45 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>