<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 10:40:35 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Harassment of journalists ‘regrettable’: NCP</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/harassment-of-journalists-regrettable-ncp</link><description>The National Citizen Party (NCP) has issued a statement over the alleged harassment of journalists by the party’s activists as they were working at the Shahjalal International Airport in Dhaka.
In the statement, sent on Thursday by Joint Chief Coordinator Khan Muhammad Mursalin, the party sa</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 08:07:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Flooding likely in Feni's low-lying areas</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/flooding-likely-in-fenis-low-lying-areas</link><description>The Flood Forecasting &amp; Warning Centre (FFWC) of the Water Development Board has warned that the water levels of the Muhuri, Selonia and Feni rivers may rise due to heavy rainfall triggered by a deep depression in the Bay of Bengal, potentially causing short-term flooding in the low-lying areas of</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 08:22:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique will lead BNP in election, says Humayun</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-will-lead-bnp-in-election-says-humayun</link><description>Tarique Rahman will lead the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) in the upcoming 13th parliamentary election slated for February 2026.
The party’s Acting Chairman's Foreign Affairs Advisor Humayun Kabir confirmed this on Thursday at Shahjalal International Airport, responding to journalists'</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 08:37:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prisoner dies at DMCH hours after admission</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/prisoner-dies-at-dmch-hours-after-admission</link><description>A prisoner died at Dhaka Medical College Hospital (DMCH) on Thursday, hours after being admitted there.
The deceased was identified as Md Amir Hossain, 38, UNB reports. 
Amir fell sick at Dhaka Central Jail on Wednesday night, said jail guard Arman, leading to his admission at the hospital a</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 08:52:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Israel intercepts 39 aid boats heading for Gaza, organisers say, sparking criticism</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/israel-intercepts-39-aid-boats-heading-for-gaza-organisers-say-sparking-criticism</link><description>Israeli forces have intercepted 39 boats carrying aid and foreign activists, including Swedish campaigner Greta Thunberg, to Gaza, leaving only one vessel still sailing towards the Palestinian enclave, the flotilla organisers said on Thursday.
 
Cameras broadcasting live feeds from</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 09:07:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two more Dengue deaths reported, total reaches 202</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/two-more-dengue-deaths-reported-total-reaches-202</link><description>Two more people have died of dengue fever in the past 24 hours, raising the number of fatalities from the mosquito-borne disease in Bangladesh to 202 this year.
During this period, 396 more patients were hospitalised with the viral fever, bringing the total number of cases to 48,228 so far this ye</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 09:37:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Sindur Khela’ marks farewell to Goddess Durga ending 10-day Puja festivities</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/sindur-khela-marks-farewell-to-goddess-durga-ending-10-day-puja-festivities</link><description>The devotees of Goddess Durga have bid her farewell with love and tears in their eyes amid the sounds of drums, conch shells and brass cymbals.
The Dashami, or tenth day rituals for Durga Puja, kicked off with Bihit Puja after 9am at the Dhakeshwari National Temple, bdnews24.com reports. 
La</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 10:07:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Overnight rain floods Chattogram, causes traffic chaos</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/overnight-rain-floods-chattogram-causes-traffic-chaos</link><description>Some low-lying areas in the port city of Chattogram were submerged due to heavy overnight rainfall, causing immense suffering of residents, commuters, particularly office-bound people on Thursday.
From Wednesday night until Thursday morning, torrential rainfall left knee-deep water in areas, inclu</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 10:22:08 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>