<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 09:37:05 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>EC restricts watercraft movement on polling day</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-restricts-watercraft-movement-on-polling-day</link><description>Ahead of the 13th Jatiya Sangsad election and referendum, the Election Commission (EC) has imposed restrictions on the movement of certain watercrafts on the polling day as well as before and after it.
In a letter isasued on Tuesday, the EC said in view of the polls, the movement of launches and e</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 06:33:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BGB border outposts inaugurated at St. Martin, Teknaf</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bgb-border-outposts-inaugurated-at-st-martin-teknaf</link><description>Border Guard Bangladesh (BGB) Director Major General Mohammad Ashrafuzzaman Siddiqui has inaugurated the Saint Martin Border Outpost (BOP) under Teknaf Battalion (2 BGB) and the newly established Sea-Beach BOP in Teknaf, aiming to further strengthen border and coastal security.
The BGB DG inaugura</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 06:53:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Over 432,000 expatriates complete postal voting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/over-432000-expatriates-complete-postal-voting</link><description>A total of 432,989 expatriate voters, who registered through the 'Postal Vote BD' app to cast their ballots in the 13th Jatiya Sangsad election and referendum, have completed their voting.  
Salim Ahmad Khan, Team Leader of the ‘OCV-SDI’ project on expatriate voter registration, d</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 06:50:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Security tightened at Bangladesh Secretariat as three jailed for illegal entry</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/security-tightened-at-bangladesh-secretariat-as-three-jailed-for-illegal-entry</link><description>Security has been tightened at the Bangladesh Secretariat, with the Ministry of Home Affairs intensifying monitoring of entry and vehicle movement within the complex ahead of the national election.
Three people have been sentenced to jail for attempting to enter the Secretariat illegally, the mini</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 07:05:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Video shows flames flying from NASA plane that touched down without landing gear</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/video-shows-flames-flying-from-nasa-plane-that-touched-down-without-landing-gear</link><description>A NASA research plane malfunctioned and had to touch down in Texas without landing gear on Tuesday, sliding across the runway on its belly and sending plumes of flame behind it, a video posted to social media showed.
The crew landed the plane at Ellington Airport, southeast of Houston, and are "al</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 07:20:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rwanda files arbitration case against UK over cancelled asylum deal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/rwanda-files-arbitration-case-against-uk-over-cancelled-asylum-deal</link><description>Rwanda said late on Tuesday that it had filed an arbitration case against Britain over a cancelled asylum deal, which British Prime Minister Keir Starmer scrapped in 2024.
Under the deal, agreed between the two countries before Starmer took office, Rwanda would have been paid to take in migrants w</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 07:35:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pinterest will lay off 15% of its workforce as the platform pivots resources to AI</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/pinterest-will-lay-off-15-of-its-workforce-as-the-platform-pivots-resources-to-ai</link><description>Pinterest plans to lay off under 15% of its workforce, as part of broader restructuring that arrives as the image-sharing platform pivots more of its money to artificial intelligence.
In a Tuesday securities filing, San Francisco-based Pinterest said it was making these cuts to support "transforma</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 07:50:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India says it has contained Nipah virus outbreak as some Asian countries ramp up health screenings</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/india-says-it-has-contained-nipah-virus-outbreak-as-some-asian-countries-ramp-up-health-screenings</link><description>Indian authorities said they had contained a Nipah virus outbreak after confirming two cases in the eastern state of West Bengal, as several Asian countries tightened health screenings and airport surveillance for travelers arriving from India.
India's Health Ministry said Tuesday that two N</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 08:05:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prof Yunus calls for ethical use of technology, rejects fraud for prosperity</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/prof-yunus-calls-for-ethical-use-of-technology-rejects-fraud-for-prosperity</link><description>Chief Adviser Prof Muhammad Yunus on Wednesday said Bangladesh must use technology ethically to avoid misuse and succeed in a fast-changing digital world.
“This country can never be a land of fraud. We want to hold our heads high through our own qualities. We have that capability,” he</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 08:20:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Court orders arrest of journalist Anis Alamgir in graft case</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/court-orders-arrest-of-journalist-anis-alamgir-in-graft-case</link><description>A court has ordered that journalist Anis Alamgir be placed under arrest in a case filed by the Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) over allegations of acquiring assets beyond known sources of income.
The order was issued on Wednesday by Dhaka Metropolitan Senior Special Judge Md Sabbir Fayez followin</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 08:35:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US Ambassador Christensen meets CEC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/us-ambassador-christensen-meets-cec</link><description>US Ambassador to Bangladesh Brent Christensen has held a meeting with Chief Election Commissioner AMM Nasir Uddin in Dhaka amid preparations for the upcoming 13th parliamentary elections.
The meeting began around 11:45am on Wednesday at the Nirbachan Bhaban in Agargaon.
This was Christensen&amp;rsquo</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 08:50:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BUBT Economics Department Hosts Insightful Session on "Research Methodology: Economic  Advancement in Real Life" During Research Week of the University</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/bubt-economics-department-hosts-insightful-session-on-research-methodology-economic-advancement-in-real-life-during-research-week-of-the-university</link><description>The Department of Economics at Bangladesh University of Business and Technology (BUBT) organized a keynote session titled "Research Methodology: Advancement in Real Life" as part of its Research Week festivities. The event featured esteemed academics who shared critical insights on contemporary res</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 09:05:02 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>