<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 12:43:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Keraniganj building fire still not under control after 10 hours</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/keraniganj-building-fire-still-not-under-control-after-10-hours</link><description>Emergency workers are still engaged in efforts to tame a fire at a multi-storey building in Keraniganj on the outskirts of Dhaka, more than 10 hours after it broke out.
The fire started around 5:30 am on Saturday in the basement of Jabale Noor Tower in the Aganagar area. Twenty firefighting unit</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 09:30:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Operation Devil Hunt Phase-2 to begin ahead of national election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/operation-devil-hunt-phase-2-to-begin-ahead-of-national-election</link><description>The government has decided to immediately launch "Operation Devil Hunt Phase-2" across the country to prevent subversive activities using illegal arms and to suppress 'fascist terrorists' ahead of the February national election.
Home Affairs Adviser Lt Gen (retd) Jahangir Alam Chowdhury disclosed</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 09:45:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pinched by higher prices, many Trump voters say: Don't blame the president</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/pinched-by-higher-prices-many-trump-voters-say-dont-blame-the-president</link><description>When Ron Dailey goes out to eat, he is shocked by prices on the menu.
“Breakfast is $20 no matter how you slice it,” said Dailey, 63, who voted for President Donald Trump in November 2024.
Dailey, a Denver-area resident who works for a human resources outsourcing solutions firm, think</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 10:00:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh condemns Rakhine hospital bombing</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-condemns-rakhine-hospital-bombing</link><description>Bangladesh has condemned the recent airstrike on a hospital in Myanmar's western Rakhine state, killing at least 30 people and injuring scores of others.
A foreign ministry statement issued on Saturday also expressed concern with the recent increase of violations of international humanitarian law</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 10:15:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC issues circular on JS polls nomination process</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-issues-circular-on-js-polls-nomination-process-1</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) on Saturday issued a circular outlining procedures related to the upcoming 13th Jatiya Sangsad (JS) elections. 
The directive covers the collection and submission of nomination papers, the deposit of security money, eligibility of proposers and seconders, party-</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 10:30:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Attack on Hadi ‘dangerous’ for peaceful political climate, says SHUJAN</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/attack-on-hadi-dangerous-for-peaceful-political-climate-says-shujan</link><description>Civil society platform Shushashoner Jonno Nagorik (SHUJAN) has warned that the attack on Inquilab Mancha Convener Sharif Osman Hadi could undermine the country’s peaceful political environment and democratic process ahead of the upcoming national election.
In a statement on Saturday, the org</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 10:45:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hadi's condition remains extremely critical</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/hadis-condition-remains-extremely-critical</link><description>Sharif Osman Hadi, spokesperson for Inqilab Manch, is currently admitted to the Critical Care Unit at Evercare Hospital in Dhaka after being seriously injured in a shooting by criminals. His physical condition remains extremely critical.
According to a medical board statement released on Saturday</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 11:00:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prime Bank launches program to drive Net Zero in Bangladesh’s RMG &amp; Textile Sector</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/prime-bank-launches-program-to-drive-net-zero-in-bangladeshs-rmg-textile-sector</link><description>Prime Bank PLC successfully hosted its first Customer Awareness Session on Carbon Accounting, Net Zero Pathways, and Sustainability Reporting for its Ready-Made Garments (RMG) and textile customers at the bank’s Head Office.
The session was organized with technical support from Swisscontact</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 11:15:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Thailand vows to keep fighting Cambodia, despite Trump's ceasefire claim</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/thailand-vows-to-keep-fighting-cambodia-despite-trumps-ceasefire-claim</link><description>Thailand's leader vowed to keep fighting on the disputed border with Cambodia as fighter jets struck targets on Saturday, hours after US President Donald Trump said he had brokered a ceasefire.
Prime Minister Anutin Charnvirakul posted on Facebook that the Southeast Asian nation would "continue to</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 11:30:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Attack on Hadi pre-planned, part of a deep conspiracy: CA</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/attack-on-hadi-pre-planned-part-of-a-deep-conspiracy-ca</link><description>Chief Adviser Prof Muhammad Yunus on Saturday said the attack on Osman Hadi was pre-planned, part of a deep conspiracy and a big force is working behind it."This attack is very symbolic. They want to show their power and want to disrupt all the election arrangements. These must be dealt with united</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 12:03:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EU countries agree 2026 fishing quotas, avoid tighter Mediterranean curbs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/eu-countries-agree-2026-fishing-quotas-avoid-tighter-mediterranean-curbs</link><description>European Union fisheries ministers struck a deal on Saturday on 2026 fishing quotas, avoiding an earlier proposal to tighten restrictions in the Mediterranean.
Spain, which opposed a European Commission plan to cut trawler fishing days in the Mediterranean next year, welcomed the agreement.
"We h</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 12:18:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Enhancing coordination between public, private sectors essential: Speakers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/enhancing-coordination-between-public-private-sectors-essential-speakers</link><description>Speakers at a seminar today (Saturday) said that enhancing coordination between the public and private sectors alongside greater public engagement is essential for the health sector’s overall improvement. 
Speakers made the observation at a seminar on “Strengthening Confidence in</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 12:33:05 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>