<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 09:23:37 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>NBR adds 131,000 new VAT payers in December</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/nbr-adds-131000-new-vat-payers-in-december</link><description>The National Board of Revenue (NBR) registered around 131,000 new Value Added Tax (VAT) entities across the country in December under a special nationwide VAT registration campaign.
The NBR observed VAT Day on December 10 and VAT Week from December 10 to 15, 2025, with the theme “Register on</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 05:45:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mustafizur dropped from KKR squad on BCCI directive</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/mustafizur-dropped-from-kkr-squad-on-bcci-directive</link><description>Bangladesh pacer Mustafizur Rahman, the only Bangladeshi cricketer to secure a team in this year’s Indian Premier League (IPL), has been dropped from the Kolkata Knight Riders (KKR) squad following a directive from the Board of Control for Cricket in India (BCCI).
KKR had signed Mustafizur f</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 06:00:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Former NCP leader Tasnim Jara’s nomination rejected</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/former-ncp-leader-tasnim-jaras-nomination-rejected</link><description>The nomination papers of Tasnim Jara, an independent candidate from the Dhaka-9 constituency and a former NCP leader, have been rejected by the Dhaka district returning officer.
The decision was announced on Saturday (January 3) following the scrutiny of nomination papers.
According to her electi</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 06:15:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>30th DITF kicks off</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/30th-ditf-kicks-off</link><description>The curtain rose on the 30th Dhaka International Trade Fair (DITF) on Saturday as Commerce Adviser Sk Bashir Uddin formally inaugurated the month-long event at the China-Bangladesh Friendship Exhibition Center (CBFEC) in Purbachal, Rupganj.
Describing the fair as a landmark in the country's commer</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 06:30:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique’s Bogura-6 nomination declared valid</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tariques-bogura-6-nomination-declared-valid</link><description>The nomination paper of BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman for the Bogura-6 constituency was declared valid on Saturday.
Returning Officer Md Toufiqul Rahman announced the decision in the morning after scrutinising nomination papers at his office.
The nomination of Jamaat-e-Islami-backed candidat</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 06:45:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>bKash launches ‘bHive’ to provide students with early corporate exposure</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bkash-launches-bhive-to-provide-students-with-early-corporate-exposure</link><description>Traditionally, students gain professional exposure through internships at the end of their academic life. Breaking away from this conventional approach, bKash has introduced a unique career development initiative titled ‘bHive’, designed to connect students with the corporate environmen</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 07:00:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat’s Abdul Haq loses nomination over loan default; two others cleared in Dhaka-2 race</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jamaats-abdul-haq-loses-nomination-over-loan-default-two-others-cleared-in-dhaka-2-race</link><description>Jamaat-e-Islami nominated candidate Abdul Haq’s nomination paper for Dhaka-2 constituency has been cancelled on grounds of loan default.
The announcement came Saturday from Returning Officer and Dhaka District Commissioner Rezaul Karim during the scrutiny of nomination papers.
Addressing Ha</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 07:30:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Paper and packaging named product of the year as 30th Dhaka International Trade Fair opens</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/paper-and-packaging-named-product-of-the-year-as-30th-dhaka-international-trade-fair-opens</link><description>The 30th Dhaka International Trade Fair (DITF) has opened, with paper and packaging being named as the product of the year as part of efforts to diversify Bangladesh's exports.
The fair, which was delayed by two days following the death of former prime minister Khaleda Zia, was inaugurated by Comm</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 07:45:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat chief Shafiqur cleared in Dhaka-15, CPB’s Rubel disqualified</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jamaat-chief-shafiqur-cleared-in-dhaka-15-cpbs-rubel-disqualified</link><description>Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami chief Md Shafiqur Rahman’s nomination papers for Dhaka-15 constituency have been declared valid by election officials.
BNP’s Shafiqul Islam Khan Milton has also been cleared, while CPB’s Sajedul Huq Rubel’s nomination has been rejected.
The decis</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 08:00:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jatiya Party leader Anisul Islam Mahmud’s nomination rejected in Chattogram-5</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jatiya-party-leader-anisul-islam-mahmuds-nomination-rejected-in-chattogram-5</link><description>The nomination papers of Anisul Islam Mahmud, chairman of a breakaway faction of the Jatiya Party, have been rejected for the Chattogram-5 (Hathazari) parliamentary constituency.
The decision was announced on Saturday by Chattogram Divisional Commissioner and Returning Officer Md Zia Uddin durin</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 08:31:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Venezuela blames explosions on US 'military aggression'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/venezuela-blames-explosions-on-us-military-aggression</link><description>Venezuela said it rejected "military aggression" by the United States after multiple explosions rocked capital Caracas and other areas early on Saturday.
Attacks also took place in the states of Miranda, Aragua and La Guaira, a government statement said, prompting President Nicolas Maduro to decla</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 08:46:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Abdus Sattar made Tarique’s private secretary, Saleh Shibly press secretary</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/abdus-sattar-made-tariques-private-secretary-saleh-shibly-press-secretary</link><description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman has appointed ABM Abdus Sattar, former Secretary of the Bangladesh government, as his private secretary, and AAM Saleh (Saleh Shibly), former General Secretary of Dhaka Reporters' Unity, as his press secretary.
The appointments were announced on Saturday in a pre</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 09:01:12 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>