<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 16:49:26 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>New ordinance increases bank deposit protection to Tk 200,000</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/new-ordinance-increases-bank-deposit-protection-to-tk-200000</link><description>The government has approved a draft of the “Deposit Protection Ordinance, 2025”, which will increase the deposit guarantee from Tk 100,000 to Tk 200,000 for bank and financial institution depositors.
The ordinance was approved by the Advisory Council, ensuring that if a bank or financi</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 15:02:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New cyber safety ordinance provision clears Digital Security Act defendants</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/new-cyber-safety-ordinance-provision-clears-digital-security-act-defendants</link><description>The government has introduced a new provision in the Cyber Protection Ordinance, effectively dismissing all cases filed under the repealed Digital Security Act.
As a result, all individuals convicted or charged under the law will be granted immunity from the charges, according to the Chief Advisor</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 15:17:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shahidul Alam among flotilla detainees sent to Israeli prison</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/shahidul-alam-among-flotilla-detainees-sent-to-israeli-prison</link><description>Bangladeshi photographer and writer Shahidul Alam and several other activists detained from a Gaza-bound flotilla have been transferred to Ketziot Prison in Israel.
The information was confirmed by the Freedom Flotilla Coalition and Adalah – The Legal Center for Arab Minority Rights in Israe</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 15:32:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prof Yunus confirms Feb polls as first genuine election in years</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/prof-yunus-confirms-feb-polls-as-first-genuine-election-in-years</link><description>Chief Adviser Prof Muhammad Yunus on Thursday reaffirmed the government’s commitment to holding a national election in the first half of February, stating that it would mark the first genuinely democratic vote in many years.
“What happened in the last 16 years was a mockery of an elect</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 15:19:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Government approves merger of five Shariah-based private banks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/government-approves-merger-of-five-shariah-based-private-banks</link><description>The interim government has approved the merger of five financially struggling Shariah-based private banks to form a single new bank.
The banks involved in this merger are First Security Islami Bank, Global Islami Bank, Union Bank, EXIM Bank, and Social Islami Bank.
The merged entity will initiall</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 15:34:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Taliban minister’s first India visit puts Delhi in a diplomatic fix over flag protocol</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/taliban-ministers-first-india-visit-puts-delhi-in-a-diplomatic-fix-over-flag-protocol</link><description>Afghanistan’s UN-sanctioned Foreign Minister Amir Khan Muttaqi has arrived in India for a week-long official visit, marking the first trip by a senior Taliban leader to New Delhi since the group returned to power in 2021 following the withdrawal of US-led forces.
According to NDTV, Muttaqi w</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 16:04:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC offered no explanation for excluding ‘Shapla’ from list of poll symbols, says NCP</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-offered-no-explanation-for-excluding-shapla-from-list-of-poll-symbols-says-ncp</link><description>Leaders of the National Citizen Party (NCP) are refusing to budge from their demand for allocation of the “Shapla” or water lily as electoral symbol during a meeting with the Election Commission.
At the Thursday meeting, the party also sought an explanation from the commission as to wh</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 16:19:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Casemiro embraces leadership role as Brazil captain under Ancelotti</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/casemiro-embraces-leadership-role-as-brazil-captain-under-ancelotti</link><description>Casemiro will don the captain's armband for the 17th time in Brazil's friendly against South Korea on Friday, with the experienced midfielder embracing his leadership role both on and off the pitch under manager Carlo Ancelotti.
Back in the squad since the Italian's arrival after a long period awa</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 16:34:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Leaders react to agreement on Gaza ceasefire</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/leaders-react-to-agreement-on-gaza-ceasefire</link><description>US President Donald Trump said Israel and Hamas had reached a deal for a Gaza ceasefire and hostage release under the first phase of his plan for ending the two-year-old war in the Palestinian enclave.
Following are comments on the agreement from leaders and officials around the world:
US PRESIDE</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 16:49:22 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>