<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 14:29:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Community Bank Bangladesh PLC holds its 72nd Board Meeting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/community-bank-bangladesh-plc-holds-its-72nd-board-meeting</link><description>The 72nd Board Meeting of Community Bank Bangladesh PLC. was held at the Police Headquarters on Sunday, 01 February, 2026.
The meeting was chaired by Mr. Baharul Alam, BPM, Inspector General of Police, Bangladesh and Chairman of Community Bank Bangladesh PLC, according to a media release. 
D</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 11:38:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Men are directors’: Jamaat women play down top post</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/men-are-directors-jamaat-women-play-down-top-post</link><description>The women’s division of the Jamaat-e-Islami has said it views men as women’s “directors” and thus does not consider holding the top position in the party as “important”.
They made the remarks at a briefing at the Nirbachan Bhaban on Sunday, after a meeting betwe</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 11:53:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt must act on atrocities against citizens: Touhid Hossain</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-must-act-on-atrocities-against-citizens-touhid-hossain</link><description>Apparently expressing displeasure over the way minority-related issues are reported, Foreign Affairs Adviser Md Touhid Hossain on Sunday said minorities are citizens of Bangladesh and it is the government’s responsibility to take action if any atrocities are committed against them.
“On</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 12:08:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BRAC Bank launches Post-Maternity Return-to-Work Support Programme</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/brac-bank-launches-post-maternity-return-to-work-support-programme</link><description>BRAC Bank has introduced a Post-Maternity Return-to-Work Support Programme to enable new mothers to transition back to work with confidence, dignity, and sustained wellbeing.
Designed as a holistic journey rather than a single intervention, the programme offers structured support before, during, a</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 12:23:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Saudi ministry suspends Umrah contracts of 1,800 foreign agencies</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/saudi-ministry-suspends-umrah-contracts-of-1800-foreign-agencies</link><description>Saudi Arabia’s Ministry of Hajj and Umrah has suspended contracts with about 1,800 foreign Umrah travel agencies, giving them 10 days to resolve compliance issues identified during a routine performance review.
The action affects agencies operating in the Umrah sector out of an estimated tot</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 12:38:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Russia's Medvedev says victory will come soon in Ukraine war</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/russias-medvedev-says-victory-will-come-soon-in-ukraine-war</link><description>Dmitry Medvedev, deputy chairman of Russia’s powerful Security Council, said that Russia will “soon” win military victory in the Ukraine war but the key thing was to prevent any further conflict.
“Soon,” Medvedev, who served as Russian president from 2008 to 2012, sai</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 12:53:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Adviser Touhid Hossain ditches claims of giving up diplomatic passport</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/adviser-touhid-hossain-ditches-claims-of-giving-up-diplomatic-passport</link><description>Foreign Affairs Adviser Md Touhid Hossain on Sunday said reports claiming that he had surrendered his diplomatic passport are untrue, although he acknowledged that some of his colleagues have opted for ordinary passports to facilitate quicker visa processing due to travel-related issues.
“He</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 13:08:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Army Chief urges officers to perform election duties impartially</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/army-chief-urges-officers-to-perform-election-duties-impartially</link><description>Bangladesh Army Chief General Waker-Uz-Zaman has emphasised fulfilling responsibilities through professionalism, impartiality, discipline, patience, and citizen-friendly behavior during the election.
The Army chief came up with the remarks while speaking after laying the foundation stone of the Ol</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 13:23:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Revolutionary Guards have no plan to hold military exercises in Gulf: Iran official</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/iranian-official-says-revolutionary-guards-have-no-plan-to-hold-military-exercises-in-the-gulf</link><description>The naval forces of Iran's Revolutionary Guards have no plan to carry out live-fire exercises in the Strait of Hormuz as reported by some media outlets earlier this week, an Iranian official told Reuters on Sunday.
Iran's state-run Press TV reported on Thursday that the force would carry out the e</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 13:38:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Remittance tops $3b for 2 months before polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/remittance-inflows-exceed-3b-for-two-consecutive-months-before-election</link><description>Remittance inflows have crossed $3 billion for a second consecutive month with the parliamentary election looming, with expatriates sending $3.17 billion in January.
On Sunday, the latest Bangladesh Bank report showed remittance receipts in January were up 45.1 percent from a year earlier.
In Jan</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 13:53:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Boeing aircraft deal soon: Foreign adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/boeing-aircraft-deal-soon-foreign-adviser</link><description>Bangladesh government is going to sign a deal with US aviation giant Boeing very soon to procure new aircraft for the state-owned carrier Biman Bangladesh Airlines, the country’s foreign affairs adviser has said, citing an acute shortage of planes that has forced the airline to suspend operat</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 14:08:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Banks to remain closed for 4 days</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/banks-to-remain-closed-for-4-days</link><description>All scheduled banks in Bangladesh will remain closed for four consecutive days from February 11 to 14 due to the national election and the regular weekend.
Bangladesh Bank on Sunday issued a notification announcing a holiday on February 11 and 12 (Wednesday and Thursday) to facilitate the election</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 14:23:57 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>