<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 11:40:58 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Mexican military kills cartel boss 'El Mencho' in US-backed raid</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/mexican-military-kills-cartel-boss-el-mencho-in-us-backed-raid</link><description>One of Mexico's most notorious drug lords, Nemesio Oseguera, or "El Mencho," was killed in a military raid on Sunday, sparking widespread retaliatory violence.
President Claudia Sheinbaum has been under mounting pressure from Washington to intensify her offensive against drug cartels blamed for pr</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 07:56:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Normal for elected govt to choose its own people’: Tajul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/normal-for-elected-govt-to-choose-its-own-people-says-departing-ict-chief-prosecutor</link><description>Tajul Islam has described his removal as chief prosecutor of the International Crimes Tribunal (ICT) as a “normal phenomenon”, saying it is natural for an elected government to appoint people of its choice to key state positions.
Speaking to reporters at the tribunal premises on Monday</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 08:30:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Iran agreed secret shoulder-fired missile deal with Russia: Report</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/iran-agreed-secret-shoulder-fired-missile-deal-with-russia-report</link><description>Iran agreed a secret 500 million euro ($589 million) arms deal with Russia to acquire thousands of advanced shoulder-fired missiles, the Financial Times reported on Sunday.
The agreement, signed in Moscow in December, commits Russia to deliver 500 man-portable "Verba" launch units and 2,500 "9M336</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 08:45:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US Ambassador meets Khalilur, discusses issues of mutual interest</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/us-ambassador-meets-minister-khalilur-discusses-issues-of-mutual-interest</link><description>US Ambassador to Bangladesh Brent T Christensen on Monday met Foreign Minister Dr Khalilur Rahman and discussed issues of mutual interest.
"So pleased to continue working together to make both of our countries safer, stronger, and more prosperous," said Ambassador Christensen after the meeting.
T</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 09:00:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chinese Ambassador meets PM Tarique Rahman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/chinese-ambassador-meets-pm-tarique-rahman</link><description>Chinese Ambassador to Bangladesh Yao Wen met Prime Minister Tarique Rahman on Monday.
The meeting was held at the Prime Minister’s office at the Secretariat around 11:00 am, said Prime Minister’s Additional Press Secretary Atikur Rahman Rumon.
He said the Chinese envoy congratulated t</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 09:15:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Man killed in mob beating over theft suspicion in Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/man-killed-in-mob-beating-over-theft-suspicion-in-dhaka</link><description>A 35-year-old man has died from injuries suffered during a “mob beating" after being accused of stealing construction materials in Postogola of Dhaka’s Shyampur.
The victim, identified as Abdur Rahim, passed away while undergoing treatment at Dhaka Medical College Hospital on Monday mo</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 09:30:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EU eyes launching new chapter with new Bangladesh govt</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/eu-eyes-launching-new-chapter-with-new-bangladesh-govt</link><description>Ambassador of the European Union (EU) to Bangladesh Michael Miller, on Monday, said the EU is the country's most reliable and largest commercial partner, as well as a highly significant political ally for the new government.
"We look forward to launching a new chapter with intensified relations wi</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 09:45:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>PM chairs inter-ministerial meeting on launching 'Farmer Card'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/pm-chairs-inter-ministerial-meeting-on-launching-farmer-card</link><description>Prime Minister Tarique Rahman, on Monday, chaired an inter-ministerial meeting on launching 'Farmer Card' aimed at ensuring fair prices for crops produced by farmers.
The Prime Minister presided over the meeting at the Cabinet Division in  Secretariat, Prime Minister's Press Secretary Saleh S</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 10:00:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Human rights are under assault, says UN secretary general</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/human-rights-are-under-assault-says-un-secretary-general</link><description>Human rights are under assault worldwide, the United Nations chief warned on Monday, citing widespread abuses of international law and devastating civilian suffering in conflicts in Sudan, Gaza, and Ukraine.
“The rule of law is being outmuscled by the rule of force,” said UN Secretary</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 10:15:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>President says BNP gave him '100pc support' amid removal attempts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/president-says-bnp-gave-him-100pc-support-amid-removal-attempts</link><description>President Md Shahabuddin has said he received “100 per cent support” from the BNP during what he described as a difficult period under the interim government.
In an interview with the Bangla daily Kaler Kantho published on Monday, the head of state said that the Muhammad Yunus-led inte</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 10:30:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>High interest, extortion, energy crisis ‘suicidal’ for economy: DCCI President</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/high-interest-extortion-energy-crisis-suicidal-for-economy-dcci-president</link><description>High bank lending rates, unstable law and order marked by extortion, energy uncertainty and lack of coordination in revenue management are proving ‘suicidal’ for the economy, President of the Dhaka Chamber of Commerce &amp; Industry (DCCI) Taskeen Ahmed said on Monday.
Taskeen made the rem</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 10:45:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka seeks beneficial ties with every country: FM</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dhaka-seeks-beneficial-ties-with-every-country-fm</link><description>Foreign Minister (FM) Dr. Khalilur Rahman on Monday said Dhaka seeks to build mutually beneficial relations with every country and strengthen partnerships on the basis of equality and respect, while firmly upholding national sovereignty and non-interference principles.
He made the remarks while sp</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 11:00:46 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>