<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 16:28:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>'Be in no doubt' EU will retaliate to any new US tariffs, Ireland says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/be-in-no-doubt-eu-will-retaliate-to-any-new-us-tariffs-ireland-says</link><description>The European Union will retaliate if US tariff threats against European allies over Greenland materialise, but it is premature to consider using the bloc's "Anti-Coercion Instrument", Ireland's prime minister said on Sunday.
"The tempo here has increased very dramatically, very quickly. Be in no d</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 13:51:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pubali Bank’s ADC Division holds Annual Business Conference-2026</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/pubali-banks-adc-division-holds-annual-business-conference-2026</link><description>Pubali Bank PLC's ADC Division holds Annual Business Conference-2026 at the bank’s head office auditorium on Sunday.
Mohammad Ali, Managing Director and CEO of Pubali Bank, was present as chief guest. Mohammad Esha, Mohammad Shahadat Hossain, Ahmed Enayet Manzur, Md. Shahnewaz Khan and Moham</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 14:06:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>2 burnt bodies recovered from abandoned community centre at Savar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/2-burnt-bodies-recovered-from-abandoned-community-centre-at-savar</link><description>Police recovered two charred bodies from an abandoned community centre in Savar municipality area on Sunday.
Local people spotted the bodies at the community centre, about 500 yards away from Savar Model Police Station premises and informed police through national emergency number 999 who recovere</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 14:21:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Uttara Bank inaugurates one stop service</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/uttara-bank-inaugurates-one-stop-service</link><description>Uttara Bank PLC has inaugurated its ‘One Stop Service’ at a function at its corporate branch in Dhaka on Sunday, according to a press release.
Mr. Md. Abul Hashem, Managing Director &amp; CEO of Uttara Bank PLC, inaugurated the service.
Additional Managing Director Mr. Maksudul Hasan, Dep</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 14:36:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rumeen Farhana asked to show cause over ‘mob creation’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rumeen-farhana-show-caused-over-mob-creation</link><description>Rumeen Farhana, the independent candidate for Brahmanbaria-2, has been served a show-cause notice over allegations that she incited a mob and obstructed a mobile court during an official operation.
The government has asked her to explain her actions in connection with the incident.</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 14:36:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ICMAB elects new committee for 2026, with Kausar Alam as president</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/icmab-elects-new-committee-for-2026-with-kausar-alam-as-president</link><description>The Institute of Cost and Management Accountants of Bangladesh (ICMAB) has announced its new executive committee for the year 2026.
In the first meeting of the 19th Council, Md. Kausar Alam FCMA was elected as the President of the Institute. The council also elected a distinguished panel of profes</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 15:06:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Syrian forces advance deeper into the US‑backed, Kurdish‑controlled northeast</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/syrian-forces-advance-deeper-into-the-usbacked-kurdishcontrolled-northeast</link><description>Syrian government troops are pushing towards Raqqa and Hasakah in the northeast of the country, the last strongholds of the US-backed autonomous Kurdish-led administration, government officials and security sources said on Sunday.
They had earlier taken control of the Deir al-Zor’s main oil</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 14:51:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ashanur Rahman wins The International Creative Arts Award 2025</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ashanur-rahman-wins-the-international-creative-arts-award-2025</link><description>Novelist and essayist Md. Ashanur Rahman has been awarded The International Creative Arts Award 2025 by the International Creative Arts, Language &amp; Development Research Centre of the University of Dhaka for his outstanding contribution to literature and its role in “Enriching Minds and Inspir</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 15:06:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BRAC Bank accelerates loan recovery through real-time digital litigation tools</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/brac-bank-accelerates-loan-recovery-through-real-time-digital-litigation-tools</link><description>BRAC Bank has strengthened its loan recovery drive by equipping frontline officials with an advanced digital tab integrated with a mobile-enabled Litigation Management System (LMS), enabling real-time access to lawsuit information at the field level.
According to a press release, the initiative is</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 15:21:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>100 pc textbook print of Ebtedayee completed, 99pc in secondary level</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/100-pc-textbook-print-of-ebtedayee-completed-99pc-in-secondary-level</link><description>Printing and distribution of free new textbooks at all levels in the 2026 academic year is almost completed.
Chairman of National Curriculum and Textbook Board (NCTB) Mahbubul Hoque Patwary told BSS on Sunday.
He said overall progress of textbook printing for secondary level (Class VI-IX) and Ebt</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 15:36:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Libya’s security authorities free more than 200 migrants from ‘secret prison’, two security sources say</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/africa/libyas-security-authorities-free-more-than-200-migrants-from-secret-prison-two-security-sources-say</link><description>Libya’s security authorities have freed more than 200 migrants from what they described as a secret prison in the town of Kufra in the southeast of the country after they were held captive in inhuman conditions, two security sources from the city told Reuters on Sunday.
The security sources,</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 15:51:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rooppur targets fuel loading by February</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rooppur-nuclear-plant-aims-to-complete-fuel-loading-by-february-end</link><description>The first unit of Rooppur Nuclear Power Plant in Pabna’s Ishwardi is targeting completion of fuel loading by the end of February.
Project officers told Salehuddin Ahmed, science and technology and finance advisor, of the timeline, according to a media statement from the Chief Advisor’s</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 16:06:53 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>