<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 16:33:34 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Feb-12 polls must be fair, with no room for bias: Prof Yunus</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/feb-12-polls-must-be-fair-with-no-room-for-bias-prof-yunus</link><description>Chief Adviser Prof Muhammad Yunus on Monday said it is the responsibility of all stakeholders - the government, the Election Commission, and political parties - to ensure that the election scheduled for February 12 is held in a ‘fair and festive’ atmosphere.
“I seek the cooperati</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 14:45:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC set to sit with political parties Tuesday over postal ballots</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-set-to-sit-with-political-parties-tuesday-over-postal-ballots</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) will hold a meeting on Tuesday with the representatives of political parties contesting the national election to discuss issues and concerns related to postal ballots.
The meeting is scheduled to be held at 4:00 pm at the Election Commission, and officials from Banglad</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 15:00:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ziaur Rahman’s 90th birth anniversary celebrated</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ziaur-rahmans-90th-birth-anniversary-celebrated</link><description>The 90th birth anniversary of martyred president Ziaur Rahman, Bir Uttam, revered as the architect of multiparty democracy and also founder of Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP), was celebrated on Monday in a befitting manner.
Marking the anniversary, BNP flags were hoisted at the central office a</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 14:08:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP to rehabilitate families of casualties from July Uprising if comes to power: Rizvi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-to-rehabilitate-families-of-casualties-from-july-uprising-if-comes-to-power-rizvi</link><description>BNP Senior Joint Secretary General Ruhul Kabir Rizvi today said the sacrifices made by the July fighters for the good of the state are unprecedented and if BNP comes to power in the upcoming election, the families of the martyrs and the injured will be rehabilitated.
“If BNP is elected with</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 14:23:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh to celebrate Shab-e-Barat on Feb 3 night</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-to-celebrate-shab-e-barat-on-feb-3-night</link><description>The Muslim festival of Shab-e-Barat will be celebrated in Bangladesh on the night of Feb 3, according to the National Moon-Sighting Committee.
The date was set in a meeting presided over by Md Kamal Uddin, secretary of the Ministry of Religious Affairs at the Islamic Foundation in the Baitul Mukar</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 14:38:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>69 pc growth of remittance inflow till Jan 18</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/69-pc-growth-of-remittance-inflow-till-jan-18</link><description>Inflow of remittances witnessed a year-on-year growth of 69 percent reaching US$2,040 million in the first 18 days of January, according to the latest data of Bangladesh Bank (BB) issued on Monday.
Last year, during the same period, the country’s remittance inflow was $1,207million.
During</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 14:53:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>RAB member killed in Sitakunda clash</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/rab-member-killed-in-sitakunda-clash</link><description>A member of the Rapid Action Battalion (RAB) has been killed and three others critically injured in a gunfight with “local criminals” in Jungle Salimpur of Chattogram’s Sitakunda.
The clash erupted on Monday afternoon during a RAB‑7 operation in the area.
The dead has been ident</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 15:08:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Forex reserves to exceed $35b by FY26: BB chief</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/forex-reserves-to-exceed-35b-by-fy26-bb-chief</link><description>Bangladesh Bank (BB) Governor Dr. Ahsan H. Mansur on Monday expressed strong optimism regarding the country’s macroeconomic stability, projecting that foreign currency reserves are on track to meet and surpass US$35 billion by the end of the current fiscal year 2025-26 (FY26).
“Reachin</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 15:23:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Student groups stage demo protesting postponement of SUST student union election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/student-groups-stage-demo-protesting-postponement-of-sust-student-union-election</link><description>Students of Shahjalal University of Science and Technology (SUST) blocked the Sylhet-Sunamganj regional highway protesting the High Court order that postponed the first SUST students union election in almost 30 years, slated for Tuesday (Jan 20).
Witnesses said the students brought out a processio</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 15:38:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>10 injured in BNP activists’ fraternal clash in Jhenaidah</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/10-injured-in-bnp-activists-fraternal-clash-in-jhenaidah</link><description>At least 10 individuals were injured in a clash between two BNP factions over establishing dominance in Shailkupa upazila of Jhenaidah on Monday morning.
The incident took place at Bishnudia village under Manoharpur union.
Police and local sources said supporters of district Jubo Dal joint genera</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 15:53:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Administration penalised me thrice: Rumeen</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/rumeen-farhana-says-administration-punished-her-thrice-over-single-offence</link><description>Rumeen Farhana, the independent candidate for Brahmanbaria-2, has said the administration has “punished” her three times over an offence.
She accused the election authorities of showing “bias” during a meeting with journalists at the Brahmanbaria Press Club on Monday.
She</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 16:08:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique should face show-cause notice before others over electoral code violation, says NCP</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-should-face-show-cause-notice-before-others-over-electoral-code-violation-says-ncp</link><description>The National Citizen Party (NCP) leaders have renewed their offensive against Tarique Rahman barely three weeks before the Feb 12 vote, saying the BNP supremo should be the first to explain the allegations of violating the election code of conduct.
Their tirade against Tarique came minutes after t</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 16:23:15 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>