<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 09:44:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Abul Kasem Khan new chairperson of BUILD</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/abul-kasem-khan-new-chairperson-of-build</link><description>Abul Kasem Khan, vice chairman of AK Khan and Company Limited, has been appointed chairperson of Business Initiative Leading Development (BUILD) for the 2026-27 tenure.
Mr Khan, a member of the BUILD trustee board since 2020, assumed the leadership role following a formal resolution at the 39th tr</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 04:50:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BTRC adds new frequency bands for NGSO satellite</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/btrc-adds-new-frequency-bands-for-ngso-satellite</link><description>The Bangladesh Telecommunication Regulatory Commission (BTRC) has appended new frequency bands for Non-Geostationary Orbit (NGSO) satellite services, signalling a significant regulatory move to meet the growing demand for next-generation satellite connectivity in Bangladesh.
In a circular issued r</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 05:05:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DU completes preparations to observe Amar Ekushey tomorrow</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/du-completes-preparations-to-observe-amar-ekushey-tomorrow</link><description>Dhaka University (DU) has completed all preparations for observing Amar Ekushey and International Mother Language Day tomorrow (Saturday), as announced in a press release from the university's Public Relations Office on Thursday.
The release states that strict entry regulations will be enforced on</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 05:20:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ICT proceedings to continue as usual: Tajul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ict-proceedings-to-continue-as-usual-tajul</link><description>Chief Prosecutor Muhmmad Tajul Islam, at a press briefing on Thursday, stated that trial proceedings of the International Crimes Tribunal (ICT) in Dhaka would continue at the same pace as before.
He noted that although the government had not made any formal announcement, the ICT had been informed</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 05:35:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>18 researchers receive PhD, 10 MPhil from DU</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/18-researchers-receive-phd-10-mphil-from-du</link><description>Eighteen researchers have received PhD degree and ten others MPhil from Dhaka University (DU) in recent times.
The degrees were approved at a Syndicate meeting on February 1, presided over by DU Vice-Chancellor Professor Niaz Ahmed Khan. The information was confirmed in a press release, issued by</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 05:50:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>MANIKGANJ, SYLHET: Too many brick kilns put public health, environment in crisis</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/manikganj-sylhet-too-many-brick-kilns-put-public-health-environment-in-crisis</link><description>An excessive number of brick klins have been polluting the environment in a union in Manikganj, while pollution from unauthorised brick klins deteriorates public health and the environment across four districts in the Sylhet division.
Our correspondent from Manikganj writes, Singair Upazila's Bald</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 06:05:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gaza deaths in war's first 15 months higher than reported, study says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/gaza-deaths-in-wars-first-15-months-higher-than-reported-study-says</link><description>More than 75,000 Palestinians were killed in the first 15 months of Israel's military assault in Gaza, a figure far higher than the 49,000 deaths local health officials announced at the time, says a new study by The Lancet Global Health medical journal.
The peer-reviewed study, published on Wednes</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 06:20:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No security threat surrounding Feb 21 events, says DMP chief</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/no-security-threat-surrounding-feb-21-events-says-dmp-chief</link><description>Dhaka Metropolitan Police Commissioner Sheikh Md Sazzat Ali has said there is no security threat surrounding the observance of Language Martyrs’ Day and International Mother Language Day on Feb 21.
However, he said a multi-layered security arrangement has been put in place, with 15,000 polic</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 07:08:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Food stocks sufficient to keep Ramadan market stable, says commerce minister</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/food-stocks-sufficient-to-keep-ramadan-market-stable-says-commerce-minister</link><description>Commerce Minister Khandaker Abdul Muktadir has said the government has sufficient food stocks to keep prices of essential commodities stable during Ramadan.
Speaking to reporters at Sylhet Osmani International Airport on Friday, he said ensuring price stability was one of the key responsibilities</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 07:23:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Public sufferings in the name of movement won’t be tolerated : RAB</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/public-sufferings-in-the-name-of-movement-wont-be-tolerated-rab</link><description>No one will be allowed to hold the general public hostage or create public suffering in the name of movements or demands, said RAB Director General AKM Shahidur Rahman on Friday.
All necessary measures will be taken to ensure uninterrupted movement and daily life of ordinary people, he told report</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 09:04:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two suspected robbers lynched by mob in Gaibandha</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/two-suspected-robbers-lynched-by-mob-in-gaibandha</link><description>Two men have been beaten to death by locals on suspicion of robbery in Gaibandha’s Sadullapur Upazila.
The incident occurred at dawn on Friday in Khorddmojahidpur village, according to Sadullapur Police Station chief (OC) Abdul Alim.
Police said the men were part of a group that allegedly a</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 09:19:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CNG filling stations to remain closed from 3pm-9pm during Ramadan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cng-filling-stations-to-remain-closed-from-3pm-9pm-during-ramadan</link><description>The government has extended the daily downtime for CNG filling stations during Ramadan to ensure an adequate gas supply for power generation at Iftar.
In a notice issued on Friday, the Energy and Mineral Resources Division said CNG stations will remain closed from 3pm to 9pm each day from the firs</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 09:34:17 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>