<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 13:33:35 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>CA stresses self-reliance, quality education in budget formulation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ca-stresses-self-reliance-quality-education-in-budget-formulation</link><description>Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus on Wednesday put strong emphasis on formulating budget in a self-reliance manner focusing quality education, rural development, youth-women empowerment, local production and health.
The Chief Adviser laid the emphasis while reviewing the revised budget, which</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 10:04:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>TIB finds Tk 29.27 billion irregularities in six BPDB solar projects</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tib-finds-tk-2927-billion-irregularities-in-six-bpdb-solar-projects</link><description>Irregularities amounting to over Tk 29.27 billion were identified in six government and independent power producer (IPP) solar projects undertaken by the Bangladesh Power Development Board (BPDB) between October 2010 and October 2025, according to a study released by Transparency International Bang</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 10:19:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique’s flight at midnight: BNP</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tariques-flight-to-depart-london-at-midnight-says-salahuddin</link><description>Acting BNP chief Tarique Rahman’s flight for Bangladesh will depart from London’s Heathrow Airport shortly after midnight Bangladesh time, senior leader Salahuddin Ahmed has said.
Speaking at a press conference at the BNP chairperson’s Gulshan office on Wednesday afternoon, Salah</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 10:34:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prothom Alo, Daily Star attackers to be brought to book: Press Secretary</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/prothom-alo-daily-star-attackers-to-be-brought-to-book-press-secretary</link><description>Chief Adviser’s Press Secretary Shafiqul Alam on Wednesday said all those involved in the recent attacks on Prothom Alo and The Daily Star offices would be brought to book.
Thirty-one people have so far been arrested in connection with the attacks, seeing videos and other visuals, he told a</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 10:49:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Attorney general to ‘resign, contest in polls’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/attorney-general-asaduzzaman-to-resign-and-contest-in-polls</link><description>Attorney General Md Asaduzzaman has shared his willingness to step down from the top legal officer rank of the state to contest in the general elections.
On Wednesday, he told the media he had sought the nomination already.
“I’m still holding the post of attorney general. I’ll s</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 11:04:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BRTA tops corruption list among public service offices: BBS survey</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/brta-tops-corruption-list-among-public-service-offices-bbs-survey</link><description>The Bangladesh Road Transport Authority (BRTA) has been identified as the most corruption-prone public service office in the country, according to the Citizen Perception Survey (CPS) 2025, released by the Bangladesh Bureau of Statistics (BBS).
The survey found that 63.29 percent of citizens who so</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 11:19:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>447th board meeting of Al-Arafah Islami Bank held</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/447th-board-meeting-of-al-arafah-islami-bank-held</link><description>The 447th board meeting of Al-Arafah Islami Bank PLC was held on Wednesday, December 24, 2025, at the Bank’s Head Office.
Chairman of the Board of Directors Khwaja Shahriar presided over the meeting, according to a press release.
The overall business performance of the Bank was reviewed and</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 11:34:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hadi murder: Suspect’s 'associate' held with firearm</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hadi-murder-probe-motorcycle-riders-associate-held-with-firearm-in-motel-raid</link><description>Police have arrested an alleged associate of the rider of the motorcycle used in the drive-by of Sharif Osman bin Hadi, seizing a foreign firearm and ammunition.
Himon Rahman Shikdar, 32, was arrested on Wednesday morning at a local motel.
Acting on his information, officers later recovered a for</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 11:49:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shimanto Bank inks MoU with Dhaka Central International Medical College &amp; Hospital</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/shimanto-bank-inks-mou-with-dhaka-central-international-medical-college-hospital</link><description>Shimanto Bank PLC has recently signed a Memorandum of Understanding (MoU) with Dhaka Central International Medical College &amp; Hospital at the Bank’s Head Office.
Under this agreement, all Debit and Credit Card holders, as well as employees of Shimanto Bank, will be entitled to enjoy exclusive</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 12:04:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rumin Farhana collects nomination papers as independent candidate</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rumin-farhana-picks-up-nomination-papers-for-brahmanbaria-2-as-independent-candidate</link><description>Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) leader Rumin Farhana has collected nomination papers for Brahmanbaria-2 to contest the parliamentary polls as an independent candidate.
The seat has been ceded by her party to its alliance partner Jamiat Ulama-e-Islam Bangladesh.
Sarail Upazila Jubo Dal’s</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 12:19:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>90th meeting of Shari'ah Supervisory Committee of Shahjalal Islami Bank held</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/90th-meeting-of-shariah-supervisory-committee-of-shahjalal-islami-bank-held</link><description>The 90th meeting of Shari'ah Supervisory Committee of Shahjalal Islami Bank PLC (SJIBPLC) was held on 24th December 2025 at the Board meeting room of the Corporate Head Office of the Bank.
The Chairman of Shari'ah Supervisory Committee of Shahjalal Islami Bank PLC Mufti Shamsuddin Zia, presided ov</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 12:34:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sohel from Mymensingh wins a scooter through Nagad transactions</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/sohel-from-mymensingh-wins-a-scooter-through-nagad-transactions</link><description>Shafiqul Islam Sohel of Mymensingh has won a Hero Pleasure Refresh 102cc scooter by making transactions through Nagad.
He received the prize by participating in Nagad’s campaign titled “Asha Aar Fera, Surprise Sera” [Come back or start fresh, surprises at their best].
Popular te</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 12:49:07 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>