<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 17:27:58 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>910th Executive Committee meeting of Shahjalal Islami Bank held</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/910th-executive-committee-meeting-of-shahjalal-islami-bank-held</link><description>The 910th meeting of the Executive Committee (EC) of Shahjalal Islami Bank PLC. (SJIB PLC) was held on 10th December 2025 at Corporate Head Office of the bank.
The meeting was presided over by Mr. Akkas Uddin Mollah, the Chairman of Executive Committee (EC) of the bank, according to a media releas</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 13:56:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Flat as ‘bribe’: Tulip faces prosecution</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/acc-to-prosecute-british-mp-tulip-siddiq-over-receiving-flat-as-bribe</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) has approved a chargesheet against UK Labour MP Tulip Siddiq over allegations that she received a flat at Dhaka’s Gulshan as a bribe.
The flat was allegedly obtained from Eastern Housing Limited after orchestrating the illegal transfer of a plot through a</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 14:11:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CID charges ex-minister Dastagir Gazi over ‘laundering’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cid-charges-former-awami-league-minister-holam-dastagir-gazi-with-money-laundering</link><description>The Criminal Investigation Department (CID) has brought charges of money laundering against former textiles and jute minister Golam Dastagir Gazi and seven others involving Tk 870 million.
The CID informed the media about the filing of the case on Thursday.
The suspects in the case include his pe</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 14:26:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Belgium deputy PM: Russian frozen assets to be used for Ukraine loan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/belgium-deputy-pm-russian-frozen-assets-to-be-used-for-ukraine-loan</link><description>Russian frozen assets will have to be used for Ukraine at some point, Belgium’s deputy prime minister Vincent Van Peteghem said on Thursday, added however Belgium “would not take any reckless compromises” before it agreed to any deal over this.
“At some point, these frozen</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 14:41:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>European bird flu spike due to record wild birds cases, EFSA says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/european-bird-flu-spike-due-to-record-wild-birds-cases-efsa-says</link><description>An unprecedented number of bird flu outbreaks among wild birds and their wide geographic spread are driving an early and strong wave of the disease in Europe this year, the European Food Safety Authority said on Thursday.
Highly pathogenic avian influenza has led to the culling of hundreds of mill</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 14:56:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khaleda remains in critical state under intensive treatment: Board</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/khaleda-remains-in-critical-state-under-intensive-treatment-board</link><description>BNP Chairperson and former Prime Minister Begum Khaleda Zia remains in critical condition at Evercare Hospital, where she is on ventilator support and receiving intensive care for multiple serious complications, according to the medical board overseeing her treatment.
In its latest update provided</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 15:11:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tobacco industry alarmed at govt’s reluctance to allow stakeholder-inclusive consultation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/tobacco-industry-alarmed-at-govts-reluctance-to-allow-stakeholder-inclusive-consultation</link><description>Leading companies in the tobacco industry today issued a joint statement, expressing their serious concerns over the government’s attempt to pass the proposed amendment to the Tobacco Control Act without a stakeholder-inclusive consultation in the absence of appropriate Parliamentary process.</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 15:26:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Child rescued after 32 hours in Rajshahi well</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/2-year-old-child-rescued-from-abandoned-well-after-32-hours-in-rajshahi</link><description>The Fire Service has rescued a 2-year-old child from a borehole in Rajshahi, 32 hours after he slipped in.
The Fire Service recovery team retrieved the toddler, identified as Sajid Hossain, around 9pm on Thursday using a tunnel dug next to the well in Tanore Upazila.
The incident occurred on Wedn</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 15:41:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BB purchases $149m from 16 banks to stabilise forex rate</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh-bank-purchases-149-million-from-16-banks-to-stabilise-forex-rate</link><description>Bangladesh Bank has purchased a significant amount of US dollars from local banks as part of its ongoing efforts to stabilise the foreign exchange market and support the flow of remittances and repatriate export earnings.
On Thursday (December 11), the central bank acquired approximately $149 mill</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 15:56:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>WHO chief 'not worried' about US bilateral deals affecting pandemic treaty</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/who-chief-not-worried-about-us-bilateral-deals-affecting-pandemic-treaty</link><description>The World Health Organization chief said on Thursday that he was hopeful an annex to a pandemic treaty would be adopted next year, saying that he did not see bilateral negotiations between the United States and African states as a threat.
WHO chief Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus told reporters at a pr</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 16:30:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nobel Peace Prize winner Machado vows to bring award back to Venezuela</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/nobel-peace-prize-winner-machado-vows-to-bring-award-back-to-venezuela</link><description>Nobel Peace Prize laureate Maria Corina Machado said she planned to take her award back to Venezuela, but declined to say on Thursday when she would return to her home country after leaving in great secrecy to receive the honour.
Venezuelan opposition leader Machado arrived in Oslo in the ea</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 16:45:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two-year-old dies after 32-hour rescue from pit in Rajshahi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/two-year-old-dies-after-32-hour-rescue-from-pit-in-rajshahi</link><description>A two-year-old boy who was pulled from a deep pit after a 32-hour rescue operation in Rajshahi’s Tanore upazila has died, officials said.
Fire Service Director (Operation and Maintenance) Lieutenant Colonel Mohammad Tajul Islam said doctors at the Tanore Upazila Health Complex declared the c</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 17:00:46 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>