<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 12:45:20 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>US strikes Venezuela after Trump's threats against Maduro</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-strikes-venezuela-after-trumps-threats-against-maduro</link><description>The US has carried out strikes inside Venezuela, a US official said, as explosions rocked the capital Caracas following months of threats by President Donald Trump against Venezuela's President Nicolas Maduro.
The Venezuelan government said attacks also took place in the states of Miranda, Aragua</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 09:45:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC urges voters to safeguard secrecy of postal ballots</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-urges-voters-to-safeguard-secrecy-of-postal-ballots</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has urged voters to strictly protect the secrecy of postal ballots, cautioning that sharing any information, images, or videos of their vote or ballot on social media constitutes a punishable offence under the law.
In a message issued today (Saturday), the EC stated, "</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 10:00:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique Rahman’s nomination cleared for Dhaka-17 seat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-rahmans-nomination-cleared-for-dhaka-17-seat</link><description>Election officials have declared the nomination papers of BNP leader Tarique Rahman valid for the Dhaka-17 constituency in the upcoming 13th parliamentary election.
The decision was announced on Saturday following the scrutiny of nomination papers at the returning officer’s office in Segunba</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 10:15:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US forces detain Venezuela's President Maduro</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-forces-detain-venezuelas-president-maduro</link><description>US President Donald Trump said on Saturday that American forces had carried out an attack on Venezuela and detained the country’s President Nicolás Maduro, according to reports by international media.
In a statement, Trump claimed the United States had launched a “major operatio</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 10:16:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prof Yunus conveys condolences to Switzerland after deadly resort fire</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/prof-yunus-conveys-condolences-to-switzerland-after-deadly-resort-fire</link><description>Chief Adviser Prof Muhammad Yunus has expressed his deepest condolences to Swiss Confederation President Guy Parmelin following a devastating fire at a bar in the ski resort town of Crans-Montana that killed at least 40 people and injured 119 others, one of the deadliest tragedies in Switzerland&amp;rs</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 10:31:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How to help your child fall in love with reading</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/others/how-to-help-your-child-fall-in-love-with-reading</link><description>For schoolchildren, January means the joy of holding new books, the sweet smell of fresh notebooks, and the quiet excitement of a new classroom. The first month brings joy to the lives of children and teenagers. For many of them, getting a book in hand at this time means their duty is to memorise c</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 10:46:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DITF to boost exports, economic activity, jobs: Yunus</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ditf-to-boost-exports-economic-activity-jobs-yunus</link><description>Highlighting the importance of economic stability and growth, Chief Adviser Prof Muhammad Yunus has expressed optimism that the 30th 'Dhaka International Trade Fair (DITF) 2026' will help expand economic activity, create jobs and strengthen Bangladesh’s exports.
“From the very outset,</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 11:01:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cold wave sweeps 9 districts, more expected in January</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cold-wave-sweeps-9-districts-more-expected-in-january</link><description>The Bangladesh Meteorological Department (BMD) has said a mild cold wave is currently sweeping over nine districts in the country’s north-western region.
The department has forecast two to three mild to moderate cold waves across the country during the month of January, bdnews24.com reports.</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 11:16:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Political stability crucial for economic recovery before election: DCCI</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/political-stability-crucial-for-economic-recovery-before-election-dcci</link><description>Dhaka Chamber of Commerce &amp; Industry (DCCI) has warned that political uncertainty ahead of Bangladesh’s national election could threaten economic recovery, urging timely and effective policy measures to sustain growth and bolster investor confidence in 2026.
In a media release on Saturday, t</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 11:32:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nominations of BNP's Babar, wife cleared for Netrokona-4 constituency</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/nominations-of-bnps-babar-wife-cleared-for-netrokona-4-constituency</link><description>The Election Commission has declared the nominations of former state minister Lutfozzaman Babar and his wife Tahmina Zaman Sraboni valid.
The couple has now entered the election race for the Netrokona-4 constituency, which covers Mohanganj, Madan, and Khaliajuri.
Tahmina is running as an independ</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 11:47:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>17 nominations validated in Thakurgaon, Fakhrul among candidates</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/17-nominations-validated-in-thakurgaon-fakhrul-among-candidates</link><description>The nomination papers of 17 candidates across three constituencies in Thakurgaon, including that of BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir, have been declared valid by the Returning Officer for the 13th national election.
The announcement was made on Saturday morning at the office of th</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 12:02:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CAB seeks govt action to rein in LPG, sugar, edible oil prices</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cab-seeks-govt-action-to-rein-in-lpg-sugar-edible-oil-prices</link><description>Consumers Association of Bangladesh (CAB) has issued a seven-point demand to the government, warning of widespread consumer frustration amid what it calls abnormal and sustained price hikes in sugar, liquefied petroleum gas (LPG) and edible oils.
In a statement on Saturday, CAB accused an influent</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 12:17:59 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>