<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 04:37:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Keraniganj building fire under control after 7 hrs; 45 rescued</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/keraniganj-building-fire-under-control-after-7-hrs-45-rescued</link><description>A massive fire that broke out at a 10-storey building in the Dhaka's South Keraniganj on Saturday was brought under control after nearly seven hours of intensive efforts by firefighters.
The blaze started around 5:37am on the ground floor of Jabel-e-Noor Tower, which houses a jhut (garment scrap)</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 01:45:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Negative margin assets risk market pressure during NBFI liquidation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/negative-margin-assets-risk-market-pressure-during-nbfi-liquidation</link><description>The negative margin accounts of subsidiaries of non-bank financial institutions (NBFIs) slated for liquidation should be settled through liquidators to avoid potential selling pressure on the equity market, experts said.
The recommendation comes after the Bangladesh Bank proposed the liquidation o</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 02:00:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Healthcare confidence erodes amid systemic weaknesses</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/healthcare-confidence-erodes-amid-systemic-weaknesses</link><description>Bangladesh's healthcare system continues to face mounting pressure from low public spending, rising treatment costs and slow adoption of modern technologies, experts and stakeholders said on Saturday.
These systemic shortcomings that also include weak regulation and shortages of skilled profession</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 02:15:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NSU hosts Quran Conference and Seerah Exhibition 2025</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/article/nsu-hosts-quran-conference-and-seerah-exhibition-2025</link><description>North South University (NSU) hosted the "NSU Quran Conference and Seerah Exhibition 2025" at the NSU Plaza Area recently, bringing together prominent Islamic scholars and university leadership to discuss the relevance of Quranic teachings in contemporary life.
The grand conference featured disting</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 02:30:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladeshi team wins silver medal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/article/bangladeshi-team-wins-silver-medal</link><description>"Being part of the Seoul International Invention Fair 2025 was an extraordinary and eye-opening experience. I had the opportunity to observe how global innovators approach complex problems, design advanced solutions, and maintain precision under scrutiny," said Calibrator-Z team member Jayed.
At S</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 02:45:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Are Bangladesh's teachers ready for AI?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/article/are-bangladeshs-teachers-ready-for-ai</link><description>Gone are the days when the traditional chalkboard was the prime focus of classrooms in Bangladesh. In its place, a new and increasingly influential presence has begun to emerge: artificial intelligence (AI). Globally as well as in Bangladesh's schools, AI use has rapidly gained speed over the past</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 03:00:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Stories of rural women changing their lot</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/analysis/stories-of-rural-women-changing-their-lot</link><description>When Shilpi from Dakshin Paikpara in Chandpur suddenly found herself in a role of raising two children alone, she feared her life had reached a dead end. Her husband had abandoned the family, and her days were spent worrying about how to manage food, school fees, and the most basic needs. Today, th</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 03:15:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Procurement vision and national security</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/analysis/procurement-vision-and-national-security</link><description>A nation's procurement vision and its national security priorities are closely linked. In today's competitive geopolitical environment, procurement is no longer a routine administrative function. It plays a direct role in safeguarding sovereignty, strengthening resilience and ensuring long-term nat</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 03:30:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>TIB concerned over fundamental changes to NHRC Ordinance</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tib-concerned-over-fundamental-changes-to-nhrc-ordinance</link><description>Transparency International Bangladesh (TIB) has claimed that the newly-adopted fundamental changes to the National Human Rights Commission (NHRC) Ordinance 2025 have placed the commission's formation under direct bureaucratic control, erasing prospects for independence from government influence.
T</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 03:45:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BD must focus on tech, edu, skill dev to harness youth dividend</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bd-must-focus-on-tech-edu-skill-dev-to-harness-youth-dividend</link><description>Speakers at a programme on Saturday emphasised that Bangladesh should prioritise technology-based entrepreneurship, time-relevant education, and skill development for youths to fully benefit from the country's demographic dividend.
They also highlighted the need to strengthen industry-academia lin</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 04:00:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DU Arts, Law, Social Sciences unit intake test held</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/du-arts-law-social-sciences-unit-intake-test-held</link><description>The admission test for the first-year undergraduate programmes of the Arts, Law and Social Sciences faculties of Dhaka University for the 2025-26 academic session was held on Saturday (December 13).
The examination took place from 11:00 am to 12:30 pm. A total of 107,701 candidates appeared for th</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 04:15:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP stages nationwide demo; Inqilab Manch holds protest rally</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bnp-stages-nationwide-demo-inqilab-manch-holds-protest-rally</link><description>The Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) on Saturday organised a nation-wide protest programme to condemn the heinous assassination attempt on Inqilab Manch founder Osman Hadi, who was shot by miscreants on Friday noon.
Hadi is an aspirant for Dhaka-8 constituency in the 13th parliamentary election.</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 04:30:58 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>