<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 13:42:37 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>BNP to ensure fee institutional internet, if voted to power: Mahdi Amin</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-to-ensure-fee-institutional-internet-if-voted-to-power-mahdi-amin</link><description>Adviser to the BNP Chairman and the party's Election Steering Committee Spokesperson Dr Mahdi Amin today (Saturday) said that if the party comes to power, free institutional internet facilities will be ensured for all. 
He said, "BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman has announced plans to gradually pr</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 11:20:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cuba declares "international emergency" in response to US executive order</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/cuba-declares-international-emergency-in-response-to-us-executive-order</link><description>Cuban Foreign Minister Bruno Rodriguez Parrilla said Friday that Cuba has declared an "international emergency" in response to a recent executive order of tariff threats issued by US President Donald Trump.
Rodriguez said in a post on X that the Cuban people, with the solidarity of the internation</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 11:35:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Power gel, detonators seized from abandoned Sylhet school</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rab-recovers-power-gel-detonators-from-deserted-primary-school-building-in-sylhet</link><description>The Rapid Action Battalion (RAB) has recovered 25 power gel sticks and 27 electric detonators from an abandoned school building in Sylhet’s Kanaighat Upazila, materials the force described as being used to make “high-grade explosives”.
The items were recovered on Friday night fro</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 11:50:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique pledges to export handloom goods worldwide if elected</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-pledges-to-export-handloom-goods-worldwide-if-elected</link><description>BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman has pledged to take Bangladesh’s handloom products to global markets, saying his party would launch export initiatives for the sector if it forms the government.
Speaking at an election rally at the Bangladesh Small and Cottage Industries Corporation (BSCIC) Indus</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 12:05:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Is future remittance sustainable without skilled migration?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/is-future-remittance-sustainable-without-skilled-migration</link><description>Remittance has long been a reliable pillar of the Bangladesh economy. Its contribution is evident in stabilising foreign exchange reserves, keeping rural consumption active, and reducing poverty. However, a fundamental question has now surfaced: Is it possible to keep future remittances sustainable</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 11:28:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC dispatches ballots to over 518,000 domestic voters</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-dispatches-ballots-to-over-518000-domestic-voters</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has sent postal ballots to 518,603 voters across the country who registered through the “Postal Vote BD” app to cast their votes in the 13th Jatiya Sangsad election and referendum.  
Salim Ahmad Khan, Team Leader of the OCV-SDI project on expatria</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 11:43:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Warsh 'regime change' faces steep hurdles at a sprawling US central bank</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/warsh-regime-change-faces-steep-hurdles-at-a-sprawling-us-central-bank</link><description>Kevin Warsh checks a long list of boxes for President Donald Trump as his pick to run the Federal Reserve, with longstanding political and social ties to the president, deep Wall Street connections and a well-tailored demeanor, but how deeply and quickly he will cut interest rates and how aggressiv</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 11:58:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Third shipment of US wheat arrives at Ctg port</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/third-shipment-of-us-wheat-arrives-at-ctg-port</link><description>Another consignment of 58,359 metric tonnes (MTs) of wheat from the United States (US) has arrived at Chittagong Port.
The vessel MV WF Artemis, carrying the wheat, docked at the outer anchorage of the country’s premier seaport on Saturday, the Food Ministry said in a statement.
Under the a</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 12:13:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sarba Mitra Chakma backtracks, refuses to quit DUCSU post</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/sarba-mitra-chakma-backtracks-refuses-to-quit-ducsu-post</link><description>Sarba Mitra Chakma, a Dhaka University Central Students’ Union (DUCSU) executive member who has faced criticism over a series of controversies, has withdrawn his decision to resign.
Speaking to bdnews24.com on Saturday afternoon, Sarba Mitra said students had urged him not to step down, desc</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 12:28:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>JnU psychology department bids farewell to first batch of MCCP programme</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/jnu-psychology-department-bids-farewell-to-first-batch-of-mccp-programme</link><description>The Department of Psychology at Jagannath University marked a historic milestone this week, hosting a grand farewell ceremony for the very first batch of the Master's in Counselling and Clinical Psychology (MCCP) program.
The event, held at the department’s Laboratory-1, was an emotional yet</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 12:43:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Eastern Lubricants Blenders holds 57th Annual General Meeting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/eastern-lubricants-blenders-holds-57th-annual-general-meeting</link><description>The 57th Annual General Meeting of Eastern Lubricants Blenders PLC. was held virtually through Digital Platform on 31st January 2026 at 03:00 pm.
The Chairman of the Board of Directors of Eastern Lubricants Blenders PLC. Mr. A. H. M. Nurul Islam (Retired Secretary to the Government of Bangladesh)</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 12:58:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BASIC Bank’s Managers Conference-2026 held</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/basic-banks-managers-conference-2026-held</link><description>BASIC Bank PLC, 100 per cent state-owned commercial bank, held the Managers Conference—2026 on Saturday at Mukti Auditorium, Biddut Bhaban in the Capital, according to a press release.
Helal Ahmed Chowdhury, Chairman of the bank's Board of Directors, inaugurated the conference as Chief Guest</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 13:13:53 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>