<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 13:04:36 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Is SpiceJet barred from flying over Bangladesh skies?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/is-spicejet-barred-from-flying-over-bangladesh-skies</link><description>The Civil Aviation Authority of Bangladesh (CAAB) has refuted reports in the Indian media that SpiceJet has been barred from entering the country’s airspace over unpaid dues.
Several Indian outlets, citing news agency PTI, reported that Bangladesh was not “allowing” the Indian ai</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 10:40:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Inmate dies after falling ill at Dhaka Central Jail</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/inmate-dies-after-falling-ill-at-dhaka-central-jail</link><description>An inmate at Dhaka Central Jail died after falling ill, officials said on Thursday.
The deceased was identified as Abdul Khaleque, 65, son of the late Kafil Uddin.
Prison guard Abdullah said Khalek fell ill inside the jail.
On the instructions of the authorities, he was taken to Dhaka Medical Co</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 10:11:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two jailed as authorities seize 400kg of horse meat in Sirajganj</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/food/two-jailed-as-authorities-seize-400kg-of-horse-meat-in-sirajganj</link><description>Authorities have seized around 400kg of horse meat in Sirajganj’s Kazipur Upazila and jailed two men for attempting to smuggle it for sale.
The drive was carried out on Friday morning in the Meghai jetty area along the Jamuna River, said Kazipur Upazila administrator (UNO) Mustafizur Rahman.</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 10:26:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh lifts suspension of visa services in Delhi: report</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-lifts-suspension-of-visa-services-in-delhi-report</link><description>Bangladesh has resumed visa services for Indian citizens at its High Commission in New Delhi around two months after they were suspended, Indian media report.
The services were restored on Friday morning, according to India Today.
The development comes three days after the BNP-led government took</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 10:41:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Kremlin says it can't say yet when new talks on Ukraine will take place</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/kremlin-says-it-cant-say-yet-when-new-talks-on-ukraine-will-take-place</link><description>Kremlin spokesman Dmitry Peskov said on Friday that he cannot yet confirm when and where a new round of talks on Ukraine will take place.
Earlier on Friday, Russian state news agency TASS reported, citing a source, that next talks would be held in Geneva with the participation of delegations from</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 10:56:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Injured tigress likely to return to Sundarbans in March</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/injured-tigress-likely-to-return-to-sundarbans-in-march</link><description>The tigress that was rescued after being trapped and seriously injured is expected to be released back into her natural habitat in the Sundarbans as early as March, officials said.
The animal has shown significant recovery after receiving about 45 days of treatment at the rescue centre in Khulna C</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 11:11:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Temperatures rising, but no relief from rain yet</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/temperatures-rising-but-no-relief-from-rain-yet</link><description>Temperatures are rising across Bangladesh, with the Met Office saying there is little prospect of rain in the coming days.
“We had indicated earlier that temperatures would rise after the 15th of February. This trend is expected to continue over the next few days,” Meteorologist Kazi J</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 11:26:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Man stabbed to death in Jashore</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/man-stabbed-to-death-in-jashore</link><description>A village doctor was stabbed to death by miscreants in Sharsha upazila of Jashore while returning home after offering prayers on Thursday night.
The incident took place around 9:30 pm at Baripota village in Sharsha upazila.
The deceased was identified as Al Amin, son of Rafiqul Islam of the Shars</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 11:41:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US tariff revenue at risk in Supreme Court ruling tops $175 billion, Penn-Wharton estimates</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/us-tariff-revenue-at-risk-in-supreme-court-ruling-tops-175-billion-penn-wharton-estimates</link><description>More than $175 billion in US tariff collections are at risk of having to be refunded if the US Supreme Court rules against President Donald Trump’s broad emergency tariffs, Penn-Wharton Budget Model economists said on Friday.
Their estimate, produced at a request from Reuters, was derived fr</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 11:56:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Amar Ekushey: Nation to pay tribute to language martyrs at zero hour</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/amar-ekushey-nation-to-pay-tribute-to-language-martyrs-at-zero-hour</link><description>The nation is set to observe ‘Amar Ekushey’, the Language Martyr’s Day and the International Mother Language Day early Saturday, marking the supreme sacrifice of the language heroes for upholding the dignity of the mother tongue, Bangla.
The day will also be observed around the w</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 12:11:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>President for being more mindful in preserving quality, dignity of Bangla</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/president-for-being-more-mindful-in-preserving-quality-dignity-of-bangla</link><description>President Mohammed Shahabuddin urged all the Bangla-speaking people to be ever more mindful in its proper practice and in preserving its quality and dignity.
“Language is the foremost custodian and carrier of a nation’s existence, heritage, and culture . . . As Bangla was earned throug</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 12:26:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat chief to visit Shaheed Minar for the first time</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jamaat-chief-to-visit-shaheed-minar-for-the-first-time</link><description>Jamaat-e-Islami chief and Leader of the Opposition Shafiqur Rahman has announced his plan to visit the Central Shaheed Minar on International Mother Language Day, marking a first for the party chief.
While the party's student front Bangladesh Islami Chhatra Shibir has traditionally held rallies an</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 12:41:58 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>