<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 07:30:44 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Low-pressure area over Southeast Bay likely to intensify: BMD</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/low-pressure-area-over-southeast-bay-likely-to-intensify-bmd</link><description>A low-pressure area has formed over the Southeast Bay and adjoining regions, and it is likely to intensify, the Bangladesh Meteorological Department (BMD) said in its bulletin on Friday morning.
Rain or thundershowers are expected at one or two places over the Chattogram and Sylhet divisions.
Els</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 04:52:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rare dinosaur mummies help scientists recreate their prehistoric lives</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/rare-dinosaur-mummies-help-scientists-recreate-their-prehistoric-lives</link><description>Researchers have unearthed a spooky pair of dinosaur mummies that seem to have been preserved in an unexpected way.
These dinosaur remains are different from the wrapped mummies of Egypt or natural human mummies that get accidentally preserved in bogs or deserts. Mummified dinosaurs are so old tha</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 05:07:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Over 30 mln people in Sudan in need of humanitarian assistance: UN agencies</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/over-30-mln-people-in-sudan-in-need-of-humanitarian-assistance-un-agencies</link><description>Sudan is facing one of the world's most severe emergencies, with more than 30 million people in need of humanitarian assistance, including over 9.6 million internally displaced people and nearly 15 million children, four UN agencies said Thursday.
In a joint press release, the International Organi</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 05:38:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>WEEKLY KITCHEN MARKET: Edible oil, veggies get costlier; commoners' woes mount</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/weekly-kitchen-market-edible-oil-veggies-get-costlier-commoners-woes-mount</link><description>Prices of edible oil and vegetables went up again last week, adding to sufferings of the common consumers.
Vegetable prices continued to rise. Brinjal now sells for Tk120-200 per kg, bitter gourd for Tk 100-110, pointed gourd for Tk 100-110, okra for Tk 100-110, long yard beans for Tk 110-120, tea</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 05:53:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>INDUSTRIAL, FACTORY FIRES: 152 incidents claim 131 lives, injure 578 from 2018 to June 2025</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/industrial-factory-fires-152-incidents-claim-131-lives-injure-578-from-2018-to-june-2025</link><description>A total of 152 fire incidents happened in industries and factories from 2018 to June 2025 that claimed 131 lives and injured 578, revealed a latest research study of labour safety rights groups.
From 2022 to June 2025 a total of 13 incidents of chemical explosions took place at ready-made garments</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 06:08:55 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>