<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 20:21:14 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>No tourists on Day 2 in Saint Martin’s Island</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/no-tourists-on-day-2-in-saint-martins-island</link><description>For the second day of the tourist season, not a single visitor have travelled to Saint Martin’s Island, leaving local traders disheartened after being granted permission to operate for three months.
Although overnight stays are not allowed in November, small traders -- particularly restauran</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 16:59:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique urges unity for single BNP candidates</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-urges-unity-for-single-bnp-candidates</link><description>Tarique Rahman has urged BNP leaders to rally behind a single candidate in every constituency, cautioning that “covert autocracy still lurks in the shadows, driven by hidden ambitions”.
Speaking virtually from London on Sunday night at a party event, the acting BNP chairman also announ</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 16:56:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cyclones, rainfall, and morning fog likely in Nov</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cyclones-rainfall-and-morning-fog-likely-in-nov</link><description>Bangladesh may witness the formation of two to three low-pressure systems over the Bay of Bengal in November, with at least one potentially developing into a cyclone.
The Bangladesh Meteorological Department (BMD) in a long-term forecast on Sunday also indicated that fog could form in certain area</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 17:11:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Why upholding child rights is important for every country</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/why-upholding-child-rights-is-important-for-every-country</link><description>The conflicts taking place in different parts of the world- Gaza, Ukraine and many other countries in Africa, South Asia and South East Asia have raised once again the need for all countries to remember that the rights of children, if not observed, can create serious osmotic effects on the communit</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 17:41:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Lax enforcement of laws and security of life</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/lax-enforcement-of-laws-and-security-of-life</link><description>The Odhikar and the Manabadhikar Sangskriti Sangstha, two human rights organisations, in their latest reports have come up with alarming pictures of the lax law and order and worsening security of life in the country. While the number of extrajudicial killings stood at 40 in the last 14 months, the</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 17:56:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Is the world closer to the doomsday?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/is-the-world-closer-to-the-doomsday</link><description>As Trump directed his country's Department of War to what he said start testing their Nuclear Weapons on an equal basis in response to other countries' testing programmes, the world is going to enter the insanely competitive era of nuclear testing. Here, by other countries, he has evidently meant R</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 18:11:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fast-tracking land dispute resolution</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/fast-tracking-land-dispute-resolution</link><description>The Land Crime Prevention and Remedy Act, 2023 was enacted to expedite the resolution of land-related disputes outside the courtroom through an administrative process. However, its enforcement remains pending so far. It is heartening to know from a recent Financial Express report that the present g</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 18:26:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UN chief Guterres urges govts worldwide to ensure press freedom</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/un-chief-guterres-urges-govts-worldwide-to-ensure-press-freedom</link><description>United Nations Secretary-General António Guterres has called on governments across the world to ensure that journalists can carry out their work freely and safely everywhere.
In a statement marking the 11th International Day to End Impunity for Crimes against Journalists, he wrote media pro</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 19:40:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Probe finds glaring graft, bloated payouts to power plant owners</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/probe-finds-glaring-graft-bloated-payouts-to-power-plant-owners</link><description>Most private-sector power plants implemented during the previous Awami League government's tenure were steeped in blatant "corruption, fraud and irregularities" in the process of executing deals, investigators found.



A national committee formed after the fall of the past government in a stud</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 19:55:03 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>