<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 01:53:40 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>ICT orders notice in newspapers to summon Sajeeb Wazed Joy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ict-orders-notice-in-newspapers-to-summon-sajeeb-wazed-joy</link><description>The International Crimes Tribunal (ICT) on Wednesday ordered the publication of a notice in two national dailies to summon Sajeeb Wazed Joy, son of former Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina, in a case related to crimes against humanity during the July-August uprising in 2024.
A two-member judicial panel</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 15:45:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khaleda Zia responds to treatment, doctors optimistic about her progress</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/khaleda-zia-responds-to-treatment-doctors-optimistic-about-her-progress</link><description>BNP Chairperson Begum Khaleda Zia is responding to treatment at Evercare Hospital in the capital as she did in the past, according to her personal physician and BNP leader Dr AZM Zahid Hossain.
Addressing the media outside the hospital on Wednesday night, the BNP standing committee member said the</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 16:00:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Written exams for assistant teacher posts across eight divisions on Jan 2</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/written-exams-for-assistant-teacher-posts-across-eight-divisions-on-jan-2</link><description>Although the recruitment notifications were issued in two phases, the written examination for assistant teacher positions in government primary schools across all eight divisions will be held simultaneously on Jan 2.
Masud Akhtar Khan, additional secretary of the school division at the primary edu</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 16:30:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Secretariat staff call off sit-in after assurance of government order on allowance</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/secretariat-staff-call-off-sit-in-after-assurance-of-government-order-on-allowance</link><description>Employees have withdrawn their sit-in after receiving assurances that a government order (GO) will be issued to introduce a “Secretariat allowance”.
They ended their protest around 8:30pm on Wednesday, after blocking Finance Advisor Salehuddin Ahmed inside his office for six hours on t</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 16:45:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Comprehensive preparations underway to ensure free, fair polls: Home Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/comprehensive-preparations-underway-to-ensure-free-fair-polls-home-adviser</link><description>Home Affairs Adviser Lt. Gen. (Retd) Md. Jahangir Alam Chowdhury has said comprehensive preparations are in progress to ensure that the upcoming 13th National Parliamentary Election is conducted in a fair, peaceful and festive environment.
He made the remarks on Wednesday afternoon following a v</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 17:00:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How banks could facilitate everyone</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/how-banks-could-facilitate-everyone</link><description>When Rubel (pseudonym), a small supplier in Gazipur, went to a commercial bank last month to ask for a small loan, the credit officer shook his head. ''We aren't approving any new loan proposal until the bank manages its bad loans,'' the officer said. Rubel is not alone in this. Bangladesh's bankin</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 16:56:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pledges for increased use of renewable energy and Bangladesh reality</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/pledges-for-increased-use-of-renewable-energy-and-bangladesh-reality</link><description>This year's COP30 failed to reach a consensus on finalising roadmaps and timeframe to phase out fossil fuel. However, UN member countries have been submitting their own Nationally Determined Contributions (NDC) targets for reducing Greenhouse Gas (GHG) emission. Bangladesh has submitted its NDC rep</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 17:11:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Curbing use of black money in elections</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/curbing-use-of-black-money-in-elections</link><description>The concern expressed by leading economists over influence of money in politics, lack of good governance and its impact on economy portrays a grim picture of the country's political and economic landscape. This worry of the economists, which is also the worry of common citizens, was articulated on</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 17:26:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Interest rate and inflation to stay stubborn</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/interest-rate-and-inflation-to-stay-stubborn</link><description>At a time when fiscal discipline is crucial for the economy to stabilise, it is not easy to navigate the tortuous course of financial policy and action. The contractionary monetary policy with domestic high interests followed by the country certainly proves useful in containing inflation  for</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 17:41:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rescue efforts continue eight hours after 2-year old falls into Rajshahi borehole</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rescue-efforts-continue-eight-hours-after-2-year-old-falls-into-rajshahi-borehole</link><description>A desperate rescue is under way in Rajshahi’s Tanore Upazila, where a two-year-old boy has been trapped in a 35-foot-deep borehole for eight hours.
Firefighters are supplying oxygen in the hole to keep him alive, while excavators dig beside the narrow, 16-inch-wide hole in a race against tim</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 17:56:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat activist stabbed to death in Rajshahi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-activist-stabbed-to-death-in-rajshahi</link><description>A young member of the Jamaat-e-Islami-backed labour wing was hacked to death in Rajshahi city on Wednesday evening, police said.
The victim, Shanto, 26, son of Md Hasnat of Alimganj Purba Para, was a worker of the Kashiadanga thana unit of the Shramik Kalyan Federation, UNB reports. 
The att</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 18:11:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh's economic growth slows but inflation reined in</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladeshs-economic-growth-slows-but-inflation-reined-in</link><description>Bangladesh's economic growth may decelerate to 4.7 per cent in the current fiscal year but inflation gets bridled with tighter monetary-policy actions, shows a mixed picture portrayed by the Asian Development Bank.



The development financier, however, paints a better scenario of South Asia</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 19:13:13 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>