<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 14:49:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>100,000 health workers will be hired to improve healthcare: State minister</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/100000-health-workers-will-be-hired-to-improve-healthcare-state-minister</link><description>The government will soon recruit 100,000 health workers to improve the quality of healthcare across the country, State Minister for Health and Family Welfare MA Muhit has said.
During a visit to the Sirajganj 250-bed General Hospital on Thursday afternoon, he emphasised that the health sector has</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 12:45:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Poet Mohon Raihan selected, but not awarded</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/poet-mohon-raihan-selected-but-not-awarded</link><description>Without warning or explanation, the Bangla Academy has left poet Mohon Raihan empty-handed at the Amar Ekushey Book Fair, withholding the literature award for which he had been selected.
The poet left the ceremony bewildered, alleging that a decades-old poem about Colonel Taher had barred him from</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 13:00:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Iran promises flexibility at nuclear talks amid threat of US strikes</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/iran-promises-flexibility-at-nuclear-talks-amid-threat-of-us-strikes</link><description>Iran pledged to show flexibility at indirect talks with the United States on their longstanding nuclear dispute on Thursday, with Tehran under pressure to agree to a deal or face US military strikes.
The third round of talks in Geneva, which began on Thursday morning, will discuss Iran's nuclear p</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 13:15:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Finance minister declines to comment on Mansur’s departure from BB</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/finance-minister-declines-to-comment-on-mansurs-departure-from-bb</link><description>Finance Minister Amir Khosru Mahmud Chowdhury has declined to comment on the departure of economist Ahsan H Mansur from Bangladesh Bank, which was marked by protests and agitation.
Asked on Thursday whether the manner of the governor’s exit was “right”, the minister repeatedly sa</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 13:30:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Yunus likely to vacate Jamuna on Saturday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/yunus-likely-to-vacate-jamuna-on-saturday</link><description>The now-dissolved interim government’s chief adviser, Muhammad Yunus, is expected to vacate the State Guest House Jamuna on Saturday.
Public Works Department Chief Engineer Md Khalekuzzaman Chowdhury said the Jamuna would be vacated on Saturday afternoon, according to bdnews24.com.
After ta</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 12:47:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UCB opens new branch in Daganbhuiyan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ucb-opens-new-branch-in-daganbhuiyan</link><description>United Commercial Bank PLC (UCB), as part of its ongoing initiative to expand banking services across the country, has inaugurated a new branch in Daganbhuiyan, Feni.
According to a press release, the branch has been launched with the aim of delivering modern, fast, and reliable banking services t</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 13:02:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>405th board meeting of Shahjalal Islami Bank held</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/405th-board-meeting-of-shahjalal-islami-bank-held</link><description>The 405th meeting of the Board of Directors of Shahjalal Islami Bank PLC was held on Wednesday at the Corporate Head Office of the bank.
The meeting was presided over by Chairman Mr. Mohammed Younus. The board approved a number of investment proposals, according to a press release.
Among others t</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 13:17:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC revises referendum results, cuts both ‘Yes’ and ‘No’ votes</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-revises-referendum-results-cuts-both-yes-and-no-votes</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has brought a major revision to the results of the referendum held to implement the July National Charter (constitutional reform), reducing both ‘Yes’ and ‘No’ votes compared to the previously announced figures.
The revised information was publi</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 13:32:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pubali Bank holds 200th meeting of Executive Risk Management Committee</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/pubali-bank-holds-200th-meeting-of-executive-risk-management-committee</link><description>The 200th Meeting of the Executive Risk Management Committee (ERMC) of Pubali Bank PLC was held recently through a virtual platform, according to a press release.
Managing Director &amp; CEO Mohammad Ali attended the meeting as Chief Guest and Deputy Managing Directors- Ahmed Enayet Manzur, Md. Shahne</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 13:47:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>'LPG market monitoring to be intensified to ease consumers' hassle'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/lpg-market-monitoring-to-be-intensified-to-ease-consumers-hassle</link><description>Commerce Minister Khandaker Abdul Muktadir today (Thursday) said the government will strengthen Liquefied Petroleum Gas (LPG) market monitoring through local administrations to ensure that consumers do not face harassment and that no one can engage in market abuse at the retail level.
The minister</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 14:02:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Girl abducted, found dead after family seeks justice over rape</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/narsingdi-girl-15-abducted-found-dead-after-family-seeks-justice-over-rape</link><description>A 15-year-old girl was abducted from her father and later found dead in Narsingdi after her family sought justice over her rape, police, relatives and locals said.
Her body was found in a mustard field between Bilpar and Darikandi in Mahishashura Union of Sadar Upazila on Thursday, Prothom Alo rep</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 14:17:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NRBC Bank observes ‘Remittance Service Month’ during Holy Ramadan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/nrbc-bank-observes-remittance-service-month-during-holy-ramadan</link><description>NRBC Bank PLC is observing the holy month of Ramadan as a ‘Special Remittance Service Month’ to encourage expatriates to send remittances through formal banking channels and to further expand related services, according to a press release.
On this occasion, special gifts are being offe</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 14:32:56 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>