<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 10:24:44 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Bus catches fire after being hit by a motorcycle in southern India, killing at least 25</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/bus-catches-fire-after-being-hit-by-a-motorcycle-in-southern-india-killing-at-least-25</link><description>A passenger bus erupted into flames after a motorcycle crashed into it early Friday, killing at least 25 people and injuring several others in southern India, police said.
The fire tore through the bus within minutes, trapping dozens of passengers as it sped along a highway near Kurnool district i</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 08:26:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cyclone threat looms as fresh low forms over Bay of Bengal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cyclone-threat-looms-as-fresh-low-forms-over-bay-of-bengal</link><description>A low-pressure area has formed over the southeast Bay of Bengal, which may intensify into a depression before potentially developing into a cyclone, according to the Bangladesh Meteorological Department (BMD).
In a special weather bulletin issued on Friday, the Met Office advised fishing boats and</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 08:41:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UK businesses show tentative signs of a turnaround, PMI survey suggests</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/uk-businesses-show-tentative-signs-of-a-turnaround-pmi-survey-suggests</link><description>British businesses might be at a turning point with the manufacturing sector showing signs of a recovery and inflation pressures receding, but caution is still weighing on firms ahead of next month's government budget, a survey showed on Friday.
The preliminary UK Composite Purchasing Managers' In</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 09:11:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India won't rush into trade deals, rejects restrictive conditions: trade min</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/india-wont-rush-into-trade-deals-rejects-restrictive-conditions-trade-minister-says</link><description>India will not rush into signing any trade agreements and will reject conditions from partner countries that restrict its trading choices, Trade Minister Piyush Goyal said on Friday.
The country is negotiating a long-pending free trade agreement with the European Union, with differences remaining</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 09:41:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hobbled by US tariffs, carpet weavers in India's Kashmir struggle to stay afloat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/hobbled-by-us-tariffs-carpet-weavers-in-indias-kashmir-struggle-to-stay-afloat</link><description>Gulzar Ahmad Bhat, a former carpet weaver in India's Jammu and Kashmir region, now sells tea on the shores of the scenic Dal Lake, abandoning his craft of 35 years after increased US tariffs left him unable to afford his children's school fees and medicine for his family of six.
Thousands of India</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 09:56:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump says talks with Canada off after ad invokes Reagan as free-trader</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-says-talks-with-canada-off-after-ad-invokes-reagan-as-free-trader</link><description>US President Donald Trump said on Thursday trade talks with Canada were terminated after a Canadian political advertisement used the recorded voice of late president Ronald Reagan saying tariffs cause trade wars and economic disaster.
Trump, who imposed import tariffs on Canadian steel, aluminum a</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 10:11:53 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>