<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 08:36:47 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>No government can guarantee zero violence: Press Secretary</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/no-government-can-guarantee-zero-violence-press-secretary</link><description>Chief Adviser’s Press Secretary Shafiqul Alam on Sunday said that no government can guarantee there will be no attempts at violence, particularly when influential actors are actively calling for disruption.
"But the conditions today are not the same as before. Security forces are under close</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 05:26:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Man killed in Dinajpur road crash</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/man-killed-in-dinajpur-road-crash289</link><description>A 40-year-old man was killed and another person injured when a covered van hit a stationary truck from behind on Dinajpur-Gobindaganj regional highway in Ghoraghat upazila of Dinajpur district on Sunday.
The deceased was identified as Al Amin, 40, a helper of a covered van, reports UNB.
The accid</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 05:41:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Australia Virtual Education Expo 2026 to connect Bangladeshi students with leading universities</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/article/australia-virtual-education-expo-2026-to-connect-bangladeshi-students-with-leading-universities</link><description>Eduko Pathways Bangladesh is going to organise the Australia Virtual Education Expo 2026 on February 10, 2026 (Tuesday) providing Bangladeshi students with unprecedented access to representatives from more than 45 Australian universities through a comprehensive virtual platform.
The Zoom-based exp</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 05:56:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NSU concludes 10th National Career Fair with record industry participation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/article/nsu-concludes-10th-national-career-fair-with-record-industry-participation</link><description>The Career and Placement Centre (CPC) of North South University (NSU) successfully concluded the 10th National Career Fair (NCF) 2026 with a formal closing ceremony held at NSU Plaza recently. The three-day flagship event brought together leading employers, industry professionals, students, and gra</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 06:11:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>From roots to wings</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/article/from-roots-to-wings</link><description>At some point in their academic journey, most students confront a quiet but persistent question: Am I prepared? It often surfaces in moments of comparison, during late nights filled with uncertainty, or when the future feels too distant and undefined. In today's fast-changing world where competitio</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 06:26:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Japan's Takaichi aims for blizzard of votes in rare winter election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/japans-takaichi-aims-for-blizzard-of-votes-in-rare-winter-election</link><description>Japanese voters trudged through snow on Sunday to cast their ballots in an election predicted to hand Prime Minister Sanae Takaichi a resounding win, though record dumps in some parts of the country snarled traffic and could dent turnout.
The conservative coalition of Takaichi, the nation's first</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 06:41:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How a single project can reshape a region</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/analysis/how-a-single-project-can-reshape-a-region</link><description>As a development analyst, I have spent much of my career studying how large infrastructure projects alter regional economies. Too often, such projects promise transformation but leave behind only partial gains. Rooppur, however, tells a different story. What is unfolding in this quiet corner of Pab</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 06:56:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Washington Post publisher announces departure, following mass layoffs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/washington-post-publisher-will-lewis-announces-departure-following-mass-layoffs</link><description>Washington Post publisher and CEO Will Lewis is leaving the newspaper, it announced on Saturday after carrying out widespread layoffs this week.
"During my tenure, difficult decisions have been taken in order to ensure the sustainable future of The Post so it can for many years ahead publish high-</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 07:11:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Election campaign ends on Tuesday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/election-campaign-ends-on-tuesday</link><description>Electioneering by contesting candidates in the 13th National Parliament Election and Referendum, scheduled for February 12, will conclude at 7:30 am on Tuesday, exactly 48 hours before voting begins.
The campaign, which started on January 22, will end in line with electoral rules requiring all pol</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 07:26:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>4 organisations write open letter to CA to keep Ctg Port operational</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/4-organisations-write-open-letter-to-ca-to-keep-ctg-port-operational</link><description>Four export-oriented trade bodies -- the Bangladesh Garment Manufacturers and Exporters Association (BGMEA), Bangladesh Knitwear Manufacturers and Exporters Association (BKMEA), Bangladesh Employers’ Federation (BEF), and Bangladesh Textile Mills Association (BTMA) -- have written an open let</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 07:41:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh, Japan sign MoU to boost environmental cooperation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-japan-sign-mou-to-boost-environmental-cooperation</link><description>Bangladesh and Japan have signed a Memorandum of Understanding to strengthen bilateral cooperation on environmental protection and sustainable development.
The MoU was signed in Tokyo on Friday between Bangladesh’s Ministry of Environment, Forest and Climate Change and Japan’s Ministry</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 07:56:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ctg Port remains operational despite strike, chairman says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ctg-port-remains-operational-despite-strike-chairman-says</link><description>SM Moniruzzaman, chairman of the Chittagong Port Authority, has said operations at the country's main port remain normal despite an ongoing strike by workers and employees.
He made the remarks at a media briefing outside the port building on Sunday, about an hour after it had originally been sched</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 08:11:34 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>