<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 06:34:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Germany reaffirms support for Bangladesh in resolving Rohingya crisis</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/germany-reaffirms-support-for-bangladesh-in-resolving-rohingya-crisis</link><description>Parliamentary State Secretary to the German Federal Ministry for Economic Cooperation and Development (BMZ) and Member of German Bundestag, Johann Saathoff, has said Germany remains firmly committed to supporting Bangladesh and the international community in seeking durable solutions for the Rohing</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 03:34:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gaza ceasefire holds: Trump</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/gaza-ceasefire-holds-trump</link><description>US President Donald Trump said on Wednesday that a US-backed ceasefire in Gaza was not at risk after local authorities reported that 26 people had been killed in Israeli strikes, as Israel and Hamas traded accusations of blame for the violence.
Israeli planes launched strikes in Gaza on Tuesday af</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 03:49:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Blanket market heats up in Rajshahi as winter nears</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/blanket-market-heats-up-in-rajshahi-as-winter-nears</link><description>The blanket market in Rajshahi is already warming up, with the winter getting very close.
Retailers report brisk sales and notably fair prices compared to last year, as early-season demand meets increased wholesale costs.
From New Market to Ranibazar, the makeshift roadside stalls are selling a w</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 04:19:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Aman farmers of Rangpur agri region, Gopalganj see bumper production</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/aman-farmers-of-rangpur-agri-region-gopalganj-see-bumper-production</link><description>Farmers of five districts of the Rangpur agriculture region and Gopalganj district are optimistic about achieving a good yield of Aman paddy this season, as cultivation of the crop has increased remarkably in the last ten years.
Our correspondent from Rangpur reports that, currently, the Aman padd</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 04:34:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Each $1.0 investment can save $14 in health, social costs’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/each-10-investment-can-save-14-in-health-social-costs</link><description>Every US$1.0 investment in family planning can save $14 in health and social costs, prevent 30 per cent of maternal deaths, and reduce two-thirds of unintended pregnancies in the country, according to the National Family Planning Strategy for 2025-2030, launched on Tuesday.
The strategy addresses</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 04:49:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>One dies as Cyclone Montha lashes India's east coast</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/one-dies-as-cyclone-montha-lashes-indias-east-coast</link><description>One person was killed on India's eastern coast after Cyclone Montha made landfall around midnight, with heavy rain and gusty winds also damaging crops and utility poles, officials said on Wednesday.
India's weather department has forecast extremely heavy rain on Wednesday for the coastal states of</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 05:04:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How a residential area turns into a place of urban gathering</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/how-a-residential-area-turns-into-a-place-of-urban-gathering</link><description>Dhanmondi is one of the prominent residential and commercial areas in Dhaka city. Art, culture, food, fashion, education, and medical treatment are all factors nourished in this area. There are some popular areas where people like to roam with family and friends.
This place becomes more crowded in</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 05:19:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How to resist the lure of discounts, ‘new arrivals’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/how-to-resist-the-lure-of-discounts-new-arrivals</link><description>"It's been only ten days, and I have only a little money left in my pocket."
Many of us have faced the situation where we spend so much in the first half of the month that there's barely anything left for the second half.
In this world of endless online sales, constant "new arrivals," and irresis</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 05:34:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nvidia will build AI supercomputers for US Energy Department</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/nvidia-will-build-ai-supercomputers-for-us-energy-department</link><description>Nvidia CEO Jensen Huang came to Washington on Tuesday with a message for the Trump administration: the US can win the AI battle if the world, including China's massive developer base, runs on Nvidia systems.
In his address at the first Nvidia developers' conference held in Washington, Huang walked</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 06:04:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rain, thundershowers likely over Rangpur, Rajshahi, Khulna</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rain-thundershowers-likely-over-rangpur-rajshahi-khulna</link><description>The Bangladesh Meteorological Department (BMD) forecast that rain or thundershowers is likely to occur at many places over Rangpur, Rajshahi and Khulna divisions, beginning at 9:00 am today.
"Light to moderate rain or thundershowers is likely to occur at many places over Rangpur, Rajshahi and Khul</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 06:19:52 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>