<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 19:17:47 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Pakistan's first female central bank head Shamshad Akhtar dies</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/pakistans-first-female-central-bank-head-shamshad-akhtar-dies</link><description>Shamshad Akhtar, the first and only woman to lead Pakistan's central bank and a two-time caretaker finance minister, died at 71, the finance ministry said on Saturday.
Akhtar was serving as chairperson of the Pakistan Stock Exchange at the time of her death, giving her a rare role spanning Pakista</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 16:10:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>30 NCP leaders urge Nahid Islam not to form alliance with Jamaat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/30-ncp-leaders-urge-nahid-islam-not-to-form-alliance-with-jamaat</link><description>Thirty leaders of the National Citizens Party (NCP) have written to party convener Nahid Islam, urging him not to form any political alliance with Jamaat-e-Islami, citing the party’s controversial historical role and recent divisive activities.
The memorandum, delivered on Saturday, expresse</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 16:25:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Protests continue over justice for Hadi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/protests-continue-over-justice-for-hadi</link><description>Protests demanding justice for Shaheed Sharif Osman bin Hadi, spokesperson of Inqilab Moncho, continued for the second consecutive day at Shahbagh in the capital on Saturday.
Protesters, including women and children, joined the demonstration and chanted various slogans.
As of 8:30 pm, demonstrato</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 16:40:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BSF halts fence construction at Joypurhat border after BGB intervention</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bsf-halts-fence-construction-at-joypurhat-border-after-bgb-intervention</link><description>Indian Border Security Force (BSF) attempted to construct a barbed wire fence at the Ghonapara border in Panchbibi upazila of Joypurhat on Saturday morning, violating international border regulations, but were forced to stop after intervention by Border Guard Bangladesh (BGB).
Early Saturday morni</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 16:55:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique visits Evercare again to see ailing mother</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-visits-evercare-again-to-see-ailing-mother</link><description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman visited Evercare Hospital in the capital on Saturday night to see his ailing mother and former Prime Minister Begum Khaleda Zia.
Tarique arrived at the hospital around 9:40pm, BNP media cell member Sayrul Kabir Khan said.
This was the second time Tarique visited</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 17:10:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Miraz’s Sylhet Titans pip Noakhali Express in last-ball BPL drama</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/mirazs-sylhet-titans-pip-noakhali-express-in-last-ball-bpl-drama</link><description>Sylhet Titans edged past Noakhali Express in a thrilling match that went down to the very last ball in the Bangladesh Premier League (BPL).
Mehidy Hasan Miraz’s side secured a one-wicket victory in their backyard, surpassing Noakhali’s 143 with a leg bye on the final delivery on Saturd</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 16:41:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Industry first in gas supply to fuel economic growth</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/industry-first-in-gas-supply-to-fuel-economic-growth</link><description>Industrial consumers will get top priority in gas supply as the government prepares such a fuel-feeding recipe aimed at fuelling economic growth, now largely subdued following political upheavals, sources say.
"Industry will be on top of our priority and we want that the industrial consumers will</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 16:56:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The political economy of nation-building</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/the-political-economy-of-nation-building</link><description>A  textbook definition of  the well-worn word ‘nation’ may denote ‘a group of people who share a common identity  based on shared history, culture, tradition, custom, religion, language and a sense of unity or belonging together. Here, ‘nation’ is mostly</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 17:11:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Alarming rise in suicides</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/alarming-rise-in-suicides</link><description>The revelation that an average of around 40 people die by suicide every day in Bangladesh is a chilling indicator of a profound and largely unaddressed social crisis.  Police records on unnatural deaths show that between 2020 and 2024, a total of 73,597 suicide cases were recorded. That means</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 17:26:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BD-India trade in travel services</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/bd-india-trade-in-travel-services</link><description>December is usually a month of holiday-making for most people in Bangladesh.  A large number of people wait throughout the year for the month when they can travel home and abroad with their families and friends. For most outbound tourists from Bangladesh, neighbouring India is the first destin</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 17:41:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ensuring expeditions commercial justice</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/ensuring-expeditions-commercial-justice</link><description>Amid a series of new laws and initiatives introduced recently by the interim government to ease public suffering and speed up the delivery of justice, the proposed Commercial Courts Ordinance 2025 stands out as a potentially transformative measure. It comes at a time when the country's judiciary is</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 17:56:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique thanks nation for warm welcome</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-thanks-nation-for-warm-welcome</link><description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman on Saturday expressed gratitude to the people of Bangladesh for their warm reception following his return to the country after 17 years abroad.
In a message posted on his verified Facebook page, he said, “Dear friends, sisters, and brothers across Banglades</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 18:11:46 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>