<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 15:56:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Jamaat Ameer calls for peaceful counting, says nation won’t accept ‘New Fascism’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jamaat-ameer-calls-for-peaceful-counting-says-nation-wont-accept-new-fascism</link><description>Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami Ameer Dr. Shafiqur Rahman on Thursday said that any disorder during vote counting would not reflect the people’s aspirations, saying reports from across the country suggest that citizens would not welcome any ‘new fascism.’
“The nation had regaine</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 12:40:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hasnat's opponent Jasim boycotts election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/hasnats-opponent-jasim-boycotts-election</link><description>Jasim Uddin, the BNP-backed and Gono Odhikar Parishad candidate, on Thursday announced a boycott of voting in the Cumilla-4 (Debidwar) constituency.
His main rival in the seat is Hasnat Abdullah, chief organiser of the National Citizen Party (NCP). 
Speaking on Facebook Live in the afternoon</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 12:55:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Saudi Arabia appoints new investment minister, according to Royal decree</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/saudi-arabia-appoints-new-investment-minister-according-to-royal-decree</link><description>Saudi Arabia appointed Fahd bin Abduljalil bin Ali al Saif as the new investment minister, replacing Khalid Al-Falih, according to a royal decree on Thursday.</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 12:41:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two jailed for attempting to cast fake votes</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/two-jailed-for-attempting-to-cast-fake-votes</link><description>Two individuals have been sentenced to two years in jail each after attempting to cast fraudulent votes in the Sirajganj-4 and Jhalakhati-2 constituencies.
The incident in Sirajganj took place on Thursday at a polling station in Ullapara.
Md Sanu Akand, head of the constituency’s election i</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 12:56:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Festive atmosphere beyond anyone’s imagination: Mirza Fakhrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/festive-atmosphere-beyond-anyones-imagination-mirza-fakhrul</link><description>BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir on Thursday said the country is set to have an elected government and parliament through the ongoing national election.
“None had imagined the voting would be so festive. The enthusiasm and interest of the people are remarkable. I have visite</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 13:11:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP thanks authorities, urges vigilance until final results announced</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bnp-thanks-authorities-urges-vigilance-until-final-results-announced</link><description>Claiming that its victory is inevitable, the BNP on Thursday urged party leaders and activists to remain vigilant until the final election results are announced.
Speaking at a press conference, BNP’s Election Steering Committee spokesperson Dr Mahdi Amin also thanked the government, administ</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 13:26:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Viral video shows 5 men stamping ballots at Mymensingh polling station</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/viral-video-shows-5-men-stamping-ballots-at-mymensingh-polling-station</link><description>A group of men has stormed a polling booth in Mymensingh-11 and stamped ballot papers, with video of the breach circulating widely on social media.
The incident unfolded at Lohaboi Baradi Government Primary School in Bhaluka's Meduari Union around 2:30pm on Thursday, according to Upazila administr</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 13:41:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chattogram turnout thins in final hours</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/chattogram-sees-midday-surge-fade-into-afternoon-slump</link><description>Voter presence in Chattogram dropped sharply in the final hours of the national election and state reform referendum on Thursday, despite a significant surge during the morning and midday periods.
Visits to at least eight centres across four constituencies revealed near‑empty premises in the final</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 13:56:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Russia fully blocks WhatsApp, talks up state-backed alternative</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/russia-fully-blocks-whatsapp-talks-up-state-backed-alternative</link><description>US messenger app WhatsApp, owned by Meta Platforms, has been completely blocked in Russia for failing to comply with local law, the Kremlin said on Thursday, suggesting Russians turn to a state-backed “national messenger” instead.
“Due to Meta’s unwillingness to comply with</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 14:11:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>North Korea’s Kim positioning daughter as successor</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/north-koreas-kim-positioning-daughter-as-successor</link><description>North Korean leader Kim Jong Un appears to be taking steps to consolidate his daughter's position as successor, and there are signs she is providing input on policy matters, South Korean lawmakers said on Thursday, citing a spy agency briefing.
South Korea's National Intelligence Agency (NIS) will</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 14:26:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Child drowns as mother goes to vote in Chuadanga</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/child-drowns-as-mother-goes-to-vote-in-chuadanga</link><description>A child has drowned in Chuadanga’s Alamdanga Upazila as his mother was at the polling centre to cast her ballot.
The incident occurred around 10:30am in Kharad village in the Upazila, said Alamdanga Police chief Bani Israel.
The child -– three-year-old Hasan -– was the son of vi</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 14:41:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh Polls: Vote counting underway; early results show who’re leading</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-polls-vote-counting-underway-early-results-show-whore-leading</link><description>Preliminary results from 12 out of 185 polling stations in Thakurgaon-1 (Sadar) constituency show BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir leading.
He has secured 12536 votes so far. His nearest rival, Jamaat’s candidate Delwar Hossain, has received 9,359 votes.
Counting is underwa</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 14:56:32 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>