<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 12:56:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>CA orders recovery of ‘looted weapons’ before election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ca-orders-quick-recovery-of-looted-weapons-ahead-of-election</link><description>Chief Advisor Muhammad Yunus has directed authorities to quickly recover illegal firearms and weapons looted from police stations ahead of the 13th general election.
He issued the directive at a meeting of the National Implementation Committee on Administrative Reorganisation (NICAR) at the State</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 10:37:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump shares Macron message offering G7 summit, questioning Greenland tactics</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-shares-macron-message-offering-g7-summit-questioning-greenland-tactics</link><description>French President Emmanuel Macron told Donald Trump he did not understand what the U.S. President was “doing on Greenland,” and offered to host a G7 meeting inviting Russia and others, according to a screenshot of the messages Trump posted online.
In the messages, Macron told Trump he c</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 10:10:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Greece will cooperate with Israel on anti-drone systems, cybersecurity, Greek minister says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/greece-will-cooperate-with-israel-on-anti-drone-systems-cybersecurity-greek-minister-says</link><description>Greece will cooperate with Israel on anti-drone systems and cybersecurity, Greek Defence Minister Nikos Dendias said on Tuesday after meeting his Israeli counterpart in Athens.
With strong economic and diplomatic ties, Greece and Israel operate an air training center on Greek territory and have he</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 10:25:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Russia's Lavrov says Greenland is not a 'natural part' of Denmark</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/russias-lavrov-says-greenland-is-not-a-natural-part-of-denmark</link><description>Russian Foreign Minister Sergei Lavrov said on Tuesday that Greenland was not "a natural ​part" of Denmark and that the problem of ‌former colonial territories was becoming more acute.
U.S. President Donald Trump has said ‌he wants full U.S. control of Greenland, an autonomous territory</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 10:40:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Kazi Food Industries Limited holds Annual Business Conference 2026</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/kazi-food-industries-limited-holds-annual-business-conference-2026</link><description>Leading food manufacturing company Kazi Food Industries Limited organized a two-day “Annual Business Conference 2026” at Seagull Hotel, Cox’s Bazar, on January 14–15.
This year, the theme of the conference was “Innovate.Elevate.Dominate,” according to a media re</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 10:55:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fishermen’s bodies found 10 days after Meghna boat capsize</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fishermens-bodies-found-10-days-after-meghna-boat-capsize</link><description>Police have recovered the bodies of three fishermen 10 days after an engine-powered fishing boat capsized in the Meghna River.
River Police Inspector Gautam Chandra Mandal confirmed the recoveries of the bodies in Barishal’s Hizla and Mehendiganj on Tuesday morning.
The dead were identified</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 11:10:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Holy Ramadan set to begin Feb 19</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/holy-ramadan-set-to-begin-feb-19</link><description>The holy month of Ramadan is expected to begin on February 19, according to the Islamic Foundation.
The Islamic Foundation released the timings of Sehri, the meal consumed early in the morning by Muslims before fasting and iftar, the meal eaten after sunset during Ramadan on Tuesday.

The image</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 11:25:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bengal Islami Life Insurance celebrates the milestone of achieving BDT 100 crore in premium collection</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bengal-islami-life-insurance-celebrates-the-milestone-of-achieving-bdt-100-crore-in-premium-collection</link><description>Bengal Islami Life Insurance Limited has achieved the historic milestone of collecting BDT 100 crore in premiums in 2025.
To mark this achievement, a colorful celebration ceremony was held on Saturday (18 January 2026) at the TCB Auditorium in Karwan Bazar, Dhaka, presided over by the company&amp;rsqu</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 11:40:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Blast kills seven at Chinese-run restaurant in Afghan capital</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/blast-kills-seven-at-chinese-run-restaurant-in-afghan-capital</link><description>Militant group Islamic State claimed an explosion that officials said killed a Chinese national and six Afghans, while injuring several more as it tore through a Chinese-run restaurant in a heavily guarded part of Afghanistan's capital.
Monday's blast took place in the commercial Shahr-e-Naw area</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 11:55:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sylhet knock out former champions Rangpur from BPL</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/cricket/sylhet-knock-out-former-champions-rangpur-from-bpl</link><description>In a heart-stopping finish at the Sher-e-Bangla National Stadium, Chris Woakes struck a massive six off the final ball to guide the Sylhet Titans to an incredible victory over the Rangpur Riders in the BPL Eliminator on Tuesday.
The breath-taking win keeps Sylhet's title hopes alive, propelling th</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 12:10:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Toyota Bangladesh Limited &amp; BIDA hold meeting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/toyota-bangladesh-limited-bida-hold-meeting</link><description>The management of Toyota Bangladesh Limited (TBL), a 100% subsidiary of Toyota Tsusho Asia Pacific and Toyota Tsusho Japan, recently met with Ashik Chowdhury, Chairman of the Bangladesh Investment Development Authority (BIDA), to discuss the sustainable future of the automotive industry in Banglade</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 12:25:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt approves sweeping administrative reforms</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-approves-sweeping-administrative-reforms</link><description>The interim government has approved a wide-ranging set of administrative reforms aimed at improving transparency, efficiency and accountability across key state institutions, as preparations intensify for the next national election.
At the meeting of the National Implementation Committee on Admini</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 12:40:02 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>