<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 03:13:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>President Parade (Winter)-2025 held at BAF Academy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/president-parade-winter-2025-held-at-baf-academy</link><description>The President Parade (Winter)-2025, marking the commissioning of No 87 BAFA (Bangladesh Air Force Academy) Course, Direct Entry-2025B and SPSSC-2025B of Bangladesh Air Force, was held at BAF Academy in Jashore on Thursday.
Chief of Air Staff Air Chief Marshal Hasan Mahmood Khan attended the ceremo</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 17:15:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Six tycoons shortlisted for siphoned-off asset recovery rapidly</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/six-tycoons-shortlisted-for-siphoned-off-asset-recovery-rapidly</link><description>The Bangladesh Bank has shortlisted six tycoons and decided to speed up probe and disposal of cases against them over the laundered money siphoned off to several countries.
Investigators name the suspect conglomerates like NASSA, Beximco, Saifuzzaman, Sikder Group, S. Alam and Orion.
On Wednesday</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 17:30:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Next frontier of Bangladesh's export diversification</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/next-frontier-of-bangladeshs-export-diversification</link><description>There are always points in the economic development of countries where the roadmap for the future becomes distinctly visible once the driving engine, which for so long propelled success to dizzying heights, is no longer commensurate with ambitions born out of success. Bangladesh has finally reached</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 17:45:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A journalist's journey through history and the craft</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/reviews/a-journalists-journey-through-history-and-the-craft</link><description>Journalism is not only a profession; it demands passion, devotion and commitment. It also comes with the responsibility to serve readers, viewers and listeners with unbiased information and perspectives they need to make important decisions in everyday life.
Aspiring journalists may wonder how the</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 18:00:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tremors shake the nation, but not its conscience</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/tremors-shake-the-nation-but-not-its-conscience</link><description>Much has been written, discussed about and warned against the vulnerability of Dhaka to major earthquakes. Yet very little has changed in the way buildings are constructed here. Seismologists, who claim that Bangladesh sits on active fault lines, have long been warning that a strong earthquake coul</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 18:31:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Addressing biting poverty and moribund economy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/addressing-biting-poverty-and-moribund-economy</link><description>When about 2.0 million people of a country fall below the poverty line in a year, it certainly points to that country's economic malaise. But if this follows the previous year's more than three million people's plunge into poverty with no projection of a turnaround in sight, the nation has reasons</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 18:46:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fighting the complex web of poverty</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/fighting-the-complex-web-of-poverty</link><description>Bangladesh, long celebrated as a global success story in poverty reduction, now confronts one of its most daunting challenges in nearly a decade. A new World Bank assessment warns that as many as 62 million Bangladeshis are at risk of sliding back into poverty. The WB, through its projection that p</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 19:01:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Blame-ridden RAJUK up for overhaul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/blame-ridden-rajuk-up-for-overhaul</link><description>Blame-ridden RAJUK is now up for restructuring as the interim government's cabinet endorses an ordinance for a sweeping overhaul of the capital-development authority, amidst latest spell of criticisms about building construction following a moderate earthquake.
The Council of Advisers in its meeti</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 01:21:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Condemned convict Hasina gets 21 years in prison</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/condemned-convict-hasina-gets-21-years-in-prison</link><description>Deposed Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina, already carrying death sentence, is now sentenced to 21 years' imprisonment in three corruption cases over alleged abuse of power in acquiring plots at RAJUK's Purbachal New Town Project.
Her daughter Saima Wazed Putul and son Sajeeb Wazed Joy are each sentenc</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 01:36:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>High interest, weak investment to blame: Experts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/high-interest-weak-investment-to-blame-experts</link><description>Bangladesh's economy is trapped in a difficult-to-break vicious cycle of high interest rates, persistent inflation, weak investment, and slowing gross domestic product (GDP) growth, making it increasingly challenging to revive private-sector activities, experts say.
They note that the financial se</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 01:51:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Long-awaited 700 MHz spectrum auction on Jan 14</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/long-awaited-700-mhz-spectrum-auction-on-jan-14</link><description>The government has fixed January 14 next year for the auction of the long-awaited 700 MHz spectrum, signalling a decisive move towards releasing a band that has been locked in legal and regulatory disputes for nearly two decades.
The date was formally announced in the Instructions for Radio Freque</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 02:06:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Central bank to rationalise pay as Islamic banks merge</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/central-bank-to-rationalise-pay-as-islamic-banks-merge</link><description>Bangladesh Bank (BB) plans to rationalise the salary structures of employees at the five struggling Islamic banks set for merger, as part of efforts to reduce their administrative costs.
Speaking to reporters, BB assistant spokesperson Mohammad Shahriar Siddiqui said the five banks will be consoli</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 02:21:49 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>