<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 13:29:32 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>NBR chairman hints at further extension for online return submission</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/nbr-chairman-hints-at-further-extension-for-online-return-submission</link><description>National Board of Revenue (NBR) Chairman Abdur Rahman Khan has hinted at a possible further extension of the deadline for online income tax return submission, as a significant number of registered taxpayers are yet to file their returns digitally.
Indicating the possibility of an extension, he sai</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 12:02:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US intelligence indicates Putin's war aims in Ukraine are unchanged</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-intelligence-indicates-putins-war-aims-in-ukraine-are-unchanged</link><description>US intelligence reports continue to warn that Russian President Vladimir Putin has not abandoned his aims of capturing all of Ukraine and reclaiming parts of Europe that belonged to the former Soviet empire, six sources familiar with US intelligence said, even as negotiators seek an end to the war</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 10:59:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fog blankets parts of Bangladesh, colder days ahead</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fog-blankets-parts-of-bangladesh-colder-days-ahead</link><description>Fog has enveloped parts of the country, including the capital Dhaka, with the Bangladesh Meteorological Department (BMD) forecasting that the condition will persist for several more days, particularly in the northern and western regions.
Meteorologist Md Toriful Newaz Kabir told bdnews24.com on Su</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 11:14:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump set to expand immigration crackdown in 2026 amid backlash</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/trump-set-to-expand-immigration-crackdown-in-2026-despite-brewing-backlash</link><description>US President Donald Trump is preparing for a more aggressive immigration crackdown in 2026 with billions in new funding, including by raiding more workplaces — even as backlash builds ahead of next year’s midterm elections.
Trump has already surged immigration agents into major US citi</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 11:29:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka visit ends ‘in pain’ for Shiraz Ali Khan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/entertainment/shiraz-ali-khan-leaves-dhaka-in-anguish-vows-not-to-return-until-culture-is-safe</link><description>Renowned classical musician Shiraz Ali Khan, a great-grandson of Ustad Alauddin Khan, has announced that he will not return to Bangladesh until artists, music and cultural institutions are “respected and protected”.
In a Facebook post on Sunday, he wrote the decision was not born of an</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 11:44:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Swiss interior minister open to social media ban for children</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/swiss-interior-minister-open-to-social-media-ban-for-children</link><description>Switzerland must do more to shield children from social media risks, Interior Minister Elisabeth Baume-Schneider was quoted as saying on Sunday, signalling she was open to a potential ban on the platforms for youngsters.
Following Australia's recent ban on social media for under-16s, Baume-Schneid</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 11:59:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Republican critics fear incomplete disclosure of Epstein files will loom over midterms</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/republican-critics-fear-incomplete-disclosure-of-epstein-files-will-loom-over-midterms</link><description>Extensive redactions and the limited number of documents released related to convicted sex offender Jeffrey Epstein angered some Republicans and did little to defuse a scandal threatening the party ahead of 2026 midterm elections.
The Trump administration touted this week's release of a cache of E</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 12:14:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BB slashes provisioning rates to boost agri, CMSME lending</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/bb-slashes-provisioning-rates-to-boost-agri-cmsme-lending</link><description>In a strategic move to stimulate credit flow to vital sectors of the economy, Bangladesh Bank (BB) has announced a significant reduction in provisioning requirements for short-term agricultural and small-scale enterprise credits.
According to a directive issued on Sunday, the central bank has deci</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 12:29:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Walton wins 'Best Brand Award-2025' in three categories</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/walton-wins-best-brand-award-2025-in-three-categories</link><description>Bangladesh’s capital market-listed tech giant Walton secured three best brand recognitions again this year. It received the ‘Best Brand Award-2025’ in three categories- refrigerator, air conditioner and television.
Walton Refrigerator secured this prestigious award for the last 1</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 12:44:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC assures stability, signals crackdown on disruptions</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/election-commission-says-law-and-order-stable-vows-tough-actions-against-disruptions</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has said the overall law and order situation remains under control, while warning of strict action against anyone seeking to disrupt the electoral process.
On Sunday, the constitutional body responsible for organising the parliamentary election said efforts were under</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 12:59:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Travel ban imposed on main suspect Faisal in Hadi murder case</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/travel-ban-imposed-on-main-suspect-faisal-in-hadi-murder-case</link><description>A court in Dhaka on Sunday imposed travel ban on Faisal Karim Masud, main suspect in the grisly murder of Inqilab Mancha spokesperson Shaheed Sharif Osman Hadi.
Additional Chief Metropolitan Magistrate Awlad Hossain Mohammad Zunaid passed the order upon a petition of the investigation officer (IO)</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 13:14:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BRAC University holds 2nd International Case Conference on Business and Management 2025</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/brac-university-holds-2nd-international-case-conference-on-business-and-management-2025</link><description>BRAC University hosted the 2nd International Case Conference on Business and Management (ICCBM 2025) on the Merul Badda campus in Dhaka recently on the theme “AI Innovation and Sustainability: Rethinking Enterprise, Practice and Leadership in the Global South”.
The case conference is a</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 13:29:32 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>