<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 12:51:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Level playing field exists in Bangladesh: Press Secretary</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/complete-level-playing-field-exists-in-bangladesh-election-process-press-secretary</link><description>Chief Adviser’s Press Secretary Shafiqul Alam on Friday said a complete level playing field exists in the country’s ongoing election process, asserting that the overall environment remains favourable.
“We believe there is a completely level playing field in the election. The envi</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 11:15:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gas pressure falls in Dhaka as Titas pipeline damaged</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/gas-pressure-falls-in-dhaka-after-damage-to-titas-pipeline-at-bottom-of-turag-river</link><description>Gas pressure in Dhaka has gotten “extremely low” after a cargo trawler’s anchor damaged a gas distribution pipeline under the Turag River in the capital’s Aminbazar area, according to Titas Gas Transmission and Distribution PLC.
In a press release published on its Facebook</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 11:30:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Media’s role crucial in preventing rumors &amp; misinformation: Information Secretary</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/medias-role-crucial-in-preventing-rumors-and-misinformation-information-secretary</link><description>Information and Broadcasting Secretary Mahbuba Farzana has called on media journalists to support the ongoing nationwide awareness campaign aimed at educating voters about the referendum. She also urged journalists to assist in countering rumors and misinformation surrounding the election process.</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 10:29:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Flower Festival kicks off in Chattogram DC Park</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/flower-festival-kicks-off-in-chattogram-dc-park</link><description>The month-long Chattogram Flower Festival–2026 kicked off on Friday at DC Park in Sitakunda upazila, transforming the area into a vibrant floral kingdom.
Senior Secretary of the Ministry of Public Administration Md Ehsanul Haque inaugurated the festival, marking the fourth edition of the eve</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 10:44:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>With tension high in Minnesota, border agent shoots two in Oregon traffic stop</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/with-tension-high-in-minnesota-border-agent-shoots-two-in-oregon-traffic-stop</link><description>Minnesota officials complained they were denied access to the scene evidence, case materials or interviews. US Department of Homeland Security Secretary Kristi Noem told reporters in New York that Minnesota simply did not have jurisdiction.
Without access, the Minnesota Bureau of Criminal Apprehen</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 10:59:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP Standing Committee to meet tonight</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-standing-committee-to-meet-tonight</link><description>The BNP Standing Committee is going to hold a meeting on Friday night to discuss the current political situation and organisational matters.
The meeting will be held at 9pm at the BNP Chairperson’s Gulshan office, said BNP Media Cell member Sayrul Kabir Khan.
BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rah</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 11:14:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>3 detained over Shariatpur bomb explosion</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/police-detain-3-individuals-over-shariatpur-bomb-explosion-that-killed-2</link><description>Police have detained three individuals over the crude bomb explosion in Zajira Upazila of Shariatpur that killed two people and injured several others.
The explosion occurred in the Mulai Beparikandi area of Bilaspur Union, reportedly when crude bombs were being made in a house.
The Criminal Inve</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 11:29:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Iran cuts internet as Supreme Leader warns protesters</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/iran-cuts-internet-as-supreme-leader-warns-protesters</link><description>Iran was largely cut off from the outside world on Friday after authorities blacked out the internet to curb expanding protests, with phone calls not reaching the country, flights cancelled and online Iranian news sites only intermittently updating.
Supreme Leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei accused pr</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 11:44:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DNCC to beautify spaces under elevated expressway</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dncc-to-beautify-spaces-under-elevated-expressway</link><description>Dhaka North City Corporation (DNCC) has undertaken an initiative for the beautification of the open space under the Dhaka Elevated Expressway.
Talking to reporters at the site, the beautification site at Uttara on Friday, DNCC Administrator Mohammad Ejaz said plantation, gardening and seating arra</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 11:59:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jewellery maker Pandora's growth hit by weak US market</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/jewellery-maker-pandoras-growth-hit-by-weak-us-market</link><description>Danish jewellery brand Pandora (PNDORA.CO) warned of weaker 2025 sales growth on Friday, denting its shares, after US shoppers spent less than expected in the key holiday season.
Pandora, which sells $80 charm bracelets and lab-grown diamond jewellery made at its own factories in Thailand, is grap</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 12:14:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Lebanon signs gas exploration deal with international consortium</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/lebanon-signs-gas-exploration-deal-with-international-consortium-amid-economic-crisis</link><description>Lebanon 's government on Friday signed a deal with an international consortium to explore gas in an offshore area bordering Israel.
The deal for exploration at the so-called Block 8 off the coast of southern Lebanon comes after Lebanon and Israel signed a 2022 agreement over their maritime border.</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 12:29:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC publishes new Bangla version of RPO</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-publishes-new-bangla-version-of-rpo</link><description>Election Commission (EC) Secretariat has published an updated and authentic full Bangla version of the “Representation of the People Order (RPO), 1972”.
The gazette of the Bangla version of the RPO, which is available in the website of the BG Press, has been published ahead of the upco</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 12:44:04 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>