<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 11:38:08 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Airbus A320 ousts Boeing 737 as most-delivered jet in history</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/airbus-a320-ousts-boeing-737-as-most-delivered-jet-in-history</link><description>Europe's Airbus broke a major commercial barrier on Tuesday when its A320 family of planes overtook the Boeing 737 to become the most-delivered jetliner in history. Boeing's decades-old record fell as a jet was delivered overnight to Saudi carrier Flynas, bringing deliveries to 12,260 since the A32</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 09:40:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India probes Adani Defence for tax evasion on missile parts imports, sources say</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/india-probes-adani-defence-for-tax-evasion-on-missile-parts-imports-sources-say</link><description>Indian authorities are investigating Adani Enterprises' defence unit for evading import taxes on components used to make missiles, two government sources with direct knowledge said, marking the newest regulatory scrutiny of the group.
Adani Defence Systems and Technologies is one of the smaller bu</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 08:42:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>12-kg LPG price cut by Tk 29 per cylinder</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/12-kg-lpg-price-cut-by-tk-29-per-cylinder</link><description>Bangladesh Energy Regulatory Commission (BERC) has cut the retail price of 12 kg LPG by Tk 29 per cylinder to Tk 1,241 for October.
The commission slashed the LPG selling price for private operators in line with the existing downtrend of oil and gas prices in the international market.
T</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 09:12:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Conscience’ to reach ‘red zone’ early tomorrow morning, Shahidul Alam says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/conscience-to-reach-red-zone-early-tomorrow-morning-shahidul-alam-says</link><description>The Conscience, a part of the Freedom Flotilla Coalition (FFC), is expected to reach the 'red zone' early tomorrow morning, Bangladeshi activist Shahidul Alam has said in a Facebook post today (Tuesday).
The flotilla, carrying journalists and medics, is continuing its voyage despite the threat of</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 09:42:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt approves import of 50,000 mts rice from India, wheat from US</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/govt-approves-import-of-50000-mts-rice-from-india-wheat-from-us</link><description>The government on Tuesday approved a proposal to import 50,000 metric tonnes of non-Basmati parboiled rice from India under the international open tender system for the fiscal year 2025–26.
The Advisers Council Committee on Government Purchase (ACCGP) in its meeting approved the proposal, re</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 10:12:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Clarke, Devoret and Martinis win 2025 Nobel Prize in Physics</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/clarke-devoret-and-martinis-win-2025-nobel-prize-in-physics</link><description>U.S.-based scientists John Clarke, Michel Devoret and John Martinis won the 2025 Nobel Prize in Physics for "experiments that revealed quantum physics in action", the award-giving body said on Tuesday.
"This year's Nobel Prize in Physics has provided opportunities for developing the next generatio</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 10:27:36 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>