<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 11:21:04 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>South Asia Insurance celebrates 26th anniversary</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/south-asia-insurance-celebrates-26th-anniversary</link><description>The 26th anniversary of South Asia Insurance Company Limited was celebrated at the company's head office in Dhaka recently.
The event was held under the chairmanship of Mr Muhammad Nurul Alam Chowdhury, Chief Executive Officer of South Asia Insurance Company Limited.
The event was conducted</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 09:04:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CA orders arrest of Hadi’s killers, maintain law and order before polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ca-orders-arrest-of-hadis-killers-maintain-law-and-order-before-polls</link><description>Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus has directed law enforcement agencies to swiftly arrest those involved in the killing of Osman Hadi and others engaged in illegal activities and keep the law and order situation normal at any cost before the national elections.
“Ahead of the upcoming na</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 09:19:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Law and order to improve ahead of election, hopes CEC Nasir</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/law-and-order-to-improve-ahead-of-election-hopes-cec-nasir</link><description>Chief Election Commissioner (CEC) AMM Nasir Uddin stated on Monday that he is confident the overall law-and-order situation will further improve as the election approaches.
"As the polling day approaches, you will see, InshaAllah, the law and order situation will improve further. There will be no</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 09:34:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Publishers, political, business leaders protest against mob violence</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/publishers-political-business-leaders-protest-against-mob-violence</link><description>The Newspaper Owners' Association of Bangladesh (NOAB) and the Editors’ Council have jointly organised a protest meeting against mob violence at a city hotel on Monday.
Leaders from various political parties, media and journalists’ organisations, business communities, lawyers, cultural</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 09:49:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh set to sign first EPA with Japan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladesh-set-to-sign-first-epa-with-japan</link><description>The country is likely to sign its first Economic Partnership Agreement (EPA) with Japan, under which 97 per cent of Bangladeshi goods, including readymade garments, will receive duty-free access to the Japanese market.
Advisor to the Ministry of Commerce Sheikh Basir Uddin disclosed the informatio</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 10:04:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCP leader 'out of danger' after being shot in Khulna</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ncp-leader-out-of-danger-after-being-shot-in-khulna</link><description>Motaleb Shikdar, the Khulna divisional chief of the NCP-affiliated Jatiya Sramik Shakti, has been declared out of danger after being shot in the head in Khulna city.
Khulna Medical College Hospital Superintendent Mohammad Akhtaruzzaman told reporters on Monday that Motaleb had sustained a gunshot</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 09:35:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Lynching of Hindu youth in Mymensingh: 12 accused put on 3-day remand</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/lynching-of-hindu-youth-in-mymensingh-12-accused-put-on-3-day-remand</link><description>A Mymensingh court on Monday placed 12 accused on a three-day remand in connection with the killing of Dipu Chandra Das in Bhaluka upazila of Mymensingh district on December 18.
Senior Chief Judicial Magistrate Shahdat Hossain passed the order, said court inspector Sheikh Mostasinur Rahman.
Those</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 09:50:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Delivering under fire: How Nova Post became Ukraine's wartime success story</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/delivering-under-fire-how-nova-post-became-ukraines-wartime-success-story</link><description>On a November weekday in the Ukrainian city of Chernihiv, an air raid siren pierced through the morning bustle at a Nova Post branch as manager Ihor Shutkovskyi ushered staff and customers to the safety of a concrete shelter.
Minutes later, the all-clear given, the team was back behind the counter</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 10:05:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BD set to receive electricity from Rooppur nuclear plant next year: Russian Envoy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bd-set-to-receive-electricity-from-rooppur-nuclear-plant-next-year-russian-envoy</link><description>Bangladesh could begin receiving electricity from its first nuclear power plant as early as next year, Russia’s ambassador to Bangladesh has said, marking a major milestone in one of the country’s most ambitious infrastructure projects and underscoring Moscow’s long-standing energ</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 10:20:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Highest security for Tarique Rahman’s homecoming on Dec 25: Home Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/highest-security-for-tarique-rahmans-homecoming-on-dec-25-home-adviser</link><description>Home Adviser Lieutenant General (Retd) Md Jahangir Alam Chowdhury has said the highest level of security will be ensured for the homecoming of Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman on December 25.
“Maximum security measures have already been taken to ensure the sa</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 10:35:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hadi murder to be tried at Speedy Trial Tribunal: Law advisor</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hadi-murder-to-be-tried-at-speedy-trial-tribunal-law-advisor</link><description>The murder of Osman Hadi, convenor of Inqilab Moncho, will be tried at the Speedy Trial Tribunal, with proceedings expected to be completed within 90 days, according to Law Advisor Asif Nazrul.
The case will be handled by a tribunal under the Speedy Trial Tribunal Act 2002 once police submit their</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 10:50:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Kremlin says US intelligence conclusions cited by Reuters 'not true'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/kremlin-says-us-intelligence-conclusions-cited-by-reuters-not-true</link><description>The Kremlin said on Monday that US intelligence was wrong if it believed Russian President Vladimir Putin wanted to seize all of all Ukraine and parts of Europe that were once part of the former Soviet empire.
Reuters cited six unidentified sources last week as saying US intelligence reports conti</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 11:05:09 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>