<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 10:20:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Menacing proliferation of three-wheelers in Dhaka City</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/analysis/menacing-proliferation-of-three-wheelers-in-dhaka-city</link><description>The proliferation of auto-rickshaws has reached the tipping point where their earlier version of pedal rickshaws is on the verge of vanishing from the scene. Electricity stored in a battery pack through charging turns a motor into mechanical power to drive the three-wheelers. This is why the vehicl</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 06:41:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Retired officials from 25 BCS cadres demand retrospective promotion, citing discrimination</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/retired-officials-from-25-bcs-cadres-demand-retrospective-promotion-citing-discrimination</link><description>Retired officials from 25 Bangladesh Civil Service (BCS) cadres -- all except the administration cadre -- have demanded promotions and equal benefits, alleging discrimination in government service.
They also called for an ordinance based on key recommendations of the Public Administration Reform C</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 07:11:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh seaports on alert as low intensifies into depression over Bay of Bengal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-seaports-on-alert-as-low-intensifies-into-depression-over-bay-of-bengal</link><description>The low-pressure area over the southeast Bay of Bengal and adjoining areas has intensified, first into a well-marked low and subsequently into a depression, according to the Bangladesh Meteorological Department (BMD).
The BMD warned on Saturday that the weather system might escalate further and tu</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 07:44:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Put aside differences, join polls: Fakhrul to all parties</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/put-aside-differences-join-polls-fakhrul-to-all-parties</link><description>BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir on Saturday urged all political parties to take part in the upcoming national election, putting aside minor differences, to help restore the democratic process in the country.
"I call upon all political parties to join the coming election by puttin</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 08:14:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Beximco Pharma provides access to breakthrough treatment for cystic fibrosis patients worldwide</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/beximco-pharma-provides-access-to-breakthrough-treatment-for-cystic-fibrosis-patients-worldwide</link><description>Cystic fibrosis (CF) is a rare but life-threatening genetic disorder with very low life expectancy. Globally, an estimated 189,000 people are suffering from CF, of whom only 60% are diagnosed and just 27% receive treatment. Trikafta from US-based Vertex Pharmaceuticals, is a breakthrough triple com</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 08:59:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Southeast University welcomes Fall 2025 freshers with grand orientation programmes</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/southeast-university-welcomes-fall-2025-freshers-with-grand-orientation-programmes</link><description>Southeast University (SEU) warmly welcomed newly admitted students of the Fall 2025 Semester through a freshers’ reception and orientation programmes held on October 23, 2025, at the university’s Multipurpose Hall.
The programme consisted of two separate sessions, organised by SEU&amp;rsqu</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 09:29:38 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>