<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 11:34:35 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>RMG workers demand salary, bonus before 20th Ramadan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/rmg-workers-demand-salary-bonus-before-20th-ramadan</link><description>Garment workers have demanded that their outstanding wages and a bonus equivalent to one month’s salary be paid by the 20th of Ramadan.
The demand was raised at a rally held in front of the National Press Club in the capital on Friday, organised by different garment workers’ organisati</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 07:52:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US aims to bring in 4,500 white South Africans per month as refugees</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-aims-to-bring-in-4500-white-south-africans-per-month-as-refugees</link><description>The US aims to process 4,500 refugee applications from white South Africans per month, far above President Donald Trump's stated refugee program cap, and is installing trailers on embassy property in Pretoria to support the effort, a US contracting document said.
The new target, contained in a pre</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 08:22:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Moderate quake shakes Bangladesh; epicentre located near Khulna</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/moderate-quake-shakes-bangladesh-epicentre-located-near-khulna</link><description>A moderate earthquake jolted most parts of the country, including the capital Dhaka, on Friday afternoon.
The tremor was felt around 1:53 pm, triggering panic among residents in several districts.
According to the European-Mediterranean Seismological Centre (EMSC), the earthquake originated at 1:</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 09:00:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh denounces Israeli annexation move at OIC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-denounces-israeli-annexation-move-at-oic</link><description>Bangladesh has strongly denounced Israel's recent land legislation aimed at annexing the occupied Palestinian territory, with Foreign Minister Dr Khalilur Rahman urging an immediate ceasefire in Gaza and reaffirming support for an independent Palestinian state.
Addressing the Open-Ended OIC Execut</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 09:15:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Optimum media freedom to be ensured maintaining accountability: Info minister</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/optimum-media-freedom-to-be-ensured-maintaining-accountability-info-minister</link><description>Information and Broadcasting Minister Zahir Uddin Swapan, on Friday, said to ensure free flow of information to commoners, maximum freedom of the media will be ensured by determining the scope of accountability based on opinions of all stakeholders, including journalists.
He made the remark respon</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 09:30:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Eight held over Awami League flash procession in Dhanmondi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/eight-held-over-awami-league-flash-procession-in-dhanmondi</link><description>Police have arrested seven leaders of the Awami League's women's wing and a microbus driver during a flash procession in Dhaka’s Dhanmondi.
Assistant Commissioner Shah Mustafa Tariquzzaman of the DMP’s Dhanmondi Zone said the arrests were made around 6:15am on Friday, reports bdnews24.</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 10:00:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Buses, trams and trains grind to a halt across Germany at start of 2-day strike</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/buses-trams-and-trains-grind-to-a-halt-across-germany-at-start-of-2-day-strike</link><description>Buses, trams and trains across Germany ground to a halt early Friday as local transport workers heeded a call by the Verdi public sector union to stage a strike on Feb 27 and 28.
The union is aiming to gain leverage in negotiations that cover working conditions, specifically working hours and shif</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 10:15:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ousted PM Hasina charged in another July Uprising murder case</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ousted-pm-hasina-charged-in-another-july-uprising-murder-case</link><description>Police have pressed formal charges against ousted prime minister Sheikh Hasina and 25 others over the fatal shooting of a man during the July Uprising in Dhaka’s Gulshan.
The Anti-Terrorism Unit submitted the chargesheet on Feb 18 in connection with the killing of 24-year-old Abuzar Sheikh.</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 10:30:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>PM to launch family card programme in Bogura in March 10</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/pm-to-launch-family-card-programme-in-bogura-in-march-10</link><description>Prime Minister Tarique Rahman is scheduled to visit Bogura to inaugurate the government’s Family Card programme on March 10.
He will formally launch the programme at Bogura Sadar upazila, according to local media reports.
The information was confirmed on Friday by BNP Media Cell member Shay</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 10:46:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Malaysia police launch probe into alleged plot to topple government</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/malaysia-police-launch-probe-into-alleged-plot-to-topple-government</link><description>Malaysia's top police official said on Friday authorities were investigating an alleged conspiracy to "topple the government and sabotage national stability".
The alleged plot involved a local influential figure as well as an international media agency, Inspector-General of Police Mohd Khalid Isma</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 11:01:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Home minister’s stance will guide probe into police killings: Fakhrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/home-ministers-stance-will-guide-probe-into-police-killings-fakhrul</link><description>“The big challenge before the new government is to ensure accountability and re-establish the framework of good governance,” he says Local Government, Rural Development and Cooperatives Minister Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir has said the investigation into the killing of police members du</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 11:16:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Narsingdi teen rape-murder: Five arrested, hunt on for prime suspect</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/narsingdi-teen-rape-murder-five-arrested-hunt-on-for-prime-suspect</link><description>Police have arrested five people in connection with the rape and subsequent killing of a teenage girl in Narsingdi, allegedly carried out to conceal the crime.
A case has been filed against nine accused, while the prime suspect remains at large.
Dhaka Range Deputy Inspector General (DIG) Rezaul K</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 11:31:07 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>