<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 20:25:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Mustafizur axe from IPL sparks controversy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/cricket/mustafizurs-kkr-release-draws-criticism-from-indian-congress-leader-world-cup-winner</link><description>The decision to drop Bangladesh fast bowler Mustafizur Rahman from the 2026 Indian Premier League (IPL) has drawn sharp criticism from former Indian state minister for external affairs and current Congress MP Shashi Tharoor
Tharoor questioned the Board of Control for Cricket in India’s (BCCI</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 16:46:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump ends Maduro’s heavy-handed rule in Venezuela</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/nicolas-maduros-heavy-handed-rule-in-venezuela-is-finally-ended-by-trump</link><description>Nicolas Maduro ruled Venezuela with a heavy hand for more than 12 years, presiding over deep economic and social crises and resisting pressure from domestic opponents and foreign governments for political change.
His rule abruptly ended on Saturday when President Donald Trump announced US forces h</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 17:01:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Latin America reacts after US capture of Maduro</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/condemnation-and-applause-in-latin-america-after-us-seizes-venezuelas-maduro</link><description>Former Chattogram North District BNP convenor Golam Akbar Khondakar has asserted that the recent wave of killings in Raozan stems from extortion, encroachment, and disputes over the sand trade rather than political rivalry.
Speaking after the scrutiny of nomination papers at the Chattogram deputy</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 17:16:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Raozan killings caused by crime, not politics: Golam Akbar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/killings-in-raozan-linked-to-extortion-and-sand-trade-not-politics-says-golam-akbar</link><description>Former Chattogram North District BNP convenor Golam Akbar Khondakar has asserted that the recent wave of killings in Raozan stems from extortion, encroachment, and disputes over the sand trade rather than political rivalry.
Speaking after the scrutiny of nomination papers at the Chattogram deputy</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 17:31:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh gets cautious as  global rice price spikes</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladesh-gets-cautious-as-global-rice-price-spikes</link><description>Global rice-price spike in recent months has nudged  major rice-consuming countries like Bangladesh into bracing with preparation to fend off any external shocks to food security.
According to the FAO Rice Price Update (January 2026), the FAO All Rice Price Index rose 4.3 per cent month on mo</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 18:02:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hindu-Buddhist-Christian Unity Council leaders meet Tarique, mourn Khaleda’s death</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hindu-buddhist-christian-unity-council-leaders-meet-tarique-mourn-khaledas-death</link><description>Leaders of the Bangladesh Hindu Buddhist Christian Unity Council met BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman on Saturday night and expressed condolences over the death of former Prime Minister and BNP Chairperson Begum Khaleda Zia.
The meeting was held at the BNP Chairperson’s Gulshan office, sai</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 18:17:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>About willful defaulters in amortising bank loan dues</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/about-willful-defaulters-in-amortising-bank-loan-dues</link><description>Subjecting willful loan defaulters to rigorous actions for loan recovery is fully justifiable from bankers' viewpoint. The central  bank   issued  a circular ( BRPD  circular no.:6 dated  12.03.2024) instructing all scheduled  banks   to  identify  willf</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 18:32:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Can a single health vision remedy AMR crisis?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/reviews/can-a-single-health-vision-remedy-amr-crisis</link><description>After a week of illness, a rural doctor changed a 6-year-old's antibiotic for the third time. Two days later, the child lay in Dhaka Shishu Hospital with sepsis. Nearby in Gazipur, a farmer watched 3,000 broiler chickens die from a gut infection no longer controlled by the "growth promoter" mix in</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 18:50:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Green revolution in RMG: Leave no factories behind</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/green-revolution-in-rmg-leave-no-factories-behind</link><description>For apparel makers, 2025 has been an exceptionally challenging year. In the aftermath of the July-August 2024 uprising that ended Sheikh Hasina's authoritarian rule, the sector had hoped for a fresh start. Instead, a series of setbacks has pushed the industry into renewed crisis. Frequent labour un</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 19:05:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Challenge of curbing inflation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/challenge-of-curbing-inflation</link><description>For the last three years, the country has been experiencing high inflation, eroding the real income of fixed-income people as money loses its value and becomes a melting asset. So, the key question now is whether inflation will continue to rise in the new year. Though inflation witnessed a modest d</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 19:20:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No place for lawlessness in telecom sector</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/no-place-for-lawlessness-in-telecom-sector</link><description>The launch of National Equipment Identity Register (NEIR) at the start of the new year constitutes a long-overdue step to curtail the chaos and illicit trade that have defined much of Bangladesh's mobile handset sector. For years the sector has functioned with a large grey zone where illegal import</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 19:35:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Transport sector development stalls under interim admin</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/transport-sector-development-stalls-under-interim-admin</link><description>Road and rail transport development has made little headway during the interim government's tenure, as reluctance to approve new or high-cost projects has slowed infrastructure expansion.
Even relatively low-cost initiatives such as bus route rationalisation (BRR) and bus rapid transit (BRT) have</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 19:50:16 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>