<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 05:22:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Chhengarchar Municipality runs short of 90pc staff</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/chhengarchar-municipality-runs-short-of-90pc-staff</link><description>Despite being a 1st class municipality, Chhengarchar Paurasava in Matlab Uttar upazila of the district runs short of 90 percent staff in the office; and that's why around one lakh dwellers are being deprived of getting due services.
They have been facing many difficulties in the day to day life fo</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 01:42:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Climate-tolerant farming changes lives in coastal Dakop</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/climate-tolerant-farming-changes-lives-in-coastal-dakop</link><description>Khulna's Dakop was once a poverty-stricken and disaster-prone coastal region of South-West Bangladesh, but thanks to the now prevalent climate tolerant farming practices, it has become an example of a silent revolution featuring a notable participation of women farmers.
Frequent cyclones, tidal su</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 01:57:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EDOTCO signs deal with telcos to boost nationwide connectivity</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/edotco-signs-deal-with-telcos-to-boost-nationwide-connectivity</link><description>In a significant move to enhance the country's digital infrastructure, EDOTCO Bangladesh entered into a tower-sharing agreement on Sunday with state-owned Teletalk and a leading private telecom operator to support wider network expansion across Bangladesh.
Under the arrangement, EDOTCO will provid</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 02:27:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Janata Bank rolls out two digital initiatives</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/janata-bank-rolls-out-two-digital-initiatives</link><description>Janata Bank PLC has rolled out two major digital initiatives - the NFC-enabled "Taka Pay Card" and the "E-Credit Management System", aiming to enhance customer service and modernise loan disbursement through digital transformation.
The bank launched the initiative marking the celebration of Tarunn</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 02:42:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gaza ceasefire, aid to resume after airstrikes kill 26</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/gaza-ceasefire-aid-to-resume-after-airstrikes-kill-26</link><description>The Israeli military said on Sunday a ceasefire in Gaza had resumed after an attack killed two of its soldiers and prompted a wave of airstrikes that Palestinians said killed 26 people, in the most serious test yet of this month's US-brokered truce.
US President Donald Trump said the ceasefire he</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 03:12:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Female student of JnU’s Zobayed held</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/female-student-of-jnus-zobayed-held</link><description>Police have taken a female student into custody for questioning as a “suspect” over the murder of Zobayed Hossain, a Jagannath University leader of the Jatiyatabadi Chhatra Dal.
The arrest took place shortly after 11:00 pm on Sunday, as the officers picked up the student from Noor Box</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 03:27:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cargo plane skids off runway into sea in Hong Kong, killing two</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/cargo-plane-skids-off-runway-into-sea-in-hong-kong-killing-two</link><description>Two Hong Kong airport security staff were killed on Monday after a cargo plane from Dubai skidded off the runway on landing, collided with their security patrol vehicle and pushed it into the sea, the city's airport operator said.
The Boeing 747 involved in the deadliest airport incident in the fi</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 03:57:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Crown jewels stolen from Louvre Museum in four minutes</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/others/crown-jewels-stolen-from-louvre-museum-in-four-minutes</link><description>In a minutes-long strike Sunday inside the world’s most-visited museum, thieves rode a basket lift up the Louvre ’s facade, forced a window, smashed display cases and fled with priceless Napoleonic jewels, officials said.
The daylight heist about 30 minutes after opening, with visitors</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 04:12:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gucci owner to sell beauty unit to L'Oreal for $4.66b</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/gucci-owner-to-sell-beauty-unit-to-loreal-for-466b</link><description>Gucci owner Kering said on Sunday it has agreed to sell its beauty business to L'Oreal for 4 billion euros ($4.66 billion), as new CEO Luca de Meo moves to tackle the luxury group's high debt and refocus on its core fashion business.
Under the deal, French beauty giant L'Oreal will acquire Kering'</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 04:27:15 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>