<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 06:35:37 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Campaigns pace up as constituency-wise voter list out</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/campaigns-pace-up-as-constituency-wise-voter-list-out</link><description>Election candidates of different political parties and independent ones are passing busy time conducting campaigns to attract voters as the Election Commission (EC) has unveiled constituency-wise final voter list.
Candidates of Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP), Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami, Nation</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 05:09:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>One-person company registration galore</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/one-person-company-registration-galore</link><description>One-person companies (OPCs) galore with a record 301 registered in just first six months of the fiscal year, surpassing the total formed in several previous full years, official data show.
According to statistics from the Office of the Registrar of Joint Stock Companies and Firms (RJSC), the six-m</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 05:24:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Seven dead, 82 missing in Indonesian landslide</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/seven-dead-82-missing-in-indonesian-landslide</link><description>Seven people have died and 82 are missing after a landslide hit in Indonesia's West Java province, Indonesia's disaster mitigation agency said on Saturday, amid reports of heavy rain in the area.
A local official said the landslide struck a village in West Bandung region.
"The number of missing p</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 04:12:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chickpeas, edible oil, sugar get pricier</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/chickpeas-edible-oil-sugar-get-pricier</link><description>Prices of chickpeas, edible oil, and sugar increased in the last week for no plausible reasons.
Prices of the aforesaid items remained high over the past few weeks, though the holy month of Ramadan, when consumption of these items goes up, is weeks away, trading sources said.
Chickpeas were selli</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 04:27:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>JU students' short film 'The Haze' honoured in Greece</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/ju-students-short-film-the-haze-honoured-in-greece</link><description>A short film produced by students of Jahangirnagar University (JU) has earned international recognition at a film festival in Greece.
The experimental short film- 'The Haze'- received an honourable mention in the best original
score and soundtrack category at the Athens International Monthly Art</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 04:42:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Saraswati Puja: Festivity all across DU Jagannath Hall</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/saraswati-puja-festivity-all-across-du-jagannath-hall</link><description>Devotion, reverence, and youthful enthusiasm filled the Jagannath Hall premises of Dhaka University (DU) on Friday as Saraswati Puja was celebrated in a vibrant and festive atmosphere.
From early morning, the sound of conch shells and ululation echoed across the hall, while devotees offered flower</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 04:57:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Government slashes airline surcharge to 14.25pc</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/government-slashes-airline-surcharge-to-1425pc</link><description>The government has significantly reduced the annual airport surcharge rates for airlines, lowering the maximum penalty from 72 per cent to about 14.25 per cent to ease financial pressure on struggling carriers and align charges with regional standards. 
Under the amended rules, no surcharge w</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 05:12:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EU Ambassador Michael Miller visits Ctg port</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/eu-ambassador-michael-miller-visits-ctg-port</link><description>CHITTAGONG, Jan 23: Ambassador of the European Union to Bangladesh Michael Miller visited Chittagong port, the prime sea port of Bangladesh on Thursday.
Michael Miller expressed his satisfaction over the development of the Chittagong port during the visit. The European Union envoy met with Chairma</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 05:27:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Broad-gauge line on Lalmonirhat–Parbatipur route: Railway DG</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/broad-gauge-line-on-lalmonirhat-parbatipur-route-railway-dg</link><description>The government has a long-term plan for the installation of a broad-gauge rail line on the Lalmonirhat–Parbatipur route and construction of a new Teesta rail bridge, Railway Director General Afzal Hossain has said.
He disclosed the plan while talking to journalists Friday night after inspect</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 05:42:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Iran will treat any attack as 'all-out war,' senior official says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/iran-will-treat-any-attack-as-all-out-war-senior-official-says</link><description>Iran will treat any attack "as an all-out war against us," a senior Iranian official said on Friday, ahead of the arrival of a US military aircraft carrier strike group and other assets in the Middle East in the coming days.
"This military buildup - we hope it is not intended for real confrontatio</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 05:57:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Israel aims to ensure more Palestinians are let out of Gaza than back in</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/israel-aims-to-ensure-more-palestinians-are-let-out-of-gaza-than-back-in</link><description>Israel wants to restrict the number of Palestinians entering Gaza through the border crossing with Egypt to ensure that more are allowed out than in, three sources briefed on the matter said ahead of the border's expected opening next week.
The head of a transitional Palestinian committee backed b</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 06:12:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC urges postal voters to submit ballots promptly</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-urges-postal-voters-to-submit-ballots-promptly</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has called on expatriate voters casting their ballots by post to return them as quickly as possible to ensure they are counted.
In a statement issued on Saturday, the commission said postal ballots must reach the relevant returning officer by 4:30 pm on February 12 to</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 06:27:04 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>