<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 10:24:34 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>RSTP proposes 3 more metro rail corridors</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/rstp-proposes-3-more-metro-rail-corridors</link><description>Development of three more metro rail corridors has been proposed in the Revised Strategic Transport Plan (RSTP), of which updating is now at the final stage.
However, officials said the new corridors would be working as the bus priority corridors in the next two decades.
The RTSP proposed total s</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 06:06:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP candidate Shama Obaid reports lower income, higher assets</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-candidate-shama-obaid-reports-lower-income-higher-assets</link><description>BNP candidate Shama Obaid's annual income has dropped over the past seven years, even as the value of her assets has grown significantly.
Shama, who is contesting the Faridpur-2 constituency covering Saltha and Nagarkanda, disclosed the figures in documents submitted to the Election Commission a</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 06:21:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Israel on high alert for possibility of US intervention in Iran</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/israel-on-high-alert-for-possibility-of-us-intervention-in-iran</link><description>Israel is on high alert for the possibility of any US intervention in Iran as authorities there confront the biggest anti-government protests in years, according to three Israeli sources with knowledge of the matter.
President Donald Trump has repeatedly threatened to intervene in recent days and</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 06:36:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Minimum temperature falls by 1°C, mild cold wave persists</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/minimum-temperature-falls-by-1c-mild-cold-wave-persists</link><description>The country’s minimum temperature dropped by one degree Celsius today, while a mild cold wave continues to affect several regions, said the Bangladesh Meteorological Department (BMD).
Weather is expected to remain dry with partly cloudy skies at times over the next 24 hours from 9 am on Sund</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 08:00:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladeshi girl killed by gunfire from Myanmar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladeshi-girl-killed-by-gunfire-from-myanmar</link><description>A child has reportedly been killed in Cox's Bazar's Teknaf after being struck by gunfire coming from across the border in Myanmar.
The deceased was identified as Afnan, 12, the daughter of Mohammad Jasim from Ward No. 3 of Whykong Union, reports bdnews24.com.
The incident occurred early on Sunday</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 08:15:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Youth shot dead in Khulna</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/youth-shot-dead-in-khulna</link><description>A 26-year-old young man was shot dead by unidentified assailants at Bagmara in Rupsha upazila of Khulna district early Sunday.
The deceased was identified as Abdul Rashed alias Pikul, son of Abdul Auwal of Rupsha upazila, reports UNB.
SM Sabur Hossain, officer-in-charge (OC) of Rupsha Police Stat</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 08:30:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP leader Dulu cleared in long-running tax evasion case</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-leader-dulu-cleared-in-long-running-tax-evasion-case</link><description>A court has acquitted senior BNP leader Ruhul Quddus Talukder Dulu in a tax evasion case filed more than 15 years ago.
The verdict was delivered on Sunday by Judge Rabiul Alam of Dhaka's Fourth Special Judge’s Court, reports bdnews24.com.
Dulu, a former state minister for land and a former</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 08:45:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bride, groom killed in gas cylinder blast at wedding in Pakistan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/bride-groom-killed-in-gas-cylinder-blast-at-wedding-in-pakistan</link><description>A gas cylinder explosion during a wedding reception at a home in Pakistan’s capital killed at least eight people, including the bride and groom, police said Sunday.
The blast occurred overnight as guests gathered to celebrate the couple, causing part of the house to collapse, according to th</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 09:00:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two crushed under wheels of train in Netrakona</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/two-crushed-under-wheels-of-train-in-netrakona</link><description>Two people died after being crushed under the wheels of a train in Sadar upazila of Netrekona district on Saturday.
The deceased were identified as Russel Islam, 25, son of Lutfur Rahman of Sherpur district and Akash Roy, 24 of Dinajpur district. They were workers of a rice mill in Netrakona distr</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 09:15:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Iran warns Washington it will retaliate against any attack</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/iran-warns-washington-it-will-retaliate-against-any-attack</link><description>Iran warned ​President Donald ‌Trump on Sunday ‌that any U.S. attack would lead to Tehran ⁠striking ‌back against Israel and ‍regional U.S. military bases as "legitimate targets", Parliament ​Speaker Mohammad ‌Baqer Qalibaf told parliament.
Israel is on high alert for the ⁠</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 09:30:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NBR chief calls for decisive shift to full digitisation of revenue administration</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/nbr-chief-calls-for-decisive-shift-to-full-digitisation-of-revenue-administration</link><description>Chairman of the National Board of Revenue (NBR) Md Abdur Rahman Khan on Tuesday underscored the need for a decisive transition to full digitisation, saying a modern, technology-driven revenue administration is essential to enhance efficiency, transparency and taxpayer services.
He also mentioned t</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 09:45:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC restores Nagorik Oikko chief Manna’s candidacy on appeal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ec-restores-nagorik-oikko-chief-mannas-candidacy-on-appeal</link><description>The Election Commission has reinstated the candidacy of Nagorik Oikko chief Mahmudur Rahman Manna for the Bogura-2 (Shibganj) constituency in the upcoming 13th parliamentary election.
The decision was made on Sunday after the commission heard Manna’s appeal against the rejection of his nomin</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 10:00:45 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>