<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 12:45:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Tigers act normal despite controversies, says Shanto</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/bangladesh-players-act-normal-despite-controversies-says-shanto</link><description>Bangladesh players are often forced to mask the impact of controversies in the build-up to, and during, major tournaments, despite how the external noise affects them, Test captain Najmul Hossain Shanto said.
Uncertainty looms over Bangladesh’s participation in the Twenty20 World Cup followi</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 10:14:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Banglalink launches nationwide Wi-Fi calling service</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/banglalink-launches-nationwide-wi-fi-calling-service</link><description>Banglalink, the country’s leading innovative digital operator, has officially launched its nationwide Voice over Wi Fi (VoWiFi) calling service, enabling customers across Bangladesh to make high quality voice calls using Wi Fi alongside mobile networks.
With the nationwide rollout, customers</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 10:29:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Iran's exiled crown prince rises as a figure in protests</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/irans-exiled-crown-prince-rises-as-a-figure-in-protests-decades-after-leaving-his-homeland</link><description>He has been in exile for nearly 50 years. His father, Iran’s shah, was so widely hated that millions took to the streets in 1979, forcing him from power. Nevertheless, Iran’s Crown Prince Reza Pahlavi is trying to position himself as a player in his country’s future.
Pahlavi succ</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 10:44:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘No chance’ of fair vote without curbing ‘mobs’, says Jatiya Party's Patwary</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/no-chance-of-fair-vote-without-curbing-mobs-says-jatiya-partys-patwary</link><description>Jatiya Party Secretary General Shameem Haider Patwary has said there is "no possibility" of the 13th parliamentary election being held fairly unless “mobs" are brought under control.
Speaking during a media briefing at the Election Commission (EC) on Saturday following appeal hearings on par</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 10:59:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Normal gas supply still hours away: Titas</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/gas-pressure-to-take-a-few-more-hours-to-normalise-titas</link><description>Titas Gas Transmission and Distribution Company Ltd has said it may take several more hours for gas pressure to fully return to normal in parts of Dhaka, even after replacing a damaged valve on a distribution line along Mirpur Road.
In a statement issued on Saturday afternoon, the state-run distri</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 11:14:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India’s 2025 rice exports surge to near record</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/indias-2025-rice-exports-surge-to-near-record-as-curbs-lifted</link><description>India’s rice exports jumped 19.4 per cent last year to the second-highest level on record after New Delhi lifted all export curbs, making shipments more competitive, government and industry officials told Reuters on Saturday.
An improved flow of rice from the world’s largest exporter c</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 11:29:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Elite premium cards unveiled at ‘UCB Night’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/elite-premium-cards-unveiled-at-ucb-night</link><description>“UCB Night – The Beginning of a New Era” was held on 9 January 2026 at the Radisson Blu Water Garden Hotel in the capital. 
Two highly anticipated elite cards, 'UCB Visa Infinite Card and UCB Mastercard World Elite', were unveiled at the program, according to a media release</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 11:15:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pabna-1, Pabna-2 polls suspended</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/pabna-1-pabna-2-polls-suspended-following-court-order-over-constituency-boundaries</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has suspended the Feb 12 parliamentary elections in Pabna-1 and Pabna-2 following a court order over constituency boundary disputes.
On Saturday, Pabna Deputy Commissioner and Returning Officer Shahid Mostafa said he had received an official letter from the EC confirmi</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 11:30:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh makes key progress in US trade ties: CA’s office</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-makes-key-progress-in-us-trade-ties-cas-office</link><description>Bangladesh has achieved an 'important step forward' towards strengthening its mutually beneficial trade relationship with the United States, opening the door to greater market access and new opportunities for its vital textile and apparel sector.
In response to a request from National Security Adv</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 11:45:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC hearing puts 51 candidates back in race</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/saturdays-ec-hearing-brings-51-candidates-back-into-election-race</link><description>In a boost for their hopes ahead of Bangladesh’s national election, 51 aspirants regained their candidacies on Saturday, including independent candidate Tasnim Jara from Dhaka-9 and Jamaat-e-Islami’s AHM Hamidur Rahman Azad from Cox’s Bazar-2.
The Election Commission, led by Chie</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 12:00:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘July activists’ seize Jatiya Party office in Bogura, demand party’s ban</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/july-activists-seize-jatiya-party-office-in-bogura-demand-partys-ban</link><description>Activists identifying themselves as “July fighters” have seized the Bogura district Jatiya Party office and hung banners there, while shouting slogans demanding the party’s ban.
The incident took place around 11am on Saturday at Kazi Nazrul Islam Road in the town, bdnews24.com re</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 12:15:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Yemen's main separatist group denies it is disbanding</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/yemens-main-separatist-group-denies-it-is-disbanding</link><description>Yemen's main separatist group, the Southern Transitional Council, denied on Saturday it was disbanding, contradicting a statement by one of its members that the group had decided to dissolve itself.
The conflicting statements highlight a split in the STC, a group backed by the United Arab Emirates</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 12:30:57 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>