<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 11:18:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Christiansen confirmed as US envoy to BD</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/christiansen-confirmed-as-us-envoy-to-bd</link><description>Brent Christiansen has been confirmed as the next US Ambassador to Bangladesh at a time of political transitions and heightened regional sensitivity in the South Asian nation.
Sources say the US Senate, the upper house of the American parliament, Congress, has consented to his current diplomatic a</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 06:03:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Extortionist arrested with arms, ammo in Ctg</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/extortionist-arrested-with-arms-ammo-in-ctg</link><description>CHATTOGRAM Dec 19: Police arrested an alleged extortionist on Thursday night over an extortion attempt at a construction site in Chattogram's Panchlaish area, where a group of attackers allegedly opened fire after the project owner refused to pay Tk 5.0 million. The arrested person, Md Didar (36),</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 06:18:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Child dies as BNP leader's house locked and set on fire</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/child-dies-as-bnp-leaders-house-locked-and-set-on-fire</link><description>A seven-year-old girl of a local BNP leader was burnt to death after miscreants locked their house from outside and set it on fire in Bhabaniganj of Lakshmipur’s Sadar upazila on Friday night.
The deceased, Ayesha Begum Binti, 7, was the youngest daughter of Md Belal, assistant organising se</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 06:34:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ICT prosecutor Zoha's home 'set ablaze' in Magura</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ict-prosecutor-zohas-home-set-ablaze-in-magura</link><description>The family home of BTV Director-General (DG) Mahbubul Alam and Tanvir Hassan Zoha, a prosecutor at the International Crimes Tribunal (ICT), has been hit by an apparent arson attack in Magura.
The incident occurred shortly after 10:30pm on Friday at "Zoha Bhaban", located opposite the Magura Distri</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 06:49:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Netizens urged to report posts inciting violence</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/netizens-urged-to-report-posts-inciting-violence</link><description>The National Cyber Security Agency has called on the public to report social media posts that promote terrorism or incite violence amid heightened concerns over online content linked to unrest.
In a statement issued on Saturday, the Ministry of Posts and Telecommunications said such posts could be</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 07:04:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Additional police, BGB deployed in Dhaka for Hadi's funeral</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/additional-police-bgb-deployed-in-dhaka-for-hadis-funeral</link><description>Border Guard Bangladesh (BGB) personnel have been deployed at the Parliament complex and several other key locations across Dhaka ahead of the funeral prayers for slain political activist Sharif Osman Hadi.
The border security force shared this development in a message issued on Saturday.
In addi</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 07:19:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh Shilpakala Academy suspends all programmes indefinitely</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-shilpakala-academy-suspends-all-programmes-indefinitely</link><description>The Bangladesh Shilpakala Academy has announced the indefinite suspension of all its programmes and exhibitions until further notice.
The decision was taken citing the declaration of state mourning following the death of Sharif Osman Hadi and other unavoidable circumstances.
The announcement was</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 08:06:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AK Khandker, a Liberation War hero and Bangladesh's first Air Force chief, dies at 95</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ak-khandker-a-liberation-war-hero-and-bangladeshs-first-air-force-chief-dies-at-95</link><description>AK Khandker, the deputy chief of staff of the Bangladesh forces during the Liberation War and the country’s first Air Force chief, has died at the age of 95.
He passed away from complications related to old age around 10:30am on Saturday, according to the Army's public relations wing ISPR.</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 08:21:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NRBC Bank organises first AI-driven conference</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/nrbc-bank-organises-first-ai-driven-conference</link><description>NRBC Bank has organised the ‘AML and CFT Conference 2025’, marking the first use of Artificial Intelligence (AI) technology, to enhance institutional capacity and strengthen awareness among bank officials on the prevention of money laundering and terrorist financing.
The day-long confe</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 09:07:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Janaza of Osman Hadi held at Manik Mia Avenue amid massive turnout</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/janaza-of-osman-hadi-held-at-manik-mia-avenue-amid-massive-turnout</link><description>The namaz-e-janaza of Inquilab Moncho spokesperson Sharif Osman Hadi was held at the South Plaza of the Jatiya Sangsad Bhaban on Saturday afternoon.
Chief Adviser Prof Muhammad Yunus, advisers and leaders and activists of BNP, Jamaat-e-Islami, Inquilab Moncho, National Citizens Party (NCP) and the</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 09:22:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hadi will 'live on in the hearts of every Bangladeshi': Yunus</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/you-will-live-on-in-the-hearts-of-every-bangladeshi-yunus-pays-tribute-to-osman-hadi</link><description>Chief Advisor Muhammad Yunus has said as long as Bangladesh exists, Sharif Osman Hadi will remain in the hearts of all Bangladeshis.
In an emotional tribute to Inqilab Moncho Convenor Hadi during his funeral prayers at the Parliament's South Plaza on Saturday, Yunus said: "Thousands have gathered</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 10:10:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Seven elephants killed in India train accident</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/seven-elephants-killed-in-india-train-accident</link><description>Seven elephants were killed and one injured when a Delhi-bound train collided with a herd in northeast India early on Saturday, district police chief VV Rakesh Reddy said.
The incident in the Hojai district of Assam state occurred at a location that is not a designated elephant corridor, Northeast</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 10:25:45 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>