<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 11:41:44 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>23 injured as BNP, Jamaat supporters clash in Meherpur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/23-injured-as-bnp-jamaat-supporters-clash-in-meherpur</link><description>At least 23 people have been injured in clashes between supporters of the BNP and Jamaat-e-Islami in Meherpur’s Mujibnagar and Gangni Upazilas amid allegations of obstructing voters from going to polling stations.
The violence began on Thursday morning and spread across two locations, prompt</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 09:36:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A woman was told her ballot had already been cast. Banani polling paused for 24 minutes</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/a-woman-was-told-her-ballot-had-already-been-cast-banani-polling-paused-for-24-minutes</link><description>Voting has been suspended for around 24 minutes at a polling centre in the capital’s Banani area after a dispute arose over whether a voter had already cast her ballot.
The incident occurred around 1:15 pm on Thursday at the Banani Model School centre when Aklima, a resident of Korail slum</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 09:51:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No cause for alarm over polls: EC secy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/no-cause-for-alarm-over-election-says-ec-secretary</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has said there is no alarming situation in the Feb 12 election and referendum, even as scattered incidents surface outside polling centres.
At a briefing at the Nirbachan Bhaban after 1pm, EC Secretary Akhtar Ahmed said isolated disruptions had been contained by local</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 08:37:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Results will be accepted if election is free, neutral: Tarique Rahman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/results-will-be-accepted-if-election-is-free-neutral-tarique-rahman</link><description>BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman today (Thursday) said the poll results will be accepted if the election is held in a free, fair and neutral manner.
"If the election is held in a free, fair, impartial manner and without controversy, then why shouldn't we accept it? We will accept it. However, of course</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 08:52:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Voting won’t change our fate,’ say Korail slum voters</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/voting-wont-change-our-fate-say-korail-slum-voters</link><description>“There may not be any benefit for us, but voting is taking place. So I came to vote.”
These were the words of Amina Begum, a woman in her sixties and a resident of Korail slum, after casting her ballot in the ongoing general election and referendum on Thursday, bdnews24.com reports.
H</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 09:07:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP says victory is ‘certain’ as voting continues</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-says-victory-is-certain-as-voting-continues</link><description>The BNP has described the 2026 election as “free and fair” and said its victory is "certain".
The remarks were made on Thursday by Mahdi Amin, spokesperson for the BNP’s Election Management Committee, at a press conference, bdnews24.com reports. 
“By establishing the</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 09:22:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP candidate alleges delay tactics in Dhaka-15</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnps-milton-flags-long-queues-alleges-delay-tactics-in-dhaka-15</link><description>BNP candidate Shafiqul Islam Khan Milton has raised allegations of deliberate delays in polling, claiming voters in Dhaka-15 are facing unusually long queues.
On Thursday at 2:25pm, he Monipur Uchcha Vidyalaya and College (Main Monipur Girls’ Branch) and reported slow voting, suggesting pres</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 09:37:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>French diplomat with Epstein ties denies accusations after government alerts prosecutor</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/french-diplomat-with-epstein-ties-denies-accusations-after-government-alerts-prosecutor</link><description>A French diplomat suspected of transferring United Nations documents to late financier Jeffrey Epstein denies all allegations made against him, his lawyer said.
French Foreign Minister Jean-Noel Barrot said this week he had alerted prosecutors and initiated disciplinary proceedings against Aidan,</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 09:52:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Teen girl, 2 others hurt as crude bombs hurled at Gopalganj polling centre</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/teen-girl-2-others-hurt-as-crude-bombs-hurled-at-gopalganj-polling-centre</link><description>Three people including a teenage girl were injured as miscreants hurled several crude bombs at a polling centre in Gopalganj Sadar upazila during voting on Thursday morning.
The injured were identified as Ansar members Sukanta Majumdar and Jamal Hossain and Amena Khanam, 14, daughter of Assaf Ali</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 10:07:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hasnat Abdullah optimistic about victory in Cumilla-4</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/hasnat-abdullah-optimistic-about-victory-in-cumilla-4</link><description>Hasnat Abdullah, the 11-party alliance candidate for the Cumilla-4 constituency, expressed optimism about his electoral victory as voting progressed peacefully at all centres in Debiddar upazila of Cumilla on Tuesday.
Till 3:30 pm, The FE found over 50 per cent voter turnout at four centres in the</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 10:22:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>People are voting spontaneously: Rizwana</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/people-are-voting-spontaneously-rizwana</link><description>Information and Broadcasting Adviser Syeda Rizwana Hasan on Thursday said, despite challenges and useless debates, people are exercising their voting rights spontaneously.
“People are voting spontaneously today,” she told journalists after casting her vote at Ideal School and College o</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 10:37:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>It feels like Eid, creating a new Bangladesh: Prof Yunus</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/it-feels-like-eid-creating-a-new-bangladesh-prof-yunus</link><description>Chief Adviser Prof Muhammad Yunus on Thursday expressed optimism about Bangladesh’s future, describing the atmosphere surrounding the twin elections as festive and historic, saying it feels like Eid as the nation embarks on building a new Bangladesh.
“It is like Eid....fantastic. A big</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 10:52:57 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>