<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 06:37:20 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Sharif Osman's health condition stable after slight deterioration</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/sharif-osmans-health-condition-stable-after-slight-deterioration</link><description>The health condition of Inqilab Mancha spokesman Sharif Osman Hadi was stated to be stable on Tuesday after slight deterioration following initial medical tests in Singapore, according to his family sources.
In a Facebook post on Tuesday, quoting Sharif Osman Hadi's brother, the Inqilab Mancha sai</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 01:55:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt to host Global Sourcing Expo twice a year from 2026</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/govt-to-host-global-sourcing-expo-twice-a-year-from-2026</link><description>The government is set to organise the Global Sourcing Expo twice a year to showcase Bangladesh's strengths to international buyers and diversify its export basket, according to sources at the Ministry of Commerce.
Officials said the decision follows positive responses from exhibitors, global buyer</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 02:10:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt spending on DAEE project may jump 78pc</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-spending-on-daee-project-may-jump-78pc</link><description>Government spending on the Dhaka-Ashulia Elevated Expressway (DAEE) project is likely to rise by 78 per cent as the Bangladesh Bridge Authority (BBA) has finalised a revised cost estimate of Tk 272.33 billion.
The government's contribution to the DAEE project was Tk 59.51 billion, which increased</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 02:25:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tk 2.39b skill dev projects proposed for Rohingya host communities</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tk-239b-skill-dev-projects-proposed-for-rohingya-host-communities</link><description>The Ministry of Youth and Sports has proposed two skill-development projects worth Tk 2.39 billion with support from the New Development Bank (NDB) of the BRICS countries, aiming to generate employment for youths from Rohingya host communities in Cox's Bazar and across the Chattogram division, offi</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 02:40:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>20 pc of Bangladeshi Hajj pilgrims to go to KSA via Madinah next year</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/20-pc-of-bangladeshi-hajj-pilgrims-to-go-to-ksa-via-madinah-next-year</link><description>Twenty per cent of Bangladeshi Hajj pilgrims must travel to Saudi Arabia via Madinah next year and 30 per cent will return through the same route.
A high official of the Religious Affairs Ministry told the FE that they had sent a letter to all lead Hajj agencies informing the 2026 Hajj agreement b</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 02:55:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>One hacked to death in city</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/one-hacked-to-death-in-city</link><description>A man was stabbed to death in public on Monday night at Taltola Mor of Naddapara under Dakshinkhan Police Station in the capital.
The victim was identified as Md Shajahan (43).
According to the police station concerned, he came under the attack around 8:45 pm (Monday) in the area.
According to e</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 04:30:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>43 firms win ICSB Awards for corporate governance excellence</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/43-firms-win-icsb-awards-for-corporate-governance-excellence</link><description>A total of 43 corporate entities listed on the country's stock market were honoured with the prestigious ICSB National Award in recognition of their efforts to uphold corporate governance standards.
The Institute of Chartered Secretaries of Bangladesh (ICSB) organised the awards ceremony titled '1</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 04:45:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>RU holds 12th Convocation today</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/ru-holds-12th-convocation-today</link><description>After weeks of speculation, Rajshahi University (RU) is set to hold its 12th Convocation today (Wednesday-) at the university stadium. The main ceremony will begin at 8:00 am.
A total of 5,969 graduates from 12 faculties, who completed their undergraduate (honours) degrees between 2016 and 2018, w</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 05:00:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BSC to procure 22 new mother vessels</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bsc-to-procure-22-new-mother-vessels</link><description>Bangladesh Shipping Corporation (BSC), the state-owned maritime operator, is preparing a landmark plan to procure 22 mother vessels worth Tk 10,000 crore, aiming to strengthen the nation’s control over seaborne foreign trade.
If implemented over the next five years, the initiative will signi</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 05:15:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP leader Tarique warns of difficult times ahead, urges unity</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-leader-tarique-warns-of-difficult-times-ahead-urges-unity</link><description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman has called on party members to remain united, warning that “conspiracies” were still brewing in Bangladesh.
He made the remarks at a discussion organised by the London unit of the BNP at London’s City Pavilion on Tuesday to mark Victory Day.
"I</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 05:30:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BCPS hosts winter retreat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bcps-hosts-winter-retreat</link><description>The Bangladesh Communications Professionals Society (BCPS) on Tuesday organised a day-long Winter Retreat: Comms Edition at CCLUB in Gazipur, bringing together around 45 communications professionals from NGOs, brands and the corporate sector.
The retreat opened with a session titled “Discove</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 05:45:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump adds seven countries to full travel ban list</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-adds-seven-countries-to-full-travel-ban-list</link><description>US President Donald Trump on Tuesday expanded a list of countries subject to a full travel ban, prohibiting citizens from an additional seven countries, including Syria, from entering the United States.
The White House said in a statement that Trump signed a proclamation "expanding and strengtheni</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 06:00:20 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>