<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 16:28:46 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Unnatural death charges brought after metro bearing pad fall</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/family-brings-unnatural-death-charges-after-metro-bearing-pad-fall-kills-pedestrian</link><description>The victim’s family has filed an unnatural death case over the death of a pedestrian who was struck by a falling bearing pad from a metro rail pillar in Dhaka’s Farmgate.
Tejgaon Police Station chief Mobarak Hossain said the case was initiated on Sunday night following the daytime acci</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 13:24:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>More than 1,400 flights delayed as government shutdown hits Day 27</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/more-than-1400-flights-delayed-as-government-shutdown-hits-day-27</link><description>More than 1,400 flights were delayed on Monday after more than 8,600 late flights Sunday as air traffic controller absences continue to disrupt travel and a federal government shutdown reached its 27th day.
The Federal Aviation Administration said Monday that air traffic controller staffing issues</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 13:39:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCC Bank launches Visa Business Multicurrency Debit Card to empower SMEs customers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ncc-bank-launches-visa-business-multicurrency-debit-card-to-empower-smes-customers</link><description>NCC Bank has officially launched its Visa Business Multicurrency Debit Card, a cutting-edge financial solution tailored to meet the evolving needs of SMEs &amp; startups clients, according to a press release.
The Visa Business Multicurrency Debit Card is designed to provide businesses with enhanced fi</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 14:09:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ACC approves case against former BARI DG, 43 others for illegal recruiting process</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/acc-approves-case-against-former-bari-dg-43-others-for-illegal-recruiting-process</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) has approved a case against 44 people, including former Director General of the Bangladesh Agricultural Research Institute (BARI), Dr Rafiqul Islam Mandol, for allegedly recruiting 42 scientific assistants illegally, violating government laws and regulations.
T</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 14:24:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>National Bank holds inspiring ‘Managers Meet’ with branch leaders of Barishal Region</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/national-bank-holds-inspiring-managers-meet-with-branch-leaders-of-barishal-region</link><description>National Bank PLC hosted an energetic and purpose-driven “Managers Meet” in Barishal on 27 October 2025, bringing together 23 dynamic branch managers from across the region for a day of inspiration, strategy, and shared vision.
The event served as a powerful platform to review performa</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 14:54:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cameroon’s Biya re-elected at 92, opposition reports gunfire</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/cameroons-biya-re-elected-at-92-opposition-reports-gunfire</link><description>Cameroon’s President Paul Biya, the world’s oldest serving ruler, secured an eighth term in office on Monday, vote results showed, as the main opposition challenger who has also claimed victory reported gunfire near his home.
Biya, 92, won 53.66% of the vote, against 35.19% for his for</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 15:09:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Karmasangsthan Bank holds public hearing and complaint resolution program</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/karmasangsthan-bank-holds-public-hearing-and-complaint-resolution-program</link><description>As part of the celebration of “Youth Festival 2025,” Karmasangsthan Bank organized a flagship program titled “Customer Service Fortnight.”
On October 27, 2025, simultaneous Public Hearing and Complaint Resolution Programs were held at 33 branches across 33 regional offices</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 15:24:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BRAC Bank TARA, Green Delta Insurance host breast cancer awareness event</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/brac-bank-tara-green-delta-insurance-host-breast-cancer-awareness-event</link><description>BRAC Bank TARA, in collaboration with Green Delta Insurance, hosted a discussion session titled ‘Rise Above Fear’ to mark Breast Cancer Awareness Month.
The inspiring evening attended by 80 women customers and guests celebrated courage, compassion, and the shared commitment to advancin</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 15:39:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prof Yunus calls for preserving all records of National Consensus Commission</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/prof-yunus-calls-for-preserving-all-records-of-national-consensus-commission</link><description>Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus on Monday highlighted the importance of preserving all documents, videos, audios and photographs related to the discussions from the formation of the National Consensus Commission to the formulation of its final recommendations, describing them as invaluable a</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 16:09:27 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>