<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 05:19:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Govt to slash tariffs of 6 state power plants</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/govt-to-slash-tariffs-of-6-state-power-plants</link><description>Power tariffs of half a dozen of the state-owned power plants are set to be cut years after initiation of their commercial operations, said sources.
The proposed new tariffs are expected to get approved by the Advisors Council Committee on Economic Affairs as state-run Bangladesh Power Development</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 01:41:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Government issues PPR 2025</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/government-issues-ppr-2025</link><description>Making the electronic government procurement (e-GP) compulsory for all public agencies, the government on September 28 issued the Public Procurement Rules (PPR) 2025, replacing the 2008 version.
It has also removed the ±10 per cent price cap on work procurement, which existed in the PPR 200</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 01:56:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>July Charter Implementation: Commission awaits last-minute political consensus</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/july-charter-implementation-commission-awaits-last-minute-political-consensus</link><description>The National Consensus Commission is scheduled to meet political parties October 5 in what could be a decisive sitting to settle how the July Charter will be implemented.
With little progress made since the last adjourned meeting in September, the Commission is banking on last-minute consensus bef</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 02:11:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BDBL seeks Tk 50b from govt to help support its operations</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bdbl-seeks-tk-50b-from-govt-to-help-support-its-operations</link><description>The state-run Bangladesh Development Bank PLC (BDBL) has sought Tk 50 billion as financial support from the government to help expand its overall operations, sources said.
Managing Director and CEO Md. Jashim Uddin in a letter made such a request to the Finance Adviser, aiming to boost the bank's</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 02:41:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Philippines quake death toll rises to 69</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/philippines-quake-death-toll-rises-to-69</link><description>The death toll from a 6.9-magnitude earthquake that hit the central Philippines has risen to 69, a disaster official said on Wednesday as the government mobilised agencies to search for survivors and restore power and water supplies.
In Bogo city in the north of Cebu province, which was near the e</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 03:07:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt cautious about taking fresh loans: Salehuddin</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/govt-cautious-about-taking-fresh-loans-salehuddin</link><description>The government would pursue a "cautious stance" on obtaining foreign loans amid the significant rise in total external debts, Finance Adviser Dr Salehuddin Ahmed said Tuesday.
"This year, we are very cautious about taking new loans," he told a group of reporters at his Bangladesh Secretariat offic</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 03:37:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US, UK announce US$96m in fresh aid for Rohingyas</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/us-uk-announce-fresh-aid-commitment-of-us96m-to-rohingyas</link><description>The United States (US) and the United Kingdom (UK) have announced fresh aid commitments totalling US$96 million at the first-ever High-Level Conference on the Situation of the Rohingya Muslims and Other Minorities in Myanmar, held at the UN headquarters on Tuesday.
Chief Adviser’s Press Secr</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 04:07:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CA leaves New York for home after nine-day visit</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ca-leaves-new-york-for-home-after-nine-day-visit</link><description>Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus has left New York for home, wrapping up his nine-day visit to the United States.
An Emirates Airlines commercial flight carrying the chief adviser and his entourage departed John F Kennedy International Airport at 11:10 pm (New York time) on Tuesday.
Banglad</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 04:22:21 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>