<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 17:19:04 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Bank merger cuts salaries of 5 Islamic banks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/merged-islamic-banks-to-reduce-salaries-to-standardise-pay-preserving-jobs</link><description>Administrators overseeing the merger of five Shariah-based banks have taken steps to reduce salaries, allowances, and other benefits for officers and employees as part of the integration process.
The banks facing financial strain are Exim Bank, First Security Islami Bank, Global Islami Bank, Union</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 14:31:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>National seminar calls for formal recognition of women farmers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/national-seminar-calls-for-formal-recognition-of-women-farmers</link><description>Speakers on Thursday at a national-level seminar urged for the formal recognition of women farmers to uphold the human rights.
 
They said women constitute 58 per cent of the total agricultural workforce in Bangladesh, making them the majority in the sector. 
 
The speakers said</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 14:37:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Expat registration for 7 countries likely to reopen on Friday: EC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/expat-registration-for-7-countries-likely-to-reopen-on-friday-ec</link><description>The Election Commission plans to resume Out-of-Country voter registration on Friday for Bangladeshi expatriates in seven countries after suspending it due to incorrect or incomplete mailing addresses provided by many applicants.
The seven countries are Bahrain, Kuwait, Malaysia, Oman, Qatar, Saudi</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 14:52:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No phone purchased before Dec 16 would be blocked using NEIR: BTRC Chairman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/no-phone-purchased-before-dec-16-would-be-blocked-using-neir-btrc-chairman</link><description>No phone purchased before December 16 next will be blocked, said Mahmud Hossain, Commissioner, Bangladesh Telecommunication Regulatory Commission (BTRC) on Thursday.
“Measures are being taken to bring all existing handsets in the market under legal channels for the sake of public security an</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 15:07:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Thailand shifts gear in flood evacuation; Indonesia death toll climbs to 61</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/thailand-shifts-gear-in-flood-evacuation-indonesia-death-toll-climbs-to-61</link><description>Flood rescue teams in Thailand readied drones to deliver aid and helicopters dropped supplies to people marooned on rooftops on Thursday, as the death toll from its worst floods in years rose and the number killed by a cyclone in Indonesia climbed to 61.
Thailand’s government said 55 people</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 15:22:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>5 madrasha students stabbed by ‘fellow student’ in Gazipur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/5-madrasha-students-stabbed-by-fellow-student-in-gazipur</link><description>Five students of a madrasha were stabbed allegedly by a fellow student in Sreepur upazila of Gazipur on Thursday.
The injured were identified as Rifat, Nadim, Muhin, Rifat, and Rashidul, students of Gararan Khaliliya Bahumukhi Fazil Madrasa.
The victims said their final examinations were underway</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 15:37:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>4,042 candidates clear 46th BCS written exam</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/4042-candidates-clear-46th-bcs-written-exam</link><description>The Public Service Commission (PSC) has released the results of the 46th Bangladesh Civil Service (BCS) written examination, with 4,042 candidates making the cut.
The results were published at 9pm on Thursday, PSC spokesperson SM Matiur Rahman confirmed.
Candidates can check their outcome at www.</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 15:44:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Back-to-back fires hit Karwan Bazar and Moghbazar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/back-to-back-fires-hit-karwan-bazar-and-moghbazar</link><description>Two separate fires broke out at a shanty adjacent to the Karwan Bazar railway gate in Tejgaon and at an eight-storey building in Moghbazar on Thursday night.
Duty officer at the Fire Service and Civil Defence control room Rakibul Hasan said they received the first call at 8:50pm from Karwan Bazar</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 15:59:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Putin says US-Ukraine text could form basis for future peace deal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/putin-says-us-ukraine-text-could-form-basis-for-future-peace-deal</link><description>Russian President Vladimir Putin said on Thursday that outline draft peace proposals discussed by the United States and Ukraine could become the basis of future agreements to end the conflict in Ukraine, but that if not Russia would fight on.
US President Donald Trump has long said he wants to end</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 16:14:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>46pc of Bangladeshis use feature phones: official</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/46-per-cent-of-bangladeshis-use-feature-phones-miss-government-benefits-official</link><description>Information and Communication Technology Division Secretary Shish Haider Chowdhury has said 46 percent of Bangladesh’s population still use feature or button phones, leaving them “deprived” of the benefits of various government initiatives due to their lack of internet connectivit</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 16:29:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rented barge allegedly cut up in BNP leader’s dockyard</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rented-barge-allegedly-cut-up-in-bnp-leaders-dockyard</link><description>A barge has been allegedly cut up at a dockyard by a man posing as its owner.
The barge’s original owner, Rakesh Sharma, lodged the case at Sonargaon Police Station on Monday, alleging that the vessel was dismantled without his permission.
He named seven suspects, including: Md Zafar, 42, S</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 16:44:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Panna pulls out of Hasina’s defence</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/lawyer-zi-khan-panna-withdraws-from-hasinas-defence-over-lack-of-confidence-in-ict</link><description>Senior lawyer ZI Khan Panna has said he will not act as state-appointed lawyer for Sheikh Hasina in two cases involving enforced disappearances and torture at the TFI and JIC during the Awami League government.
Freedom fighter Panna, a Supreme Court lawyer, was initially appointed on Nov 23 by a t</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 16:59:19 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>