<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 10:24:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Consensus commission submits July charter implementation order to CA</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/consensus-commission-submits-july-charter-implementation-order-to-ca</link><description>The National Consensus Commission has officially submitted its recommendations on the implementation of the July National Charter (Constitutional Reform) to the Chief Adviser of the Interim Government, Professor Muhammad Yunus, who also serves as the Commission’s Chairman.
The handover cerem</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 07:45:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Official letter issued to suspend international flights at Cox’s Bazar Airport</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/official-letter-issued-to-suspend-international-flights-at-coxs-bazar-airport</link><description>The Ministry of Civil Aviation and Tourism has suspended scheduled international flights at Cox’s Bazar Airport in line with a government decision.
According to a press release issued by the ministry on Tuesday, the directive was made through an official letter signed by the ministry’s</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 08:30:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Garment leaders frustrated over failure to meet CA</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/garment-leaders-frustrated-over-failure-to-meet-ca</link><description>Leaders of the country’s readymade garment (RMG) sector have expressed frustration over their repeated but unsuccessful attempts to meet Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus to discuss pressing industry issues.
“We have been trying for the past four months to get an appointment with</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 09:00:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EBL becomes the first bank to conduct Climate Risk Assessment</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ebl-becomes-the-first-bank-to-conduct-climate-risk-assessment</link><description>Eastern Bank PLC. (EBL) has released its standalone Sustainability Report 2024, reaffirming its leadership in Environmental, Social, and Governance (ESG) excellence in Bangladesh’s banking sector.
The report, prepared in the light of IFRS S1 – Sustainability Disclosures and IFRS S2 &amp;nd</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 09:15:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No response yet on Hasina's extradition request: Touhid Hossain</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/no-response-yet-on-hasinas-extradition-request-touhid-hossain</link><description>Foreign Affairs Adviser Md Touhid Hossain stated on Tuesday that Bangladesh has sought the extradition of former Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina in accordance with legal procedures and a court order, but has yet to receive a response from India.
“We have followed the legal procedures avail</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 09:45:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Awami League became bankrupt after 2014: Mahfuj Alam</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/awami-league-became-bankrupt-after-2014-mahfuj-alam</link><description>Information and Broadcasting Adviser Md. Mahfuj Alam today (Tuesday) said that the Awami League faced insolvency or bankruptcy subsequent to the year 2014. "Despite the party's organizational size, its internal viability had been severely undermined," he said while speaking as the special gues</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 10:00:35 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>