<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 05:24:35 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Mobile-phone users startled finding myriad devices under each NID</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/mobile-phone-users-startled-finding-myriad-devices-under-each-nid</link><description>A ruckus centering the National Equipment Identity Register (NEIR) rollout has ensued and a weird revelation of umpteen devices surreptitiously connected with each NID startled mobile-phone users.



The bizarre finds stoke concerns among the users as to whether their sets were being used by fr</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 18:30:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Taka devaluation decelerates for policy buttress against dive</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/taka-devaluation-decelerates-for-policy-buttress-against-dive</link><description>Local-currency taka depreciated marginally in the just-past calendar year as policy buttress and steady dollar flow deterred steep devaluation suffered in 2024, sources say.
This is due to tighter monetary policy, strong dollar inflow and subdued demand for the greenback, according to central bank</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 02:01:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Commercial court ordinance issued</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/commercial-court-ordinance-issued</link><description>President Mohammed Shahabuddin has signed the Commercial Court Ordinance 2026, a landmark move for speedy, efficient, and transparent adjudication for commercial disputes.
The gazette, issued on Thursday night, said the ordinance would come into effect immediately.
Analysts say this initiative is</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 02:16:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt issues new shipping agent licensing rules</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/govt-issues-new-shipping-agent-licensing-rules</link><description>The government has issued the country's first-ever shipping agent licensing rules, marking a significant step towards streamlining the operations of shipping agents across the nation.
Under the new guidelines, agents who obtain licences from any river port or seaport customs station will now be ab</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 02:31:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Midsize projects also face budget downsizing</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/midsize-projects-also-face-budget-downsizing</link><description>Many midsize development schemes also find their fate entwined with megaprojects in the infrastructure sector in downsizing budget outlays as the interim government tries to make two ends meet with limited funds.
Sources say a large number of medium-scale development schemes under the Annual Devel</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 02:46:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scrutiny of nomination papers for Dhaka constituencies today</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/scrutiny-of-nomination-papers-for-dhaka-constituencies-today</link><description>Scrutiny of nomination papers submitted by the candidates of 20 constituencies of Dhaka district for the 13th parliamentary election is going to be held today (Saturday).
A total of 236 candidates submitted nomination papers untill last Monday when the deadline for nomination papers submission end</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 03:32:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Stocks stay positive amid renewed optimism</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/stocks-stay-positive-amid-renewed-optimism</link><description>The benchmark index of the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) continued its upward trajectory this week, buoyed by an optimistic start to the first session of the New Year.
Market analysts attributed the market's optimism to growing hopes for improved political clarity in the run-up to the parliamentary e</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 03:47:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>MFS transactions maintain rising trend in Oct '25</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/mfs-transactions-maintain-rising-trend-in-oct-25</link><description>Transactions through mobile financial services (MFS) continued their upward trajectory in October 2025, buoyed mainly by strong person-to-person (P2P), cash-in, and cash-out activities, reflecting sustained consumer reliance on digital platforms for daily financial needs.
The number of MFS transac</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 03:48:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Wage board proposes minimum wage of Tk 12,600 for workers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/wage-board-proposes-minimum-wage-of-tk-12600-for-workers</link><description>The Minimum Wage Board has proposed a new minimum monthly wage of Tk 12,600 for workers in the iron foundry and engineering workshop sector, marking the first wage revision in over 15 years since the last adjustment in 2010.
Under the new proposal, workers would also receive a 5 per cent annual wa</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 04:03:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rebuilding trust, unity and a shared national future</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/analysis/rebuilding-trust-unity-and-a-shared-national-future</link><description>Political division is a universal reality. No country in the world is free from differences in ideology, beliefs, or political allegiance. Even in the most established democracies, allegations of vote rigging, manipulation, and misinformation surface from time to time.
Yet, despite these imperfect</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 04:18:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ADR the faster way of justice dispensation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/analysis/adr-the-faster-way-of-justice-dispensation</link><description>As Bangladesh's national elections draw closer, political pressures increase -- and their wave effects are also felt in industrial areas. Especially in industry-dense zones such as Ashulia, Savar, Gazipur, and Narayanganj, a latent instability often emerges before and after elections. This directly</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 04:33:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How time changes and perception of generations follows suit</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/analysis/how-time-changes-and-perception-of-generations-follows-suit</link><description>At a time when the Generation Z or popularly known as Gen Z is making media splashes all across the globe, there are reasons to be inquisitive about what its preceding or post-generations stood for. Its immediately preceding generation is Generation Y or Millennials born between 1980 and 1994. The</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 04:48:07 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>