<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 07:31:34 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Textile yarn bond curbs spark industry divide</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/textile-yarn-bond-curbs-spark-industry-divide</link><description>The Ministry of Commerce has recommended excluding imports of 10-30-count yarn from the duty-free bonded warehouse facility, citing the need to shield Bangladesh's local spinning industry from mounting pressure caused by low-priced imports.
The proposal has triggered sharp reactions from garment e</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 04:17:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Training for polling officers for general election begins Jan 22</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/training-for-polling-officers-for-general-election-begins-jan-22</link><description>Training for presiding officers, assistant presiding officers and polling officers for the parliamentary polls and the referendum will begin across Bangladesh on January 22.
The Election Training Institute (ETI) Director General Muhammad Hasanuzzaman said the programme would cover electoral laws,</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 04:52:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Guatemalan prison hostages freed</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/guatemalan-prison-hostages-freed</link><description>Guatemala's president declared a state of siege on Sunday after security forces freed dozens of prison guards held hostage by inmates, ending a weekend of gang violence that left at least seven police officers dead and another 10 injured.
Rioting inmates had taken 46 hostages at three men's prison</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 05:07:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US needs Greenland because of European 'weakness': Bessent</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-needs-greenland-because-of-european-weakness-bessent-says</link><description>European "weakness" necessitates US control of Greenland for global stability, US Treasury Secretary Scott Bessent said on Sunday even as some lawmakers sounded alarms about the Trump administration's effort to acquire the Arctic territory held by Denmark.
Speaking on NBC's "Meet the Press" progra</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 05:22:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chinmoy Das, 22 others to face trial in murder case of lawyer Alif</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/chinmoy-das-22-others-to-face-trial-in-murder-case-of-lawyer-alif</link><description>A Chattogram court has ordered the murder case of lawyer Saiful Islam Alif to trial, indicting 23 suspects, including Sammilita Sanatan Jagaran Jote, or United Hindu Awakening Alliance, spokesman Chinmoy Krishna Das.
Chattogram Speedy Trial Tribunal Judge Md Zahidul Haque framed the charges on Mon</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 05:37:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Death toll in Karachi mall fire jumps to 11</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/death-toll-in-karachi-mall-fire-jumps-to-11</link><description>Firefighters in Karachi began searching on Monday for more than 60 missing people after a massive fire destroyed a shopping mall in Pakistan's most populous city, while the death toll from the disaster rose to 11.
The fire started late on Saturday at the sprawling, multi-storey Gul Plaza shopping</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 05:52:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Motorcycle crash kills school student in Narail</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/motorcycle-crash-kills-school-student-in-narail</link><description>A school student was killed and another person critically injured in a road accident in the SM Sultan Bridge area of Narail district on Sunday night after a motorcycle lost control.
The deceased was identified as Mehedi Hasan,17, a student of Narail Government Technical School and College and an S</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 06:07:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>JCD continues sit-in outside EC headquarters</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jcd-continues-sit-in-outside-ec-headquarters</link><description>Bangladesh Jatiotabadi Chatrodal (JCD) on Monday continued its sit-in programme for the second consecutive day in front of the Election Commission (EC), raising three demands, including allegations of bias in the postal ballot system.
The BNP’s student wing started the day’s sit-in pro</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 06:22:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Billionaires’ wealth hits new peak in 2025 as inequality deepens: Oxfam</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/billionaires-wealth-hits-new-peak-in-2025-as-inequality-deepens-oxfam</link><description>Billionaire wealth surged at three times its recent pace last year to reach its highest level on record, deepening economic and political divides that threaten democratic stability, anti-poverty group ​Oxfam said on Monday.
In a report timed for the opening of the World Economic ‌Forum in Dav</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 06:37:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India proposes linking BRICS digital currencies</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/global/india-proposes-linking-brics-digital-currencies</link><description>India's central bank has proposed that BRICS countries link their official digital currencies to make cross-border trade and tourism payments easier, two sources said, which could reduce reliance on the US dollar as geopolitical tensions rise.
The Reserve Bank of India (RBI) has recommended to the</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 06:52:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tribunal receives charge sheet against Shamim Osman, 12 others</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tribunal-receives-charge-sheet-against-shamim-osman-12-others</link><description>The prosecution has submitted a formal charge sheet to the International Crimes Tribunal against former Narayanganj lawmaker Shamim Osman and 12 others, including his son, over alleged crimes against humanity committed during the July Uprising.
Prosecutor Gazi MH Tamim confirmed on Monday that t</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 07:07:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nassa Group’s assets to be sold to clear workers’ dues: Labour adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/nassa-groups-assets-to-be-sold-to-clear-workers-dues-labour-adviser</link><description>Labour and Employment Adviser Brigadier General (Retd) M Sakhawat Hossain has said a decision has been taken to sell the assets of Nassa Group, in line with a court order, to pay workers’ dues and service benefits.
He made the remarks on Sunday while presiding over the 15th meeting of the Ad</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 07:22:18 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>