<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 05:23:41 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Train fares rise via bridge charge</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/train-fares-rise-via-bridge-charge</link><description>Bangladesh Railway (BR) has increased train fares by up to Tk 226 on six key routes, including Dhaka-Cox's Bazar, with the revised rates taking effect on Saturday.
A senior BR official said the hike has been imposed in the form of a pontage charge to cover the maintenance costs of railway bridges,</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 02:54:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Lack of tax incentives deters RMG firms from going public</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/lack-of-tax-incentives-deters-rmg-firms-from-going-public</link><description>Readymade garment (RMG) companies are among the major targets for new listings to help the secondary market grow, but they have not been offered any incentives to go public.
A major purpose of listing is to get tax benefits but RMG companies, irrespective of their status as listed or non-listed, p</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 03:09:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>3 killed as 5 vehicles fall into Dhaleshwari River from ferry</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/3-killed-as-5-vehicles-fall-into-dhaleshwari-river-from-ferry</link><description>At least three people have died after five vehicles, including a truck fell, into the Dhaleshwari River from a ferry in Narayanganj.
The incident occurred around 9:30pm on Saturday in the Boktabali area of Narayanganj Sadar Upazila.
A team of River Police divers later recovered two bodies around</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 03:08:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BITHYYYYYYYYYYY  KICH</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bithyyyyyyyyyyy-kich</link><description>https://open.spotify.com/artist/1RIY4rSfGKxNHJVCYoi05A?si=Fq5crUhIS9u5ArYCY4s93Q</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 03:23:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Poultry industry in deep crisis as farmers lose Tk 13b a month</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/poultry-industry-in-deep-crisis-as-farmers-lose-tk-13b-a-month</link><description>A deepening crisis in Bangladesh's poultry industry is forcing thousands of small-scale farmers to shut down their operations due to soaring production costs, market manipulation by middlemen, and a collapse in farm-gate prices, industry insiders said on Saturday.
Farmers are losing nearly Tk 13 b</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 03:38:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The last call for a personal brand</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/youth-and-entrepreneurship/the-last-call-for-a-personal-brand</link><description>If you've been waiting for the 'perfect moment' to take your personal brand seriously, the window isn't just closing, but it's being boarded up. In the digital age of 2025, the window for building a meaningful presence is narrowing. For executives and entrepreneurs, this isn't a drill or a side pro</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 03:53:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Flair's Pitch 2.0 crowns top innovators at grand finale at the University of Chittagong</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/youth-and-entrepreneurship/flairs-pitch-20-crowns-top-innovators-at-grand-finale-at-the-university-of-chittagong</link><description>The national business idea competition Flair's Pitch 2.0, presented by AMA Coffee and powered by PUSTI, reached its conclusion recently with a grand finale at the Law Faculty Auditorium, University of Chittagong. The event showcased seven exceptional semifinalist teams competing for top honours thr</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 04:08:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How podcasts are shaping Bangladesh's future workforce</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/youth-and-entrepreneurship/how-podcasts-are-shaping-bangladeshs-future-workforce</link><description>Revolution is taken to the streets, but in Bangladesh, a silent 'revolution' has been carried out through headphones. Yes, we are talking about the podcasts. The global podcasting phenomenon is rapidly becoming a defining feature of the nation's digital arena. Today enthusiastic tech-savvy youths h</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 04:23:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DU Sheikh Mujib hall replaced with ‘Shaheed Osman Hadi Hall’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/du-sheikh-mujib-hall-replaced-with-shaheed-osman-hadi-hall</link><description>After burying beside the grave of National Poet Kazi Nazrul Islam, agitated students replaced ‘Sheikh Mujibur Rahman Hall’ with ‘Shaheed Osman Hadi Hall’ at Dhaka University (DU) on Saturday night.
On Saturday night around 9pm, leaders of the hall union brought a crane to t</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 04:38:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US forces seize another oil tanker off coast of Venezuela</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-forces-seize-another-oil-tanker-off-coast-of-venezuela</link><description>US Secretary of Homeland Security Kristi Noem said Saturday that the US forces seized another oil tanker off the coast of Venezuela earlier in the day.
"In a pre-dawn action early this morning on Dec. 20, the US Coast Guard, with the support of the Department of War apprehended an oil tanker that</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 04:53:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Case filed over attack on Chhayanaut</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/case-filed-over-attack-on-chhayanaut</link><description>A case has been initiated over the attack on the headquarters of preeminent cultural organisation Chhayanaut in Dhaka following a night of widespread violence sparked by the death of political activist Sharif Osman bin Hadi.
Dhanmondi Police Station chief (OC) Saiful Islam said the case was lodged</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 05:08:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trader stabbed to death by ‘muggers’ in Jatrabari</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/trader-stabbed-to-death-by-muggers-in-jatrabari</link><description>A trader was stabbed to death, allegedly by muggers in the Jatrabari area of Dhaka on Saturday.
The deceased was identified as Ashish Joaddar, 32, son of Amal Joyaddar of Paturia village in Magura Sadar. He was a cloth trader, reports UNB.
Al Amin, a witness, said when Ashish was walking past a w</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 05:23:41 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>