<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 11:19:32 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>First Irish artist Oona Hyland’s solo exhibition in Dhaka highlights bilateral ties</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/entertainment/first-irish-artist-oona-hylands-solo-exhibition-in-dhaka-highlights-bilateral-ties</link><description>An exclusive solo exhibition of acclaimed Irish artist Oona Hyland titled "An Duanaire: Visual Poems of the Dispossessed," was inaugurated on Tuesday, the first of its kind by an Irish artist in Bangladesh.
"Oona Hyland is spending three weeks in Dhaka for an artistic cultural exchange - the first</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 07:40:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>PTERC Chairman Mazadul selected as IBFB member</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/pterc-chairman-mazadul-selected-as-ibfb-member</link><description>International Business Forum of Bangladesh (IBFB) has selected Md Mazadul Hoque as its member.
Previously, IBFB selected Dr Zaidi Sattar, chairman of Policy Research Institute (PRI), as its member, says a media release.
Md Mazadul Hoque, chairman of Policy Think &amp; Economic Research Centre (PTERC)</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 07:55:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IMF to probe ‘NPL data concealment’ in Bangladesh’s banking sector</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/imf-to-probe-npl-data-concealment-in-bangladeshs-banking-sector</link><description>The International Monetary Fund (IMF) is set to launch an investigation into the years-long concealment of a staggering volume of non-performing loans (NPLs) in Bangladesh’s banking sector, seeking to identify those responsible for the large-scale cover-up.
The global lender is examining whe</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 08:25:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BB abolishes five Islamic bank boards</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bb-abolishes-five-islamic-bank-boards</link><description>Bangladesh Bank (BB) has dissolved the boards of the five liquidity-crisis-ridden Islamic banks facing mergers.
The central bank called the board of directors of the struggling unconventional banks on the day and shared the decision to dissolve their boards as part of the ongoing merger move by th</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 08:40:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Stock index sinks below 5000-mark after four months</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/stock-index-sinks-below-5000-mark-after-four-months</link><description>The key index of the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) fell below the ‘psychological’ threshold of 5000-mark after four months on Wednesday as jittery investors dumped their holdings amid a lack of clear direction ahead of the national election.
Market analysts said the lingering confidence c</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 08:55:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Halda River declared as ‘Fish Heritage’; fishing banned</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/halda-river-declared-as-fish-heritage-fishing-banned</link><description>The government has officially declared the Halda River, Bangladesh’s largest natural breeding ground for carp fish, as the country’s first ‘Fish Heritage’ site.
A gazette notification in this regard was issued on Wednesday. It also imposed a complete ban on fishing and othe</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 09:25:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Conducive environment to be ensured for holding fair election: Home adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/conducive-environment-to-be-ensured-for-holding-fair-election-home-adviser</link><description>Home Affairs Adviser Lieutenant General (Retd.) Md Jahangir Alam Chowdhury today (Wednesday) said the upcoming national parliamentary elections will be free and fair, and acceptable to all. 
"Necessary instructions have been given to authorities concerned, including the law enforcement agenci</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 09:40:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mamdani to Trump: 'Turn the volume up'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/mamdani-to-trump-turn-the-volume-up</link><description>New York City Mayor-elect Zohran Mamdani wasted no time calling out President Donald Trump, formally kicking off the battle that will likely define relations between the 34-year-old mayor and the president whose celebrity is tied to the city.
 
"Donald Trump, since I know you’re w</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 09:55:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Settle applications of expat voters by Thursday: EC to field officials</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/settle-applications-of-expat-voters-by-thursday-ec-to-field-officials</link><description>The Election Commission has directed its field officials to dispose of applications, filed by expatriate Bangladeshis for registering as voters, by Thursday (Nov 6) ahead of the general election.
All applications submitted by October 31, 2025 must be resolved by November 6, following the completio</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 10:25:47 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>