<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 05:40:56 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>US, UK announce US$96m in fresh aid for Rohingyas</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/us-uk-announce-fresh-aid-commitment-of-us96m-to-rohingyas</link><description>The United States (US) and the United Kingdom (UK) have announced fresh aid commitments totalling US$96 million at the first-ever High-Level Conference on the Situation of the Rohingya Muslims and Other Minorities in Myanmar, held at the UN headquarters on Tuesday.
Chief Adviser’s Press Secr</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 04:07:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CA leaves New York for home after nine-day visit</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ca-leaves-new-york-for-home-after-nine-day-visit</link><description>Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus has left New York for home, wrapping up his nine-day visit to the United States.
An Emirates Airlines commercial flight carrying the chief adviser and his entourage departed John F Kennedy International Airport at 11:10 pm (New York time) on Tuesday.
Banglad</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 04:22:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Italy to end support for Gaza flotilla as Israeli action looms</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/italy-to-end-support-for-gaza-flotilla-as-israeli-action-looms</link><description>Italy said on Tuesday it would stop tracking an international flotilla trying to deliver aid to Gaza with a military vessel, leaving activists vulnerable to Israeli forces.
The Global Sumud Flotilla, consisting of more than 40 civilian boats with over 500 people including parliamentarians, lawyers</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 03:25:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Reebok denies claims of logo removal from Israel team jerseys</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/reebok-denies-claims-of-logo-removal-from-israel-team-jerseys</link><description>Sports brand Reebok denied on Tuesday that it had asked for its logo to be removed from jerseys belonging to teams of the Israel Football Association, countering claims made by Israeli media reports.
"Reebok is proud of our record as a unifier of all cultures on and off the pitch. Reports in Israe</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 03:40:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka's air turns ‘good’ under influence of morning rain</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/dhakas-air-quality-turns-good-under-influence-of-morning-rain</link><description>Under the influence of rainfall since early morning, Dhaka, the overcrowded capital city of Bangladesh, ranked 84th on the list of cities with the worst air quality, with an AQI score of 44 at 10:10 am this morning (Wednesday, October 1, 2025).
Today, Dhaka’s air was classified as ‘goo</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 04:10:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DSEX advances for second session as investors pile into banks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/dsex-advances-for-second-session-as-investors-pile-into-banks</link><description>The prime bourse gained for the second consecutive day on Tuesday, backed mainly by banks, many of which reported hefty losses for the latest quarters.
The Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) opened the day's session on a positive note and maintained the trend until closure. At the end of the session, the</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 04:40:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dominage Steel rejects TV report of factory shutdown, admits business slowdown</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/dominage-steel-rejects-tv-report-of-factory-shutdown-admits-business-slowdown</link><description>Dominage Steel Building Systems has rejected a media report claiming its factory had remained shut, though it acknowledged a slowdown in business.
In response to an investigative report aired by a national TV channel, the company expressed confidence that it would rebound once political stability</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 04:55:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cordaid places roadmap for saline-resilient coastal farming</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/cordaid-places-roadmap-for-saline-resilient-coastal-farming</link><description>Cordaid has called for scaling up saline-resilient agriculture in Bangladesh's southern coastal belt, where rising salinity threatens food security and livelihoods.
At a learning-sharing seminar titled "Breaking the Salt Barrier: Rewriting the Story of Saline Lands in Southern Bangladesh" held on</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 05:10:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tony Blair's return to Middle East diplomacy reopens old wounds and new doubts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/tony-blairs-return-to-middle-east-diplomacy-reopens-old-wounds-and-new-doubts</link><description>When Tony Blair was first tasked with forging a lasting peace between Israel and the Palestinians in 2007, the White House cautioned that the former British prime minister was not "superman" and "he doesn't have a cape".
After failing to achieve much of note in that role, Blair is preparing once a</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 05:25:56 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>