<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 15:27:43 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Alcohol seized from JU hall room, student suspended</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/20-bottles-of-liquor-seized-at-jahangirnagar-university-hall-room-student-suspended</link><description>Jahangirnagar University has suspended a student for a year after foreign liquor was recovered from a room in the Jatiya Kabi Kazi Nazrul Islam Hall.
An office order on Monday confirmed that 20 bottles of liquor were seized from Room No. 723 during a university administration raid on Sunday. 11 bo</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 12:06:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fakhrul warns of conspiracies to pull country backwards</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/fakhrul-warns-of-conspiracies-to-pull-country-backwards</link><description>BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir has called for national unity, claiming that plots are afoot to drag Bangladesh backward once again.
Speaking at a prayer session on Monday, he noted that the nation faces numerous conspiracies and silent schemes that must be overcome.
Addressing</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 12:21:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BCB awaits ICC meeting after decision against playing World Cup in India</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/bcb-awaits-icc-meeting-after-decision-against-playing-world-cup-in-india</link><description>The Bangladesh Cricket Board (BCB) is now awaiting a response from the International Cricket Council (ICC) after announcing it would not travel to India for the T20 World Cup.
The ICC is expected to invite the board for a meeting shortly, BCB President Aminul Islam said on Monday, bdnews24.com rep</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 12:36:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>8 police officers suspended over releasing colleague who ‘carried yaba’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/8-police-officers-suspended-over-releasing-colleague-who-carried-yaba</link><description>Authorities have suspended eight police personnel from Chattogram’s Bakalia after preliminary evidence found them releasing a fellow officer who was detained with yaba.
The order was issued on Monday by Chattogram Metropolitan Police (CMP) Commissioner Hasib Aziz, said CMP Assistant Commissi</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 12:51:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pakistan PM pays tribute to Khaleda Zia at Bangladesh mission</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/pakistan-pm-pays-tribute-to-khaleda-zia-at-bangladesh-mission</link><description>Pakistan Prime Minister Muhammad Shehbaz Sharif on Monday visited the Bangladesh High Commission in Islamabad to offer condolences over the death of former Prime Minister Begum Khaleda Zia.
During the visit, the Pakistan prime minister wrote his remarks in the visitors’ book, paying tribute</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 13:06:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nicolas Maduro at US court to face drug charges</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/nicolas-maduro-at-us-court-to-face-drug-charges</link><description>Venezuela's deposed leader Nicolas Maduro arrived at a New York court on Monday to face drug charges while the UN was to debate the legality of US President Donald Trump's extraordinary operation to capture him.
In the biggest US intervention in Latin America since the 1989 invasion of Panama, Spe</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 13:21:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khaleda created unique public-private synergy in economy: Moyeen Khan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/khaleda-created-unique-public-private-synergy-in-economy-moyeen-khan</link><description>Former Prime Minister Khaleda Zia created a unique combination between the public and private sectors in Bangladesh’s business and economic landscape, said BNP Standing Committee member Abdul Moyeen Khan on Monday.
He made the remarks while speaking at a doa and remembrance programme organis</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 13:36:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Obaidul Quader placed on ventilator support in Kolkata</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/obaidul-quader-placed-on-ventilator-support-in-kolkata</link><description>Obaidul Quader, general secretary of the Awami League, whose activities were banned following the July movement, is reported to be in a critical condition and receiving treatment on ventilator support in Kolkata.
Hospital and related sources said he is undergoing treatment in the intensive care un</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 13:51:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UCB posts landmark achievement in deposit mobilisation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ucb-posts-landmark-achievement-in-deposit-mobilisation</link><description>United Commercial Bank PLC (UCB) posted a landmark achievement in deposit mobilization, setting a new standard in Bangladesh’s banking industry at a time when the sector has been navigating significant economic and financial challenges.
In 2025, UCB recorded an exceptional deposit growth of</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 14:06:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Denmark PM urges Trump to stop threats to take over Greenland</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/denmark-pm-urges-trump-to-stop-threats-to-take-over-greenland</link><description>The leaders of Denmark and Greenland on Sunday urged U.S. President Donald Trump to stop threatening to take over Greenland, after he reiterated his wish to do so in an interview with The Atlantic magazine.
“It makes absolutely no sense to talk about the U.S. needing to take over Greenland.</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 14:21:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>911th Executive Committee meeting of Shahjalal Islami Bank held</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/911th-executive-committee-meeting-of-shahjalal-islami-bank-held</link><description>The 911th meeting of the Executive Committee (EC) of Shahjalal Islami Bank PLC (SJIB PLC) was held recently at the Corporate Head Office of the bank, according to a press release.
The meeting was presided over by Mr. Akkas Uddin Mollah, the Chairman of the Executive Committee (EC) of the bank. The</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 14:36:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Man shot dead in public in Jashore</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/man-shot-dead-in-public-in-jashore</link><description>Assailants have gunned down a young man in public in Monirampur Upazila, Jashore.
The incident occurred around 5:45 pm at Kapalia Bazaar on Monday, according to Additional Police Superintendent Abul Basar, bdnews24.com reports.</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 14:51:41 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>