<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 17:19:31 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>BNP dissolves committees in Patuakhali-3 constituency</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-dissolves-committees-in-patuakhali-3-constituency</link><description>The Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) has dissolved its Golachipa and Dashmina Upazila committees in Patuakhali, the constituencies from which Gono Odhikar Parishad President Nurul Haque Nur is running for parliament.
The order, signed by senior BNP Joint Secretary Ruhul Kabir Rizvi on Saturday,</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 12:51:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nepal’s ambassador meets Tarique Rahman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nepals-ambassador-meets-tarique-rahman</link><description>Nepal’s Ambassador to Bangladesh Ghanashyam Bhandari on Saturday called on Chairman of the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) Tarique Rahman at the latter’s office and discussed issues of mutual interest.
During the meeting, they reviewed the current state of Bangladesh-Nepal relations</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 13:06:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP’s Fahim Chowdhury gets Sherpur-2 candidacy back</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnps-fahim-chowdhury-gets-sherpur-2-candidacy-back</link><description>Mohammad Fahim Chowdhury, the BNP-nominated candidate for Sherpur-2 (Nakla–Nalitabari), has regained his candidacy after the Election Commission’s appeal board on Saturday declared his nomination valid.
The decision came following a hearing on January 17 regarding allegations of dual c</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 13:21:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pangaon terminal commences operations under MEDLOG Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/pangaon-terminal-commences-operations-under-medlog-bangladesh</link><description>The Pangaon Inland Container Terminal (PICT) at West Keraniganj in Dhaka district has commenced operation under the management of MEDLOG Bangladesh Private Ltd.
The operation was formally inaugurated on Saturday on the premises of the terminal, a strategically located facility near the capital, wi</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 13:36:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP, Jamaat candidates in Feni-1 show-caused</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bnp-jamaat-candidates-in-feni-1-served-show-cause-notices-over-facebook-campaigning</link><description>Two candidates contesting the 13th National Parliamentary Election from Feni-1 constituency, BNP candidate Rafiqul Alam Majnu and Jamaat-e-Islami's Advocate SM Kamal Uddin, have been served show-cause notices for allegedly violating the election code of conduct by campaigning on Facebook.
The noti</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 13:51:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh garment exports to Europe top €18b, up 7.5pc</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladeshs-garment-exports-to-europe-exceed-eur18-billion-growing-over-75-per-cent</link><description>RMG exports to Europe cross €18 billion
The European Union’s apparel import market witnessed a significant reshuffling in 2025, as Bangladesh’s exports to the bloc climbed to €18.06 billion despite a broader trend of falling unit prices and aggressive competition from China.</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 14:06:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>British high commissioner meets Tarique Rahman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/british-high-commissioner-meets-tarique-rahman</link><description>British High Commissioner to Bangladesh Sarah Cooke on Saturday met BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman at the latter's office in the capital.
The meeting took place at 5:55pm at the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) Chairman's Political Office in the city's Gulshan area, Shayrul Kabir Khan, member of BN</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 14:21:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pacer Al Fahad rips through India with 5-wicket haul in U19 World Cup</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/cricket/pacer-al-fahad-rips-through-india-with-5-wicket-haul-in-u19-world-cup</link><description>Pacer Al Fahad produced a dazzling display with the ball as Bangladesh restricted India to 238 in their opening U19 World Cup match.
He grabbed five wickets for 38 runs in 9.2 overs at the Queens Sports Club in Bulawayo on Saturday.
He became the eighth Bangladeshi to bag a 5-wicket haul at the t</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 14:52:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Venezuela’s new leader moves to tighten her grip on power</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/venezuelas-new-leader-moves-to-tighten-her-grip-on-power</link><description>In the 12 days since the US seized Venezuelan President Nicolas Maduro, interim President Delcy Rodriguez has been working to consolidate her own power, installing loyalists in key positions to protect herself from internal threats while meeting US demands to boost oil production.
Rodriguez, 56, a</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 15:07:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique Rahman, family convey greetings to chief adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-rahman-family-convey-greetings-to-chief-adviser</link><description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman and his family on Saturday conveyed greetings to Chief Adviser Professor Dr Muhammad Yunus.
On behalf of Tarique Rahman, his wife Dr Zubaida Rahman and their daughter Barrister Zaima Rahman, BNP Chairman’s Private Secretary ABM Abdus Sattar presented a flor</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 15:22:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCP threatens protests over dual citizens</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ncp-threatens-protests-over-dual-citizens</link><description>The National Citizen Party (NCP) has warned it will take to the streets if dual citizens are allowed to contest in the parliamentary polls.
Labelling Sunday, the final day of the EC’s appeal hearings, as a “red line”, NCP cautioned that any attempt to let dual citizens or loan de</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 16:11:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Badiul Alam Majumdar withdraws remarks on journalists amid backlash</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/badiul-alam-majumdar-withdraws-remarks-on-journalists-amid-backlash</link><description>Shushashoner Jonno Nagorik (SHUJAN) Secretary Dr Badiul Alam Majumdar on Friday night withdrew controversial remarks about journalists following strong protests from local media professionals.
Dr Badiul came under criticism after he allegedly referred to journalists as “pet dogs of political</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 16:26:45 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>