<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 06:38:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Q1 budget surplus jumps on revenue surge</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/q1-budget-surplus-jumps-on-revenue-surge</link><description>The government posted a sharply higher budget surplus for the first quarter of this fiscal year ending September last as revenue growth surpassed government spending during the period.
This is a rare fiscal breathing space to take actions to stimulate the growth momentum and fight the inflationary</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 03:45:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Merged banks' depositors to get no profit for 2024, 2025</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/merged-banks-depositors-to-get-no-profit-for-2024-2025</link><description>Depositors of five banks undergoing merger will not receive any profit on their deposits for 2024 and 2025, as the central bank has directed the banks to recalculate deposit balances under the approved resolution scheme.
The banks-First Security Islami Bank, Social Islami Bank, Union Bank, Global</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 04:00:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>After flood, Boro season unfolds in Sunamganj</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/after-flood-boro-season-unfolds-in-sunamganj</link><description>As the vast haor waters slowly recede, life in Sunamganj's low-lying wetlands is once again defined by urgency, mud and relentless labour by farmers.
Across the district, farmers have plunged into the Boro cultivation season, racing against a narrow planting window that will determine their liveli</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 04:15:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka's air quality remains ‘very unhealthy’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dhakas-air-quality-remains-very-unhealthy</link><description>Dhaka, the densely populated capital of Bangladesh, ranked first among the world's most polluted cities on Thursday morning, recording an Air Quality Index (AQI) of 271 at 9:13 am.
Today, the city's air was classified as 'very unhealthy', indicating a serious health threat, according to the AQI re</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 04:30:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump says Zelensky, not Putin, is holding up a Ukraine peace deal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-says-zelensky-not-putin-is-holding-up-a-ukraine-peace-deal</link><description>US President Donald Trump told Reuters that Ukraine - not Russia - is holding up a potential peace deal, a rhetoric that stands in marked contrast to that of European allies, who have consistently argued Moscow has little interest in ending its war in Ukraine.
In an exclusive interview in the Oval</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 04:45:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump questions Reza Pahlavi's ability to garner support in Iran</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-questions-reza-pahlavis-ability-to-garner-support-in-iran</link><description>US President Donald Trump said on Wednesday that Iranian opposition figure Reza Pahlavi "seems very nice" but expressed uncertainty over whether Pahlavi would be able to muster support within Iran to eventually take over.
In an exclusive Reuters interview in the Oval Office, Trump said there is a</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 05:00:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Speakers highlight expanded CEF role in strengthening citizen engagement</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/speakers-highlight-expanded-cef-role-in-strengthening-citizen-engagement</link><description>Speakers said the expansion of Nagarikata: Civic Engagement Fund (CEF) marked a new chapter in deepening citizen participation and inclusive governance in Bangladesh, as the programme broadened its reach with the support of new development partners.
They stressed that citizen-led initiatives backe</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 05:00:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Packaging industry can reach $50b exports: Amir Khasru</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/packaging-industry-can-reach-50b-exports-amir-khasru</link><description>Bangladesh's packaging industry has the potential to reach $50 billion in exports if proper policy support is provided, said BNP Standing Committee member and former commerce minister Amir Khasru Mahmud Chowdhury on Wednesday.
"If the BNP is able to form the next government, adequate policies will</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 05:15:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Zant Accessories Limited to invest Tk 800m in NSEZ in Ctg</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/zant-accessories-limited-to-invest-tk-800m-in-nsez-in-ctg</link><description>Foam manufacturer Zant Accessories Limited is set to invest Tk 800 million in the National Special Economic Zone (NSEZ) in Chattogram.
It will establish a plant on five acres of land to manufacture polyurethane foam, polyethylene foam, recycled foam, mattress, pillow, comforter and shoe insole.</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 05:30:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Iran has 'no plan' to execute protesters: Trump</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/iran-has-no-plan-to-execute-protesters-trump</link><description>US President Donald Trump says Tehran has "no plan" to execute protesters, but still hasn't ruled out US military action against the country over its violent crackdown on anti-government demonstrators.
The US and UK are both reducing the number of personnel at the Al-Udeid air base in Qatar, while</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 05:45:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BD, Nepal map deeper trade, transit ties</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bd-nepal-map-deeper-trade-transit-ties</link><description>The two-day 8th Bangladesh-Nepal commerce secretary level meeting (CSLM) concluded on Wednesday, focusing on deepening trade, transit and connectivity cooperation between the two neighbouring countries amid evolving regional and global trade dynamics.
The meeting reviewed progress since the 7th CS</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 06:00:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Venezuela’s Delcy vows to continue releasing prisoners detained under Maduro</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/venezuelas-acting-president-vows-to-continue-releasing-prisoners-detained-under-maduro</link><description>Venezuela’s acting President Delcy Rodríguez said Wednesday her government would continue releasing prisoners detained under former President Nicolás Maduro’s rule in what she described as “a new political moment” since his ouster by the United States earlier t</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 06:15:30 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>