<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 17:19:37 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>UN, US express solidarity after earthquake in Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/un-us-express-solidarity-after-earthquake-in-dhaka</link><description>The United Nations and the United States on Friday expressed deep sympathy and solidarity with those affected by a strong earthquake in Dhaka, as both conveyed support while authorities continue assessing the tremor’s impact.
In a statement shared on social media, the UN in Bangladesh said i</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 14:47:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Earthquake upends Narayanganj couple’s life</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/father-misses-daughters-funeral-rushes-between-hospitals-with-injured-wife</link><description>The 5.7 magnitude earthquake that rattled Bangladesh on Friday has upended the lives of Abdul Haque and Kulsum Begum, a couple from Narayanganj, who lost their 10-month-old daughter in the disaster.
The daughter, Fatema, identified with a single name, was in her mother’s lap when a wall coll</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 15:02:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mastermind of fake visa scam arrested in city</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/mastermind-of-fake-visa-scam-arrested-in-city</link><description>The Criminal Investigation Department (CID) arrested the mastermind of an organised fraud ring that embezzled Tk 12.2 million from 28 people by promising jobs, visas and air tickets to Russia.
The accused Abdullah, 45, was detained on Thursday from Lalmatia in Mohammadpur, said a CID press release</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 15:17:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Earthquake epicentre Narsingdi sees five deaths, scores of injuries</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/earthquake-epicentre-narsingdi-sees-five-deaths-scores-of-injuries</link><description>The worst earthquake in decades in Bangladesh has killed five people and injured more than 100 in its epicentre — Narsingdi.
The fatalities included a father and his son, who were crushed to death after an eave collapsed on them.
A wall collapsed on a man, killing him. Another man died fall</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 15:32:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Watchman dies in railing collapse during quake</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/security-guard-struck-by-falling-railing-during-quake-dies-in-dhaka</link><description>A security guard has died in Dhaka’s Mugda after a railing from the roof of an under-construction building collapsed during the earthquake.
The guard, identified with a single name Maksud, was critically injured when the 5.7 magnitude earthquake struck on Friday.
He was taken to Mugda Gener</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 15:47:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Frustration deepens in BNP allies as seat-sharing talks stall ahead of election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/frustration-deepens-in-bnp-allies-as-seat-sharing-talks-stall-ahead-of-election</link><description>Almost three weeks after the BNP unveiled its list of potential contenders for 236 constituencies, a quiet unease is spreading among the party’s allies.
What began as hopeful indications for a unified electoral strategy has now turned into growing frustration, as the long-expected seat-shari</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 15:18:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Zelenskiy say he won't betray Ukrainian interests in US-led peace process</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/zelenskiy-say-he-wont-betray-ukrainian-interests-in-us-led-peace-process</link><description>President Volodymyr Zelenskiy said on Friday he would not betray Ukraine's interests in a US-led peace process, warning that Kyiv faces a choice between losing a key partner and its national dignity at one of the most perilous moments in its history.
The 28-point plan that the United States has pr</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 15:33:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fintech revolution &amp; financial inclusion</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/fintech-revolution-financial-inclusion</link><description>In South Asia, more specifically in Bangladesh, the most significant financial innovation of this decade has neither been an opening of bank branches, an expansion in banks, nor an increased governmental regulation of finance. Rather, innovation has been brought by the mobile phone, which is increa</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 15:48:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Toilet success, sewer failure</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/toilet-success-sewer-failure</link><description>Last Wednesday, countries observed the World Toilet Day with three key messages: we'll always need the toilet, toilets are under pressure and we need toilets fit for the future. The significance of these messages cannot be overstated. UN-Water, the UN's coordination mechanism on water and sanitatio</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 16:03:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Rohingya's path to self determination</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/the-rohingyas-path-to-self-determination</link><description>During last Ramadan, standing beside UN Secretary General Antonio Guterres in a refugee camp, Professor Muhammad Yunus expressed his hope that the Rohingya community would be able to offer their next Eid prayers in their homeland of Arakan. His words kindled a fragile expectation among a persecuted</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 16:18:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Earthquake and the risk to Dhaka residents</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/earthquake-and-the-risk-to-dhaka-residents</link><description>Earthquakes seldom announce themselves before they strike yet their consequences reflect years of choices made about how cities grow and how safety is enforced. The tremor that rippled through Dhaka and nearby districts on Friday morning was a moderate event by global standards, but even so it made</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 16:33:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>400 hurt in Gazipur as buildings crack from quake</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/earthquake-injures-400-in-gazipur-as-buildings-crack-control-rooms-opened</link><description>At least 400 people have been injured in Gazipur after rushing out of buildings during an earthquake, most of them reported to be workers.
The tremor occurred at 10:38am on Friday, with its epicentre in Narshingdi’s Madhabdi, said Bangladesh Meteorological Department’s Seismology Centr</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 16:48:33 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>