<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 08:59:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Bangladesh, US sign reciprocal tariff agreement</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladesh-us-sign-reciprocal-tariff-agreement</link><description>The Agreement on Reciprocal Tariff between Bangladesh and the United States was signed on Monday. On the Bangladesh side, the signatories were Commerce Adviser Sheikh Bashir Uddin and National Security Adviser Khalilur Rahman, and on US side, Ambassador Jamieson Greer, US Trade Representative.
Neg</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 01:59:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BB tightens scrutiny of large loans</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/bb-tightens-scrutiny-of-large-loans</link><description>Bangladesh Bank is set to impose stricter inspection of large loans as part of its push to rein in irregularities linked to collateral valuation and mortgage documentation.
The move targets loans exceeding Tk 500 million, which have often been associated with inflated asset values and forged docum</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 02:14:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique reaffirms BNP pledge for economic democratisation, rebound</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-reaffirms-bnp-pledge-for-economic-democratisation-rebound</link><description>BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman delivers a televised speech on Monday.
BNP Chairperson Tarique Rahman reaffirmed BNP's election pledges for economic democratisation and rebound besides restoring the phrase 'Absolute trust and faith in the Almighty Allah' at the beginning of the constitution, as it was</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 02:29:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Calm comes down on poll campaigns</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/calm-comes-down-on-poll-campaigns</link><description>Calm comes down on poll campaigns, sometimes having turned vituperative, as the countdown begins for voting Thursday in post-uprising referendum and general election.
The Election Commission has banned electioneering rallies and publicity from 7:00am Tuesday (today) in the run-up to the polls, bei</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 01:30:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chittagong port tackles backlog as operations normalise</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/chittagong-port-tackles-backlog-as-operations-normalise</link><description>As operations at the Chittagong Port began in full swing on Monday morning after a bumpy week, there were 24 box ships at the jetties and outer anchorage, according to port data.
Some of these vessels faced inordinate delays in getting berth due to the work stoppage by the agitating workers centri</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 01:45:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC now allows mobile phones at polling centres</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-now-allows-mobile-phones-at-polling-centres</link><description>In the face of widespread criticism, the Bangladesh Election Commission (EC) on Monday revoked its decision to ban mobile phones at polling stations, a day after issuing a circular in this regard.
Different stakeholders, including journalists, political parties, election observers and rights organ</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 02:00:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BD-Japan EPA to boost jobs, investment, says commerce adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/bd-japan-epa-to-boost-jobs-investment-says-commerce-adviser</link><description>Bangladesh's Economic Partnership Agreement (EPA) with Japan is poised to unlock wide-ranging employment opportunities for Bangladeshi workers -- particularly in nursing and caregiving -- while attracting fresh Japanese investment into the country's expanding services sector, Commerce Adviser Sk Ba</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 02:15:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Economists warn next govt of reform test</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/economists-warn-next-govt-of-reform-test</link><description>Bangladesh's next elected government will inherit an economy that is functioning but fragile, with mounting fiscal, financial and external pressures threatening growth, investment and social stability, economists and policy experts warned on Monday.
While the interim administration has helped aver</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 02:30:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>37 polling centres in capital 'risky'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/37-polling-centres-in-capital-risky</link><description>Dhaka Metropolitan Police (DMP) Commissioner Sheikh Md Sajjat Ali said 37 polling centres in the capital are risky. Seven police personnel will be stationed at each of these centres to ensure safety and security of the voters during the election day on February 12.
"Some 37 polling centres are ris</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 02:45:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>H1 capital machinery imports drop 16.06pc to $904.59m</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/h1-capital-machinery-imports-drop-1606pc-to-90459m</link><description>Bangladesh's capital-machinery imports sustained another 16.06-percent fall in the 1st half of the current fiscal year (FY), signaling a deepening crisis in private-sector confidence and ongoing investment stagnation, according to sources.
The import value of capital machinery declined to US$904.5</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 03:00:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gross forex reserves exceed $34 billion</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/gross-forex-reserves-exceed-34-billion</link><description>Bangladesh's gross foreign exchange reserves crossed the $34 billion-mark on Monday following a higher inflow of remittances ahead of the upcoming national elections and the holy Ramadan.
Reserves rose to $34.06 billion on the day from $33.24 billion on February 2, according to the Bangladesh Bank</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 03:15:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Surayya Akhtar Jahan made DNCC administrator</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/surayya-akhtar-jahan-made-dncc-administrator-1</link><description>Surayya Akhtar Jahan has been appointed as administrator of the Dhaka North City Corporation (DNCC) after the government decided not to renew the one-year contract of Mohammad Azaz.
The appointment of Mr. Surayya, an Additional Secretary at the Local Government Division, was made through a gazette</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 03:30:48 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>