<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 15:28:38 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Mobile phone traders block Sonargaon hotel intersection in Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/mobile-phone-traders-block-sonargaon-hotel-intersection-in-dhaka</link><description>Mobile phone traders linked with the “unofficial” handset market have blocked the Pan Pacific Sonargaon hotel intersection in Dhaka.
At 6.15pm on Wednesday, Tejgaon Division Additional Deputy Commissioner Fazlul Karim said all surrounding roads had been closed to traffic because of the</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 12:00:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique Rahman stresses gaining people’s support for BNP’s win in polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-rahman-stresses-gaining-peoples-support-for-bnps-win-in-polls</link><description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman on Wednesday called on party members to intensify their efforts to win public support in the upcoming election, saying that ensuring the victory of the ‘Sheaf of Paddy’ is essential to protect the country and promote its progress through the party&amp;rsqu</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 12:15:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Remittance inflow exceeds $1.16b in 9 days of December</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/remittance-inflow-exceeds-116b-in-9-days-of-december</link><description>The strong upward trend in remittance continues as Bangladesh received more than US$1.16 billion in the first nine days of December, according to the latest data from Bangladesh Bank.
The amount marks a 22.6 percent rise from the same period last year when expatriates sent around $945 million.
Of</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 12:30:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BB allows entrepreneurs to Import Capital Machinery without BIDA’s approval</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh-bank-allows-entrepreneurs-to-import-capital-machinery-without-bidas-approval</link><description>Bangladesh Bank now allows capital machinery import in foreign credit without permission from the Bangladesh Investment Development Authority (BIDA).
Companies can now directly import necessary machinery and equipment using foreign loans with a minimum three-year term, without needing prior approv</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 12:45:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trust Bank introduces UnionPay-branded cards for global payment convenience</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/trust-bank-introduces-unionpay-branded-cards-for-global-payment-convenience</link><description>Trust Bank PLC has officially introduced UnionPay-branded cards, expanding its card portfolio and enhancing global payment convenience for customers.
The service was inaugurated by Mr. Ahsan Zaman Chowdhury, Managing Director &amp; CEO of Trust Bank PLC, at a launching ceremony attended by senior offi</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 13:00:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Supreme Court secretariat to be opened on Thursday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/supreme-court-secretariat-to-be-opened-on-thursday</link><description>Chief Justice (CJ) Syed Refaat Ahmed will inaugurate the Supreme Court Secretariat at a programme on the apex court premises on Thursday afternoon.
Md Shafiqul Islam, Public Relations Officer (PRO) of the Bangladesh Supreme Court, confirmed the matter on Wednesday.
Earlier, the government issued</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 13:15:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sumaiya Islam wins the Franco-German Award for Human Rights</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/sumaiya-islam-wins-the-franco-german-award-for-human-rights</link><description>Human rights defender and Executive Director of Bangladesh Nari Sramik Kendra (BNSK), Ms. Sumaiya Islam, has been awarded the 2025 Franco-German Award for Human Rights and the Rule of Law.
Ambassadors of France and Germany to Bangladesh, Mr. Jean-Marc Séré-Charlet and Dr. Rüdige</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 13:30:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sonali Bank holds 40th Senior Management Team meeting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/sonali-bank-holds-40th-senior-management-team-meeting</link><description>The 40th Senior Management Team (SMT) meeting of Sonali Bank PLC was held at the bank’s head office conference room on Wednesday, according to a press release.
SMT Chairman and MD &amp; CEO of Sonali Bank PLC, Md. Shawkat Ali khan presided over the meeting. Among others, Deputy Managing Director</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 13:45:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pranay Verma highlights cultural bonds linking Dhaka and Delhi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/pranay-verma-highlights-cultural-bonds-linking-dhaka-and-delhi</link><description>Highlighting the cultural interconnections between Bangladesh and India, Indian High Commissioner to Bangladesh Pranay Verma on Wednesday recalled that Deepavali is widely celebrated across Bangladesh, often alongside Kali Puja and popularly known as Shyama Puja - Deepanita Mahotsav.
These shared</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 14:00:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prime Bank customers to enjoy special offer on loan for BYD vehicles</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/prime-bank-customers-to-enjoy-special-offer-on-loan-for-byd-vehicles</link><description>Prime Bank PLC customers in Bangladesh will now enjoy an exclusive offer on loans for purchasing BYD vehicles. CG Runner BD Limited is the authorised distributor for BYD vehicles in Bangladesh.
In this regard, an agreement was signed recently at BYD Bangladesh Flagship Showroom, Tejgaon in Dhaka,</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 14:15:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two-year-old child trapped in abandoned deep well in Rajshahi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/two-year-old-child-trapped-in-abandoned-deep-well-in-rajshahi</link><description>A two-year-old boy became trapped inside an abandoned deep well in Koelhat village of Pachander Union in Tanor upazila of Rajshahi on Wednesday afternoon.
Sajid, son of Rakib, fell into the 35-feet-deep pipe while playing near his home in Koelhat Purbapara village. Locals initially tried to rescue</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 14:30:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Doubts over acceptable polls persist: Debapriya</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cpds-debapriya-says-concerns-about-credible-election-remain-despite-assurances</link><description>Debapriya Bhattacharya, fellow at the Centre for Policy Dialogue (CPD), has expressed concerns over the country’s capacity to hold a “credible and acceptable election”.
He spoke after a regional consultation organised by the Citizen Platform for SDG Implementation, Bangladesh, on</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 14:45:22 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>