<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 04:21:29 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Unnamed suspects charged over murder of Chattogram businessman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/unnamed-suspects-charged-over-murder-of-chattogram-businessman</link><description>Charges have been filed against unnamed suspects in the killing of businessman Abdul Hakim near Madunaghat Bridge in Chattogram, three days after the shooting.
Hakim’s wife Tasfia Alam Tanju, lodged the complaint at Hathazari Police Station on Friday, said Circle’s Additional Superinte</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 17:12:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Birds sang like dawn during solar eclipse: study</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/study-shows-how-solar-eclipse-made-some-birds-sing-like-a-new-day-dawned</link><description>On Apr 8, 2024, a total solar eclipse traversed a wide swathe of North America stretching 2,500 miles (4,000 km) from Mexico's Pacific Coast through Texas and across 14 other US states into Canada. The period of totality, when the moon covered the face of the sun, lasted about four minutes dependin</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 17:27:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Final farewell for Syed Manzoorul Islam at DU</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dhaka-university-to-pay-tribute-to-academic-syed-manzoorul-islam-saturday</link><description>Emeritus professor and writer Syed Manzoorul Islam will be taken to Dhaka University for a final farewell on Saturday.
Teachers, students, and well-wishers will pay their respects in front of the Aparajeyo Bangla sculpture at 10:30am, after which he will be taken to the Central Shaheed Minar at 11</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 17:57:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ganatantri leader Swapan Sen dies at 73</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ganatantri-leader-swapan-sen-dies-at-73</link><description>Swapan Sen, vice-president of the Chattogram district unit of the Ganatantri Party, has died at the age of 73.
He passed away early on Friday while undergoing treatment at Chattogram General Hospital, where he had been admitted for several days with age-related complications, said Mitul Das Gupta,</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 18:12:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New tax zones manned by few borrowed staffers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/new-tax-zones-manned-by-few-borrowed-staffers</link><description>Expanding tax nets for a must-have boost to Bangladesh's deficient revenues falters as the National Board of Revenue (NBR) appointed top officials to newly created tax zones mostly sans supporting staff.
Sources have said most of the zones have yet to receive approval for appointing support-staf</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 18:27:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Deregulated imports boosting economy, pressuring reserves</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/deregulated-imports-boosting-economy-pressuring-reserves</link><description>Bangladesh sees a significant rise in import orders, with a leap in September, in what is seen as an early indication of the country's economic rebound after months of recession.
However, officials and money-market experts sound alert as the deregulated export resurgence has a domino effect on the</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 01:54:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Japanese projects stall amid political transition</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/japanese-projects-stall-amid-political-transition</link><description>Most Japan-funded projects and investment plans in Bangladesh have lost momentum since the interim government took office, as officials admit there is little room to move things forward before a new administration is in place.
With national elections approaching, Japanese investors and development</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 02:09:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Interbank money transactions make resounding rebound with rapid rise</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/interbank-money-transactions-make-resounding-rebound-with-rapid-rise</link><description>Interbank short-term lending and borrowing on the call-money market is making a resounding rebound, with the September turnover recording a 26.6-percent month-on-month rise to Tk 1.47 trillion.
Bankers and analysts say the turnaround is taking place on the back of increasing liquidity on the money</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 02:39:01 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>