<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 06:34:33 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Tarique supports interim govt's US tariff deal, wants deeper trade ties</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-supports-interim-govts-us-tariff-deal-wants-deeper-trade-ties</link><description>Bangladesh Nationalist party (BNP) Chairman Tarique Rahman seeks to develop wider trade cooperation between Bangladesh and the United States to strengthen the bilateral ties.

The BNP leader has also lent support to the interim government- negotiated tariff agreement with the US Trump administrat</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 18:40:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ICC envoy to visit Dhaka over WC venue row</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/icc-envoy-to-visit-dhaka-as-bangladesh-holds-firm-on-world-cup-venue-stance</link><description>An International Cricket Council (ICC) representative will arrive in Dhaka on Saturday to discuss Bangladesh’s venue concerns for the T20 World Cup, marking a fresh attempt to break the deadlock over where the Tigers will play their games.
Initially, a two-member ICC delegation was expected</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 18:55:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Revenue control pushes Chittagong Port’s profit to 5-year high</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/revenue-control-pushes-chittagong-ports-profit-to-5-year-high</link><description>Chittagong Port has recorded a net profit of Tk 31.43 billion in 2025, the highest in the past five years.
Non-VAT and tax revenues contributed Tk 18.05 billion to the government treasury, also a five-year high.
Port Administration Director Md Omar Faruk said, “Since 2021, revenue has g</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 19:10:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>China hospital chains in Bangladesh, first one to be built in Nilphamari</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/china-hospital-chains-in-bangladesh-first-one-to-be-built-in-nilphamari</link><description>Modern-day China hospital chains in Bangladesh begin with a big venture in the country's far north to cater all low-cost treatments and specialised care at higher expenses, officials say.
Northern Nilphamari district is set to host the country's first high-standard, large-scale 'Bangladesh-China F</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 02:30:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Restoring macroeconomic stability rests on revenue policy upgrade</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/restoring-macroeconomic-stability-rests-on-revenue-policy-upgrade</link><description>A time-bound structural and policy rejig of the revenue system is imperative for restoring and sustaining Bangladesh's macroeconomic stability as insufficient domestic resources upend government plans and generate overall volatility.
To this end, a multi-stakeholder taskforce on revenue reform is</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 02:45:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Meeting with Jamaat chief was part of 'routine engagement,' India says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/meeting-with-jamaat-chief-was-part-of-routine-diplomatic-engagement-india-says</link><description>New Delhi has said the reported meeting between a senior Indian diplomat and Jamaat-e-Islami chief Shafiqur Rahman was part of routine diplomatic engagement, responding nearly two weeks after the issue surfaced in the media.
The Indian Ministry of External Affairs made the comment on Friday, accor</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 03:00:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Why Bangladesh's farmers lose while city consumers pay more</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/why-bangladeshs-farmers-lose-while-city-consumers-pay-more</link><description>For Foishal Rahman, a middle-aged resident of Shantinagar in Dhaka, a simple visit to the local kitchen market has become a source of profound anxiety.
"I grew up in a village where vegetables were practically free during the harvest season. Today, in Dhaka, I am paying nearly four times the price</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 04:00:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Weekly Market Review: Stocks back in red amid selling pressure</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/weekly-market-review-stocks-back-in-red-amid-selling-pressure</link><description>The benchmark equity index ended the week in negative territory, snapping a three-week winning streak as market sentiment turned cautious amid mounting concerns over the ongoing domestic gas crisis and escalating geopolitical tensions.
Analysts pointed out that the market recovery, which had been</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 05:00:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump names Rubio, Tony Blair, Kushner to Gaza 'Board of Peace'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-names-rubio-tony-blair-kushner-to-gaza-board-of-peace-under-trumps-plan</link><description>The White House on Friday announced some members of a so-called "Board of Peace" that is to supervise the temporary governance of Gaza, which has been under a fragile ceasefire since October.
The names include US Secretary of State Marco Rubio, President Donald Trump's special envoy Steve Witkoff,</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 05:41:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two die as three buses collide on Dhaka-Sylhet highway</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/two-die-as-three-buses-collide-on-dhaka-sylhet-highway</link><description>Two people were killed and ten others injured a triangular collision among three buses on the Dhaka-Sylhet highway in Osmaninagar upazila of Sylhet district on Saturday.
The identities of the deceased could not be confirmed immediately, according to a UNB report.
The accident occurred around 7:00</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 05:56:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EU observers see no need for security alerts during Bangladesh elections</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/eu-observers-see-no-need-for-security-alerts-during-bangladesh-elections</link><description>The European Union Election Observation Mission has said that it does not anticipate issuing any security alerts during its monitoring of Bangladesh’s parliamentary election.
Speaking at a media briefing in Dhaka on Saturday, Inta Lase, the mission’s deputy chief observer, said the EU</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 06:11:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump threatens new tariffs on countries opposing Greenland takeover</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-threatens-new-tariffs-on-countries-opposing-greenland-takeover</link><description>US President Donald Trump has threatened to place tariffs on nations that do not go along with his ambitions to annex Greenland, the BBC reports.
Trump said at a White House meeting on Friday that he "may put a tariff on countries if they don't go along with Greenland", which is a self-governing t</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 06:26:05 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>