<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 17:24:44 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Month-long awareness campaign on road safety begins</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/month-long-awareness-campaign-on-road-safety-begins</link><description>A month-long road safety awareness campaign has begun in Dhaka to increase public awareness and thus prevent road accidents and reduce the number of accidental casualties. 
The campaign is being conducted by Swift Solution, a private organisation that has been working on road safety for a lon</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 14:56:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladeshi among 3 killed, 58 injured in UAE as Iranian attacks continue</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladeshi-among-3-killed-58-injured-in-uae-as-iranian-attacks-continue</link><description>Three people, including a Bangladeshi national, were killed and 58 others injured in the United Arab Emirates since the launch of Iranian attacks on February 28, the UAE Ministry of Defence said.
The casualties include individuals of Emirati, Egyptian, Ethiopian, Filipino, Pakistani, Iranian, Indi</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 15:11:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pakistani PM visit to Russia has been postponed, TASS reports</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/pakistani-pm-visit-to-russia-has-been-postponed-tass-reports</link><description>Pakistan’s Prime Minister Shehbaz Sharif’s visit to Russia, initially scheduled for Mar 3-5, has been postponed due to the “current regional situation”, Russian state news agency TASS reported on Sunday, citing an unnamed source.
It said the dates of the visit will be agree</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 14:59:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dubai gold flows curbed as flights halted due to US-Israeli strikes on Iran</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/dubai-gold-flows-curbed-as-flights-halted-due-to-us-israeli-strikes-on-iran</link><description>Physical gold flows to and from Dubai’s bullion trading hub will be severely curbed in coming days as airlines cancel flights due to US and Israeli strikes on Iran and Tehran’s retaliation, three metals industry sources said.
Dubai’s trading hub is a major gold supplier to Switze</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 15:14:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Man burnt in Cox’s Bazar gas pump explosion dies in Dhaka hospital</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/man-burnt-in-coxs-bazar-gas-pump-explosion-dies-in-dhaka-hospital</link><description>A CNG-run autorickshaw driver, who was critically injured in a gas pump explosion in Cox’s Bazar’s Kolatali, has succumbed to his injuries while undergoing treatment at the National Institute of Burn and Plastic Surgery in Dhaka.
The victim, identified as Abu Taher, breathed his last a</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 15:29:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat condemns Khamenei’s killing, holds protest rally in Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jamaat-condemns-khameneis-killing-holds-protest-rally-in-dhaka</link><description>Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami on Sunday held a rally protesting a heinous attack on Iran by the United States and Israel and the assassination of Iran’s Supreme Leader, Ayatollah Ali Khamenei.
The rally began at 3:00 pm at the north gate of Baitul Mukarram National Mosque.
Thousands of leaders</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 15:44:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Expat Bangladeshi Hajj pilgrims advised for health check-ups, vaccination</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/expat-bangladeshi-hajj-pilgrims-advised-for-health-check-ups-vaccination</link><description>The Ministry of Religious Affairs has issued directives regarding health check-ups and vaccination for registered expatriate Bangladeshi Hajj pilgrims for the 2026 Hajj.
For ensuring smooth Hajj management, registered expatriate Bangladeshi pilgrims intending to perform Hajj in 2026 must undergo t</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 15:59:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pakistan high commissioner meets Home Minister Salahuddin Ahmed</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/pakistan-high-commissioner-meets-home-minister-salahuddin-ahmed</link><description>Pakistan High Commissioner Imran Haider has met Home Minister Salahuddin Ahmed on the same day as the Indian envoy’s visit.
Indian High Commissioner Pranay Verma held talks with the minister at the home ministry on Sunday morning, and Imran met him at his office in the afternoon.
An evening</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 16:14:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gulshan, Mirpur, and Lalbagh get new DCs in DMP shake-up</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/gulshan-mirpur-and-lalbagh-get-new-dcs-in-dmp-shake-up</link><description>The Dhaka Metropolitan Police (DMP) has reshuffled the responsibilities of four officers with the rank of deputy commissioner.
Acting DMP Commissioner Md Sarwar issued an order to this effect on Sunday.
This marks the first internal shake-up in the DMP leadership since the newly elected governmen</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 16:29:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh may see heatwaves, Kalbaishakhi storms by late March</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/bangladesh-may-see-heatwaves-kalbaishakhi-storms-by-late-march</link><description>Bangladesh is likely to experience its first heatwaves of the year in late March, coupled with the threat of severe nor'westers, commonly known as Kalbaishakhi storms.
The Bangladesh Meteorological Department (BMD) on Sunday forecast that one or two mild to moderate heatwaves might sweep over the</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 16:44:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Power supply to remain suspended in parts of Sylhet Monday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/power-supply-to-remain-suspended-in-parts-of-sylhet-monday</link><description>Power supply will remain suspended in various areas of Sylhet from 6:15 am to 11:00 am on Monday (March 2) due to reconductoring work on a transmission line.
Bangladesh Power Development Board (BPDB), Sylhet Sales and Distribution Division-3, disclosed the information on Sunday.
According to the</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 16:59:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No room for corrupt officials in Housing Ministry: Minister</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/no-room-for-corrupt-officials-in-housing-ministry-minister-zakaria-taher-sumon</link><description>Housing and Public Works Minister Zakaria Taher Sumon on Sunday warned that there is no room for corrupt officials in his ministry.
“The proper use of people’s tax money must be ensured, and development work must be completed within the stipulated time while maintaining quality standar</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 17:14:53 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>