<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 09:23:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Elon Musk's $1 trillion Tesla pay plan wins shareholder approval</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/elon-musks-1-trillion-tesla-pay-plan-wins-shareholder-approval</link><description>Tesla CEO Elon Musk won shareholder approval on Thursday for the largest corporate pay package in history as investors endorsed his vision of morphing the EV maker into an AI and robotics juggernaut.
The proposal was approved with over 75 per cent support, and Musk bounded to the stage of the comp</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 06:06:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AEB holds discussion on National Revolution and Solidarity Day</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/aeb-holds-discussion-on-national-revolution-and-solidarity-day</link><description>The Association of Engineers, Bangladesh (AEB), the country’s sole professional platform for nationalist-minded engineers, organised a discussion marking National Revolution and Solidarity Day 2025 on Thursday evening at the Institution of Engineers, Bangladesh (IEB) auditorium in Dhaka, acco</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 06:21:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BCB forms probe panel after harassment claims by Jahanara Alam</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/bcb-forms-probe-panel-after-harassment-claims-by-jahanara-alam</link><description>The Bangladesh Cricket Board (BCB) has announced the formation of an investigation committee after former national women’s team captain Jahanara Alam alleged that she faced sexual harassment and psychological abuse from members of the team management during the 2022 ICC Women’s World Cu</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 06:36:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Flights delayed at Delhi airport after technical glitch</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/flights-delayed-at-delhi-airport-after-technical-glitch</link><description>Aircraft movement at Delhi airport was hampered on Friday because its Air Traffic Control system suffered a technical problem, the Airports Authority of India (AAI) said after several flights were disrupted at one of the world's busiest airports.
Top airlines IndiGo, Air India and Spicejet said th</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 06:51:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Case filed over murder of ‘BNP activist’ Sarwar in Ctg shooting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/case-filed-over-murder-of-bnp-activist-sarwar-in-chattogram-shooting</link><description>The family of Sarwar Hossain Babla, who was shot and killed during a BNP event in Chattogram, has filed a case over his murder.
Seven suspects have been named in the case filed by Sarwar’s father Abdul Quader on Friday, said Jashim Uddin, the chief of Bayezid Bostami Police Station.
Two of</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 07:06:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Authorities urge calm after fire report near Rooppur nuclear plant</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/authorities-urge-calm-after-fire-report-near-rooppur-nuclear-plant</link><description>Officials from the Rooppur Nuclear Power Plant Project have urged the public not to be misled by misinformation or rumours surrounding a recent fire that broke out near the plant in Pabna.
In a statement issued on Thursday night, Saikat Ahmed, senior scientific information officer for the plant's</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 07:21:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Army warns of legal action over false social media posts on Gazipur arrests</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/army-warns-of-legal-action-over-false-social-media-posts-on-gazipur-arrests</link><description>Bangladesh Army has warned that legal action would be taken against those spreading false or misleading information about the arrests of seven people, including a former Jatiyatabadi Chhatra Dal (JCD) leader of Sreepur upazila in Gazipur district, on social media.
At a press briefing on Friday mor</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 07:15:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fire destroys 15 shops in Lakshmipur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/fire-destroys-15-shops-in-lakshmipur</link><description>Fifteen shops have been destroyed in a fire in Lakshmipur’s Ramgati Upazila.
The blaze broke out in a market in the Alexander Bazar area early on Friday morning, according to Khokon Majudar, station officer of the Ramgati Fire Service.
Locals said the fire originated from an electrical shor</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 07:30:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Conspiracy brewing to shatter democracy again after mass uprising: Fakhrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/conspiracy-brewing-to-shatter-democracy-again-after-mass-uprising-fakhrul</link><description>A conspiracy is being hatched to subvert democracy in Bangladesh again after the July Uprising, says BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir.
He remarked while speaking to the media after laying wreaths at the grave of former president and BNP founder Ziaur Rahman in Dhaka's Sher-e-Bangl</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 07:45:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Attorney general says he can contest polls while in office</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/attorney-general-says-he-can-contest-polls-while-in-office</link><description>Attorney General Md Asaduzzaman has said there is no legal barrier to his participation in the upcoming national elections while holding his current post, arguing that the country's top law officer is not a government employee under the Constitution.
Speaking to reporters at his office on Thursday</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 08:00:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>'Fraudster' held over cheating businessman out of Tk 1.5m</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/fraudster-held-over-cheating-businessman-out-of-tk-15m</link><description>Police have arrested an individual linked with a fraud gang for allegedly swindling a businessman out of Tk 1.5 million.
The name of the arrestee is Md Saddam Hossain (35).
He was arrested by the Cyber Police Centre (CPC) unit of Criminal Investigation Department (CID) from South Keraniganj's Has</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 08:15:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Primary teachers to stage nonstop sit-in from Saturday for pay bump</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/primary-teachers-to-stage-nonstop-sit-in-from-saturday-for-pay-bump</link><description>Assistant teachers of government primary schools are set to launch a fresh protest programme, demanding that their salaries be raised to the 10th grade pay scale and to press for long-pending promotions.
On Saturday, they plan to begin a "continuous" sit-in at Dhaka’s Central Shaheed Minar,</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 08:30:10 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>