<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 23:21:50 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nobel Peace Prize winner Machado vows to bring award back to Venezuela</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/nobel-peace-prize-winner-machado-vows-to-bring-award-back-to-venezuela</link><description>Nobel Peace Prize laureate Maria Corina Machado said she planned to take her award back to Venezuela, but declined to say on Thursday when she would return to her home country after leaving in great secrecy to receive the honour.
Venezuelan opposition leader Machado arrived in Oslo in the ea</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 16:45:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two-year-old dies after 32-hour rescue from pit in Rajshahi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/two-year-old-dies-after-32-hour-rescue-from-pit-in-rajshahi</link><description>A two-year-old boy who was pulled from a deep pit after a 32-hour rescue operation in Rajshahi’s Tanore upazila has died, officials said.
Fire Service Director (Operation and Maintenance) Lieutenant Colonel Mohammad Tajul Islam said doctors at the Tanore Upazila Health Complex declared the c</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 17:00:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Financing a green revolution in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/financing-a-green-revolution-in-bangladesh</link><description>A new-world order—one described by increasing numbers of economists as the climate economy—is arising. Rather than being fueled by smoke and coal, it will be propelled by clean energies, climate-resilient infrastructure, clean technologies, and sustainable finance. In reaction to global</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 16:45:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Legendary singers &amp; musicians of Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/reviews/legendary-singers-musicians-of-bangladesh</link><description>In early 1940s, the folk song composer and singer Abbas Uddin Ahmed (1901-59) met a young man named Hemanta Mukherjee (1920-89) at a Kolkata radio station.  After listening to him singing, Abbas praised Hemanta profusely. “Please bless me,” Hemanta beseeched him.  Abbas’</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 17:00:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Why cruelty to animals keeps repeating</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/why-cruelty-to-animals-keeps-repeating</link><description>A recent incident of allegedly killing eight newborn puppies by stuffing them in a sack and drowning them in a pond by a woman in Pabna has once again exposed a harsh reality about the treatment of animals in Bangladesh. Our society has a longstanding problem with cruelty to animals but our legal s</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 17:15:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>When food hygiene is not a priority</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/when-food-hygiene-is-not-a-priority</link><description>A high-level meeting chaired by Chief Adviser Muhammad Yunus and held at the state guest house Jamuna on Sunday last emphasised the need for making foods safe for consumption. Indeed, food safety is a much neglected issue in this country. Admittedly, the burgeoning food production was impossible wi</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 17:30:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A new chapter for  judiciary</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/a-new-chapter-for-judiciary</link><description>Bangladesh's judiciary is poised to enter a new era of institutional independence and operational efficiency with the promulgation of the Supreme Court Secretariat Ordinance 2025-a long-anticipated reform that grants the Supreme Court financial and administrative autonomy. This landmark measure fun</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 17:45:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khaleda under close monitoring: medical board</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/medical-board-says-khaleda-zia-is-being-treated-under-intensive-observation</link><description>BNP chief Khaleda Zia remains under intensive observation in the Critical Care Unit of Dhaka’s Evercare Hospital, her medical board has said.
A bulletin signed by board head Dr Shahabuddin Talukder outlined the latest assessment of Khaleda’s condition on Thursday.
The board said, &amp;ldq</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 18:21:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Desperate Gazans pull iron bars from rubble to construct tents and scratch out a living</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/desperate-gazans-pull-iron-bars-from-rubble-to-construct-tents-and-scratch-out-a-living</link><description>As winter bites in Gaza, displaced Palestinians set out every day to homes destroyed by Israel. There they rip out iron rods from the walls and use them to prop up their flimsy tents or sell to scratch out a living in an enclave that will take years to recover from war.
The rods have become a ho</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 18:36:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Election 2026: 3 EC officials appointed as returning officers for first time</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/election-2026-3-ec-officials-appointed-as-returning-officers-for-first-time</link><description>For the first time in the country’s parliamentary election history, the Election Commission (EC) appointed three of its own officials, along with two divisional commissioners and 64 district deputy commissioners (DCs), as returning officers for the February 12 election and referendum.
Accord</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 18:51:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Economic stability remains under threat without bank resolution regime: Experts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/economic-stability-remains-under-threat-without-bank-resolution-regime-experts-at-a-seminar</link><description>Speakers and policy makers in a seminar on Thursday warned that Bangladesh's economic stability remains severely threatened without the immediate establishment of a credible bank resolution regime.
The warning was issued from a seminar hosted by the Policy Research Institute of Bangladesh (PRI), w</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 19:06:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Election, referendum on Feb 12</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/election-referendum-on-feb-12</link><description>Bangladesh gets in the process of democratic transition from the post-uprising interregnum with the rollout of poll schedule Thursday for general election and reform referendum to be held on February 12 next. Political parties active through the 5th-August 2024 student-mass uprising instantly wel</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 19:21:30 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>