<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 21:20:46 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Al-Arafah Islami Bank holds 30th AGM</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/al-arafah-islami-bank-holds-30th-agm</link><description>The 30th Annual General Meeting (AGM) of Al-Arafah Islami Bank was held virtually on Wednesday, November 12, 2025, at the Bank’s Head Office.
Chairman of the Bank Khwaja Shahriar presided over the meeting, according to a press release.
The meeting was attended by Board Directors Md. Shahin</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 15:53:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bus catches fire at Mawa expressway entrance</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bus-catches-fire-at-mawa-expressway-entrance</link><description>A bus has caught fire on the road at the Dolaipar Para entrance to the Mawa expressway in Dhaka.
Firefighters rushed to the scene after receiving the alert and brought the flames under control.
Rozina Akter, duty officer at the Fire Service control room, said two units were dispatched at 6:38 pm</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 16:08:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>37 killed in Peru road crash</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/37-killed-in-peru-road-crash</link><description>At least 37 people were killed and dozens injured after a bus plunged into a ravine in the Arequipa region of southern Peru, local authorities said on Wednesday.
The fatalities included 36 people who died on site, and another person who died in hospital, said Walther Oporto, Arequipa's regional he</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 16:23:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Orbis’s VR simulator installed at Ispahani Eye Hospital</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/orbiss-vr-simulator-installed-at-ispahani-eye-hospital</link><description>A fundamental virtual reality (VR) simulation system was installed at Ispahani Islamia Eye Institute and Hospital (IIEI&amp;amp;H) in Dhaka on Wednesday.
The VR simulation system has been installed at the hospital to provide eye surgeons with realistic, hands-on training aimed at enhancing their cataract</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 16:23:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Man hurt in cocktail blasts at DU's TSC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/man-hurt-in-cocktail-blasts-at-dus-tsc</link><description>A man was injured following cocktail explosions at the Teacher-Student Centre (TSC) of Dhaka University on Wednesday night.
The identity of the injured person could not be confirmed immediately.
A journalist’s motorcycle parked nearby was also partially damaged, reports UNB.
The blasts, re</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 16:38:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Passenger bus catches fire at Dhaka's Dholaipar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/passenger-bus-catches-fire-at-dhakas-dholaipar</link><description>A passenger bus caught fire at Dholaipar intersection in Dhaka  on Wednesday evening.
The fire broke out around 6:38 pm, according to fire service officials.
Upon receiving the report, two units from the Postogola Fire Station rushed to the spot and brought the blaze under control within abo</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 16:53:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Train catches fire at Tejgaon Railway Station</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/train-catches-fire-at-tejgaon-railway-station</link><description>A stationary train has caught fire at Tejgaon Railway Station in Dhaka.
Dhaka Railway Police Station chief Zainal Abedin said the incident occurred around 9:30 pm on Wednesday.
“No one was injured in the fire,” he confirmed.
A video circulating on social media shows flames engulfing</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 17:08:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Evaly owners sentenced to five years in prison</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/evaly-owners-sentenced-to-five-years-in-prison</link><description>A Dhaka court has sentenced Mohammad Rassel, managing director of the e-commerce company Evaly, and his wife, the company’s Chairman Shamima Nasrin, to five more years in prison in a fraud case.
Additional Chief Metropolitan Magistrate Md Zakir Hossain delivered the verdict on Wednesday, rep</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 17:23:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Helping citizens share responsibility for democratic climate adaptation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/helping-citizens-share-responsibility-for-democratic-climate-adaptation</link><description>Climate change is not only an environmental or scientific problem; it is fundamentally a social, ethical, and political challenge. Dr Chloe Lucas, an environmental social scientist at the University of Tasmania, approaches this complexity through her pioneering project titled "Helping Citizens Shar</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 17:54:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tackling water scarcity in Barind tracts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/tackling-water-scarcity-in-barind-tracts</link><description>That ground water table is falling dangerously low is a major worry for the country. This has been going on over the last few decades and experts have been repeatedly sounding alarms. Over-extraction to meet the growing need of an increasing population is the obvious reason. Some of the extracted w</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 18:09:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Beyond Bangladesh's graduation from LDC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/beyond-bangladeshs-graduation-from-ldc</link><description>At a time when a high-level United Nations (UN) team arrives in Dhaka to discuss Bangladesh's progress for graduation from its least developed country (LDC) status to a developing nation, Japan brings off a tariff reform allowing continuation of the generalised system of preference (GSP) for the ne</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 18:24:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Danish shipping giant Maersk outfit signing $550m deal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/danish-shipping-giant-maersk-outfit-signing-550m-deal</link><description>Danish shipping giant Maersk is set to take charge of developing and operating Bangladesh's Laldia Container Terminal (LCT) in Chattogram under a US$550-million deal through its one subsidiary, opening avenues for enhancing foreign investment, officials say.



An official announcement was made</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 20:27:04 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>