<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 19:16:32 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Dhaka Metro link briefly suspended after drone falls on tracks in Uttara</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dhaka-metro-link-briefly-suspended-after-drone-falls-on-tracks-in-uttara</link><description>Metro rail services have temporarily been suspended after a drone was found on the tracks between Uttara Centre and Uttara South stations.
According to authorities, train operations were halted from 8:47pm to 8:56pm on Saturday, lasting nine minutes.
Md Ahsan Ullah Sharifi, deputy project directo</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 15:46:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Israeli airstrikes kill 14 people in Gaza, medics say</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/israeli-airstrikes-kill-14-people-in-gaza-medics-say</link><description>Israeli airstrikes in Gaza killed at least 14 people and wounded several others, local health authorities said on Saturday, in a further test of a fragile ceasefire between the Palestinian militant group Hamas and Israel.
Witnesses and medics said the first attack hit a car in the densely populate</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 16:01:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Stock market rebounds as DSEX gains 166 points, rises 1.2 per cent over week</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/stock-market-rebounds-as-dsex-gains-166-points-rises-12-per-cent-over-week</link><description>After two consecutive weeks of decline, the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) showed signs of recovery last week, with the benchmark DSEX index rising 166 points and average daily turnover increasing over 12 per cent.
Analysis of DSE’s weekly report shows the index started the week at 4,702 points</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 16:16:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP will review telecom, all other policies if voted to power: Khosru</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bnp-will-review-telecom-all-other-policies-if-voted-to-power-khosru</link><description>BNP standing committee member Amir Khosru Mahmud Chowdhury on Saturday said if elected, BNP will review all policies including those related to the telecommunications sector.
“As telecom policy is critical, it must be formulated with the opinions of stakeholders. The type of licenses issued</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 16:31:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ministers used to visit me in prison, ex-minister Babar says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ministers-used-to-visit-me-in-prison-ex-minister-babar-says</link><description>Former home minister Lutfozzaman Babar has claimed Awami League ministers used to visit him while he was in prison.
At a rally in Netrokona’s Mohanganj on Saturday, he claimed he endured 17 and a half years in jail on “false” cases, receiving three death sentences and three lif</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 16:46:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Man in ‘critical condition’ after being shot in Dhaka's Kadamtali</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/man-in-critical-condition-after-being-shot-in-dhakas-kadamtali</link><description>A man has been shot at Dhaka’s Kadamtali and left in a “critical condition”.
Around 6:15pm on Saturday, Md Shahin, 31, was rushed to Dhaka Medical College Hospital (DMCH) after being shot in Jurain Chairman Bari locality, police said.
Shahin works at a furniture shop in the area</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 17:01:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DU shuts for 15 days amid quake panic</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/dhaka-university-announces-15-day-closure-as-tremor-fears-grip-students</link><description>Dhaka University has declared a 15-day closure as concerns mount over students’ safety following repeated tremors.
Prof M Jahangir Alam Chowdhury, the university’s treasurer, told bdnews24.com after a Syndicate meeting on Saturday night that students must leave their residential halls</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 17:16:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Reforming Bangladesh's banking sector - piecemeal or holistic approach?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/reforming-bangladeshs-banking-sector-piecemeal-or-holistic-approach</link><description>Haradhan Sarker
 
Bangladesh Bank (BB) in the current regime of the interim government is committed to reforming the banking sector. It   is  a  long-awaited  requirement to  streamline  the  banking system of  the  country, and fortunately,</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 17:31:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ensuring  structural integrity of city buildings</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/ensuring-structural-integrity-of-city-buildings</link><description>The writing has long been on the wall that a powerful earthquake is quite likely any time. Friday's 5.7-magnitude tremor, with its epicentre in Narsingdi, sent a powerful jolt through Dhaka and surrounding areas. Many described the frightening shock as unprecedented in their memory, as buildings sw</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 17:46:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Restoring stability in the banking sector</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/restoring-stability-in-the-banking-sector</link><description>The financial sector in Bangladesh is at a crossroads now amid the interim government's hectic efforts towards widespread redressal of irregularities, which has been long overdue. The task is challenging, and there is no quick fix for the problems created, deliberately or otherwise, by the previous</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 18:01:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Now IMED finds Savar leather park faultlines</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/now-imed-finds-savar-leather-park-faultlines</link><description>A government watchdog has dug out an epitome of operational, environmental, and governance "failures" in a vital project that continue to undermine Bangladesh's leather sector and its global competitiveness, thereby causing the country to miss millions in foreign exchange.



On such a discover</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 18:16:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Police should act to combat violent crime</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/police-should-act-to-combat-violent-crime</link><description>Miscreants gunned down a political worker reportedly belonging to the youth wing of the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP), named Golam Kibria, on Monday (November 17) evening from Pallabi area in the city, unchallenged either by the watching public or any law-enforcer.  Evidently, this</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 18:31:50 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>