<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 07:19:46 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Mexico plans to build Latin America’s most powerful supercomputer</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/mexico-plans-to-build-latin-americas-most-powerful-supercomputer</link><description>Mexico has announced plans to construct what it says will be Latin America’s most powerful supercomputer, aiming to boost the country’s artificial intelligence capabilities and vastly expand its data processing capacity.
The supercomputer, named “Coatlicue” after</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 04:25:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sylhet's rail link with Dhaka, Ctg restored after four hours</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/sylhets-rail-link-with-dhaka-ctg-restored-after-four-hours</link><description>Rail communication between Sylhet and the rest of the country resumed four hours after a wagon of an oil-laden freight train derailed in Mallikpur area of Fenchuganj upazila on Saturday night.
According to railway officials, a wagon of freight train No. 952 went off the tracks around 9:30 pm, snap</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 04:40:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US State Department stops processing visas for Afghan allies</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/us-state-department-stops-processing-visas-for-afghan-allies</link><description>US President Donald Trump’s administration has ordered its diplomats worldwide to stop processing visas for Afghan nationals, according to a State Department cable seen by Reuters, effectively suspending the special immigration program for Afghans who helped the United States during its 20-ye</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 04:55:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Premier Division Chess League to begin Wednesday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/premier-division-chess-league-to-begin-wednesday</link><description>The Premier Division Chess League will begin on Wednesday at the Bangladesh Chess Federation (BCF) hall in Dhaka.
Ahead of the league, the number draw of the participating teams will be held on Tuesday at the venue.
A total of twelve teams are participating in the League, organised by BCF, report</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 05:10:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Telescope in Chile captures stunning new picture of a cosmic butterfly</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/telescope-in-chile-captures-stunning-new-picture-of-a-cosmic-butterfly</link><description>A telescope in Chile has captured a breathtaking new image of a planetary nebula that resembles a graceful cosmic butterfly. The stunning picture, released by the National Science Foundation’s NOIRLab on Wednesday, was taken last month by the Gemini South telescope.
The nebula, officially kn</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 05:25:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Four shot dead at birthday party in California</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/four-shot-dead-at-birthday-party-in-california</link><description>Four people died after 14 people were shot at a family gathering in Stockton city in northern California on Saturday night, police said.
The shooting took place at a child's birthday party, Stockton's Vice Mayor Jason Lee said in a Facebook post.
"I am in contact with staff and public safety offi</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 05:40:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladeshi dies after UAE road crash</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladeshi-dies-after-uae-road-crash</link><description>A Bangladeshi migrant has died in the United Arab Emirates, 10 days after being critically injured in a road accident while delivering food.
Rubel Ahmed, 35, from Sylhet's Moglabazar, died on Friday night at Abu Dhabi's Mafraq Hospital, where he had been in intensive care since the collision, acco</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 05:45:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Maritime ports asked to keep hoisted signal No 2</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/maritime-ports-asked-to-keep-hoisted-signal-no-2</link><description>Maritime ports of Chattogram, Cox's Bazar, Mongla and Payra have been advised to keep hoisted distant warning signal No 2 as the cyclonic storm ‘Ditwah’ over the southwest Bay of Bengal and adjoining coastal Sri Lanka moved northwards over the southwest Bay of Bengal and adjoining Tamil</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 06:00:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two killed as bus rams motorcycle in Jashore</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/two-killed-as-bus-rams-motorcycle-in-jashore</link><description>Two motorcyclists were killed after a bus hit their motorcycle on Saturday night while they were on their way to visit a patient at Jashore General Hospital.
The accident occurred around 8:00 pm at Jagahati area on the Jashore-Chaugachha road, reports BSS.
The deceased were identified as Selim Ho</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 06:15:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Factory worker killed after being hit by train in Ctg</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/factory-worker-killed-after-being-hit-by-train-in-ctg</link><description>A factory worker was killed after being hit by a train in Mirsarai upazila of Chattogram on Saturday evening.
The accident occurred around 7:00 pm at the Chinki Astana Railway Station area on the Dhaka-bound track of the Dhaka-Chattogram rail line.
The deceased was identified as Tutul Kanti Dhar,</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 06:30:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Stocks edge up in early trading</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/stocks-edge-up-in-early-trading15983</link><description>The country’s bourses saw a positive start on Sunday as key indices in both Dhaka and Chattogram moved up during the first hour of trading, with most companies posting gains.
At the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE), the benchmark DSEX index rose by 3 points in early trading.
While the Shariah-bas</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 06:45:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Burnt body of woman found at roadside in Ctg</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/burnt-body-of-woman-found-at-roadside-in-ctg</link><description>Police have recovered the burnt body of an unidentified woman from the side of a road in Chattogram's Sitakunda.
The incident took place on Saturday night in the Abdullahghata area, close to the Dhaka–Chattogram Highway.
Police said that the initial accounts from witnesses suggest the woman</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 07:00:47 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>