<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 22:22:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Tarique Rahman to return to country on December 25</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-rahman-to-return-to-country-on-december-25</link><description>BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir has said Tarique Rahman, the acting chairman of the party, will return to the country from the United Kingdom on December 25.
The BNP leader gave the information at a press conference after a meeting of the party’s highest policy-making body,</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 15:59:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Climate Justice Assembly to be held in Dhaka on Dec 13-14</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/climate-justice-assembly-to-be-held-in-dhaka-on-dec-13-14</link><description>Organisers of the Climate Justice Assembly, scheduled for Dec 13-14, briefed reporters at a press conference at the National Press Club in Dhaka.
They talked about the main modalities of the two-day event and answered questions from journalists.
Among those who spoke were Md Shamsuddoha, chief ex</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 16:14:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scores of migrants cross into Poland through hidden Belarus border tunnel</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/scores-of-migrants-cross-into-poland-through-hidden-belarus-border-tunnel</link><description>More than 180 migrants crossed into Poland through a tunnel hidden in a forest on the border with Belarus, frontier guards said on Friday.
Around 130 of them were detained in Poland after the passage was discovered on Thursday, but the rest were still on the run, the Polish Border Guard said in a</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 16:29:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hadi in ‘very critical’ condition after bullet causes massive brain injury: doctor</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hadis-condition-very-critical-after-bullet-causes-massive-brain-injury-doctor-says-there-is-fight-in-him</link><description>Sharif Osman Hadi, spokesman of the Inquilab Mancha who is running as an independent candidate for Dhaka-8 at the 13th parliamentary election, remains in critical condition after being shot from close range in Bijoynagar, Dhaka soon after Jumma prayers on Friday.
Hadi was immediately taken to Dhak</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 17:43:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh's poverty reversal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/bangladeshs-poverty-reversal</link><description>As Bangladesh approaches the end of 2025, the country faces one of its most serious socio-economic crises in decades. The decades-long trajectory of steady growth and poverty reduction is now under threat. Economic slowdown, rampant inflation, political instability, and climate-related shocks are c</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 17:58:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Intellectual dishonesty distorts history</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/intellectual-dishonesty-distorts-history</link><description>December is a time for the Bangladeshis to reflect on the sacrifices and achievements made during the war of liberation. Fifty-five years ago, Bangladesh was first recognised as an independent country. Bhutan recognised Bangladesh on December 6, 1971, and India did the same the next day. Two days b</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 18:13:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Deconstructing the viral confrontation at MMCH</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/deconstructing-the-viral-confrontation-at-mmch</link><description>A causality department in-charge at Mymensingh Medical College Hospital did last Saturday what almost no one does these days. When the Director General (DG) of the Directorate General of Health Services (DGHS) visited his operation theatre, he publicly challenged the DG over missing a three-day tra</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 18:28:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Creating oversight body to prevent custodial torture</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/creating-oversight-body-to-prevent-custodial-torture</link><description>Given the long history of torture and even deaths of detainees in police custody, the creation of an independent oversight mechanism to prevent such serious human rights abuse has been long overdue. Especially, with the nightmarish experience of gratuitous murders in police custody and establishmen</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 18:43:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Doctor believes bullet exited through Hadi’s skull</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/doctor-believes-bullet-exited-through-hadis-skull</link><description>Doctors at Dhaka Medical College Hospital say the bullet that struck Sharif Osman bin Hadi may have passed clean through his skull.
Zahid Raihan, the neurosurgeon who operated on him, says Hadi is in “extremely critical” condition and that they are unable to offer any hopeful updates.</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 18:58:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Yunus calls Hadi’s brother, pledges ‘full’ government backing</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/yunus-calls-hadis-brother-pledges-full-government-backing</link><description>Chief Advisor Muhammad Yunus has spoken by phone with Omar bin Hadi, brother of Sharif Osman bin Hadi, the spokesman of Inquilab Mancha and a potential independent candidate for Dhaka-8 who was shot earlier in the day.
The interim prime minister contacted him at 9pm on Friday, expressing concern o</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 19:13:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DUCSU protests shooting of Osman Hadi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/ducsu-protests-shooting-of-osman-hadi</link><description>The Dhaka University Central Students’ Union (DUCSU) staged a protest march today evening condemning the shooting of Inqilab Mancha spokesperson and aspiring independent candidate for Dhaka-8 constituency, Sharif Osman Hadi, who was critically injured after armed assailants opened fire on him</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 19:28:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Power div seeks extra fund in revised budget</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/power-div-seeks-extra-fund-in-revised-budget</link><description>Additional budgetary allocations have been sought for public entities under different ministries to enable them to pay off electricity-bill arrears as they owe a hefty amount to the power-distribution companies.
Sources say the Power Division has requested the Ministry of Finance to make additiona</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 19:43:48 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>