<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 01:41:52 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Gold price sees year's steepest drop after 8 consecutive hikes</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/gold-price-sees-years-steepest-drop-after-8-consecutive-hikes</link><description>After eight consecutive price hikes, the Bangladesh Jewellers Association (BAJUS) has slashed gold prices by over Tk 8,000 per bhori, marking the steepest single-day drop of the year.
According to a BAJUS press release issued Wednesday night, the price of 22-carat gold has been reduced by Tk 8,386</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 16:22:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Israel must allow UN relief agency to supply aid to Gaza: ICJ</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/israel-must-allow-un-relief-agency-to-supply-aid-to-gaza-icj</link><description>The International Court of Justice said on Wednesday that Israel must allow the U.N. aid agency in Gaza, known as UNRWA, to provide humanitarian assistance to the Palestinian territory.
The U.N. General Assembly had requested the Hague-based court last year to clarify Israel’s legal responsi</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 16:08:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Referendum must come first: Jamaat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jamaat-calls-for-referendum-before-polls-accuses-bnp-of-creating-complications</link><description>The Jamaat-e-Islami has urged Chief Advisor Muhammad Yunus to hold the referendum by late November without falling into the BNP’s “traps”.
Speaking on Wednesday evening after a meeting with Yunus at the State Guest House Jamuna, the party’s deputy chief Syed Abdullah Muhamm</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 16:38:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tainted plates, unequal lives</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/tainted-plates-unequal-lives</link><description>Food adulteration in Bangladesh has evolved into one of the country's most alarming public health and governance crises-an issue that cuts across class lines but disproportionately punishes the poor. It is no longer just a question of hygiene or regulation; it has become a sociological symptom of d</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 17:08:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Restoring trust in BBS data</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/restoring-trust-in-bbs-data</link><description>The Bangladesh Bureau of Statistics (BBS) has long been facing a crisis of credibility regarding the accuracy and reliability of its data. For various reasons, the public cannot help but take the state-owned agency's data with a grain of salt. The latest blow to the BBS's credibility came when a se</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 17:23:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Independence of national statistical body</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/independence-of-national-statistical-body</link><description>Turned into a subservient organisation---one that was pliant to accommodate politically motivated data manipulation, the Bangladesh Bureau of Statistics (BBS) earned quite an infamy. Political or dictatorial governments resorted to such ploys in order to present a rosy picture of the vital national</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 17:38:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Health catastrophe in Gaza will last ‘for generations’, says WHO chief</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/health-catastrophe-in-gaza-will-last-for-generations-says-who-chief</link><description>Gaza is facing a health "catastrophe" that will last for "generations to come”, the World Health Organization (WHO) Director-General Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus has warned.
Speaking to BBC Radio 4’s Today programme, he said a massive surge in humanitarian aid is essential to meet the co</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 18:09:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prof Yunus seeks cooperation from political parties for peaceful Feb polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/prof-yunus-seeks-cooperation-from-political-parties-for-peaceful-feb-polls</link><description>Chief Adviser Prof Muhammad Yunus on Wednesday sought cooperation from all 'active' political parties to ensure that the national election, scheduled for February next year, is held in a 'peaceful and festive' manner.
“You can be assured of our neutrality. We have already taken various steps</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 18:24:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>LGED keen to support controversial 'MPs' projects' of past regime</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/lged-keen-to-support-controversial-mps-projects-of-past-regime</link><description>A much-debated project distributing development works for Members of Parliament (MPs) during the deposed Awami League regime makes a comeback with cost and time escalations despite being earlier forsaken by the current interim government, sources say.



The Local Government Division (LGD) ha</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 18:39:11 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>