<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 21:21:04 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>118 joint secretaries promoted to additional secretary posts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/118-joint-secretaries-promoted-to-additional-secretary-posts</link><description>A total of 118 officials of the administration cadre have been promoted to the rank of additional secretary at the final stage of the interim government’s tenure.
The promotions were confirmed in a government notification issued on Tuesday.
According to the notification, the officials were</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 15:45:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US hinted at tariff relief for Bangladeshi goods, says Lutfey Siddiqi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/us-hinted-at-tariff-relief-for-bangladeshi-goods-says-lutfey-siddiqi</link><description>Bangladeshi goods may soon face lower tariffs in the United States, Chief Advisor’s International Affairs Special Envoy Lutfey Siddiqi has said after recent bilateral discussions.
On Tuesday, he said the tariffs are “expected to remain around 20 per cent”.
 “We hope t</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 16:00:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat Ameer vows to build safe, dignified Bangladesh for women, children</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-ameer-vows-to-build-safe-dignified-bangladesh-for-women-children</link><description>Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami Ameer Dr Shafiqur Rahman today (Tuesday) said his party wants to build a curse-free Bangladesh where women and children can live in safety, dignity and security.
“Wrong policies and widespread plunder by previous governments forced one factory after another to shut</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 16:47:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Economic reading of BD's 2025 ordinances</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/economic-reading-of-bds-2025-ordinances</link><description>In 2025, Bangladesh's interim government issued 78 ordinances covering labour rights, judicial procedures, digital security, and constitutional governance. These ordinances carry economic consequences. As economic activity is ultimately governed by law, changes in rules and institutions directly af</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 17:02:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCP demands action over harassment of Nasiruddin, warns EC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ncp-demands-action-over-harassment-of-nasiruddin-warns-ec</link><description>National Citizen Party (NCP) Convener Nahid Islam on Tuesday warned the Election Commission (EC) and demanded punishment over the harassment of Nasiruddin Patwary, Jamaat-backed alliance candidate for Dhaka-8 and NCP’s chief coordinator, during electioneering in the city.
The incident took p</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 17:27:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Political pressure, economic insecurity threaten media freedom: Speakers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/political-pressure-economic-insecurity-threaten-media-freedom-speakers</link><description>Speakers at a dialogue on media reform on Tuesday  expressed concern over  safety, political interference and economic vulnerability of journalists
The dialogue, titled “Media Reform in Bangladesh: Between Freedom, Responsibility and Power,” was held at the CIRDAP Auditorium</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 17:42:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Wealthy nations' retreat from global development efforts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/wealthy-nations-retreat-from-global-development-efforts</link><description>A troubling shift is emerging across the global development landscape, as many of the world's wealthiest nations cutback commitments that once formed the backbone of international aid and cooperation. A recent study warns that several high-income economies-including the United States and Japan-are</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 17:57:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Firm stance needed on unfair Adani power deal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/firm-stance-needed-on-unfair-adani-power-deal</link><description>The National Review Committee formed by the interim government to look into the suspected anomalies in the power purchase agreements (PPAs) struck with the Indian Adani Power Ltd and some local independent power generation companies during the Awami League-led autocratic regime has come up with evi</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 18:12:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A nation's pledge to never relive the darkness</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/a-nations-pledge-to-never-relive-the-darkness</link><description>When Professor Muhammad Yunus stepped through the corridors of the July Mass Uprising Memorial Museum, the act itself transcended the protocol of a state visit. This was not a symbolic tour or a courtesy call on the museum. This act itself is a statement of historical accountability. In a nation th</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 18:27:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A blueprint for restoring trust</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/a-blueprint-for-restoring-trust</link><description>The stability and integrity of a nation’s banking system are fundamental pillars of economic prosperity and public confidence. To ensure these systems function effectively, insulated from short-term pressures and vested interests, a comprehensive and principled reform agenda is essential. The</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 18:42:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Country not yet ready to absorb aftershocks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/country-not-yet-ready-to-absorb-aftershocks</link><description>Bangladesh is not yet fully prepared to absorb the aftershocks from least-developed country (LDC) graduation with key sectors like banking and finance and manufacturing staring at significant challenges looming large.
Economists, business leaders and experts came up with such forewarning at a roun</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 18:57:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Families of slain July Uprising activists seek Chankharpul murder verdict review</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/families-of-slain-july-uprising-activists-seek-chankharpul-murder-verdict-review</link><description>Family members of slain July Uprising activists have submitted a memorandum seeking a review of the verdict in a crimes against humanity case involving the killing of six people in Dhaka’s Chankharpul during the 2024 movement.
Eight family members of those killed in the August 2024 Anti-disc</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 19:12:58 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>