<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 15:39:37 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>icddr,b, Washington University develop complementary food for children</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/icddrb-washington-university-develop-complementary-food-for-children</link><description>TIME has named a gut-restoring complementary food for undernourished children developed by icddr,b and Washington University to TIME’s Best Inventions of 2025.
The complementary developed through a long-standing collaboration between the International Centre for Diarrhoeal Disease Research,</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 14:00:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Details of the Gaza ceasefire agreement</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/details-of-the-gaza-ceasefire-agreement</link><description>Israel's government approved the Gaza ceasefire and hostage release deal early on Friday, setting the clock ticking on the first phase of an agreement that aims to end the two-year-old war.
The agreement covers only an initial stage, including handing over hostages held in Gaza in exchange for Pal</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 14:15:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Expat ‘July activist’ Abdul Hamid laid to rest with state honours in Chattogram</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/expat-july-activist-abdul-hamid-laid-to-rest-with-state-honours-in-chattogram</link><description>Expatriate July activist Abdul Hamid was laid to eternal rest with state honours in his family grave in Chattogram on Friday, 18 days after his death.
His remains arrived at Chattogram’s Shah Amanat International Airport this morning on a Bangladesh Biman flight, where relatives wept openly</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 13:31:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt committed to communal harmony: Home Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-committed-to-communal-harmony-home-adviser</link><description>Home Affairs Adviser Lieutenant General Md. Jahangir Alam Chowdhury (Retd.) has said that the government remains deeply committed to preserving communal harmony and ensuring peaceful religious coexistence across the country.
“The interim government has taken all necessary steps to ensure tha</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 13:46:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nobel committee places politics over peace: White House</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/nobel-committee-places-politics-over-peace-white-house</link><description>The White House on Friday criticised the Nobel Prize committee's decision to grant the peace prize to a Venezuelan opposition leader instead of U.S. President Donald Trump, who aggressively lobbied for the award and touted his role in brokering international ceasefire deals.
"President Trump will</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 14:01:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Charter’s legal basis a matter of survival: Khelafat chief</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/legal-basis-of-july-charter-a-matter-of-life-or-death-says-khelafats-mamunul</link><description>Bangladesh Khelafat Majlish chief Mamunul Haque has demanded that the general election be held under the legal framework of the July Charter, calling it “a matter of life or death”.
Addressing the interim government, he accused the authorities of failing to establish the Charter’</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 14:16:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Football dispute sparks bloody clash in Brahmanbaria village</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/football-dispute-sparks-bloody-clash-in-brahmanbaria-village</link><description>At least 30 people were injured as two groups of villagers clashed over a football match in Ashuganj Upazila of Brahmanbaria on Friday.
Several houses were also vandalised during the violence.
The incident took place in the Durgapur Bazar area of Durgapur union around Friday morning.
According t</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 14:31:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ambassador Miller reaffirms EU’s unequivocal opposition to death penalty</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ambassador-miller-reaffirms-eus-unequivocal-opposition-to-death-penalty</link><description>Ambassador and Head of the Delegation of the European Union to Bangladesh Michael Miller on Friday reaffirmed the EU’s unequivocal opposition to the death penalty in all cases and under all circumstances.
“More than two-thirds of countries worldwide have abolished the death penalty in</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 15:01:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shahidul Alam to return home on Saturday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/shahidul-alam-to-return-home-on-saturday</link><description>Renowned Bangladeshi photographer and human rights activist Shahidul Alam, who was released by Israeli authorities on Friday after joining a Free Palestine campaign, is expected to arrive in Dhaka at 4:55 am on Saturday, according to the Chief Adviser’s Press Wing.
Earlier in the day, Shahid</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 15:16:19 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>