<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 17:26:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>NEIR launch deferred to January 1</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/neir-launch-deferred-to-january-1</link><description>The Bangladesh Telecommunication Regulatory Commission (BTRC) has postponed the launch of the National Equipment Identification Register (NEIR) by 15 days, setting January 1 as the revised start date.
Previously scheduled for December 16, Victory Day, the launch had sparked protests from mobile ph</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 14:24:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Press Secretary sees no possibility of AL’s participation in election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/press-secretary-sees-no-possibility-of-als-participation-in-election</link><description>Apparently ruling out the possibility of the Awami League’s participation in the upcoming national election, Chief Adviser’s Press Secretary Shafiqul Alam on Monday said that no democratic country in the world would allow an organisation led by such a ‘terrible criminal’ to</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 14:39:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gaza struggles to pull bodies from rubble as storms rock damaged buildings</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/gaza-struggles-to-pull-bodies-from-rubble-as-storms-rock-damaged-buildings</link><description>Authorities in Gaza warned on Monday that more war-damaged buildings may collapse because of heavy rain in the devastated Palestinian enclave and said the weather was making it hard to recover bodies still under the rubble.
Two buildings collapsed in Gaza on Friday, killing at least 12 people acco</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 14:54:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Students lock CU administrative building over Pro-VC’s remarks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/students-lock-cu-administrative-building-over-pro-vcs-remarks</link><description>Students of Chittagong University (CU) on Monday locked the university’s administrative building demanding the removal of Pro-Vice Chancellor (Academic) Prof Mohammad Shamim Uddin Khan for his alleged controversial remarks over the killings of intellectuals in 1971.
Under the banner of Sarba</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 15:09:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘For all I know, she could be dead’ says son of Myanmar’s Suu Kyi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/for-all-i-know-she-could-be-dead-says-son-of-myanmars-suu-kyi</link><description>With her health failing and an information vacuum around Myanmar's detained former leader Aung San Suu Kyi, her son worries that he may not even know if she passed away.
Kim Aris told Reuters he has not heard from his 80-year-old mother in years, and has received only sporadic, secondhand details</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 15:41:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Metro rail services to be suspended for 40 minutes on Victory Day</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/metro-rail-services-to-be-suspended-for-40-minutes-on-victory-day</link><description>Metro rail services will be suspended for 40 minutes on Tuesday on the occasion of Victory Day.
“The operation of the mass rapid transit (MRT) line-6 will remain halted for 40 minutes (from 11:50am to 12:30pm) on December 16 to ensure the safety of para troopers,” according to a notifi</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 15:56:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Those serving foreign interests will not remain safe: Mahfuj Alam</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/those-serving-foreign-interests-will-not-remain-safe-mahfuj-alam</link><description>Former adviser and frontline leader of the July Uprising Mahfuj Alam on Monday said those who serve the interests of India or other foreign powers would not be allowed to remain safe in Bangladesh if the country’s people themselves are unsafe.
“If we are not safe in this country, our e</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 16:11:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Access to SC courtrooms restricted for security reasons</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/access-to-sc-courtrooms-restricted-for-security-reasons</link><description>The Supreme Court has restricted access to its courtrooms for trial candidates and anyone other than lawyers in both its divisions from Monday, citing security concerns.
The notification said the Supreme Court, being the highest judicial institution of the country, requires strict security to ensu</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 16:26:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nobel laureate Machado injured as she fled Venezuela, spokesperson says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/nobel-laureate-machado-injured-as-she-fled-venezuela-spokesperson-says</link><description>Nobel Peace Prize laureate Maria Corina Machado fractured a vertebra while fleeing Venezuela on a small boat last week to receive the award in Oslo, a spokesperson for the opposition leader said on Monday, confirming a Norwegian media report.
Machado went to Norway in defiance of a decade-long tra</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 16:41:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Intelligence skills ‘seem lost’ since Aug 5: Nahid</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nahid-says-intelligence-agencies-skills-have-vanished-since-aug-5</link><description>National Citizen Party (NCP) chief Nahid Islam has raised alarms over the capability of the country’s intelligence agencies following the attack on Inqilab Moncho Convenor Sharif Osman bin Hadi.
On Monday, Nahid said the country’s intelligence agencies were used to “suppress all</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 16:56:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat chief demands CEC clarify Hadi attack remarks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-chief-shafiqur-demands-explanation-of-cecs-comments-on-hadi-shooting</link><description>Jamaat-e-Islami chief Shafiqur Rahman has demanded an explanation for the comments made by Chief Election Commissioner AMM Nasir Uddin on the attack on Inqilab Moncho Convenor Sharif Osman bin Hadi.
Speaking at a Victory Day discussion on Monday, he said if the CEC’s explanation fails to eas</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 17:11:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Current account deficit widens in July–October</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/current-account-deficit-widens-in-july-october</link><description>Bangladesh’s current account deficit widened during July–October of the current fiscal year, driven by weaker export performance, official data show.
The deficit expanded to US$749 million, up 17 per cent from the same period a year earlier.
Export earnings rose modestly by 1.8 per ce</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 17:26:53 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>