<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 21:18:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>BRAC Bank partners Mhadi Support Services to extend digital lending programme ‘Shafollo’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/brac-bank-partners-mhadi-support-services-to-extend-digital-lending-programme-shafollo</link><description>BRAC Bank has entered into a partnership with Mhadi Support Services Limited to extend digital lending facilities to the organisation’s support staffers through the bank’s digital lending platform, Shubidha App, according to a press release.
Through this initiative, BRAC Bank will enab</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 15:47:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New police commissioner for Gazipur Met Police; new SPs in 6 districts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/new-police-commissioner-for-gazipur-met-police-new-sps-in-6-districts</link><description>The government made some important new postings on the police, including a new commissioner for one of the largest and most critical police forces in the country - the Gazipur Metropolitan Police (GMP).
It also posted six new superintendents of police (SPs) in as many key districts across the coun</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 16:02:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh Betar to air live verdict on crimes against humanity</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-betar-to-air-live-verdict-on-crimes-against-humanity</link><description>Bangladesh Betar will broadcast live the verdict on crimes against humanity to be delivered tomorrow by the International Crimes Tribunal-1 in Dhaka.
The announcement was made in a press release today signed by Bangladesh Betar Deputy Director Roksana Rahman, BSS reports. 
The live coverage</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 16:34:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chhatra Shakti holds torch procession on eve of Hasina's verdict</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/chhatra-shakti-holds-torch-procession-on-eve-of-hasinas-verdict</link><description>Jatiya Chhatra Shakti, formerly Bangladesh Ganatantrik Chhatra Sangsad (BGCS), brought out a torchlight procession on Sunday evening ahead of the verdict in the cases against former Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina and two others accused of crimes against humanity during last year’s July–Au</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 16:49:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Man with six petrol bombs held in Mohammadpur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/man-with-six-petrol-bombs-held-in-mohammadpur</link><description>Rapid Action Battalion (Rab) arrested a man in the capital’s Mohammadpur area on Sunday evening for allegedly planning acts of arson and sabotage.
The elite force also recovered six petrol bombs, one samurai sword, one gas lighter and an Android mobile phone from his possession, UNB reports.</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 17:04:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Different dimensions have emerged from the COP30 climate summit</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/different-dimensions-have-emerged-from-the-cop30-climate-summit</link><description>The 30th "Conference of the Parties" (COP30) to the UN Framework Convention on Climate Change (UNFCCC) is taking place from November 6-21, 2025 in Belém, Brazil. It has brought together world leaders, scientists, non-governmental organisations, and civil society to discuss priority actions t</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 17:29:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Referendum without shaping outlines</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/referendum-without-shaping-outlines</link><description>Holding a national election is a very important event for any country only more so when it is in a momentous transition. Bangladesh, following the July-August uprising, was on the cusp of such a new order. Whether the historical change will materialise desirably, however, hinges not so much on the</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 17:44:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Traders' call for redress goes in vain</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/traders-call-for-redress-goes-in-vain</link><description>The Transparency International, Bangladesh (TIB) in early March this year, revealed that private buses and minibuses pay over Tk10.59 billion annually as extortion money to political affiliates, the police, the Bangladesh Road Transport Association (BRTA), city corporations and municipal officials</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 17:59:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Crude bombs explode in front of Adviser Rizwana’s home</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crude-bombs-explode-in-front-of-adviser-rizwanas-home</link><description>Two crude bomb explosions occurred in front of the residence of Syeda Rizwana Hasan, Adviser to the Ministries of Environment, Forest and Climate Change, and Water Resources, in the Central Road area of the capital on Sunday night at around 9 pm. 
No casualties were reported.
Adviser Rizwana conf</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 18:14:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trinamool BNP leader Shamsher Mobin announces retirement from politics</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/trinamool-bnp-leader-shamsher-mobin-announces-retirement-from-politics</link><description>Shamsher Mobin Chowdhury, chairman of the Trinamool BNP, has announced his retirement from politics, reports bdnews24.com.
On Sunday night, he said, “I have fully retired from politics. I am now not involved in anything.”
Asked why he was stepping down, Mobin, who transitioned from di</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 18:29:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ominous shadow of joblessness, poverty</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/ominous-shadow-of-joblessness-poverty</link><description>That all is not well with the state of Bangladesh's economy is corroborated by several recently published local and international studies. Even though the government managed to stabilise the economy to a large extent from the mess it inherited, prolonged political uncertainty appears to be a major</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 19:15:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Automated bond utilisation permission mandatory for export industries</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/automated-bond-utilisation-permission-mandatory-for-export-industries</link><description>Using automated system is made mandatory for issuing utilisation permission (UP) for export-oriented industries from December 1, as allegations of misuse of duty-free facility galore.



The National Board of Revenue (NBR) announced the decision Sunday, after a meeting with leaders of the count</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 19:30:44 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>