<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 08:33:04 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>More condolences pour in for Khaleda Zia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/more-condolences-pour-in-for-khaleda-zia</link><description>Different organisations and individuals continued to express condolences over the death of former Premier Begum Khaleda Zia, who breathed her last on Tuesday and was buried with state honour on Wednesday.
They highlighted Begum Zia's lifelong struggle for sustaining the country's democracy and her</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 05:17:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>RU female student’s hanging body recovered from hostel</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/ru-female-students-hanging-body-recovered-from-hostel</link><description>Police recovered the hanging body of a female student of Rajshahi University (RU) from a student hostel in the Binodpur area of Rajshahi city on Wednesday afternoon.
The deceased was identified as Lamisa Nawrin Pushpita, a first-year student of the Department of Islamic History and Culture. She ha</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 05:32:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique thanks CA, all others for support during Khaleda’s janaza</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-thanks-ca-all-others-for-support-during-khaledas-janaza</link><description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman on Thursday expressed his heartfelt gratitude to the Chief Adviser and advisers of the interim government, members of the armed forces, law-enforcement agencies, government officials and media professionals for their role in ensuring a dignified and orderly farewe</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 05:47:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New York, new year, new mayor</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/mamdanis-inauguration-new-york-new-year-new-mayor</link><description>Zohran Mamdani was a trailblazing candidate whom many in his city of 8 million -- some with hope, some with trepidation -- expect to be a disruptive New York mayor.
The democratic socialist's plans for his first day in office on Thursday nod to his politics and priorities, without straying far fro</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 05:30:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka’s air persist in ‘unhealthy for sensitive groups’ zone</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dhakas-air-persist-in-unhealthy-for-sensitive-groups-zone</link><description>Dhaka, the overcrowded capital city of Bangladesh, has ranked fifth on the list of cities with the worst air quality with an AQI score of 184 at 10:10 am on Thursday (January 1, 2026). 
Dhaka's air was classified as 'unhealthy for sensitive groups', referring to a health threat, according to</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 05:45:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>All of Bangladesh has become my family:Tarique</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/all-of-bangladesh-has-become-my-familytarique</link><description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman has expressed gratitude to the millions of people who paid their respects to his mother, former prime minister and BNP chairperson Khaleda Zia, during her funeral and burial.
“Today, at a time of greatest sorrow, I feel like this whole nation is my family</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 06:00:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Stocks open year on positive note with new hope</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/stocks-open-year-on-positive-note-with-new-hope-1</link><description>Stocks opened higher on Thursday, the opening day of the New Year 2026, as bargain hunters favoured taking positions in potentially lucrative shares amid renewed optimism.
The market opened higher, aided by the price appreciation of particular large-cap stocks, as opportunistic investors are expec</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 06:15:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Indian tobacco stocks fall as new tax is imposed on cigarettes</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/indian-tobacco-stocks-fall-as-new-tax-is-imposed-on-cigarettes</link><description>Shares of Indian tobacco companies fell on Thursday after the government imposed a new tax on cigarettes, making them costlier for an estimated 100 million smokers in the world's most populous country.
ITC, maker of Gold Flake and the market leader, dropped 4.4 per cent, while Godfrey Phillips Ind</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 06:30:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fuel prices cut by Tk 2 a litre at start of 2026</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/fuel-prices-cut-by-tk-2-a-litre-at-start-of-2026</link><description>Bangladesh cut retail fuel prices by Tk 2 a litre from January 1, reversing an increase imposed a month earlier as part of its automatic fuel pricing mechanism.
The Energy and Mineral Resources Division said in a notification issued late Wednesday that the prices of diesel, octane, petrol and kero</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 06:45:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nothing secret about it: Jamaat chief on meeting with Indian diplomats</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/nothing-secret-about-it-jamaat-chief-on-meeting-with-indian-diplomats</link><description>Jamaat-e-Islami chief Shafiqur Rahman has hit out at reports that he held a “secret meeting” with Indian diplomats, saying there was “nothing confidential” about the contact.
In a Facebook post on Thursday, Shafiqur said he met two Indian diplomats around the middle of last</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 07:00:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh bans e-cigarettes, vapes under tightened tobacco law</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-bans-e-cigarettes-vapes-under-tightened-tobacco-law</link><description>The interim government has issued an ordinance banning e-cigarettes, vapes and all other emerging tobacco products as part of a sweeping overhaul of the country’s tobacco control laws.
The Smoking and Tobacco Products Use (Control) (Amendment) Ordinance, 2025, was promulgated on Wednesday by</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 08:01:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Biman profit jumps 178pc with Tk 7.85 billion gain</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/biman-profit-jumps-178pc-with-tk-785-billion-gain</link><description>Bangladesh’s state-owned carrier Biman Bangladesh Airlines posted a net profit of Tk 7.85 billion (Tk 785.21 crore) in fiscal 2024–25, nearly tripling its earnings from a year earlier, as higher passenger traffic and tighter cost controls boosted the airline’s financial performanc</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 08:16:29 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>