<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 04:37:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Higher taxing of billionaires likely to narrow inequality</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/higher-taxing-of-billionaires-likely-to-narrow-inequality</link><description>Ramping up the tax incidence on high-net-worth individuals (HNWI) is under government strategy to narrow widening income inequality in Bangladesh as the Gini index is getting imbalanced.



Medium and Long-term Revenue Strategy (MLTRS) for the financial year 2025-26 to FY2034-35, published by t</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 19:09:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BD-India ties anchored in economics</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bd-india-ties-anchored-in-economics</link><description>Bangladesh is seeking to recalibrate its relationship with neighbouring India by drawing a clear distinction between political discourse and economic decision-making, says Finance Adviser Dr Salehuddin Ahmed, amid ongoing tensions on both sides.
Emphasising pragmatism over rhetoric, he told report</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 01:56:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New refinery gets ECNEC clearance after long delays</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/new-refinery-gets-ecnec-clearance-after-long-delays</link><description>Long 17 years' wait for an energy-boosting facility ends with the endorse of a project for building a second unit of the Eastern Refinery planned for augmenting Bangladesh's crude-oil-refining capacity.
The Executive Committee of the National Economic Council (ECNEC) approved the "Modernisation an</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 02:11:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Indian envoy summoned again over recurrent attacks on BD missions</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/indian-envoy-summoned-again-over-recurrent-attacks-on-bd-missions</link><description>Bangladesh summoned India's high commissioner in Dhaka Tuesday and lodged protest against unrelenting ruckus and acts of vandalism targeting Bangladeshi missions in India.
In a retaliatory move on the day India also summoned Bangladesh High Commissioner Riaz Hamidullah.
However, India deployed 15</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 02:26:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt, WB sign four deals to secure $350m loans</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/govt-wb-sign-four-deals-to-secure-350m-loans</link><description>The Bangladesh government and the World Bank's (WB) soft-lending arm International Development Association (IDA) recently signed four agreements with relevant stakeholders to secure loans of $350 million.
State-run Petrobangla had inked project agreement and facility agreement with the IDA and thr</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 02:41:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Islamic banks register deposit, remittance growth in Oct '25</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/islamic-banks-register-deposit-remittance-growth-in-oct-25</link><description>Bangladesh's Islamic banking sector saw considerable growth in investments in October 2025, signalling steady expansion in Shariah-compliant banking activities.
The Bangladesh Bank (BB) data shows investments rose from Tk 5.18 trillion in October 2024 to Tk 5.77 trillion in October 2025, reflectin</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 02:56:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka airport restricts entry of non-passengers for 24 hours</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dhaka-airport-restricts-entry-of-non-passengers-for-24-hours</link><description>Entry to the Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport (HSIA) area in Dhaka will be restricted to passengers only from 6:00pm on December 24 to until 6:00pm tomorrow (Thursday), according to the airport authorities.
"In the interest of maintaining smooth passenger service, security, and operational d</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 03:11:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sylhet div faces severe regional disparity</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/sylhet-div-faces-severe-regional-disparity</link><description>Sylhet division has become the worst victim of regional disparity in the banking sector, with the region witnessing the lowest inflow of bank credits despite its immense potential.
While people in the four districts of the division contribute significantly to the deposit portfolio of the banking s</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 03:26:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt offers rewards to curb air pollution</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/govt-offers-rewards-to-curb-air-pollution</link><description>The government has announced an incentive-based initiative to combat air pollution by encouraging citizens to submit photographs of waste burning in open areas.
In a statement issued on Tuesday, the Ministry of Environment said air pollution has emerged as a serious threat to public health in Bang</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 03:41:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hidden liabilities threaten to cripple Power Grid, outweigh assets</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/hidden-liabilities-threaten-to-cripple-power-grid-outweigh-assets</link><description>State-run Power Grid has undisclosed liabilities which, if taken into account, would exceed the value of its assets and impair its ability to repay.
The company's auditors flagged the liabilities in qualified opinions attached to the FY25 financial statements. To get independent judgements about t</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 03:56:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>SQ Brokerage licence cancelled by DSE</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/sq-brokerage-licence-cancelled-by-dse</link><description>The Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) has revoked another Trading Right Entitlement Certificate (TREC) licence - SQ Brokerage House Ltd - for violation of trading rules.
The prime bourse on Tuesday announced the regulatory decision on its website, stating that the brokerage firm failed to commence tradin</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 04:11:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Investors fear losses, shy away from converting Beximco sukuk</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/investors-fear-losses-shy-away-from-converting-beximco-sukuk</link><description>Most of the unit holders of Beximco Green Sukuk have shown reluctance in converting bonds into shares although four years have passed, fearing losses.
In a stock exchange filing on Tuesday, the Investment Corporation of Bangladesh (ICB), the trustee of the debt securities, said only 18 unit holder</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 04:26:45 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>