<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 15:34:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Rupayan Group chairman faces graft charges</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/acc-prosecutes-rupayan-real-estate-chairman-over-illegal-land-use</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) has prosecuted Liaquat Ali Khan Mukul, chairman of Rupayan Real Estate Limited, on charges of illegally obtaining land-use clearance, special project approval, and design and construction permits in violation of a court-imposed stay.
The project of the real est</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 12:23:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Meghna Bank holds Annual Business Conference-2026</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/meghna-bank-holds-annual-business-conference-2026</link><description>The Annual Business Conference of Meghna Bank PLC was successfully held on 20th January 2026 at a renowned hotel in Dhaka.
According to a press release, the conference was attended by Uzma Chowdhury, Chairperson of the bank, as the chief guest. Syed Mizanur Rahman, the Managing Director, presided</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 12:38:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hadi murder: Key suspect’s ‘associate’ to be quizzed</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/key-suspect-faisals-associate-rubel-to-be-interrogated-for-six-days-over-hadi-murder</link><description>A Dhaka court has granted police six days to interrogate Faisal Rubel Ahmed, a close associate of Faisal Karim Masud—the prime suspect in the murder of Inqilab Moncho leader Sharif Osman bin Hadi.
Dhaka Additional Chief Metropolitan Magistrate Jashita Islam passed the order on Thursday, conf</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 12:53:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Islami Bank holds board meeting on Thursday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/islami-bank-holds-board-meeting-on-thursday</link><description>A meeting of the board of directors of Islami Bank Bangladesh PLC was held on Thursday at Islami Bank Tower, according to a press release.
Professor Dr. M. Zubaidur Rahman, chairman of the bank, presided over the meeting. Mohammad Khurshid Wahab, chairman of the executive committee, Md. Abdus Sala</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 13:08:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Berger Paints Bangladesh partners with Banglalink Orange Club</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/berger-paints-bangladesh-partners-with-banglalink-orange-club</link><description>Berger Paints Bangladesh Limited has formed a strategic partnership with Banglalink Orange Club through its exclusive Berger Experience Zone to elevate home living for discerning homeowners across Bangladesh.
According to a press release, through this collaboration, Banglalink Orange Club Members</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 13:23:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IOM launches emergency response following fire at Rohingya camp</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/iom-launches-emergency-response-following-fire-at-rohingya-camp</link><description>The International Organization for Migration (IOM) has launched an emergency response following a large fire in a Rohingya refugee camp in Cox’s Bazar early Tuesday morning.
According to a statement, relief efforts are being carried out in close coordination with the Government of Bangladesh</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 13:38:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt withdraws transfer orders of eight Upazila administrators</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-withdraws-transfer-orders-of-eight-upazila-administrators</link><description>The interim government has withdrawn an order transferring eight Upazila administrators (UNOs) just a day after they issued it ahead of the parliamentary polls.
The Ministry of Public Administration cancelled the earlier decision through a fresh notification on Thursday.
The officers affected by</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 13:53:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Community Bank, Sandhani Life Insurance sign bancassurance agreement</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/community-bank-sandhani-life-insurance-sign-bancassurance-agreement</link><description>Community Bank Bangladesh PLC and Sandhani Life Insurance Company Ltd have signed a Bancassurance agreement aimed at providing integrated insurance services to customers across the country.
According to a press release, through this partnership, insurance products of Sandhani Life Insurance will b</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 14:08:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump says Ukraine peace efforts ‘getting close’ ahead of Zelensky talks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-says-ukraine-peace-efforts-getting-close-ahead-of-zelensky-talks</link><description>US President Donald Trump said peace efforts on Ukraine were “getting close” ahead of a meeting with President Volodymyr Zelensky in Davos on Thursday, as US envoy Steve Witkoff said negotiations were down to one last issue.
US and Ukrainian officials have spent weeks in frenetic shutt</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 14:23:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh Bank requires adequate operational, administrative independence: Finance adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/bangladesh-bank-requires-adequate-operational-administrative-independence-finance-adviser</link><description>Finance Adviser Dr Salehuddin Ahmed has said Bangladesh Bank requires adequate operational and administrative independence to perform its duties effectively.
The adviser also pointed out that such autonomy must be balanced with accountability within the sovereign framework of the state.
He came u</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 14:38:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>2 candidates hid British citizenship in affidavits: TIB</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/2-candidates-hid-british-citizenship-in-affidavits-tib</link><description>Transparency International Bangladesh (TIB) has said at least two candidates contesting the 13th parliamentary election concealed their dual citizenship in their submitted affidavits.
Both the candidates are British citizens but their affidavits made no mention of this, said Dr. Iftekharuzzaman, e</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 14:53:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Central bank adopts direct action strategy to expedite reforms: Governor</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/central-bank-adopts-direct-action-strategy-to-expedite-reforms-governor</link><description>Bangladesh Bank (BB) Governor Dr Ahsan H Mansur has said the central bank has adopted a direct action strategy by forming three specific task forces instead of a banking commission so that the country can expedite financial sector reforms.
Describing the financial sector reforms through the bankin</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 15:08:38 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>