<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 11:19:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>No safe level: Stakeholders rally at Press Club to demand action against lead pollution</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/no-safe-level-stakeholders-rally-at-press-club-to-demand-action-against-lead-pollution</link><description>Under the global theme "No Safe Level: Act Now to End Lead Exposure," YouthNet Global and Pure Earth Bangladesh, in coordination with the Department of Environment and with support from UNICEF, jointly organised a public awareness rally, human chain, and discussion session at the Dhaka Press Club t</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 08:24:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>London-bound flight collides with boarding bridge at Sylhet’s Osmani International Airport</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/london-bound-flight-collides-with-boarding-bridge-at-sylhets-osmani-international-airport</link><description>A Bangladesh Biman aircraft has collided with a boarding bridge at Sylhet’s Osmani International Airport.
The accident occurred around 10:30am on Wednesday, according to Hafiz Uddin Ahmed, director of the airport, bdnews24.com reports.
The flight was to carry 262 passengers to London. After</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 08:39:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Consensus commission recommendations deceptive: Fakhrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/consensus-commission-recommendations-deceptive-fakhrul</link><description>BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir has called the recommendations made by the National Consensus Commission on the implementation of the July National Charter “deceptive” and demanded their immediate amendment.
He made the call at a discussion on Thursday, while sharing</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 08:54:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Saudi economy minister forecasts 2025 real GDP growth at 5.1pc</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/saudi-economy-minister-forecasts-2025-real-gdp-growth-at-51pc</link><description>Saudi Arabia’s economy minister forecast real GDP growth of 5.1% for 2025, supported by the non-oil sector, as the kingdom accelerates efforts to diversify away from oil.
“We forecast to close the year...in terms of total real GDP growth at around 5.1% and for non-oil GDP around 3.8%,&amp;</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 09:09:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Argentina to ask US appeals court to overturn $16.1 billion YPF judgment</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/argentina-to-ask-us-appeals-court-to-overturn-161-billion-ypf-judgment</link><description>A US appeals court will on Wednesday consider whether Argentina must pay investors $16.1 billion after seizing control of state-owned oil company YPF (YPFDm.BA) more than a decade ago.
The 2nd US Circuit Court of Appeals in Manhattan will review US District Judge Loretta Preska's September 2</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 09:24:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Israel says it will uphold Gaza ceasefire as strikes kill 104 people</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/israel-says-it-will-uphold-gaza-ceasefire-as-strikes-kill-104-people</link><description>The Israeli military said on Wednesday that it had resumed enforcing a ceasefire accord in Gaza, as health officials in the enclave said airstrikes had killed 104 people, with both sides trading blame for violations of the deal.
Israel launched airstrikes in Gaza late on Tuesday, saying it mounted</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 09:54:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>South Korea welcomes Trump with its highest award, a golden crown and ketchup</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/south-korea-welcomes-trump-with-its-highest-award-a-golden-crown-and-ketchup</link><description>South Korea welcomed US President Donald Trump on Wednesday with a replica gold crown and awarded him with the "Grand Order of Mugunghwa", the country's highest decoration, the presidential office said.
Trump landed in South Korea on the final leg of a trip through Asia that also saw stops in Mala</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 10:09:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Water cannons, sound grenades used on Ebtedayee teachers’ protest</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/water-cannons-sound-grenades-used-on-ebtedayee-teachers-protest</link><description>Police have used force to disperse a march by teachers from Ebtedayee madrasas to demand the nationalisation of their educational institutions.
The march from the National Press Club to the Secretariat was held under the banner of the Independent Ebtedayee Madrasa Teachers' Unity Movement Implemen</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 10:39:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>PRI urges strong political commitment to monetary, fiscal reforms</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/pri-urges-strong-political-commitment-to-monetary-reforms-protection-of-bbs-independence</link><description>The Policy Research Institute of Bangladesh (PRI) has urged both the interim government and the incoming elected government to demonstrate strong political commitment to major reforms in the monetary and fiscal sectors, while safeguarding the independence of Bangladesh Bank.
“Central bank in</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 10:54:59 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>