<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 05:20:16 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>BAN holds 8th Startup Showcase at IUB</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ban-holds-8th-startup-showcase-at-iub</link><description>Bangladesh Angels Network (BAN), an angel investment platform, on Saturday organised its 8th Startup Showcase at the Independent University Bangladesh (IUB) auditorium in the city.
The event, sponsored by Trust Bank PLC, brought together investors, founders, and ecosystem leaders, with Sadat Ahmed</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 04:00:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Patenga interchange work to end by June</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/patenga-interchange-work-to-end-by-june</link><description>CHATTOGRAM, Dec 06: The construction of the Coastal Road, popularly known as Chattogram Ring Road, with updated design is nearing completion.
To date, 70 per cent of the intersection work has been done at the Patenga junction, which connects three mega projects and two important points. Once this</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 02:50:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh's bold undergrad founders</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/article/bangladeshs-bold-undergrad-founders</link><description>For university students with a business idea scribbled in a notebook or a prototype built in their hostel room, the wait is over. The Undergrad Startup Challenge 2025, Bangladesh's largest startup competition exclusively for undergraduate students, has officially opened registration.
Organised by</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 03:05:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>PulseTech secures US$ 3.0m to transform Bangladesh's pharmaceutical supply chain</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/article/pulsetech-secures-us-30m-to-transform-bangladeshs-pharmaceutical-supply-chain</link><description>PulseTech, a B2B healthtech platform operating in Bangladesh, has successfully closed a US$ 3.0 million Pre-Series A funding round. The investment was co-led by Iterative and AVV, marking AVV's inaugural investment in the country. The capital will support PulseTech's ambitious plans to reshape phar</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 03:20:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How Bangladesh's youths are rediscovering social connection</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/article/how-bangladeshs-youths-are-rediscovering-social-connection</link><description>Every Eid afternoon tells the same story in households across Dhaka. Several cousins gather in the drawing room, phones in hand, scrolling through feeds whilst sitting shoulder to shoulder. Someone suggests Uno, a card game. A few agree half-heartedly, but within twenty minutes, everyone's back on</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 03:35:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DU Business Studies unit admission test held</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/du-business-studies-unit-admission-test-held</link><description>The admission test for the first-year undergraduate programme under Dhaka University's 'Business Studies Unit' for the 2025-26 academic year has been held.
The exam took place on Saturday (6 December) from 11:00 am to 12:30 pm. This year, a total of 34,062 applicants sat for the test against 1,050</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 03:50:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A group of RU students announce boycott of 12th convocation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/a-group-of-ru-students-announce-boycott-of-12th-convocation</link><description>A section of students from the 60th, 61st, and 62nd batches of Rajshahi University have announced a boycott of the university's 12th convocation.
They made the announcement at a press conference held on Saturday (6 December) at 12:00 pm at the university's Transport Market, citing the authorities'</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 04:05:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shobuj murder: Hasina charged with ‘planning’, 3 of her ex-ministers charged with giving the order</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/shobuj-murder-hasina-charged-with-planning-3-of-her-ex-ministers-charged-with-giving-the-order</link><description>Deposed prime minister Sheikh Hasina and three of her former ministers have been charged with “planning and criminal conspiracy to commit murder, financial assistance, supplying firearms and giving direct and indirect orders” leading to the murder of CNG autorickshaw driver Md Shobuj in</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 04:20:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>23 killed in nightclub fire in India's Goa</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/23-killed-in-nightclub-fire-in-indias-goa</link><description>At least 23 people died after a fire at a nightclub in India's Goa state, the chief minister of the state said on Sunday, as videos on social media showed ambulances lining up to help the injured.
The incident occurred around 12:04 am local time (1834 GMT Saturday) in the village of Arpora, the st</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 04:35:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India warns IndiGo of regulatory action</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/india-warns-indigo-of-regulatory-action</link><description>India's aviation watchdog on Saturday warned airline IndiGo of regulatory action after it cancelled thousands of flights over the last week, stranding passengers and forcing government action to limit a surge in airfares caused by the crisis.
The country's biggest airline, IndiGo cancelled the fli</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 04:50:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Youth stabbed to death in Jashore</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/youth-stabbed-to-death-in-jashore</link><description>A 22-year-old youth was stabbed to death near Ansar Camp in Bejpara of  Jashore town on Saturday midnight
Tanvir, son of Mintu from Shankarpur Hazarigat, was found bleeding near the camp around 12:55 am, reports UNB.
Locals rushed him to Jessore 250-Bed General Hospital, where doctors declar</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 05:05:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>220 MW Sonagazi solar plant gets green light</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/220-mw-sonagazi-solar-plant-gets-green-light</link><description>In a major push toward clean energy, the government has taken up a plan to ramp up renewable power generation and reduce reliance on coal and fuel-based electricity that contributes to environmental degradation.
The project titled “Construction of Sonagazi 220MW Solar Power Plant,&amp;rdqu</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 05:20:16 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>