<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 04:59:52 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>EU Chief Observer calls twin polls a big day for Bangladesh democracy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/eu-chief-observer-calls-twin-polls-a-big-day-for-bangladesh-democracy</link><description>Chief Observer of the European Union Election Observation Mission (EU EOM) to Bangladesh Ivars Ijabs on Thursday said it is really a big day for Bangladesh’s democracy as they started observing the country’s twin elections-- national election and referendum - across the country.
"I thi</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 02:37:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Women voters turn up early at Dhaka-16 polling centres</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/women-voters-turn-up-early-at-dhaka-16-polling-centres</link><description>Asfia Begum, 69, arrived at MDC Model School and College in Mirpur's Pallabi, at around 8:20 am to cast her vote in the 13th parliamentary elections on Thursday.
Like her, many women voters turned up early at polling centres in Dhaka-16 to avoid long queues later in the day. Of the total 199,323 r</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 02:38:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Peaceful voting witnessed at Dhaka polling centres</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/peaceful-voting-witnessed-at-dhaka-polling-centres</link><description>Voting was proceeding peacefully at several polling centres in the capital on Thursday, with satisfactory voter turnout reported in the morning hours.
During visits to different centres, FE reporters found balloting under way in an orderly manner. At Centre-14 at Pallabi Government College under D</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 02:53:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Free, fair polls matter more than win or loss: Nahid Islam</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/free-fair-polls-matter-more-than-win-or-loss-nahid-islam</link><description>Jamaat-led alliance candidate and National Citizen Party convener Nahid Islam on Thursday said ensuring a free and fair election is more important than electoral victory or defeat, stressing that the real test is whether people can exercise their voting rights without obstruction.
Speaking to repo</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 03:08:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat Ameer casts vote at Monipur centre</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-ameer-casts-vote-at-monipur-centre</link><description>Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami Ameer Dr Shafiqur Rahman cast his vote at 8:15 am on Thursday at the Monipur High School (Boys’ Branch) polling centre.
The Jamaat leader went to the polling station around 8:00 am and cast his vote.
Voting began at Monipur High School polling centre in the city&amp;r</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 03:23:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka-9 sees slow voter turnout</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dhaka-9-sees-slow-voter-turnout</link><description>Voter turnout in Dhaka-9 was reported to be relatively low in the early hours of Thursday’s 13th National Elections. However, election officials expressed hope that participation would pick up as the day progresses.
At Khilgaon Model High School, which hosts three polling centres under Dhaka</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 03:38:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Crowds gather at Gulshan centre ahead of Tarique, Dr Yunus voting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crowds-gather-at-gulshan-centre-ahead-of-tarique-dr-yunus-voting</link><description>A large crowd gathered outside Gulshan Model High School and College polling centre on Thursday morning as BNP leader Tarique Rahman and Nobel laureate Dr Muhammad Yunus were scheduled to cast their votes.
FE reporter at the scene said supporters and onlookers thronged the area, creating a lively</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 03:24:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cavalry unit of police patrols Dhaka streets to ensure peaceful polling</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cavalry-unit-of-police-patrols-dhaka-streets-to-ensure-peaceful-polling</link><description>The Cavalry unit of Bangladesh Police, along with other regular and specialised units, has been patrolling city streets to maintain a peaceful polling environment in the capital on Thursday.
The special unit was also seen spreading awareness about voters’ code of conduct on election day.
Th</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 03:39:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique casts vote under tight security in Dhaka-17</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-casts-vote-under-tight-security-in-dhaka-17</link><description>BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman cast his vote amid tight security at Gulshan Model School and College on Thursday at 9:36 am.
He was accompanied by his wife, Zubaida Rahman, and daughter, Zaima Rahman. Members of the army and police were deployed around the polling centre to ensure strict security, ac</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 03:54:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka-9 candidate Jara casts vote in Dhaka-11</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/dhaka-9-candidate-jara-casts-vote-in-dhaka-11</link><description>Dr Tasnim Jara, the independent candidate from Dhaka-9, cast her vote at 8:40 am on Thursday at the Taltala Prime School and College polling centre in Khilgaon under Dhaka-11 constituency.
Although she is contesting from Dhaka-9, Jara’s residential address falls under Dhaka-11, so she was un</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 04:09:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>It'll send tremendous signal to world: Commonwealth about Bangladesh polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/itll-send-tremendous-signal-to-world-commonwealth-about-bangladesh-polls</link><description>Chairperson of the Commonwealth Observer Group Nana Akufo-Addo on Thursday expressed satisfaction over the smooth beginning of vote casting at Viqarunnisa Noon School and College and hoped that this trend would continue throughout the day.
"So far so good," the Chairperson and former President of</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 04:24:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hasnat casts ballot in Cumilla-4, urges voters to turn out without fear</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/hasnat-casts-ballot-in-cumilla-4-urges-voters-to-turn-out-without-fear</link><description>Hasnat Abdullah, the 11-party alliance candidate for the Cumilla-4 constituency, has cast his vote and encouraged the public to exercise their franchise freely.
The National Citizen Party (NCP) leader joined the queue at Gopalnagar High School centre in Debidwar Upazila at 8am on Thursday to deliv</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 04:39:12 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>