<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 08:31:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Zubaida Rahman arrives in Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/zubaida-rahman-arrives-in-dhaka</link><description>Zubaida Rahman, the wife of Tarique Rahman and daughter-in-law of BNP chief Khaleda Zia, has arrived in Dhaka.
She landed at Dhaka’s Shahjalal International Airport on board a Biman Bangladesh Airlines flight around 10:45 am on Friday, according to Atikur Rahman Rumon, a BNP spokesman.
&amp;ldq</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 05:53:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Midland Bank donates ambulance to Anjuman Mufidul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/midland-bank-donates-ambulance-to-anjuman-mufidul</link><description>Midland Bank PLC has donated an ambulance to Anjuman Mufidul Islam, a charitable organisation and one of the leading ambulance service providers in Dhaka, serving both patients and deceased persons within and outside the capital. The donation is part of the Bank’s commitment to social wellbei</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 05:45:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khaleda Zia’s flight uncertain before Sunday; her condition worsens slightly</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/khaleda-zias-flight-uncertain-before-sunday-her-condition-worsens-slightly</link><description>BNP Chairperson Begum Khaleda Zia is unlikely to travel to London before Sunday as her planned medical flight has been delayed because the special air ambulance provided by the Emir of Qatar has still not arrived in Dhaka.
BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir told UNB that the air amb</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 06:00:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Kaaba seen like a bright light from 400k km above earth; picture goes viral</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/kaaba-seen-like-a-bright-light-from-400k-km-above-earth-picture-goes-viral</link><description>A stunning  photograph taken from orbit has gone viral online, revealing Mecca’s Kaaba glowing like a luminous point from 400 kilometers above Earth.
The image, captured from the International Space Station (ISS), highlights Islam’s holiest site as a radiant center within the city</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 06:15:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CU student's hanging body recovered from Ctg flat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/cu-students-hanging-body-recovered-from-ctg-flat</link><description>A student of Chittagong University has been found dead at a flat in the port city in an apparent suicide.
Omar Faruk Sumon, a student in the university’s Arabic Department from the 2021–22 session, was discovered hanging from a ceiling fan hook at a residence on Road No. 5 in the Khuls</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 06:30:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Xi joins Macron in southwest China on rare trip with a global leader outside Beijing</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/xi-joins-macron-in-southwest-china-on-rare-trip-with-a-global-leader-outside-beijing</link><description>Chinese President Xi Jinping accompanied his French counterpart Emmanuel Macron to Chengdu on Friday, a rare gesture seemingly reserved for the head of Europe's second-largest economy that highlights Beijing's focus on Paris in its dealings with the European Union.
 
The French president b</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 06:45:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Night temperatures may drop by 1–2°C: Met office</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/night-temperatures-may-drop-by-1-2c-met-office</link><description>Bangladesh Meteorological Department (BMD) has forecast a slight fall in night temperatures across the country, with readings expected to drop by 1–2°C.
“Night temperatures may fall by 1–2°C, while day temperatures are likely to remain nearly unchanged across the country,</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 07:00:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cash moving back to vaults amid higher rates</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/cash-moving-back-to-vaults-amid-higher-rates</link><description>The currency held outside banks has been flowing back into vaults in greater volumes in recent months, providing some sort of respite to commercial lenders amid persisting liquidity tightness.
Deposits amounting to Tk 260 billion that flowed out returned to the banking sector in the last four mont</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 07:22:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bringing back killers of July Uprising is our main goal: Press Secretary</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bringing-back-killers-of-july-uprising-is-our-main-goal-press-secretary</link><description>Chief Adviser’s Press Secretary Shafiqul Alam on Friday reaffirmed the government’s commitment to bringing back those responsible for the July killings, calling it a “pledge to the martyrs.”
Speaking at the inauguration of an inter-college football tournament at Magura Gove</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 07:37:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Israel sets 2026 defence budget at $34 billion despite ceasefire in Gaza</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/israel-sets-2026-defence-budget-at-34-billion-despite-ceasefire-in-gaza</link><description>The Gaza war has been costly for Israel, which spent $31bn in 2024 on its military conflicts with Hamas and with Hezbollah
Israel's defence budget for 2026 has been set at 112 billion shekels ($34.63 billion), the defence minis
"We will continue to act decisively to reinforce the IDF and to fully</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 07:52:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>One dies, five get injured as pickup, microbus collide in Chattogram</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/one-dies-five-get-injured-as-pickup-microbus-collide-in-chattogram</link><description>At least one person has died and five others, including women and children, have been injured in a road crash involving a pickup truck and a microbus in Chattogram’s Hathazari.
The accident occurred on the Chattogram-Khagrachhari regional highway in the Farhadabad area of the Upazila on Frid</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 08:07:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh Bank steps up dollar purchases</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladesh-bank-steps-up-dollar-purchases</link><description>The Bangladesh Bank has strengthened its intervention in the foreign exchange market, purchasing US$132 million from five banks in the interbank spot market on Thursday to help stabilise the dollar-taka exchange rate.
The move comes amid continued pressure on the local currency and a broader effor</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 08:22:06 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>