<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 11:37:35 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Bangladesh set to ratify three ILO conventions on workplace safety and harassment</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladesh-set-to-ratify-three-ilo-conventions-on-workplace-safety-and-harassment</link><description>Bangladesh will ratify three conventions of the International Labour Organization (ILO) related to occupational safety and health and violence and harassment soon.Among the three, conventions 155 and 187 are related to OSH safety and culture and convention 190 is an international treaty establishin</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 08:30:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IFIC celebrates its glorious 49th anniversary</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ific-celebrates-its-glorious-49th-anniversary</link><description>On Wednesday, October 8, 2025, IFIC celebrated its glorious 49th anniversary.
The celebration took place at the Multipurpose Hall of IFIC Tower, Purana Paltan, Dhaka, according to a media release. 
The ceremony was graced by the Chairman of the Board of Directors, Mr. Md. Mehmood Husain, alo</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 08:45:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>28 murders in Rampura: Warrants against 4 BGB personnel</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/arrest-warrants-issued-against-4-bgb-personnel-over-28-murders-in-rampura</link><description>The International Crimes Tribunal (ICT) has issued arrest warrants against four Border Guard Bangladesh personnel in a case of crimes against humanity over the killings of 28 people in Dhaka’s Rampura during the July Uprising.
A three-member bench led by Tribunal-1 Chairman Justice Md Golam</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 09:00:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>July Charter to be signed by October 16: Prof Ali Riaz</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/july-charter-to-be-signed-by-october-16-prof-ali-riaz</link><description>National Consensus Commission (NCC) Vice Chair Prof Ali Riaz said on Wednesday that the Commission will submit its final recommendations to the government by October 10, with the goal of enabling political parties to sign the July National Charter 2025 by October 16.
“The Commission will han</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 09:15:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP’s Fakhrul meets EU Ambassador Miller</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bnps-fakhrul-meets-eu-ambassador-miller</link><description>BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir has met with European Union Ambassador Michael Miller.
The hour-long meeting began at 11am on Wednesday at the party chairperson’s office in Dhaka's Gulshan.
The discussions focused on the upcoming elections, the electoral process, and matte</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 09:45:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Everything has an end,' says ex-minister Palak during court appearance</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/everything-has-an-end-says-ex-minister-palak-during-court-appearance</link><description>Former state minister for ICT Zunaid Ahmed Palak has been placed under arrest in another murder case linked to last year's July Uprising.
Other political figures formally arrested in the case include former textiles and jute minister Golam Dastagir Gazi, former Dhaka North City Corporation mayor A</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 10:00:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tabith, Kiron get spots on FIFA committees</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/bangladesh-football-officials-tabith-awal-mahfuza-akhter-kiron-join-fifa-committees</link><description>Bangladesh Football Federation (BFF) President Tabith Awal and Women’s Wing Chairman Mahfuza Akhter Kiron have been named to two committees under FIFA, the governing body for international football.
Tabith was nominated for the Football Technology, Innovation, and Digital Transformation Comm</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 10:15:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Court freezes 56 bank accounts of ex-minister Ruhal, wife, son</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/court-freezes-56-bank-accounts-of-ex-minister-ruhal-wife-son</link><description>A Dhaka court on Wednesday ordered the freezing of 56 bank accounts of former Health Minister AFM Ruhal Haque, his wife Ila Haque, and their son Ziaul Haque over graft allegations.
Dhaka Metropolitan Senior Special Judge Md Sabbir Faiz passed the order, allowing a plea of the Anti-Corruption Commi</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 10:30:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CUCSU election campaign in full swing</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/cucsu-election-campaign-in-full-swing</link><description>Campaigning for the long-awaited Chattogram University Central Students' Union (CUCSU), Hall Councils, and student representative elections to the Senate has gathered momentum, with candidates intensifying their outreach efforts ahead of the October 15 polls.
Candidates and their supporters are no</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 10:45:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Quality of govt grants recipient films must be improved: Information Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/quality-of-govt-grants-recipient-films-must-be-improved-information-adviser</link><description>Information and Broadcasting Adviser Md. Mahfuj Alam said today (Wednesday) that the production style of government grants- recipient films should be improved. 
The Ministry of Information and Broadcasting will provide support to improve the quality of films receiving the government grants, h</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 11:15:55 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>