<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 04:35:37 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Rent-seeking, bureaucracy-business nexus threaten dev prospects, says adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rent-seeking-bureaucracy-business-nexus-threaten-dev-prospects-says-adviser</link><description>Bangladesh's long-term development prospects may face serious setbacks unless rent-seeking in politics and the collusive nexus between business and bureaucracy are dismantled, Planning Adviser Dr Wahiduddin Mahmud said on Sunday.
He said meaningful institutional reform, an efficient bureaucracy an</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 01:15:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Inflation up for food-price rises</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/inflation-up-for-food-price-rises</link><description>Inflation edges up in Bangladesh as some pricier key consumer items drive November count to 8.29 per cent, overshooting the central bank's 6.5-percent annual target for this fiscal year.
According to official data released Sunday, the month's reading was 0.12-percentage-point higher than October's</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 01:30:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt to finalise it today, business leaders raise concerns</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/govt-to-finalise-it-today-business-leaders-raise-concerns</link><description>Business leaders have expressed concern that the ongoing amendment to the rules governing trade organisations may fail to ensure the emergence of proper business leadership for the country's economic development, despite the government's year-long efforts to streamline the regulations.
They have q</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 01:45:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rupali Haque elected FICCI president for 2026-2027</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/rupali-haque-elected-ficci-president-for-2026-2027</link><description>Rupali Haque Chowdhury, managing director of Berger Paints Bangladesh Limited, has been elected president of the Foreign Investors' Chamber of Commerce and Industry (FICCI) for the 2026-2027 term.
Besides, Deepal Abeywickrema, chairman and managing director of Nestlé Bangladesh PLC, and Moh</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 02:00:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nov PMI falls as economic expansion slows sharply</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/nov-pmi-falls-as-economic-expansion-slows-sharply</link><description>Bangladesh's Purchasing Managers' Index (PMI) declined by 7.8 points to 54 in November last over the previous month, reflecting a slower expansion in key economic sectors.
A PMI reading above 50 indicates that the sector/economy is generally 'expanding' while a reading of 50 indicates 'no change'</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 02:15:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ADB's fossil fuel focus raises alarms</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/adbs-fossil-fuel-focus-raises-alarms</link><description>Bangladesh has so far received US$17.34 billion in 106 projects from the Asian Development Bank (ADB), including nearly $6.0 billion for 36 gas-focused schemes that collectively support 3,659MW generation capacity, a new study has revealed.
Civil society groups say this long-standing reliance on f</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 02:30:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CA for urgent action to ensure food safety</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ca-for-urgent-action-to-ensure-food-safety</link><description>Chief Adviser Prof Muhammad Yunus has expressed deep concern over the rising levels of toxic substances in food, calling for urgent and coordinated action to curb contamination and protect public health.
Speaking at a high-level meeting at the State Guest House Jamuna on Sunday, Prof Yunus urged m</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 02:45:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>HC questions ACC's inaction on alleged loan irregularities</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hc-questions-accs-inaction-on-alleged-loan-irregularities</link><description>The High Court has directed the Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) and Bangladesh Bank to dispose of, within 90 days, a petition seeking an investigation into allegations of loan irregularities and money laundering by Nice Spun, a subsidiary of the Noman Group.
The order comes amid claims that the c</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 03:00:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Adopt environment-friendly, resilient means: Researchers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/adopt-environment-friendly-resilient-means-researchers</link><description>Researchers at the flagship academic event of the Bangladesh Institute of Development Studies (BIDS) on Sunday suggested adopting environment-friendly and resilient means to address the country's climate impacts.
The Annual BIDS Conference on Development was held in the capital in a number of acad</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 03:15:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ACC sues S Alam, Janata Bank officials</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/acc-sues-s-alam-janata-bank-officials</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) has filed a case against 34 individuals -- including senior Janata Bank officials and top executives linked to trading entities of the S Alam Group -- over alleged loan fraud, abuse of authority, and criminal breach of trust amounting to Tk 19.64 billion.
The c</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 03:30:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New 3-party alliance formed ahead of nat'l polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/new-3-party-alliance-formed-ahead-of-natl-polls</link><description>A new political alliance called the 'Democratic Reform Alliance', comprising three political parties, was launched on Sunday.
The parties involved are the National Citizen Party (NCP), Amar Bangladesh Party (AB Party), and Rashtra Sangskar Andolon.
NCP convener Nahid Islam made the announcement a</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 03:45:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Soybean oil price rises by Tk 6 per litre, palm oil up Tk 16</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/soybean-oil-price-rises-by-tk-6-per-litre-palm-oil-up-tk-16</link><description>The country's refiners have increased the price of bottled soybean oil by Tk 6.0 a litre to Tk 195, while palm oil prices have risen by Tk 16 a litre. The price of loose soybean oil has been raised by Tk 7.0 per litre.
The Bangladesh Vegetable Oil Refiners and Vanaspati Manufacturers Association (</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 04:00:48 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>