<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 04:42:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>One group fled after snatching voting rights, another plotting again: Tarique</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/one-group-fled-after-snatching-voting-rights-another-plotting-again-tarique</link><description>BNP Chairperson Tarique Rahman on Thursday said one group had stripped people of their voting rights and fled the country while another group had remained out of sight for years but is now conspiring again.
“Everyone must remain alert to ensure ballot boxes are protected and empty boxes cann</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 18:37:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Freed Chhatra League leader Saddam accuses Bagerhat jailer of Tk 500,000 bribe demand</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/freed-chhatra-league-leader-saddam-accuses-bagerhat-jailer-of-tk-500000-bribe-demand</link><description>Jewel Hasan Saddam, a leader of the now-banned Bangladesh Chhatra League who was released on bail from Jashore Central Jail, has accused the Bagerhat district jailer of demanding Tk 500,000.
Saddam made the allegation on Wednesday evening after returning to his home in Sabekdanga, Bagerhat Sadar,</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 18:52:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Merged Islamic banks' clients getting maximum 9.5pc profit</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/merged-islamic-banks-clients-getting-maximum-95pc-profit</link><description>Depositors in the five Islamic banks merged into the newly formed Sammilito Islami Bank will receive profits at market rates of up to 9.5 per cent, says the regulator.



But depositors in nine non-bank financial institutions (NBFIs) up for liquidation would receive only their principal amounts</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 19:54:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Inheritance tax proposed under major reforms</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/inheritance-tax-proposed-under-major-reforms</link><description>A government-constituted expert panel has recommended introducing inheritance tax as part of broader efforts to widen Bangladesh's tax base and uplift the tax-to-GDP ratio to 15-20 per cent by 2035.
The proposal is incorporated in the National Taskforce for Tax Reform report submitted to the Chief</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 02:27:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh Bank rebases REER to reflect economic reality</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladesh-bank-rebases-reer-to-reflect-economic-reality</link><description>Bangladesh Bank has redrawn one of the most closely-watched indicators of the country's external competitiveness, updating its real effective exchange rate (REER) index to better reflect today's economic realities.
For the first time, the central bank has factored remittance inflows into the calcu</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 02:42:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Export industries can import raw materials duty-free for trade boost</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/export-industries-can-import-raw-materials-duty-free-for-trade-boost</link><description>Export-oriented industries can import raw materials duty-free under a new import policy that the government believes will strengthen trade competitiveness and support industrial growth.
The post-uprising interim government Thursday approved the Import Policy Order 2025-2028 alongside a raft of ord</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 02:57:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>High Court asks for appeal again on NCT deal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/high-court-asks-for-appeal-again-on-nct-deal</link><description>The High Court (HC) on Thursday discharged a rule that questioned the legality of the government action to award the container-handling contract of the New Mooring Container Terminal (NCT) at the Chittagong Port to a foreign company.
The verdict was delivered by a single-member bench of Justice Za</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 03:12:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EU designates Iran's Revolutionary Guards as terrorist organisation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/eu-designates-irans-revolutionary-guards-as-terrorist-organisation-in-policy-shift</link><description>European Union foreign ministers on Thursday agreed to include the Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps on the bloc's list of terrorist organisations, putting the powerful guards in a category similar to that of Islamic State and al Qaeda and marking a symbolic shift in Europe's approach to Iran's lea</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 03:27:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Four years on, ICT Division proposes 154pc cost hike</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/four-years-on-ict-division-proposes-154pc-cost-hike</link><description>The ICT Division has submitted a second revision proposal for the Bangladesh Institute of Frontier Technology (BIFT) preliminary infrastructure project, estimating the cost at Tk 38.90 billion, a 153.5-percent increase from the current estimate of Tk 15.34 billion.
This came after just 15 per cent</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 03:42:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BTMA suspends factory shutdown programme</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/btma-suspends-factory-shutdown-programme</link><description>The Bangladesh Textile Mills Association (BTMA) has suspended its programme to shut down factories following government assurances to resolve the ongoing crisis in the spinning sector.
In a statement issued on Thursday, the primary textile millers' trade body announced the withdrawal of its earlie</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 03:57:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BARC, PKSF to work together for inclusive agricultural growth</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/barc-pksf-to-work-together-for-inclusive-agricultural-growth</link><description>Palli Karma-Sahayak Foundation (PKSF) and the Bangladesh Agricultural Research Council (BARC) will work jointly to strengthen links between agricultural research and extension to achieve inclusive growth.
Although agriculture is a key pillar of food security and employment, it contributes only abo</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 04:12:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>3 RMG factories get LEED certification</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/3-rmg-factories-get-leed-certification</link><description>Three more local garment factories have received LEED (Leadership in Energy and Environmental Design) certification from the US Green Building Council (USGBC), with one achieving the highest score globally, taking Bangladesh's total to 273 LEED-certified factories.
HAMS Garments Ltd, located in Sr</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 04:27:39 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>