<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 11:14:11 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Morocco: The tales of deserts, mountains and the sea</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/others/morocco-the-tales-of-deserts-mountains-and-the-sea</link><description>I fell in love with you watching Casablanca
Back row of the drive-in show in the flickering light
Popcorn and cokes beneath the stars
Became champagne and caviar
Making love on a long hot summer's night
 
I am from the generation who grew up listening to the song Casablanca by Bertie Hig</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 08:58:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gano Forum signs July Charter</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/gano-forum-signs-july-charter</link><description>Gano Forum has signed the July Charter, joining the list of political parties endorsing the political accord initiated by the National Consensus Commission.
Gano Forum’s acting president and valiant freedom fighter Subrata Chowdhury and general secretary Dr Md Mizanur Rahman signed the chart</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 09:28:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ICC Bangladesh to host ICC Global Banking Commission Meeting in Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/icc-bangladesh-to-host-icc-global-banking-commission-meeting-in-dhaka</link><description>The International Chamber of Commerce (ICC) Banking Commission, Paris, has proposed to hold the ICC Global Banking Commission Meeting jointly with ICC Bangladesh in Dhaka during October- November 2027.
The proposal was accepted by ICC Bangladesh Banking Commission Meeting held on 12 October 2025,</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 08:59:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Salahuddin says attempts to pit BNP against July Uprising will fail</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/salahuddin-says-attempts-to-pit-bnp-against-july-uprising-will-fail</link><description>BNP Standing Committee Member Salahuddin Ahmed on Sunday said no attempt to pit the BNP against the July Uprising will succeed.
"It would be wrong to think that a fascist ruler was toppled in just 36 days. This was the result of 16 years of continuous struggle and sacrifice. So, I think any attemp</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 09:14:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Protests over fee hike paralyse cargo operations at Ctg port</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/protests-over-fee-hike-paralyse-cargo-operations-at-ctg-port</link><description>Cargo movement at Chattogram Port has slowed to a crawl as workers and transport owners protest against recent increases in service and entry fees, reports bdnews24.com.
The Clearing and Forwarding (C&amp;amp;F) Agents Association observed a four-hour work stoppage on Sunday, while truck, covered van and</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 09:29:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Education Adviser hopes protesting MPO teachers will return to classes</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/education-adviser-hopes-protesting-mpo-teachers-will-return-to-classes</link><description>Education Adviser CR Abrar on Sunday expressed hope that the protesting the MPO-listed teachers will return to classrooms following the government’s announcement of a 5% house rent allowance based on their basic salary.
“The Ministry of Education has always tried to safeguard the inter</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 09:44:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>North Korean soldier defects to South Korea</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/north-korean-soldier-defects-to-south-korea</link><description>A North Korean soldier defected to South Korea by crossing the heavily fortified Demilitarized Zone between the two countries on Sunday, the South's military said in a statement.
The soldier was taken into custody by South Korean guards who had been monitoring his movements, the military said, say</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 10:14:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Saudi cooperation sought for oastal rainwater harvesting project</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/saudi-cooperation-sought-for-oastal-rainwater-harvesting-project</link><description>Saudi Ambassador to Bangladesh Dr Abdullah Jaefer H Bin Abiyah paid a courtesy visit to Syeda Rizwana Hasan, Adviser to the Ministry of Environment, Forest and Climate Change, at her office in the Secretariat on Sunday.
During the meeting, Adviser Rizwana Hasan sought Saudi Arabia’s cooperat</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 10:29:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DCCI urges fire safety at all levels of ports</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/dcci-urges-fire-safety-at-all-levels-of-ports</link><description>President of the Dhaka Chamber of Commerce and Industry (DCCI) Taskeen Ahmed today (Sunday) urged the authorities concerned to implement effective measures to improve fire safety and overall security at all levels of Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport (HSIA), as well as at other ports.
“</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 10:44:31 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>