<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 03:11:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Palestinian Ambassador meets Khaleda Zia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/palestinian-ambassador-meets-khaleda-zia</link><description>Palestinian Ambassador to Bangladesh, Mr. Yousef S. Y. Ramadan today (Tuesday) met BNP Chairperson and former Prime Minister Begum Khaleda Zia at her Gulshan residence in the capital.
BNP Media Cell member Shayrul Kabir Khan confirmed the meeting, saying it lasted around an hour, BSS reports.&amp;nbsp</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 18:37:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP’s Moyeen Khan urges recognition of changed political reality</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnps-moyeen-khan-urges-recognition-of-changed-political-reality</link><description>While visiting the Durga Puja mandap at Seba Sangha in Narsingdi town on Tuesday night, BNP Standing Committee member Dr Abdul Moyeen Khan said that Bangladesh’s political and social reality has changed within the last year and people must remain alert to ensure justice and democracy.
&amp;ldquo</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 18:52:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Farashuddin finds 15 rogue companies imperilling economy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/farashuddin-finds-15-rogue-companies-imperilling-economy</link><description>When political power converges with economic interests, the result is the rise of corporations that function much like the East India Company of colonial times, warns Dr. Mohammed Farashuddin.
Speaking at a Policy Research Institute (PRI) event in Dhaka on Tuesday, the former Bangladesh Bank Gov</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 19:37:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt to slash tariffs of 6 state power plants</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/govt-to-slash-tariffs-of-6-state-power-plants</link><description>Power tariffs of half a dozen of the state-owned power plants are set to be cut years after initiation of their commercial operations, said sources.
The proposed new tariffs are expected to get approved by the Advisors Council Committee on Economic Affairs as state-run Bangladesh Power Development</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 01:41:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Government issues PPR 2025</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/government-issues-ppr-2025</link><description>Making the electronic government procurement (e-GP) compulsory for all public agencies, the government on September 28 issued the Public Procurement Rules (PPR) 2025, replacing the 2008 version.
It has also removed the ±10 per cent price cap on work procurement, which existed in the PPR 200</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 01:56:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>July Charter Implementation: Commission awaits last-minute political consensus</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/july-charter-implementation-commission-awaits-last-minute-political-consensus</link><description>The National Consensus Commission is scheduled to meet political parties October 5 in what could be a decisive sitting to settle how the July Charter will be implemented.
With little progress made since the last adjourned meeting in September, the Commission is banking on last-minute consensus bef</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 02:11:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BDBL seeks Tk 50b from govt to help support its operations</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bdbl-seeks-tk-50b-from-govt-to-help-support-its-operations</link><description>The state-run Bangladesh Development Bank PLC (BDBL) has sought Tk 50 billion as financial support from the government to help expand its overall operations, sources said.
Managing Director and CEO Md. Jashim Uddin in a letter made such a request to the Finance Adviser, aiming to boost the bank's</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 02:41:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>At least 27 dead after powerful quake hits Philippines</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/at-least-27-dead-after-powerful-quake-hits-philippines</link><description>The death toll from a powerful 6.9-magnitude earthquake in the central Philippines has risen to 27 with more than 140 people injured, and officials on Wednesday warned the numbers could climb further as rescuers access collapsed buildings.
The earthquake struck off the coast of Bogo City in Cebu p</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 02:56:18 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>