<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 06:38:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Bangladesh Bank moves to speed up settlement of Tk 750.52 billion audit backlogs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladesh-bank-moves-to-speed-up-settlement-of-tk-75052-billion-audit-backlogs</link><description>The central bank has initiated a move to fast-track the settlement of long-standing audit backlogs involving more than Tk 750.52 billion, sources said.
Such long-standing fund impasses regarding the 1,206 unsettlement audit objections at the Bangladesh Bank (BB) remain a big concern, officials sai</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 02:32:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>China's Sinopec gets go-ahead to drill 5 hydrocarbon wells</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/chinas-sinopec-gets-go-ahead-to-drill-5-hydrocarbon-wells</link><description>China's state corporation Sinopec gets the go-ahead to drill five new hydrocarbon wells on the gas-rich Bhola island as Bangladesh moves to enhance output of the fuel to feed the energy-hungry economy.
State-run Bangladesh Petroleum Exploration and Production Company Ltd (BAPEX) issued Wednesday n</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 02:47:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>H1 apparel exports slide amid weak demand, trade frictions</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/h1-apparel-exports-slide-amid-weak-demand-trade-frictions</link><description>Bangladesh's readymade garment (RMG) exports to non-traditional markets posted negative growth in the first half of the current fiscal year, reflecting prolonged weakness in global demand amid economic uncertainty across key economies.
Rising living costs, sluggish growth, shifting trade regimes a</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 03:30:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nationwide internet blackout reported in Iran</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/nationwide-internet-blackout-reported-in-iran-as-protests-persist</link><description>A nationwide internet blackout was reported in Iran on Thursday, internet monitoring group NetBlocks said, as protests over economic hardships continued around the country.
No further information on the internet outage was immediately available.
Witnesses in the capital Tehran and major cities of</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 03:45:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US Senate votes to curb military action in Venezuela</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-senate-votes-to-curb-military-action-in-venezuela-trump-says-oversight-could-last-years</link><description>The US Senate voted on Thursday to advance a resolution that would bar President Donald Trump from taking further military action against Venezuela without congressional authorization, even as Trump said US oversight of the troubled nation could last years.
The Senate voted 52 to 47 on a procedura</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 04:00:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Three die as bus crashes into parked truck in Ctg’s Mirsharai</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/three-die-as-bus-crashes-into-parked-truck-in-ctgs-mirsharai</link><description>Three people have been killed after a passenger bus crashed into a parked truck in the Baroiarhat area of Chattogram’s Mirsharai Upazila.
The incident occurred in the Gumghat area of the Dhaka-Chattogram Highway around 2:00 am on Friday, according to Mohammad Zakaria, chief of Jorarganj High</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 04:45:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Renata secures Turkish approval, opens new export market</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/renata-secures-turkish-approval-opens-new-export-market</link><description>Renata has secured high-class recognition from one more stringent drug authority, which opened up an opportunity to export medicines to Turkey.
In a filing on Thursday, the listed drug manufacturer informed that it had received regulatory approval from the Turkish Medicines and Medical Devices Age</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 05:00:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC suspends elections in two Pabna constituencies amid boundary dispute</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-suspends-elections-in-two-pabna-constituencies-amid-boundary-dispute</link><description>The Election Commission has decided to temporarily suspend the election process in two of Pabna’s parliamentary seats amid a dispute over the revision of the constituency boundaries and under orders from the Supreme Court.
Election Commissioner Abdur Rahmanul Masud said on Friday, “Acc</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 05:15:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BUILD urges expansion of scope</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/build-urges-expansion-of-scope</link><description>Business Initiative Leading Development (BUILD), a public-private dialogue platform, has urged the expansion of the scope of duty-free raw material import facilities for non-bonded exporters to drive export diversification.
It made the call on Thursday at a dialogue titled "Duty-Free Import of Raw</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 05:30:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BGMEA, BKMEA and BTMA seek balanced tariff policy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bgmea-bkmea-and-btma-seek-balanced-tariff-policy</link><description>Entrepreneurs and leaders of BGMEA, BKMEA and BTMA have called on the government to adopt a balanced tariff policy to resolve the ongoing dispute over yarn imports, aiming to make both the readymade garment (RMG) and spinning sectors more competitive in the export market.
The call came during a me</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 05:45:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>SME board pays price for speculative excess, sheds 22pc in 2025</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/sme-board-pays-price-for-speculative-excess-sheds-22pc-in-2025</link><description>The SME board of the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) suffered a sharp year-on-year decline in 2025, significantly underperforming the main market index.
Sixteen of the 20 SME stocks suffered erosion in market value during the period, many of which had experienced unusual surges without any fundamental</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 06:00:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Export cash incentives to continue till June 2026</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/export-cash-incentives-to-continue-till-june-2026</link><description>The government will continue to provide cash incentive facilities for exporters for an additional six months in order to support them during ongoing global economic challenges.
According to a notification issued by the Finance Division of the Ministry of Finance on Wednesday, the government has ex</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 06:15:06 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>