<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 07:22:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Revised margin rules curb speculative stock rallies</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/revised-margin-rules-curb-speculative-stock-rallies</link><description>The revised margin rules have diminished the dominance of speculative stocks in the secondary market as they lost the status as marginable securities.
The Bangladesh Securities and Exchange Commission (Margin) Rules 2025 came into effect on November 6. Before that, market manipulators could create</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 03:30:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Unilever reaffirms quality pledge on World Quality Day</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/unilever-reaffirms-quality-pledge-on-world-quality-day</link><description>Unilever Bangladesh Limited marked the World Quality Day on Tuesday by showcasing its robust quality assurance framework, underscoring its commitment to delivering safe, reliable and world-class products to consumers in the country.
At a special workshop held at the company's Dhaka headquarters, i</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 03:45:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Five tourists killed in Chile snowstorm</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/five-tourists-killed-in-chile-snowstorm</link><description>Five foreign tourists were killed after a powerful snowstorm struck Torres del Paine National Park in Patagonia, southern Chile, the local government said Tuesday.
Jose Antonio Ruiz, the presidential delegate for the Magallanes and the Chilean Antarctica Region, said the dead were two Mexicans, tw</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 04:00:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt may revise proposed travel agency ordinance to boost FDI</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/govt-may-revise-proposed-travel-agency-ordinance-to-boost-fdi</link><description>The government is likely to amend the draft Bangladesh Travel Agency (Registration and Regulation) (Amendment)-2025 Ordinance after concerns that its 100 per cent local ownership requirement could block foreign investment, officials said.
The proposed changes aim to prevent customer harassment on</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 04:15:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How an 11-year-old Bangladeshi girl made it to Everest Base Camp</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/how-an-11-year-old-bangladeshi-girl-made-it-to-everest-base-camp</link><description>Everest Base Camp is a dream destination for mountain lovers and travellers. Every mountain person dreams of standing before Mount Everest, and that dream begins at the Everest Base Camp.
But can a child make this dream come true?
Yes, an 11-year-old Bangladeshi girl named Atanaaz Hayat Chowdhury</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 04:30:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Making traditional homemade food tastier for children</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/making-traditional-homemade-food-tastier-for-children</link><description>Remember what the millennials had for their meal as children? Home-cooked meals from their grandmother, mothers, often their sister-in-laws, and sisters. The foods were prevalent but rich in affection and health benefits. The foods had an identity based on the race of people, district-wise.
Before</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 04:45:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Myanmar refugees join Thai workforce</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/myanmar-refugees-join-thai-workforce</link><description>Tun Min Lat climbs a bamboo ladder in the longan orchards of eastern Thailand, moving from tree to tree as he plucks the juicy tropical fruit in the sweltering heat of a November morning.
For the first time in the nearly two decades he has lived in Thailand, the 42-year-old Myanmar refugee is able</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 05:00:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nearly half of global population live in cities: UN report</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/others/nearly-half-of-global-population-live-in-cities-un-report</link><description>Nearly half of the global population of 8.2 billion live in cities across the world today, according to a UN report released on Tuesday.
The World Urbanisation Prospects 2025: Summary of Results showed that the world has become increasingly urban, with the number of people living in cities having</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 05:15:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Thirteen people killed in Israeli strike on Lebanon's Sidon</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/thirteen-people-killed-in-israeli-strike-on-lebanons-sidon</link><description>An Israeli strike on the southern Lebanese city of Sidon killed 13 people and wounded several others, the Lebanese Health Ministry said on Tuesday.
The Israeli military said that it struck militants who it said were operating in a training compound in the crowded Ain al-Hilweh Palestinian refugee</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 05:30:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>First kiss was 20 million years ago by early primates, scientists say</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/first-kiss-was-20-million-years-ago-by-early-primates-scientists-say</link><description>Kissing did not begin with star-crossed human lovers but with the primate ancestors of great apes around 20 million years ago, according to a study published on Wednesday.
Researchers from Oxford University and the Florida Institute of Technology wanted to examine when kissing began, given that fr</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 06:03:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Journalist Sohel freed from DB custody, shares account of ordeal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/journalist-sohel-freed-from-db-custody-shares-account-of-ordeal</link><description>The Detective Branch (DB) of police has released Mizanur Rahman Sohel, secretary of the Online Editors Alliance and head of online at the Bangla daily Bhorer Kagoj, after questioning. He was handed over to his family at around 10:15 am on Wednesday.
In a long Facebook post shared after his release</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 06:18:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Garment scraps gutted in Gazipur fire</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/garment-scraps-gutted-in-gazipur-fire</link><description>A huge quantity of jhut (garment scraps) was damaged as a fire broke out at a warehouse in Sreepur upazila of Gazipur on Wednesday.
According to the fire service, the fire started around 12:30 am at Sarwar Hossain’s warehouse in Bakultola on Mawna-Sreepur road.
On information, initially a f</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 06:33:40 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>