<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 18:28:54 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Burnt Mirpur plant ‘not linked to BGMEA’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/mirpur-washing-facility-where-fire-broke-out-not-part-of-bgmea</link><description>The Bangladesh Garment Manufacturers and Exporters Association (BGMEA) has said the factory in Mirpur’s Rupnagar, where a deadly fire broke out, is not a member of the organisation.
According to a statement from the trade body on Tuesday, the facility in Shiallbari is a washing plant, not a</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 15:30:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique Rahman expresses shock over Mirpur fire; calls for transparent probe</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-rahman-expresses-shock-over-mirpur-fire-calls-for-transparent-probe</link><description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman on Tuesday expressed deep shock and sorrow over the devastating fire at a garment factory and a chemical warehouse in the Shialbari area of Mirpur, urging a transparent investigation to ensure those responsible are brought to justice.
In a post on his verified Fa</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 15:45:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IMF forecasts modest economic recovery for Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/imf-forecasts-modest-economic-recovery-for-bangladesh</link><description>The International Monetary Fund (IMF) has projected that Bangladesh’s economy will experience a modest recovery in the current fiscal year 2025-26 (FY26).
The multilateral lender forecasted that Bangladesh’s gross domestic product (GDP) growth could reach 4.9 percent in FY26, according</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 16:00:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Security heightened ahead of RUCSU polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/security-heightened-ahead-of-rucsu-polls</link><description>The authorities concerned have taken strict security measures ahead of Rajshahi University Central Students’ Union (RUCSU), Senate student representative, and hall union elections scheduled for Thursday.
Rajshahi Metropolitan Police (RMP) Commissioner Mohammad Abu Sufian said that 2,000 poli</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 16:30:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Water Lily’ symbol must be allocated: NCP</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/water-lily-symbol-must-be-allocated-ncp</link><description>In a sharp reaction to the Election Commission’s latest letter, the National Citizen Party (NCP) on Tuesday insisted that the ‘Water Lily’ must be allocated as its electoral symbol, saying the matter “does not depend on the Commission’s whim.”
“Even today,</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 16:31:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nazrul Islam Khan falls sick, hospitalised</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nazrul-islam-khan-falls-sick-hospitalised</link><description>BNP Standing Committee member Nazrul Islam Khan on Tuesday admitted to United Hospital in the capital’s Gulshan area on Wednesday night due to gallbladder complications.
BNP Standing Committee member Professor AZM Zahid Hossain said Nazrul was hospitalised after doctors found stones in his g</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 17:01:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt committee approves over 55m copies of school textbooks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-committee-approves-over-55m-copies-of-school-textbooks</link><description>A government committee on Tuesday gave approval of a proposal for printing, binding and supplying some 55 million (5.54 crore) copies of textbooks free of cost for secondary-level students for the 2026 academic year.
The textbooks will be distributed among students of class 9, Dakhil class 9, SSC</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 17:16:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Woman found dead in travel bag in Narayanganj</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/woman-found-dead-in-travel-bag-in-narayanganj</link><description>Police have recovered the body of a young woman from inside a travel bag in Sonargaon upazila of Narayanganj.
Sonargaon Police chief Rashedul Hasan Khan said the body was found in Mograpara Union around 6:00 pm on Tuesday.
Police said the woman appeared to be around 20 years old, reports bdnews24</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 17:31:29 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>