<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 12:47:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Flash rallies by banned party ‘exist only online’: DMP</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dmp-chief-dismisses-banned-partys-flash-rallies-as-social-media-shows</link><description>Dhaka Metropolitan Police Commissioner SM Sazzat Ali has said the recent flash rallies organised by the Awami League and its affiliates “exist only on social media”, dismissing the activity as virtual displays rather than real street movements.
On Thursday, Commissioner Sazzat urged th</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 09:57:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>King Charles and Pope Leo pray together in a 500-year first</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/king-charles-and-pope-leo-pray-together-in-a-500-year-first</link><description>Britain’s King Charles and Pope Leo prayed together in the Vatican’s Sistine Chapel on Thursday, in the first joint worship including an English monarch and a Catholic pontiff since King Henry VIII broke away from Rome in 1534.
Latin chants and English prayers echoed through the chapel</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 10:12:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sellers cancel deals with Chinese oil refiner Yulong after UK sanctions, sources say</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/sellers-cancel-deals-with-chinese-oil-refiner-yulong-after-uk-sanctions-sources-say</link><description>Several suppliers have cancelled sales of Middle Eastern and Canadian oil to China's Yulong Petrochemical after the UK imposed sanctions on the refiner, which is likely to push it to buy more Russian crude, multiple sources familiar with the deals said.
The refiner, China's newest with a capacity</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 10:42:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Islami Bank and Mastercard launch Digital Payment Ecosystem at CU</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/islami-bank-and-mastercard-launch-digital-payment-ecosystem-at-cu</link><description>Islami Bank Bangladesh PLC, in collaboration with Mastercard inaugurated a fully cashless university campus at Chattogram University under Bangladesh Bank’s ‘Cashless Bangladesh’ initiative.
The transformation will enable teachers, students and visitors to conduct cashless transa</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 10:57:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hasina did not flee, she was forced to leave: Lawyer</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/hasina-did-not-flee-she-was-forced-to-leave-lawyer</link><description>Sheikh Hasina’s state-appointed lawyer has rejected the attorney general’s accusation that the deposed prime minister fled Bangladesh to evade justice, saying instead that she was “forced to leave”.
The exchange came on Thursday during the closing arguments of the July Upri</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 11:12:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh set a challenging total for West Indies in series decider</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/bangladesh-set-a-challenging-total-for-west-indies-in-series-decider</link><description>Riding on a 176-run opening stand between Saif Hassan and Soumya Sarkar, Bangladesh compiled 296 for 8 in the series decider against West Indies in Mirpur on Thursday.
It was Bangladesh’s highest total in ODIs in Mirpur in seven years.
Before departing for 82 off 72 balls with six fours and</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 11:27:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Wall Street futures dip as investors assess earnings, trade risks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/global/wall-street-futures-dip-as-investors-assess-earnings-trade-risks</link><description>Several suppliers have cancelled sales of Middle Eastern and Canadian oil to China's Yulong Petrochemical after the UK imposed sanctions on the refiner, which is likely to push it to buy more Russian crude, multiple sources familiar with the deals said.
The refiner, China's newest with a cap</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 11:57:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Integrated efforts needed to improve Dhaka’s traffic system: DMP Commissioner</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/integrated-efforts-needed-to-improve-dhakas-traffic-system-dmp-commissioner</link><description>Dhaka Metropolitan Police (DMP) Commissioner Sheikh Mohammad Sajjat Ali on Thursday stressed the need for coordinated efforts among all relevant agencies to improve the capital’s traffic management system.
He made the remarks while addressing an orientation seminar marking the conclusion of</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 12:12:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India poised to sharply cut Russian oil imports after sanctions, sources say</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/india-poised-to-sharply-cut-russian-oil-imports-after-sanctions-sources-say</link><description>Indian refiners are poised to sharply curtail imports of Russian oil to comply with new US sanctions on two top Russian producers, industry sources said on Thursday, potentially removing a major hurdle to a trade deal with the United States.
The change comes as India faces punishing 50 per cent ta</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 12:27:15 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>