<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 18:36:26 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>EC clears two new political parties for registration, including Aam Jonotar Dal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ec-clears-two-new-political-parties-for-registration-including-aam-jonotar-dal</link><description>The Election Commission has decided to register two new parties, including the Aam Jonotar Dal, whose general secretary had made headlines in early November by staging a hunger strike demanding his party’s registration.
The second party selected for registration is Jonotar Dal, bdnews24.com</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 15:45:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tea worker killed in BSF firing in Moulvibazar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tea-worker-killed-in-bsf-firing-in-moulvibazar</link><description>The Indian Border Security Force has reportedly killed a Bangladeshi tea worker in Moulvibazar’s Kulaura Upazila.
Kulaura Police Station chief Omar Faruq Mondol confirmed the incident occurred along the border in Muraichhara on Thursday afternoon.
The victim has been identified as Sukhiram</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 15:17:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Experts press for transparent security reform in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/experts-press-for-transparent-security-reform-in-bangladesh</link><description>Speakers at a dialogue in Dhaka have highlighted the importance of ensuring sustained, inclusive and accountable approaches to security sector reform in Bangladesh.
They reaffirmed that effective police reform, democratic oversight, constructive media engagement and the integration of gender and h</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 15:32:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UK universities limit recruitment from Bangladesh, Pakistan, FT reports</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/uk-universities-limit-recruitment-from-bangladesh-pakistan-ft-reports</link><description>At least nine UK universities are restricting or suspending recruitment of students from Bangladesh and Pakistan, the Financial Times reported.
The moves follow tighter UK Home Office rules on student visa refusals, the newspaper said.
Universities including Wolverhampton, Sunderland, Coventry, L</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 15:47:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh’s export receipts decline in November</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladeshs-export-receipts-decline-in-november</link><description>Bangladesh’s export earnings have fallen for four consecutive months, though the cumulative total for the first five months of the fiscal year remains marginally above last year.
The Export Promotion Bureau (EPB) reported on Thursday that the country earned $3.89 billion from exports in Nove</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 16:02:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Berlin deploys fighter jets to Poland after Russian drone incursions</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/berlin-deploys-fighter-jets-to-poland-after-russian-drone-incursions</link><description>Germany has deployed five Eurofighter jets and some 150 military personnel to the Polish town of Malbork to help secure the country's airspace, the German air force said on Thursday, in response to Russian drone incursions in September.
Polish F-16 fighter jets, Dutch F-35s, Italian AWACS surveill</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 16:17:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AI, automation &amp; the future of work in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/ai-automation-the-future-of-work-in-bangladesh</link><description>There come tipping points in the economic life of a nation when small changes will just not be enough anymorea period when the very fabric of working, learning, and adding value is being turned upside down by new technologies that promise revolution rather than evolution. Bangladesh stands at one o</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 16:32:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Healthy soil for a healthy nation: why soil health matters</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/analysis/healthy-soil-for-a-healthy-nation-why-soil-health-matters</link><description>Soil alone contributes significantly to sustaining resilient food, water and energy security. Bangladesh's fertile and sacred soil bears the legacy of historical triumph, cultural pride and agricultural revolution. However, we are careless and cruel to our soil, ignoring its health and dignity. Our</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 16:47:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The stark truth about homeless children</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/the-stark-truth-about-homeless-children</link><description>The recent story of a boy who went viral for climbing onto the roof of the Dhaka Metro Rail train was initially seen as a dangerous act. But his interview with journalists revealed a much more alarming and neglected issue in our country. Yasin is his name but he does not know how he came to Dhaka o</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 17:03:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Education heading for the wilderness</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/education-heading-for-the-wilderness</link><description>When annual examinations of government primary and secondary schools along with pre-test examinations of grade 10 are used as a pawn for realising demands by teachers, the rot set in the country's education is laid bare. Although the Bangladesh Government Secondary Teachers' Association has tempora</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 17:18:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Revised budget warrants a balancing act</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/revised-budget-warrants-a-balancing-act</link><description>The mid-year budget revision for fiscal year 2025-26 has placed the interim government in an undeniably difficult position. On the one side lies a formidable financial crunch; on the other, persistent demands from ministries and agencies for the full release of their allocated funds. Reconciling th</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 17:33:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How Europe wants to unlock Russia's frozen cash for Ukraine</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/how-europe-wants-to-unlock-russias-frozen-cash-for-ukraine</link><description>The European Union is trying to lend Ukraine tens of billions of dollars, as support from Washington wanes, Russia ekes out gains on the battlefield and Kyiv edges closer to a funding crunch early next year.
The 27-member bloc is discussing borrowing against Russian assets held in Europe frozen by</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 17:48:13 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>