<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 13:11:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>13th Parliament to begin first session on March 12</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/13th-parliament-to-begin-first-session-on-march-12</link><description>The 13th Parliament will go into its first session on March 12.  President Mohammed Shahabuddin has summoned the session to convene at 11:00 am on Thursday in the Parliament chamber of the Jatiya Sangsad Bhaban.
The President summoned the session under the powers conferred by Article 72(1) of</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 11:01:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prompt action against interference in police work: Home Minister</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/prompt-action-against-interference-in-police-work-home-minister</link><description>Home Minister Salahuddin Ahmed on Monday warned that immediate action will be taken against anyone who will obstruct the police in carrying out their duties.
He made the remarks after a meeting with the heads of law enforcement agencies at the Ministry of Home Affairs.
The minister said no one&amp;md</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 11:16:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>2,701 constables to be recruited on emergency basis: Home minister</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/2701-constables-to-be-recruited-on-emergency-basis-home-minister</link><description>Home Minister Salahuddin Ahmed on Monday said 2,701 police constables will be recruited on an emergency basis to address the existing manpower shortage in the force.
Talking to journalists at the Secretariat, the minister said restoring law and order and rebuilding public confidence remain the gov</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 11:31:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UAE-Bangladesh joint venture to invest $10m at BEPZA Economic Zone</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/uae-bangladesh-joint-venture-to-invest-10m-at-bepza-economic-zone</link><description>Integrated Composite Industries Ltd., a UAE-Bangladesh joint venture company, has signed a land lease agreement with Bangladesh Export Processing Zones Authority (BEPZA) to establish a Fibre Reinforced Polymer (FRP) composite products, steel frame and accessories manufacturing industry at the BEPZA</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 11:46:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Commodity prices, supply satisfactory, says Minister Muktadir</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/commodity-prices-supply-satisfactory-says-minister-muktadir</link><description>Commerce Minister Khandaker Abdul Muktadir on Monday said commodity prices and supply in the capital’s markets remain satisfactory during Ramadan, warning that action will be taken if any irregularities are found.
The minister made the remarks after a surprise visit to Mohammadpur Town Hall</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 12:01:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>HC orders closure of all abandoned tube-well shafts across Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hc-orders-closure-of-all-abandoned-tube-well-shafts-across-bangladesh</link><description>The High Court on Monday directed the authorities concerned to seal all abandoned deep tube-well shafts across the country within three months, following the deaths of several children who fell into open shafts in different areas.
The HC bench of Justice Ahmed Sohel and Justice Fatema Anwar passed</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 11:41:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chad closes border with Sudan after clashes kill five soldiers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/africa/chad-closes-border-with-sudan-after-clashes-kill-five-soldiers</link><description>Chad closed its eastern border with Sudan on Monday after weekend clashes linked to Sudan's civil war killed five Chadian soldiers, two sources told Reuters.
The conflict in Sudan between the Sudanese army and the paramilitary Rapid Support Forces, which erupted in Apr 2023, has periodically spill</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 11:56:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Recommended officers of 45th BCS asked to submit FF certificates</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/recommended-officers-of-45th-bcs-asked-to-submit-ff-certificates</link><description>The government on Monday asked the recommended candidates to submit freedom fighter (FF) certificates under the FF quota for appointment to various cadre posts through the 45th Bangladesh Civil Service (BCS).
The Ministry of Public Administration issued a notification in this regard, signed by Sen</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 12:11:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EU trade chief to participate in G7 meeting on Monday to discuss new tariff uncertainty, EU Commission says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/eu-trade-chief-to-participate-in-g7-meeting-on-monday-to-discuss-new-tariff-uncertainty-eu-commission-says</link><description>European Trade Commissioner Maros Sefcovic will participate in a meeting of G7 trade ministers later on Monday to discuss the uncertainty created by U.S. President Donald Trump’s introduction of new blanket 15% tariffs after a U.S. Supreme Court ruling on Friday.
A European Commission spokes</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 12:26:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EU says it will accept no increase in US tariffs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/eu-says-it-will-accept-no-increase-in-us-tariffs-after-supreme-court-ruling-a-deal-is-a-deal</link><description>The container ship MSC Ronit R, which departed the French port of Le Havre eight days previously, arrives at the Port Newark Container Terminal in Newark, New Jersey, US, July 27, 2025. REUTERS/Eduardo Munoz
The European Commission demanded on Sunday that the United States stick to the terms of an</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 12:41:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Stocks rebound at DSE, CSE after days of decline</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/stocks-rebound-at-dse-cse-after-days-of-decline</link><description>Stocks rebounded on Monday as indices rose at both the bourses—Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) and Chittagong Stock Exchange (CSE), snapping a streak of declines, with most listed companies posting gains.
At the DSE, the benchmark DSEX advanced 85 points at the close. The Shariah-based DSES gaine</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 12:56:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Man killed as two groups clash over ‘supremacy’ in Gopalganj</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/man-killed-as-two-groups-clash-over-supremacy-in-gopalganj</link><description>A clash between rival groups reportedly over local supremacy in Gopalganj’s Muksudpur has left a man dead and at least 10 others injured.
The incident occurred around 11am on Monday in Kamalapur village, according to Muksudpur Police chief Abdullah Al Mamun.
The victim has been identified a</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 13:11:18 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>