<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 14:30:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Migratory birds continue to skip Tanguar Haor</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/migratory-birds-continue-to-skip-tanguar-haor</link><description>Although winter is about to end this year, migratory birds have almost been absent at the Tanguar Haor in Sunamganj district, as bird species have continued to skip the spot over the past few years, according to locals.
Known as the country’s second largest freshwater wetland, the haor is a</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 10:48:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CA orders crackdown on document forgery</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ca-orders-crackdown-on-document-forgery-to-protect-overseas-labour-market-reputation</link><description>Chief Adviser, Professor Muhammad Yunus, has directed authorities to take urgent action against forgery and the use of fake skill training certificates, warning that such practices are damaging the country’s reputation in the international labour market.
The directive was issued on Sunday&amp;nb</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 11:03:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>July Uprising fighter dies in hospital</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/july-uprising-fighter-dies-in-hospital</link><description>Another fighter injured during the July–August uprising  in 2024 died at a hospital in the capital on Sunday.
Thirty-two-year-old Ashraful succumbed to his injuries around 8:00 am while undergoing treatment at the Intensive Care Unit (ICU) of the National Institute of Neuroscience</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 11:18:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>10 crude bombs recovered in Shariatpur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/10-crude-bombs-recovered-in-shariatpur</link><description>Joint forces in a drive seized ten crude bombs from near a house in an abandoned condition in Naria upazila of Shariatpur district early Sunday.
Tipped off, a team of joint forces comprising army and police conducted a drive at Chitu Madbar Kandi village around 3:30 am and recovered ten crude bomb</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 11:33:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US ambassador meets foreign adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/us-ambassador-meets-foreign-adviser</link><description>US Ambassador to Bangladesh Brent T Christensen met with Foreign Affairs Adviser Md Touhid Hossain on Sunday and discussed issues of bilateral relations.
"Excellent meeting with the Advisor for Foreign Affairs Md. Touhid Hossain. We had a productive discussion on key elements of our bilateral rela</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 11:48:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ex-India coach Rajput out to win respect for minnows UAE at T20 World Cup</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/ex-india-coach-rajput-out-to-win-respect-for-minnows-uae-at-t20-world-cup</link><description>Nearly two decades after guiding a youthful India to the inaugural Twenty20 World Cup title, coach Lalchand Rajput finds himself back on the global stage, although the landscape and the stakes have shifted.
Now at the helm of the United Arab Emirates national team, the former India player is navig</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 12:03:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pressure grows on British PM Starmer over Mandelson fallout</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/pressure-grows-on-british-prime-minister-starmer-over-mandelson-fallout</link><description>A senior minister faced questions about British Prime Minister Keir Starmer's future on Sunday and the deputy prime minister appeared to break ranks with his boss over his decision to appoint Peter Mandelson as ambassador to the United States.
Starmer is facing what is widely seen as the biggest c</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 12:18:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>5th Crown Cement Language Day Cup Golf Tournament held</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/5th-crown-cement-language-day-cup-golf-tournament-held</link><description>The 5th Crown Cement Language Day Cup Golf Tournament was held at Army Golf Club in Dhaka from February 4 to 7, 2026, according to a press release.
Around 815 golfers from clubs across the country, including army personnel, civilians, and foreigners, participated in this tournament.
General Waker</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 12:33:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New chair elected to lead negotiations on global plastic pollution treaty</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/new-chair-elected-to-lead-negotiations-on-global-plastic-pollution-treaty</link><description>The Intergovernmental Negotiating Committee (INC) to develop an international legally binding instrument on plastic pollution, including in the marine environment, today (Sunday) elected Ambassador Julio Cordan, of Chile, as the next INC Chair during the third part of the fifth session (INC-5.3).</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 12:48:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No Ctg port lease-out under interim government: BIDA Chairman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/no-ctg-port-lease-out-under-interim-government-bida-chairman</link><description>The interim government will not lease out the New Mooring Container Terminal at Chattogram Port during its tenure, said the head of the country’s investment authority, dismissing the reported move over finalising a deal with global port operator DP World.
Chowdhury Ashik Mahmud Bin Harun, ex</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 13:03:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Education Ministry begins MPO registration for 1,719 educational institutions</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/education-ministry-begins-mpo-registration-for-1719-educational-institutions</link><description>The Ministry of Education has started the initial process of enrolling 1,719 private educational institutions (schools and colleges) across the country in the first phase of MPO.
The ministry said that a letter has already been sent to the Finance Department seeking consent for the MPO enrollment</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 13:18:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prevent forgery of skill development training certificates: Chief adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/prevent-forgery-of-skill-development-training-certificates-chief-adviser</link><description>Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus on Sunday directed the authorities concerned to take effective measures to prevent forgery of skill development training certificates and the use of fake certificates to safeguard Bangladesh's reputation in the international labour market.
"There is significa</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 13:33:34 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>