<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 09:53:49 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Police arrest key suspect over stabbing eighth-grader to death in Rayerbazar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/police-arrest-key-suspect-over-stabbing-eighth-grader-to-death-in-rayerbazar</link><description>Police have arrested the key suspect over the brutal stabbing of an eighth-grade schoolgirl outside her home in Rayerbazar.
The suspect, identified only as Siam, was arrested on Thursday morning at Kalabagan, said Dhanmondi Zone Assistant Commissioner Shah Mostafa Tarikuzzaman.
“An FIR has</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 05:59:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>JCI Dhaka South announces new leadership for 2026</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/jci-dhaka-south-announces-new-leadership-for-2026</link><description>The annual general assembly of Junior Chamber International (JCI) Dhaka South was held on Wednesday at the Gulshan Club in the capital, marking a significant transition in leadership for the year 2026.
During the ceremonial event, Md. Naeem Haider was formally announced as the local president of J</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 06:14:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh Bank incident signals ‘government-backed mob culture’, Jamaat chief says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bangladesh-bank-incident-signals-government-backed-mob-culture-jamaat-chief-says</link><description>Jamaat-e-Islami chief Shafiqur Rahman has condemned the protests surrounding the former governor of Bangladesh Bank and his advisor, describing the events as the formal debut of a government-backed "mob culture".
In a verified Facebook post on Thursday morning, the Leader of the Opposition in parl</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 06:29:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt will establish liberal democratic state system to promote knowledge, science: PM</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-will-establish-liberal-democratic-state-system-to-promote-knowledge-science-pm</link><description>Prime Minister Tarique Rahman today said the current government will work to establish a liberal democratic state system with moral standards and dignity so that the country can move forward in all branches of knowledge and science, including education, literature, arts, science and technology.
"I</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 06:44:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DU metro rail station to remain closed for two hours for Book Fair Inauguration</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/du-metro-rail-station-to-remain-closed-for-two-hours-for-book-fair-inauguration</link><description>The metro rail station at Dhaka University (DU) will remain closed for two hours on Thursday (today), centring the inauguration of the Amar Ekushey Book Fair by Prime Minister Tarique Rahman.
During the closure, no passengers will be allowed to enter or exit the station, and no trains will stop th</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 06:59:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Police arrest 100 during overnight Ramadan crackdown in Mohammadpur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/police-arrest-100-during-overnight-ramadan-crackdown-in-mohammadpur</link><description>Dhaka police have conducted a sweeping overnight operation in Mohammadpur and Adabor, arresting 100 suspected criminals as part of efforts to curb gangs, extortionists, and drug dealers.
The raids, carried out from 10pm Wednesday to 2am Thursday, were aimed at restoring public safety, officers sai</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 07:14:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Court directs authorities to seek Interpol red notice against British MP Tulip</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/court-directs-authorities-to-seek-interpol-red-notice-against-british-mp-tulip</link><description>A Dhaka court has directed authorities to initiate steps to request an Interpol red notice for British MP Tulip Siddiq, niece of former prime minister Sheikh Hasina.
Metropolitan Senior Special Judge Md Sabbir Faiz passed the order on Wednesday, according to court bench assistant Riaz Hossain.
Th</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 07:29:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>PM calls for depoliticising education, research, arts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/pm-calls-for-depoliticising-education-research-arts</link><description>Prime Minister Tarique Rahman on Thursday said education, research, arts and literature should remain free from political influence in a civilised society.
"I believe that politicising education, research and the practice of arts and literature is never a mark of a civilised society," he said whil</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 07:44:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat accuses President of oath breach</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-accuses-president-of-oath-breach</link><description>The opposition party Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami on Wednesday accused President Mohammed Shahabuddin of breaching his constitutional oath by allegedly disclosing internal and confidential matters in a recent newspaper interview, triggering fresh political debate.
The opposition party Bangladesh Jam</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 07:59:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>4.8 magnitude earthquake jolts Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/48-magnitude-earthquake-jolts-bangladesh</link><description>An earthquake measuring 4.8 on the Richter scale was felt in several parts of Bangladesh at 12:04 pm on Thursday after an interval of nearly 13 hours, according to the United States Geological Survey (USGS).
The epicentre was located in Gyalshing of West Sikkim in India, about 455 kilometres north</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 08:14:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>100 held in Mohammadpur raids</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/100-held-in-mohammadpur-raids</link><description>Dhaka police have conducted a sweeping overnight operation in Mohammadpur and Adabor, arresting 100 suspected criminals as part of efforts to curb gangs, extortionists, and drug dealers.
The raids, carried out from 10 pm Wednesday to 2 am Thursday, were aimed at restoring public safety, officers s</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 08:59:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Growing business of selling 'pure' products in Ramadan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/food/growing-business-of-selling-pure-products-in-ramadan</link><description>Many things vary from generation to generation, but one thing is becoming exponentially more tiring: the lack of purity in our food. In this life full of hassle, all we can afford is polluted air and adulterated food. 
The urgency of this issue becomes even more profound during Ramadan, a mon</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 09:14:50 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>