<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 07:16:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Gazans trek to ruined homes as Israeli forces pull back under ceasefire</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/gazans-trek-to-ruined-homes-as-israeli-forces-pull-back-under-ceasefire</link><description>Thousands of displaced Palestinians trekked over the wastelands of Gaza to return to the ruins of their abandoned homes on Friday, after a ceasefire took effect and Israeli troops began pulling back under the first phase of an agreement to end the war.
A huge column of people filed on foot north a</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 05:48:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Man killed as bus hits covered van on Dhaka-Mawa Expressway</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/man-killed-as-bus-hits-covered-van-on-dhaka-mawa-expressway</link><description>A man was killed and 10 others injured when a passenger bus collided with a covered van on the expressway in Shibchar upazila of Madaripur district on Saturday.
The deceased was identified as Shamim Ahmed, the driver of the covered van, reports BSS.
According to Shibchar Highway Police Station, t</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 04:42:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>At least 7 dead after Philippines hit by twin quakes</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/at-least-7-dead-after-philippines-hit-by-twin-quakes</link><description>Two powerful offshore earthquakes struck off the southern Philippines on Friday, killing at least seven people, while towns near the epicentre suffered structural damage and authorities warned of strong aftershocks.
The first quake of magnitude 7.4, in waters off the town of Manay in the province</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 05:12:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Venezuela lodges complaint with UN Security Council over US actions</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/venezuela-lodges-complaint-with-un-security-council-over-us-actions</link><description>Venezuela's ambassador to the United Nations, Samuel Moncada, has accused the United States at the UN Security Council of taking actions that threaten peace in Venezuela and across the region.
"These are not isolated incidents -- they represent a growing threat to the peace and security of our nat</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 05:27:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>FDA says Indian cough syrups linked to child deaths not shipped to US</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/fda-says-indian-cough-syrups-linked-to-child-deaths-not-shipped-to-us</link><description>The US Food and Drug Administration confirmed on Friday that toxic cough syrups linked to children's deaths in India had not been shipped to the United States.
The World Health Organization has said India has a "regulatory gap" in screening locally sold syrup medicines.
The US FDA said it was awa</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 05:57:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>LPG cylinder prices should be below Tk 1,000, says energy adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/lpg-cylinder-prices-should-be-below-tk-1000-says-energy-adviser</link><description>Energy Adviser Fouzul Kabir Khan has stressed the need to bring down the price of a 12kg liquefied petroleum gas (LPG) cylinder below Tk 1,000, urging the private sector to boost efficiency and end the practice of profiteering.
Speaking at a policy dialogue on Bangladesh’s LPG sector organis</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 06:27:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Environment human rights defenders’ protection must be ensured: Rizwana</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/environment-human-rights-defenders-protection-must-be-ensured-rizwana</link><description>Environment Adviser Syeda Rizwana Hasan on Saturday stressed the need to ensure the protection of environmental human rights defenders and bring their safety under a legal framework.
"Environmental defenders around the world are facing killings and violence, an issue that the United Nations has hi</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 06:57:58 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>