<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 16:48:29 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>‘Yes’ or ‘No’ vote campaign by govt staff punishable: EC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/yes-or-no-vote-campaign-by-govt-staff-punishable-ec</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has warned against any government staff campaigning for either a “Yes” or “No” vote in the referendum.
The EC sent a directive to all returning officers on Thursday, saying taking sides would constitute a “punishable offence” under t</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 12:57:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Toddler endures another day in court as mother’s bail deferred</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/toddler-endures-another-day-in-court-as-mothers-bail-deferred</link><description>A one-and-a-half-year-old child has spent yet another day at a Dhaka court compound, waiting for the release of his mother Topsha Biswas, whose bail plea in hearing a police assault case is deferred to Sunday.
The toddler, Pranay Biswas from Dhamrai, has been staying at court as his mother remains</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 13:12:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Russia ready to evacuate staff from Iran's Bushehr nuclear plant</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/russia-is-ready-to-evacuate-its-staff-from-irans-bushehr-nuclear-plant-if-necessary-tass-reports</link><description>Russia is ready to evacuate its staff from Iran's Bushehr nuclear power plant if necessary, Alexei Likhachev, the head of Russia's state nuclear corporation, was cited as saying on Thursday by the state news agency TASS.
President Vladimir Putin said last year that hundreds of Russians were workin</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 13:27:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Southeast Bank completes centralisation, automation of documentation and limit loading functions</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/southeast-bank-completes-centralisation-automation-of-documentation-and-limit-loading-functions</link><description>The Credit Administration Division (CAD) of Southeast Bank PLC (SEBPLC) hosted an event on Wednesday to mark the successful completion of its full centralisation and automation of documentation and limit loading functions.
According to a press release, this strategic engagement significantly impro</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 13:42:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>'Political commitment, inclusive planning, coordinated action needed for Bhola's development'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/political-commitment-inclusive-planning-coordinated-action-needed-for-bholas-development</link><description>Sustainable development in Bhola requires political commitment, inclusive planning, and coordinated action among stakeholders, speakers at a National Dialogue on Thursday said.
The dialogue, “Our Vision for Fair Elections and Bhola’s Development,” was organised by Coast</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 13:57:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US ambassador warns of China's growing manufacturing dominance</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-ambassador-warns-of-chinas-growing-manufacturing-dominance</link><description>The top US envoy to China called Thursday for fair and reciprocal trade between the world's two largest economies and expressed concern about projections that China's dominance of global manufacturing will grow even further in the years to come.
US Ambassador David Perdue told business and governm</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 14:12:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mohammed Younus elected as chairman of Shahjalal Islami Bank</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/mohammed-younus-elected-as-chairman-of-shahjalal-islami-bank</link><description>Mr. Mohammed Younus has been unanimously elected as Chairman of the Board of Directors of Shahjalal Islami Bank PLC during its 404th Board meeting held on Wednesday.
In the same meeting, Mr. Mohiuddin Ahmed was re-elected and Mr. Fakir Akhtaruzzaman was elected as Vice-Chairmen, respectively, of t</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 14:27:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Three more local garment factories receive LEED certification</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/three-more-local-garment-factories-receive-leed-certification</link><description>Three more local garment factories have received LEED certification from the US Green Building Council (USGBC), with one achieving the highest score globally, taking the total number to 273.
HAMS Garments Ltd-- located in Sreepur of Gazipur has achieved Leadership in Energy and Environmental Desig</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 14:42:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BB buys $55m through dollar auction</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/bb-buys-55m-through-dollar-auction</link><description>Bangladesh Bank (BB) today (Thursday) purchased US$55 million from five commercial banks through multiple auction methods as part of its ongoing strategy to curb the depreciation of the US dollar against the taka and revitalise the remittance and export sectors. According to central bank data,</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 16:03:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Microcredit borrowers to become bank owners; ordinance promulgated</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/microcredit-borrowers-to-become-bank-owners-ordinance-promulgated</link><description>The interim government has promulgated the ‘Microfinance Bank Ordinance, 2026’ to further streamline the country’s microcredit operations, create employment opportunities, alleviate poverty, and ensure ownership of microfinance institutions by borrowers themselves.
Under the newl</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 16:18:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt approves new import policy, key ordinances to boost exports, protect women</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-approves-new-import-policy-key-ordinances-to-boost-exports-protect-women</link><description>The interim government has approved a new Import Policy Order for 2025–2028 alongside a raft of ordinances aimed at strengthening trade facilitation, expanding legal protections for women, and updating regulatory frameworks across several sectors.
The decisions were taken at the weekly meeti</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 16:33:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Protect your votes, conspiracies still on: Tarique Rahman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/protect-your-votes-conspiracies-still-on-tarique-rahman</link><description>BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman on Thursday warned that a “vote-rigging conspiracy” by a party has not yet ended and urged voters to remain vigilant to protect their votes in the upcoming national election.
“The conspiracy of one party has not ended yet. One party has fled the countr</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 16:48:29 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>