<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 06:54:26 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Metro rail staff threaten agitation over voting rights</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/metro-rail-staff-threaten-agitation-over-voting-rights</link><description>Around 2,000 employees of the Dhaka metro rail company have threatened to launch a tough protest programme to press for their voting rights, alleging that the authorities cancelled all leave without making arrangements for them to cast their votes.
In a notice issued on February 2, the Dhaka Mass</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 03:45:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>2 dead, 13 injured as building collapses in India's Rajasthan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/2-dead-13-injured-as-building-collapses-in-indias-rajasthan</link><description>At least two people were killed and 13 others injured in Saturday's building collapse in Kota in India's western state of Rajasthan, a government official said Sunday.
Briefing the media on the mishap, Kota's Divisional Commissioner Anil Agrawal said two dead bodies had been recovered from the sit</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 04:00:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IDRA pushes deep reforms to strengthen insurance sector</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/idra-pushes-deep-reforms-to-strengthen-insurance-sector</link><description>The interim government has launched a sweeping reform agenda for Bangladesh's insurance sector, targeting long-standing governance failures, weak regulation and eroded public trust that have driven insurance penetration to historic lows.
The reforms aim to stabilise troubled insurers, protect poli</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 04:15:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>First 'Incubation Hub' launched at RU to encourage industry-oriented research</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/first-incubation-hub-launched-at-ru-to-encourage-industry-oriented-research</link><description>Rajshahi University (RU) has launched its first-ever 'Incubation Hub' with the aim of transforming university education and research into industry-oriented initiatives, creating entrepreneurs, increasing domestic production, and building a self-reliant nation.
The Incubation Hub has been establish</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 04:30:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Over 75pc voters still equate dev with infrastructure, job creation, reveals CPD survey</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/over-75pc-voters-still-equate-dev-with-infrastructure-job-creation-reveals-cpd-survey</link><description>More than three-quarters of voters in Bangladesh continue to equate development with visible infrastructure such as roads, bridges and culverts, along with employment generation, reflecting a narrow understanding of progress that could undermine sustainable and green development, according to a new</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 04:45:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hili land port highway upgrade delayed again, cost jumps to Tk 588cr</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/hili-land-port-highway-upgrade-delayed-again-cost-jumps-to-tk-588cr</link><description>A major road development project meant to strengthen connectivity between Dhaka and Hili land port in Dinajpur is facing further delays, with the government proposing a sharp rise in costs and an extension of the implementation timeline by nearly three years beyond the original deadline.
 
T</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 05:00:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Indefinite strike again at Ctg Port</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/indefinite-strike-again-at-ctg-port</link><description>Workers protesting under the banner of the Chittagong Port Protection Struggle Council are continuing their indefinite strike to push for a four-point list of demands, including the cancellation of the lease of the New Mooring Container Terminal (NCT) to UAE-based DP World.
The port workers and em</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 04:49:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Election fever absent in Kurigram’s char areas amid daily struggles</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/election-fever-absent-in-kurigrams-char-areas-amid-daily-struggles</link><description>Despite the rising political atmosphere ahead of the national elections, the impact is barely felt in the char areas of Kurigram.
For residents here, immediate concerns far outweigh electoral politics — from securing a home and accessing medical care to ensuring their families survive</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 05:04:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique pledges to restore 'BDR' name</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-pledges-to-restore-bdr-name</link><description>Tarique Rahman has said the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) will restore the name of the Bangladesh Rifles (BDR) should the party return to power.
On Saturday, he said the BNP plans to consult with the Army to declare the anniversary of the Pilkhana massacre as “Martyred Soldiers Day&amp;rdqu</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 05:19:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Brad Arnold, lead singer of Grammy-nominated rock band 3 Doors Down, dies at 47</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/entertainment/brad-arnold-lead-singer-of-grammy-nominated-rock-band-3-doors-down-dies-at-47</link><description>Brad Arnold, the lead singer of the Grammy-nominated rock band 3 Doors Down, died Saturday, months after he announced that he had been diagnosed with Stage 4 kidney cancer. He was 47.
The band said in a statement that Arnold "passed away peacefully, surrounded by loved ones, in his sleep after his</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 05:34:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Italy not to join Board of Peace: FM</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/italy-not-to-join-board-of-peace-fm</link><description>Italy "cannot participate" in the US proposed Board of Peace as its charter conflicts with Italy's Constitution, Italian Foreign Minister Antonio Tajani said Saturday.
In an interview with Italy's ANSA news agency, Tajani said the board's charter posed "insurmountable" legal conflicts with Article</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 05:49:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Female voters 62.8 million in JS polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/female-voters-628-million-in-js-polls</link><description>A total of 6,28,85,525 female voters will be eligible to cast their ballots in the 13th Jatiya Sangsad (JS) Election and Referendum scheduled for February 12, as the overall number of voters are 12,77,11,899 across the country.
Among the total, the remaining 6,48,25,154 is male voters and 1,220 be</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 06:04:08 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>