<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 03:17:22 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Govt suspends int'l flights at Cox's Bazar Airport</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-suspends-intl-flights-at-coxs-bazar-airport</link><description>The Ministry of Civil Aviation and Tourism (MoCAT) has suspended all scheduled and non-scheduled international flights at Cox's Bazar Airport following a government directive.
In a notification issued on Monday, the ministry said international flight operations at the airport will remain suspended</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 23:42:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Experts foresee 'huge' problem with merger of five Islamic banks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/experts-foresee-huge-problem-with-merger-of-five-islamic-banks</link><description>Criticising the central bank's proposed merger of five problem-ridden Islamic banks, speakers at a roundtable discussion expressed the fear that the merged Sariah-based bank could become a huge burden for the government.
Their fear comes in the backdrop of experience gained earlier from the merger</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 23:57:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A2i project faces massive cost surge</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/a2i-project-faces-massive-cost-surge</link><description>The government's flagship Aspire-to-Innovate (a2i) project has run into major financial controversy after racking up deferred payments of Tk 3.0 billion in its data-preservation segment, twelve times the original allocation.
Despite an initial provision of only Tk 250 million, the project author</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 00:12:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US need not worry over BD-China ties, says adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/us-need-not-worry-over-bd-china-ties-says-adviser</link><description>Foreign Affairs Adviser Md Touhid Hossain said on Tuesday that there is no reason for the United States or any other country to be concerned about Bangladesh's balanced relationship with China.
He made the remark while responding to a question at the Ministry of Foreign Affairs regarding comment</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 00:27:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt tightens spending control, bars extra budget allocations</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-tightens-spending-control-bars-extra-budget-allocations</link><description>The government has imposed a strict expenditure ceiling on all ministries and divisions as part of its ongoing austerity measures amid mounting fiscal pressures and slower revenue growth.

According to a recent directive from the Ministry of Finance, total expenditure in the revised budget for fi</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 00:42:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Power import payment rules relaxed</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/power-import-payment-rules-relaxed</link><description>Bangladesh Bank (BB) has relaxed regulations governing power-import payments, allowing authorised dealer banks to make outward remittances for electricity purchases under government-approved cross-border arrangements without obtaining prior approval for each case from the central bank.
In a circul</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 00:57:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bond yields climb as banks hold back</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bond-yields-climb-as-banks-hold-back</link><description>Yields on two types of long-term treasury bonds rose sharply on Tuesday, as banks showed reluctance to invest their surplus funds in government securities in an effort to manage their portfolios more efficiently.
According to auction results, the cut-off yield, effectively the interest rate, on</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 01:27:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Marico posts record quarterly revenue on strong Parachute sales</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/marico-posts-record-quarterly-revenue-on-strong-parachute-sales</link><description>Marico has secured double-digit revenue growth year-on-year to Tk 5 billion in the second quarter through September this year, the highest quarterly revenue since its listing on the secondary market.
The growth, achieved in an adverse macroeconomic situation, was driven by the company's flagship</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 01:57:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Land sales boost Eastern Housing's Q1 profit by 27pc</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/land-sales-boost-eastern-housings-q1-profit-by-27pc</link><description>Eastern Housing declared a 27 per cent rise in profit to Tk 201.79 million for the first quarter through September of FY26 as revenue from land sales experienced a boost and finance income grew modestly.
The company witnessed higher growth in land sales compared to its apartment business in Q1 o</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 02:12:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Runner Automobiles returns to profit in FY25 on strong three-wheeler sales</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/runner-automobiles-returns-to-profit-in-fy25-on-strong-three-wheeler-sales</link><description>Runner Automobiles returned to profit in FY25, driven by robust sales growth, particularly in the three-wheeler segment, after enduring losses for two consecutive years.
The country's pioneering motorcycle manufacturer reported a consolidated profit of Tk 102 million in FY25 against a loss of Tk</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 02:27:35 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>