<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 15:21:49 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nomination of Jamaat candidate, 16 others cancelled in Ctg</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nomination-of-jamaat-candidate-16-others-cancelled-in-ctg</link><description>The nomination papers of Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami candidate Dr. AKM Fazlul Haque in the Chattogram-9 constituency have been cancelled due to unclear information about dual citizenship and failure to submit required documents.
Additionally, a total of 16 candidates had their nominations cancelled</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 14:06:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt promotes three additional secretaries</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-promotes-three-additional-secretaries</link><description>The government has promoted three additional secretaries to the rank of secretary.
The Ministry of Public Administration issued three separate notifications on Sunday confirming the promotions.
Md Saidur Rahman Khan, director general of the Department of Social Services, was promoted to secretary</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 12:37:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jute spinners demand suspension of raw jute exports amid supply crisis</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/jute-spinners-demand-suspension-of-raw-jute-exports-amid-supply-crisis</link><description>Bangladesh Jute Spinners Association (BJSA) on Sunday urged the government to completely suspend raw jute exports, warning that continued exports amid declining production and soaring prices could severely damage the country’s jute industry.
The demand was formally placed through an applicat</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 12:52:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sonali Bank holds Doa Mahfil seeking eternal peace of Khaleda Zia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/sonali-bank-holds-doa-mahfil-seeking-eternal-peace-of-khaleda-zia</link><description>Sonali Bank PLC arranged a Doa mahfil to pray for the eternal peace of former Prime Minister and BNP Chairperson Begum Khaleda Zia.
Doa mahfil was held at the bank’s mosque on Sunday after the prayer of Zohor, according to a press release.
Chairman of Sonali Bank PLC, Mohammad Muslim Chowdh</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 13:07:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shimanto Bank Inks MoU with Novoair Limited</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/shimanto-bank-inks-mou-with-novoair-limited</link><description>Shimanto Bank PLC has recently signed a Memorandum of Understanding (MoU) with Novoair Limited at the Bank’s Head Office.
Under this agreement, all Debit and Credit Card holders of Shimanto Bank will be entitled to enjoy special facilities when availing services from Novoair Limited, accordi</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 13:22:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Venezuela’s Maduro sits in US custody as loyalists vow defiance</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/venezuelas-maduro-sits-in-us-custody-as-loyalists-vow-defiance</link><description>Venezuela's toppled leader Nicolas Maduro was in a New York detention center on Sunday awaiting drug charges after President Donald Trump ordered an audacious raid to capture him, saying the US would take control of the oil-producing nation.
The image of the 63-year-old Maduro blindfolded and hand</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 13:37:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC declares 1,842 candidate valid, 723 invalid in 300 constituencies</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-declares-1842-candidate-valid-723-invalid-in-300-constituencies</link><description>The Election Commission has declared 1,842 candidates valid while 723 others invalid for the country’s 300 constituencies as the five-day scrutiny process of nomination papers ended on Sunday.
During the scrutiny started on December 30, the returning officers accepted the nomination papers o</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 13:52:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>403rd board meeting of Shahjalal Islami Bank held</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/403rd-board-meeting-of-shahjalal-islami-bank-held</link><description>The 403rd meeting of the Board of Directors of Shahjalal Islami Bank PLC was held recently at the Corporate Head Office of the Bank.
The meeting was presided over by the Chairman A. K. Azad. The Board approved a number of investment proposals, according to a press release.
Among others, the Vice-</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 14:07:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BRAC healthcare: A quiet reminder of what our health system could be</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/brac-healthcare-a-quiet-reminder-of-what-our-health-system-could-be</link><description>For months, during my daily commute, a modest signboard reading BRAC Healthcare at Siddheswari kept catching my eye. I paid little attention at first, assuming it was just another pharmacy — one more addition to Dhaka’s crowded streetscape of drugstores and clinics. Curiosity, however,</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 14:22:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Secondary level students to get all textbooks by January 15: NCTB</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/secondary-level-students-to-get-all-textbooks-by-january-15-nctb</link><description>The National Curriculum and Textbook Board (NCTB) has expressed optimism to ensure distributing the rest of all the books for the secondary students by January 15.
After completing the distribution of hundred percent textbooks of the pre-primary and primary level students, the NCTB has fixed the t</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 14:37:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCP leader held over Dinajpur ‘extortion’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/ncp-leader-held-over-dinajpur-extortion</link><description>Police have arrested NCP leader Tafsir Hasan in an extortion case in Bochaganj Upazila in Dinajpur.
According to Anwar Hossain, additional police superintendent of the district, Tafsir and his associate Monjurul Islam were detained around Saturday midnight.
Both were sent to jail on Sunday aftern</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 14:52:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Political motives were behind enforced disappearances, says Commission in final report</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/political-motives-were-behind-enforced-disappearances-says-commission-in-final-report</link><description>The Commission of Inquiry on Enforced Disappearances today (Sunday) submitted its final report to Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus, stating that enforced disappearances in Bangladesh were largely politically motivated and carried out with involvement from the highest levels of the immediate p</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 15:07:10 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>