<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 03:14:18 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Misuse of climate fund must be stopped</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/misuse-of-climate-fund-must-be-stopped</link><description>Bangladesh, one of the world's most climate-exposed nations, has recently got a sobering reminder how vulnerable its own governance systems remains in the face of an unfolding planetary emergency. The latest findings of the Transparency International Bangladesh (TIB) reveal that more than half of t</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 17:00:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Child labour and development parameter</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/child-labour-and-development-parameter</link><description>The multiple indicator cluster survey (MICS) carried out by the Bangladesh Bureau of statistics (BBS) has presented an alarming picture of child labour and various negative aspects related to it. As high as 9.2 per cent children in the age bracket of 5-17 are compelled to perform tasks requiring ph</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 17:15:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UN rights body regrets Hasina’s death sentence, calls verdict important for victims</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/un-rights-body-regrets-hasinas-death-sentence-calls-verdict-important-for-victims</link><description>The United Nations human rights body on Monday said they "regret" the imposition of the death penalty, which they oppose in all circumstances but described the verdict as an important moment for victims of the grave violations committed during the suppression of protests last year.
“The hand</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 17:30:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP hails Hasina’s death sentence verdict, says justice served</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-hails-hasinas-death-sentence-verdict-says-justice-served</link><description>BNP on Monday night said it believes justice has been served through the International Crimes Tribunal’s verdict sentencing deposed Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina to death for crimes against humanity committed during the July-August Uprising.
“After a long judicial process, following int</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 18:01:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCSA urges media not to air speeches of convicted persons</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ncsa-urges-media-not-to-air-speeches-of-convicted-persons</link><description>National Cyber Security Agency (NCSA) has requested not to air the speech of the convicted persons on the media for the interest of the national security.
Post, Telecommunication and Information Technology Affairs Ministry’s release said today (Monday), BSS reports. 
The release said,</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 18:16:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ousted PM Hasina sentenced to death</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ousted-pm-hasina-sentenced-to-death</link><description>Bangladesh's ousted prime minister Sheikh Hasina was Monday sentenced to death for the "crimes against humanity" committed during the July-August mass uprising last year that toppled her government. In its verdict telecast live, the International Crimes Tribunal-1 (ICT-1) in Dhaka also handed dow</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 18:31:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Swiss logistics giant to operate Pangaon Inland Container Terminal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/swiss-logistics-giant-to-operate-pangaon-inland-container-terminal</link><description>MEDLOG, a Switzerland-based world leader in inland logistics, will to manage and operate the Pangaon Inland Container Terminal (PICT) near Dhaka for 22 years.
A concession agreement was signed to this end between Chittagong Port Authority (CPA) and MEDLOG Bangladesh Private Ltd on Monday (November</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 20:00:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka to send formal letter to Delhi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dhaka-to-send-formal-letter-to-delhi</link><description>The Ministry of Foreign Affairs has called upon India to hand over to the Bangladesh government former Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina and former Home Minister Asaduzzaman Khan Kamal, both fugitives who were sentenced to death by the International Crimes Tribunal on Monday for crimes against humanity.</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 01:31:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hasina's punishment milestone for future: Salahuddin</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/hasinas-punishment-milestone-for-future-salahuddin</link><description>BNP Standing Committee member Salahuddin Ahmed on Monday said that while the punishment handed down to Sheikh Hasina does not fully reflect the gravity of her crimes, the verdict represents a significant milestone for the country's future.
The International Crimes Tribunal on Monday sentenced form</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 01:46:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat satisfied over death sentence to Hasina</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-satisfied-over-death-sentence-to-hasina</link><description>Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami expressed on Monday satisfaction with the verdict sentencing ousted Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina to death in a case over crimes against humanity committed during the July (2024) mass uprising.
In its immediate reaction following the judgement delivered on Monday, the par</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 02:01:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCP demands execution of sentence on Hasina in a month</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ncp-demands-execution-of-sentence-on-hasina-in-a-month</link><description>National Citizen Party (NCP) has demanded the execution of ousted prime minister Sheikh Hasina's death sentence be carried out within one month.
"The convicted criminals responsible for enforced disappearances and genocide are the worst not just in Bangladesh, but across global history," NCP conve</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 02:16:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Next polls to fix country’s future course for 100 yrs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/next-polls-to-fix-countrys-future-course-for-100-yrs</link><description>Upcoming dual voting in national elections and referendum will determine the course of Bangladesh for over 100 years, says Chief Adviser of the post-uprising government Prof Muhammad Yunus while instructing deputy commissioners to play fair in the polls.
He asks the DCs to carry out their responsi</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 02:31:33 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>