<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 22:32:20 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Turkish observers meet Tarique ahead of polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/turkish-observers-meet-tarique-ahead-of-polls</link><description>A delegation of Turkish election observers met BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman at his Gulshan office on Wednesday night ahead of tomorrow’s national election.
The delegation, visiting Bangladesh to observe the 13th National Parliament election and concurrent referendum, arrived at the chairman&amp;r</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 18:58:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Police to wear hidden cameras during polls: EC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/police-to-wear-hidden-cameras-during-polls-ec</link><description>Police personnel deployed at polling centres for the 13th National Parliamentary Elections and referendum tomorrow will wear hidden cameras as part of enhanced security measures, the Election Commission (EC) said on Wednesday.
The information was disclosed in a statement signed by EC Director (Pub</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 19:13:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>T20 WC boycott was govt’s  decision, I remain firm on this: Asif Nazrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/cricket/t20-wc-boycott-was-govts-decision-i-remain-firm-on-this-asif-nazrul</link><description>Youth and Sports Adviser Dr. Asif Nazrul has clarified that the decision for Bangladesh not to play the T20 World Cup matches in India was taken solely by the government due to security concerns, dispelling confusion arising from his recent remarks.
In a Facebook post on Wednesday, the Adviser add</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 19:28:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat Ameer to cast vote in Monipur Centre</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-ameer-to-cast-vote-in-monipur-centre</link><description>Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami Ameer Dr Shafiqur Rahman will cast his vote at 8:00 am on Thursday.
He will vote at the Monipur High School (Boys’ Branch) polling centre in his constituency, Dhaka-15, located at 60 feet area, Jamaat said in a statement on Wednesday, reports UNB.
Meanwhile, Chief</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 19:43:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Result sheet irregularity: Presiding officer removed from duty in Jhenaidah</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/result-sheet-irregularity-presiding-officer-removed-from-duty-in-jhenaidah</link><description>The presiding officer of Salimunnesa Girls’ School polling centre under Jhenaidah-4 constituency was removed from election duty on Wednesday night following the seizure of 23 signed result sheets.
The removed officer, Jasmine Ara, was serving as presiding officer at Centre No. 5 of Kaliganj</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 19:58:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Five arrested in Dhaka for breaching election code</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/five-arrested-in-dhaka-for-breaching-election-code</link><description>A summary trial court on Wednesday detained and sentenced five people, including a Jamaat-e-Islami activist, for violating the election code of conduct in different areas of the capital.
In Sutrapur, a Jamaat worker, Habibur Rahman, 63, was caught red-handed while allegedly preparing to distribute</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 20:13:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Krishak Dal leader’s veins severed in Rajshahi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/krishak-dal-leaders-veins-severed-in-rajshahi</link><description>A local leader of Krishak Dal sustained critical injuries after miscreants severed the veins of both his hands and legs in Charghat upazila of Rajshahi on Wednesday afternoon.
The injured was identified as Biraj Ali, 47, son of late Amir Mollah of Ramchandrapur village. He is the general secretary</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 20:28:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Election spending stirs price pressures</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/election-spending-stirs-price-pressures</link><description>The 13th national election, being held today (Thursday), is widely believed to have injected a short-term burst of liquidity into the economy, pushing up prices in several local markets.
Transport, food, campaign materials and related services have seen noticeable spikes in demand in the run-up to</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 21:45:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Central law and order cell set up for polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-sets-up-central-law-and-order-cell-ahead-of-election</link><description>The Election Commission has set up a Central Law and Order Coordination Cell to help ensure that the national election and referendum are held in a fair and peaceful manner.
The cell is operating from Room 417 of the Election Commission building.
It has been established to facilitate information-</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 17:25:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nazrul urges voters to guard polling centres in shifts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/nazrul-urges-voters-to-guard-polling-centres-in-shifts</link><description>BNP Standing Committee Member and Chairman of the party’s Central Election steering Committee Nazrul Islam Khan on Wednesday urged party leaders, activists and voters to guard polling centres in shifts to ensure a free and fair election.
He made the call at an emergency press conference held</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 22:00:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two election officials detained for 'dining at Jamaat leader’s house' in Lakshmipur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/two-election-officials-detained-for-dining-at-jamaat-leaders-house-in-lakshmipur</link><description>Two election officials were detained in Lakshmipur on Wednesday night after they allegedly left their polling centre and went to have dinner at the residence of a local Jamaat leader.
The incident took place at Nolthogi Madinatul Ulum Islamia Madrasa polling centre under the Lakshmipur-3 (Sadar) c</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 22:15:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Brother of Kurigram-2 NCP candidate attacked</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/brother-of-kurigram-2-ncp-candidate-attacked</link><description>The National Citizen Party (NCP) on Wednesday alleged that the brother of its Kurigram-2 candidate Atiq Mujahid was attacked.
In a Facebook post, the party claimed that Ashiq, brother of the NCP-nominated candidate, was attacked by Chhatra Dal President Amimul, Shaon, Sohel and around 35 BNP activ</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 22:30:58 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>