<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 09:28:18 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Country to fully implement payment interoperability by 2027: BB governor</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/country-to-fully-implement-payment-interoperability-by-2027-bb-governor</link><description>Bangladesh Bank (BB) Governor Dr Ahsan H Mansur has said the country is expected to fully implement interoperability across its payment ecosystem by July 2027.
To reach this milestone and move toward a cashless or less-cash society, the central bank has signed a digital agreement with the Gates Fo</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 06:14:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Man crushed under train in Gazipur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/man-crushed-under-train-in-gazipur</link><description>An unidentified man was killed after being hit by a train in Kaliakair of Gazipur district on Monday.
The deceased, aged about 60 years, was wearing a lungi and a t-shirt, reports UNB.
The train hit the man on the Dhaka-Rajshahi railway route in the Bajhizoltoli area of Kaliakair, said Joydebpur</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 06:29:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Woman killed being hit by pickup van in Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/woman-killed-being-hit-by-pickup-van-in-dhaka</link><description>An unidentified woman was killed after being hit by a speeding pickup van in front of Forazi Hospital at the Rampura area in Dhaka on Sunday night.
Hasan, a pedestrian, said that when the woman, aged about 65, was crossing the road, the pickup van knocked her down around 10:45 pm, reports UNB.
So</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 06:44:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>90pc people in S Asia will be at risk of extreme heat by 2030: WB</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/90pc-people-in-s-asia-will-be-at-risk-of-extreme-heat-by-2030-wb</link><description>South Asia, with its dense population, high temperature and exposed geography, is one of the world’s most climate-vulnerable regions—and Bangladesh is among the most at risk, according to the World Bank's latest report.
By 2030, nearly 90 per cent of the region’s population will</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 06:46:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Legal processes have driven all reforms: Asif Nazrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/legal-processes-have-driven-all-reforms-asif-nazrul</link><description>Law, Justice and Parliamentary Affairs Adviser Dr Asif Nazrul today said that all reforms and changes in the country have been achieved through legal processes.
"In cases of family disputes, people no longer need to physically go to court, as free services are now available through legal aid. Unde</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 07:01:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh sees 319 murders in October</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/bangladesh-sees-319-murders-in-october</link><description>As Bangladesh approaches its national elections scheduled for February 2025, crime statistics indicate a rise in criminal incidents across the country.
According to police headquarters statistics, October saw 319 murders nationwide, slightly up from 297 in September but just below 321 cases in Aug</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 07:16:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mob kills youth over suspected theft in Faridpur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/mob-kills-youth-over-suspected-theft-in-faridpur</link><description>A youth was beaten to death by an angry mob on suspicion of theft in Nagarkanda upazila of Faridpur early Monday.
The deceased was identified as Shahin, 23, son of Mostafa from Gajgah area of the upazila. Three others were injured in the incident.
The injured were identified as Suman Sheikh (25),</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 07:31:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Construction worker beaten to death on theft suspicion</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/construction-worker-beaten-to-death-on-theft-suspicion</link><description>A construction worker was beaten to death in a mob attack over suspected theft in Sonachora area of Bandar upazila of Narayanganj on Monday morning.
The deceased was identified as Parvez, 30, son of the late Tara Mia of Siddhirganj’s Barmashil area.  Parvez was a tenant at Bulbul Misha&amp;</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 07:46:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EU envoy calls for stronger Bangladesh–EU cooperation in civil aviation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/eu-envoy-calls-for-stronger-bangladesh-eu-cooperation-in-civil-aviation</link><description>European Union Ambassador and Head of Delegation to Bangladesh Michael Miller has underscored the potential for deeper Bangladesh-EU collaboration in the civil aviation sector, emphasising the need for a fair and competitive environment to unlock that potential.
He highlighted the EU’s offer</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 08:01:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>324 foreign ships dock at Mongla Port in 146 days of FY-26</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/324-foreign-ships-dock-at-mongla-port-in-146-days-of-fy-26</link><description>Mongla Port, the country's second-largest seaport, recorded the arrival of 324 foreign commercial ships in the first 146 days of the current 2025-26 fiscal year (FY), significantly boosting its revenue earnings.
According to the Mongla Port Authority (MPA), of the total ships, 41 carried 13,854 TE</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 08:16:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two bodies recovered in Dhaka, Bagerhat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/two-bodies-recovered-in-dhaka-bagerhat</link><description>The bodies of two men have been recovered from the Bakshi Bazar area of Dhaka and Chitalmari upazila of Bagerhat.
In Dhaka, police recovered the body of an unidentified man, aged around 65, from the Bakshi Bazar area in the capital on Monday morning.
The body was found around 11:00 am and was lat</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 08:31:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt importing rice from India to keep prices stable</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/govt-importing-rice-from-india-to-keep-prices-stable</link><description>The government has decided to import rice from India to keep rice prices stable in the market, said Finance Adviser Salehuddin Ahmed.
He shared the information while talking to reporters after a meeting of the Advisory Council Committee on Government Procurement at the Secretariat on Monday. He sa</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 08:46:42 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>