<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 15:33:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>ACC sues 3 BCS cadres for using fake certificates to get job</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/acc-sues-3-bcs-cadres-for-using-fake-certificates-to-get-job</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) on Tuesday filed three cases against three BCS cadres on charges of obtaining jobs in the Bangladesh Civil Service (BCS) by submitting forged academic certificates to the Public Service Commission (PSC).
Among them, two joined the BCS Administration Cadre and o</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 13:15:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Abbas ordered attack on Patwary, Tarique consented: Nahid</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/abbas-ordered-attack-on-patwary-tarique-consented-nahid</link><description>NCP Convenor Nahid Islam has alleged that the “attack” on the party’s Dhaka-8 candidate Nasiruddin Patwary was carried out on the “instructions” of BNP candidate Mirza Abbas, with the “consent” of Tarique Rahman.
Speaking at a press conference on Tuesday a</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 13:30:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Newly-formed Shari’ah Supervisory Committee meets with Board of Directors of Islami Bank</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/newly-formed-shariah-supervisory-committee-meets-with-board-of-directors-of-islami-bank</link><description>An exchange of views between the Board of Directors of Islami Bank Bangladesh PLC and the members of the newly formed Shar‘ah Supervisory Committee was held on Tuesday at the Islami Bank Tower, according to a press release.
Professor Dr. M. Zubaidur Rahman, chairman of the bank, Mohammad Khu</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 13:45:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IFIC Bank opens ATM Booth at Arbella premises, Gazipur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ific-bank-opens-atm-booth-at-arbella-premises-gazipur</link><description>To make financial transactions easier and faster, IFIC Bank installed an ATM booth at the premises of Arbella Fashion Limited, located in Sreepur, Gazipur.
The booth was formally inaugurated on Tuesday, by the bank’s Head of Operations, Mr. Helal Ahmed, and the Managing Director of Arbella F</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 14:00:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shimanto Bank Inks MoU with Trust And Pay Limited</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/shimanto-bank-inks-mou-with-trust-and-pay-limited</link><description>Shimanto Bank has recently signed a Memorandum of Understanding (MoU) with Trust And Pay (TAP) at the bank’s head office, according to a press release.
As part of this agreement, Shimanto Bank customers will enjoy the facility to transfer funds from their accounts to Trust And Pay (TAP) acco</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 13:15:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trust Bank launches Visa Signature Plus credit card</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/trust-bank-launches-visa-signature-plus-credit-card</link><description>Trust Bank PLC has officially launched its premium credit card ‘Visa Signature Plus’ on 22nd January 2026, marking another milestone in the bank’s continuous efforts to enhance its card portfolio and customer experience.
The new credit card was unveiled by the Chairman of Trust B</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 13:30:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Community Bank launches charge-free special deposit products for NRB customers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/community-bank-launches-charge-free-special-deposit-products-for-nrb-customers</link><description>Community Bank Bangladesh PLC has introduced two charge-free special deposit products—“Community ProbashShonchoy” and “Community ProbashPriojon”—designed for Non-Resident Bangladeshis (NRBs) and families dependent on expatriate income.
The launch was announced a</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 13:45:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BRAC Bank touches 172,502 lives in 2025 through CSR initiatives</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/brac-bank-touches-172502-lives-in-2025-through-csr-initiatives</link><description>BRAC Bank has positively impacted 172,502 lives across Bangladesh in 2025 through its impactful Corporate Social Responsibility (CSR) initiatives, according to a press release.
From women’s education and disability inclusion to climate adaptation and humanitarian initiatives, the bank’</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 14:00:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Temporary suspension of Al-Arafah Islami Bank’s different services in phases for system upgradation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/temporary-suspension-of-al-arafah-islami-banks-different-services-in-phases-for-system-upgradation</link><description>To enhance technological capacity and ensure more secure and uninterrupted banking services, Al-Arafah Islami Bank PLC has undertaken a modernization of its Core Banking System (CBS), according to a press release.
As a result, all banking services will remain temporarily suspended for three days f</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 14:15:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC bans motorcycles for 3 days ahead of election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-bans-motorcycles-for-3-days-ahead-of-election</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has imposed restrictions on the plying of motorcycles across the country three days before and after the national election.
According to the EC directives issued on Tuesday, the movement of four types of vehicles — trucks, microbuses, taxi-cab and motorcycles &amp;md</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 14:30:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>July Charter will ensure religious rights of citizens: Ali Riaz</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/july-charter-will-ensure-religious-rights-of-citizens-ali-riaz</link><description>Chief Adviser’s Special Assistant Professor Ali Riaz on Tuesday said the July National Charter will ensure the religious rights of every citizen and establish a society based on equality, human dignity, and social justice.
 “July National Charter will establish a society based on</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 14:45:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>51.4pc growth of remittance inflow in first 26 days of January</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/514pc-growth-of-remittance-inflow-in-first-26-days-of-january</link><description>Inflow of remittances witnessed a year-on-year growth of 51.4 per cent reaching US$2,708 million in the first 26 days of January, according to the latest data of Bangladesh Bank (BB) issued on Tuesday.
Last year, during the same period, the country's remittance inflow was $1,789 million.
During t</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 15:00:44 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>