<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 16:41:08 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Humayun elected president, Akik general secretary in BADC Agriculturalists’ Association poll</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/humayun-elected-president-akik-general-secretary-in-badc-agriculturalists-association-poll</link><description>In the biannual election of the Central Executive Committee of the Bangladesh Agricultural Development Corporation (BADC) Agriculturalists’ Association, Md. Humayun Kabir has been elected president, and Dr Md Akikul Islam Akik has been elected general secretary.
A total of 60 candidates from</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 14:22:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Islami Bank customers organise human chain against S. Alam era appointees</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/islami-bank-customers-organise-human-chain-against-s-alam-era-appointees</link><description>The Islami Bank Customer Forum staged a human chain demonstration today (Sunday) demanding the cancellation of "illegal appointments" made when it was controlled by the S. Alam Group, and protesting the "monopolistic control" exercised by the group in the broader banking sector.
The demonstration,</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 13:51:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>8 killed in a day by lightning strikes in four districts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/8-killed-in-a-day-by-lightning-strikes-in-four-districts</link><description>Eight people were killed and two others injured by lightning strikes in Cumilla, Bogura, Kurigram and Jhenaidah districts on Sunday.
Among the deceased, three died in Cumilla, two in Jhenaidah, another two in Kurigram and one in Bogura district, UNB reports. 
In Cumilla, three people includi</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 14:06:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Digital Media Forum to honor journalists, media professionals at Digital Media Excellence Award 2025</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/digital-media-forum-to-honor-journalists-media-professionals-at-digital-media-excellence-award-2025</link><description>Digital Media Forum (DMF) is set to host the second edition of the "Digital Media Excellence Award 2025" to recognize outstanding contributions in journalism, media, and digital innovation.
This year’s awards will be presented across 19 categories on Saturday, 25 October 2025, according to a</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 14:36:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Political parties agree on referendum to implement July Charter: Ali Riaz</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/political-parties-agree-on-referendum-to-implement-july-charter-ali-riaz</link><description>National Consensus Commission (NCC) Vice-Chairman Professor Ali Riaz has said all political parties have agreed to ensure people’s participation to implement the “July National Charter, 2025” and hold a referendum to secure public support.
He said this while briefing reporters at</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 14:51:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tornado destroys over 500 houses in Nilphamari, injures 30</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/tornado-destroys-over-500-houses-in-nilphamari-injures-30</link><description>A sudden tornado struck Garagram Union of Kishoreganj Upazila in Nilphamari on Sunday morning, injuring at least 30 people and damaging over 500 houses.
Most injuries were caused by falling tree branches and collapsing homes. Among the injured, Taiful, 30, Tasin, 25, Royal, 30, Gulchan, 40, and At</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 15:21:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>49th Special BCS admit card download starts Sunday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/49th-special-bcs-admit-cards-available-for-download-from-sunday</link><description>Job seekers can download the admit card for the 49th Special BCS written examination, which is scheduled for next Friday, starting from Sunday night.
More than 312,000 candidates applied to take the multiple-choice question (MCQ) test for this Special BCS, which aims to recruit 683 teachers for go</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 15:36:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Eminent academic Syed Manzoorul Islam put on life support</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/eminent-academic-syed-manzoorul-islam-put-on-life-support</link><description>Syed Manzoorul Islam, emeritus professor and eminent writer, has been placed on life support at Labaid Hospital in Dhaka.
He has been undergoing treatment at the hospital since Friday, after suffering a heart attack.
Quoting the doctor, Mazharul Islam, chief executive of publishing house Anyaprok</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 16:06:04 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>