<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 20:27:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>EC to start disposing appeals against decisions on nomination papers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-to-start-disposing-appeals-against-decisions-on-nomination-papers</link><description>The Election Commission on Saturday will kick off the nine-day hearing and disposal of the appeal petitions filed against the acceptance and rejection of nomination papers during the scrutiny as the deadline for receiving such petitions expired on Friday.
The Commission, chaired by Chief Election</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 16:15:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Suspects infiltrated Osman Hadi’s campaign to ‘disrupt election’: chargesheet</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/suspects-infiltrated-osman-hadis-campaign-to-disrupt-election-chargesheet</link><description>The murder of Inqilab Moncho Convenor Sharif Osman bin Hadi was carried out to “obstruct” the parliamentary election, according to a chargesheet submitted by investigators.
The chargesheet says suspect Faisal Karim Masud and his associates infiltrated Hadi’s election campaign wit</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 16:30:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fine-grain rice prices rise, vegetables refuse to dip</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fine-grain-rice-prices-rise-vegetables-refuse-to-dip</link><description>The arrival of BRRI-28 rice in the market despite old stocks has failed to ease prices, with finer rice varieties rising by up to Tk 5 per kg within a week, while coarse rice prices have remained largely unchanged.
Visits to Shantinagar, Segunbagicha and Jatrabari markets in Dhaka on Friday, the w</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 16:45:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Police ‘bar’ devotees from High Court shrine</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/police-bar-devotees-from-annual-urs-at-high-court-shrine</link><description>Police have allegedly barred attendance at the annual urs at the shrine of Shah Khaza Sharfuddin Chishti, located next to the High Court, devotees have said.
Police, however, said the daytime observances of the urs had already ended, and that some devotees remained at the site afterwards.
They we</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 17:00:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tailwinds may lift economic growth to 5.0pc in FY26</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/tailwinds-may-lift-economic-growth-to-50pc-in-fy26</link><description>Bangladesh's slow-pace economic growth may be ramped up to 5.0 per cent by tailwinds before this fiscal year ends on June 30, 2026, as estimated by BMI, a unit of Fitch Ratings.
 "We maintain our growth forecast of 5.0 per cent for FY2025/26," the global ratings agency's unit says in its late</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 17:15:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mirza Fakhrul’s income edges up in seven years</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/mirza-fakhruls-income-edges-up-in-seven-years-assets-jump-sharply</link><description>Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir has declared an annual income of around Tk 1.2 million and total assets worth more than Tk 15 million in his election affidavit.
A comparison with his previous affidavit shows that while his annual income has increase</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 17:30:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique’s visit to northern region postponed</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tariques-visit-to-northern-region-postponed-following-ec-request</link><description>Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) chief Tarique Rahman has postponed his planned visit to the northern region following a request from the Election Commission (EC).
The decision was announced following a meeting of the party’s National Standing Committee on Friday night.
The four-day visit</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 17:45:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>18 detained over teacher hiring question leaks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/18-detained-over-deals-to-supply-question-papers-for-primary-teacher-hiring-exam</link><description>Police have detained 18 people in Naogaon on charges of question paper leaks and fraud in the recruitment exams for assistant teachers at government primary schools.
Naogaon District Police Superintendent Mohammad Tarequl Islam revealed the matter at a press conference around 7pm on Friday.
The s</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 18:00:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Role of judgment in risk-based supervision</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/role-of-judgment-in-risk-based-supervision</link><description>Risk-based supervision is one of the most important changes in modern banking supervision. It is important not because it creates new rules, but because it changes how supervisors think and work. In the past, supervisors treated most banks in the same way. They depended mainly on periodic inspectio</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 18:15:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka needs public shuttle bus service</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/dhaka-needs-public-shuttle-bus-service</link><description>To facilitate commute for visitors to the 30th Dhaka International Trade Fair, taking place at the Bangladesh-China Friendship Exhibition Centre in Purbachal, the Bangladesh Road Transport Corporation (BRTC) has pressed into service shuttle buses. The shuttle buses will operate daily from multiple</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 18:30:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Discovering the wonders of Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/discovering-the-wonders-of-bangladesh</link><description>Vacationing is no longer a luxury enjoyed by a select few but an increasingly routine part of contemporary life. That tourism has expanded so rapidly, aided by rising incomes and widespread digital connectivity, indicates required means and mindset of a growing number of people for travel. This tra</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 18:45:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Meeting fertiliser needs of Boro farmers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/meeting-fertiliser-needs-of-boro-farmers</link><description>Chronic shortage of natural gas has been hampering fertiliser production especially at the five urea fertiliser-producing plants operated by the state-owned Bangladesh Chemical Industries Corporation (BCIC). But Boro being the country's major dry season rice crop (January-February its peak planting</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 19:00:54 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>