<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 17:18:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Bangladesh Navy warship sails for Sri Lanka to join International Fleet Review</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-navy-warship-sails-for-sri-lanka-to-join-international-fleet-review</link><description>Bangladesh Navy warship BNS Prottoy left for the Indian Ocean island of Sri Lanka on Thursday to take part in an International Fleet Review (IFR), being held as part of the Sri Lankan Navy’s 75th anniversary.
The international maritime gathering will be held in Colombo from November 27 to 30</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 15:27:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bomb attack on DUCSU member’s home</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/attempted-arson-bomb-attack-at-ducsu-member-rafias-mymensingh-residence</link><description>Assailants have thrown a crude bomb at DUCSU member Umma Uswatun Rafia’s house in Mymensingh, while pouring flammable materials in an attempt to set the residence on fire.
Her family is reportedly in a state of panic following the attack.
The incident took place around 2:45am on Wednesday a</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 15:42:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Yunnan business delegation urges more Bangladesh consulates in China</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/yunnan-business-delegation-urges-more-bangladesh-consulates-in-china-chinese-mission-in-chattogram</link><description>A visiting business delegation from China’s Yunnan province has called on the Bangladesh government to open more consulates in key Chinese regions, in addition to its existing mission in Canton (Guangzhou), and recommended that China set up a consulate in Chattogram to further deepen and faci</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 14:45:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gas supply reduced across Titas Gas network until Friday morning</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/gas-supply-reduced-across-titas-gas-network-until-friday-morning</link><description>Authorities have warned of low gas pressure in the distribution network of Titas Gas until Friday morning due to reduced liquefied natural gas (LNG) supply.
According to an emergency message from Titas on Thursday, the gas supply is decreasing due to “urgent maintenance work” at the LN</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 15:00:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh becomes first Asian country to ratify all 10 ILO fundamental instruments</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladesh-becomes-first-asian-country-to-ratify-all-10-ilo-fundamental-instruments</link><description>The International Labour Organization (ILO) on Thursday commended the Government of Bangladesh for the landmark ratification of three key ILO Conventions, including two fundamental ILO Conventions on occupational safety and health, reflecting the country’s strong commitment to promoting safer</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 15:15:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Saboteurs to be declared ‘Unwanted’ in Dhaka: DMP Commissioner</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/saboteurs-to-be-declared-unwanted-in-dhaka-dmp-commissioner</link><description>Dhaka Metropolitan Police (DMP) Commissioner Sheikh Md Sajjat Ali on Thursday warned that persons involved in acts of sabotage will be declared “unwanted” in the capital under existing laws.He said those orchestrating planned crude bomb attacks and arson on vehicles to create public pan</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 15:30:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Some 4,000 expats register on first day to vote in next election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/some-4000-expats-register-on-first-day-to-vote-in-next-election</link><description>Over 4,000 expatriate Bangladeshis registered on Thursday, the first day of the “Postal Vote BD” app launched by the Election Commission in a bid to allow more Bangladeshis residing abroad to participate in the upcoming national election.
As of 7:30 pm on Thursday, a total of 4,026 vot</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 15:45:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Unpacking emotional costs of remittance narrative</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/unpacking-emotional-costs-of-remittance-narrative</link><description>Labour migration has become one of Bangladesh's most celebrated development narratives. Over the decades, millions of Bangladeshis have travelled to the Gulf, Southeast Asia, Europe, and beyond, sending home remittances that sustain households and stabilise the national economy. These flows of mone</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 16:00:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Police, RAB launch crackdown to make Raozan ‘terror-free’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/police-rab-launch-crackdown-to-make-raozan-terror-free</link><description>Eight light guns (LG), along with local weapons and ammunition have been recovered in a special joint drive conducted by police and RAB members in Chattogram’s Raozan.
No arrests have been reported until now.
The drive, conducted on the early hours of Thursday across different locations in</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 16:15:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Should government still be in business?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/should-government-still-be-in-business</link><description>At a recent roundtable on business climate organised by The Financial Express, the vice chairman of the Export Promotion Bureau has posed a pertinent question: should the government be doing business at all? The question is as old as the state-owned enterprises themselves and is more relevant today</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 16:30:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hunger and food insecurity stare in the face of world</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/hunger-and-food-insecurity-stare-in-the-face-of-world</link><description>Reports on hunger and food insecurity are unnerving. The 2025 state of food security and nutrition in the world (SOFI) report finds that 673 million people constituting 8.3 per cent of the global population faced acute hunger in 2024. The SOFI is an annual publication by five important United Natio</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 16:45:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Labour ordinance goes past tripartite agreement</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/labour-ordinance-goes-past-tripartite-agreement</link><description>The interim government's amendment of the labour law, despite objections raised by business groups during the draft stage, has triggered fresh protests demanding its withdrawal. Opponents argue that some key provisions deviate from the understandings reached earlier in tripartite meetings involving</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 17:00:42 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>