<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 05:22:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Govt to revise FoC import ceiling for raw materials</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/govt-to-revise-foc-import-ceiling-for-raw-materials</link><description>The government is set to revise the Free of Cost (FoC) raw material-import ceiling in the upcoming amendments to the Import Policy Order 2021-2024, aiming to safeguard local industries, strengthen domestic value addition, and support to investment in backward linkage industries, according to minist</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 00:31:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No hope for interest cut as inflation stays intractable</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/no-hope-for-interest-cut-as-inflation-stays-intractable</link><description>Interest rate cannot be reduced in the near future as price-fueled inflation still stays intractably high, Bangladesh Bank Governor Dr Ahsan H Mansur said Monday to set at rest businesses' pleas.
Speaking at same function, Meanwhile, National Board of Revenue (NBR) Chairman Md Abdur Rahman Khan al</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 00:46:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Air ambulance not arriving today</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/air-ambulance-not-arriving-today</link><description>The air ambulance arranged for BNP Chairperson Khaleda Zia is not arriving in Dhaka today.
It was supposed to land at the Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport today and take her to the UK tomorrow (Wednesday).
The Civil Aviation Authority of Bangladesh (CAAB) approved the aircraft's landing req</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 01:01:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Democratise political, economic processes for sustainable dev</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/democratise-political-economic-processes-for-sustainable-dev</link><description>Speakers at an event in the capital on Monday emphasised the need for democratising political and economic processes, as well as ensuring good governance for sustainable development.
Also, they said unless a sound democracy was there and the elected representatives were made accountable, developme</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 01:16:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Delayed SPM operation benefits pvt sector at public expense</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/delayed-spm-operation-benefits-pvt-sector-at-public-expense</link><description>The delay in starting operations of the country's maiden single-point mooring (SPM) system -- designed to unload fuel quickly and cheaply -- is allegedly benefiting private operators, who are earning hefty profits at the expense of public money, industry insiders said.
Allegations are rife that al</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 01:31:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>World Bank seeks faster government approvals for project effectiveness</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/world-bank-seeks-faster-government-approvals-for-project-effectiveness</link><description>The World Bank (WB) has sought the government's cooperation for faster approvals to make a $350-million financing facility effective and operationalised.
The facility aims to enhance Bangladesh's energy-sector security.
The World Bank Board of Directors in June this year approved the "Energy Sect</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 01:46:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Institutional fragmentation, weak financing among key hurdles</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/institutional-fragmentation-weak-financing-among-key-hurdles</link><description>Institutional fragmentation, weak financing, and rising climate pressures continue to limit broader water-security outcomes in Bangladesh, according to the Asian Water Development Outlook (AWDO) 2025.
The Asian Development Bank (ADB) released the outlook on Monday, showing that while policy framew</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 02:01:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>HC rejects writ seeking protective measures</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/hc-rejects-writ-seeking-protective-measures</link><description>The High Court has summarily rejected a writ petition challenging the legality of the government initiative to merge five troubled private banks without ensuring any protection for the shareholders' interest and without issuing any shares to the existing general shareholders.
The High Court bench</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 02:16:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tariff cuts, data-driven subsidies key to boosting agriculture: Study</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/tariff-cuts-data-driven-subsidies-key-to-boosting-agriculture-study</link><description>Eliminating import tariffs on key agricultural machinery and allocating subsidies based on data-driven mechanisation are vital to increasing agricultural output, according to a study presented at the Annual BIDS Conference on Development (ABCD) 2025.
The study also recommended standardising subsid</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 02:31:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Onion prices fall after allowing imports</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/onion-prices-fall-after-allowing-imports</link><description>Onion prices have started to ease across several districts since Sunday after news broke that Bangladesh had allowed limited imports from India.
The move has brought swift relief to consumers after weeks of volatility caused by supply shortages and a prolonged import suspension.
Traders say the m</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 02:46:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IFRS 9 adoption key to restoring trust in banking sector: Experts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/ifrs-9-adoption-key-to-restoring-trust-in-banking-sector-experts</link><description>Accounting professionals have called for the adoption and effective implementation of International Financial Reporting Standard (IFRS) 9 to strengthen risk assessment, restore public trust and improve transparency in Bangladesh's banking sector.
For years, loan classification and provisioning in</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 03:01:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bd Thai Aluminium posts 2.5 times higher Q1 loss</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/bd-thai-aluminium-posts-25-times-higher-q1-loss</link><description>Bd. Thai Aluminium posted a 2.5 times higher loss in the first quarter of FY26 compared to the same quarter of the previous year, amounting to Tk 89.44 million.
The earnings disclosure should come as a shock to investors after Bd. Thai's stock had been bid up by more than 50 per cent in less than</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 03:16:50 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>