<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 14:20:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Arson attack yet another security failure: Udichi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/udichi-decries-govt-inaction-despite-threats-prior-to-dhaka-office-attack</link><description>Udichi Shilpigosthi has hit out at the government’s failure to provide security despite alerting authorities to prior threats of an attack on its central office in Dhaka.
The cultural organisation made the allegation at a rally held on Saturday protesting the arson attack on its central offi</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 10:45:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US, Russian officials to meet in Florida for more Ukraine talks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-russian-officials-to-meet-in-florida-for-more-ukraine-talks</link><description>US negotiators are set to meet Russian officials in Florida on Saturday for the latest talks aimed at ending Russia’s war in Ukraine, as President Donald Trump’s administration tries to coax an agreement out of both Russia and Ukraine to end the conflict.
The meeting follows US talks o</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 11:00:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Factory official handed Dipu over to ‘mob’: RAB</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rab-says-factory-floor-manager-handed-dipu-das-over-to-enraged-crowd</link><description>The Rapid Action Battalion (RAB) has claimed a floor manager handed Dipu Chandra Das over to an enraged crowd after forcing him to resign from his job.
Dipu, 28, who worked at a Bhaluka-based readymade garment factory named Pioneer Knitwears BD Ltd, was beaten to death by a mob on Thursday in Myme</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 11:15:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Inqilab Moncho gathers at Shahbagh after Hadi’s burial</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/inqilab-moncho-gathers-at-shahbagh-after-hadis-burial</link><description>Following the burial rites of Sharif Osman bin Hadi, the Inqilab Moncho has blocked Shahbagh.
Around 4pm on Saturday, they began streaming in at Shahbagh, shouting slogans such as “Delhi or Dhaka – Dhaka, Dhaka”, protesting Hadi’s killing and urging justice for the perpetra</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 11:30:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UN chief condemns Houthi detention of another 10 UN staff in Yemen</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/africa/un-chief-condemns-houthi-detention-of-another-10-un-staff-in-yemen</link><description>United Nations Secretary-General Antonio Guterres on Friday condemned the Houthi detention of another 10 UN personnel in Yemen, taking the total to 69, his spokesperson said.
The Iran-aligned Houthis detained the additional UN staff on Thursday, said UN spokesperson Stephane Dujarric, and Guterres</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 11:45:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Vested quarter making evil efforts to tarnish July spirit: Abrar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/vested-quarter-making-evil-efforts-to-tarnish-july-spirit-abrar</link><description>Education Adviser Prof. Dr. Chowdhury Rafiqul Abrar on Saturday said a vested quarter is carrying out evil efforts to tarnish the spirit of the July Uprising.
In a statement, he said that because of the evil efforts of that quarter, there is also a risk that the conspiracies of anti-Bangladesh fas</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 12:00:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>French presidential silverware keeper faces trial over suspected porcelain theft</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/french-presidential-silverware-keeper-faces-trial-over-suspected-porcelain-theft</link><description>France's presidential silverware keeper and two other men are set to stand trial over the suspected theft of porcelain and other precious tableware, the Paris prosecution office said.
The Elysee, the president's official residence, had reported the disappearance of silverware and tableware pieces</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 12:15:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump appointee inspired by conservative media outlet to push for probe of Democratic congressman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-appointee-inspired-by-conservative-media-outlet-to-push-for-probe-of-democratic-congressman</link><description>A mortgage fraud probe of a Democratic congressman began last month after William Pulte, the Republican head of the Federal Housing Finance Agency, referred allegations from a conservative news site to his agency’s inspector general for possible criminal investigation, government emails seen</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 12:30:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Italian police arrest 384, seize 1.4 tonnes of drugs in nationwide crackdown</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/italian-police-arrest-384-seize-14-tonnes-of-drugs-in-nationwide-crackdown</link><description>Italian police said on Saturday they had arrested 384 people and seized 1.4 tonnes of drugs in a large-scale operation against drug trafficking.
In addition to the arrests, officers had put under investigation 655 individuals, including 39 minors, and confiscated 35kg of cocaine and more than 40 f</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 12:45:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shahbagh clears after calls for justice in Hadi killing</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/protesters-leave-shahbagh-after-demanding-justice-for-hadis-killing</link><description>Protesters demanding justice for the killing of Sharif Osman bin Hadi have left Shahbagh intersection after staging a demonstration calling for justice in the killing of the Inqilab Moncho leader.
Following Hadi’s burial on the Dhaka University campus on Saturday, activists of the platform a</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 13:00:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Anis Alamgir lands in jail after interrogation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/journalist-anis-alamgir-sent-to-jail-after-interrogation</link><description>Journalist Anis Alamgir has been sent to jail after interrogation concluded in an Anti-Terrorism Act case filed with Uttara West Police Station in Dhaka.
The order was issued on Saturday by Dhaka Metropolitan Magistrate Md Hasan Shahadat, confirmed Prosecution Sub-Inspector Shamim Hossain.
After</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 13:15:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh writes to Meta for strict content monitoring until election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-writes-to-meta-for-strict-content-monitoring-until-election</link><description>The National Cyber Security Agency (NCSA) has urged Meta to closely monitor social media content, citing concerns that platforms are being used to incite violence amid Bangladesh’s ongoing political crisis.
The NCSA sent a letter to the American multinational technology company on Friday.
T</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 13:30:56 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>