<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 11:17:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>How Bangladesh's youths are rediscovering social connection</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/youth-and-entrepreneurship/how-bangladeshs-youths-are-rediscovering-social-connection-1</link><description>Every Eid afternoon tells the same story in households across Dhaka. Several cousins gather in the drawing room, phones in hand, scrolling through feeds whilst sitting shoulder to shoulder. Someone suggests Uno, a card game. A few agree half-heartedly, but within twenty minutes, everyone's back on</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 09:19:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>PulseTech secures US$ 3.0m to transform Bangladesh's pharmaceutical supply chain</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/youth-and-entrepreneurship/startups/pulsetech-secures-us-30m-to-transform-bangladeshs-pharmaceutical-supply-chain-1</link><description>PulseTech, a B2B healthtech platform operating in Bangladesh, has successfully closed a US$ 3.0 million Pre-Series A funding round. The investment was co-led by Iterative and AVV, marking AVV's inaugural investment in the country. The capital will support PulseTech's ambitious plans to reshape ph</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 09:34:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh's bold undergrad founders</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/youth-and-entrepreneurship/bangladeshs-bold-undergrad-founders-2</link><description>For university students with a business idea scribbled in a notebook or a prototype built in their hostel room, the wait is over. The Undergrad Startup Challenge 2025, Bangladesh's largest startup competition exclusively for undergraduate students, has officially opened registration.
Organised b</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 09:49:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Attempts being made to divide people in name of religion: Fakhrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/attempts-being-made-to-divide-people-in-name-of-religion-fakhrul</link><description>A certain group has been "creating divisions in the name of religion in the country,” says BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir.
He remarked at a discussion on Sunday morning, according to bdnews24.com.
He said, ‘‘Today, an attempt is being made to create a major</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 09:00:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Salman F Rahman, his brother face fraud allegations</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/salman-f-rahman-his-brother-face-fraud-allegations</link><description>A Dhaka court has taken into consideration a fraud complaint against Salman F Rahman, vice-chairman of Beximco Group, his brother ASF Rahman, the conglomerate’s chairman, and four others linked to Beximco Aviation.
The complaint was filed at the court of Metropolitan Magistrate Najmin Akter</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 09:15:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hong Kong election turnout in focus amid anger over deadly fire</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/hong-kong-election-turnout-in-focus-amid-anger-over-deadly-fire</link><description>Hong Kong’s citizens were voting on Sunday in an election where the focus is on turnout, with residents grieving and traumatised after the city’s worst fire in nearly 80 years and the authorities scrambling to avoid a broader public backlash.
Security was tight in the northern district</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 09:30:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Uganda opposition candidate says he was beaten by security forces</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/africa/uganda-opposition-candidate-says-he-was-beaten-by-security-forces</link><description>Uganda's opposition candidate Bobi Wine said he was beaten alongside his aides and supporters by security forces while campaigning in the country's north, in an escalation of violence ahead of the country's presidential election on January 15.
Wine, a pop star-turned-politician, whose real name is</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 09:45:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh extends voting window by an hour for parliamentary election, referendum</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-extends-voting-window-by-an-hour-for-parliamentary-election-referendum</link><description>Polling centres will be open from 7:30 am to 4:30 pm on the day of the parliamentary election and the July Charter referendum due in early February next year.
The Election Commission (EC) decided at a meeting chaired by Chief Election Commissioner AMM Nasir Uddin on Sunday, according to bdnews24.c</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 10:00:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Benin minister says coup attempt underway, situation under control</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/africa/benin-minister-says-coup-attempt-underway-situation-under-control</link><description>A group of soldiers in the West African nation of Benin claimed on national television to have seized power on Sunday, though the government said forces loyal to President Patrice Talon were working to foil the coup plot.
The move was latest threat to democratic norms in the region, coming after a</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 10:15:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tribunal to hear defence arguments on enforced disappearance charges Tuesday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tribunal-to-hear-defence-arguments-on-enforced-disappearance-charges-tuesday</link><description>The International Crimes Tribunal (ICT) has set Tuesday to hear defence submissions on whether charges should be framed in a case alleging torture at the military’s Joint Interrogation Cells (JIC) during the Awami League's rule.
The Tribunal-1 bench, led by Justice Md Golam Mortuza Mozumder,</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 10:30:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chinese jets point radar at Japanese aircraft, Japan says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/chinese-jets-point-radar-at-japanese-aircraft-japan-says</link><description>Japan said on Sunday that Chinese fighter jets had aimed their radar at Japanese military aircraft in two "dangerous" incidents near Japan's Okinawa islands, an account Beijing disputed.
"These radar illuminations are a dangerous act that went beyond what is necessary for the safe flight of aircra</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 10:45:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Actor Salman Shah Murder: Courts order to provide investigation report on January 13</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/actor-salman-shah-murder-courts-order-to-provide-investigation-report-on-january-13</link><description>A Dhaka court on Sunday asked the authorities concerned to provide the investigation report on January 13 in the case filed over the death of actor Salman Shah in 1996.
Dhaka Metropolitan Magistrate Jewel passed the order.
Mohammad Alamgir Kumkum, maternal uncle of actor Salman filed a case again</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 11:00:42 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>