<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 09:28:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Singapore to raise age limit for first-time blood donors to 65</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/singapore-to-raise-age-limit-for-first-time-blood-donors-to-65</link><description>Singapore will raise the upper age limit for first-time blood donors to 65 from 60, effective Jan. 2 next year, the Health Sciences Authority (HSA) said.
Under the new rules, first-time donors will be allowed to give blood up to one day before their 66th birthday, while repeat donors may continue</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 05:11:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fire at high-rise building in Babubazar under control</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fire-at-high-rise-building-in-babubazar-under-control</link><description>A fire that broke out early this morning at Haji Tower, a 14-storey commercial cum residential building in the Babubazar area of Armanitola in Old Dhaka, was brought under control.
Nine firefighting units rushed to the scene within five minutes after the fire originated on the sixth floor of the b</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 05:26:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump says US needs Greenland for security</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-says-us-needs-greenland-for-security</link><description>US President Donald Trump reasserted on Monday that the United States needs Greenland for its national security and said a special envoy he appointed to the Arctic island would "lead the charge."
Trump named Louisiana Governor Jeff Landry on Sunday as his special envoy to Greenland, drawing renewe</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 05:41:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>If you don’t work properly, I lose sleep: CEC to election officials</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/if-you-dont-work-properly-i-lose-sleep-cec-to-election-officials</link><description>Chief Election Commissioner AMM Nasir Uddin has directed field administration officials, including returning officers, to carry out their duties strictly in line with the law and election regulations ahead of the 13th parliamentary elections and referendum.
He urged officials to perform their duti</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 06:14:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ten houses gutted in Gazipur fire</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/ten-houses-gutted-in-gazipur-fire</link><description>At least ten houses were gutted in a fire that broke out at Abdar village in Sreepur upazila of Gazipur district on Tuesday.
Md Nurul Karim, inspector of Sreepur Fire Service and Civil Defence, said the fire broke out at a tin-shed house in the morning and engulfed the adjoining houses, reports UN</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 06:29:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Body of abducted businessman found after six hours</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/body-of-abducted-businessman-found-after-six-hours</link><description>A businessman who was abducted at gunpoint from his showroom in Dupchanchia upazila of Bogura was found dead about six hours later, police said.
The deceased was identified as Pintu Akand, 35, a resident of Lohachura village in Raninagar upazila of Naogaon district.
He was the owner of a ‘L</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 06:44:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Japan to give duty free access for 7,379 Bangladeshi products once EPA is signed</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/japan-to-give-duty-free-access-for-7379-bangladeshi-products-once-epa-is-signed</link><description>Japan is set to grant duty-free entry for 7,379 Bangladeshi products once the Bangladesh-Japan Economic Partnership Agreement (EPA) is signed, according to the Japan Bangladesh Chamber of Commerce and Industry (JBCCI).
It also stated that the EPA is expected to deepen trade, investment, and servic</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 07:01:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh summons high commissioner again</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-summons-high-commissioner-again</link><description>Bangladesh has summoned India’s high commissioner in Dhaka on Tuesday over a series of protests and acts of vandalism targeting Bangladeshi missions in India.
The latest summons underscores mounting strain in bilateral ties during Bangladesh’s fragile political transition.
Since the i</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 08:19:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Airport authorities impose 24-hour visitor ban for Tarique’s homecoming</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/airport-authorities-impose-24-hour-visitor-ban-for-tariques-homecoming</link><description>Authorities have banned visitors at Shahjalal International Airport for 24 hours to manage crowds ahead of BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman’s return to the country.
According to a statement on Tuesday, authorities said the restriction will be in place from 6pm on Dec 24 to 6pm on Dec 25.</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 07:31:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ECNEC okays Tk 354.65 billion project to modernise Eastern Refinery</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ecnec-okays-tk-35465-billion-project-to-modernise-eastern-refinery</link><description>The Executive Committee of the National Economic Council (ECNEC) on Tuesday approved a Tk 354.65 billion project to modernise and expand Eastern Refinery Limited (ERL), aiming to strengthen Bangladesh's energy security, produce cleaner fuel and cut dependence on imported refined petroleum products.</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 07:46:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Protests at Bangladesh High Commission in Delhi over Dipu Das's lynching</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/protests-at-bangladesh-high-commission-in-delhi-over-dipu-dass-lynching</link><description>A major protest has erupted outside the Bangladesh High Commission in New Delhi in the wake of the brutal killing of a Hindu man, Dipu Chandra Das, in Mymensingh last week.
The demonstrations are being led by Vishwa Hindu Parishad (VHP) and Bajrang Dal to denounce alleged atrocities against Hindus</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 08:34:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ICT orders trial of Hasina, Kamal and 15 Army officers over alleged disappearances, torture at TFI</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ict-orders-trial-of-hasina-kamal-and-15-army-officers-over-alleged-disappearances-torture-at-tfi</link><description>The International Crimes Tribunal has ordered the start of trial proceedings against deposed prime minister Sheikh Hasina, former home minister Asaduzzaman Khan Kamal and 15 Army officers over allegations of enforced disappearances and torture during the previous Awami League government.
The order</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 08:49:29 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>