<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 15:08:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Country’s GDP grows 3.69pc in FY25</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/countrys-gdp-grows-369pc-in-fy25</link><description>Bangladesh’s economy grew by 3.69 percent in the last fiscal year (FY25), driven by moderate performances by the agriculture, industry and services sectors.
According to the latest data by the Bangladesh Bureau of Statistics (BBS), the GDP growth rate during the 4th or the April to June quar</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 12:30:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Remittance inflow witnesses 14.4pc growth till Oct 8</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/remittance-inflow-witnesses-144pc-growth-till-oct-8</link><description>Inflow of remittances witnessed 14.4 percent (pc) growth, reaching US$8,390 million during the period from July 1 to October 8, 2025 which was $7,332 million during the same period of the previous fiscal year.
According to the latest data of Bangladesh Bank (BB) issued, expatriates sent remittance</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 12:45:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>HSC, equivalent exam results likely on Oct 16</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hsc-equivalent-exam-results-likely-on-oct-16</link><description>The chiefs of nine Boards of Intermediate and Secondary Education have announced Oct 16 as the possible date for the publication of the HSC and equivalent examinations’ results.
Bangladesh Madrasah Education Board Chairman Mian Md Nurul Haq said the decision was reached during a meeting of t</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 13:00:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Modi and Starmer tout India-UK trade deal as new Indian investment unveiled</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/modi-and-starmer-tout-india-uk-trade-deal-as-new-indian-investment-unveiled</link><description>Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi and British counterpart Keir Starmer hailed the potential on Thursday of their months-old trade deal to transform commercial links, as London unveiled new Indian investment in Britain and said "this is just the start".
Starmer is in the financial capital of Mumb</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 13:30:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Interim govt using counterterrorism law for renewed crackdown: HRW</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/interim-govt-using-counterterrorism-law-for-renewed-crackdown-hrw</link><description>Bangladesh’s interim government led by Muhammad Yunus, a Nobel peace laureate, is increasingly using the recently amended counterterrorism law to arrest alleged supporters of the deposed Awami League government, Human Rights Watch has said in a statement.
The United Nations human rights team</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 13:16:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>July National Charter to be signed on Oct 15</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/july-national-charter-to-be-signed-on-oct-15</link><description>The July National Charter 2025 will be signed on October 15 at the South Plaza of the Jatiya Sangsad. 
The historic signing ceremony will be led by Chief Adviser of the Interim Government and Chairman of the National Consensus Commission Professor Dr Muhammad Yunus, BSS reports. 
Repres</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 13:31:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Does the Gaza deal mean the two-year-old war is over?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/does-the-gaza-deal-mean-the-two-year-old-war-is-over</link><description>US President Donald Trump says the deal agreed between Israel and Hamas marks the first steps toward a "strong, durable, and everlasting peace" that will end the two-year-old Gaza war.
Yet Wednesday's agreement reached in the Egyptian resort of Sharm el-Sheikh, a favoured location for Middle East</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 13:46:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Israel and Hamas sign ceasefire and hostage deal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/israel-and-hamas-sign-ceasefire-and-hostage-deal</link><description>Israel and the Palestinian militant group Hamas signed an agreement on Thursday to cease fire and free Israeli hostages in exchange for Palestinian prisoners, in the first phase of US President Donald Trump's initiative to end the war in Gaza.
Officials on both sides confirmed they had signed the</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 14:01:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCP pushes for ‘Water Lily’, demands removal of other national emblems</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ncp-pushes-for-water-lily-demands-removal-of-other-national-emblems</link><description>The National Citizen Party (NCP) on Thursday reiterated its call to the Election Commission to allocate ‘Water Lily’ as its electoral symbol.
The party also demanded that the Commission remove other national emblems, including the ‘Sheaf of Paddy’ and the ‘Star’</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 14:31:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Musk’s Tesla package pays him billions even if he misses ‘Mars-shot’ goals</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/musks-tesla-package-pays-him-billions-even-if-he-misses-mars-shot-goals</link><description>When Tesla directors offered Elon Musk the biggest executive pay package in corporate history in September, it reassured investors that he would have to achieve the equivalent of “Mars-shot milestones” to earn $878 billion in Tesla stock over 10 years.
The board’s proposal said M</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 14:46:23 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>