<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 11:49:39 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>26,515 police deployed in capital for election security: DMP</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/26515-police-deployed-in-capital-for-election-security-dmp</link><description>A total of 26,515 police personnel have been deployed across the capital to ensure maximum security during the national election and referendum, said DMP Deputy Commissioner (Media) Muhammad Talebur Rahman on Wednesday.
Specialised units, including the Bomb Disposal Unit, SWAT, K-9 Unit and Crime</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 08:48:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Over 1,400 polling stations in Dhaka flagged as 'high risk'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/over-1400-polling-stations-in-dhaka-flagged-as-high-risk</link><description>More than 1,400 polling stations across 13 constituencies in Dhaka have been identified as high risk ahead of the 13th national election, according to officials.
Dhaka Divisional Commissioner and Returning Officer Sharaf Uddin Ahmed Chowdhury said striking forces will be deployed in greater number</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 09:03:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jahangir visits PHQ control room, two police stations in the city</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jahangir-visits-phq-control-room-two-police-stations-in-the-city</link><description>Home Adviser Lieutenant General (Retd.) Md. Jahangir Alam Chowdhury today (Wednesday) visited the Central Control Room at Police Headquarters (PHQ) to review law enforcement preparedness ahead of tomorrow’s general elections and referendum-2026, according to a press release.
During the visit</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 09:18:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US moves to counter China in Bangladesh, plans to pitch defence alternatives</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/us-moves-to-counter-china-in-bangladesh-plans-to-pitch-defence-alternatives</link><description>The United States is concerned about China's expanding presence in South Asia and is planning to offer Bangladesh’s next government US and allied defence systems as alternatives to Chinese hardware, Washington's ambassador to Dhaka told Reuters.
Bangladesh votes in a general election on Thur</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 09:33:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Vested group spreading falsehoods out of fear: Dr Shafiqur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/vested-group-spreading-falsehoods-out-of-fear-dr-shafiqur</link><description>Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami Ameer Dr Shafiqur Rahman on Wednesday alleged that a vested quarter is spreading disinformation out of fear of the party’s growing popularity and public support.
In a post on his verified Facebook page, he said that as the nation prepares for a free, fair and credi</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 09:48:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Banglabandha Land Port closed for 3 days for elections</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/banglabandha-land-port-closed-for-3-days-for-elections</link><description>Import and export activities through the Banglabandha Land Port in Panchagarh will remain suspended for three consecutive days due to the 13th parliamentary election.
However, passenger movement will remain normal on the two days before and after the voting day, but not on election day itself.
As</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 10:03:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>When will Bangladesh’s election results be announced?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/when-will-bangladeshs-election-results-be-announced</link><description>Questions are being raised over when results will be declared following voting in Bangladesh’s 13th parliamentary election and referendum.
For the first time, a referendum is being held alongside a parliamentary election. The Election Commission (EC) has already indicated that counting and t</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 09:48:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat leader’s arrest with cash ‘stage-managed drama’, party claims</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-leaders-arrest-with-cash-stage-managed-drama-party-claims</link><description>Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami Assistant Secretary General Ahsanul Mahboob Zubair on Wednesday claimed the arrest of Thakurgaon district Jamaat Ameer Belal Uddin with a large amount of cash as a `stage-managed drama by law enforcers’.
Speaking at an emergency press conference at the party’</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 10:03:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Where will interim government advisers cast their ballots?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/where-will-interim-government-advisers-cast-their-ballots</link><description>The Advisers of the interim government will cast their ballots in the upcoming 13th parliamentary election and referendum at certain designated polling centres on Thursday.
Chief Adviser Muhammad Yunus will cast his vote at the Gulshan Model High School and College centre. He is likely to reach th</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 10:18:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat leader Belal Uddin hospitalised after arrest ‘with Tk 50 lakh’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-leader-belal-uddin-hospitalised-after-arrest-with-tk-50-lakh</link><description>Thakurgaon district unit Jamaat-e-Islami Ameer Belal Uddin Pradhan, who was detained at Saidpur Airport ‘with around Tk 50 lakh’, fell ill and was admitted to a hospital on Tuesday afternoon.
After he complained of illness, he was taken to Saidpur 100-bed Hospital in Nilphamari distric</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 10:33:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CEC not ‘scared’ of consequences facing predecessors</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/asked-if-he-is-worried-about-consequences-faced-by-predecessors-cec-sees-nothing-scary</link><description>Chief Election Commissioner AMM Nasir Uddin says he does not fear facing consequences similar to that of his two predecessors.
Responding to a question on Wednesday, the day before the election, he said he has been working in line with his pledge to deliver a free, fair and credible election.
Two</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 10:48:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique inaugurates free animal clinic in Banani</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-inaugurates-free-animal-clinic-in-banani</link><description>BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman on Wednesday inaugurated a Free Animal Clinic in the capital’s Banani area to ensure free medical services for animals.
The clinic has been set up by Bangladesh Animal Welfare Association (BAWA).
The organisers said the ‘Free Animal Clinic’ will provi</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 11:03:59 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>