<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 14:20:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Probe report in Salman Shah murder case on Dec 7</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/probe-report-in-salman-shah-murder-case-on-dec-7</link><description>A Dhaka court on Tuesday set December 7 for submitting probe report in a case lodged against 11 over the murder of Bangla movie star Salman Shah in 1996.
Dhaka Metropolitan Magistrate Saifuzzaman passed the order, accepting first information report of the case.
Earlier in the day, Salman Shah&amp;rsq</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 11:55:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Banking sector faces capital shortfall of Tk 1.55 trillion</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/banking-sector-faces-capital-shortfall-of-tk-155-trillion</link><description>The financial health of Bangladesh’s banking sector has worsened sharply, with troubled banks facing a combined capital shortfall exceeding Tk 1.55 trillion in the June quarter.
This alarming figure marks a sharp increase from the Tk 1.1026 trillion (Tk 110,260 crore) deficit recorded in the</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 12:25:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prime Bank partners with Brac Healthcare to offer exclusive discounts on screening packages</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/prime-bank-partners-with-brac-healthcare-to-offer-exclusive-discounts-on-screening-packages</link><description>Prime Bank PLC has entered into a strategic partnership with Brac Healthcare Limited to offer exclusive discounts on a range of health screening packages for its valued customers.
A signing ceremony to commemorate this partnership was recently held at Prime Bank’s Corporate Office in Dhaka,</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 11:45:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Burimari land port halts import-export for 3 days during Kali Puja</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/burimari-land-port-halts-import-export-for-3-days-during-kali-puja</link><description>The trade activities at Lalmonirhat’s Burimari land port with India’s Changrabandha Port have been suspended for three days from Monday to Wednesday (Oct 20-22) on the occasion of the Hindu festival Kali Puja (Diwali).
Although trade activities have been suspended since Monday morning,</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 12:00:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Drik-ULAB collaboration on Research and Storytelling in Journalism</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/drik-ulab-collaboration-on-research-and-storytelling-in-journalism</link><description>The University of Liberal Arts Bangladesh and Drik Trust have signed an MoU to launch a collaborative program titled “Ctrl+Alt+Story: Research and Storytelling in Journalism.”
Under this partnership, students of Media Studies and Journalism, English, and related disciplines will have t</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 12:15:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pakistani envoy meets food adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/pakistani-envoy-meets-food-adviser</link><description>Newly appointed Pakistani High Commissioner to Bangladesh Imran Haider on Tuesday met with Food and Land Adviser Ali Imam Majumder at his office at the secretariat here.
During the meeting, issues related to bilateral interests, including rice import from Pakistan, were discussed, said a press rel</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 12:30:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Children present six-point manifesto to govt, political parties ahead of elections</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/children-present-six-point-manifesto-to-govt-political-parties-ahead-of-elections</link><description>Ahead of the upcoming national elections in Bangladesh, over 200 children have issued a six-point manifesto, urging the government, political parties, and all concerned actors to prioritise child protection and rights in their commitments, policies, and programmes.
The manifesto calls for quality</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 13:15:36 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>