<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 12:56:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Tasnim Jara gets 'football' symbol in Dhaka-9</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tasnim-jara-gets-football-symbol-in-dhaka-9</link><description>Independent candidate Dr. Tasnim Jara has been allotted her preferred 'football' symbol to contest the upcoming 13th Jatiya Sangsad elections from Dhaka-9 constituency.
The Dhaka Divisional Commissioner and Returning Officer, Sharaf Uddin Ahmed Chowdhury, formally handed over the symbol allotment</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 09:15:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Malaysia to charge two top military officers over alleged corruption</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/malaysia-to-charge-two-top-military-officers-over-alleged-corruption</link><description>Malaysia’s Anti-Corruption Commission said on Wednesday it will charge two top military officers following a probe into money laundering and graft allegations.
Former army chief Muhammad Hafizuddiean Jantan will be charged under money laundering laws while former armed forces chief Mohd Niza</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 09:30:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Too many banks; Bangladesh needs only 10–15: Governor</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/too-many-banks-bangladesh-needs-only-10-15-governor</link><description>Bangladesh Bank Governor Dr Ahsan H Mansur on Wednesday said that 10 to 15 banks would be enough for Bangladesh’s economy, signalling a major move towards consolidating the nation’s overcrowded financial sector.
Speaking at a seminar titled ‘Banking Sector: Current Challenges and</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 09:45:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hifazat congratulates Islami Andolan for cutting ties with Jamaat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/hifazat-e-islam-congratulates-islami-andolan-for-cutting-ties-with-jamaat-e-islami</link><description>Hifazat-e-Islam Bangladesh chief Allama Shah Muhibullah Babunagari has congratulated Islami Andolan Bangladesh and its chief Mufti Syed Rezaul Karim for severing ties with the Jamaat-e-Islami alliance ahead of the upcoming national election.
The statement, signed by Muhibullah, was sent to the med</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 10:00:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Italy supports democratic transition, raises concern over illegal migration</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/italy-supports-democratic-transition-raises-concern-over-illegal-migration</link><description>Italy has expressed its full support for Bangladesh’s democratic transition, said a spokesman of the CA Office on Wednesday. 
Italy’s Undersecretary for Defence (Deputy minister for defence), Matteo Perego di Cremnago, denoted the support when he paid a courtesy call on Chief Advi</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 10:15:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A look at Trump's Board of Peace and who has been invited</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/a-look-at-trumps-board-of-peace-and-who-has-been-invited</link><description>The Board of Peace led by US President Donald Trump was originally envisioned as a small group of world leaders overseeing the Gaza ceasefire plan. Since then, the Trump administration's ambitions have ballooned into a more sprawling concept, with Trump extending invitations to dozens of nations an</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 10:30:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Assassin of Japan’s former PM Abe sentenced to life in prison</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/assassin-of-japans-former-pm-abe-sentenced-to-life-in-prison</link><description>A man accused of fatally shooting former Japanese Prime Minister Shinzo Abe was sentenced to life in prison on Wednesday, three and a half years after the incident that stunned the nation.
Tetsuya Yamagami, 45, was arrested on the spot in July 2022 after fatally firing at Abe with a homemade gun w</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 10:45:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Online tax return filing confusing despite NBR claims: Unilever Consumer Care Chairman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/online-tax-return-filing-confusing-despite-nbr-claims-unilever-consumer-care-chairman</link><description>Masud Khan, chairman of Unilever Consumer Care, has termed Bangladesh’s online tax return filing system confusing and difficult, contradicting repeated claims by National Board of Revenue (NBR) Chairman Abdur Rahman Khan that the system is user-friendly.
Speaking at a discussion held on We</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 11:00:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Will NCP’s Hasnat Abdullah get an easy ride now in Comilla-4?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/will-ncps-hasnat-abdullah-get-an-easy-ride-now-in-comilla-4</link><description>That is the question in Cumilla-4 after the High Court upheld a decision that knocked a key rival out of the race, sharply narrowing the field and leaving NCP’s Hasnat Abdullah to face a much weaker challenge.
On Wednesday, a High Court bench of Justice Razik Al Jalil and Justice Md Anwarul</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 11:15:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>HC petition seeks Ramadan school closure</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/lawyer-moves-high-court-to-shut-all-schools-during-ramadan</link><description>A Supreme Court lawyer has filed a petition in the High Court seeking to declare all government and private schools closed for the entire month of Ramadan.
Lawyer Ilias Ali Mandal lodged the petition on Tuesday.
The petition says, in the list of holidays and the academic calendar for 2026, govern</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 11:30:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Standard Chartered Bangladesh, World Vision join forces to build climate resilience in coastal communities</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/standard-chartered-bangladesh-world-vision-join-forces-to-build-climate-resilience-in-coastal-communities</link><description>Standard Chartered Bangladesh has agreed a new partnership with World Vision Bangladesh to launch two climate resilience initiatives designed to protect livelihoods, restore fragile ecosystems, and improve access to safe drinking water in some of Bangladesh’s most climate-vulnerable coastal r</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 11:45:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt allocates Tk 10m more for Hadi’s family</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/government-allocates-additional-tk-10m-for-expenses-of-hadis-wife-child</link><description>The Chief Advisor’s Office has decided to provide an additional Tk 10 million to cover the living expenses of the family of Sharif Osman bin Hadi.
The decision to bear the expenses of Hadi’s widow and child came a day after the government allocated Tk 10 million to purchase a flat in D</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 12:00:22 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>