<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 19:17:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Lebanon nears Hezbollah disarmament south of Litani: PM</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/lebanon-close-to-completing-disarmament-of-hezbollah-south-of-litani-river-says-pm</link><description>Lebanon is close to completing the disarmament of Hezbollah south of the Litani River, Prime Minister Nawaf Salam said on Saturday, as the country races to fulfil a key demand of its ceasefire with Israel before a year-end deadline.
The US-backed ceasefire, agreed in November 2024, ended more than</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 16:13:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CBDCs &amp; stablecoins: set to redefine financial system</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/cbdcs-stablecoins-set-to-redefine-financial-system</link><description>Every day, millions of people and businesses send money across borders - and wait. A remittance can take days to arrive, fees quietly erode income, and trillions of dollars remain locked in correspondent banking systems designed decades ago for a slower, analogue economy. For developing countries,</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 16:28:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Impact of meditation on health</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/impact-of-meditation-on-health</link><description>There is growing interest in the application of and research on meditation observing its beneficial effects on mental and physical health. There are around 275 million people practicing meditation in the world. In the United States of America (USA), 61 million people meditate and in United Kingdom</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 16:43:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>My brief brush with Osman Hadi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/reviews/my-brief-brush-with-osman-hadi</link><description>In the aftermath of last year’s anti-Hasina uprising in Bangladesh, several student leaders emerged from obscurity, propelled by a mix of anger and a demand for justice. Sharif Osman Hadi was one of them.
I first encountered Osman Hadi in September 2024 at the TSC junction of Dhaka Universit</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 16:58:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A dark day for our media</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/a-dark-day-for-our-media</link><description>In the midst of the political and extra-political turbulence of the last few days, the attack on the head offices of two national dailies, Prothom Alo and The Daily Star, in Dhaka will go down as one of the most tragic and shameful incidents in the history of the country's media industry.  On</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 17:00:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh lags behind in GVC-related trade</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/bangladesh-lags-behind-in-gvc-related-trade</link><description>Over the past thirty years, Global Value Chains (GVCs) have played a critical role in international trade and growth. Many countries have tried to increase their participation in GVCs to stay competitive in production and trade. As a result, GVC-related trade has become a key focus of trade policy.</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 17:15:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Clean air as a public health imperative</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/clean-air-as-a-public-health-imperative</link><description>Long dismissed as an unavoidable cost of development, air pollution in Bangladesh has now become a serious threat to the country's future generation. A recent World Bank report shows that hazardous air exposure has reached levels where every schoolgoing child inhales air beyond safe limits, rising</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 17:30:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Attorney General to contest Jhenaidah-1 seat for BNP</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/attorney-general-to-contest-jhenaidah-1-seat-for-bnp</link><description>Attorney General Md Asaduzzaman has announced that he will resign from his post and contest the parliamentary election from Jhenaidah-1 (Shailkupa) constituency on the paddy sheaf symbol.
“I will submit my nomination papers for the parliamentary elections along with everyone. I want to becom</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 17:45:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>President mourns death of Bangladesh's first Air Force chief AK Khandker</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/president-mourns-death-of-bangladeshs-first-air-force-chief-ak-khandker</link><description>President Mohammed Shahabuddin has expressed sorrow at the death of AK Khandker, the deputy chief of staff of the Bangladesh forces during the Liberation War and the country’s first Air Force chief.
He died around 10:30am on Saturday, aged 96.
Khandker was a pioneering figure in the formati</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 18:00:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ramadan countdown begins with Rajab moon sighting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/ramadan-countdown-begins-after-rajab-crescent-sighted-in-middle-east</link><description>The countdown to the month of Ramadan begins with Abu Dhabi confirming the sighting of the crescent moon of Rajab, the seventh month in the Islamic calendar.
According to Gulf News, Sunday is the first day of Rajab, one of Islam’s four sacred months.
Rajab marks the beginning of the final s</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 18:30:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Five vehicles plunge into Dhaleshwari from ferry</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/man-missing-as-ferry-mishap-sends-truck-four-other-vehicles-into-dhaleshwari-river</link><description>A ferry mishap has seen five vehicles, including a truck, plunge into the Dhaleshwari River while crossing in Narayanganj, leaving one person missing.
The incident occurred around 9pm on Saturday in the middle of the river, according to Inspector Md Rakibuzzaman, chief of the Boktabali River Polic</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 18:45:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Uprising warrior buried beside Poet Nazrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/uprising-warrior-buried-beside-poet-nazrul</link><description>Mass-uprising warrior and national electoral candidate martyr Sharif Osman Bin Hadi was laid to eternal rest beside National Poet Kazi Nazrul Islam following mass funeral in Dhaka on Saturday afternoon, amid a renewed pledge for building an equitable Bangladesh.



His janaza was held at the So</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 19:00:52 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>