<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 07:21:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>College student hacked to death in Habiganj</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/college-student-hacked-to-death-in-habiganj</link><description>A college student was hacked to death in broad daylight on Wednesday in Balakipur village of Baniachong upazila of Habiganj district over a family dispute.
The deceased was identified as Sadeq Chowdhury, 18, a first-year commerce student at Sachindra College in Baniachang, reports UNB.
The victim</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 04:52:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Student commits suicide in Dhaka’s Moghbazar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/student-commits-suicide-in-dhakas-moghbazar</link><description>An 18-year-old student committed suicide at his home in Dhaka’s Moghbazar area on Wednesday night.
The deceased was identified as Shahnewaz Jamal (18), a first-year student at Willes Little Flower School and College.
Police said that Shahnewaz was found hanging in his room at their house in</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 05:22:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ex-MP Tahura Ali, mother of actress Shaon, passes away</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ex-mp-tahura-ali-mother-of-actress-shaon-passes-away</link><description>Begum Tahura Ali, a former member of parliament (MP) from a reserved seat for women and director of the Citizen Group, passed away at a hospital in Dhaka early Thursday.
She died at 6:11 am while undergoing treatment at United Hospital in Dhaka, according to a post on Citizen Cables’ Faceboo</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 05:37:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rain, thundershowers likely in Ctg</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rain-thundershowers-likely-in-ctg</link><description>The Bangladesh Meteorological Department (BMD) forecast rain or thundershowers is likely to occur at one or two places over Chattogram division in the next 24 hours, beginning at 9:00 am today (Thursday).
"Rain or thundershowers is likely to occur at one or two places over Chattogram division," ac</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 05:52:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP delegation meets with CEC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-delegation-meets-with-cec</link><description>A BNP delegation is meeting with Chief Election Commissioner AMM Nasir Uddin ahead of the 13th national parliamentary elections.
The meeting began at 11:45 am on Thursday at the Nirbachan Bhaban, reports bdnews24.com.
The delegation is led by BNP National Standing Committee member Abdul Moyeen Kh</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 06:06:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Auto-rickshaw driver killed in Mymensingh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/auto-rickshaw-driver-killed-in-mymensingh</link><description>A 38-year-old auto-rickshaw driver was killed and his vehicle snatched by miscreants in Mymensingh on Wednesday night.
The deceased was identified as Masud Mia, son of Khorshed Ali of Bhalukjan area under Fulbaria municipality in the district, reports UNB.
According to police and locals, Masud to</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 06:21:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>July Uprising: Three reasons given for actor Iresh Zaker’s exemption from case</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/july-uprising-three-reasons-given-for-actor-iresh-zakers-exemption-from-case</link><description>A petition has been filed seeking the discharge of actor Iresh Zaker from the murder case of BNP activist Mahfuz Alam Sraban, who was killed during the July Uprising.
On Oct 9, the investigating officer, Inspector Sajjad Roman of Mirpur Model Police Station, submitted an interim report to the cour</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 06:51:50 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>