<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 12:49:49 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Food ministry gets new secretary</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/food-ministry-gets-new-secretary</link><description>The government has promoted the additional secretary of the public administration ministry, Md Firoz Sarkar, to the rank of secretary of the food ministry.
“The order, published in the public interest, will come into effect immediately,” according to a public administration ministry no</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 09:46:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>3-storey building catches fire at Chawkbazar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/3-storey-building-catches-fire-at-chawkbazar</link><description>A fire broke out at a three-storey residential building in Old Dhaka’s Chawkbazar on Monday afternoon.
The blaze started on the top floor of the building around 4:40pm, said Anwarul Islam, warehouse inspector of the Fire Service and Civil Defence.
Upon receiving the information, four firefi</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 10:01:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UK PM Starmer praises budget for retaining market confidence, sees growth ahead</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/uk-pm-starmer-praises-budget-for-retaining-market-confidence-sees-growth-ahead</link><description>British Prime Minister Keir Starmer said last week's budget had retained market confidence which was key to providing stability for investors and businesses, and would in time lead to economic growth.
Starmer gave a speech on Monday in which he sought to defend the budget outlined last week by fin</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 10:16:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prime Bank signs Payroll Banking Agreement &amp; Cash Management Services with Quality Feeds Limited</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/prime-bank-signs-payroll-banking-agreement-cash-management-services-with-quality-feeds-limited</link><description>Prime Bank PLC. recently signed an agreement with Quality Feeds Limited, a leading Bangladeshi animal feed manufacturer, to offer comprehensive Payroll Banking and Cash Management services.
The signing ceremony took place at Quality Feed’s corporate office in Dhaka, according to a media rele</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 10:31:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh Bank clears path to liquidate nine troubled NBFIs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh-bank-clears-path-to-liquidate-nine-troubled-nbfis</link><description>Bangladesh Bank has approved the liquidation of nine non-banking financial institutions (NBFIs) after years of irregularities, mismanagement and failure to return depositors’ funds, marking one of the largest clean-ups of the sector to date.
The central bank’s Board of Directors signed</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 10:46:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No physical displacement of metro rail in earthquake: DMTCL</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/no-physical-displacement-of-metro-rail-in-earthquake-dmtcl</link><description>The Mass Rapid Transit (MRT) metro rail was not affected by the recent earthquake, as experts confirmed that no physical displacement was detected.
“There was no physical displacement of the metro rail due to the recent earthquake,” said Md Faruk Ahmed, Managing Director of Dhaka Mass</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 11:01:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ICC chief says US sanctions won't change court's handling of cases</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/icc-chief-says-us-sanctions-wont-change-courts-handling-of-cases</link><description>The president of the International Criminal Court said on Monday US sanctions imposed on senior court officials disrupt their personal lives but vowed the institution would not yield to outside pressure.
President Donald Trump's administration slapped targeted sanctions on nine ICC officials, incl</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 11:16:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BRAC Bank TARA, Neeramoy to extend digital healthcare privileges for women customers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/brac-bank-tara-neeramoy-to-extend-digital-healthcare-privileges-for-women-customers</link><description>BRAC Bank has partnered with Neeramoy Digital Services Limited to unlock a suite of exclusive digital healthcare benefits at a lower cost for its TARA women customers, reinforcing the programme’s mission to uplift women’s well-being with meaningful, tech-enabled solutions.
Under this c</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 11:31:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UK and US poised to agree zero-tariffs deal on pharmaceuticals</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/uk-and-us-poised-to-agree-zero-tariffs-deal-on-pharmaceuticals-the-times-says</link><description>The UK is poised to agree on a major pharmaceuticals deal with the US, which will mean zero import tariffs on pharmaceutical products into the US and lead to an increase in NHS spending on medicines, The Times reported on Monday.
The UK government is understood to have agreed to lower an industry</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 11:46:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Landmine casualties hit 4-year high, driven by conflicts in Syria, Myanmar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/landmine-casualties-hit-4-year-high-driven-by-conflicts-in-syria-myanmar</link><description>Deaths and injuries from landmines and unexploded ordnance hit a four-year high in 2024, driven by conflicts in Syria and Myanmar, a new report showed on Monday.
The data comes as a number of European countries move to withdraw from a treaty banning landmine use, citing the threat of Russian aggre</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 12:01:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Promises beyond capacity are betrayal of people: Rizvi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/promises-beyond-capacity-are-betrayal-of-people-rizvi</link><description>With the national election on the horizon, BNP Senior Joint Secretary General Ruhul Kabir Rizvi on Monday stressed that political promises must remain within realistic bounds, warning that pledges beyond capacity amount to a betrayal of the people.
Rizvi made the remarks at a policy-focused town h</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 12:16:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Five Chinese killed in cross-border attacks from Afghanistan: Tajikistan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/tajikistan-says-five-chinese-nationals-killed-in-cross-border-attacks-from-afghanistan-in-past-week</link><description>Five Chinese nationals have been killed and five more injured in Tajikistan in attacks launched from neighbouring Afghanistan over the past week, Tajik authorities and China's embassy in the Central Asian country said on Monday.
China's embassy in Dushanbe, the capital, advised Chinese companies a</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 12:31:30 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>