<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 07:21:26 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Trump blocks chips deal, cites security, China-related concerns</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/trump-blocks-chips-deal-cites-security-china-related-concerns</link><description>President Donald Trump on Friday blocked US photonics firm HieFo Corp's $3 million acquisition of assets in New Jersey-based aerospace and defense specialist Emcore, citing national security and China-related concerns.
In an order released by the White House, Trump said HieFo was "controlled by a</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 05:10:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Canada asks Air India to probe pilot’s removal over alcohol influence</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/canada-asks-air-india-to-probe-incident-of-pilot-removed-from-plane-under-influence-of-alcohol-source-says</link><description>Canada's transport regulator has asked Air India to investigate an incident of a pilot who was removed from a plane before it was due to take off and found to be under the influence of alcohol, a person familiar with the matter said.
Two breathalyser tests conducted by Canadian police at Vancouver</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 05:25:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka’s temperature drops to season’s lowest 12.5°C</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dhakas-temperature-drops-to-seasons-lowest-125c</link><description>Amid shivering cold and dense fog, Dhaka recorded the season’s lowest 12.5 Degrees Celsius on Saturday morning, according to Bangladesh Metrological Department.
Dhaka and its surrounding areas may remain covered by moderate to dense fog until noon, it said.
The prevailing cold and foggy con</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 05:40:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rumeen Farhana’s income rises 22-fold in six years</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/rumeen-farhanas-income-rises-22-fold-in-six-years</link><description>The declared income and assets of Rumeen Farhana, who was recently expelled from the BNP, have changed markedly over the past six years.
A comparison of election affidavits submitted in 2019 and those filed in 2025 ahead of the 13th parliamentary polls shows that her annual income increased more t</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 05:55:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DWASA moves to set up Tk 7.21b training, research academy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dwasa-moves-to-set-up-tk-721b-training-research-academy</link><description>Dhaka Water Supply and Sewerage Authority (DWASA) is set to establish a dedicated Training and Research Academy aimed at reducing its long-standing dependence on costly local and foreign consultancy services.
The proposed project, titled 'Dhaka Wasa Training and Research Academy Establishment', wi</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 05:15:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka's air quality second worst in the world on Saturday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dhakas-air-quality-second-worst-in-the-world-on-saturday</link><description>Dhaka has ranked as the second most polluted city in the world on Saturday, according to Air Quality Index (AQI) data.
Even on a weekend, the Bangladeshi capital recorded an AQI score of 261 at 11am, placing the air quality in the “very unhealthy” category.
Afghanistan’s capit</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 05:30:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NBR adds 131,000 new VAT payers in December</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/nbr-adds-131000-new-vat-payers-in-december</link><description>The National Board of Revenue (NBR) registered around 131,000 new Value Added Tax (VAT) entities across the country in December under a special nationwide VAT registration campaign.
The NBR observed VAT Day on December 10 and VAT Week from December 10 to 15, 2025, with the theme “Register on</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 05:45:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mustafizur dropped from KKR squad on BCCI directive</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/mustafizur-dropped-from-kkr-squad-on-bcci-directive</link><description>Bangladesh pacer Mustafizur Rahman, the only Bangladeshi cricketer to secure a team in this year’s Indian Premier League (IPL), has been dropped from the Kolkata Knight Riders (KKR) squad following a directive from the Board of Control for Cricket in India (BCCI).
KKR had signed Mustafizur f</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 06:00:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Former NCP leader Tasnim Jara’s nomination rejected</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/former-ncp-leader-tasnim-jaras-nomination-rejected</link><description>The nomination papers of Tasnim Jara, an independent candidate from the Dhaka-9 constituency and a former NCP leader, have been rejected by the Dhaka district returning officer.
The decision was announced on Saturday (January 3) following the scrutiny of nomination papers.
According to her electi</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 06:15:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>30th DITF kicks off</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/30th-ditf-kicks-off</link><description>The curtain rose on the 30th Dhaka International Trade Fair (DITF) on Saturday as Commerce Adviser Sk Bashir Uddin formally inaugurated the month-long event at the China-Bangladesh Friendship Exhibition Center (CBFEC) in Purbachal, Rupganj.
Describing the fair as a landmark in the country's commer</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 06:30:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique’s Bogura-6 nomination declared valid</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tariques-bogura-6-nomination-declared-valid</link><description>The nomination paper of BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman for the Bogura-6 constituency was declared valid on Saturday.
Returning Officer Md Toufiqul Rahman announced the decision in the morning after scrutinising nomination papers at his office.
The nomination of Jamaat-e-Islami-backed candidat</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 06:45:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>bKash launches ‘bHive’ to provide students with early corporate exposure</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bkash-launches-bhive-to-provide-students-with-early-corporate-exposure</link><description>Traditionally, students gain professional exposure through internships at the end of their academic life. Breaking away from this conventional approach, bKash has introduced a unique career development initiative titled ‘bHive’, designed to connect students with the corporate environmen</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 07:00:48 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>