<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 13:28:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Hong Kong mourns victims of blaze that killed 128 and counting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/hong-kong-mourns-victims-of-blaze-that-killed-128-and-counting</link><description>Hong Kong on Saturday mourned the 128 people known to have died in a massive fire at a high-rise apartment complex, a toll that is likely to rise with 150 still missing days after the disaster.Authorities have arrested 11 people in connection with the city's worst blaze in nearly 80 years as they i</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 10:23:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Workshop held on advancing diversity, equality and inclusion in media</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/workshop-held-on-advancing-diversity-equality-and-inclusion-in-media</link><description>A practical guideline is needed to ensure equal rights, opportunities, participation, and representation for persons with disabilities and all gender diverse people in the media and in news coverage based on fairness. This guideline will provide media professionals with various directions. As the i</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 10:38:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Advisers clear draft amendment to foreign donations law</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/advisers-clear-draft-amendment-to-foreign-donations-law</link><description>The Council of Advisers on Saturday approved in principle the draft of the Foreign Donations (Voluntary Activities) Regulation (Amendment) Ordinance, 2025, noting that the updated law has been made more stakeholder-friendly.
The approval came during a special meeting of the Council held at the Chi</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 10:53:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prime Bank re-elects Tanjil Chowdhury as Chairman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/prime-bank-re-elects-tanjil-chowdhury-as-chairman</link><description>The Board of Directors of Prime Bank PLC., in its 585th meeting, has re-elected Tanjil Chowdhury as Chairman of the bank.
Chowdhury first assumed the role of Chairman in 2020 and has since led Prime Bank through a transformative period of growth and innovation, according to a media release.</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 11:08:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Home Adviser visits Evercare Hospital to enquire about Khaleda Zia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/home-adviser-visits-evercare-hospital-to-enquire-about-khaleda-zia</link><description>Home Affairs Adviser Lt Gen (retd) Jahangir Alam Chowdhury visited Evercare Hospital in the capital on Saturday to enquire about the health condition of critically ill BNP Chairperson Begum Khaleda Zia.
He reached the hospital shortly after 1:15pm and talked to the doctors overseeing her treatment</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 11:23:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BPL drops players linked to fixing allegations from final auction list</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/bpl-drops-players-linked-to-fixing-allegations-from-final-auction-list</link><description>The Bangladesh Cricket Board has removed a group of players from the final Bangladesh Premier League (BPL) auction list amid ongoing concerns over alleged fixing links.
While the board has not formally named the cricketers, seven players who appeared in the preliminary draft are missing from the f</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 11:38:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt has no objection to Tarique’s return, says CA press secretary</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-has-no-objection-to-tariques-return-says-ca-press-secretary</link><description>The interim government on Saturday said there is no restriction or objection regarding BNP Acting Chairperson Tarique Rahman’s return to the country.
Chief Adviser's Press Secretary Shafiqul Alam made it clear when he was asked whether there is any restriction or objection from the governmen</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 11:27:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh celebrates 50 years of Timor-Leste’s Proclamation of Independence</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-celebrates-50-years-of-timor-lestes-proclamation-of-independence</link><description>Bangladesh celebrated the 50th anniversary of Timor-Leste’s Proclamation of Independence with a grand reception held on 28 November 2025 at the Grand Ballroom of Hotel Sheraton, Dhaka.
The event, hosted by Engr. Kutubuddin Ahmed, Honorary Consul of Timor-Leste to Bangladesh, brought together</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 11:42:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How does the Hong Kong tower fire compare to other recent building blazes?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/how-does-the-hong-kong-tower-fire-compare-to-other-recent-building-blazes</link><description>A blaze that ripped through a massive apartment block in Hong Kong has claimed at least 128 lives, with 150 people still missing, surpassing the toll of a similar incident at London's Grenfell Tower in 2017.
 
Here is how the disaster compares to some other major building fire incidents arou</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 11:57:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Aminul urges BNP activists to avoid crowding outside hospital</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/aminul-urges-bnp-activists-to-avoid-crowding-outside-hospital</link><description>Convener of Dhaka North City unit BNP, Aminul Haque on Saturday urged party leaders and activists not to gather at the entrance of Evercare Hospital, where BNP Chairperson and former Prime Minister Begum Khaleda Zia is receiving treatment.
Addressing the crowd this afternoon via a microphone outsi</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 12:12:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fakhrul calls for policies to revive industries; make looters accountable</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/fakhrul-calls-for-policies-to-revive-industries-make-looters-accountable</link><description>BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir on Saturday emphasised the urgent need for reopening factories and industries closed over the past 15 years, reminding that their shutdown has left 1.4 million people unemployed.
Speaking at the ‘4th Bangladesh Economic Summit 2025’ in</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 12:27:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khaleda not fit to travel abroad now: Fakhrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/khaleda-not-fit-to-travel-abroad-now-fakhrul</link><description>BNP Chairperson Khaleda Zia, currently receiving treatment in a Dhaka hospital, is not in a condition to be sent abroad at this moment, Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir has said.
The BNP secretary general provided the update on Khaleda’s condition at a press conference on Saturday afternoon at he</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 12:42:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>