<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 04:25:49 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Return back to Nature ensures survival of human race</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/return-back-to-nature-ensures-survival-of-human-race</link><description>Nepal has emerged as the most Nature-connected nation in the world, according to a research, first of its kind, conducted by academics from Britain and Austria. Involved with the ground-breaking research was Miles Richardson, a famed professor of Nature connectedness at the University of Derby. The</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 19:42:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Reining in online gambling</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/reining-in-online-gambling</link><description>The reported government's move to crack down on online gambling deserves unreserved commendation. For too long, this digital menace has flourished unchecked, feeding on people's vulnerabilities and taking advantage of technological loopholes. The decision, taken at a high-level meeting at the Bangl</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 19:57:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No scope to protect investors’ interests in merging five banks: BB</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/no-scope-to-protect-investors-interests-in-merging-five-banks-bb</link><description>Bangladesh Bank has said that under the Bank Resolution Ordinance 2025, there is currently no scope to consider the protection of investors’ or shareholders’ interests in the ongoing merger of five Shariah-based banks.
In a statement issued on Thursday night, the central bank clarified</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 20:12:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Forex buffer wanes amid earnings, spending mismatch</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/forex-buffer-wanes-amid-earnings-spending-mismatch</link><description>Bangladesh sees its foreign-currency buffers wane amid a rather abrupt earnings dip and external payments, stoking fears of pressure on the country's current-account balance too soon.
The fall in foreign-currency surplus happened principally because of the steadily growing overseas liabilities of</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 01:59:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>WB, ADB unite under new framework for Bangladesh’s development financing</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/streamlining-bangladesh-development-financing-wb-adb-unite-under-new-framework</link><description>The World Bank (WB) and the Asian Development Bank (ADB) would work together to finance Bangladesh's big projects as the country signed a mutual framework for streamlining their loans and ensuring the best utilisation of the money, officials said on Thursday.
From now on, both the key multilateral</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 02:14:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ancillaries dominate spending in WB-funded BBS capacity upgrade project</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ancillaries-receive-most-allocation-in-wb-funded-bbs-capacity-upgrade-project</link><description>Most money for a World Bank-funded development project for Bangladesh Bureau of Statistics (BBS) has been allocated for operational expenses on ancillaries that range from toiletries to foreign trainings, raising questions about justification.
On the wish-list are toilet tissues, toilet cleaning d</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 02:29:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh can stop 11pc GDP erosion if no child drops out of school: UNESCO Report</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh-can-stop-11pc-gdp-erosion-if-no-child-drops-out-of-school-unesco-report</link><description>Bangladesh could avert an economic loss equivalent to 11 per cent of its gross domestic product (GDP) by ensuring that no child drops out of school, according to a report by the United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization (UNESCO).
The potential gain could increase to as much</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 02:44:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Padma Oil logs record profit, declares highest-ever dividend</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/padma-oil-logs-record-profit-declares-highest-ever-dividend</link><description>Padma Oil has posted a record annual profit of Tk 5.63 billion for FY25, driven by higher sales and substantial non-operating income from bank deposits.
The state-run oil distributor also registered a 38 per cent year-on-year profit growth for the year, according to price-sensitive information pub</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 02:59:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>HC upholds fines on Beximco, BD Finance stock manipulators</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/hc-upholds-fines-on-beximco-bd-finance-stock-manipulators</link><description>The High Court (HC) has upheld the securities regulator's decision to impose fines on 22 investors, including individuals, for manipulating stock prices of Beximco and BD Finance.
In an order issued on Thursday, an HC bench comprising Justice Kazi Zinat Hoque and Justice Aynun Nahar Siddiqua valid</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 03:26:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP pledges to implement signed July Charter, urges parties not to derail polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-pledges-to-implement-signed-july-charter-urges-parties-not-to-block-polls-with-new-issues</link><description>BNP on Thursday reaffirmed its full commitment to implementing the “July National Charter”, signed on October 17, and urged all political parties not to raise new issues or create crises that could hinder the upcoming election.
The party made its position clear on the ongoing political</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 03:41:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No new licences for MFIs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/no-new-licences-for-mfis</link><description>No new licences will be issued to microfinance institutions (MFIs), as the microfinance sector in Bangladesh is now overcrowded, said Dr Mohammad Helal Uddin, Executive Vice Chairman of the Microcredit Regulatory Authority (MRA).
He made the remarks while speaking as the chief guest at an event or</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 03:56:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Consensus Commission bins claims of Tk 830m expenditure on hospitality</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/consensus-commission-bins-claims-of-tk-830-million-expenditure-on-hospitality</link><description>The National Consensus Commission (NCC) has refuted claims that it spent Tk 830 million on hospitality, stating that its total expenditure was Tk 17.1 million, of which Tk 4.5 million was spent on hospitality.
“A very recent campaign by a certain quarter has falsely alleged that the National</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 04:11:51 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>