<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 03:38:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Ensure law and order at any cost</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ensure-law-and-order-at-any-cost</link><description>Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus has directed security agencies to ensure that law and order are maintained "at any cost" in the lead-up to the upcoming national election, amid growing concerns over political tensions, targeted violence, and attacks on media and cultural institutions.
The di</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 02:04:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Inflation to cool below 7pc by June for policy panaceas</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/inflation-to-cool-below-7pc-by-june-for-policy-panaceas</link><description>People's income-sapping inflation is expected to steadily fall below 7 per cent by June 2026, healed by contractionary monetary policy, fiscal restraint and improving balance across key economic indicators.
Such a feel-good ambiance of economic rebound from previous slowdown comes clear from a gov</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 02:19:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>17 arrested, 31 identified over attacks on Prothom Alo, Daily Star</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/17-arrested-31-identified-over-attacks-on-prothom-alo-daily-star</link><description>The law enforcement agencies have arrested 17 individuals and identified 31 others in connection with recent vandalism and arson attacks on the offices of Prothom Alo and The Daily Star.
The arrests were made following a thorough analysis of video footage of the incidents, said Additional Commissi</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 02:34:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Excelerate Energy to start LNG supply from early January</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/excelerate-energy-to-start-lng-supply-from-early-january</link><description>US-based Excelerate Energy is set to begin supplying liquefied natural gas (LNG) to Bangladesh from early January under a long-term contract, providing a fresh boost to the country's strained natural gas-supply system.
"We will start purchasing LNG from the US company from January under a sales an</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 01:35:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ADB, GoB sign loan deals worth $688m to support project</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/adb-gob-sign-loan-deals-worth-688m-to-support-project</link><description>The Asian Development Bank (ADB) and the Government of Bangladesh (GoB) on Monday signed loan agreements worth $688 million to upgrade the 35-kilometre Chattogram-Dohazari railway line.
The South Asia Sub-regional Economic Cooperation (SASEC)-Chattogram-Dohazari Railway Project will also construct</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 01:50:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Court orders sending Benazir's household items to CA's Relief Fund</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/court-orders-sending-benazirs-household-items-to-cas-relief-fund</link><description>A Dhaka court has directed that household items seized from the Gulshan flats of former Inspector General of Police (IGP) Benazir Ahmed, including used and unused clothes, kitchen appliances, crockery and other consumables, be handed over to the Chief Adviser's Relief Fund instead of being auctione</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 02:05:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NBFC lending drops 4.62pc in Q3'25</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/nbfc-lending-drops-462pc-in-q325</link><description>Loan and advance disbursements by non-bank financial companies (NBFCs) continued to decline in the July-September period of 2025, extending a downward trend that began after peaking in the first quarter of the year, despite remaining well above last year's levels.
Total disbursements of economic-p</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 02:20:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gold price hits new record at Tk 222,082 per bhori</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/gold-price-hits-new-record-at-tk-222082-per-bhori</link><description>Gold prices jumped to an all-time high at Tk 222,082 per bhori in the local market as the Bangladesh Jewellers Association (BAJUS) revised the price of the 22-carat gold anew on Monday night.
The new rate will come into effect from today (Tuesday), BAJUS said in a statement.
BAJUS adjusted the go</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 02:35:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Regulatory and institutional gaps key challenges for eco-industrial parks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/regulatory-and-institutional-gaps-key-challenges-for-eco-industrial-parks</link><description>Regulatory and institutional gaps as well as technical-capacity constraints of the stakeholders are the key challenges for implementing environmentally-friendly Eco-Industrial Parks (EIPs) in Bangladesh, speakers observed at a workshop.
The workshop titled 'Eco-Industrial Parks (EIP) Light Touch A</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 02:50:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ESG reporting gains pace among Bangladeshi companies</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/esg-reporting-gains-pace-among-bangladeshi-companies</link><description>The number of Bangladeshi firms more than doubled to 16 in terms of reporting on Environmental, Social and Governance (ESG) compliance in the last two years, according to Bloomberg.
ESG is the most recognised sustainability matrix worldwide, and the global investment data provider Bloomberg leads</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 03:05:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamuna Oil, Meghna Petroleum see billions stuck in cash-strapped banks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/jamuna-oil-meghna-petroleum-see-billions-stuck-in-cash-strapped-banks</link><description>State-run Jamuna oil and Meghna Petroleum are at 'high credit risk' as their investments in fixed deposit receipts (FDRs) equivalent to Tk 16.95 billion are stuck with banks facing acute liquidity crises.
The banks are Global Islami Bank, Union Bank, First Security Islami Bank, Social Islami Bank,</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 03:20:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BSC approves 25pc cash dividend after record profit</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/bsc-approves-25pc-cash-dividend-after-record-profit</link><description>The board of directors of Bangladesh Shipping Corporation (BSC) has approved a 25 per cent cash dividend for FY25 at its 48th annual general meeting (AGM), held in Chattogram on Monday.
Brigadier General (retd) Dr M Shakhawat Hossain, adviser to the Ministry of Shipping and chairman of the BSC boa</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 03:35:39 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>