<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 17:19:13 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Attacks on two media outlets is a shame for nation: Salahuddin</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/attacks-on-two-media-outlets-is-a-shame-for-nation-salahuddin</link><description>BNP Standing Committee member Salahuddin Ahmed on Sunday described the recent arson attacks on two leading newspapers as a shame for the nation, questioning the government’s role over the incidents.
“The unfortunate incidents that occurred a few days ago, where several leading newspape</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 13:49:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>402nd board meeting of Shahjalal Islami Bank held</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/402nd-board-meeting-of-shahjalal-islami-bank-held</link><description>The 402nd meeting of the Board of Directors of Shahjalal Islami Bank PLC was held on 17th December 2025 at Corporate Head Office of the bank.
The meeting was presided over by the Chairman Mr. A. K. Azad. The board approved a number of investment proposal, according to a press release.
Among other</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 14:04:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Managing key state institutions becomes difficult, says Asif Nazrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/managing-key-state-institutions-becomes-difficult-says-asif-nazrul</link><description>Law Advisor Asif Nazrul has said managing key state institutions has become difficult due to their “weakened foundation over the past one and a half decades.”
In his speech at the seventh convocation of the State University of Bangladesh (SUB) in Purbachal on Sunday, he said: “De</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 14:19:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NRB Bank holds its 12th Annual General Meeting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/nrb-bank-holds-its-12th-annual-general-meeting</link><description>NRB Bank PLC successfully conducted its 12th Annual General Meeting (AGM), at which the shareholders approved the audited financial statements for the preceding year, declaration of dividend, appointment of the statutory auditors and corporate governance auditors for the year 2025 and fixation of t</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 14:34:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bank Asia partners with Heidelberg Materials Bangladesh on integrated cash management</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bank-asia-partners-with-heidelberg-materials-bangladesh-on-integrated-cash-management</link><description>Bank Asia PLC and Heidelberg Materials Bangladesh PLC have entered into a strategic partnership to introduce an integrated cash management solution for further strengthening the collaboration between the two organisations, according to a press release.
The agreement was formally signed by Mr. Soha</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 14:49:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat-e-Islami backs Inqilab Moncho’s 24-hour ultimatum for Hadi killers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-e-islami-backs-inqilab-monchos-24-hour-ultimatum-for-hadi-killers</link><description>Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami has expressed solidarity with the 24-hour ultimatum issued by Inqilab Moncho, demanding the immediate arrest of those responsible for the killing of Sharif Osman Hadi.
Jamaat-e-Islami Secretary General Mia Golam Parwar, urged the government to clarify its position and sw</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 15:04:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Kazi Farms Kitchen crowned number one frozen food brand for 4th consecutive year</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/kazi-farms-kitchen-crowned-number-one-frozen-food-brand-for-4th-consecutive-year</link><description>Kazi Farms Kitchen has once again been recognised as the number one frozen food brand in Bangladesh at the prestigious 17th Best Brand Award 2025, marking an exceptional 4th consecutive win in this category.
The award ceremony, organised by Bangladesh Brand Forum, was held on Saturday at the Grand</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 15:19:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hadi murder: CID finds Tk 1.27 billion abnormal transactions linked to Faisal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/hadi-murder-cid-finds-tk-127-billion-abnormal-transactions-linked-to-faisal</link><description>The Criminal Investigation Department (CID) has uncovered evidence of “suspicious transactions” worth Tk 1.27 billion in bank accounts linked to Faisal Karim Masud, key suspect in the murder of Sharif Osman bin Hadi, and his associates.
In a Sunday press note, the CID said it has launc</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 15:34:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Daylong protests force six pro-Awami League deans at Rajshahi University to resign</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/daylong-protests-force-six-pro-awami-league-deans-at-rajshahi-university-to-resign</link><description>In the face of a daylong student protest, six pro-Awami League deans at Rajshahi University have resigned.
Registrar Professor Iftikharul Alam Masud confirmed the resignations on Sunday night.
The students staged demonstrations throughout the day, including the locking of dean chambers and confin</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 15:49:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Urgent, inclusive, localised action suggested to address lightning risks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/urgent-inclusive-localised-action-suggested-to-address-lightning-risks</link><description>A new study has called for urgent, inclusive, and localised action to address lightning risks, one of the country’s fastest-growing climate-related hazards.
The study highlighted that lightning strikes claimed nearly 2,000 lives and injured more than 1,300 people between 2009 and 2024, dispr</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 16:04:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique Rahman urges vigilance against efforts to ‘cause anarchy’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-rahman-urges-vigilance-against-efforts-to-cause-anarchy</link><description>Acting BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman has warned that some elements are attempting to create “anarchy” across the country and urged party activists to remain vigilant.
Attending an inauguration of a digital memorial for those slain in the July Uprising in Bogura, he said the coming days w</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 16:19:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Police find no evidence of ‘locked’ door before BNP leader's home set ablaze</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/police-find-no-evidence-of-locked-door-before-bnp-leaders-home-set-ablaze</link><description>Police claim they have found no evidence of the BNP leader’s house in Lakshmipur being locked before it was set on fire with petrol, despite allegations.
The fire broke out at the house of Belal Hossain, the co-organising secretary of BNP’s Bhabaniganj Union in Sadar Upazila, on Friday</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 16:34:24 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>