<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 07:30:26 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Rising uncertainty pushes global supply chains to diversify in 2026</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/rising-uncertainty-pushes-global-supply-chains-to-diversify-in-2026</link><description>Uncertainty driven by trade tensions and geopolitical pressures is prompting both buyers and suppliers to accelerate diversification strategies, aiming to bolster resilience in 2026, which is expected to be a more volatile year, according to a new report.
The study, conducted by Quality Inspection</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 03:48:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Eastland Insurance initiates its 40th anniversary celebration</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/eastland-insurance-initiates-its-40th-anniversary-celebration</link><description>Eastland Insurance Company Limited hosted a Mezbaan at the Officers' Club in Dhaka on Saturday, initiating its 40th anniversary celebration.
Chairman of the Board of Directors of the company Mr. Mahbubur Rahman, flanked by esteemed gusts, cut a cake at the event to mark the beginning of the celebr</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 04:03:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>25 killed in attack by Islamic State-backed group in Congo</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/africa/25-killed-in-attack-by-islamic-state-backed-group-in-congo</link><description>An attack by an Islamic State-linked militant group in eastern Congo killed at least 25 people early Sunday, a rights group based in Ituri province said.
The dead from the attack by the Allied Democratic Force, or ADF, include 15 men who were burned alive in a house and seven who were shot in the</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 04:18:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>15 killed, 28 missing after ferry sinks in Southern Philippines</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/15-killed-28-missing-after-ferry-sinks-in-southern-philippines</link><description>At least 15 bodies were recovered, and 28 people remained missing after an inter-island ferry carrying at least 350 people sank early Monday morning in waters off Basilan province in the southern Philippines, authorities said.
Romel Dua, a Philippine Coast Guard (PCG) commander, said at least 316</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 04:33:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Over 11,400 flights cancelled as massive winter storm hits US</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/over-11400-flights-cancelled-as-massive-winter-storm-hits-us</link><description>A massive winter storm made for a brutal travel day Sunday, with widespread cancellations and delays at some of the nation's busiest airports.
Widespread snow, sleet and freezing rain threatened nearly 180 million people — more than half the US population — in a path stretching from th</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 04:48:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Verdict in Chankharpul killings case today</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/verdict-in-chankharpul-killings-case-today</link><description>The International Crimes Tribunal-1 is set to its verdict in the case over the killing of six people during the July Uprising of 2024 at Chankharpul in the capital on Monday.
On January 20, the three-member bench of the tribunal led by its Chairman Justice Golam Mortuza Mozumder, deferred the verd</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 05:03:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladeshi worker dies after fall from building in Qatar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladeshi-worker-dies-after-fall-from-building-in-qatar</link><description>A Bangladeshi expatriate worker died after falling from a four-storey building at a construction site in Qatar on Sunday.
The deceased was identified as Liton Das, 23, a resident of the Chhakapan area in Kulaura upazila of Moulvibazar district. He was the son of Nantu Das.
The incident occurred i</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 05:18:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India to slash tariffs on cars to 40pc in trade deal with EU</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/india-to-slash-tariffs-on-cars-to-40pc-in-trade-deal-with-eu</link><description>India plans to slash tariffs on cars imported from the European Union to 40 per cent from as high as 110 per cent, sources said, in the biggest opening yet of the country's vast market as the two sides close in on a free trade pact that could come as early as Tuesday.
Prime Minister Narendra Modi'</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 05:33:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gold blasts past $5,000 an ounce for first time ever</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/gold-blasts-past-5000-an-ounce-for-first-time-ever</link><description>Gold surged to a record high above $5,000 an ounce on Monday, extending ​a historic rally as investors piled into the safe-haven asset amid rising geopolitical uncertainties.
Spot gold rose ‌1.98 per cent to $5,081.18 per ounce by 0323 GMT, after touching $5,092.71 earlier. US gold futures fo</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 05:48:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh Embassy in US to remain closed due to inclement weather</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-embassy-in-us-to-remain-closed-due-to-inclement-weather</link><description>The Bangladesh Embassy in Washington, DC, will remain closed on Monday (January 26) due to inclement weather, according to a message issued by the mission.
The embassy said all consular appointments scheduled for the day will be appropriately rescheduled.
For emergencies, the embassy has asked Ba</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 06:03:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scrapping bonded yarn imports may hurt RMG exports: BGBA</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/scrapping-bonded-yarn-imports-may-hurt-rmg-exports-bgba</link><description>The Bangladesh Garment Buying House Association (BGBA) has warned that scrapping the bonded warehouse facility for yarn imports could disrupt the supply chain, push up production costs and undermine apparel exports, urging the government to withdraw what it described as a "self-destructive" decisio</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 06:18:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nilphamari Bangladesh-China hospital will reduce patient flow to Dhaka, Rangpur: CA</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/nilphamari-bangladesh-china-hospital-will-reduce-patient-flow-to-dhaka-rangpur-ca</link><description>A new Bangladesh–China Friendship General Hospital in Nilphamari will play a key role in decentralising healthcare and easing the pressure on hospitals centred in Rangpur and Dhaka, says Chief Adviser Muhammad Yunus.
His remarks came on Sunday while approving the project to establish the 100</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 06:33:24 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>