<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 03:20:29 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>FIFA to broadcast World Cup match schedule unveiling on Saturday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/fifa-to-broadcast-world-cup-match-schedule-unveiling-on-saturday</link><description>FIFA said it will reveal the updated match schedule for the 2026 World Cup in a live global broadcast from Washington on Saturday, nearly 24 hours after the final draw determines the tournament’s unprecedented 12 groups of four.
The show, set for 12:00pm EST (1700 GMT), will confirm venues a</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 17:09:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cold waves may sweep parts of Bangladesh after middle of December</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/cold-waves-may-sweep-parts-of-bangladesh-after-middle-of-december</link><description>One or two mild to moderate cold waves may sweep across the western and northern parts of Bangladesh in the second half of December, the Bangladesh Meteorological Department (BMD) has forecast.
The prediction came in a long-term weather forecast for the current month, issued on Monday.
It warned</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 17:24:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CNG autorickshaw driver shot dead in Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cng-autorickshaw-driver-shot-dead-in-dhaka</link><description>A CNG-powered autorickshaw driver has been shot dead in Dhaka’s Jurain.
The man, identified only as Bappa, 30, was taken to Dhaka Medical College Hospital around 7pm on Monday with a gunshot wound to the waist, where doctors declared him dead.
Inspector Md Faruk, in-charge of the hospital&amp;r</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 17:56:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Independent central bank: ideal vs illusion</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/independent-central-bank-ideal-vs-illusion</link><description>This article is inspired by recent discourses and insightful commentaries across the print media on the “Need for an Independent Central Bank (ICB).” Few would contest their arguments that political dominance over the Bangladesh Bank (BB) has undermined monetary discipline, distorted cr</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 18:11:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Single-dose vaccine against dengue</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/single-dose-vaccine-against-dengue</link><description>Brazil is learnt to have launched a single-dose anti-dengue vaccine last Wednesday (November 30) after obtaining its registration approval by the county's drug regulator, Anvisa. Developed by Butantan Institute in Sao Paulo, the vaccine called, Butantan-DV, is claimed to be the world's first single</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 18:26:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Political will a must to restore confidence in businesses</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/political-will-a-must-to-restore-confidence-in-businesses</link><description>In Bangladesh today, the central question facing the economy is not simply how to stabilise financial institutions or stimulate investment. It is whether the political leadership possesses the will to confront decades of entrenched corruption, rebuild trust in public institutions, and restore confi</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 18:41:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Correlation between energy crunch and industrial production</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/correlation-between-energy-crunch-and-industrial-production</link><description>Energy consumption has historically been a vital indicator of robust economic activities and improved living standards. But when this input turns irregular and insufficient, driving up its costs to an outrageous level, the manufacturing sector can hardly be sustainable. Bangladesh, according to sea</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 18:56:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>77 more upazilas get new UNOs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/77-more-upazilas-get-new-unos</link><description>The government has appointed Upazila Nirbahi Officers (UNOs) in 77 more upazilas.
The Ministry of Public Administration issued a gazette notification in this regard, appointing senior assistant secretaries to the posts.
This comes after the first phase of appointments on November 26, when 166 upa</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 19:11:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Factories mostly linked to US market feel strain</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/factories-mostly-linked-to-us-market-feel-strain</link><description>A survey supported by two international agencies has found jacked-up US tariff's emerging but uneven business impacts on Bangladesh's garment export as factories mostly linked to the American market are already showing signs of strain.



High market concentration with exports heavily reliant o</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 19:26:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rice, fish, meat key drivers of Oct food inflation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/rice-fish-meat-key-drivers-of-oct-food-inflation</link><description>Rice, fish, and meat remained the dominant drivers of food inflation in October, accounting for 99.78 per cent of the total, while a continued decline in vegetable prices helped temper overall price pressures, according to the General Economics Division (GED) of the Planning Commission.
The Novemb</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 02:00:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka continues attempts to revise overpriced JICA metro-rail bids</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/dhaka-continues-attempts-to-revise-overpriced-jica-metro-rail-bids</link><description>Dhaka Metro Rail Company continues its effort for negotiating over-priced quotations in various contracts of metro-rail projects and will soon send a reminder to the projects' Japanese financier.
Managing Director of Dhaka Mass Transit Company Limited (DMTCL) Faruque Ahmed explained the move durin</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 02:15:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Parts of Chattogram shaken by 4.9-magnitude quake</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/49-magnitude-earthquake-in-myanmar-shakes-parts-of-chattogram</link><description>A moderate earthquake struck near Falam in Myanmar shortly before 1:00 am on Tuesday and was felt in parts of Chattogram.
According to the US Geological Survey (USGS), the quake occurred at 12:55am Bangladesh time, registering 4.9 on the Richter scale.
The epicentre was located 81.8km east of Fal</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 02:30:59 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>