<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 11:37:58 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Hundreds of mourners injured at Odinga memorial in Kenya, local media reports</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/africa/hundreds-of-mourners-injured-at-odinga-memorial-in-kenya-local-media-reports</link><description>Hundreds of mourners were injured on Saturday at a memorial service for Kenyan opposition leader Raila Odinga as crowds swelled, the Standard newspaper said on its X account.
Two people were killed and more than 160 others were injured at the state funeral of Kenyan opposition leader Raila Odinga</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 08:52:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EBL cardholders to enjoy exclusive privileges at Truefitt and Hill</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ebl-cardholders-to-enjoy-exclusive-privileges-at-truefitt-and-hill</link><description>Truefitt &amp; Hill Bangladesh, the globally acclaimed grooming salon for men, is now offering exclusive privileges to EBL cardholders.
An agreement in this regard was signed recently at EBL’s head office in Dhaka by M. Khorshed Anowar, Deputy Managing Director and Head of Retail and SME Banking</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 09:22:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rybakina dispatches Paolini to reach Ningbo final and boost WTA Finals bid</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/more-sports/rybakina-dispatches-paolini-to-reach-ningbo-final-and-boost-wta-finals-bid</link><description>Kazakh third seed Elena Rybakina powered past Italy's Jasmine Paolini with a clinical 6-3 6-2 victory on Saturday to secure her place in the Ningbo Open final, keeping her hopes of qualifying for next month's WTA Finals on track.
The 2022 Wimbledon champion broke second-seeded Paolini for a 5-3 le</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 09:37:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Afghanistan pull out of T20 tri-series in Pakistan amid conflict</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/afghanistan-pull-out-of-t20-tri-series-in-pakistan-amid-conflict</link><description>Afghanistan have withdrawn from their Twenty20 international tri-series in Pakistan next month following the death of three local cricketers that the Afghanistan Cricket Board said were due to military strikes in Paktika province.
Afghanistan, Pakistan and Sri Lanka were due to meet in the tournam</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 10:07:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fakhrul urges shift from streets to parliament to strengthen democracy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/fakhrul-urges-shift-from-streets-to-parliament-to-strengthen-democracy</link><description>BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir on Friday urged political parties to shift their activities and focus from the streets to parliament, emphasising the need for strengthening parliamentary democracy in Bangladesh.
Speaking at a general meeting and conference of the Bangladesh Water</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 10:22:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘July Warriors’ clash: 900 accused in four cases</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/july-warriors-clash-900-accused-in-four-cases</link><description>Police have filed four cases in connection with the clashes that erupted as law-enforcing agencies moved to disperse “July Warriors” and their families, who gathered at the venue of the July Charter signing ceremony.
As many as 900 unidentified people were accused in the cases over van</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 10:37:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shahjalal Airport fire: Flight to Dhaka lands at Sylhet airport</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/shahjalal-airport-fire-flight-to-dhaka-lands-at-sylhet-airport</link><description>Authorities have suspended all flights at Dhaka’s Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport after a fire broke out in the cargo area.
In the aftermath, a flight from Saudi Arabia’s Riyadh, was unable to land in Dhaka and was diverted to Sylhet’s Osmani International Airport.
Bangla</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 10:52:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh, Italy agree to joint operations, intelligence sharing</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-italy-agree-to-joint-operations-intelligence-sharing-to-combat-human-trafficking</link><description>Bangladesh has reached an agreement with Italy to exchange intelligence and carry out joint operations between law-enforcing agencies.
According to a media statement from the home ministry on Saturday, the understanding was reached during a ministerial-level meeting between the two countries&amp;rsquo</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 11:22:57 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>