<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 18:30:38 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>BNP leaves 63 seats open for allies</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-leaves-63-seats-open-for-allies</link><description>The Bangladesh Nationalist Party has withheld 63 parliamentary seats to accommodate allies, signalling a broader seat-sharing drive ahead of the general election due in February.
Unveiling an initial slate of 237 candidates who will run under the party’s “sheaf of paddy” symbol,</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 15:11:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Assailants attack tanker off Somalia in suspected pirate strike</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/assailants-attack-tanker-off-somalia-in-suspected-pirate-strike</link><description>Armed assailants attacked a commercial tanker off the coast of Mogadishu on Monday, firing at the vessel after attempting to board the ship in the first suspected Somali piracy incident of its kind since 2024, maritime sources said.
If confirmed, this would be the first Somali piracy attack agains</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 15:26:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique Rahman to contest from Bogura-6</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-rahman-to-contest-from-bogura-6</link><description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman will contest from Bogura-6 constituency in the upcoming 13th national parliamentary election.
BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir made the announcement at a press conference at the BNP Chairperson's office in Gulshan on Monday.
Fakhrul said that BN</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 15:56:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>November rain smashes onion fields</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/november-rain-smashes-onion-fields</link><description>Onion prices shot up to Tk 100-120 a kg, marking above 30 per cent hike in last two days.
November Rain in places amid the ongoing depression in the Bay had smashed newer crops in Pabna, Rajshahi and Faridpur regions.
Onion farmers in the region are now sourcing edible onion to grow seed onion (m</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 16:11:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>World's first flying car factory starts trial production in China</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/worlds-first-flying-car-factory-starts-trial-production-in-china</link><description>XPENG AEROHT, the flying car affiliate of Chinese electric vehicle maker XPENG, on Monday began trial production at the world's first intelligent factory for mass-produced flying cars -- a milestone in the commercialization of next-generation transport.
Located in the Huangpu district of Guangzhou</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 16:55:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DU female teacher files case over dissemination of distorted photo</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/du-female-teacher-files-case-over-dissemination-of-distorted-photo</link><description>A female teacher of premier Dhaka University on Monday filed a case under the country’s tough Cyber Security Act over dissemination of her “distorted photographs” along with vulgar comments on social media platforms.
Police said assistant Professor of the university’s publi</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 17:10:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fraud posing as customs officer arrested at HSIA</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fraud-posing-as-customs-officer-arrested-at-hsia</link><description>Members of the Airport Armed Police Battalion (APBn-13) have arrested a member of an organized fraud gang posing as customs officials at Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport (HSIA).
The arrestee was identified as Md. Sabur Khan, 25, reports UNB.
According to police sources, Sabur and his accomp</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 17:25:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Marvel schedules 2026 worldwide releases for Spider-Man and Avengers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/entertainment/marvel-schedules-2026-worldwide-releases-for-spider-man-and-avengers</link><description>Marvel Studios has announced two major global release dates for 2026 that fans around the world are eagerly anticipating: July 31 and December 18.
'Spider-Man: Brand New Day' will swing into cinemas on July 31, 2026, with Tom Holland reprising his role as Peter Parker.
The production is already u</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 17:40:22 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>