<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 14:20:36 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Merchandise exports record 14.25pc decline in December</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/merchandise-exports-record-1425pc-decline-in-december</link><description>Bangladesh's single-month merchandise export earnings in December 2025 declined for the fifth consecutive month on a year-on-year basis, registering a 14.25 per cent fall compared to the same month in 2024.
Bangladesh fetched $3.96 billion last month, which was $4.62billion in December 2024, acc</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 11:21:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>People from all walks of life pay tributes at Khaleda Zia’s grave</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/people-from-all-walks-of-life-pay-tributes-at-khaleda-zias-grave</link><description>People from all walks of life and various organisations, including Dhaka University teachers of the White Panel, Bangladesh Open University (BOU) and the Ex-Forces Association, paid tributes to former Prime Minister and BNP Chairperson Khaleda Zia by visiting her grave on Sunday.
As in previous da</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 11:36:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Salehuddin wants swift FRC automation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/advisor-salehuddin-directs-swift-approval-execution-of-frc-automation-programme</link><description>Finance Advisor Salehuddin Ahmed has asked the Financial Reporting Council (FRC) to take immediate steps to approve and implement its automation programme, aiming to strengthen financial discipline in Bangladesh.
The directive came on Sunday during a seminar at the Ministry of Finance on the role</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 11:51:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AIUB participates in 5th Transnational Project Meeting of the Erasmus+ SOHO Project held in Lyon, France</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/aiub-participates-in-5th-transnational-project-meeting-of-the-erasmus-soho-project-held-in-lyon-france</link><description>The 5th Transnational Project Meeting of the Erasmus+ SOHO Project was successfully hosted by Université Lumière Lyon 2, France, on 27–28 November 2025.
The SOHO initiative—Smart, Optimized, High-quality, and On-demand Tourism Innovative Education for Sustainable and Gree</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 12:06:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ACC to sue BB official, 25 others over Tk 9 billion embezzlement</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/acc-to-sue-bb-deputy-governor-25-others-over-tk-9-billion-embezzlement-from-national-bank</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) has decided to file a case against 26 individuals, including Dr Md Kabir Ahmed, a deputy governor and former observer of National Bank Limited, over allegations of embezzling Tk 9.03 billion through forged documents and fraudulent loan transactions.
ACC Directo</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 12:21:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>At least 25 dead, 14 missing in Nigeria boat accident, officials say</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/at-least-25-dead-14-missing-in-nigeria-boat-accident-officials-say</link><description>At least 25 people have died and 14 others remain missing after a boat carrying dozens of passengers capsized in Yobe State, northeastern Nigeria, officials said on Sunday.
The accident occurred just before 8 p.m. local time (1900 GMT) on Saturday when the large canoe, which had departed Adiyani v</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 12:36:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique Rahman voices concern over rising mob violence: Saiful Haque</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-rahman-voices-concern-over-rising-mob-violence-saiful-haque</link><description>Biplobi Workers Party General Secretary Saiful Haque on Sunday said BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman on Sunday expressed concern over mob violence and the growing insecurity of people’s lives and property.
“He is worried about mob violence and the insecurity of people’s lives a</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 12:51:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt set to approve Tk 30,000 crore cut in revised ADP</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/govt-set-to-approve-tk-30000-crore-cut-in-revised-adp</link><description>The government is set to approve a sharply downsized Revised Annual Development Programme (RADP) for the current fiscal year, with the National Economic Council (NEC) scheduled to give final approval at its meeting on Monday.
Officials at the Planning Commission said the revised ADP is expected to</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 13:06:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Savings certificate returns cut put on hold</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/government-suspends-plan-to-reduce-interest-on-savings-certificates</link><description>The government has withdrawn its decision to cut interest rates on some national savings certificates.
As a result, investors will receive the same returns as before for the first six months of this year, January through June, the Internal Resources Division Secretary Abdur Rahman Khan said on Sun</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 13:21:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jatiya Party’s Chunnu falls out of Kishoreganj-3 race after nomination scrutiny</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jatiya-partys-chunnu-falls-out-of-kishoreganj-3-race-after-nomination-scrutiny</link><description>Jatiya Party Secretary General Mujibul Haque Chunnu and 13 others have been declared ineligible to run for parliament in three constituencies of Kishoreganj.
The scrutiny of nominations filed for Kishoreganj-1, 2, and 3 was held from 10am to 1pm at the deputy commissioner’s office on Sunday,</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 13:36:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Egypt, Qatar sign MOU to boost LNG sales and import cooperation, Egypt says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/egypt-qatar-sign-mou-to-boost-lng-sales-and-import-cooperation-egypt-says</link><description>Egypt and Qatar signed a memorandum of understanding to boost cooperation in LNG sales and imports, including terms for supplying Qatari shipments to Egypt's Ain Sokhna and Damietta ports, Egypt's petroleum ministry said on Sunday.
QatarEnergy said in a statement that the agreement includes supply</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 13:51:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nomination of Jamaat candidate, 16 others cancelled in Ctg</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nomination-of-jamaat-candidate-16-others-cancelled-in-ctg</link><description>The nomination papers of Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami candidate Dr. AKM Fazlul Haque in the Chattogram-9 constituency have been cancelled due to unclear information about dual citizenship and failure to submit required documents.
Additionally, a total of 16 candidates had their nominations cancelled</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 14:06:21 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>