<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 13:20:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>BNP alleges planned disinformation, vote rigging</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bnp-accuses-rival-party-of-disinformation-drive-preparations-for-fake-voting</link><description>The Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) has alleged that a certain political party is systematically spreading propaganda and preparing to cast fake votes to manipulate the parliamentary polls.
Mahdi Amin, spokesperson for the party’s central election steering committee, raised these concerns</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 10:31:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Banks, stock markets to remain closed for 4 days</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/banks-stock-markets-to-remain-closed-for-4-days</link><description>All banks and stock markets in Bangladesh will remain closed for four consecutive days starting Wednesday (February 11) due to the national election and the referendum.
To facilitate voter participation and ensure smooth security arrangements, the government has declared a two-day public holiday o</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 10:46:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt to provide financial aid, house to family of Dipu Das</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-to-provide-financial-aid-house-to-family-of-dipu-das</link><description>The government is going to provide financial assistance and construct a house for the family of Dipu Chandra Das, who was killed in a “mob” attack following allegations of blasphemy in Mymensingh’s Bhaluka Upazila.
The Chief Advisor’s Office (CAO) announced the decision on</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 11:01:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ex-Biman chief, wife to be grilled over ‘child abuse’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ex-biman-chief-shafiqur-wife-to-be-interrogated-over-child-abuse</link><description>Police have secured five days to question former Biman Bangladesh Airlines managing director and CEO Shafiqur Rahman and his domestic worker Rupali Khatun in a case filed over the alleged abuse of a child domestic worker.
Shafiqur’s wife, known only as Bithi, will be grilled for seven days,</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 11:16:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>86.4pc voters surveyed feel safe going to polling stations: survey</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/864pc-voters-surveyed-feel-safe-going-to-polling-stations-survey</link><description>Amid some anxieties, a combined 86.4 per cent of voters surveyed said they feel safe going to polling stations.
Of the 86.4 per cent, 64.0 per cent responded “yes” and 22.4 per cent said “somewhat”.
Similarly, a combined 82.5 per cent said they expect religious or ethnic m</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 11:31:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BGMEA welcomes Bangladesh–US reciprocal tariff agreement</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bgmea-welcomes-bangladesh-us-reciprocal-tariff-agreement</link><description>The Bangladesh Garment Manufacturers and Exporters Association (BGMEA) today (Tuesday) welcomed the signing of a reciprocal tariff agreement between Bangladesh and the United States, describing it as a positive development for the country’s export-oriented apparel sector.
The agreement was s</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 11:46:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>International poll observers meet CA</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/international-poll-observers-meet-ca</link><description>International election observation missions from the United States, Turkey, and the Commonwealth held separate courtesy meetings with Chief Adviser, Professor Muhammad Yunus, as preparations continue for the country’s upcoming national polls.
On Tuesday, a five-member delegation from the Int</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 12:01:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Zeroing energy bills biggest success for interim govt: Fouzul Kabir</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/zeroing-energy-bills-biggest-success-for-interim-govt-fouzul-kabir</link><description>Clearing massive outstanding dues owed to foreign energy suppliers has been the biggest achievement of the interim government in the energy sector, Power, Energy and Mineral Resources Adviser Muhammad Fouzul Kabir Khan said on Tuesday, marking his last working day in office.
Speaking at a press co</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 12:16:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pabna bus crash death toll rises to 4</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/pabna-bus-crash-death-toll-rises-to-4</link><description>The death toll from a head-on collision between two passenger buses in Pabna’s Santhia Upazila has risen to four, including a driver and an assistant.
At least 25 passengers from the two buses were injured in the crash, several of them in critical condition, police said.
The accident occurr</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 12:31:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Armed forces allowed inside polling stations: Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/armed-forces-allowed-inside-polling-stations-adviser</link><description>Home Affairs Adviser Lt Gen Md Jahangir Alam Chowdhury on Tuesday said any kind of chaos at polling stations will be dealt with strictly, as armed forces members are being allowed inside polling stations for the first time.
“Any disruption at polling centers will be dealt with strictly. Ther</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 12:46:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique reviews ground situation after campaign</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-chief-tarique-assesses-constituency-level-situation-from-party-office-after-campaign</link><description>After spending several days travelling across the country for election campaigning, BNP Chairperson Tarique Rahman is now working from his office in Gulshan.
From there, he has been speaking with party leaders, activists, and candidates across the country, seeking updates from candidates on the si</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 13:01:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mild earthquake jolts Sylhet; epicentre in Gowainghat upazila</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/mild-earthquake-jolts-sylhet-epicentre-in-gowainghat-upazila</link><description>A mild tremor shook Sylhet and its adjacent areas on Tuesday.
According to the Bangladesh Meteorological Department (BMD), the tremor was recorded at 5:32 pm with a magnitude of 4.0 on the Richter scale.
The epicentre of the earthquake was Gowainghat upazila of Sylhet division, 214 km North-East</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 13:16:54 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>