<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 12:49:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>14 killed, 16 injured in road accident in Pakistan’s Punjab</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/14-killed-16-injured-in-road-accident-in-pakistans-punjab</link><description>At least 14 passengers were killed and 16 others injured in a head-on collision between a bus and a van in Pakistan’s eastern Punjab province on Wednesday, officials said.
The bus was carrying players of the University of Veterinary and Animal Sciences to Lahore to participate in a sports ev</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 09:34:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Swiss police believe around 40 died at Swiss bar explosion, Italy says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/swiss-police-believe-around-40-died-at-swiss-bar-explosion-italy-says</link><description>Swiss police believe around 40 people died and 100 were injured in a fire during a New Year's Eve party in the resort town of Crans-Montana, the Italian Foreign Ministry said in a statement on Thursday.
It added that the blaze was not thought to have been caused by arson. The victims could not be</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 09:49:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No legal scope to defer election over Khaleda Zia’s death: Salahuddin</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/no-legal-scope-to-defer-election-over-khaleda-zias-death-salahuddin</link><description>BNP Standing Committee member Salahuddin Ahmed on Thursday said there is no legal scope to suspend or defer the election following the death of BNP Chairperson and former Prime Minister Begum Khaleda Zia.
"There is no legal scope to defer the election. Since our party has nominated alternative can</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 10:04:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Metro probe flags bearing pad flaws, urges third-party check</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/metro-rail-probe-body-flags-bearing-pad-flaws-urges-third-party-check</link><description>The inquiry committee formed after the accidental death caused by the fall of a bearing pad found faults in the design and quality of two bearing pads, but recommended cross-checking the entire metro rail system by an independent foreign party.
However, the committee ensured the safety of metro ra</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 10:19:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Lawyer ‘beaten to death’ in Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/lawyer-allegedly-beaten-to-death-in-dhakas-bashundhara</link><description>Police have received reports that a lawyer has allegedly been beaten to death in Bashundhara Residential Area of Dhaka.
The incident occurred around 10pm on Wednesday, as citizens began celebrating the coming of New Year, following a collision between a motorcycle and a private car.
According to</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 10:34:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bonded warehouses go fully online for UP approval</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/manual-up-ends-as-nbr-enforces-mandatory-online-clearance-for-bonded-warehouses</link><description>From the first day of the year, exporters operating bonded warehouses must obtain Utilisation Permission (UP) exclusively through an online system to import raw materials under duty-free facilities, marking a decisive shift in the bonded management regime.
In a media statement issued on Thursday,</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 10:49:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Around 40 killed, 100 injured in explosion in Swiss ski resort bar, police say</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/around-40-killed-100-injured-in-explosion-in-swiss-ski-resort-bar-police-say</link><description>Around 40 people have been killed and 100 injured, most of them seriously, after an explosion tore through a crowded bar during a New Year's Eve party in the upscale ski resort of Crans-Montana, Swiss officials said on Thursday.
A fire broke out at 1.30 am (0030 GMT) in a bar called "Le Constellat</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 11:04:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>3 ex-AL leaders to contest in polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/three-former-awami-league-leaders-enter-election-race-as-jp-jatiya-party-independent-candidates</link><description>Ahead of the parliamentary polls, three former Awami League leaders have filed nominations to contest under different banners, signalling a shift in loyalties and ambitions.
They are participating as Jatiya Party, JP, and independent candidates.
Two of the trio had previously sought Awami League</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 11:19:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>South Asian nations’ gesture highlights Khaleda’s respect, stature: Foreign Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/south-asian-nations-gesture-highlights-khaledas-respect-stature-foreign-adviser</link><description>Foreign Affairs Adviser Md Touhid Hossain on Thursday said it was a ‘positive gesture’ from the South Asian countries towards former Prime Minister Khaleda Zia who earned a kind of accessibility, respect and dignity among people at home and in South Asia.
“I think it’s a ve</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 11:34:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hasan Tarek Chowdhury joins DSE as GM</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/hasan-tarek-chowdhury-joins-dse-as-gm</link><description>Hasan Tarek Chowdhury on Thursday joined the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE), the country’s premier stock market, as the General Manager of HR and Admin.
Before taking on this leadership role at the DSE, he served as the Head of People and Culture Business Partnering at Japan Tobacco Internationa</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 11:49:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NEIR launched, mobile traders attack BTRC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/mobile-traders-clash-with-regulators-at-btrc-in-protest-against-neir-launch</link><description>The launch of the National Equipment Identification Register (NEIR) has been met with attack and vandalism at the BTRC office in Agargaon.
The service was kicked off as part of mandatory mobile handset registration on Thursday.
In protest, mobile traders resorted to violence in the afternoon as p</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 12:04:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mursalin quits NCP over ‘ideological rift’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/mursalin-quits-ncp-over-ideological-rift</link><description>Khan Muhammad Mursalin, joint chief coordinator of the National Citizen Party (NCP), resigned from the party on Thursday, citing ideological differences and disillusionment over its political direction.  Mursalin announced the decision in a Facebook post in the afternoon, saying he had st</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 12:19:20 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>