<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 15:26:36 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>IPDC’s Rizwan Dawood Shams named CEO of the year 2025</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ipdcs-rizwan-dawood-shams-named-ceo-of-the-year-2025</link><description>IPDC Finance PLC's Managing Director, Rizwan Dawood Shams, has been honored with the prestigious ‘Chief Executive Officer (CEO)/Managing Director (MD) of the Year 2025’ (For Business Revenue Per Annum 100 Crore - 499 Crore Category) award at the Bangladesh C-Suite Awards, presented by t</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 12:40:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BB opens door for B2B2C export model</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bb-opens-door-for-b2b2c-export-model</link><description>Bangladesh Bank (BB) has allowed shipments under a Business-to-Business-to-Consumer (B2B2C) framework to expand the country’s export channels.
To this end, the central bank on Monday issued a circular, enabling exporters to sell goods to global consumers through internationally recognised on</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 12:55:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fire at DU’s Bijoy 71 hall brought under control</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fire-at-dus-bijoy-71-hall-brought-under-control</link><description>The fire flamed at the Bijoy 71 hall of the Dhaka University is now fully under control, according to BSS.
A fire erupted at the hall's extension canteen around 6 pm on Monday, triggering explosions of four gas cylinders and rapidly escalating the blaze.
The blaze lasted for nearly 15 minutes bef</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 13:10:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>43rd meeting of Task Committee of IBCF held</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/43rd-meeting-of-task-committee-of-ibcf-held</link><description>The 43rd Meeting of the Task Committee of Islamic Banks Consultative Forum (IBCF) was held on Thursday, November 20, 2025, in the Board Room of Shahjalal Islami Bank PLC, according to a press release.
The meeting was presided over by Mosleh Uddin Ahmed, Managing Director of Shahjalal Islami Bank P</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 13:25:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>People don’t want corruption: ACC Chairman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/people-dont-want-corruption-acc-chairman</link><description>Chairman of the Anti Corruption Commission (ACC) Dr. Mohammad Abdul Momen on Monday said that 100 percent people of the country don’t want corruption.
“The main task of the ACC is to create conscious against corruption by holding such public hearings,” he said this while addressi</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 13:40:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCC Bank, Mastercard unveil premium card portfolio to elevate digital payments in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ncc-bank-mastercard-unveil-premium-card-portfolio-to-elevate-digital-payments-in-bangladesh</link><description>NCC Bank and Mastercard have announced a strategic collaboration with the launch of an exclusive portfolio of premium cards designed to deliver enhanced convenience, financial flexibility, and world-class privileges to customers.
According to a press release, this marks the first-ever association</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 13:55:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>MTB Foundation holds program to prevent avoidable blindness in ethnic community in Kulaura</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/mtb-foundation-holds-program-to-prevent-avoidable-blindness-in-ethnic-community-in-kulaura</link><description>As part of its commitment towards the healthcare sector of the country, MTB Foundation, in partnership with Ispahani Islamia Eye Institute and Hospital (IIEI&amp;amp;H) recently organized a ‘Community Eye Health Partnership for preventing avoidable Blindness of the Ethnic Community’ in Kulaura,</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 14:10:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Meghna Bank holds AML, CFT training for Khulna region</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/meghna-bank-holds-aml-cft-training-for-khulna-region</link><description>Meghna Bank PLC arranged a day-long training program on Anti-Money Laundering (AML) andCombating the Financing of Terrorism (CFT) for the branch officials of Khulna Zone recently.
The day-long sessions were conducted by Mr. Mohammad Mokter Hossain, Additional Director, of BFIU &amp; Mr. ShahalmKazi, J</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 14:25:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khaleda urges all to pray for her amid health concerns</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/khaleda-urges-all-to-pray-for-her-amid-health-concerns</link><description>BNP Chairperson and former Prime Minister Khaleda Zia, undergoing treatment under intensive medical supervision at Evercare Hospital in the capital, on Monday urged the people of the country to pray for her speedy recovery.
“Since her admission to Evercare Hospital on Sunday night, the BNP C</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 14:40:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US terminates temporarily legal status for Myanmar citizens</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-terminates-temporarily-legal-status-for-myanmar-citizens</link><description>The Trump administration is ending temporary legal status for citizens of Myanmar who are in the United States, the US Department of Homeland Security said in a notice on Monday.
The Temporary Protected Status (TPS) designation for Myanmar was set to expire on Tuesday.
“After reviewing coun</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 14:55:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bachelor of Madrasa Education programme launched at Islamic University</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/bachelor-of-madrasa-education-programme-launched-at-islamic-university</link><description>The authorities of Islamic University in Kushtia officially launched the Bachelor of Madrasa Education programme under its Institute of Islamic Education and Research, marking a significant step toward professionalising madrasa teaching in the country.
An admission test circular, signed by IIER di</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 15:10:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BDR mutiny case: 35 freed on bail from Kashimpur Jail</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bdr-mutiny-case-35-freed-on-bail-from-kashimpur-jail</link><description>A total of 35 former Bangladesh Rifles (BDR) personnel were released on bail from Kashimpur Jail in Gazipur on Monday evening in connection with the BDR mutiny case.
Relatives of the accused received them at the main gate of the prison.
Earlier, on Thursday, 53 others had been granted bail by a s</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 15:25:39 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>