<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 13:46:51 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>BNP candidate Ishraque Hossain seeks removal of Sutrapur OC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-candidate-ishraque-hossain-seeks-removal-of-sutrapur-oc</link><description>BNP candidate Ishraque Hossain has called on the Election Commission to remove the chief (OC) of Sutrapur Police Station, alleging biased conduct.
Ishraque, who is contesting in the Dhaka-6 seat in the Feb 12 election, also requested that the polling centre at Cosmopolitan School and College in Su</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 10:04:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat candidates won't take plots, duty-free if elected: Shafiqur Rahman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-candidates-wont-take-plots-duty-free-if-elected-shafiqur-rahman</link><description>Jamaat-e-Islami chief Shafiqur Rahman has said that members of his party will refuse government-allocated plots and duty-free vehicles if elected to parliament.
Speaking at an election rally in Habiganj on Saturday, Shafiqur said Jamaat candidates would also publicly disclose annual income and exp</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 10:19:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nearly 35pc of election candidates have no income tax records: SHUJAN</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nearly-35pc-of-election-candidates-have-no-income-tax-records-shujan</link><description>Nearly 35 per cent of the 2,026 candidates contesting the 13th parliamentary election, or 707 individuals, have no publicly available income tax records, according to data from civil society organisation Shushashoner Jonno Nagorik (SHUJAN).
The findings were presented on Saturday at a press confer</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 10:34:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ShopUp expands global footprint through joint venture with Holy Makkah Municipality</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/shopup-expands-global-footprint-through-joint-venture-with-holy-makkah-municipality</link><description>ShopUp today (Saturday) announced an expansion of its global footprint through a strategic partnership between its Saudi-based brand, Sary, and Al-Balad Al-Amin Technologies—the investment arm of the Holy Makkah Municipality.
The partnership establishes a new joint venture dedicated to activ</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 11:36:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CPD flags credibility risks in referendum amid gaps in framework</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cpd-flags-credibility-risks-in-referendum-amid-gaps-in-framework</link><description>The Centre for Policy Dialogue (CPD) has cautioned that the credibility of the upcoming referendum may come under scrutiny due to weaknesses in the existing legal framework and related ordinances, urging policymakers to prioritise the integrity of the parliamentary election process.CPD Director Kha</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 11:51:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>WHO says one person dead from Nipah virus in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/who-says-one-person-dead-from-nipah-virus-in-bangladesh</link><description>The World Health Organization said on Friday that a woman had died in northern Bangladesh in January after contracting the deadly Nipah virus infection.
The case in Bangladesh, where Nipah cases are reported almost every year, follows two Nipah virus cases identified in neighbouring India, which h</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 12:06:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shops to shutter for two days around Bangladesh vote</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/shops-to-shutter-for-two-days-around-bangladesh-vote</link><description>Shops, shopping malls and commercial establishments across Bangladesh are set to be closed for two days, including polling day, as the country gears up for the parliamentary elections.
The Bangladesh Shop Owners’ Association said all stores, including those in Dhaka, will be closed on Feb 11</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 12:21:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>2 shot as campaigners clash in Munshiganj</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/2-shot-as-campaigners-clash-in-munshiganj</link><description>Violence has broken out between supporters of the BNP and an independent candidate over election campaigning in Sadar Upazila of Munshiganj-3 seat, leaving at least two people with gunshot wounds.
The clash took place on Saturday afternoon in Munshikandi village, Munshiganj's Additional Superinten</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 12:36:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Privacy-first social platform ZKTOR enters Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/privacy-first-social-platform-zktor-enters-bangladesh</link><description>As ZKTOR expands beta testing from India and Nepal into Bangladesh and Sri Lanka, its design-led model raises deeper questions about data sovereignty, youth opportunity, and the future of regional digital infrastructure.
Developed by Softa Technologies Limited, ZKTOR has already undergone mass pub</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 12:53:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Md Ahteshamul Haque Khan joins Dutch-Bangla Bank as Managing Director and CEO</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/md-ahteshamul-haque-khan-joins-dutch-bangla-bank-as-managing-director-and-ceo</link><description>Md. Ahteshamul Haque Khan joined Dutch-Bangla Bank as the Managing Director and CEO on 7 February 2026.
Before joining as the Managing Director &amp; CEO, Mr. Khan was the Deputy Managing Director and Chief Business Officer (CBO) of the same bank for around 6 years. He was also the Chief Operating Off</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 13:08:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump map shows entire Kashmir as part of India</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/trump-map-shows-entire-kashmir-as-part-of-india</link><description>The Donald Trump administration has released a map showing the entire region of Kashmir as part of India, marking a major shift from previous US maps that excluded Pakistan-administered Kashmir.
The graphic, shared by the Office of the United States Trade Representative (USTR) on X, while announci</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 13:23:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh, Maldives eye direct shipping, halal food cooperation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladesh-maldives-eye-direct-shipping-halal-food-cooperation</link><description>Bangladesh and the Maldives on Saturday reaffirmed their commitment to strengthening bilateral cooperation, with a focus on direct shipping connectivity and expanded collaboration in the halal food industry to boost trade, transport efficiency and sustainable supply chains.
The commitment was made</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 13:38:47 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>