<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 17:17:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>City Bank publishes its inaugural ESG report</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/city-bank-publishes-its-inaugural-esg-report</link><description>City Bank PLC has published its inaugural Environmental, Social and Governance (ESG) Report, “Bank on Solidity, Banking on Sustainability”, marking a key milestone in its sustainability journey. Building on previous Sustainability Reports, this comprehensive ESG Report aligns with globa</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 15:10:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BRAC Bank, VisionSpring join MBM Group in celebrating World Sight Day</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/brac-bank-visionspring-join-mbm-group-in-celebrating-world-sight-day</link><description>BRAC Bank, VisionSpring, and MBM Group jointly celebrated World Sight Day 2025 at Cutting Edge Industries Limited, a concern of MBM Group, according to a press release.
The event was organised by MBM Group to mark the occasion with BRAC Bank, which facilitated the eye screening of their factory wo</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 15:25:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>12 officers relocated to B’baria over traffic issues</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/adviser-fouzul-orders-12-dhaka-officers-to-serve-in-bbaria-to-tackle-traffic-issues</link><description>Road Transport Adviser Fouzul Kabir Khan has ordered 12 ministry officials, including senior engineers, to leave their Dhaka offices and work from a temporary base in Brahmanbaria to improve conditions on the Dhaka–Sylhet Highway.
After inspecting the damaged section of the highway on Wednes</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 15:40:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Afghan Taliban foreign minister heads for first visit to India to foster ties abroad</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/afghan-taliban-foreign-minister-heads-for-first-visit-to-india-to-foster-ties-abroad</link><description>Afghanistan’s Taliban foreign minister left for New Delhi on Wednesday, his ministry said, in what would be the first visit to India by a Taliban leader since the group seized power in 2021.
The trip highlights Taliban efforts to expand engagement with regional powers in a quest for economic</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 15:55:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IMF chief says global economy doing ‘better than feared,’ risks remain</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/imf-chief-says-global-economy-doing-better-than-feared-risks-remain</link><description>The world economy has proven more resilient than expected despite acute strains from multiple shocks, the head of the International Monetary Fund said on Wednesday, forecasting only a slight slowing of global growth this year and in 2026.
IMF Managing Director Kristalina Georgieva said the US econ</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 15:32:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Former Chhatra League leader Ajoy Kar claims he stayed home during July protests</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/former-chhatra-league-leader-ajoy-kar-claims-he-stayed-home-during-july-protests</link><description>Former Bangladesh Chhatra League leader Ajoy Kar Khokon has told a Dhaka court that he remained at home throughout the July protests.
He also said he did not hold any position in the Awami League and was “denied” a party nomination despite applying.
Police secured permission to hold A</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 16:02:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Raytheon to sell Pakistan medium-range air-to-air missiles for F-16 fleet</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/raytheon-to-sell-pakistan-medium-range-air-to-air-missiles-for-f-16-fleet</link><description>US arms manufacturer Raytheon is set to sell advanced medium-range air-to-air missiles to Pakistan.
The deal was confirmed on Tuesday after the company published an amended contract that added Pakistan to the list of buyers, according to Dawn.
These US missiles will be integrated into the Pakista</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 16:17:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Experts blame lack of awareness for rising ‘Diabetic Foot’ amputations</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/experts-blame-lack-of-awareness-for-rising-diabetic-foot-amputations</link><description>An alarming number of people in Bangladesh are losing their feet due to complications from ‘diabetic foot’ disease, caused largely by ignorance and negligence, experts have warned.
Speaking at a discussion marking International Podiatry Day 2025, they stressed that increased awareness</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 16:47:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP condemns Bagerhat journalist’s killing, warns of destabilisation attempt</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bnp-condemns-bagerhat-journalists-killing-warns-of-destabilisation-attempt</link><description>BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir on Wednesday night condemned the killing of Bagerhat journalist SM Hayat Uddin, saying that a group of miscreants are once again trying to create instability and anarchy in the country for their own benefit.
“After the fall of the Awami autoc</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 17:02:26 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>