<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 07:23:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>SYLHET CITY: 24 buildings marked vulnerable to earthquake yet to be demolished</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/sylhet-city-24-buildings-marked-vulnerable-to-earthquake-yet-to-be-demolished</link><description>SYLHET, Dec 04: A total of 24 buildings considered to be highly vulnerable in Sylhet city would soon be demolished, official sources said.
These structures have remained in a dilapidated condition for a long period of time, although these were earlier marked as vulnerable to earthquake.
Related i</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 04:38:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two ordinances get nod to protect forest, biodiversity, wildlife</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/two-ordinances-get-nod-to-protect-forest-biodiversity-wildlife</link><description>The interim government has passed two ordinances relating to the country's forest, biodiversity, and wildlife protection. These are "Forest and Tree Conservation Ordinance 2025" and "Wildlife (Conservation and Security) Ordinance 2025".
The approval was given at a meeting of the Council of Adviser</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 04:53:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Metro card online top-ups gain traction</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/metro-card-online-top-ups-gain-traction</link><description>Metro rail passengers are increasingly embracing the new online recharge facility, introduced to spare them the long queues at station counters.
In just one week, more than 11,000 cards were topped up through the digital platform, signalling strong public acceptance of the service.
The Dhaka Tran</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 05:08:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No concrete plan of DU renovations after tremor: JCS</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/no-concrete-plan-of-du-renovations-after-tremor-jcs</link><description>Jatiya Chhatra Shakti (JCS) leaders said DU administration failed to disclose the duration and plan of the renovations-citing which the authorities closed the institution following last month's tremor.
JCS Dhaka University (DU) unit President Tahmid Al Muddassir Chowdhury made the remarks during a</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 05:23:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US widens travel ban to more than 30 countries</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-widens-travel-ban-to-more-than-30-countries</link><description>The US plans to expand the number of countries covered by its travel ban to more than 30, US Homeland Security Secretary Kristi Noem said on Thursday.
Noem, in an interview on Fox News' "The Ingraham Angle," was asked to confirm whether the administration of President Donald Trump would be increas</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 05:38:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Zubaida Rahman arrives in Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/zubaida-rahman-arrives-in-dhaka</link><description>Zubaida Rahman, the wife of Tarique Rahman and daughter-in-law of BNP chief Khaleda Zia, has arrived in Dhaka.
She landed at Dhaka’s Shahjalal International Airport on board a Biman Bangladesh Airlines flight around 10:45 am on Friday, according to Atikur Rahman Rumon, a BNP spokesman.
&amp;ldq</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 05:53:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Midland Bank donates ambulance to Anjuman Mufidul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/midland-bank-donates-ambulance-to-anjuman-mufidul</link><description>Midland Bank PLC has donated an ambulance to Anjuman Mufidul Islam, a charitable organisation and one of the leading ambulance service providers in Dhaka, serving both patients and deceased persons within and outside the capital. The donation is part of the Bank’s commitment to social wellbei</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 05:45:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khaleda Zia’s flight uncertain before Sunday; her condition worsens slightly</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/khaleda-zias-flight-uncertain-before-sunday-her-condition-worsens-slightly</link><description>BNP Chairperson Begum Khaleda Zia is unlikely to travel to London before Sunday as her planned medical flight has been delayed because the special air ambulance provided by the Emir of Qatar has still not arrived in Dhaka.
BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir told UNB that the air amb</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 06:00:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Kaaba seen like a bright light from 400k km above earth; picture goes viral</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/kaaba-seen-like-a-bright-light-from-400k-km-above-earth-picture-goes-viral</link><description>A stunning  photograph taken from orbit has gone viral online, revealing Mecca’s Kaaba glowing like a luminous point from 400 kilometers above Earth.
The image, captured from the International Space Station (ISS), highlights Islam’s holiest site as a radiant center within the city</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 06:15:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CU student's hanging body recovered from Ctg flat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/cu-students-hanging-body-recovered-from-ctg-flat</link><description>A student of Chittagong University has been found dead at a flat in the port city in an apparent suicide.
Omar Faruk Sumon, a student in the university’s Arabic Department from the 2021–22 session, was discovered hanging from a ceiling fan hook at a residence on Road No. 5 in the Khuls</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 06:30:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Xi joins Macron in southwest China on rare trip with a global leader outside Beijing</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/xi-joins-macron-in-southwest-china-on-rare-trip-with-a-global-leader-outside-beijing</link><description>Chinese President Xi Jinping accompanied his French counterpart Emmanuel Macron to Chengdu on Friday, a rare gesture seemingly reserved for the head of Europe's second-largest economy that highlights Beijing's focus on Paris in its dealings with the European Union.
 
The French president b</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 06:45:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Night temperatures may drop by 1–2°C: Met office</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/night-temperatures-may-drop-by-1-2c-met-office</link><description>Bangladesh Meteorological Department (BMD) has forecast a slight fall in night temperatures across the country, with readings expected to drop by 1–2°C.
“Night temperatures may fall by 1–2°C, while day temperatures are likely to remain nearly unchanged across the country,</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 07:00:47 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>