<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 04:54:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>How much will Tarique earn as PM?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/how-much-will-tarique-earn-as-prime-minister-and-what-perks-come-with-the-office</link><description>If all goes as planned, BNP Chairperson Tarique Rahman is poised to assume office as Bangladesh’s next prime minister, completing a remarkable journey from years of exile to the very centre of state power.
As anticipation builds around his return to government, many are asking a simpler, mor</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 19:03:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Regulator's move for digital bank licensing flops amid protests</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/regulators-move-for-digital-bank-licensing-flops-amid-protests</link><description>A decisive regulatory move for licensing digital banks flops as an emergency board meeting of Bangladesh Bank backtracked following strong protest from officers against such last-minute decision during governmental transition.



Sources said a strong protest from the BB officers' platform upse</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 19:18:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Coppertech's pre-IPO accounts come under fresh regulatory scrutiny</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/coppertechs-pre-ipo-accounts-come-under-fresh-regulatory-scrutiny</link><description>The securities regulator has set out to verify the authenticity of Coppertech Industries' pre-IPO financial statements to uncover any irregularities linked to the controversy surrounding the company's 2019 listing.
A decision to investigate Coppertech Industries was made in November last year, but</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 01:41:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Green Delta earnings flat in 2025 as claim expenses surge</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/green-delta-earnings-flat-in-2025-as-claim-expenses-surge</link><description>Despite higher premium income, Green Delta Insurance's profit remained almost flat at Tk 545 million in 2025 compared to the year before, due to higher expenses on claim settlement and lower income from subsidiaries.
The general insurer's consolidated earnings per share (EPS) stood at Tk 5.44 in 2</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 01:56:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DSE, CSE cut trading hours during Ramadan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/dse-cse-cut-trading-hours-during-ramadan</link><description>The Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) and the Chittagong Stock Exchange (CSE) have reduced trading time by 40 minutes during the holy month of Ramadan.
Trading on the bourses will begin at 10:00am as usual and continue until 1:50pm, including a 10-minute post-closing session, in line with banking hours,</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 02:11:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>People suffer amid LPG shortage, price soars</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/people-suffer-amid-lpg-shortage-price-soars</link><description>Acute shortage of liquefied petroleum gas (LPG) cylinders and its high prices all of a sudden has left Chandpur residents reeling in hardships during food preparation as consumers seen running from one shops to another in vain and food shops, restaurants and hotels suffering losses.
Talking to the</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 02:26:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique leads BNP back to govt today</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-leads-bnp-back-to-govt-today</link><description>Bangladesh's political landscape is poised for a historic moment as Zia-family heir Tarique Rahman will be sworn in as prime minister to lead the country out of political upheaval-triggered upsets.
The head of Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP), who had led his party through difficult times from e</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 03:13:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>FY26 Jul-Jan ADP execution 5-year low</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/fy26-jul-jan-adp-execution-5-year-low</link><description>Bangladesh's Annual Development Programme (ADP) implementation is still on a weak trajectory as the implementing agencies have failed to revamp the usual execution of development projects, officials say.
They say the ADP execution rate during the first seven months of FY26 slowed to a five-year lo</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 03:28:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh Bank buys $5.0b in 7 months to stabilise forex rate</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladesh-bank-buys-50b-in-7-months-to-stabilise-forex-rate</link><description>Bangladesh Bank has purchased more than US$5.0 billion from commercial banks over the past seven months in a sustained effort to keep the dollar-taka exchange rate stable and support exporters and remitters.
The latest intervention came as inward remittance inflows strengthened sharply in early Fe</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 03:45:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Petrobangla struggles to recover Tk 2.1b stuck in seven troubled banks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/petrobangla-struggles-to-recover-tk-21b-stuck-in-seven-troubled-banks</link><description>State-owned energy corporation Bangladesh Oil, Gas and Mineral Corporation (Petrobangla) is facing mounting challenges in recovering Tk 2.10 billion placed as fixed deposits in seven troubled private and scheduled banks, raising concerns over funding for key gas-development projects.
Despite the m</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 04:00:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Maldives President to meet Tarique Rahman after oath-taking ceremony</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/maldives-president-to-meet-tarique-rahman-after-oath-taking-ceremony</link><description>President of the Republic of the Maldives Dr Mohamed Muizzu will meet newly elected Prime Minister Tarique Rahman after attending his swearing-in ceremony on Tuesday.
The President is paying an official visit to Bangladesh at the invitation of Chief Adviser Prof Muhammad Yunus to attend the oath-t</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 04:15:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP MPs begin arriving at parliament for swearing-in</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bnp-mps-begin-arriving-at-parliament-for-swearing-in</link><description>Newly elected BNP lawmakers have begun arriving at the parliament complex ahead of their swearing-in ceremony.
Vehicles carrying the MPs started entering the complex from 9:00 am on Sunday. The oath ceremony is scheduled for 10:00 am, where Chief Election Commissioner AMM Nasir Uddin will administ</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 04:30:06 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>