<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 15:24:04 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>ACC to prosecute 4 recruiting agencies</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/four-recruiting-agencies-face-corruption-charges-over-embezzlement-laundering</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission is going to take legal steps against five people from four recruiting agencies over allegations of embezzlement and money laundering through syndication while sending workers to Malaysia.
On Tuesday, ACC Director General Md Akhtar Hossain said the cases will bring ch</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 14:04:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shahjalal Islami Bank signs MoU with Best Western Plus Bay Hills Hotel</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/shahjalal-islami-bank-signs-mou-with-best-western-plus-bay-hills-hotel</link><description>A Memorandum of Understanding (MoU) was signed between Shahjalal Islami Bank PLC and Best Western Plus Bay Hills Hotel on Tuesday at the bank's Corporate Head Office, according to a press release.
Mr. Imtiaz U. Ahmed, Additional Managing Director of Shahjalal Islami Bank PLC and Mr. Shahadat Hossa</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 12:35:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Asif Nazrul expects clear update on Charter implementation within days</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/asif-nazrul-expects-clear-update-on-charter-implementation-within-days</link><description>Law Affairs Adviser Asif Nazrul on Tuesday said that a clear update on the implementation of the July Charter will be known within the next two to three days.
“Political parties will provide us with a unified directive after internal consultations, as we had expected. However, we have not re</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 12:50:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Recognition of ‘July Revolution’ key for 2026 election: Jamaat Ameer</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/recognition-of-july-revolution-key-for-2026-election-jamaat-ameer</link><description>Jamaat-e-Islami Ameer Dr Shafiqur Rahman on Tuesday said that recognising the ‘July Revolution’ is a prerequisite for participating in the 2026 national election.
“Those who do not recognise the July Revolution, there will be no elections in 2026 for them. To give recognition to</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 13:05:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCC Bank, Department of Youth Development sign MoU</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ncc-bank-department-of-youth-development-sign-mou</link><description>With the aim of empowering the young generation of the country and achieving sustainable economic growth, NCC Bank has recently signed a Memorandum of Understanding (MoU) with the Department of Youth Development, according to a press release.
Under this strategic collaboration, NCC Bank will provi</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 13:20:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Visual artist Shahad Sharif awarded Bangladesh Achievers Award 2025</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/others/visual-artist-shahad-sharif-awarded-bangladesh-achievers-award-2025</link><description>Entrepreneur and visual artist Shahad Sharif has been awarded the prestigious Bangladesh Achievers Award 2025 by the Bangladesh Achievers Awards committee.
Shahad Sharif, the founder and CEO of Graficity Communication, received the award at a ceremony at the Bangladesh-China Friendship Convention</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 13:35:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mutual Trust Bank holds BM and BAMLCO Conference</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/mutual-trust-bank-holds-bm-and-bamlco-conference</link><description>Mutual Trust Bank PLC (MTB) arranged Branch Manager (BM) and Branch Anti Money Laundering Compliance Officer (BAMLCO) Conference on November 08, 2025 to update and create awareness on key deliverables for Anti Money Laundering &amp; Combating Financing of Terrorism (AML&amp;amp;CFT) compliance.
According to a</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 13:50:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh Bank governor gets ‘C’ grade in Global Finance assessment</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh-bank-governor-gets-c-grade-in-global-finance-assessment</link><description>Bangladesh Bank (BB) Governor Ahsan H. Mansur has been awarded a ‘C’ grade in the 2025 assessment by the international financial magazine, Global Finance.
This grading signifies that the central bank’s performance under his leadership has been classified as ‘mixed’ by</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 14:05:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Another bus set on fire in Dhaka’s Sutrapur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/another-bus-set-on-fire-in-dhakas-sutrapur</link><description>Miscreants set another bus on fire in front of the Sutrapur fire station in Old Dhaka on Tuesday evening amid rising arson incidents.
A unit of the Fire Service rushed to the spot and doused the blaze within 10 minutes, said Rafi Al Faruk, duty officer of the Fire Service and Civil Defence control</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 14:20:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>FSIB administrators exchange views with clients of Mohakhali Branch</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/fsib-administrators-exchange-views-with-clients-of-mohakhali-branch</link><description>Muhommad Badiuzzaman Dider, Administrator and Executive Director of Bangladesh Bank exchanged views with the clients at Mohakhali Branch on Tuesday, according to a press release.
Muhammad Ansarul Kabir, Associate Administrator and Additional Director of Bangladesh Bank, Mr. Mohammed Masud Parvez,</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 14:35:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Community Bank Bangladesh holds 70th board meeting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/community-bank-bangladesh-holds-70th-board-meeting</link><description>The 70th Board Meeting of Community Bank Bangladesh PLC was held at the Police Headquarters on Monday, according to a press release.
The meeting was chaired by Mr. Baharul Alam BPM, Inspector General of Police, Bangladesh and Chairman of Community Bank Bangladesh PLC. During the meeting important</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 14:50:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Raiding retailers won’t help, real culprits must be caught: Adviser Bashir</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/raiding-retailers-wont-help-real-culprits-must-be-caught-adviser-bashir</link><description>Commerce Adviser Sk Bashir Uddin on Tuesday said that raids on retail and mid-level outlets have limited impact, as the main perpetrators behind market irregularities often escape accountability.
 “Our goal is to protect consumers’ interests, not to restrict trade,” he said</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 15:05:16 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>