<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 04:32:44 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Krishna Nandi named Jamaat candidate in Khulna-1</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/krishna-nandi-named-jamaat-candidate-in-khulna-1</link><description>The Jamaat-e-Islami has declared Krishna Nandi as its candidate for the Khulna-1 seat for the parliamentary election.
To make this change, the party replaced its earlier nominee in the constituency formed by the minority-dominated Upazilas of Dakope and Batiaghata.
Nandi currently serves as presi</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 18:14:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>High Court orders halt to hill-cutting at Rangamati university site</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/high-court-orders-halt-to-hill-cutting-at-rangamati-university-site</link><description>The High Court has ordered an immediate stop to the hill-cutting carried out for the construction of the Rangamati Science and Technology University building.
The bench of Justice Sikdar Mahmudur Razi and Justice Raziuddin Ahmed issued the directive on Wednesday following a writ petition filed by</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 18:29:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A slew of 7,379 BD products getting free market access</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/a-slew-of-7379-bd-products-getting-free-market-access</link><description>Bangladesh's maiden bilateral free-trade agreement is being signed this month with Japan that will accord 7,379 Bangladeshi products duty-free quota-free (DFQF) market access to world's third-largest economy immediate after the deal-making, officials say.



The deal, coming under the umbrella</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 18:44:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka shaken by early-morning quake</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dhaka-shaken-by-early-morning-quake</link><description>A mild earthquake was felt once again in the capital Dhaka and nearby areas on Thursday (December 4). The 4.1-magnitude tremor was recorded at 6:14 am.
According to the Bangladesh Meteorological Department, the quake’s epicentre was in Shibpur upazila of Narsingdi.
The European-Mediterranea</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 01:36:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Falling Indian Rupee may prove mixed blessing for Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/falling-indian-rupee-may-prove-mixed-blessing-for-bangladesh</link><description>A deep depreciation of the Indian rupee or INR may offer short-term relief for Bangladeshi importers but could pose disadvantage to exporters, particularly apparel sector where India is emerging as a strong competitor.
Economists see the INR slide as a "double-edged sword" for Bangladesh, acting b</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 01:51:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh gets deep into hard-term debts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh-gets-deep-into-hard-term-debts</link><description>Bangladesh is increasingly getting into hard-term-debt burden by taking volumes of non-concessional loans particularly for bankrolling some mega-and major projects, officials say and warn of forex risks.
In the first quarter of the current fiscal year (FY) 2025-26, the country had already crossed</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 02:06:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>FoC limit removal to hit local value addition</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/foc-limit-removal-to-hit-local-value-addition</link><description>Leading textile mill owners and garment accessories manufacturers have strongly opposed the government's reported plan to remove the existing Free of Cost (FoC) import ceiling as part of amending the Import Policy Order 2021-2024, warning that such a move will severely undermine local value additio</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 02:21:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt set to slash mobile phone import duty to curb illegal market</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/govt-set-to-slash-mobile-phone-import-duty-to-curb-illegal-market</link><description>The government has initiated a major move to cut import duty on mobile handsets, aiming to lower consumer prices and curb the influx of illegal, cloned and refurbished devices.
The decision came from a high-level coordination meeting held on Monday at the office of Faiz Ahmad Taiyeb, Special Assis</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 02:36:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New MPPA framework set to transform renewables</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/new-mppa-framework-set-to-transform-renewables</link><description>Experts and sector insiders at a discussion on Wednesday said the imminent Merchant Power Purchase Agreement (MPPA) framework would transform how industries in Bangladesh procure renewable energy.
The possible transition of the renewable energy sector would also help Bangladesh prepare for its LDC</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 02:51:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chittagong Port Authority calls for appointing admin to curb infighting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/chittagong-port-authority-calls-for-appointing-admin-to-curb-infighting</link><description>CHATTOGRAM: The Chittagong Port Authority (CPA) has requested the Ministry of Shipping to appoint an administrator to run the Bangladesh Ship Handling and Berth Operators Association, citing escalating infighting that is disrupting cargo handling at the outer anchorage.
The request has triggered a</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 03:06:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rajshahi University suspends three teachers, penalises five students</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/rajshahi-university-suspends-three-teachers-penalises-five-students</link><description>The Rajshahi University Syndicate has taken disciplinary action against three teachers and five students based on different allegations.
Of these, three teachers have been dismissed, five students have been penalised, including expulsion, according to a statement from the university's public relat</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 03:21:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump administration orders enhanced vetting for H-1B visa applicants</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-administration-orders-enhanced-vetting-for-h-1b-visa-applicants</link><description>The Trump administration on Wednesday announced increased vetting of applicants for H-1B visas for highly skilled workers, with an internal State Department memo saying that anyone involved in "censorship" of free speech be considered for rejection.
H-1B visas, which allow US employers to hire for</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 04:30:43 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>