<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 15:26:38 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>New York mayor-elect Mamdani faces test of turning bold pledges into action</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/new-york-mayor-elect-mamdani-faces-test-of-turning-bold-pledges-into-action</link><description>Zohran Mamdani, a 34-year-old democratic socialist set to take office as mayor of New York City on Jan 1, is facing intense scrutiny as questions mount over whether he can deliver on the sweeping promises that helped propel him into one of the most closely watched political jobs in the United State</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 12:14:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Beximco Pharma trading to be suspended on London Stock Exchange</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/beximco-pharma-trading-to-be-suspended-on-london-stock-exchange</link><description>Trading of Global Depositary Receipts (GDRs) for Beximco Pharmaceuticals Limited, one of Bangladesh’s largest drug manufacturers, is set to be suspended on the London Stock Exchange (LSE) starting from January 2, 2026.
The suspension comes after the company failed to publish its audited fina</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 12:29:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Maintain law and order at any cost: Bangladesh’s police chief</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/maintain-law-and-order-at-any-cost-bangladeshs-police-chief</link><description>Inspector General of Police (IGP) Baharul Alam on Monday instructed field-level police officers to maintain law and order at any cost, giving the highest priority to the upcoming national parliamentary election.
Addressing the monthly crime review meeting at the Police Headquarters, the IGP emphas</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 12:44:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prime Bank collaborates with Flowco Bangladesh to launch green financing for petrol pumps</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/prime-bank-collaborates-with-flowco-bangladesh-to-launch-green-financing-for-petrol-pumps</link><description>Prime Bank PLC and Flowco Bangladesh Limited have signed a Memorandum of Understanding (MoU) to introduce dedicated green financing facilities for petrol pump owners across Bangladesh.
According to a press release, the agreement was signed recently at bank's corporate office, marks a significant s</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 12:59:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Six IS militants, three police killed in clash in northwest Turkey</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/six-is-militants-three-police-killed-in-clash-in-northwest-turkey</link><description>A clash between Islamic State militants and Turkish police in northwest Turkey on Monday left six militants and three police officers dead, Interior Minister Ali Yerlikaya said.
The shootout took place in the Elmali district of Yalova province, south of Istanbul, when police raided a house where t</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 13:14:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Over 950,000 register for postal voting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/postal-voting-over-950000-registered-window-closes-in-two-days</link><description>The number of people who registered to vote through the Postal Voting app has exceeded 950,000.
An Election Commission (EC) media statement revealed the information on Monday afternoon.
Expatriate Bangladeshis and its citizens inside, who are eligible for the registration but have not done it yet</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 13:29:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>North Korea says it test-fired long-range cruise missiles</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/north-korea-says-it-test-fired-long-range-cruise-missiles</link><description>North Korea said on Monday it test-fired long-range strategic cruise missiles into the sea to assess its nuclear deterrence capabilities, days after it revealed apparent progress in building its first nuclear-powered submarine.
The missile launches, carried out on Sunday, were the latest in a seri</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 13:44:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Kosovo’s ‘political earthquake’ election sees Kurti resurgent</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/kosovos-political-earthquake-election-sees-kurti-resurgent</link><description>An emphatic election victory for Kosovo’s Prime Minister Albin Kurti marks a resurgence for the nationalist leader, ending a political deadlock in Europe’s youngest state and potentially determining its domestic and international agenda for years.
The win strengthens Kurti’s mand</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 13:59:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nomination papers submitted peacefully ahead of Bangladesh election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nomination-papers-submitted-peacefully-ahead-of-bangladesh-election</link><description>Candidates across the country submitted their nomination papers on Monday before the 5:00 pm deadline in a calm and orderly atmosphere for the upcoming national election billed for February 12.
Most aspirants submitted their nomination papers on the final day. A total of 3,144 nomination papers we</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 14:14:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Taxpayers must notify by Jan 15 if unable to file e-return</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/taxpayers-must-notify-by-jan-15-if-unable-to-file-e-return</link><description>Taxpayers struggling with online income tax returns have until Jan 15 to request permission for alternate filing from their tax offices.
The National Board of Revenue (NBR) issued an order on Monday setting the deadline for applications from taxpayers unable to submit e-returns.
Earlier, the onli</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 14:29:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No compromise on question of justice: Hasnat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/no-compromise-on-question-of-justice-hasnat</link><description>There will be no compromise on the issue of justice (Insaaf), said Hasnat Abdullah, chief organiser of the southern region of the National Citizen Party (NCP), on Monday.
“We will work to establish a just Bangladesh,” he said while talking to reporters after filing his nomination paper</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 14:44:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Crude bomb attack on BNP protest triggers turmoil in Bhola</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/crude-bomb-attack-on-bnp-protest-triggers-turmoil-in-bhola</link><description>Bhola town has descended into chaos after crude bombs were hurled at a protest of the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) demanding justice for its slain student leader Rezwan Amin Sifat.
Police fired blank shots to bring the situation under control after the Bangladesh Jatiya Party (BJP) office at</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 14:59:26 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>