<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 16:30:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Tarique warns against political volatility, urges election participation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-warns-against-political-volatility-urges-election-participation</link><description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman on Wednesday urged political parties not to make the country’s situation volatile by imposing various conditions, but instead to face people in next year’s national election, rather than issuing threats to the ‘fragile’ interim government.</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 14:30:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Midland Bank holds seminar at Jahangirnagar University to promote financial literacy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/midland-bank-holds-seminar-at-jahangirnagar-university-to-promote-financial-literacy</link><description>Midland Bank PLC, in collaboration with Communic-IBA of Jahangirnagar University, jointly organised a seminar on Financial Literacy on Wednesday at the Senate Hall of Jahangirnagar University, Savar, Dhaka, according to a press release.
The seminar was chaired by Professor Dr. Ireen Akther, Direct</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 14:45:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>RAB recovers petrol bombs, cocktails from Dhaka’s Mohammadpur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rab-recovers-petrol-bombs-cocktails-from-dhakas-mohammadpur</link><description>Members of the Rapid Action Battalion (RAB) recovered six petrol bombs and four crude bombs (cocktails) from the Rayerbazar Intellectuals’ Graveyard area under Mohammadpur Police Station on Wednesday evening.
The explosives were found abandoned during a special drive conducted by the Crime P</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 15:00:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Munshiganj Dacoity: 5 DB, RAB members among 7 held in Savar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/munshiganj-dacoity-5-db-rab-members-among-7-held-in-savar</link><description>Police have arrested seven people, including two members of the Dhaka District Detective Branch (DB) and three members of the Rapid Action Battalion (RAB), for their alleged involvement in looting Tk 65 lakh from a gold trader in Sreenagar upazila of Munshiganj while posing as DB officers.
The arr</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 14:23:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EBL hosts seminar at IUB to enhance financial literacy among students</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ebl-hosts-seminar-at-iub-to-enhance-financial-literacy-among-students</link><description>Eastern Bank PLC (EBL) organized an exclusive seminar titled “EBL Campus Connect: Inspiring New Generation in Banking” at Independent University, Bangladesh (IUB), on November 10.  The initiative followed the objective of enhancing financial literacy and inspiring students toward a</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 14:38:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Citizens Bank signs MoU with National Pension Authority</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/citizens-bank-signs-mou-with-national-pension-authority</link><description>Citizens Bank PLC signed a Memorandum of Understanding (MoU) with the National Pension Authority to support the implementation of the Government’s Universal Pension Scheme.
According to a press release, the signing ceremony was held on Wednesday in the conference room of Finance Division in</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 14:53:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BRAC Bank’s 2nd ‘EmpowerAbility 2025’ to accelerate inclusive growth</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/brac-banks-2nd-empowerability-2025-to-accelerate-inclusive-growth</link><description>BRAC Bank, in collaboration with the Bangladesh Business and Disability Network (BBDN), hosted 'EmpowerAbility 2025: Powering Every Ability' to accelerate Bangladesh's transition toward disability-inclusive growth.
The conference under BRAC Bank's flagship CSR initiatives 'Aporajeyo Ami' was held</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 15:08:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>British journalist slates new arrest move against Ivy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/british-journalist-bergman-condemns-fresh-arrest-bid-to-keep-ex-mayor-ivy-behind-bars</link><description>British journalist and human rights activist David Bergman has criticised the police move to show former Narayanganj City Corporation mayor Selina Hayat Ivy arrested in several new cases, just a day after the High Court granted her bail in five previous cases.
In a Facebook post on Wednesday, Berg</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 15:23:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>2 dead, 20 injured in west India factory fire</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/2-dead-20-injured-in-west-india-factory-fire</link><description>At least two people died and around 20 were injured when a fire broke out inside a pharmaceutical factory in India’s western state of Gujarat on Wednesday, confirmed the local police.
The incident took place at the factory located in Saykha GIDC area. All the victims were factory workers. Th</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 15:38:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Al-Arafah Islami Bank holds 30th AGM</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/al-arafah-islami-bank-holds-30th-agm</link><description>The 30th Annual General Meeting (AGM) of Al-Arafah Islami Bank was held virtually on Wednesday, November 12, 2025, at the Bank’s Head Office.
Chairman of the Bank Khwaja Shahriar presided over the meeting, according to a press release.
The meeting was attended by Board Directors Md. Shahin</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 15:53:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bus catches fire at Mawa expressway entrance</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bus-catches-fire-at-mawa-expressway-entrance</link><description>A bus has caught fire on the road at the Dolaipar Para entrance to the Mawa expressway in Dhaka.
Firefighters rushed to the scene after receiving the alert and brought the flames under control.
Rozina Akter, duty officer at the Fire Service control room, said two units were dispatched at 6:38 pm</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 16:08:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>37 killed in Peru road crash</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/37-killed-in-peru-road-crash</link><description>At least 37 people were killed and dozens injured after a bus plunged into a ravine in the Arequipa region of southern Peru, local authorities said on Wednesday.
The fatalities included 36 people who died on site, and another person who died in hospital, said Walther Oporto, Arequipa's regional he</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 16:23:29 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>