<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 12:56:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>BNP casts doubt on Jamaat’s hacking claim over Shafiqur's ‘misogynistic’ post</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-casts-doubt-on-jamaats-hacking-claim-over-shafiqurs-misogynistic-post</link><description>The BNP has expressed scepticism over Jamaat-e-Islami’s claim that a “misogynistic” post published from the X account of its chief Shafiqur Rahman was the result of hacking.
Jamaat said the post was made after hackers briefly took control of Shafiqur's verified X account. The BNP</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 09:49:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ex-state minister Farhad arrested over ‘corruption’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/former-state-minister-farhad-now-shown-arrested-in-corruption-case</link><description>Former state minister for public administration Farhad Hossain has been shown arrested in a graft case initiated by the Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC).
Dhaka Metropolitan Senior Special Judge Sabbir Faiz made the decision on Sunday following a plea by the investigating officer in the case.
ACC</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 10:04:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CA for early FTA talks with EU to ensure continued duty-free access</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ca-for-early-fta-talks-with-eu-to-ensure-continued-duty-free-access</link><description>Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus on Sunday called for an early start to Free Trade Agreement (FTA) negotiations with the European Union (EU), stressing the need to safeguard Bangladesh’s trade preferences in its largest export market once the current duty-free access expires in the comi</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 09:53:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Protest at DU over post on women from Jamaat chief’s account</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/protest-at-du-over-post-on-women-from-jamaat-chiefs-account</link><description>The Jatiyatabadi Chhatra Dal has staged a protest at Dhaka University, condemning a tweet from the X (formerly known as Twitter) account of Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami chief Shafiqur Rahman that called working women “prostitutes”.
On Sunday afternoon, the BNP’s student affiliate c</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 10:08:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pakistan forces kill 145 militants after attacks in Balochistan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/pakistan-forces-kill-145-militants-after-attacks-in-balochistan</link><description>Pakistan’s security forces killed 145 militants over 40 hours after coordinated attacks across Balochistan, the chief minister of the southwestern province said on Sunday, as the authorities battle one of the deadliest flare-ups in years.
The attacks underscore the persistence of insurgents</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 10:23:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tehran warns of regional conflict if US attacks Iran</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/tehran-warns-of-regional-conflict-if-us-attacks-iran</link><description>Iran's Supreme Leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei said that if the U.S. attacked Iran it would become a regional conflict, state media reported on Sunday, amid heightened tensions between Washington and Tehran.
The U.S. has built up its naval presence in the Middle East after President Donald Trump rep</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 10:38:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jail inmates among 18,000 voters in Faridpur to cast votes by postal ballots</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jail-inmates-among-18000-voters-in-faridpur-to-cast-votes-by-postal-ballots</link><description>A total of 17,988 voters including inmates of Faridpur district jail will cast their votes through postal ballots in the national election.
Among them, 52 inmates and 13 jail officials and employees will exercise their franchise through the postal ballot system.
Of the 52 jail inmate voters, two</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 10:53:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat supports women leadership in politics: Shafiqur Rahman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-supports-women-leadership-in-politics-shafiqur-rahman</link><description>Jamaat-e-Islami Ameer Dr Shafiqur Rahman on Sunday said that his party supports women leadership in politics and local government, along with economic empowerment of rural women, strong legal protection and social respect.
In a Facebook post, he said false and misleading content has been circulati</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 11:08:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Reopening of Gaza's Rafah crossing expected Monday, officials say</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/reopening-of-gazas-rafah-crossing-expected-monday-officials-say</link><description>Gaza's main border crossing in Rafah will reopen for Palestinians on Monday, Israel said, with preparations underway at the war-ravaged enclave's main gateway that has been largely shut for almost two years.
Before the war, the Rafah border crossing with Egypt was the only direct exit point for mo</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 11:23:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mobile financial service transactions to be restricted for national election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/mobile-financial-service-transactions-to-be-restricted-for-national-election</link><description>Bangladesh Bank is set to impose strict limits on mobile financial services (MFS) and internet banking transactions ahead of the upcoming national parliamentary elections.
Under the proposed measures, platforms such as bKash, Rocket, and Nagad will see a significant reduction in transaction limits</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 11:38:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Md Parvez Saiful Islam appointed as CEO of Square Food &amp; Beverage Ltd</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/md-parvez-saiful-islam-appointed-as-ceo-of-square-food-beverage-ltd</link><description>Square Food &amp; Beverage Limited (SFBL) has announced the appointment of Md. Parvez Saiful Islam as its new Chief Executive Officer (CEO).
The announcement came during the company’s Annual Sales Conference 2026, held recently in Cox’s Bazar, where the company also celebrated its 25th ann</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 11:53:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh women complete perfect qualifier campaign with 7-wicket win</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/bangladesh-women-complete-perfect-qualifier-campaign-with-7-wicket-win</link><description>Bangladesh women’s cricket team maintained a flawless record in the ICC Women’s T20 World Cup Qualifiers, securing their seventh consecutive victory by defeating the Netherlands by 7 wickets in their final match at the Upper Mulpani Cricket Ground on Sunday.
Having already booked their</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 12:08:04 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>