<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 07:19:43 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Weather may remain mainly dry</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/weather-may-remain-mainly-dry</link><description>The Bangladesh Meteorological Department (BMD) forecast the weather may remain mainly dry with partly cloudy sky across the country over the next 24 hours, beginning at 9:00 am today (Thursday). 
"Weather may remain mainly dry with partly cloudy sky across the country. But, light rain is like</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 05:57:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US buys more Argentine pesos, Bessent says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/us-buys-more-argentine-pesos-working-on-20-billion-debt-facility-bessent-says</link><description>The US again purchased Argentine pesos in the open market on Wednesday, Treasury Secretary Scott Bessent told reporters, adding that the department was working with banks and investment funds to create a $20 billion facility to invest in the South American country's sovereign debt.
Bessent said du</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 05:14:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Obaidul Quader’s younger brother arrested in Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/obaidul-quaders-younger-brother-arrested-in-dhaka</link><description>Detectives have detained Md Shahadat Hossain, younger of former minister Obaidul Quader and eight others involved with Awami League politics, in Dhaka.
Muhammad Talebur Rahman, deputy commissioner (DC-Media) of Dhaka Metropolitan Police (DMP), said this on Thursday morning.
A Detective Branch (DB</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 05:29:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Girls outperform boys in HSC results</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/girls-outperform-boys-in-hsc-results</link><description>Female students in the Higher Secondary Certificate (HSC) and equivalent examinations-2025 have outnumbered their male counterparts in achieving higher pass rate and a greater number of GPA-5 achievers likewise previous years. 
The average pass rate across the 11 education boards this year st</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 05:44:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>HSC result re-scrutiny applications open tomorrow</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hsc-result-re-scrutiny-applications-open-tomorrow</link><description>The results of this year's HSC and equivalent examinations were published today at 10 am. 
Students who are not satisfied with the results will have the opportunity to apply for re-scrutiny or challenge their marks, as in previous years.
Students can apply for re-scrutiny from tomorrow, Octo</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 05:59:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nestle to axe 16,000 jobs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/nestle-to-axe-16000-jobs-as-new-ceo-targets-sales-growth</link><description>Nestle will axe 16,000 jobs as it tries to raise sales volumes, new CEO Philipp Navratil said on Thursday, as the world's largest packaged food company reported better-than-expected sales growth thanks to pricing-led upticks in coffee and confectionery.
Navratil, the former head of Nespresso, repl</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 06:14:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>KU expels 12 students over misconduct</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ku-expels-12-students-over-misconduct</link><description>Khulna University (KU) has expelled 12 students and imposed disciplinary measures on seven others for their involvement in ragging, assault, drug use, and religious defamation.
Prof Nazmus Sadat, Director of Student Affairs of the university, confirmed the matter, reports BSS.
The decisions were</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 06:44:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>SC to resume regular judicial proceedings from Oct 19</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/sc-to-resume-regular-judicial-proceedings-from-oct-19</link><description>The Supreme Court (SC) will resume its regular judicial activities from October 19, after the vacation that began on September 7, and continue through October 18, including public and weekly holidays. Following tradition, the Chief Justice and judges of both the Appellate and High Court Divisi</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 07:14:22 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>