<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 22:24:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Administration penalised me thrice: Rumeen</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/rumeen-farhana-says-administration-punished-her-thrice-over-single-offence</link><description>Rumeen Farhana, the independent candidate for Brahmanbaria-2, has said the administration has “punished” her three times over an offence.
She accused the election authorities of showing “bias” during a meeting with journalists at the Brahmanbaria Press Club on Monday.
She</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 16:08:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique should face show-cause notice before others over electoral code violation, says NCP</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-should-face-show-cause-notice-before-others-over-electoral-code-violation-says-ncp</link><description>The National Citizen Party (NCP) leaders have renewed their offensive against Tarique Rahman barely three weeks before the Feb 12 vote, saying the BNP supremo should be the first to explain the allegations of violating the election code of conduct.
Their tirade against Tarique came minutes after t</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 16:23:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Italian fashion designer Valentino has died, la Repubblica daily says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/italian-fashion-designer-valentino-has-died-la-repubblica-daily-says</link><description>Italian fashion designer Valentino Garavani has died at the age of 93, newspaper la Repubblica and other Italian media said on Monday.</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 16:54:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Politics should be about making people’s well-being, not blaming others: Tarique Rahman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/politics-should-be-about-making-peoples-well-being-not-blaming-others-tarique-rahman</link><description>Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) Chairman Tarique Rahman today said politics should not be about blaming others; rather, it must be about improving people’s lives.
“Politics of blaming will not fill people’s stomachs. We don’t want to confine politics only to slogans, son</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 17:09:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IMF tranche delay posed no threat to Bangladesh’s economy: BB Governor</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/imf-tranche-delay-posed-no-threat-to-bangladeshs-economy-bb-governor</link><description>Bangladesh’s economy has not suffered any adverse impact despite the delay in receiving the sixth tranche of the International Monetary Fund (IMF) loan, Bangladesh Bank Governor Ahsan H Mansur said on Monday, stressing that the country has managed the economic challenges on its own strength.</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 17:24:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Geo-political storm triggers anxiety</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/geo-political-storm-triggers-anxiety</link><description>The United States (US) has attacked Venezuela and deposed Nicolas Maduro — in Washington’s most direct intervention in Latin America since the 1989 invasion of Panama.
The recent armed intervention in Venezuela has become the subject of discussion among countries all over the world. Ve</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 17:09:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Healthcare costs should top agenda</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/healthcare-costs-should-top-agenda</link><description>What pundits on social and economic issues say, celebrate the outlook of people on how to improve the health of politics, governance and so on. However, of late, attention is also turning to the more fundamental issue of public health or, in other words,  health of the very members of society</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 17:24:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Promoting ties with Nordic countries</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/promoting-ties-with-nordic-countries</link><description>As the world recalibrates economic alliances amidst technological disruption, climate insecurity and shifting geopolitics, Bangladesh's relationship with the Nordic countries -- Denmark, Finland, Iceland, Norway and Sweden -- merits renewed attention. Often eclipsed by ties with major economies in</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 17:39:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Transformation of RMG industry</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/transformation-of-rmg-industry</link><description>A quiet technological revolution is taking place in the country's garment industry. The industry's journey from its tentative beginning in the late 1970s to the current number one position in terms of leadership in energy and environment design (LEED)-certified factories is long and arduous. Its tr</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 17:54:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gold price hits fresh record in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/gold-price-hits-fresh-record-in-bangladesh</link><description>Gold prices in Bangladesh have soared to a new all-time high, with the price of 22-carat gold set at Tk 238,879 per bhori (11.664 grams), following the latest adjustment by the Bangladesh Jewellers Association (BAJUS).
In a notification issued late Monday night, BAJUS announced a price hike of Tk</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 18:09:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Governor Ahsan H Mansur wants corporate flag abroad as reserves stabilise</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/governor-ahsan-h-mansur-wants-corporate-flag-abroad-as-reserves-stabilise</link><description>Governor Ahsan H Mansur has said he wants to see Bangladesh’s corporate flag flying abroad, signalling support for more liberalised overseas investment as reserves strengthen.
Speaking at a seminar organised jointly by Policy Exchange Bangladesh and the Metropolitan Chamber of Commerce and I</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 18:24:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>MoL turns down draft Money Loan Court Act</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/mol-turns-down-draft-money-loan-court-act</link><description>The law ministry has turned down the central bank's proposal to prepare a new Artha Rin Adalat Ain (Money Loan Court Act) and suggested updating of the existing law through necessary amendments, officials say.



The draft law, prepared by the central bank, incorporated extensive punitive actio</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 19:25:02 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>