<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 11:16:37 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>JU jointly tops Bangladesh in THE World University Rankings 2026</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ju-jointly-tops-bangladesh-in-the-world-university-rankings-2026</link><description>Jahangirnagar University (JU) has once again been named among Bangladesh's leading higher education institutions, jointly securing the top position in the country according to the Times Higher Education (THE) World University Rankings 2026.
The UK-based organisation, in collaboration with Elsevier</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 09:42:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Venezuela's Maria Corina Machado wins 2025 Nobel Peace Prize</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/venezuelas-maria-corina-machado-wins-2025-nobel-peace-prize</link><description>Venezuelan opposition leader Maria Corina Machado won the Nobel Peace Prize on Friday for promoting democratic rights in her country and her struggle to achieve a transition to democracy, the Norwegian Nobel Committee said.
"When authoritarians seize power, it is crucial to recognise courageous de</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 09:57:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP's Fakhrul warns of attempt to bring bureaucracy ‘under one party’s control’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnps-fakhrul-warns-of-attempt-to-bring-bureaucracy-under-one-partys-control</link><description>Senior BNP leader Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir has alleged that efforts are being made to bring Bangladesh’s bureaucracy under the influence of a particular political party ahead of the upcoming 13th parliamentary election.
Speaking at an event in Dhaka on Friday, the BNP secretary general di</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 09:13:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ceasefire clock starts in Gaza after Israel-Hamas agreement</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/ceasefire-clock-starts-in-gaza-after-israel-hamas-agreement</link><description>A ceasefire agreement between Israel and Hamas for the Gaza Strip came into effect at noon local time, the Israeli military said Friday, adding that troops were withdrawing to agreed-upon deployment lines. The announcement came hours after Israel’s Cabinet approved President Donald Trump&amp;rsqu</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 09:28:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>3 unidentified persons found dead in Dhaka’s Shahbagh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/3-unidentified-persons-found-dead-in-dhakas-shahbagh</link><description>Police recovered the bodies of three unidentified individuals, including a woman, from separate locations in capital’s Shahbagh between Thursday night and early Friday morning.
Shahbagh Police Station’s sub-inspector Md. Ilias Kabir confirmed recovering the bodies between 9:30 pm and 1</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 09:58:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Three bodies recovered from Shahbagh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/three-bodies-recovered-from-shahbagh</link><description>Police have recovered the bodies of three people, including a woman, from separate locations in Dhaka’s Shahbagh.
The three were found unconscious at different times and taken to Dhaka Medical College Hospital (DMCH) on Thursday, where doctors declared them dead, according to Md Khaled Monsu</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 10:28:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gazans stream towards wrecked homes as Israeli forces pull back under ceasefire</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/gazans-stream-towards-wrecked-homes-as-israeli-forces-pull-back-under-ceasefire</link><description>Thousands of displaced Palestinians streamed back towards their abandoned homes on Friday after a ceasefire between Israel and Hamas went into effect and Israeli troops began pulling back from parts of Gaza.
A massive column of displaced Gazans filed north through the dust towards Gaza City, the e</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 10:58:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Japan's ruling coalition splits, throwing Takaichi's PM bid into doubt</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/japans-ruling-coalition-splits-throwing-takaichis-pm-bid-into-doubt</link><description>Sanae Takaichi's bid to become Japan's first female prime minister was thrown into doubt on Friday when her ruling party's junior coalition partner quit.
The Liberal Democratic Party, which has ruled Japan for almost all of the postwar era, selected hardline conservative Takaichi as its new</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 11:13:23 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>