<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 12:35:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Elections and referendum on same day? Consensus panel to ask government to decide</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/elections-and-referendum-on-same-day-consensus-panel-to-ask-government-to-decide</link><description>The National Consensus Commission will propose that the government decide whether to hold the national election and the referendum at the same time, panel member Badiul Alam Majumdar has said.
He made the remarks on Saturday while speaking at a “Shadow Parliament” organised by Debate f</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 10:38:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ASEAN to discuss Myanmar election observers at October summit</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/asean-to-discuss-myanmar-election-observers-at-october-summit</link><description>Myanmar's junta has invited the Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN) to send observers for planned year-end elections, and the bloc will discuss the request during a regional summit later this month, Malaysia's foreign ministry has said.
The invitation to send election observers was exte</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 09:49:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangabandhu portrait: Bangladesh JaSaD questions consensus panel's intent</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-jasad-questions-consensus-commissions-motive-behind-proposal-on-bangabandhu-portraits</link><description>The Bangladesh Jatiya Samajtantrik Dal (JaSaD) has raised objections to the National Consensus Commission’s move to seek opinions on whether portraits of Bangabandhu Sheikh Mujibur Rahman should be displayed in government and private institutions, calling it a politically motivated initiative</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 10:34:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DU to hold ‘Sarat Utsob', Satyen Sen Group’s allocation scrapped</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/dhaka-university-set-to-host-sarat-utsob-after-scrapping-satyen-sen-shilpi-groups-allocation</link><description>Dhaka University has revoked permission for the cultural organisation Satyen Sen Shilpi Group to organise the Sarat Utsob, an annual festival to mark the arrival of autumn, at the Faculty of Fine Arts’ Bakultala premises, deciding instead to organise the festival itself.
The faculty’s</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 10:49:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh can become a global hub for eye health research: Prof Nathan Congdon</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/bangladesh-can-become-a-global-hub-for-eye-health-research-prof-nathan-congdon</link><description>Bangladesh has the potential to emerge as a global leader in eye health research, combining its strong public health network with innovative partnerships that link poverty alleviation to vision care, says Prof Nathan Congdon, Research Director at Orbis International.
Speaking to The Financial Expr</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 11:04:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>PR needed to make every vote count, and for fair elections: Jamaat’s Hamidur Rahman Azad</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/pr-needed-to-make-every-vote-count-and-for-fair-elections-jamaats-hamidur-rahman-azad</link><description>Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami Assistant Secretary General AHM Hamidur Rahman Azad on Saturday stressed the need for introducing proportional representation, an electoral system where the distribution of seats in parliament would align with the proportion of total votes received by each party, in a bid</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 11:34:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh a good manufacturing hub for many global players: Indian businesses</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-a-good-manufacturing-hub-for-many-global-players-indian-businesses</link><description>Indian business community has said Bangladesh is proving to be a ‘good manufacturing hub’ for many of the international players, including players from India and described the current situation in Bangladesh as a ‘temporary phase’ when the business is to some extent ‘n</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 11:49:36 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>