<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 11:20:47 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>US says it struck IS militants in northwest Nigeria</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-says-it-struck-is-militants-in-northwest-nigeria</link><description>The United States carried out a strike against Islamic State militants in northwest Nigeria at the request of Nigeria's government, President Donald Trump and the US military said on Thursday, claiming the group had been targeting Christians in the region.
"Tonight, at my direction as Commander in</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 05:13:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Japan's cabinet approves record $785 billion budget</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/japans-cabinet-approves-record-785-billion-budget</link><description>Japanese Prime Minister Sanae Takaichi's cabinet on Friday approved a record $785 billion budget for the next fiscal year, aiming to strike a balance between her proactive fiscal policy and debt blowout concerns by limiting new bond issuance.
Faced with rising government bond yields and a weak yen</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 05:30:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Abhaynagar Upazila of Jashore: Charcoal kilns widely harming environment and public health</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/abhaynagar-upazila-of-jashore-charcoal-kilns-widely-harming-environment-and-public-health</link><description>BENAPOLE: The unchecked operation of unauthorised charcoal kilns in Abhaynagar upazila of Jashore has pushed the local environment and public health to the brink of disaster.
Toxic black smoke spewing continuously from the kilns is severely polluting the air, destroying forest resources and causin</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 05:45:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hundreds of 'Death Wells' scattered across Barind fields</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/hundreds-of-death-wells-scattered-across-barind-fields</link><description>The water crisis in the Barind region has no end in sight, but now, poorly planned well drilling is rapidly turning into a serious humanitarian risk. Across vast tracts of farmland in Rajshahi, Naogaon and Chapainawabganj, hundreds of abandoned deep tube wells and test bores lie exposed, silently t</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 06:00:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Four die as launches collide on Meghna River amid dense fog</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/four-die-as-launches-collide-on-meghna-river-amid-dense-fog</link><description>Four people have been killed in a head-on collision between two passenger launches on the Meghna River in Chandpur amid dense fog.
The collision occurred around 2:00 am on Thursday in the Harinaghat area of Chandpur Sadar Upazila, according to BIWTA Chandpur Port Officer Babu Lal Baidya.
Dhaka Di</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 06:47:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BGMEA sets new membership criteria to ensure factory safety, operational standards</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bgmea-sets-new-membership-criteria-to-ensure-factory-safety-operational-standards</link><description>The apex body of the country's apparel sector has introduced a set of new criteria for granting membership, including minimum factory space and machinery requirements, aiming to ensure basic operational and safety standards.
The Bangladesh Garment Manufacturers and Exporters Association (BGMEA) sa</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 07:02:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Textile, cottage industries fair begins in Rajshahi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/textile-cottage-industries-fair-begins-in-rajshahi</link><description>A month-long handloom, textile and cottage industries fair opened in Rajshahi on Thursday.
Organised by the Women Entrepreneurs' Association of Bangladesh (WEAB), Rajshahi chapter, the fair is being held on the northern side of the Rajshahi Central Botanical Garden and Zoo to mark the organisation</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 07:17:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Season's first cold wave grips parts of country</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/seasons-first-cold-wave-grips-parts-of-country</link><description>A mild cold wave, the first of the season, is sweeping across several districts including Jashore, Chuadanga, Gopalganj, Rajshahi, Pabna, Sirajganj and Nilphamari, according to the Bangladesh Meteorological Department (BMD).
Meteorologist Shahnaz Sultana said on Friday that the ongoing cold spell</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 07:49:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BPL set to kick off under cloud of off-field issues</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/bpl-set-to-kick-off-under-cloud-of-off-field-issues</link><description>The 12th season of the Bangladesh Premier League (BPL) gets underway on Friday, but the build-up to the country's flagship T20 competition has been dominated by organisational uncertainty and a series of off-field issues that have once again placed the tournament under scrutiny.
There has been no</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 08:04:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gas pressure to remain low for three days due to LNG supply disruption</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/gas-pressure-to-remain-low-for-three-days-due-to-lng-supply-disruption</link><description>Gas pressure will remain low today (Friday) and for the next two days—Saturday and Sunday—due to a reduction in gas supply from liquefied natural gas (LNG), caused by maintenance work at the LNG terminal and delays in cargo arrivals.
Titas Gas authorities disclosed the information in a</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 08:19:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP takes initiatives to cleanup 'July 36 Expressway Venue'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-takes-initiatives-to-cleanup-july-36-expressway-venue</link><description>Bangladesh Nationalist Party's (BNP's) Dhaka North City unit has taken the initiative to conduct cleanup drives at "July 36 Expressway" (popularly known as the 300-feet road), used for its Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman's public address, in the Purbachal area of the capital.
The multi-faceted clea</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 09:20:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Security beefed up in Savar ahead of Tarique's visit to National Martyrs’ Memorial</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/security-beefed-up-in-savar-ahead-of-tariques-visit-to-national-martyrs-memorial</link><description>Security has been ramped up at the National Martyrs’ Memorial in Savar ahead of BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman’s visit to pay tribute to the fallen heroes of the 1971 Liberation War.
Tarique, who returned home after 17 years in exile, is scheduled to visit the memorial on Friday, r</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 10:22:46 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>