<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 16:24:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Hamza Choudhury becomes brand ambassador of bKash</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/hamza-choudhury-becomes-brand-ambassador-of-bkash</link><description>Hamza Choudhury, the popular footballer of the Bangladesh National Football Team and English club Leicester City, has become the brand ambassador of bKash.
Hamza, rejuvenating Bangladeshi football fans with fresh spirit, will participate in various promotional activities of bKash to encourage cust</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 12:45:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Security on high alert ahead of verdict against Sheikh Hasina: Home adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/security-on-high-alert-ahead-of-verdict-against-sheikh-hasina-home-adviser</link><description>Home Adviser Lieutenant General (Retd) Md Jahangir Alam Chowdhury on Saturday said the law enforcement agencies have already taken all required preparations to check any untoward incident centring the verdict to be announced on Monday against ousted Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina.
"The verdict again</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 13:00:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mercantile Bank holds ‘Risk Conference 2025’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/mercantile-bank-holds-risk-conference-2025</link><description>Mercantile Bank PLC organized ‘Risk Conference 2025’ today (Saturday) at the bank’s head office in the capital.
Md. Sirajul Islam, Executive Director, Bangladesh Bank, inaugurated the conference as the chief guest, according to a media release.
Md. Anwarul Haq, Chairman of the B</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 13:15:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hero Alom gets bail after arrest on charges of attempting to murder former wife</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/hero-alom-gets-bail-after-arrest-on-charges-of-attempting-to-murder-former-wife</link><description>Content creator Ashraful Alam, widely known as Hero Alom, has secured bail after being arrested in a case filed by his former wife, accusing him of attempted murder and assault.
Dhaka Metropolitan Magistrate Rakibul Hasan passed the order on Saturday afternoon. His lawyer Shanta Saksina confirmed</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 13:30:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dengue: Five deaths, 792 hospitalisations reported in 24 hours</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/dengue-five-deaths-792-hospitalisations-reported-in-24-hours</link><description>Five more people have died of dengue fever in Bangladesh and 792 patients have been hospitalised with the disease in the past 24 hours.
The yearly tally of hospitalisations from the Aedes mosquito-borne disease has risen to 83,858, with 13,996 of them admitted in November alone.
According to the</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 13:45:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sonali Bank holds Divisional Business Meeting in Cumilla</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/sonali-bank-holds-divisional-business-meeting-in-cumilla</link><description>Sonali Bank PLC, General Manager’s Office, Cumilla and Noakhali jointly arranged a Divisional Business Review Meeting-2025 at Buro Bangladesh Auditorium on Saturday, according to a press release.
Bank’s MD &amp; CEO Md. Shawkat Ali Khan attended the meeting as chief guest. General Manager</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 14:00:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>WTO affirms commitment to boosting Bangladesh’s trade competitiveness</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/wto-affirms-commitment-to-boosting-bangladeshs-trade-competitiveness</link><description>The World Trade Organization (WTO) has reaffirmed its commitment to assisting Bangladesh in achieving export diversification and enhancing its competitive standing in international markets, primarily through the full implementation of the Trade Facilitation Agreement (TFA) and robust adherence to S</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 14:15:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No controversial officer to be in leading role in next election: IGP</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/no-controversial-officer-to-be-in-leading-role-in-next-election-igp</link><description>Inspector General of Police (IGP) Baharul Alam on Saturday said no police officer with a controversial background will be assigned to leadership roles in the upcoming national election.
 “Although the list of controversial officers has not been prepared yet, SPs and DIGs of the respecti</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 14:30:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BRAC Bank Reading Café discusses Sunil Gangopadhyay's ‘Aranyer Din Ratri’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/brac-bank-reading-cafe-discusses-sunil-gangopadhyays-aranyer-din-ratri</link><description>The members of BRAC Bank’s Reading Café recently gathered to explore and discuss ‘Aranyer Din Ratri’, the celebrated novel by renowned author Sunil Gangopadhyay, according to a press release.
The session turned into a lively exchange of thoughts as participants delved into</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 14:45:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mahfuj hopes Notun Kuri winners will bring glory to Bangladesh’s cultural arena</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/entertainment/mahfuj-hopes-notun-kuri-winners-will-bring-glory-to-bangladeshs-cultural-arena</link><description>Information and Broadcasting Adviser Md. Mahfuj Alam on Saturday expressed his hope that the child performers who won the Notun Kuri competition will earn fame in the cultural arena of Bangladesh through hard work.
He said this while addressing the award-giving ceremony for winners of the Notun Ku</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 15:00:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DU students demand ‘exemplary trial’ for teacher accused of sexual assault</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/du-students-demand-exemplary-trial-for-teacher-accused-of-sexual-assault</link><description>Dhaka University students have demanded exemplary punishment for a teacher recently accused of sexually harassing a student.
Students formed a human chain at the Raju Memorial Sculpture at Dhaka University on Saturday, demanding the investigation into chemistry teacher Ershad Halim be completed as</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 15:45:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jahangirnagar University bans all events after 10pm</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/jahangirnagar-university-bans-all-events-after-10pm</link><description>The Jahangirnagar University (JU) has imposed a ban on all events taking place on its campus after 10pm to maintain peace, order, and security.
The directive was announced in an urgent press release signed by the university’s acting registrar Dr. ABM Azizur Rahman on Saturday evening.
The n</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 16:00:49 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>