<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 11:21:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Romania expands visa application submission points for Bangladeshis</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/romania-expands-visa-application-submission-points-for-bangladeshis</link><description>Bangladeshi nationals seeking Romanian student or family reunification visas will now have more options for submitting their applications, said the Ministry of Foreign Affairs on Monday.
The Romanian Embassy in New Delhi, which usually receives these applications, has informed through a diplomatic</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 08:13:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Onion import resume through Sonamasjid land port after 3 months</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/onion-import-resume-through-sonamasjid-land-port-after-3-months</link><description>Onion import from India has resumed through the Sonamasjid land port in Chapainawabganj after a three-month suspension.
A total of 90 tonnes of onions have entered the country so far after the government granted limited permission for onion imports.
Mainul Islam, manager of Panama Sonamasjid Port</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 08:28:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BB server still down, interbank platform offline</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bb-server-still-down-interbank-platform-offline</link><description>Four days after a major power disruption, Bangladesh Bank's server has yet to be fully normal, officials said.
They said the online platform for the Interbank Data Processing (ITDP) system, which facilitates mutual exchanges between banks, remains offline due to the server malfunction.
A Banglade</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 08:43:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khaleda's London transfer delayed again</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/khaledas-london-transfer-delayed-again</link><description>Plans to fly former prime minister Khaleda Zia to London for advanced medical care have hit a fresh snag after the air ambulance hired for her travel requested the cancellation of its Tuesday landing slot in Dhaka, according to bdnews24.com.
The Civil Aviation Authority of Bangladesh (CAAB) had ap</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 08:58:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Asif Nazrul bins propaganda over mobile phone sets of expatriate workers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/asif-nazrul-bins-propaganda-over-mobile-phone-sets-of-expatriate-workers</link><description>Expatriates’ Welfare and Overseas Employment Adviser Dr Asif Nazrul has refuted the propaganda being carried out on social media over the mobile phone sets of expatriate workers.
“Lying about the interim government or about me is nothing new. Some people on social media are now spreadi</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 09:13:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Time running out for election schedule announcement: Jamaat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/time-running-out-for-election-schedule-announcement-jamaat</link><description>Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami on Monday sought the Election Commission's specific decision over the schedule announcement as 'time is running out to arrange the polls before the upcoming Ramadan'.
A Jamaat delegation, led by its Secretary General Mia Golam Parwar, held a meeting with Chief Election C</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 09:43:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Why are Thailand and Cambodia fighting along their border?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/why-are-thailand-and-cambodia-fighting-along-their-border</link><description>Fighting has reignited between Thailand and Cambodia in multiple areas at their disputed border, with both sides blaming the other and Thailand carrying out air strikes on what it said were Cambodian military installations.
The latest flare-up will be a major test of a ceasefire brokered by US Pre</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 09:58:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Preparations complete for upcoming national election: Home Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/preparations-complete-for-upcoming-national-election-home-adviser</link><description>All preparations have been taken for the upcoming national parliamentary elections, said Home Affairs Adviser Lt Gen (retd) Jahangir Alam Chowdhury on Monday.
“All necessary preparation including training for law enforcement agencies, purchase of body-worn cameras and ensuring electricity at</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 10:13:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Economy cannot stabilise without balancing power in society: Prof Mahbubullah</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/economy-cannot-stabilise-without-balancing-power-in-society-prof-mahbubullah</link><description>Bangladesh’s persistent economic fragility cannot be overcome without establishing a genuine balance of power within society and dismantling a long-running ‘loot and plunder economy’, said Former Chairman of the Development Studies Department at Dhaka University, Professor Mahbubu</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 10:28:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Poll schedule: EC calls in BTV, Betar to record announcement</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/election-commission-calls-in-btv-betar-to-record-election-schedule-announcement</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has asked state broadcasters Bangladesh Television (BTV) and Bangladesh Betar to record Chief Election Commissioner AMM Nasir Uddin’s speech announcing the schedule for the 13th parliamentary election and the national referendum.
The recording is expected to take</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 10:43:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Amnesty says India’s review of location-tracking plan ‘deeply concerning’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/amnesty-says-indias-review-of-location-tracking-plan-deeply-concerning</link><description>Amnesty International has said India’s review of a telecom industry proposal to mandate always-on satellite location tracking on phones for better lawful surveillance was “deeply concerning” and puts data of human rights defenders at risk.
Prime Minister Narendra Modi’s gov</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 10:58:20 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>