<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 22:20:32 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>India ‘always seeks stability’ in Dhaka-Delhi ties: Envoy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/india-always-seeks-stability-in-dhaka-delhi-ties-envoy</link><description>Describing the bond between Bangladesh and India as “eternal”, Indian High Commissioner to Dhaka Pranay Verma said mutual benefit and interdependence will advance the relationship.
He made the remarks at an event organised to mark India-Bangladesh Friendship Day or Maitri Diwas at Guls</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 15:11:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka-Mymensingh rail link restored</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dhaka-mymensingh-rail-link-restored</link><description>Train services between Dhaka and Mymensingh have resumed nearly three hours after the engine of the “Balaka Commuter” train broke down in Gazipur’s Sreepur.
According to Sreepur Railway Station Master Md Shamim, services restarted around 7:15pm on Saturday after a replacement eng</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 15:26:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Energy efficiency is Bangladesh's invisible power plant</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/energy-efficiency-is-bangladeshs-invisible-power-plant</link><description>Every unit of energy saved carries more value than one produced, because imported fuel travels long distances, accumulates technical losses and costs the country twice over. A kilowatt hour conserved at the source prevents the need for two kilowatt-hours of costly generation later. The Internationa</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 15:41:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Traders raise oil price defying govt order</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/traders-raise-oil-price-defying-govt-order</link><description>As the saying goes, old habits die hard. This is particularly true for market manipulators in Bangladesh, who have once again resorted to their familiar tactic of creating artificial crises to drive up the prices of essential commodities such as edible oil and onions.
In a move that reflects braze</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 15:56:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Global scrutiny of agricultural trade</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/global-scrutiny-of-agricultural-trade</link><description>International trade in agricultural products has remained static over the last few years, as reflected in global export trends. The combined share of these products is still less than one-tenth of the international merchandise trade. Nevertheless, the rule on trade in agricultural products has been</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 16:11:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Missed opportunity for police reform</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/missed-opportunity-for-police-reform</link><description>The recently approved Police Commission Ordinance stands as a missed opportunity to reform a critically important institution, with its final version betraying a deliberate unwillingness to loosen the government's control over law enforcement. By stripping away provisions that would have allowed th</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 16:26:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Journalists face rising threats in election: study</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/study-warns-of-rising-risks-for-journalists-in-2026-bangladesh-elections</link><description>A new study has warned of rising physical and digital risks for journalists during the 2026 national elections in Bangladesh.
As per a media statement issued by Digitally Right, the study titled “High Risks, Low Preparedness: Journalist Safety in 2026 Elections” has found that reporter</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 17:38:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jaiswal's maiden ODI century completes India's series win over South Africa</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/jaiswals-maiden-odi-century-completes-indias-series-win-over-south-africa</link><description>Yashasvi Jaiswal's maiden one-day international century trumped Quinton de Kock's 23rd as India clinched the series from South Africa by nine wickets on Saturday.
Jaiswal's unbeaten 116, beside Rohit Sharma's 75 and Virat Kohli's unbeaten 65 powered India to the target of 271 with 10.1 overs to sp</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 17:53:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC meets Sunday on polls, referendum</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-meets-sunday-to-set-course-for-bangladesh-election-referendum</link><description>The Election Commission, led by Chief Election Commissioner AMM Nasir Uddin, will meet on Sunday (Dec 7) to review overall preparations and finalise the date for announcing the schedule for the upcoming national election and referendum, both slated for February 2026.
The Commission has finished al</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 18:08:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Petrobangla prioritises onshore bidding round to boost gas output</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/petrobangla-prioritises-onshore-bidding-round-to-boost-gas-output</link><description>State-run Petrobangla has prioritised launching an onshore bidding round ahead of an offshore one to ramp up the country's overall natural gas output from local fields.



"We are now concentrating on inviting an international tender to carry out oil and gas exploration in onshore gas blocks, e</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 18:23:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Air ambulance for Khaleda seeks ‘Tuesday slot’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/khaledas-london-flight-german-air-ambulance-seeks-tuesday-landing-slot</link><description>The German air ambulance hired to take BNP Chairperson Khaleda Zia to London for treatment has sought a landing slot in Dhaka for Tuesday, according to a Civil Aviation Authority of Bangladesh (CAAB) official.
The official told bdnews24.com that the request came from FAI Aviation Group through a t</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 18:38:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Former Jubo Dal leader arrested by joint forces dies in Jashore</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/former-jubo-dal-leader-arrested-by-joint-forces-dies-in-jashore</link><description>A former Jubo Dal leader, who was arrested in an operation in Jashore’s Keshabpur by joint forces, has died.
The dead has been identified as Ujjal Bishwash.
“Ujjal was sent to the hospital after he had fallen sick in the prison on Friday night. He was declared dead at the hospital,&amp;rd</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 18:53:46 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>