<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 13:30:17 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Israeli prison service says 1,968 Palestinian prisoners transferred</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/israeli-prison-service-says-1968-palestinian-prisoners-transferred</link><description>The Israeli prison service says it has transferred 1,968 Palestinian prisoners and detainees as part of the ceasefire deal, according to the BBC live reporting.
They were released in two groups  -- one moved from Ofer prison to various parts of the occupied West Bank, and the other from Ktzio</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 10:45:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Palestinian prisoners receiving medical care in Gaza, says Hamas</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/palestinian-prisoners-receiving-medical-care-in-gaza-says-hamas</link><description>Released Palestinians are now being given medical treatment and examinations in hospitals across Gaza, according to the Hamas-run health ministry, according to the BBC live reporting.
Nearly 2,000 Palestinians have been freed from Israeli detention today — some transferred to the occupied We</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 11:00:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump’s Knesset speech briefly interrupted over Palestine</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trumps-knesset-speech-briefly-interrupted-over-palestine</link><description>U.S. President Donald Trump’s speech to Israel’s parliament, the Knesset, was briefly interrupted on Sunday when opposition lawmaker Ayman Odeh held up a sign calling for the recognition of a Palestinian state. Odeh later said on social media that he was removed for raising “the s</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 11:15:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump says Hamas will be disarmed but deal not yet agreed</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-says-hamas-will-be-disarmed-but-deal-not-yet-agreed</link><description>US President Donald Trump told Israel’s parliament that Gaza would be demilitarised and Hamas disarmed, drawing some of the loudest applause of his speech, according to the BBC live reporting.
However, those parts of his 20-point peace plan have not yet been agreed, and Hamas has so far reje</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 11:30:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chief adviser rolls out 6-point proposal to ensure global food security</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/chief-adviser-rolls-out-6-point-proposal-to-ensure-global-food-security</link><description>Bangladesh’s Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus has called for a fundamental overhaul of the global economic system to eliminate hunger and inequality, unveiling a six-point proposal to ensure global food security during his keynote address at the opening of the World Food Forum 2025 in R</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 11:45:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique to return and lead BNP’s electioneering: Aman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-to-return-and-lead-bnps-electioneering-aman</link><description>BNP Chairperson’s Advisory Council member Amanullah Aman on Monday said their party’s Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman will return home and lead the party’s election campaign ahead of the national election.
“The national election will be held in early 2026. Our leader Tarique</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 12:00:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Six police personnel receive BPM, PPM awards</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/six-police-personnel-receive-bpm-ppm-awards</link><description>The government has awarded Bangladesh Police Medals (BPM) and President’s Police Medals (PPM) to six police personnel for their outstanding performance in May and June 2025.
The Ministry of Home Affairs (Police Wing-2) issued a gazette notification on Monday mentioning the names of the award</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 12:30:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Will the Nobel Prize ever run out of money?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/others/will-the-nobel-prize-ever-run-out-of-money</link><description>When Alfred Nobel was presumed dead in 1888, a French newspaper printed an obituary referring to him as "The Merchant of Death." In reality, it was Alfred's brother Ludvig who had died of a heart attack in France.
But due to some misunderstanding, one French newspaper believed that it was Alfred w</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 12:45:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>16 JU students suspended over ragging allegations</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/16-ju-students-suspended-over-ragging-allegations</link><description>Sixteen students of Jahangirnagar University (JU) were temporarily suspended for allegedly ragging several first-year students of the Department of Biochemistry and Molecular Biology.
According to an office order issued by the Registrar’s Office on Monday, the students were suspended under S</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 13:00:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shahjalal Islami Bank holds financial literacy program for female CMSME entrepreneurs in Bogura</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/shahjalal-islami-bank-holds-financial-literacy-program-for-female-cmsme-entrepreneurs-in-bogura</link><description>A financial literacy program was organized on Saturday at a local hotel in Bogura for the development of CMSME women entrepreneurs at the initiative of the SME &amp; Agri Investment Division of the Corporate Head Office of Shahjalal Islami Bank PLC.
According to a press release, the financial literacy</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 13:15:17 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>