<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 13:35:38 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Fire breaks out in Mohakhali’s Korail slum</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fire-breaks-out-in-mohakhalis-korail-slum</link><description>A fire has broken out at the Korail slum in Dhaka’s Mohakhali.
Fire Service duty officer Rashed Bin Khalid confirmed the blaze at 5:22pm on Tuesday.
The Fire Service deployed seven units to bring the flames under control.
The cause of the fire and the extent of damage are yet to be determi</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 10:05:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Low forms in Bay of Bengal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/met-office-urges-caution-as-fresh-low-pressure-area-forms-in-southwest-bay-of-bengal</link><description>A low-pressure area has formed over the southwest Bay of Bengal and the adjoining Sri Lanka coast, with forecasts saying it may intensify further.
The Bangladesh Meteorological Department issued a special weather bulletin on Tuesday, asking fishing boats and trawlers not to venture into the deep s</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 10:20:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh’s first dental Unit for special children launched</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/bangladeshs-first-dental-unit-for-special-children-launched</link><description>The country’s first specialised dental Unit designed exclusively for children with special needs has begun its journey in Dhaka, marking a historic milestone in inclusive healthcare.
The health facility was inaugurated at the faith Bangladesh’s Lalmatia campus at a ceremony attended by</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 10:35:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nestlé Bangladesh defends Kitkat quality</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/nestle-bangladesh-defends-kitkat-quality</link><description>Nestlé Bangladesh has challenged the basis of a criminal case accusing it of importing substandard KitKat, saying authorities acted without reviewing documents or consulting the company before seeking arrest warrants for two senior officials.
On Tuesday, the company said in a statement that</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 10:50:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Noise-control rules issued with jail terms</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-issues-strict-noise-control-rules-with-penalties-of-up-to-two-year-jail-term</link><description>The government has issued a sweeping set of noise-control regulations that fix daytime and night-time sound limits by area type, replacing the 2006 rules and introducing penalties of up to two years’ imprisonment for violations.
The environment ministry published the gazette on Tuesday, form</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 11:05:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No woman is safe until all women are safe: Commonwealth SG</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/no-woman-is-safe-until-all-women-are-safe-commonwealth-sg</link><description>Commonwealth Secretary-General Shirley Botchwey on Tuesday said no woman is safe until all women are safe and that safety begins where fear ends—in their homes, neighbourhoods, communities and countries.
“Violence against women is perhaps one of humanity’s oldest and least punish</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 11:20:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NID correction suspended; not NID services: EC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nid-correction-suspended-not-nid-services-ec</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has clarified that the NID correction and voting address transfer services remain halted, but all other NID-related services will continue as usual ahead of the upcoming national election.
"We have temporarily stopped the NID correction process to prepare the final vot</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 11:35:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Foreign firms in Ctg Port: HC verdict Dec 4</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/high-court-to-deliver-verdict-on-foreign-deal-for-chattogram-port-on-dec-4</link><description>The High Court has set Dec 4 for announcing the verdict on a petition challenging the legality of the ongoing process of signing an agreement with a foreign company to operate the New Mooring Container Terminal (NCT) of Chattogram Port.
The bench of Justice Fatema Najib and Justice Fatema Anwar se</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 11:50:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Walton Digital Campaign Season-23 kicks off</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/walton-digital-campaign-season-23-kicks-off</link><description>Centring the winter season, the country's superbrand Walton has started the 'Digital Campaign Season-23' nationwide. Like the previous campaign, there are special offers for the buyers of Walton products, including fridge, TV, air conditioner, washing machine and BLDC fan, this season.
Under the '</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 12:05:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Council of Advisers approves draft of Referendum Ordinance</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/council-of-advisers-approves-draft-of-referendum-ordinance</link><description>The Council of Advisers on Tuesday in principle approved the draft of the ‘Referendum Ordinance, 2025’ outlining how the referendum will be conducted.
“We hope the relevant gazette will be issued by today or tomorrow,” Law Adviser Dr Asif Nazrul told reporters at the Foreig</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 12:20:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US and Russia hold peace talks in Abu Dhabi as missiles pound Kyiv</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-and-russia-hold-peace-talks-in-abu-dhabi-as-missiles-pound-kyiv</link><description>U.S. Army Secretary Dan Driscoll held talks on late on Monday and Tuesday with Russian officials in Abu Dhabi as part of an intense new push by President Donald Trump's administration to end the war in Ukraine, Driscoll's spokesperson said.
U.S. and Ukrainian officials are trying to narrow the gap</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 12:35:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bag on metro line halts trains</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dhaka-metro-services-disrupted-for-20-minutes-after-bag-falls-on-track</link><description>Train services on the metro line were suspended for 20 minutes after a bag was found on the track between Secretariat and Motijheel stations.
Md Ahsan Ullah, deputy project director (Public Relations) of Dhaka Metro Rail, said the service resumed once the bag was removed.
Operations had been halt</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 12:50:23 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>