<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 17:21:04 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Deadly cyclone dents Sri Lanka's peak tourism season</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/deadly-cyclone-dents-sri-lankas-peak-tourism-season</link><description>November to January are usually the busiest season for Herath Gedara Rohan Anil Kumara’s three-bedroom homestay in Sri Lanka’s hill country, famed for its tea plantations, historic sites and quaint villages.
But after Cyclone Ditwah tore through the island last week, killing nearly 500</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 14:09:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>JU changes hall names</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/four-jahangirnagar-university-halls-shed-sheikh-family-names</link><description>Jahangirnagar University has renamed four of its residential halls previously bearing the Sheikh family’s names.
One of the halls has been named after Felani Khatun, a 15-year-old Bangladeshi girl killed by India’s border guards in 2011 at Kurigram, causing national outrage.
The decis</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 14:24:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Misguided, emotion-driven decisions affected jute industry in the past: Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/misguided-emotion-driven-decisions-affected-jute-industry-in-the-past-adviser</link><description>Commerce, Textile and Jute and Civil Aviation and Tourism Adviser Sk. Bashir Uddin said that no misguided or emotion-driven decisions will be made in the textile sector, noting that such decisions had affected the jute industry in the past.
"We aim to achieve the export target of USD 100 billion t</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 14:39:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Lioness brought back into Dhaka zoo cage 2.5 hours after escape</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/lioness-brought-back-into-dhaka-zoo-cage-25-hours-after-escape</link><description>Authorities have managed to bring the lioness that escaped at Mirpur Zoo back into its cage.
The zoo’s Director Rafiqul Islam Talukder said the animal was tranquilised and returned to its cage at 7pm on Friday.
The lioness had escaped around 4:45pm.
The director had said immediately after</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 14:54:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Eastern Bank launches ‘EBL Priority Next Gen’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/eastern-bank-launches-ebl-priority-next-gen</link><description>Eastern Bank PLC (EBL) unveils EBL Priority Next Gen, a bespoke banking segment created for the next generation of achievers—young visionaries poised to carry forward the values, ambition and legacy of EBL’s Priority families at an exclusive launch evening at Sky Ballroom at Le Meridian</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 15:09:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khaleda’s London medical trip 'depends on her health condition'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/khaledas-london-medical-trip-depends-on-her-health-condition</link><description>The plan to take critically ill BNP Chairperson Khaleda Zia to London for advanced treatment now depends on her health condition, as the Emir of Qatar has arranged a special air ambulance from Germany after technical issues with the earlier one.
The medical board treating the BNP chief decided on</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 15:24:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Democracy liberated as autocrat defeated on Dec 6 in 1990: Tarique Rahman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/democracy-liberated-as-autocrat-defeated-on-dec-6-in-1990-tarique-rahman</link><description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman on Friday said that autocracy was defeated on December 6, 1990 in the country which resulted in liberation of democracy.
In a post on his verified Facebook page, he said, “December 6 is an unforgettable day. On this day in 1990, the era of autocracy came to</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 15:39:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prison sentence during AL tenure responsible for Khaleda’s illness: Fakhrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/prison-sentence-during-al-tenure-responsible-for-khaledas-illness-fakhrul</link><description>BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir has alleged that party chief Khaleda Zia’s long-running health complications began during her two-year imprisonment under the Awami League government.
He described it as the result of “criminal negligence” and a lack of proper med</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 15:54:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Officers attacked for seizing falsely declared goods: NBR</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/officers-attacked-for-seizing-falsely-declared-goods-nbr</link><description>The National Board of Revenue (NBR) believes a group angered by recent measures to prevent the release of falsely declared goods may have been behind the attack on two customs officers in Chattogram.
In a statement issued on Friday, the NBR said it appeared that “officers have come under att</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 16:15:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP supporters block bridge over Munshiganj-3 ticket</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bnp-supporters-block-bridge-over-munshiganj-3-ticket</link><description>Supporters of Mahiuddin Ahmed, member-secretary of the Munshiganj district BNP, blocked the Mukterpur Bridge for an hour and a half on Friday, demanding a change in the party’s nomination for the Munshiganj-3 (Sadar–Ghazaria) constituency.
The BNP has nominated Kamruzzaman Ratan, the p</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 16:30:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>8 injured in BNP factional clashes over Munshiganj-3 nomination</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/8-injured-in-bnp-factional-clashes-over-munshiganj-3-nomination</link><description>At least eight people, including a woman, were injured in clashes between two factions of the BNP in Gazaria on Friday evening over the party’s nomination for the Munshiganj-3 constituency. Several vehicles and a private office were vandalised during the violence, prompting authorities to dep</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 16:45:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The digital manufacture of dreams</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/the-digital-manufacture-of-dreams</link><description>Across the developing world, migration has long been a pathway to economic mobility, a strategy for families seeking stability or upward movement. But in recent years, a new force has reshaped how young people think about leaving home. Social media platforms such as TikTok, YouTube and Facebook are</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 17:00:45 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>