<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 10:26:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Want to act as real referee in election: CEC Nasir</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/want-to-act-as-real-referee-in-election-cec-nasir</link><description>Chief Election Commissioner AMM Nasir Uddin on Thursday said the Election Commission wants to act as a true referee in the upcoming national election, emphasising the need for cooperation from all political parties.
"You (political parties) will play in the elections. You are the players. We reall</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 06:30:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>We live in the timeless world of Humayun Ahmed</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/entertainment/we-live-in-the-timeless-world-of-humayun-ahmed-1</link><description>Some names remain unchanged even when time passes. One such name is Humayun Ahmed. His words, his stories, and his characters are still alive. People read him, watch him, and talk about him even more than when he was alive.
Humayun Ahmed began his writing career in the 1970s. His first novel, Nond</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 06:45:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Security beefed up at tribunal, across Dhaka ahead of Hasina verdict date</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/security-beefed-up-at-tribunal-across-dhaka-ahead-of-hasina-verdict-date</link><description>Authorities have beefed up security at the International Crimes Tribunal (ICT) ahead of the announcement of the verdict date in a crimes against humanity case against ousted prime minister Sheikh Hasina.
A three-member bench of the ICT led by Justice Md Golam Mortuza Mozumder will set the date on</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 07:00:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US ends penny-making run after more than 230 years</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/others/us-ends-penny-making-run-after-more-than-230-years</link><description>The US is set to make its final penny.
The Philadelphia Mint will strike its last batch of one-cent coins on Wednesday, after more than 230 years of production.
The coins will remain in circulation, but the phase-out has already prompted businesses to start adjusting prices, as they say pennies a</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 07:15:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>JU’s first-year admission tests to begin on Dec 21</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/jus-first-year-admission-tests-to-begin-on-dec-21</link><description>Jahangirnagar University (JU) will begin its admission tests for first-year students of the 2025-26 academic session (55th batch) on December 21, said JU's acting registrar ABM Azizur Rahman on Wednesday.
Regarding the schedule for individual units, Azizur Rahman said, "No decision has been taken</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 07:30:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hope for exemplary maximum punishment for Hasina, says Chief Prosecutor Tajul Islam</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hope-for-exemplary-maximum-punishment-for-hasina-says-chief-prosecutor-tajul-islam</link><description>Chief Prosecutor Tajul Islam says he expects the International Crimes Tribunal to give the maximum punishment to ousted prime minister Sheikh Hasina and her former home minister Asaduzzaman Khan Kamal in a case of crimes against humanity for trying to suppress the July Uprising.
A three-member Int</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 07:45:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New French envoy meets Fakhrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/new-french-envoy-meets-fakhrul</link><description>Newly appointed French Ambassador to Bangladesh Jean-Marc Sere-Charlet met BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir on Thursday and discussed Bangladesh's current political situation and the upcoming national election.
The hour-long meeting began around 12pm at the BNP Chairperson's offic</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 08:00:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sabotage attempt on Dhaka-Chattogram rail tracks foiled in Feni</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/sabotage-attempt-on-dhaka-chattogram-rail-tracks-foiled-in-feni</link><description>Suspected saboteurs cut down trees and placed them on the Dhaka-Chattogram railway tracks in the Maheshpur area of Feni Sadar upazila early Thursday, but a major accident was averted thanks to the prompt action of the Railway Engineering Department.
According to railway police, a routine early-mor</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 08:30:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two dead, 18 hurt in South Korea after truck crashes into market, media reports say</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/two-dead-18-hurt-in-south-korea-after-truck-crashes-into-market-media-reports-say</link><description>A light truck crashed into a market in South Korea on Thursday, ploughing 150 metres (164 yards) along a passageway lined with stalls before coming to a halt, killing two people and injuring 18, according to emergency officials and media reports.
The incident took place at a market located in Buch</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 08:45:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>President signs July Charter Implementation Order: Office</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/president-signs-july-charter-implementation-order-office</link><description>President Md Shahabuddin has signed the July National Charter Implementation Order.
An official from the president’s office told bdnews24.com the information on Thursday afternoon.
A referendum will be held in accordance with this order. The referendum will give the people’s verdict o</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 09:00:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Election, referendum to be held on same day: Yunus</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/election-referendum-to-be-held-on-same-day-yunus</link><description>Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus has announced that the upcoming national election and referendum will be held on the same day as part of the implementation process of the July National Charter.
He made the announcement in a televised address to the nation at 2:30 pm on Thursday, following a</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 09:45:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BTV to get autonomy as part of institutional reforms: Mahfuj Alam</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/btv-to-get-autonomy-as-part-of-institutional-reforms-mahfuj-alam</link><description>Information and Broadcasting Adviser Md. Mahfuj Alam today (Thursday) said that the journey of a new Bangladesh began through the sacrifices of the martyrs and the injured of the July Revolution in 2024.
"The spirit of this revolution is guiding us on the path of building a discrimination-free, ju</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 10:00:59 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>