<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 17:19:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>EC clears 58 candidates for Feb polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/whore-back-in-the-race-ec-clears-58-candidates-for-feb-polls</link><description>The Election Commission on Sunday cleared the way for 58 previously rejected aspirants to contest the upcoming national election on February 12.
Among them is Nagorik Oikya convener Mahmudur Rahman Manna for Bogura-2, two Jamaat-e-Islami nominees for Chandpur-2 and Bogura-2, and six Jatiya Party a</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 14:00:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pakistan keen to host Tigers for WC: Report</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/pakistan-offers-to-host-bangladeshs-world-cup-games-if-sri-lanka-venues-unavailable-geo-news</link><description>In a twist of events, Pakistan Cricket Board has expressed willingness to host Bangladesh’s T20 World Cup matches should co-host Sri Lanka be unable to provide suitable venues, according to Geo News.
With less than a month to go before the T20 World Cup, Bangladesh’s request to move it</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 14:15:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Qatar and UAE to join US-led effort to bolster technology supply chain</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/qatar-and-uae-to-join-us-led-effort-to-bolster-technology-supply-chain</link><description>Qatar and the United Arab Emirates will soon join a US-led initiative to secure AI and semiconductor supply chains, Undersecretary of State for Economic Affairs Jacob Helberg told Reuters in an interview.
The addition of those two countries is notable given the Middle East’s history of polit</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 14:30:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Walton celebrates ICSB and ICMAB corporate award achievements</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/walton-celebrates-icsb-and-icmab-corporate-award-achievements</link><description>Walton has achieved the ‘ICSB National Award for Corporate Governance Excellence’ for five consecutive times and the ‘ICMAB Best Corporate Award’ four consecutive times.
To mark these achievements, Walton arranged a grand event titled “Celebrating Corporate Award Achi</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 14:52:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt. asks Hajj agencies to strictly follow Saudi instructions</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-asks-hajj-agencies-to-strictly-follow-saudi-instructions</link><description>The religious affairs ministry on Sunday asked Hajj agencies and airlines strictly follow the Saudi government instructions over pilgrimage management as the first aircraft carrying pilgrims to fly on April 18.
“The ministry today sent a letter to the Hajj agencies and the three airlines, en</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 15:07:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>HC upholds arbitration council approval for second marriage</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hc-upholds-arbitration-council-approval-for-second-marriage</link><description>The High Court has dismissed a writ petition challenging the requirement of obtaining permission from an arbitration council for a second marriage under Muslim family law.
As a result, the existing legal provision requiring council approval before contracting a second marriage remains in force, pe</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 15:22:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Anisul, associates face money laundering charges</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/former-law-minister-anisul-3-others-face-money-laundering-charges</link><description>The Criminal Investigation Department (CID) has filed a case accusing former law minister Anisul Huq and three of his associates of laundering about Tk 250 million.
The case was lodged with Bhatara Police on Sunday, the CID said in a statement.
The other suspects in the case are Towfika Karim, al</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 15:37:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UK’s former US envoy apologises to Epstein’s victims, not for his own ties</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/uks-former-us-envoy-apologises-to-epsteins-victims-not-for-his-own-ties</link><description>Britain’s former US ambassador Peter Mandelson, who was dismissed over his links to Jeffrey Epstein last year, apologised on Sunday to the victims of the late convicted sex offender but not for his own actions.
Mandelson was fired in September over emails that came to light revealing a much</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 15:52:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Israeli fire kills three people in Gaza, tension rises</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/israeli-fire-kills-three-people-in-gaza-tension-rises</link><description>Israeli fire killed at least three Palestinians in two separate incidents across the enclave, local health authorities said, as tension rises over continued violence.
Medics said one Palestinian was killed in the Tuffah neighbourhood in Gaza City, in an area under Palestinian control, while two ot</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 16:07:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh sees $1.12b in remittances in first 10 days of January</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh-sees-112b-in-remittances-in-first-10-days-of-january</link><description>The remittance from Bangladeshi expatriates continued its upward momentum in January, with the country receiving more than US$1.12 billion in the first 10 days of the month.
Bangladesh received $17.39 billion in inward remittances from July to January 10, 2026, in the current fiscal year, FY 2025-</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 16:22:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt cuts Tk 120b from top development projects over slow progress</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/govt-cuts-tk-120b-from-top-development-projects-over-slow-progress</link><description>The interim government is slashing allocations for several major development projects in the Revised Annual Development Programme (RADP), cutting over Tk 120 billion from eight of the top 10 priority projects due to slow progress and fiscal constraints.
According to planning ministry sources, allo</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 16:37:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cut default rate to 25pc by March: governor</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh-central-bank-chief-asks-banks-to-cut-default-loans-to-25-per-cent-by-march</link><description>Bangladesh Bank Governor Ahsan H Mansur has directed commercial banks to reduce their non-performing loan (NPL) ratio to 25 percent by March, using a combination of restructuring, rescheduling, write-offs, and intensified recovery efforts.
The directive came during a meeting on Sunday with top exe</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 16:52:32 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>