<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 06:40:13 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>ACC to charge three serving bureaucrats</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/acc-to-charge-three-serving-bureaucrats</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) has decided to file separate cases against three serving bureaucrats for allegedly securing government jobs by submitting forged certificates to the Bangladesh Public Service Commission (BPSC).
According to ACC, it has approved the initiation of cases under Rul</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 04:16:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Abu Sayed murder verdict any day</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/abu-sayed-murder-verdict-any-day</link><description>The International Crimes Tribunal-2 (ICT-2) in Dhaka has concluded the trial proceedings in a crimes against humanity case filed over the killing of Begum Rokeya University, Rangpur (BRUR) student Abu Sayed during the July-August 2024 mass uprising.
The tribunal has set the case for verdict, which</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 04:31:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh bans motorcycles nationwide three days before election, referendum</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-bans-motorcycles-nationwide-three-days-before-election-referendum</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has imposed a three-day ban on motorcycle movement across the country ahead of the parliamentary election and referendum.
In a letter sent to the Ministry of Road Transport and Bridges on Tuesday, the commission instructed the authorities to take necessary measures to</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 04:46:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nagorik Oikko's Manna says BNP obstructing campaign, issuing threats</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/nagorik-oikkos-manna-says-bnp-obstructing-campaign-issuing-threats</link><description>Nagorik Oikko Convenor Mahmudur Rahman Manna has alleged that BNP activists are obstructing his election campaign and issuing threats in Bogura-2 constituency.
Manna made the allegations at a press conference at the Bogura Press Club around 8:30pm on Tuesday.
He said attempts to harass him began</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 05:01:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt to meet stakeholders again on Feb 3 over yarn bond exclusion</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/govt-to-meet-stakeholders-again-on-feb-3-over-yarn-bond-exclusion</link><description>The government will meet stakeholders again on February 3 as the major parties have failed to reach any consensus on the exclusion of the yarn-import bond facility.
The parties are the Bangladesh Textile Mills Association (BTMA), the Bangladesh Garment Manufacturers and Exporters Association (BGME</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 05:16:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Deputy chief minister of India's Maharashtra dies in plane crash</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/deputy-chief-minister-of-indias-maharashtra-dies-in-plane-crash</link><description>The deputy chief minister of India's western state of Maharashtra, Ajit Pawar, was killed on Wednesday as his charter aircraft went down in flames, television channels said.
Video showed billows of smoke rising from some of the burning wreckage of the plane, scattered across an open field.
Media</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 05:31:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gold vaults past $5,200 as dollar plunges</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/gold-vaults-past-5200-as-dollar-plunges</link><description>Gold broke through $5,200 for ​the first time on Wednesday, after rising more than 3.0 per cent on Tuesday, as ‌the dollar plunged to a near four-year low amid persisting geopolitical concerns, ahead of a US Federal Reserve monetary policy decision.
Spot gold jumped 1.1 per cent to $5,243.58</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 05:18:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Indian parliament to pay tribute to Khaleda Zia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/indian-parliament-to-pay-tribute-to-khaleda-zia</link><description>The Rajya Sabha, India’s upper house of parliament, is to pay tribute to former Bangladesh prime minister and late BNP chief Khaleda Zia.
According to Wednesday’s agenda, condolence motions will be moved for three people, including Khaleda, during a session commemorating the deceased.</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 05:33:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Armed men abduct six farmers from Teknaf hills</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/armed-men-abduct-six-farmers-from-teknaf-hills</link><description>Armed men have abducted six farmers from the hilly area of Whykong in Cox’s Bazar’s Teknaf Upazila.
The incident occurred on Tuesday afternoon in the hills adjacent to Kombonia Para and Minabazar, said Sub-Inspector (SI) Khokon Kanti Rudra, chief of the local police outpost.
The abduc</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 05:48:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Over 70000 flee northwestern Pakistan over fears of military operation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/over-70000-flee-northwestern-pakistan-over-fears-of-military-operation</link><description>More than 70,000 people, mostly women and children, have fled a remote region in northwestern Pakistan bordering Afghanistan over uncertainty of a military operation against the Pakistani Taliban, residents and officials said Tuesday.
Pakistan's Defense Minister Khawaja Mohammad Asif has denied th</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 06:03:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Five to die for murder of Gopalganj transport union leader Basu</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/five-to-die-for-murder-of-gopalganj-transport-union-leader-basu</link><description>A Dhaka court has sentenced five people to death for the 2016 murder of Saidur Rahman Basu, a former president of the Gopalganj Motor Workers Union.
Dhaka Speedy Trial Tribunal-1 Judge Md Rohibul Islam delivered the verdict in the case on Wednesday.
The death-row convicts are Bulbul Sheikh, Heday</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 06:18:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC restricts watercraft movement on polling day</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-restricts-watercraft-movement-on-polling-day</link><description>Ahead of the 13th Jatiya Sangsad election and referendum, the Election Commission (EC) has imposed restrictions on the movement of certain watercrafts on the polling day as well as before and after it.
In a letter isasued on Tuesday, the EC said in view of the polls, the movement of launches and e</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 06:33:01 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>