<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 14:23:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Malaysian High commissioner visits CSE</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/malaysian-high-commissioner-visits-cse</link><description>Mohd Shuhada Othman, High Commissioner of Malaysia to Bangladesh recently visited CSE head office in Chattogram.
CSE Managing Director M. Shaifur Rahman Mazumdar, FCA, FCMA, briefed the High Commissioner in detail through a presentation about CSE’s contribution, current role and future devel</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 11:20:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC issues gazette granting party registration to NCP, BaSaD Marxist</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ec-issues-gazette-granting-party-registration-to-ncp-basad-marxist</link><description>With the 13th parliamentary election approaching, the Election Commission (EC) has granted party registration to the National Citizen Party (NCP) and Bangladesher Samajtantrik Dal Marxist.
EC Secretary Akhtar Ahmed told journalists at a briefing on Tuesday afternoon at EC headquarters that a forma</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 11:15:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>World Bank delegation meets Jamaat Ameer</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/world-bank-delegation-meets-jamaat-ameer</link><description>A World Bank delegation held a meeting with Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami Ameer Dr Shafiqur Rahman on Tuesday.
The meeting was held at the Jamaat chief’s office in Bashundhara, Dhaka.
The delegation was led by Jean-Denis Pesme, Country Director of the World Bank’s Dhaka Regional Office.</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 11:30:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Record number of first-time voters to vote, AL can’t participate: Prof Yunus</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/record-number-of-first-time-voters-to-vote-al-cant-participate-prof-yunus</link><description>Chief Adviser Prof Muhammad Yunus on Tuesday said a record number of young people would cast their first ballots in the upcoming national election, as they had been unable to vote in the three rigged general elections held under the previous autocratic regime.
He said the Awami League would not be</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 11:45:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Number of voters in Bangladesh stands at 127 million</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/number-of-voters-in-bangladesh-stands-at-127-million</link><description>Bangladesh is entering the election season with a voter roll nearing the 130-million mark, after the Election Commission (EC) confirmed a final count of 127.69 million eligible citizens for next February’s general election.

The figures -- detailed at a Tuesday briefing by EC Secretary Akht</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 12:00:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dengue claims 4 more lives, 920 hospitalised in 24 hours</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dengue-claims-4-more-lives-920-hospitalised-in-24-hours</link><description>Four more deaths were reported from dengue in 24 hours till Tuesday morning, raising the number of fatalities from the mosquito-borne disease in Bangladesh to 343 this year.
During the period, 920 more patients were hospitalised with viral fever, raising the total infected-case to 86, 924 this yea</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 12:15:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Four ‘human traffickers’ held in Teknaf raid</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/four-human-traffickers-held-in-teknaf-raid</link><description>Border Guard Bangladesh (BGB) has arrested four suspected human traffickers during a raid in Cox’s Bazar’s Teknaf.
Eight others, including two children were rescued, in the operation, Lt Col Ashiqur Rahman, commander of the Teknaf-2 BGB battalion, said on Tuesday.
The detainees were i</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 12:30:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ukraine’s Zelensky plans Turkey visit to try to revive peace talks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/ukraines-zelensky-plans-turkey-visit-to-try-to-revive-peace-talks</link><description>President Volodymyr Zelensky said he planned to go to Turkey on Wednesday in an attempt to revive talks with Russia on how to end the war in Ukraine.
A Turkish source said that US special envoy Steve Witkoff would also visit Turkey on Wednesday and join the planned talks there with Zelensky.
&amp;ldq</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 12:30:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prime Bank signs agreement with Bangladesh Bank to avail Refinance Facility for Digital Nano Loans</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/prime-bank-signs-agreement-with-bangladesh-bank-to-avail-refinance-facility-for-digital-nano-loans</link><description>Prime Bank PLC. has signed an agreement with Bangladesh Bank to avail the central bank’s Refinance Facility for Digital Nano Loans.
The signing ceremony took place at the Bangladesh Bank office recently, according to a media release. 
Through this refinance scheme, Prime Bank will be a</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 12:45:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Five days to register for postal voting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/postal-voting-bangladeshi-expatriates-get-five-day-registration-slots</link><description>The Election Commission has given Bangladeshi expatriates five days to get registered on the postal voting app for participating in the next general election through the Postal Vote BD app.
After the launch on Tuesday, the postal voting registration will begin on Nov 19 in East Asia, South America</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 13:00:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>LDC graduation an opportunity to match growth with dignity: Lutfey Siddiqi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ldc-graduation-an-opportunity-to-match-growth-with-dignity-lutfey-siddiqi</link><description>Special Envoy for International Affairs Lutfey Siddiqi on Tuesday said Bangladesh’s graduation from LDC status is a chance to build a new kind of competitiveness, one based on value, skills, quality and fairness.
“This platform connects government, private sector and partners to shape</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 13:15:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump to welcome Saudi crown prince with offer of fighter jets, business deals</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-to-welcome-saudi-crown-prince-with-offer-of-fighter-jets-business-deals</link><description>U.S. President Donald Trump will roll out the red carpet for Saudi Arabia’s de facto ruler, Crown Prince Mohammed bin Salman, on Tuesday for a visit expected to advance the sale of F-35 fighter jets and a host of business deals with the kingdom.
It will be the first trip by bin Salman, widel</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 13:30:52 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>