<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 14:20:05 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nepal keen to import raw jute from Bangladesh: Nepalese Ambassador</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/nepal-keen-to-import-raw-jute-from-bangladesh-nepalese-ambassador</link><description>Nepalese Ambassador to Bangladesh Ghanashyam Bhandari on Thursday has requested the Bangladesh government to focus on the raw jute exports to meet the production needs of Nepal.
The Nepalese Ambassador came up with the urge while talking to the Commerce Adviser Sk. Bashir Uddin at the Secretariat.</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 11:32:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No major improvement in Bangladesh’s business climate: BBX survey</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/no-major-improvement-in-bangladeshs-business-climate-bbx-survey</link><description>Bangladesh’s business environment has seen little to no notable improvement over the past year, with conditions in several key areas actually deteriorating, according to the latest Business Climate Index (BBX) for FY2024-25.
The report shows that access to regulatory information, infrastruct</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 11:47:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>HSC exam results reflect reality: Dhaka Board chairman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hsc-exam-results-reflect-reality-dhaka-board-chairman</link><description>Professor Khondoker Ehsanul Kabir, chairman of the Bangladesh Inter-Education Board Coordination Committee and the Dhaka Education Board, today said this year’s Higher Secondary Certificate (HSC) examination results is “a reflection of reality.”
“Students have distanced the</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 12:02:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EU proposes 'flagship' defence projects to counter drones, protect eastern border</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/eu-proposes-flagship-defence-projects-to-counter-drones-protect-eastern-border</link><description>The European Commission on Thursday proposed four European flagship defence projects - including a counter-drone system and a plan to fortify the eastern border - as part of a drive to get the continent ready to defend itself by 2030.
The proposals, in a defence policy "roadmap", reflect fears fue</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 12:32:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>July Charter signing Friday; drone activity banned during ceremony</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/july-charter-signing-friday-drone-activity-banned-during-ceremony</link><description>The ‘July National Charter 2025’ is scheduled to be signed on Friday afternoon, with the interim government anticipating it will mark a moment of celebration by the nation.
The signing ceremony will take place at the South Plaza of the Jatiya Sangsad Bhaban. Ahead of the event, the Chi</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 12:47:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Why 4 leftist parties refuse to sign Charter?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/seven-key-objections-prompt-four-left-wing-parties-to-reject-july-charter</link><description>Four left-leaning political parties have reiterated their decision not to sign the July National Charter, citing seven specific reasons.
The parties said the Charter, which includes recommendations for state reforms and a pledge of commitments, omits the four fundamental principles of the existing</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 13:02:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CEPZ fire still raging; 19 units battling to bring blaze under control</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cepz-fire-still-raging-19-units-battling-to-bring-blaze-under-control</link><description>A massive fire that broke out at a garment factory inside the Chattogram Export Processing Zone (CEPZ) on Thursday afternoon is yet to be brought under control, with 19 firefighting units working to douse the blaze.
The fire broke around 2pm on the fifth and sixth floors of an eight-storey buildin</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 13:17:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>China blames US for global panic over rare earths controls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/china-blames-us-for-global-panic-over-rare-earths-controls</link><description>China on Thursday accused the US of stoking panic over its rare earth controls and said Treasury Secretary Scott Bessent had made "grossly distorted" remarks about a top Chinese trade negotiator, rejecting a White House call to roll back the curbs.
The official newspaper of the governing Communist</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 13:32:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chinese company signs agreement to invest in BEPZA Economic Zone</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/chinese-company-signs-agreement-to-invest-in-bepza-economic-zone</link><description>October4128 (BD) Ltd., a Chinese-owned company, signed an agreement on Thursday with the Bangladesh Export Processing Zones Authority (BEPZA) to invest US$ 19.72 million in establishing a high-end garments manufacturing facility at the BEPZA Economic Zone (BEPZA EZ) in Mirsharai, Chattogram.
Membe</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 13:47:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>48 officials appointed to Islami Bank under Hasina's direct order</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/48-officials-appointed-to-islami-bank-under-hasinas-direct-order</link><description>Recruitments at Islami Bank Bangladesh PLC occurred under the direct order of former prime minister Sheikh Hasina, with 48 officials appointed through such directives, according to sources within the bank.
Once regarded as one of the strongest private banks in Bangladesh, Islami Bank has slipped i</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 14:17:02 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>