<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 20:42:33 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>PM Tarique urges market restraint ahead of Ramadan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/pm-tarique-urges-market-restraint-ahead-of-ramadan</link><description>Prime Minister Tarique Rahman on Wednesday urged traders to exercise restraint in the market as the holy month of Ramadan is set to begin across the country on Thursday, warning against profiteering that could increase public suffering.
In a televised address to the nation at night, the Prime Mini</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 16:19:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka, Kathmandu reaffirm pledge to advance shared interests</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dhaka-kathmandu-reaffirm-pledge-to-advance-shared-interests</link><description>Visiting Nepalese Minister for Foreign Affairs Bala Nanda Sharma on Wednesday met Foreign Minister Dr Khalilur Rahman and both Ministers reaffirmed their commitment to work closely across bilateral, regional, and multilateral platforms, advancing the shared interests of the two countries and people</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 16:34:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BSS chief exits office after employee demonstration</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-sangbad-sangstha-chief-exits-office-after-employee-demonstration</link><description>The Managing Director (MD) and Chief Editor of Bangladesh News Agency (BSS) Mahbub Morshed has left the organisation’s Dhaka office following protests by journalists and staff.
The demonstration took place at the BSS Headquarters in Paltan on Wednesday, where a section of employees declared</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 16:49:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mahdi returns home, alleges ‘harassment’ in India</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/anti-discrimination-leader-mahdi-returns-to-dhaka-alleges-harassment-at-indian-airport</link><description>Mahdi Hasan, a leader of the anti-discrimination movement from Habiganj who alleged he was “detained” at an airport in India, has returned to Bangladesh.
Speaking after arriving home on Wednesday afternoon, he claimed he was harassed at an Indian airport and also faced questioning at D</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 17:04:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘We will defend national interest inch by inch’: Khalilur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/khalilur-promises-to-protect-national-interest-through-principled-balanced-diplomacy</link><description>Foreign Minister Khalilur Rahman has said the new government will conduct its foreign policy by firmly defending Bangladesh’s national interest, guided by five “core principles”.
Those principles, he said, are sovereign equality, respect for mutual independence, non-interference</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 17:19:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt appoints Saleh Shibli as PM’s press secretary, Ruman made deputy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-appoints-saleh-shibli-as-pms-press-secretary-ruman-made-deputy</link><description>Abu Abdullah M Saleh, widely known as Saleh Shibli, has been appointed press secretary to Prime Minister Tarique Rahman.
The Ministry of Public Administration issued a notification on Wednesday confirming his contractual appointment at secretary rank.
Atiqur Rahman Ruman, editor and publisher of</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 17:34:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ADP spending teeters to 21 per cent in seven months</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/adp-spending-teeters-to-21-per-cent-in-seven-months</link><description>Implementation of the Annual Development Programme (ADP) has slowed to one of its weakest levels in two decades, with only 21 percent of the allocation spent in the first seven months of the 2025-26 fiscal year.
Data released on Wednesday by the Implementation Monitoring and Evaluation Division sh</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 17:49:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt determined to break all syndicates of misdeeds</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-determined-to-break-all-syndicates-of-misdeeds</link><description>Prime Minister Tarique Rahman sets a strong tone of his government in his maiden address on Wednesday night with a vow that all syndicates of irregularities and misdeeds will be dismantled.



"Our government is determined to break all syndicates of irregularities and corruption," he said, afte</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 18:04:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Banking sector reform: a test for the new government</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/banking-sector-reform-a-test-for-the-new-government</link><description>The recent national election in Bangladesh has delivered a decisive political message. The Bangladesh Nationalist Party secured a huge majority. This is not an ordinary mandate. It reflects public frustration with economic instability and a strong desire for institutional reform. Voters have placed</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 18:19:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Market intervention: the case of TCB and OMS</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/market-intervention-the-case-of-tcb-and-oms</link><description>With the month of Ramadan fast approaching, the familiar annual spiral in the prices of essential commodities has already begun to make itself felt across the country, and with notable intensity.
Containing the seasonal and sporadic surges in the prices of daily necessities has long been a critica</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 18:34:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Overcoming tax reform challenges</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/overcoming-tax-reform-challenges</link><description>The Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) has taken the helm of the country at a time when the economy is caught on the horns of a fiscal dilemma. On the one hand, the new government has a plethora of election pledges to keep in areas such as infrastructure development, social welfare, education and h</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 18:49:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A new journey on course of democracy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/a-new-journey-on-course-of-democracy</link><description>Bangladesh has got a new government elected by the people in a largely clean and credible election. The Financial Express congratulates the new Prime Minister and the members of his Cabinet. That the people are pinning much hope on the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) is evident from the fact tha</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 19:04:47 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>