<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 09:20:59 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Two killed as bus rams motorcycle in Jashore</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/two-killed-as-bus-rams-motorcycle-in-jashore</link><description>Two motorcyclists were killed after a bus hit their motorcycle on Saturday night while they were on their way to visit a patient at Jashore General Hospital.
The accident occurred around 8:00 pm at Jagahati area on the Jashore-Chaugachha road, reports BSS.
The deceased were identified as Selim Ho</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 06:15:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Factory worker killed after being hit by train in Ctg</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/factory-worker-killed-after-being-hit-by-train-in-ctg</link><description>A factory worker was killed after being hit by a train in Mirsarai upazila of Chattogram on Saturday evening.
The accident occurred around 7:00 pm at the Chinki Astana Railway Station area on the Dhaka-bound track of the Dhaka-Chattogram rail line.
The deceased was identified as Tutul Kanti Dhar,</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 06:30:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Stocks edge up in early trading</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/stocks-edge-up-in-early-trading15983</link><description>The country’s bourses saw a positive start on Sunday as key indices in both Dhaka and Chattogram moved up during the first hour of trading, with most companies posting gains.
At the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE), the benchmark DSEX index rose by 3 points in early trading.
While the Shariah-bas</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 06:45:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Burnt body of woman found at roadside in Ctg</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/burnt-body-of-woman-found-at-roadside-in-ctg</link><description>Police have recovered the burnt body of an unidentified woman from the side of a road in Chattogram's Sitakunda.
The incident took place on Saturday night in the Abdullahghata area, close to the Dhaka–Chattogram Highway.
Police said that the initial accounts from witnesses suggest the woman</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 07:00:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>3 injured as motorcyclists attack Bangladesh-China Friendship Bridge toll plaza officers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/3-injured-as-motorcyclists-attack-bangladesh-china-friendship-bridge-toll-plaza-officers</link><description>At least three people have been injured after a group of young men have attacked toll plaza officers of the “Seventh Bangladesh-China Friendship Bridge” over the Arial Kha River in Madaripur after they asked them to pay a toll for their motorcycles.
The incident took place around 7pm o</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 07:20:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Young man found hanging at Rajshahi hotel</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/young-man-found-hanging-at-rajshahi-hotel</link><description>Police recovered the body of a 28-year-old man from a hotel room in New Market area in Rajshahi city on Saturday afternoon.
The deceased was identified as Sabuj Kumar Adhikari, hailed from Atgharia village in Raiganj upazila of Sirajganj district.
Hotel authorities said Sabuj was scheduled to che</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 07:50:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Deprived’ state-owned bank officers stage human chain</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/deprived-state-owned-bank-officers-stage-human-chain</link><description>Officers ‘deprived of promotion’ at state-owned Sonali, Agrani, Janata and Rupali banks formed a human chain in front of the Bangladesh Bank on Sunday, demanding an end to what they described as longstanding discrimination in career advancement.
The aggrieved officials alleged th</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 08:05:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two killed in gun attack outside Khulna court</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/two-killed-in-gun-attack-outside-khulna-court</link><description>Two people were shot dead when unidentified gunmen opened fire outside the Khulna District and Sessions Judge Court on Sunday. 
The deceased were identified as Rajon and Hasib of Bagmara in Rupsha upazila of the district. 
Shafiqul Islam, officer-in-charge of Sadar Police Station, said</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 08:20:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khaleda Zia responding to treatment: Dr Zahid</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/khaleda-zia-responding-to-treatment-dr-zahid</link><description>BNP Chairperson Begum Khaleda Zia's personal physician and BNP Standing Committee Member Dr AZM Zahid Hossain said that Khaleda Zia is responding to the treatment being provided by her medical team.
"Madam Zia is maintaining the treatment. She is able to receive the procedures the doctors are admi</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 08:35:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump era cools Bangladesh's US study boom</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/trump-era-cools-bangladeshs-us-study-boom</link><description>The United States has always been one of the top choices for Bangladeshi students to pursue higher studies. According to the 2024 Open Doors Report on International Educational Exchange, published in November 2024, the number of Bangladeshi students in the United States represented a 26 per cent</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 08:50:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Over 7,000 take admission test as alumni to return for Lifelong Learning Series</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/over-7000-take-admission-test-as-alumni-to-return-for-lifelong-learning-series</link><description>North South University is experiencing a particularly active week, bringing together both prospective students and established graduates through two significant programmes. The Spring 2026 undergraduate admission test drew an exceptionally large turnout, whilst the School of Business and Economics</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 09:05:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fully funded int'l programmes open doors to Bangladeshi students</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/fully-funded-intl-programmes-open-doors-to-bangladeshi-students</link><description>Another round of government and multilateral scholarships opens for the 2026 academic year, creating a competitive but promising landscape for fully funded study abroad. From late 2025 to mid-2026, application windows will open for South Korea, the European Union, the United States, Australia, Japa</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 09:20:59 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>