<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 15:27:56 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Editors’ Council condemns case against Anis Alamgir</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/editors-council-condemns-case-against-anis-alamgir</link><description>The Editors’ Council on Monday strongly condemned the filing of a case under the Anti-Terrorism Act against journalist Anis Alamgir, alleging that he was summoned to the Detective Branch (DB) office without any specific allegation.
In a statement, Editors’ Council President Nurul Kabir</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 13:39:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Returning officers asked to finalise panels of polling officers by December 18</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/returning-officers-asked-to-finalise-panels-of-polling-officers-by-december-18</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has directed the returning officers (ROs) to finalise the panels of polling officers in line with the fixed guidelines by December 18 next for the upcoming national election and the referendum on the July Charter, scheduled to be held simultaneously on February 12, 2026</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 13:54:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chilean investors cheer election of Kast as president</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/chilean-investors-cheer-election-of-kast-as-president</link><description>The Chilean peso strengthened against the US dollar on Monday after right-wing hardliner Jose Antonio Kast was elected president in a commanding runoff win against leftist candidate Jeannette Jara.
While the market had largely priced in a Kast win, his margin of victory - some 16 percentage points</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 14:09:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chief adviser releases commemorative postage stamp on Victory Day</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/chief-adviser-releases-commemorative-postage-stamp-on-victory-day</link><description>Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus has released a commemorative postage stamp on the occasion of the Great Victory Day.
He also released an opening day cover and a canceller at a ceremony at the State Guest House Jamuna in Dhaka on Monday afternoon, said the Chief Adviser’s Press Wing.</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 13:09:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Special policy issued on gun licences for election candidates</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/special-policy-issued-on-gun-licences-for-election-candidates</link><description>The government has issued a policy to allow “politically important” individuals and election candidates to obtain firearms licences and hire retainers (gunmen).
Following the shooting of Inqilab Moncho spokesperson Sharif Osman bin Hadi, the home advisor announced special security for</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 13:24:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>20 hurt in clashes between BNP, Jamaat in Bhola</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/20-hurt-in-clashes-between-bnp-jamaat-in-bhola</link><description>At least 20 people have suffered injuries in repeated clashes between the Jamaat-e-Islami and BNP activists in Bhola’s Char Fasson Upazila.
The incident occurred at Chawkbazar in Zinnagor Union on Monday, according to Char Fasson Police chief (OC) Jahangir Badsha.
The clash escalated furthe</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 13:39:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ex-Jubo League leader held in Magura</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/former-jubo-league-leader-arrested-after-buying-nomination-form-in-magura</link><description>Police have arrested a former Jubo League leader of Sreepur Upazila in Magura after he collected a nomination form to contest the national elections.
Former Upazila party president Kutubullah Hossain Mia Kuti collected nomination papers from the district returning officer’s office on Monday</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 13:54:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>British Council honours alumni at Study UK Alumni Awards 2026 in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/british-council-honours-alumni-at-study-uk-alumni-awards-2026-in-bangladesh</link><description>The British Council recently hosted the fourth edition of the prestigious Study UK Alumni Awards 2026 in Bangladesh, held at the Radisson Blu Water Garden Hotel, Dhaka.
Recently held on the awards recognised the remarkable work and achievements of alumni of UK higher education institutions across</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 14:09:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NEIR launch deferred to January 1</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/neir-launch-deferred-to-january-1</link><description>The Bangladesh Telecommunication Regulatory Commission (BTRC) has postponed the launch of the National Equipment Identification Register (NEIR) by 15 days, setting January 1 as the revised start date.
Previously scheduled for December 16, Victory Day, the launch had sparked protests from mobile ph</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 14:24:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Press Secretary sees no possibility of AL’s participation in election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/press-secretary-sees-no-possibility-of-als-participation-in-election</link><description>Apparently ruling out the possibility of the Awami League’s participation in the upcoming national election, Chief Adviser’s Press Secretary Shafiqul Alam on Monday said that no democratic country in the world would allow an organisation led by such a ‘terrible criminal’ to</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 14:39:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gaza struggles to pull bodies from rubble as storms rock damaged buildings</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/gaza-struggles-to-pull-bodies-from-rubble-as-storms-rock-damaged-buildings</link><description>Authorities in Gaza warned on Monday that more war-damaged buildings may collapse because of heavy rain in the devastated Palestinian enclave and said the weather was making it hard to recover bodies still under the rubble.
Two buildings collapsed in Gaza on Friday, killing at least 12 people acco</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 14:54:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Students lock CU administrative building over Pro-VC’s remarks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/students-lock-cu-administrative-building-over-pro-vcs-remarks</link><description>Students of Chittagong University (CU) on Monday locked the university’s administrative building demanding the removal of Pro-Vice Chancellor (Academic) Prof Mohammad Shamim Uddin Khan for his alleged controversial remarks over the killings of intellectuals in 1971.
Under the banner of Sarba</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 15:09:14 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>