<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 05:25:35 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>US tells Ukraine it must leave Donetsk for peace deal, source says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-tells-ukraine-it-must-withdraw-from-donetsk-region-for-peace-deal-says-person-familiar-with-talks</link><description>US negotiators have told Ukraine during peace talks in Berlin that it must agree to withdraw its forces from the eastern Donetsk region as part of any deal to end the nearly four-year-old war, an official familiar with the matter said.
The source, speaking on condition of anonymity as Ukrainian an</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 19:16:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Four major trade orgs to seek review of three amended provisos</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/four-major-trade-orgs-to-seek-review-of-three-amended-provisos</link><description>Four major trade bodies in Bangladesh's industrial realm seek a rethink on three key amended sections of the labour law as they believe such new provisos could adversely affect employment and hike the cost of doing business.



As planned, the organisations will initially request the reigning i</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 19:31:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CA pays homage to Liberation War martyrs on Victory Day</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ca-pays-homage-to-liberation-war-martyrs-on-victory-day</link><description>Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus on Tuesday paid rich tributes to the martyrs of the Liberation War by placing a wreath at the National Memorial here on the outskirts of the capital marking the 55th Victory Day.
He laid the wreath at the altar of the National Memorial around 6:56 am.
After</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 02:45:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jubo League leader hacked to death in Dakshinkhan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jubo-league-leader-hacked-to-death-in-dakshinkhan</link><description>A Jubo League leader has been hacked to death in a public gathering in Dhaka’s Dakshinkhan, according to police.
The dead has been identified as Shahjahan Sheikh, 46.
Police say the murder occurred at Taltola intersection at 8:45pm.
He was involved in several businesses. He was also the pr</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 03:00:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>President pays tributes to Liberation War heroes on Victory Day</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/president-pays-tributes-to-liberation-war-heroes-on-victory-day-1</link><description>President Mohammed Shahabuddin on Tuesday paid rich tributes to the martyrs of the 1971 Liberation War by placing a wreath at the National Memorial here, on the outskirts of the capital, marking the 55th Victory Day.
The Head of the State laid the wreath at the altar of the National Memorial with</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 03:15:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nation celebrates V-Day today amid new ambiance</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nation-celebrates-v-day-today-amid-new-ambiance</link><description>As the 16th December dawns today, the nation begins to celebrate the Victory Day marking Bangladesh’s liberation from the then Pakistani occupation this day 54 years ago through a nine-month bloodstained war.
On December 16 in 1971, as history says, Bangladesh was born as an independent coun</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 03:30:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hadi flown to Singapore by air ambulance</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hadi-flown-to-singapore-by-air-ambulance</link><description>An air ambulance carrying fatally-wounded Inqilab Mancha spokesperson Sharif Osman Hadi left for Singapore on Monday.
At 1:40pm, he was transferred to the air ambulance, which departed 10 minutes later.
Hadi will receive advanced treatment in Singapore.
Earlier, at 1:10pm, an ambulance carrying</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 03:45:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>LGD proposes Tk 9.79b project for 18 DSCC wards</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/lgd-proposes-tk-979b-project-for-18-dscc-wards</link><description>The Local Government Division (LGD) under the Ministry of Local Government, Rural Development and Co-operatives has submitted a Tk 9.79-billion-project proposal to upgrade 123.53 kilometres of local roads in 18 wards that were incorporated into Dhaka South City Corporation (DSCC) in 2016, sources a</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 04:00:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Past projects taking toll on state coffer</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/past-projects-taking-toll-on-state-coffer</link><description>State bank borrowing is swelling for having to fund the development projects undertaken by the fallen regime, as the interim government is in a double bind because ditching those will amount to twofold losses.
Finance Adviser of the post-uprising government Dr Salehuddin Ahmed Monday struck such d</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 04:15:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Health ministry’s poor show drags execution</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/health-ministrys-poor-show-drags-execution</link><description>Despite being the third-largest budget-holder, the Ministry of Health and Family Welfare has recorded the lowest project- implementation rate, affecting overall development progress and potentially slowing Bangladesh’s economic growth, officials said on Monday.
The slow performance has also</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 04:30:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Renata’s debt-reduction strategy may spur new entrants to secondary market</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/renatas-debt-reduction-strategy-may-spur-new-entrants-to-secondary-market</link><description>Renata’s listed preference shares, offering a 15 per cent return, may serve as an example for other companies seeking to reduce debt burdens while strengthening investor confidence.
To replace high-cost short-term loans with lower-cost, long-term funding, the drug manufacturer issued prefere</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 04:45:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bondi gunmen were inspired by Islamic State, had travelled to the Philippines, Australia police say</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/bondi-gunmen-were-inspired-by-islamic-state-had-travelled-to-the-philippines-australia-police-say</link><description>Two alleged gunmen who attacked a Hanukkah event at Sydney’s Bondi Beach had travelled to the Philippines before the assault which killed 15 people and appeared to be inspired by Islamic State, police said on Tuesday.
The attack on Sunday was Australia’s worst mass shooting in nearly 3</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 05:00:51 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>