<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 07:24:17 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Malaysia says search for flight MH370 to resume in Dec</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/malaysia-says-search-for-flight-mh370-to-resume-in-dec</link><description>The search for Malaysia Airlines flight MH370 will resume on December 30, the Transport Ministry said on Wednesday.
Exploration firm Ocean Infinity will recommence seabed search operations intermittently for a total of 55 days, the ministry said in a statement.
"The search will be carried out in</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 04:17:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>LaLiga leaders Barcelona fight back to beat Atletico 3-1</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/laliga-leaders-barcelona-fight-back-to-beat-atletico-3-1</link><description>Barcelona recovered to secure a 3-1 win over Atletico Madrid as goals from Raphinha, Dani Olmo and Ferran Torres handed the visitors their first LaLiga defeat since August and extended the champions' lead at the top after an intense clash on Tuesday.
The result puts Barca on 37 points, four ahead</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 04:32:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka Central Jail prisoner dies</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/dhaka-central-jail-prisoner-dies</link><description>A 75-year-old prisoner died after falling sick at Dhaka Central Jail on Tuesday night, the authorities said.
The deceased was identified as Abdul Matin, son of late Mirjan Ali. Details about him are yet to be known, UNB reports.
Prison officer Mirza Harun said Matin suddenly felt sick at night, p</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 04:47:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UK specialist Richard Beale arrives in Dhaka to assist in Khaleda’s treatment</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/uk-specialist-richard-beale-arrives-in-dhaka-to-assist-in-khaledas-treatment</link><description>Dr Richard Beale, a leading medical specialist from the United Kingdom, has arrived in Dhaka to assist with the treatment of BNP Chairperson and former prime minister Khaleda Zia.
Dr Beale, who heads a team of foreign medical experts, landed in Dhaka around 10:30 am on Wednesday and went straight</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 05:02:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump administration halts immigration applications for migrants from 19 travel-ban nations</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/trump-administration-halts-immigration-applications-for-migrants-from-19-travel-ban-nations</link><description>The Trump administration is pausing all immigration applications such as requests for green cards for people from 19 countries banned from travel earlier this year, as part of sweeping immigration changes in the wake of the shooting of two National Guard troops.
The changes were outlined in a poli</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 05:17:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Teachers announce 'complete shutdown' of primary schools</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/teachers-announce-complete-shutdown-of-primary-schools</link><description>Government primary school teachers in Bangladesh have announced a nationwide “complete shutdown” from Wednesday as part of their ongoing protest over pay and promotion demands.
The Primary Teachers’ Demand Implementation Council, which is leading the movement, made the announceme</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 05:32:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tetulia continues to witness lowest temperature</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tetulia-continues-to-witness-lowest-temperature</link><description>Tetulia continued to record the lowest temperature of the day at 11.1 degrees Celsius on Wednesday, while the Bangladesh Meteorological Department (BMD) has forecast generally dry weather with temporarily partly cloudy skies over most parts of the country during the next 24 hours, beginning at 9:00</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 05:47:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New-look Tk 500 banknote set to hit the market</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/new-look-tk-500-banknote-set-to-hit-the-market</link><description>Bangladesh Bank is releasing a new design for the Tk 500 note in the market. These new notes feature depictions of Bangladesh’s historic and archaeological landmarks
After the 2024 student-led mass uprising, the interim government decided to redesign all denominations of currency in circulat</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 06:02:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Arbitrary pricing’ turns Barapukuria coal into ‘windfall’ for staff, ‘financial burden’ for PDB</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/arbitrary-pricing-turns-barapukuria-coal-into-windfall-for-staff-financial-burden-for-pdb</link><description>For nearly a year, a domestic coal pricing dispute between Bangladesh’s Power Division and Energy Division has created friction between the state-owned Bangladesh Power Development Board (PDB) and the Barapukuria Coal Mining Company Limited (BCMCL).
At the heart of the conflict lies the pric</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 06:19:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Culvert repair forces single-track train movement, disrupting schedules at Kamalapur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/culvert-repair-forces-single-track-train-movement-disrupting-schedules-at-kamalapur</link><description>Services at Dhaka’s Kamalapur Railway Station have faced widespread delays after repair work on a culvert in Tejgaon forced all trains to operate on a single track for several hours.
Passengers arriving at the station on Wednesday said they were not informed of the disruption when purchasing</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 06:34:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India's Congress seeks parliament debate on state-run app for smartphones</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/indias-congress-seeks-parliament-debate-on-state-run-app-for-smartphones</link><description>India's main opposition party said on Wednesday that a government plan to preload a state-run app on smartphones violates the privacy of users and the government needed to explain itself, escalating tensions on a matter that has sparked surveillance fears.
The Indian government has confidentially</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 06:49:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Killing of 8 puppies: Ishwardi govt officer's wife arrested</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/killing-of-8-puppies-ishwardi-govt-officers-wife-arrested</link><description>Police have arrested a government officer's wife suspected of killing eight puppies that were stuffed into a sack and drowned in a pond in Pabna’s Ishwardi Upazila.
Nishi Rahman, 38, was detained on Tuesday in connection with a case filed by livestock officials under the Animal Welfare Act,</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 07:04:13 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>