<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 18:37:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Rapid, MRT Passes recharge facility via mobile app inaugurated</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rapid-mrt-passes-recharge-facility-via-mobile-app-inaugurated</link><description>Rapid Pass and MRT Passes for metro rail and other public transport systems can now be recharged online through a mobile app.
Chief Adviser’s Special Assistant for the Ministry of Road Transport and Bridges Sheik Moinuddin inaugurated the service at the conference room of the Dhaka Transport</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 16:00:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>43 products to get cash incentives for exports: BB</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/43-products-to-get-cash-incentives-for-exports-bb</link><description>In a strategic move to bolster the nation’s export earnings, Bangladesh Bank (BB) has announced a comprehensive package of export incentives and cash assistance across 43 different sectors.
The Foreign Exchange Policy Department-1 on Monday issued a circular detailing the rates applicable fo</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 15:45:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Turkey cautions against foreign intervention in Iran</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/turkey-cautions-against-foreign-intervention-in-iran</link><description>Turkey said on Monday that any foreign intervention in neighbouring Iran would lead to greater crises in the country and the region, and it called for US and Iranian negotiations to resolve existing problems.
Iran is facing its biggest demonstrations since 2022 and US President Donald Trump has th</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 16:00:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gold hits record high as prices jump by Tk 4,199 per bhori</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/gold-hits-record-high-in-bangladesh-as-prices-jump-by-tk-4199-per-bhori</link><description>Gold prices in Bangladesh soared to an all-time high as the Bangladesh Jewellers Association (BAJUS) raised the price of gold by Tk4,199 per bhori, effective from Tuesday morning.
Under the new rate, the price of 22-carat gold has been set at Tk232,055 per bhori (11.664 grams), the highest level e</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 16:15:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Greenland says it should be defended by NATO</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/greenland-says-it-should-be-defended-by-nato</link><description>Greenland's government said on Monday it will increase its efforts to ensure that the defence of the Arctic territory takes place under the auspices of NATO, and again rejected US President Donald Trump's ambition to take over the island.
Trump has said the United States must own Greenland, an aut</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 16:30:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Alphabet hits $4 trillion valuation as AI refocus lifts sentiment</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/alphabet-hits-4-trillion-valuation-as-ai-refocus-lifts-sentiment</link><description>Alphabet hit a $4 trillion market valuation on Monday, as the Google parent's sharpened artificial intelligence focus allayed doubts about its strategy and thrust it back to the forefront of the high-stakes race.
The tech giant on Wednesday surpassed Apple in market capitalisation for the first ti</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 16:45:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>41 regain candidacy, 24 rejected on third day of appeal hearings</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/41-regain-candidacy-24-rejected-on-third-day-of-appeal-hearings</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has approved 41 petitions on the third day of appeal hearings challenging returning officers’ decisions on nomination papers for the national election.
EC spokesperson Ruhul Amin Mollik said on Monday that 24 petitions were rejected during the hearings, while fou</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 17:00:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ACC files two cases against former CMP CT unit officer, wife and sisters over Tk 611.9 million illicit wealth</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/acc-files-two-cases-against-former-cmp-ct-unit-officer-wife-and-sisters-over-tk-6119-million-illicit-wealth</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) on Monday filed two separate cases against former Deputy Commissioner of Chattogram Metropolitan Police’s Counter Terrorism Unit, Md Hamidul Alam, his wife and three sisters over allegations of acquiring illicit wealth worth Tk61.19 crore.
ACC Director Ge</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 17:16:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>People want jobs plan, not promises, experts say</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/people-want-jobs-plan-not-promises-experts-say</link><description>Employment has emerged as the top concern for Bangladeshis, with citizens expecting political parties to offer clear, realistic and actionable plans rather than vague promises before the general election.
This message came from a roundtable jointly organised by Democracy International (DI) and The</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 17:31:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ICC sees no specific threat to Tigers in India</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/bangladesh-face-no-exceptional-threat-for-t20-wc-participation-in-india-says-icc-review</link><description>The Bangladesh team are not subject to any unusual or serious security risks while playing in India for the 2026 T20 World Cup, according to an ICC assessment shared with the Bangladesh Cricket Board (BCB).
The review identifies low to moderate risk levels at certain venues, which are part of rout</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 17:46:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC bars polls to all bodies, associations before Feb 12 elections done</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-bars-polls-to-all-bodies-associations-before-feb-12-elections-done</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has directed the authorities concerned not to allow elections of any organisation or association, including professional bodies, across the country before the 13th parliamentary election scheduled for February 12, 2026 - the same day as a key referendum. 
The Comm</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 18:01:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Health, education allocations face staggering cut</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/health-education-allocations-face-staggering-cut</link><description>Health and education sectors have taken the major brunt of a sizeable cut in the current development budget halfway through the fiscal year.   
The ongoing Annual Development Programme (ADP) outlay for the fiscal year 2025-26 has been cut by 13.04 per cent to Tk 2.0 trillion.
With</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 18:16:10 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>