<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 07:19:22 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>United Finance partners with IFC to expand housing and SME financing</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/united-finance-partners-with-ifc-to-expand-housing-and-sme-financing</link><description>United Finance has entered into a strategic partnership with the International Finance Corporation (IFC) to strengthen its capabilities in affordable home loans and SME financing in Bangladesh.
The agreement was signed at United Finance’s Head Office in Dhaka, says a media release.
Mohammad</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 04:55:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ISPs carrying out DDoS attacks to face stern action</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/isps-carrying-out-ddos-attacks-to-face-stern-action</link><description>The government has moved to take stern action against several internet service providers (ISPs) after receiving credible evidence that some of them organised distributed denial-of-service (DDoS) attacks from abroad to sabotage rival networks and disrupt competition in Bangladesh's internet market.</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 05:10:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Touhid seeks reopening of Bahraini visa for Bangladeshi citizens</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/touhid-seeks-reopening-of-bahraini-visa-for-bangladeshi-citizens</link><description>Foreign Affairs Adviser Md. Touhid Hossain requested that Bahrain to reopen visa facilities for Bangladeshi citizens, including businesspeople, professionals, and skilled and semi-skilled workers, to enhance people-to-people contact and strengthen economic engagement between the two countries.
He</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 05:40:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCP to Hold Emergency Press Conference</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ncp-to-hold-emergency-press-conference</link><description>The National Citizens Party (NCP) has called an emergency press conference to discuss the current political situation in the country.
According to a press release issued by the party’s media cell secretary and joint member secretary Mushfiqur Us Salehin, the briefing will take place at 12 no</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 05:55:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rain, thundershowers likely in parts of country</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rain-thundershowers-likely-in-parts-of-country-14252</link><description>Rain or thundershowers are likely to occur in different parts of the country, the Bangladesh Meteorological Department (BMD) said in its weather forecast issued at 9:00 am today (Sunday).
“Light to moderate rain or thundershowers are likely at a few places over Barishal, Chattogram and Sylhe</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 06:10:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka police apologise for traffic chaos amid protests</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dhaka-police-apologise-for-traffic-chaos-amid-protests</link><description>Police have expressed regret over severe traffic congestion in Dhaka, attributing it to protests across the city by several groups.
In a statement on Sunday, the Dhaka Metropolitan Police (DMP) said that multiple organisations launched demonstrations simultaneously to press for various demands, di</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 07:10:01 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>