<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 17:20:28 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>ADB-funded entrepreneur development training launched in Manikganj</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/adb-funded-entrepreneur-development-training-launched-in-manikganj</link><description>A month-long Entrepreneur Development Training Program has been launched in Manikganj under the ‘Skills for Industry Competitiveness and Innovation Program (SICIP)’, implemented by the Finance Division of the Ministry of Finance with financial support from the Asian Development Bank (AD</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 15:07:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BUET undergraduate applications open on Nov 16</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/buet-undergraduate-applications-open-on-nov-16</link><description>Applications for admission to undergraduate programmes at the Bangladesh University of Engineering and Technology (BUET) for the 2025-26 academic year will run from Nov 16 through to Dec 2.
According to the admission circular issued on Monday, applicants will be able to submit the fees until Dec 4</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 15:22:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Community Bank launches Community SME 360° to empower SMEs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/community-bank-launches-community-sme-360-to-empower-smes</link><description>Community Bank Bangladesh PLC has announced the official launch of “Community SME 360°,” a pioneering, all-in-one platform designed to accelerate the growth and success of small and medium enterprises (SMEs) across Bangladesh.
This landmark initiative represents a transformative st</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 15:37:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nigerian Nobel laureate Wole Soyinka says US revokes his visa</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/nigerian-nobel-laureate-wole-soyinka-says-us-revokes-his-visa</link><description>Nigeria's Nobel Prize-winning author Wole Soyinka said on Tuesday the United States had revoked his non-immigrant visa issued last year and he was told to re-apply if he wished to try again to visit the US.
The 91-year-old writer said in 2016 that he had torn up his US green card and renounced his</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 15:50:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hamas to hand over another body after Israel says remains were not of missing hostage</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/hamas-to-hand-over-another-body-after-israel-says-remains-were-not-of-missing-hostage</link><description>Hamas said it would hand over to Israel on Tuesday the body of a missing hostage found in a tunnel in Gaza, after Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu accused the militant group of violating the ceasefire in the enclave by turning over the wrong remains.
Netanyahu earlier on Tuesday said tests had sh</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 16:20:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EU to send major observation team for Bangladesh election, ambassador says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/eu-to-send-major-observation-team-for-bangladesh-election-ambassador-says</link><description>The European Union will deploy a large team of observers to monitor Bangladesh’s general elections in February, Ambassador Michael Miller told Chief Advisor Muhammad Yunus.
He confirmed the development at the State Guest House Jamuna on Tuesday, a statement from the Chief Advisor’s Off</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 16:35:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump's 'hot truck' becomes symbol of Japan trade talks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trumps-hot-truck-becomes-symbol-of-japan-trade-talks</link><description>Long associated with American ruggedness, pickup trucks such as Ford's top-selling F-150 have now become a symbol of international trade talks, showing how far countries such as Japan will go to win over US President Donald Trump.
When Trump met Japan's new prime minister and first female premier,</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 16:50:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gold price falls below Tk 200 thousand per bhori after fourth consecutive cut</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/gold-price-falls-below-tk-200-thousand-per-bhori-after-fourth-consecutive-cut</link><description>The price of gold in Bangladesh has fallen below Tk 200 thousand per bhori (11.664 grams) after the Bangladesh Jewellers Association (BAJUS) announced its fourth consecutive price reduction.
According to a BAJUS press release issued on Tuesday night, the price of 22-carat gold has been reduced by</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 17:20:28 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>