<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 12:45:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Modhumoti Bank holds 139th executive committee meeting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/modhumoti-bank-holds-139th-executive-committee-meeting</link><description>The 139th meeting of the Executive Committee of Modhumoti Bank PLC was held on Thursday, 30th October 2025 at the Bank’s Head Office premises.
The meeting was presided by EC Chairman, Mr. Salahuddin Alamgir, according to a press release.
Among others, Mr. Mostafa Kamal, Mr. Mohammad Ismail</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 10:57:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>United Finance reports 3rd quarter financial results with continued profit growth</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/united-finance-reports-3rd-quarter-financial-results-with-continued-profit-growth</link><description>United Finance PLC convened its 235th Board Meeting, where the financial results for the third quarter of 2025 were approved.
The company reported a 6% year-on-year growth in net profit for the first nine months of 2025, demonstrating resilience and operational strength amid a challenging market e</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 11:12:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>3 more die of dengue; 928 hospitalised</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/3-more-die-of-dengue-928-hospitalised</link><description>Three more deaths were reported from dengue in 24 hours till Thursday morning, raising the number of fatalities from the mosquito-borne disease in Bangladesh to 278 this year.
During the period, 928 more patients were hospitalised with viral fever, raising the total infected-case to 69,356 this ye</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 11:42:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shahjalal airport fire probe report soon: Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/probe-report-on-shahjalal-airport-fire-to-be-released-soon-says-advisor-bashir</link><description>The investigation report on the recent fire at Shahjalal International Airport’s Cargo Village will be released soon, Civil Aviation and Tourism Adviser Sheikh Bashir Uddin has said.
On Thursday, he said the eight-member team of experts from Turkey that assisted with the investigation flew b</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 11:00:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pathao introduces CNG rides with exclusive cashback offer</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/pathao-introduces-cng-rides-with-exclusive-cashback-offer</link><description>Bangladesh’s leading homegrown super app Pathao has introduced a brand-new ride option: Pathao CNG, marking its 10th anniversary.
Now, along with bikes and cars, users can enjoy the convenience of Pathao CNG all in one seamless app, Pathao, according to a media release. 
Priced between</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 11:30:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCP wants nothing but ‘Shapla’: Musa</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ncp-wants-nothing-but-shapla-musa</link><description>Although the Election Commission has added four new symbols, including the Shapla Koli, water lily bud, the National Citizen Party says it wants only the Shapla polls logo.
NCP Joint Member Secretary Zahirul Islam Musa spoke about the matter shortly after the EC issued a gazette notification addin</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 12:00:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Four police officials appointed as additional DIGs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/four-police-officials-appointed-as-additional-digs</link><description>Four police officials at the rank of superintendents of police have been promoted to the rank of additional deputy inspector general.
The Ministry of Home Affairs issued a notice on Thursday instructing the joining letters for these promotions to be sent to the senior secretary of the ministry.
T</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 12:15:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>HC orders full Dhaka air cleanup in 3 weeks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/high-court-orders-full-enforcement-of-anti-air-pollution-directives-for-dhaka-in-three-weeks</link><description>The High Court has directed that the nine-point directives it issued five years ago to curb Dhaka’s air pollution be fully implemented within three weeks, with a progress report submitted to the court afterwards.
The bench of Justice Md Rezaul Hasan and Justice Urmee Rahman passed the order</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 12:45:27 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>