<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 12:47:40 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>New Zealand population reaches 5.3m</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/new-zealand-population-reaches-53m</link><description>New Zealand’s resident population grew 0.7 percent to 5.3 million in the year ending in June 2025, with population growth slowing across all 16 regions, Stats NZ said Wednesday.
The growth was slower than in the previous two June years, 2.3 percent in 2023 and 1.7 percent in 2024, according</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 09:10:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>2 more die of dengue; 964 hospitalised</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/2-more-die-of-dengue-964-hospitalised</link><description>Two more deaths were reported from dengue in 24 hours till Wednesday morning, raising the number of fatalities from the mosquito-borne disease in Bangladesh to 275 this year.
During the period, 964 more patients were hospitalised with viral fever, raising the total infected-case to 68,428 this yea</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 09:40:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Key US mortgage rate drops to 13-month low, industry group says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/key-us-mortgage-rate-drops-to-13-month-low-industry-group-says</link><description>The interest rate on the most popular U.S. home loan dropped last week to a 13-month low after a key reading of inflation came in lower than expected, cementing expectations for another Federal Reserve interest-rate cut.
The Mortgage Bankers Association said on Wednesday the contract rate on a 30-</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 10:10:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DRC of ICAB set to arrange Accounting Day Run 2025</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/drc-of-icab-set-to-arrange-accounting-day-run-2025</link><description>The Dhaka Regional Committee (DRC) of The Institute of Chartered Accountants of Bangladesh (ICAB) is set to arrange a signature running event, "Accounting Day Run 2025" on November 7, 2025, at Hatirjheel, Dhaka, in celebration of International Accounting Day.
According to the organisers, DRC is pr</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 10:40:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rick Haque Sikder charged with Tk 215 million embezzlement, money laundering</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rick-haque-sikder-charged-with-tk-215-million-embezzlement-money-laundering</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) has pressed charges against former National Bank Limited director Rick Haque Sikder and 11 others for their alleged involvement in the embezzlement and laundering of approximately Tk 215 million abroad through credit card misuse.
According t</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 10:55:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump announces trade breakthrough with South Korea on Asia trip</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/trump-announces-trade-breakthrough-with-south-korea-on-asia-trip</link><description>Donald Trump and South Korean President Lee Jae Myung finalised details of their fraught trade deal at a summit in South Korea on Wednesday, and the US president also sounded an optimistic note about a looming summit with China's Xi Jinping.
“We made our deal, pretty much finalized it," Trum</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 11:10:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCP agrees to first proposal of consensus commission</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ncp-agrees-to-first-proposal-of-consensus-commission-on-constitutional-reform</link><description>The National Citizens Party (NCP) has agreed with the proposal made by the National Consensus Commission that if the constitutional reforms mentioned in the July Charter are not done within a specific period, it will be deemed to have been “adopted” by a constitutional council.
The con</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 11:25:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hasina warns of mass voter boycott as her party barred from election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hasina-warns-of-mass-voter-boycott-as-her-party-barred-from-election</link><description>Millions of supporters of Bangladesh’s Awami League will boycott next year’s national election, after the party was barred from contesting the polls, ousted Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina told Reuters on Wednesday from her exile in New Delhi.
Hasina, 78, said she would not return to Bang</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 11:40:38 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>