<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 12:42:29 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Venezuela mine collapse kills 14 after heavy rain</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/venezuela-mine-collapse-kills-14-after-heavy-rain</link><description>At least 14 people were killed when a gold mine collapsed in El Callao, southeastern Venezuela, following days of torrential rain, authorities said on Monday.
Officials said a command post has been established to coordinate recovery operations, led by Brig. Gen. Gregory González Acevedo, he</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 10:11:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Health officials report 5 deaths, 841 fresh cases of dengue</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/health-officials-report-5-deaths-841-fresh-cases-of-dengue-inflection-overnight</link><description>Health officials today (Tuesday) said they recorded 841 fresh cases of dengue, killing at least five persons in the past 24 hours.
"During the period, (of the 841) 125 patients were hospitalized in Barishal division, 106 in Chattogram division, 214 in Dhaka division excluding the capital, 128 in D</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 10:26:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UK trade envoy visits BRAC University to explore higher education opportunities in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/uk-trade-envoy-visits-brac-university-to-explore-higher-education-opportunities-in-bangladesh</link><description>BRAC University extended a warm welcome to the United Kingdom's Trade Envoy to Bangladesh, The Rt Hon. the Baroness Winterton of Doncaster DBE, who came on a visit to the Merul Badda campus in Dhaka on 9th October.
The Rt Hon. the Baroness Winterton of Doncaster DBE was received by Tamara Hasan Ab</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 10:56:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>MPO teachers’ ‘March to Secretariat’ halted by police</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/mpo-teachers-march-to-secretariat-halted-by-police</link><description>Police have blocked a march by MPO-affiliated teachers and employees who were heading from the Central Shaheed Minar to the Secretariat to press for three demands, including raising their housing allowance to 20 percent of their salary.
The teachers and employees began their march from Shaheed Min</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 11:26:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Remittance inflow witnesses 26.9pc growth till Oct 13</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/remittance-inflow-witnesses-269pc-growth-till-oct-13</link><description>Inflow of remittances witnessed a year-on-year growth of 26.9 percent, reaching US$1,270 million in the first 13 days of October, according to the latest data of Bangladesh Bank (BB) issued.
Last year, during the same period, the country’s remittance inflow was $1000 million, reports BSS.
D</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 11:41:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UCB and Mastercard collaborate to power faster, safer remittance flows to Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ucb-and-mastercard-collaborate-to-power-faster-safer-remittance-flows-to-bangladesh</link><description>United Commercial Bank PLC (UCB) has entered into a strategic agreement with Mastercard to leverage its Transaction Services to strengthen cross-border remittance services to Bangladesh.
The collaboration aims to make it faster, safer, and more convenient for Non-Resident Bangladeshis (NRBs) to se</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 11:56:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP may nominate 5pc women candidates in next polls: Selima Rahman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-may-nominate-5pc-women-candidates-in-next-polls-selima-rahman</link><description>BNP Standing Committee Member Begum Selima Rahman on Tuesday said the party may nominate at least five per cent women candidates in the upcoming national election.
She expressed hope that the number could increase further, enabling women to play a stronger role in politics.
She made the remarks w</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 12:11:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Five Shariah banks owe Tk 373.32b to banks, FIs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/five-shariah-banks-owe-tk-37332b-to-banks-fis</link><description>Five Shariah banks undergoing a merger are facing a massive collective liability of approximately Tk 373.32 billion (Tk 37,332 crore) in fixed deposits owed to various banks and financial institutions, according to a report of the Bangladesh Bank released on Tuesday.
The report studied the state o</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 12:41:38 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>