<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 13:49:59 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Modi to skip Tarique’s swearing-in</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/india-pm-modi-to-skip-tariques-swearing-in-report</link><description>Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi will not attend the swearing-in ceremony of BNP chief Tarique Rahman as Bangladesh’s prime minister, Indian news channel Times Now reports.
Lok Sabha Speaker Om Birla and Indian Foreign Secretary Vikram Misri will represent India at the ceremony scheduled</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 10:56:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Case filed over bomb blast in C’nawabganj: 5 held</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/case-filed-over-bomb-blast-in-cnawabganj-5-held</link><description>A case has been filed against 20 people in connection with the death of two people in a crude bomb blast in Sadar upazila of Chapainawabganj district.
Additional Superintendent of Chapainawabganj Police NM Wasim Firoz said sub-inspector of Sadar Police Station filed the case against 10 identified</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 11:11:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka stocks soar to 18-month high on post-poll optimism</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/dhaka-stocks-soar-to-18-month-high-on-post-poll-optimism</link><description>Bangladesh’s benchmark stock index posted its biggest single-day gain in nearly a year and a half on Sunday, as investors reacted to the BNP's landslide election victory and the prospect of a new government.
The Dhaka Stock Exchange’s (DSE) broad index, the DSEX, closed up 200 points,</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 11:26:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Israeli airstrikes kill 9 in Gaza, including tent camp, Palestinian officials say</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/israeli-airstrikes-kill-9-in-gaza-including-tent-camp-palestinian-officials-say</link><description>At least nine Palestinians were killed in Israeli airstrikes in the northern and southern Gaza Strip on Sunday, Palestinian civil defence and health officials said, in what Israel’s military called a response to Hamas ceasefire violations.
Medics said an Israeli airstrike on a tent encampmen</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 11:41:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No journo jailed for expressing opinion during interim govt’s tenure: Rizwana</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/no-journo-jailed-for-expressing-opinion-during-interim-govts-tenure-rizwana</link><description>Information and Broadcasting Adviser Syeda Rizwana Hasan on Sunday said no journalist was sent to jail for expressing opinions during the interim government’s tenure.
“I am not aware of any journalist being arrested solely for criticism during our tenure. Any action taken against indiv</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 11:56:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP wins 49.97pc vote share, Jamaat 31.76pc: EC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bnp-wins-4997pc-vote-share-jamaat-3176pc-ec</link><description>Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) secured 49.97 percent, while Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami gained 31.76 percent of total votes cast in the 13th parliamentary election held on February 12 last.
Besides, National Citizen Party-NCP obtained 3.05percent votes, Islami Andolan Bangladesh pocketed 2.70 p</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 11:26:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DSE, IIX sign MoU to introduce Orange bonds, Sukuk</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/dse-iix-sign-mou-to-introduce-orange-bonds-sukuk</link><description>Dhaka Stock Exchange PLC (DSE) and Impact Investment Exchange (IIX) on Sunday signed a memorandum of understanding (MoU) to collaborate on introducing and promoting Orange capital instruments, including Orange Bonds and Sukuk, in Bangladesh’s capital market.
The MoU was signed at the DSE boa</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 11:41:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Advisors not leaving country, will attend swearing-in: Press Secretary Shafiqul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/advisors-not-leaving-country-will-attend-swearing-in-press-secretary-shafiqul</link><description>Chief Advisor’s Press Secretary Shafiqul Alam has described the interim government’s advisors as the “proud sons of Bangladesh”, assuring that they are all in the country and will continue to live here to continue contributing to the development of the nation.
His comment f</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 11:56:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AIUB at Global AIFOD Summit</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/aiub-at-global-aifod-summit</link><description>The American International University-Bangladesh (AIUB) participated in the AI for Developing Countries Forum (AIFOD) Winter Summit, held at the United Nations Conference Centre (UNCC) in Bangkok, Thailand, from February 4–6, 2026.
AIUB was represented at this prestigious global forum by Dr.</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 12:11:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>JT International Bangladesh appoints new Managing Director</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/jt-international-bangladesh-appoints-new-managing-director</link><description>JT International Bangladesh Limited has appointed Dr. Oliver Kutz as its new Managing Director, effective February 2026. He will be based in Dhaka.
Oliver brings more than two decades of international experience in the tobacco industry, according to a media release. 
He began his career in 2</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 12:26:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prime Bank CEO Hassan O. Rashid resigns</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/prime-bank-ceo-hassan-o-rashid-resigns</link><description>Hassan O. Rashid, managing director and chief executive officer of Prime Bank, has resigned from his position.
Prime Bank’s board of directors accepted Rashid’s resignation at a meeting on February 10.
The decision was disclosed on Sunday through the website of Dhaka Stock Exchange.</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 12:41:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Azizur Rahman Ripon elected chairman, Sirajul Islam executive director of FERB</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/azizur-rahman-ripon-elected-chairman-sirajul-islam-executive-director-of-ferb</link><description>M. Azizur Rahman Ripon has been elected as Chairman and Serajul Islam Siraj as executive director of the Forum for Energy Reporters Bangladesh (FERB) on Sunday.
The election was held following the biennial general meeting of the FERB at Bijoy Hall of Bidyut Bhaban in the city.
M Azizur Rahman has</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 12:56:53 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>