<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 11:19:28 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Police vehicle burns in Dhaka’s Ramna, microbus catches fire in Uttara</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/police-vehicle-burns-in-dhakas-ramna-microbus-catches-fire-in-uttara</link><description>A police pickup van has caught on fire in front of the Ramna Police Station in Dhaka’s Kakrail while a fire was sparked on a microbus in the capital’s Uttara.
Both incidents occurred due to mechanical problems, according to the police and the Fire Service. No one was hurt in either inc</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 07:21:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jet Crash: Two more Milestone students return home after 114 days</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jet-crash-two-more-milestone-students-return-home-after-114-days</link><description>Two more students of Milestone School and College have returned home after 114 days of treatment for burn injuries sustained in the tragic Air Force plane crash in Uttara of Dhaka.
The returnees are Saiba Jahan Saima, 10, and Saira Jahan, 10, students of class IV, UNB reports.
On Wednesday mornin</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 07:25:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bus set ablaze in Kishoreganj</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bus-set-ablaze-in-kishoreganj</link><description>Unidentified miscreants set fire to a parked bus of Tisha Paribahan at Bajitpur Bus Stand in Kishoreganj district early Wednesday.
The incident occurred around 1:00 am at the bus stand on the Bajitpur-Dhaka highway, confirmed Bajitpur Upazila Nirbahi Officer Shahidul Islam Sohan.
He said the atta</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 07:40:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Petrol bombs thrown at Mohammadpur Preparatory School overnight</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/petrol-bombs-thrown-at-mohammadpur-preparatory-school-overnight</link><description>Assailants have reportedly conducted a petrol bomb attack on Preparatory School and College located on Iqbal Road in Dhaka’s Mohammadpur.
The incident occurred on Tuesday night, three days after an explosive device went off near the entrance of St Joseph School, not far from the institution,</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 07:55:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>469 killed in 469 road accidents in October</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/469-killed-in-469-road-accidents-in-october</link><description>A total of 469 people were killed and 1280 others injured in October in 469 road accidents, according to a BJKS (Bangladesh Jatri Kalyan Samiti) press release on Wednesday.
Meanwhile, 52 accidents on the railways resulted in 47 deaths and 30 injuries. Besides, 12 people died and 1 went missing in</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 08:10:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Chhatra League’ locks five buildings at DU</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/chhatra-league-locks-five-buildings-at-du</link><description>Five academic buildings’ gates of Dhaka University were found locked early Wednesday night. Later, Leaders of the banned organisation, Bangladesh Chhatra League (BCL) admitted on Facebook to locking the gates.
After this incident, five security guards ofthe  university, assigned to the</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 08:59:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shatabdi Paribahan bus set on fire in Mirpur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/shatabdi-paribahan-bus-set-on-fire-in-mirpur</link><description>Unidentified miscreants set fire to a Shatabdi Paribahan bus in front of Sony Cinema Hall at Mirpur-1 in Dhaka on Wednesday afternoon, police said.
Ripon, duty officer at Shah Ali Police Station, said the incident took place around 12:30 pm when several individuals on motorcycles arrived and set t</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 09:14:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Man shot dead in Badda</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/man-shot-dead-in-badda</link><description>A man has been shot dead in the Badda area of Dhaka.
The incident occurred around 3:30 am on Wednesday in Badda’s Chairman Goli, said local police station chief Habibur Rahman.
“Unidentified assailants shot and killed Mamun Shikdar, aged 38,” he said.
Habibur said Mamun worked</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 09:29:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>FBCCI to recommend tariff rationalisation to keep Ramadan prices stable</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/fbcci-to-recommend-tariff-rationalisation-to-keep-ramadan-prices-stable</link><description>The Federation of Bangladesh Chambers of Commerce and Industry (FBCCI) will recommend tariff rationalisation to the National Board of Revenue (NBR) to help keep the prices of essential commodities stable during the upcoming Ramadan.
FBCCI Administrator Abdur Rahim Khan said ensuring rational taxat</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 09:45:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh undergoing major transformation ahead of historic election: CA</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-undergoing-major-transformation-ahead-of-historic-election-ca</link><description>Chief Adviser Prof Muhammad Yunus on Wednesday conveyed to a visiting Canadian parliamentary delegation that Bangladesh is now preparing for the national election, which will be a historic moment for the nation.
“You’ve come at a time when Bangladesh is undergoing a significant transfo</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 10:00:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pay scale process involves multiple commissions, layers of approval: Salehuddin</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/pay-scale-process-involves-multiple-commissions-layers-of-approval-salehuddin</link><description>Finance Adviser Dr Salehuddin Ahmed on Wednesday said the process of pay scale implementation involves several independent commissions and multiple layers of administrative approval.
“The work of the Pay Commission is highly complex and independent. There is no government role in determining</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 10:15:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EU wants election to succeed: Khosru</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/eu-wants-to-see-successful-election-in-bangladesh-says-bnps-khosru</link><description>The European Union is closely monitoring Bangladesh’s next general election and aims to see it held successfully, senior BNP leader Amir Khosru Mahmud Chowdhury has said.
The BNP National Standing Committee member made the statement at a news briefing after a meeting between the EU ambassado</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 10:30:43 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>