<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 20:23:49 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Bangladesh hold their nerve to beat Ireland, level T20I series</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/bangladesh-hold-their-nerve-to-beat-ireland-level-t20i-series</link><description>Bangladesh drew level in the T20I series with a composed four-wicket win over Ireland in Chattogram on Saturday night.
Bangladesh chased 171 with two balls to spare after a disciplined closing stand from Mohammad Saifuddin and Mahedi Hasan finished the job.
Ireland had posted 170 for six, a total</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 16:31:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sustainable political and social climate a primary requirement to attract investment: Jamaat Ameer at economic summit</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/sustainable-political-and-social-climate-a-primary-requirement-to-attract-investment-jamaat-ameer-at-economic-summit</link><description>Jamaat-e-Islami Ameer Dr Shafiqur Rahman on Saturday stated that a sustainable political and social atmosphere in Bangladesh is the primary requirement for both foreign and domestic investors.
Shafiqur made the remarks at the third session of the Bangladesh Economic Summit 2025, organised by Bangl</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 16:46:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladeshi shot dead by BSF near border in Chuadanga</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladeshi-man-shot-dead-by-bsf-near-border-in-chuadanga</link><description>A Bangladeshi man was shot dead by India’s Border Security Force (BSF) at the Gayeshpur border in Jibannagar upazila of Chuadanga district on Saturday.
The BSF took away his body after the shooting.
The dead man was identified as Shahidul Islam, 37, son of Noskor Ali from Gayeshpur village.</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 17:01:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>As Dhaka's population surges, services go haywire</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/as-dhakas-population-surges-services-go-haywire</link><description>Dhaka as a city is imploding. Overpopulation has overwhelmed its civic amenities, while problem such as chronic traffic congestion, utility crises, environmental pollution, and other urban stresses continue to grow unchecked. Not long ago, it earned the distinction of being one of the least liveabl</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 16:16:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Global trade moderation and Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/global-trade-moderation-and-bangladesh</link><description>The calendar year 2025 is now set to enter its final month tomorrow. In other words, just a month from now, the world will see the start of another year. The annual stock-taking of global economic performance is already underway, although only relevant data for the first three quarters (January-Sep</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 16:31:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Purbachal plot case lesson for corrupt leaders</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/purbachal-plot-case-lesson-for-corrupt-leaders</link><description>The verdict against former prime minister Sheikh Hasina in three corruption cases involving valuable government plots has produced a moment of national reckoning over the abuse of political power and the dangers of unchecked authority. A Dhaka court sentenced her to a total of 21 years in prison an</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 16:46:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gaza death toll tops 70,000, health ministry says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/gaza-death-toll-tops-70000-health-ministry-says</link><description>The number of people confirmed killed in Israel's offensive in the Gaza Strip has passed the 70,000 mark, the enclave's health ministry said on Saturday.
A total of 301 people have been added to the toll since Thursday, taking it to 70,100, the ministry added. Two died in recent Israeli strikes, t</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 17:01:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Simeen in ACC scanner over ‘Tk 1bn bribe’ to Hasina</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/acc-opens-probe-into-transcom-ceo-simeens-payment-of-tk-1-billion-in-bribes-to-hasina</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) has opened an inquiry into allegations that Transcom Group Chief Executive Officer Simeen Rahman paid Tk 1 billion in bribes to Sheikh Hasina to suppress several cases lodged against her.
In the first week of this month, the ACC assigned one of its deputy direc</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 17:16:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Draft police commission law sent back</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/advisory-council-sends-back-draft-police-commission-ordinance</link><description>The Advisory Council has sent back the draft Police Commission Ordinance, 2025, one of two laws the interim government is accused of rushing through ahead of the election.
The revised draft of the Foreign Donations (Voluntary Activities) Regulation (Amendment) Ordinance, 2025, however, has receive</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 17:31:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Oil tanker derails in Fenchuganj, Sylhet rail services suspended</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/oil-tanker-derails-fenchuganj-sylhet-rail-services-suspended</link><description>Rail communication between Sylhet and the rest of the country was suspended on Saturday night after an oil tanker wagon of a freight train derailed in the Mollikpur area of Fenchuganj upazila.
The incident occurred around 9:30 pm, said Enayet Karim, officer-in-charge of Sylhet Railway Police Stati</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 20:08:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khaleda responding to treatment: Dr Zahid</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/khaleda-responding-to-treatment-dr-zahid</link><description>BNP Chairperson Begum Khaleda Zia is responding to the treatment provided by the medical board, her personal physician Professor AZM Zahid Hossain said on Saturday.
“Alhamdulillah, her condition has remained stable for the last three days--27, 28 and 29 November. In medical terms, she is mai</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 18:01:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Banking sector may need 5-10 yrs for NPL cleanup, says Mansur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/banking-sector-may-need-5-10-yrs-for-npl-cleanup-says-mansur</link><description>The new bank born out of the merger of five severely liquidity-starved unconventional banks will be launched this week, Bangladesh Bank (BB) Governor Dr Ahsan H. Mansur informed Thursday, on an upbeat note about its strong start-up capital base.
The process of launching the much-talked-about Sammi</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 20:23:49 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>