<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 17:19:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Asif announces ‘cancelled’ projects with India</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/advisor-asif-announces-cancellation-of-10-bangladesh-india-projects-foreign-advisor-coy</link><description>Local Government Advisor Asif Mahmud Shojib Bhuyain has shared details of the “cancellation” of 10 Bangladesh-India projects and agreements.
Posting a photocard on his verified Facebook page on Sunday, he said: “Discussions on the agreements began after the interim government too</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 14:40:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Kali Puja being celebrated</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/kali-puja-being-celebrated</link><description>Kali Puja or Shyama Puja, a religious festival of the Hindu community, is being celebrated across the country on Monday with due sacred fervor and enthusiasm.
The main features of the Puja are worshiping the goddess Kali, lighting earthen lamps and candles at temples and residences in addition to</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 15:10:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Madagascar coup leader names businessman as new prime minister</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/madagascar-coup-leader-names-businessman-as-new-prime-minister</link><description>Madagascar’s coup leader Colonel Michael Randrianirina, who seized power this month, named businessman and consultant Herintsalama Rajaonarivelo as the island nation’s new prime minister on Monday.
Randrianirina was sworn in as president on Friday, days after taking control in the wake</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 15:40:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Court freezes Tk 80b worth of S Alam shares</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/court-freezes-tk-80b-worth-of-s-alam-shares</link><description>A Dhaka court has ordered the freezing of shares worth Tk 80 billion linked to S Alam Group Chairman Md Saiful Alam and 105 affiliated companies.
Dhaka Metropolitan Senior Special Judge Sabbir Faiz gave the order on Monday following an application from the Anti-Corruption Commission, said spokespe</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 15:55:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Media free from government pressure: Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/media-free-from-government-pressure-adviser</link><description>Information and Broadcasting Adviser Mahfuj Alam said on Monday that the government does not exert any pressure on the media.
"The Information and Broadcasting Ministry does not call any media outlet to interfere in their work. The media is freely criticising the government at present," he said.</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 16:10:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt increases honorarium for recruitment staff</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-increases-honorarium-for-recruitment-staff</link><description>The government has revised the honorarium and remuneration rates for staff involved in recruitment and promotion activities under ministries, divisions, directorates, and departments.
A circular issued by the Ministry of Finance on Monday announced the changes, which take immediate effect.
Accord</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 16:34:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two youths drown in Meherpur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/two-youths-drown-in-meherpur</link><description>The bodies of two young men who went missing while bathing in the Bhairab River near the Ratanpur–Rashikpur switchgate in Mujibnagar upazila of Meherpur have been recovered.
A diving team from the Khulna Fire Service retrieved the bodies between 7:30 pm and 8:30 pm on Monday, officials said.</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 17:19:02 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>