<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 22:23:56 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>BERC slashes jet fuel prices for domestic, international routes</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/berc-slashes-jet-fuel-prices-for-domestic-international-routes</link><description>The Bangladesh Energy Regulatory Commission (BERC) has lowered the price of jet fuel for domestic routes from Tk 104.61 to Tk 94.93 per litre.
The price for international routes has also been reduced from 68 cents to 62 cents per litre.
The new rates, aligned with global market prices, were annou</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 16:28:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Russia says US seizure of oil tanker violates maritime law</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/russia-says-us-seizure-of-oil-tanker-violates-maritime-law</link><description>Russia said on Wednesday that the US seizure of a Russian-flagged oil tanker in the Atlantic was a violation of maritime law.
"In accordance with the 1982 UN Convention on the Law of the Sea, freedom of navigation applies in the high seas, and no state has the right to use force against vessels du</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 16:43:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dozens of AL leaders, activists quit in Gopalganj</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dozens-of-al-leaders-activists-quit-in-gopalganj</link><description>At least 50 leaders and activists of the Awami League from various levels in Muksudpur upazila of Gopalganj have resigned from the party.
The resignations were announced on Tuesday evening through separate press conferences held by Awami League leaders of Maharajpur, Bhabrashur and Banshbaria unio</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 16:58:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Labor alliance unveils 15-point manifesto ahead of 2026 national elections</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/labor-alliance-unveils-15-point-manifesto-ahead-of-2026-national-elections</link><description>The 'National Workers' Rights Advocacy Alliance' on Wednesday formally presented a 15-point "Worker Manifesto" to political parties, urging them to prioritize labor rights and social justice in their upcoming electoral agendas for the 2026 National Parliament Election.
The demand was revea</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 17:13:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rescued tigress from Sundarbans still in trauma, physically frail</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/rescued-tigress-from-sundarbans-still-in-trauma-physically-frail</link><description>A critically injured tigress rescued from a poacher’s trap in the Sundarbans remains traumatised and physically very weak, veterinarians said on Tuesday.
Professor Dr Mohammad Abu Hadi Noor Ali Khan of Mymensingh Agricultural University, who heads a four-member expert medical board at Gazipu</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 17:28:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dozens of auditors, firms under  scanners over cooking books</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/dozens-of-auditors-firms-under-scanners-over-cooking-books</link><description>A host of audit firms and auditors are under the scanner of government investigation agencies over alleged irregularities in audited financials of business tycoons implicated in the major banking-sector scams during the previous regime.
According to official sources, chartered accountants (CAs) an</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 18:06:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gas crisis after Buriganga pipeline hit</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ship-anchor-damages-titas-gas-line-supply-in-dhaka-may-take-days-to-normalise</link><description>A Titas gas pipeline running beneath the Buriganga River has been damaged after a ship’s anchor hit the line, disrupting supply to several areas of the capital, including Amin Bazar, Mirpur, Mohammadpur, Dhanmondi, Adabar, Azimpur, and Old Dhaka.
Hundreds of thousands of residents have faced</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 18:21:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Investigation opens into death of 7-year-old during circumcision at Chattogram hospital</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/investigation-opens-into-death-of-7-year-old-during-circumcision-at-chattogram-hospital</link><description>A five-member committee has been formed to investigate the death of a 7-year-old boy during a circumcision procedure at a private hospital in Chattogram city.
The committee, headed by Deputy Civil Surgeon Md Towhidul Anwar, was constituted on Wednesday.
Civil Surgeon Jahangir Alam told bdnews24.c</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 18:36:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Russia attacks two Ukrainian ports, Kyiv says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/russia-attacks-two-ukrainian-ports-kyiv-says</link><description>Russia attacked two seaports in Ukraine's Odesa region on Wednesday, killing one person and injuring eight others, Ukrainian officials said.
Russia has repeatedly attacked Ukraine's ports and foreign-flagged vessels sailing from them in recent weeks, after President Vladimir Putin vowed to cut Ukr</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 18:51:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rural health clinics: promises, performances, and despair</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/rural-health-clinics-promises-performances-and-despair</link><description>Across Bangladesh’s countryside, a remarkable health-policy transformation has unfolded over the past two decades. Tens of thousands of low-level health posts—community clinics and union-level health and family welfare centres—now bring medical care within reach of rural populatio</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 19:06:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Regulate, not ban cryptocurrency</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/regulate-not-ban-cryptocurrency</link><description>Cryptocurrency is banned in Bangladesh, but its usage is booming in the shadow of a legal grey zone and the absence of effective regulatory oversight. Bangladesh ranks 13th among 151 countries worldwide in terms of cryptocurrency usage, according to the  Global Crypto Adoption Index 2025, publ</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 19:21:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Persuading SoEs, MNCs to join stock markets</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/persuading-soes-mncs-to-join-stock-markets</link><description>If the benchmark index of a stock exchange loses 351 points in a year, its impacts on that bourse depend on its current level and typical volatility. For the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE), this margin is severe because of its current level staying below 5,000 mark. A 351-point drop in the DSE market i</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 19:36:43 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>