<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 16:44:20 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Deep depression weakens into land depression over Bay</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/deep-depression-weakens-into-land-depression-over-bay</link><description>The land deep depression over coastal Odisha and adjoining area moved northnorthwestwards, weakened into a land depression over Odisha and adjoining Chhattisgarh at 3pm on Friday, according Bangladesh Meteorological Department (BMD).
It is likely to move in a north-northwestward direction further</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 14:04:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tributes for Ahmed Rafiq at Shaheed Minar on Saturday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tributes-for-ahmed-rafiq-at-shaheed-minar-on-saturday</link><description>Language Movement activist Ahmed Rafiq will be taken to the Central Shaheed Minar on Saturday, where people from all walks of life can pay their last respects.
The tribute ceremony, organised by the Ahmed Rafiq Foundation, will begin at 11am.
Afterwards, in line with his final wish, his remains w</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 14:19:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh demands immediate release of flotilla detainees</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-slates-israeli-interception-of-gaza-aid-flotilla-demands-release-of-all-activists</link><description>Bangladesh has condemned the interception of the Global Sumud Flotilla in international waters, which was carrying humanitarian aid for Gaza, by Israeli forces.
In a statement on Friday, the foreign ministry described the act as “a flagrant violation of international law and a brazen manifes</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 14:49:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCP clarifies position on pressing for ‘Shapla’ election symbol</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ncp-continues-pressing-for-shapla-as-election-symbol-disputes-ecs-decision</link><description>The National Citizen Party (NCP) has again demanded the “Shapla” as its electoral symbol, rejecting the Election Commission’s (EC) stance that the flower cannot be allocated due to its place in the national emblem.
In a statement on Friday, NCP Convenor Nahid Islam explained why</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 15:19:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Singapore looks forward to 'working closely' with Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/singapore-looks-forward-to-working-closely-with-bangladesh</link><description>Singapore’s Foreign Minister Dr Vivian Balakrishnan has said his country looks forward to working closely with Bangladesh as it pursues its next phase of growth and development.
“With a young and hardworking population, Bangladesh has immense potential,” he said, as he met Specia</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 15:23:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chevron's Los Angeles refinery down after large fire erupts in jet fuel unit</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/chevrons-los-angeles-refinery-down-after-large-fire-erupts-in-jet-fuel-unit</link><description>Chevron’s 285,000-barrel-per-day El Segundo refinery in Southern California was mostly down on Friday after a large fire erupted in a jet fuel production unit, disrupting supply in the Golden State’s isolated energy market.
The El Segundo refinery is the second-largest refinery in Cali</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 15:38:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>4 injured in armed clash between locals in Munshiganj</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/4-injured-in-armed-clash-between-locals-in-munshiganj</link><description>At least four people were injured, including three who were shot, in a clash between two local groups over establishing supremacy in Munshiganj Sadar on Friday, said police.
Besides, several houses were vandalised during the clash. Police recovered 14 fresh grenades and nine bullet casings from th</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 15:53:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fewer foreign students, fewer dollars: US colleges feel the pinch</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/fewer-foreign-students-fewer-dollars-us-colleges-feel-the-pinch</link><description>DePaul University has told faculty it will immediately reduce spending following a 30 per cent decline in international enrollment this fall. The move is the latest by US colleges to cope with the disruptive education and immigration policies of President Donald Trump.
The amount of the reduction</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 16:23:08 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>