<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 15:20:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Tarique warns of 'ongoing' election conspiracy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-says-conspiracies-are-under-way-to-disrupt-parliamentary-polls</link><description>Tarique Rahman has warned that the conspirators have not stopped and that holding the parliamentary elections will "not be easy".
The BNP acting chief made the remarks while attending a workshop virtually from London.
“I have said earlier that holding an election will not be so easy. The co</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 13:00:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>With Fed independence in crosshairs, will Supreme Court back Trump again?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/with-fed-independence-in-crosshairs-will-supreme-court-back-trump-again</link><description>The US Supreme Court's conservative justices appear ready to endorse President Donald Trump's power to fire a regulatory agency official despite job protections given by Congress. But they have signaled reluctance to give him similar authority over the Federal Reserve in a major case set to be argu</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 13:15:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mirza Abbas calls attack on Hadi part of wider conspiracy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/mirza-abbas-calls-attack-on-hadi-part-of-wider-conspiracy</link><description>BNP senior leader Mirza Abbas on Saturday described the gun attack on Inqilab Mancha convener Sharif Osman bin Hadi ahead of the election as a small part of a larger conspiracy, not an isolated incident.
“This is not an isolated incident. First Ershad Ullah was attacked in Chattogram, now Ha</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 13:30:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US, Ukraine to discuss ceasefire in Berlin ahead of European summit</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-ukraine-to-discuss-ceasefire-in-berlin-ahead-of-european-summit</link><description>Germany will host US and Ukrainian delegations over the weekend for talks on a ceasefire in Ukraine, ahead of a summit with European leaders and President Volodymyr Zelensky in Berlin on Monday, a German official said on Saturday.
A US official said overnight that President Donald Trump's envoy St</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 13:45:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Midland Bank inaugurates Saidpur Sub Branch</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/midland-bank-inaugurates-saidpur-sub-branch</link><description>Midland Bank PLC (MDB) inaugurated its Saidpur Sub-Branch at Sahid Dr. Zikrul Haque Plaza (1st floor), Dr. Zikrul Haque Road, Saidpur, Nilphamari on December 11, 2025, according to a press release.
Md. Ahsan-uz Zaman, Managing Director &amp; CEO of the bank, inaugurated the Branch as Chief Guest along</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 14:00:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>SBAC Bank holds Annual Risk Conference 2025</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/sbac-bank-holds-annual-risk-conference-2025</link><description>SBAC Bank PLC. has organized its Annual Risk Conference 2025 on Saturday, December 13, 2025, at the Training Institute of the bank’s Head Office.
Mr. A.N.M Moinul Kabir, Director of Department of Off-site Supervision of Bangladesh Bank, attended the conference as the chief guest, according t</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 13:30:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>National Bank achieves ISO certification</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/national-bank-achieves-iso-certification</link><description>National Bank has achieved the internationally recognised ISO 27001:2022 Information Security Management System (ISMS) certification, according to a press release.
On this occasion, a certificate handover ceremony was held on 11 December 2025, at the bank’s Head Office. Mr. K. Nagaraj, Count</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 13:45:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Belarus frees Nobel winner, top opposition figures as US lifts more sanctions</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/belarus-frees-nobel-winner-top-opposition-figures-as-us-lifts-more-sanctions</link><description>Belarusian President Alexander Lukashenko freed 123 prisoners on Saturday including Nobel Peace Prize winner Ales Bialiatski and leading opposition figure Maria Kalesnikava after two days of talks with an envoy for President Donald Trump, a US statement said.
In return, the US agreed to lift sanct</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 14:00:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BRAC Bank empowers 60 women entrepreneurs in Patuakhali, Khagrachhari</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/brac-bank-empowers-60-women-entrepreneurs-in-patuakhali-khagrachhari</link><description>BRAC Bank, in partnership with the Bangladesh Open-Source Network (BdOSN), has completed two ‘Amrai TARA’ training programmes in Patuakhali and Khagrachhari, advancing its nationwide women entrepreneurship development agenda.
Across two regions, 60 emerging women entrepreneurs embarked</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 14:15:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BMCCI holds 24th AGM, showcases achievements and future vision</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bmcci-holds-24th-agm-showcases-achievements-and-future-vision</link><description>The Bangladesh-Malaysia Chamber of Commerce and Industry (BMCCI) convened its 24th Annual General Meeting (AGM) on Saturday at Renaissance Dhaka, Gulshan.
According to a press release, the meeting brought together distinguished members, past presidents, and board colleagues, reaffirming BMCCI&amp;rsqu</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 14:30:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NHRC ordinance ‘trapped by bureaucratic control’, says TIB</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nhrc-ordinance-trapped-by-bureaucratic-control-says-tib</link><description>Transparency International Bangladesh (TIB) has claimed that the National Human Rights Commission (NHRC) Ordinance is being “held hostage by a bureaucratic takeover”.
In a media statement on Saturday, the local chapter of Berlin-based Transparency International, a global anti-corruptio</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 14:45:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fully extinguishing Keraniganj building fire may take yet another day</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fully-extinguishing-keraniganj-building-fire-may-take-yet-another-day</link><description>Firefighters have contained the blaze in a multi-storey building in Keraniganj after more than 11 and a half hours, though full extinguishment is expected to take at least another day.
Fire Service teams succeeded in taming the blaze at 5:03pm on Saturday following efforts by 20 units, but removin</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 15:00:52 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>