<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 13:42:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>EBL invests Tk 7.4m for Coastal Greening and Climate Resilience on Bhasan Char</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ebl-invests-tk-74m-for-coastal-greening-and-climate-resilience-on-bhasan-char</link><description>Eastern Bank PLC. (EBL) has partnered with NouKollan Foundation Trading Company Ltd. (NKFTCL) to implement a large-scale afforestation and land restoration initiative on Bhasan Char Island.
As part of EBL’s Corporate Social Responsibility (CSR) commitment, the bank will invest BDT 7.4 millio</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 11:45:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Denmark and Greenland to face Vance in high-stakes White House meeting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/denmark-and-greenland-to-face-vance-in-high-stakes-white-house-meeting</link><description>The Danish and Greenlandic foreign ministers will meet with US Vice President JD Vance at the White House on Wednesday following weeks of threats by President Donald Trump to take control of Greenland, an autonomous territory of Denmark.
Trump has said the strategically located and mineral-rich is</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 12:00:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>5th Prime Bank Cup Golf Tournament 2026 held at Cumilla</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/5th-prime-bank-cup-golf-tournament-2026-held-at-cumilla</link><description>The three-day 5th Prime Bank Cup Golf Tournament 2026 was held with great enthusiasm from 8–10 January 2026 at the Mainamati Golf and Country Club, Cumilla Cantonment.
The tournament was inaugurated by Major General Md. Nazim-ud-Daula, SPP, ndc, psc, PhD, President of Mainamati Golf and Coun</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 11:02:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NBR Chairman signals possible VAT, turnover tax reforms for jewellery businesses</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/nbr-chairman-signals-possible-vat-turnover-tax-reforms-for-jewellery-businesses</link><description>National Board of Revenue (NBR) Chairman Md Abdur Rahman Khan on Wednesday indicated that the government may reconsider the current VAT and turnover tax system for the country’s jewellery businesses, stressing the need for fair taxation and better sectoral discipline.
“If VAT is proper</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 11:17:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Japan PM readies snap election, February 8 ballot eyed</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/japan-pm-readies-snap-election-february-8-ballot-eyed</link><description>Japan’s Prime Minister Sanae Takaichi plans to dissolve parliament next week and call a snap parliamentary election, the secretary general of her party said on Wednesday, as she seeks public backing for spending plans that have rattled financial markets.
Takaichi is considering holding the e</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 11:32:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Madrasa torched after teacher ‘elopes with student’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/noakhali-madrasa-torched-after-teacher-elopes-with-12-year-old-student</link><description>A madrasa in Noakhali’s Subarnachar Upazila has been set on fire following allegations that its head teacher had fled with a 12-year-old student.
The arson took place around midnight on Tuesday at the Syed Munshi Bari Madrasa in North Char Hasan village, said Mohammad Abu Kawsar, chairman of</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 11:47:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NATO would be 'more formidable' with US control of Greenland, Trump says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nato-would-be-more-formidable-with-us-control-of-greenland-trump-says</link><description>US President Donald Trump said anything less than Greenland "in the hands" of the United States was "unacceptable", reiterating his demand for control of the Danish territory just hours ahead of a White House meeting on the issue.
"The United States needs Greenland for the purpose of National Secu</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 12:02:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>MIDA, Sasakawa Foundation sign MoU to help conserve protect marine fisheries: CA</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/mida-sasakawa-foundation-sign-mou-to-help-conserve-protect-marine-fisheries-ca</link><description>Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus today (Wednesday) said that the Memorandum of Understanding (MoU) between the Maheshkhali Integrated Development Authority (MIDA) and Japan's renowned Sasakawa Peace Foundation (SPF) will help conserve the ocean and protect marine fisheries.
He made the remar</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 12:17:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Arguments in Abu Sayed killing case on January 20</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/arguments-in-abu-sayed-killing-case-on-january-20</link><description>The International Crimes Tribunal (ICT)-2 on Wednesday set January 20 for placing arguments in the crimes against humanity case filed over the killing of Begum Rokeya University, Rangpur (BRUR) student Abu Sayed during the July Mass Uprising.
The three-judge panel of the International Crimes Tribu</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 12:32:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Transition of Shakrain: Old Dhaka's festival in 2026</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/culture/transition-of-shakrain-old-dhakas-festival-in-2026</link><description>Mohammad Aman Mia, a 70-year-old resident of Gandaria, a 12-year-old Hasib, and a 30-year-old Fazle rabbi from Narinda, three of them have a common link of their childhood, one festival, one celebration from different eras- Shakrain. This unique kite festival can only be seen in the skies over Old</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 12:47:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Intelligence agencies aided AL in polls: report</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/election-probe-report-alleges-dgfi-nsi-officials-aided-awami-league-in-2014-2018-2024</link><description>An interim government-commissioned inquiry into the last three general elections has found that intelligence agencies were “deeply involved” in manipulating the outcomes of the last polls.
The full report, released Wednesday by the Chief Advisor’s Office, said officials from the</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 13:02:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Students leave Science Lab after announcing blockades at three Dhaka points</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/students-leave-science-lab-after-announcing-blockades-at-three-dhaka-points</link><description>Protesting students have cleared the Science Laboratory zone in Dhaka late Wednesday, ending hours of traffic disruption.
They announced fresh blockades simultaneously at three key points -- Science Laboratory, Tantibazar, and Technical intersections -- on Thursday, bdnews24.com reports. 
Th</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 13:17:27 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>