<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 12:41:04 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>BGMEA, DBP announce cooperation to develop Digital Factory Passport</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bgmea-dbp-announce-cooperation-to-develop-digital-factory-passport</link><description>Bangladesh Garment Manufacturers and Exporters Association (BGMEA) will develop an AI-enabled ESG compliance framework, namely 'Digital Factory Passport (DFP),' to strengthen transparency, accountability, and global competitiveness across the country's garment industry.
 
In this connection,</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 09:15:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Remittance inflow witnesses 14.9pc growth till Oct 5</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/remittance-inflow-witnesses-149pc-growth-till-oct-5</link><description>Inflow of remittances witnessed 14.9 percent (pc) growth, reaching US$8,008 million during the period from July 1 to October 5, 2025 which was $6,967 million during the same period of the previous fiscal year.
According to the latest data of Bangladesh Bank (BB) issued on Monday, during the first</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 09:30:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No option except holding a fair election: CEC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/no-option-except-holding-a-fair-election-cec</link><description>Chief Election Commissioner AMM Nasir Uddin on Monday said there is no alternative before the Election Commission to arranging the next national election in a fair manner in this critical time as it may shape the future of the country.
“This election is probably going to shape the future of</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 09:45:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>France in crisis as government quits just hours after being appointed</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/france-in-crisis-as-government-quits-just-hours-after-being-appointed</link><description>France's new Prime Minister Sebastien Lecornu and his government resigned on Monday, hours after Lecornu announced his cabinet line-up, in a major deepening of France's political crisis that drove stocks and the euro sharply lower.
The swift, unexpected resignation came after allies and foes alike</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 10:15:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Eli Lilly to invest over $1 billion in India to expand manufacturing capacity</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/eli-lilly-to-invest-over-1-billion-in-india-to-expand-manufacturing-capacity</link><description>Eli Lilly (LLY.N) will invest more than $1 billion in India in the coming years to boost manufacturing and supply through local drugmakers, the company said on Monday, as it seeks to tap into skilled workforce to bolster its global manufacturing expansion.
The collaborations aim to increase the av</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 10:45:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Negotiators gather for Gaza talks, mediators caution deal may not be swift</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/negotiators-gather-for-gaza-talks-mediators-caution-deal-may-not-be-swift</link><description>Hamas officials were in Egypt on Monday ahead of talks with Israel that the US hopes will bring a halt to war in Gaza and release of hostages despite contentious issues like disarmament of the Palestinian militant group under Donald Trump's plan.
Talks were set to begin as the war reaches its two-</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 11:00:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>3 more die of dengue; 782 hospitalised</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/3-more-die-of-dengue-782-hospitalised</link><description>Three more deaths from dengue were reported in the 24 hours till Monday morning as Bangladesh continues to grapple with a surge in infections.
With the latest fatalities, the total number of deaths from the Qmosquito-borne disease in Bangladesh has risen to 215 this year, according to the Director</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 11:15:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Army Chief’s remarks distorted by malicious groups: ISPR</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/army-chiefs-remarks-distorted-by-malicious-groups-ispr</link><description>The Army Chief has not made any statement about giving indemnity to anyone accused of enforced disappearances, murder, or other crimes against humanity, said a statement of the Inter Services Public Relations Directorate (ISPR) on Monday.
Some dishonest and malicious groups especially individuals</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 11:30:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Avalanche in Slovenia's Alps kills three Croatian climbers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/avalanche-in-slovenias-alps-kills-three-croatian-climbers</link><description>Three Croatian climbers were killed after an avalanche struck below the Toska mountain peak in Slovenia’s Julian Alps on Sunday, rescuers said on Monday.
The search for the trekkers, who went climbing despite weather warnings, began on Sunday when rescuers found the body of one of them befor</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 11:45:23 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>