<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 11:21:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Bangladesh to call back Mustafizur for key ODIs amid his IPL tenure</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/bangladesh-to-call-back-mustafizur-for-key-odis-amid-his-ipl-tenure</link><description>Bangladesh pace bowler Mustafizur Rahman will return home for eight days during the Indian Premier League to play a limited-overs series against New Zealand.
Mustafizur was signed by Kolkata for 92 million rupees at the IPL auction, the highest price ever paid for a Bangladeshi player.
However, h</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 09:50:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Subrata Bain’s daughter Bithi remanded for 5 days</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/subrata-bains-daughter-bithi-remanded-for-5-days</link><description>A Dhaka court has remanded Khadija Yasmin Bithi, daughter of top criminal Subrata Bain, to police custody for questioning in the murder case of Jubo Dal leader Arif for five days.
Dhaka Metropolitan Magistrate Sarah Farzana Haque issued the order following a hearing on Thursday, bdnews24.com repor</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 10:05:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Enforced disappearances: Case against Hasina, 12 Army officers ordered to trial</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/enforced-disappearances-case-against-hasina-12-army-officers-ordered-to-trial</link><description>The International Crimes Tribunal has ordered a crimes against humanity case over “enforced disappearances and torture” in joint interrogation cells against ousted prime minister Sheikh Hasina and 12 former and current Army officers to trial.
A Tribunal-1 bench led by Justice Golam Mor</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 08:52:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prayers most needed for Hadi now: Home Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/prayers-most-needed-for-hadi-now-home-adviser</link><description>Home Adviser Lt Gen (retd) Md Jahangir Alam Chowdhury on Thursday urged people of the country to pray for the recovery of Inquilab Moncho spokesperson Osman Hadi who was shot in the head on December 10.
“You all please pray for our younger brother Osman Hadi so that he can recover and come b</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 09:07:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chief Justice pays courtesy call on President</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/chief-justice-pays-courtesy-call-on-president</link><description>Chief Justice Dr Syed Refaat Ahmed paid a courtesy call on President Mohammed Shahabuddin at Bangabhaban on Wednesday.
Shabbir Ahmed Akunjee, private secretary to the Public Division secretary at the President’s Office, shared the information with the media.
During the meeting, the Chief Ju</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 09:22:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mass layoffs overshadow Guinea's Simandou mega mine as output accelerates</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/africa/mass-layoffs-overshadow-guineas-simandou-mega-mine-as-output-accelerates</link><description>Guinea's Simandou mega mining project, promoted by the military government as a symbol of the country's economic transformation, is laying off thousands of workers just as it begins exporting iron ore after decades of delays and corruption scandals.
Simandou was officially launched with pomp and a</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 09:37:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EU to lift sanctions on Kosovo and release financial aid, von der Leyen says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/eu-to-lift-sanctions-on-kosovo-and-release-financial-aid-von-der-leyen-says</link><description>The European Union is set to lift sanctions it imposed on Kosovo in 2023 over tensions in the north of the country and will release financial assistance, European Commission President Ursula von der Leyen said.
EU countries introduced punitive measures against ethnic Albanian-majority Kosovo after</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 09:52:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC issues special circular to ensure law and order for polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-issues-special-circular-to-ensure-law-and-order-for-polls</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has issued a comprehensive special circular outlining measures to maintain law and order for the 13th National Parliamentary Election and the referendum on the July National Charter (Constitutional Amendment) Implementation Order, 2025, scheduled for February 12.
The c</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 10:07:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Over 1,000 civilians killed in Sudan's Darfur when paramilitary group seized camp, UN says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/africa/over-1000-civilians-killed-in-sudans-darfur-when-paramilitary-group-seized-camp-un-says</link><description>Over 1,000 civilians were killed when a Sudanese paramilitary group took over a famine-stricken displacement camp in Sudan's Darfur in April, including about a third who were summarily executed, according to a report by the UN Human Rights Office on Thursday.
For months before the April 11-13 assa</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 10:22:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Messi receives rare $1.1 million watch during India visit</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/entertainment/messi-receives-rare-11-million-watch-during-india-visit</link><description>Football legend Lionel Messi has been gifted a rare Richard Mille watch worth around Rs 99.4 million during his visit to India, adding to the buzz surrounding his stay.
It has been reported that billionaire Mukesh Ambani’s younger son, Anant Ambani, presented the exclusive gift to Messi.
Ac</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 10:37:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt briefs diplomats about election preparations</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-govt-updates-diplomats-on-election-preparations</link><description>The Ministry of Foreign Affairs has briefed foreign diplomats over updated preparation and security measures for the upcoming general elections and referendum.
It organised the briefing at the State Guest House Padma on Thursday.
In the briefing, the diplomats were informed that the Election Comm</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 10:52:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Family approves surgery for Hadi in Singapore</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/family-approves-surgery-for-hadi-in-singapore</link><description>The family of Inqilab Moncho Convenor Sharif Osman Hadi has given its permission for doctors in Singapore to proceed with a surgery as he remains in “life or death” condition.
Inqilab Moncho said in a post on Thursday that Hadi stands at the crossroads of life and death.
“Please</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 11:07:43 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>