<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 13:31:20 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Hasina tells BBC she's not guilty of crimes against humanity</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hasina-tells-bbc-shes-not-guilty-of-crimes-against-humanity</link><description>Former prime minister Sheikh Hasina has denied committing crimes against humanity during a deadly crackdown on the July Mass Uprising that toppled her, days before the International Crimes Tribunal (ICT) is due to deliver a verdict.
Hasina is accused of being the main architect behind hundreds of</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 09:53:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No imposed law can interfere with parliament’s sovereignty: Salahuddin</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/no-imposed-law-can-interfere-with-parliaments-sovereignty-salahuddin</link><description>BNP senior leader Salahuddin Ahmed on Friday said no imposed law, order or forced proposal can be allowed to interfere with the sovereignty of the National Parliament.
"We do not want the sovereignty of the National Parliament to be undermined in any way. That is why we will not allow any imposed</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 10:34:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Law enforcers will stop violence on Hasina verdict date: Khosru</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/law-enforcers-will-stop-violence-on-hasina-verdict-date-not-parties-bnps-amir-khosru</link><description>BNP National Standing Committee Member Amir Khosru Mahmud Chowdhury says if there is any unrest on the day of the verdict in the crimes against humanity case against ousted prime minister Sheikh Hasina, it will be controlled by law-enforcing agencies.
It is not the responsibility of any political</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 10:49:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt appoints new DCs in 23 districts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-appoints-new-dcs-in-23-districts</link><description>The government has appointed new Deputy Commissioners (DCs) in 23 districts.
The Ministry of Public Administration issued two separate notifications on Thursday night in this regard transferring one Mohammad Zahidul Islam Miah, DC of Narayanganj to Chattogram and assigning officers of the rank of</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 11:04:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Japan's leader ready to meet North Korea's Kim Jong Un for 'new, fruitful' relations</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/japans-leader-ready-to-meet-north-koreas-kim-jong-un-for-new-fruitful-relations</link><description>Japanese Prime Minister Sanae Takaichi said on Friday she was ready to come "face-to-face" with North Korean leader Kim Jong Un in an effort to build "new, fruitful Japan-North Korea relations".
Takaichi said she "won't rule out any option" in order to make a breakthrough in the unresolved issue o</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 11:19:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Security Adviser Khalilur to visit India</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/security-adviser-khalilur-rahman-to-lead-bangladesh-delegation-to-india</link><description>National Security Adviser Khalilur Rahman will lead the Bangladesh delegation to the 7th NSA-level meeting of the Colombo Security Conclave in the Indian capital of New Delhi.
The event is to be held on Nov 19-20, reports bdnews24.com.
Ajit Doval, the national security Adviser of India, extended</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 11:04:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Russia pounds Kyiv with drones and missiles, killing four and injuring dozens</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/russia-pounds-kyiv-with-drones-and-missiles-killing-four-and-injuring-dozens</link><description>Russia launched a massive drone and missile attack on Kyiv early on Friday, killing four people and wounding dozens in strikes on energy facilities, apartment buildings and infrastructure, Ukrainian officials said.
President Volodymyr Zelensky said the Russian forces used 430 drones and 18 missile</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 11:19:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>3 cops come under attack while investigating case in Feni</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/3-cops-come-under-attack-while-investigating-case-in-feni</link><description>Three police personnel, including a sub-inspector, were injured in an attack allegedly by the accused of a case over the stalking and beating a woman in Parshuram upazila of Feni on Friday.
The injured, SI Munna Dey, constables Ruhul Aman and Nazmul, were admitted to the Upazila Health Complex.
S</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 11:34:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Eight Islamist parties demand separate date for referendum, resignations of 3 advisors</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/eight-islamist-parties-demand-separate-date-for-referendum-resignations-of-3-advisors</link><description>Eight Islamist political parties have announced a three-point list of demands, including a separate date for the July National Charter referendum and the resignations of three advisors to the interim government.
Jamaat-e-Islami Nayeb-e-Ameer Syed Abdullah Mohammad Taher placed the demand on behalf</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 11:49:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Women must be included in development process: Army Chief</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/women-must-be-included-in-development-process-army-chief</link><description>Chief of Army Staff General Waker-Uz-Zaman on Friday said that the country cannot progress if women, who make up half of the total population, are left out of the development process.
He made the remarks while addressing the opening session of a three-day first reunion of former cadets at Joypurha</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 12:04:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCP meets IMF delegation for policy discussions</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ncp-meets-imf-delegation-for-policy-discussions</link><description>A delegation of the National Citizen Party (NCP) met with the visiting International Monetary Fund (IMF) mission team on Friday at the Intercontinental Dhaka for a courtesy and policy discussion.
The NCP delegation thanked the IMF for its continued support to Bangladesh during this crucial period</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 12:19:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Modi’s alliance set to easily win Indian Hindi heartland vote</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/modis-alliance-set-to-easily-win-indian-hindi-heartland-vote</link><description>Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi’s ruling coalition is set to comfortably retain power in the poor and populous state of Bihar, a vote count showed on Friday, giving him a boost after a disappointing national vote last year.
Winning Bihar is crucial because it is India’s third-most-</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 12:34:56 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>