<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 15:19:40 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Lawyer files petition seeking enhanced protection for lower court judges</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/lawyer-files-petition-seeking-enhanced-protection-for-lower-court-judges</link><description>A Supreme Court lawyer has filed a petition seeking directives to strengthen security for judges serving in the lower courts.
The petition was submitted on Sunday by lawyer Yunus Ali Akond, bdnews24.com reports.
He told bdnews24.com that the petition seeks orders to improve security at judges&amp;rsq</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 12:45:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>23.1pc growth of remittance inflow till Nov 15</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/231pc-growth-of-remittance-inflow-till-nov-15</link><description>Inflow of remittances witnessed a year-on-year growth of 23.1 percent reaching US$1,523 million in the 15 days of November, according to the latest data of Bangladesh Bank (BB) issued.
Last year, during the same period, the country’s remittance inflow was $1,237 million.
During the July to</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 13:00:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>2026 Bank Holidays: 28 days on central bank’s list</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/2026-bank-holidays-28-days-on-central-banks-list</link><description>Bangladesh Bank has published the official holiday calendar for 2026, announcing a total of 28 bank closure days, outside the regular weekly holidays, for all scheduled banks.
The circular, outlining the comprehensive list of holidays, was issued by Bangladesh Bank’s Department off-Side Supe</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 12:46:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BGB deployed in Dhaka, three other districts to maintain law and order</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/bgb-deployed-in-dhaka-three-other-districts-to-maintain-law-and-order</link><description>The Border Guard Bangladesh has been deployed in four districts, including Dhaka, following a spate of violent incidents such as fires and crude bomb explosions linked to the imminent verdict in a crimes against humanity case against deposed prime minister Sheikh Hasina.
On Sunday, a statement fro</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 13:01:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BRTA to introduce automation for vehicle fitness: Chairman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/brta-to-introduce-automation-for-vehicle-fitness-chairman</link><description>Chairman of Bangladesh Road Transport Authority (BRTA) Abu Mamtaj Sad Uddin Ahmed on Sunday said that the BRTA is going to introduce automation while issuing fitness certificate of the vehicles.
 “The automation for vehicle fitness certificate will be introduced under the safe system ap</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 13:16:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>4 out of 10 children have worrisome lead levels in blood, says survey of BBS, UNICEF</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/4-out-of-10-children-have-worrisome-lead-levels-in-blood-says-survey-of-bbs-unicef</link><description>Almost four out of 10 children have worrisome lead levels in their blood, according to a new survey of BBS and UNICEF.
“New findings reveal that 38% of children aged 12–59 months and nearly 8% of pregnant women have blood lead levels above safe thresholds, with Dhaka (65%) most affecte</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 13:31:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Actress Mehazabien, her brother get bail over ‘embezzlement’ charges</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/entertainment/actress-mehazabien-her-brother-get-bail-over-embezzlement-charges</link><description>Actress Mehazabien Chowdhury and her brother Alisan Chowdhury have secured bail after surrendering before a Dhaka court in an “embezzlement” case.
On Sunday evening, they turned themselved in before the Dhaka Executive Magistrate Court-3 judge Afroza Tania.
Their lawyer, Tuhin Hawlade</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 13:46:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Discusses FDI, gas exploration, trade expansion</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/discusses-fdi-gas-exploration-trade-expansion</link><description>A delegation from the Dutch-Bangla Chamber of Commerce and Industries (DBCCI) held a meeting with Foreign Affairs Adviser Md Touhid Hossain on Sunday at the Ministry of Foreign Affairs.
During the meeting, the two sides discussed a range of key issues, including foreign direct investment (FDI), ga</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 14:01:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>5 killed as bus hits covered van in Chattogram</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/5-killed-as-bus-hits-covered-van-in-chattogram</link><description>Five people were killed and 20 others injured as a bus crashed into a stationary covered-van on Dhaka-Chattogram highway at Battala in Sitakunda upazila of Chattogram district on Sunday.
The identities of the deceased could not be known immediately.
Shahadat Hossain, Officer-in-Charge of Kumira H</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 14:16:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ACC prosecutes ex-rail DG, 5 officers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/former-railway-dg-five-officers-prosecuted-over-tk-358-billion-loss-in-van-purchase</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) has filed a case against the former director general of Bangladesh Railway and five senior officials over alleged state losses of Tk 3.58 billion in the purchase of luggage vans for transporting agricultural and other goods.
The case was lodged on Sunday at the</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 14:31:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India arrests Kashmir resident over Delhi car blast</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/india-arrests-kashmir-resident-over-delhi-car-blast</link><description>India’s federal anti-terror agency said on Sunday it had arrested a resident of Kashmir who it accused of conspiring with the driver of a car that exploded in Delhi last week, killing eight people and wounding at least 20 others.
The National Investigation Agency said it had arrested Amir Ra</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 14:46:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Social Islami Bank administrators meet Dhaka South Zone branch managers on recovery initiatives</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/social-islami-bank-administrators-meet-dhaka-south-zone-branch-managers-on-recovery-initiatives</link><description>The Administrator Team of Social Islami Bank PLC held a meeting on strengthening recovery activities with Managers of 32 branches under its Dhaka South Zone on Sunday.
According to a press release, the meeting was arranged with participants joining in person at the Bank’s Head Office, while</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 15:01:14 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>