<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 15:35:58 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>EU team meets Chattogram Jamaat leaders</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/eu-team-meets-chattogram-jamaat-leaders</link><description>Visiting European Union (EU) Election Observation Mission on Wednesday held meeting with Bangladesh Jamaat Islami Chattogram city unit leaders and extensively shared mutual views on upcoming election related issues.
Jamaat leaders at the meeting expressed their deep concern over nomination of bank</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 12:58:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UNDP, BSEC join forces to scale sustainable finance</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/undp-bsec-join-forces-to-scale-sustainable-finance</link><description>The United Nations Development Programme (UNDP) and the Bangladesh Securities and Exchange Commission (BSEC) signed a Memorandum of Understanding (MoU) on Wednesday.
The MoU was signed at the BSEC Bhaban, Dhaka, Bangladesh, marking a significant step toward mobilizing long-term domestic and intern</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 13:13:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Amnesty calls for human rights guarantees during election period in open letter to Yunus</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/amnesty-calls-for-human-rights-guarantees-during-election-period-in-open-letter-to-yunus</link><description>Bangladesh’s interim government must restore public trust by guaranteeing full respect for human rights and the rule of law in the fortnight ahead of next month’s national elections, Amnesty International’s Secretary General, Agnes Callamard, said in an open letter to Chief A</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 13:28:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP-Jamaat clash leaves 30 injured in Sherpur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bnp-jamaat-clash-leaves-30-injured-in-sherpur</link><description>At least 30 people were injured in a clash between supporters of Jamaat-e-Islami and the BNP in Jhenaigati upazila of Sherpur on Wednesday afternoon.
At least six motorcycles and over a hundred of chairs were vandalised  and set on fire during the clash that began at 3 pm.
The clash broke ou</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 13:43:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh unmoved by who thinks what about its decision on drone making: Foreign Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/doesnt-matter-who-thinks-what-about-bangladesh-decision-on-drone-making-foreign-adviser</link><description>Foreign Affairs Adviser Md Touhid Hossain on Wednesday defended the government’s decision to set up a UAV (drone) manufacturing and assembly plant in Bangladesh with support from China, stressing that it matters little what others may think about the move.
“If Bangladesh plans to estab</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 13:58:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat leader’s house set on fire in Bogura</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jamaat-leaders-house-set-on-fire-in-bogura</link><description>Miscreants set the house of a local Jamaat leader on fire at Burujbazar of Gabtoli upazila in Bogura district early Wednesday.
Shahadat Hossain, superintendent of Bogura Police, said a group of miscreants set the house of Alamgir Hossain Alam, secretary of Nepaltoli union unit Jamaat-e-Islami, on</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 14:13:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh’s foreign debt repayment tops $2bn in first half of FY</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladeshs-foreign-debt-repayment-tops-2bn-in-first-half-of-fy</link><description>Bangladesh’s foreign debt repayment crossed the $2 billion mark in the first six months of the current fiscal year (FY), as the government continues to face mounting pressure from rising external liabilities.
According to the latest updated report published by the Economic Relations Division</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 13:58:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>4-year-old falls into borehole in Raozan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/4-year-old-trapped-in-abandoned-borehole-in-raozan-as-firefighters-race-to-rescue</link><description>A 4-year-old child has fallen into an abandoned deep tube well in Chattogram’s Raozan, prompting the Fire Service to launch a rescue operation.
Fire Service officials said they received information sometime after 5pm on Wednesday that a child had fallen into the borehole at Jaynagar of Kodol</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 14:13:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IPO ‘forgery’: Auditors under ACC scanner</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/acc-to-launch-investigation-into-auditing-firms-over-tk-122bn-embezzlement</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) is going to investigate the role auditing firms played in the “embezzlement” of Tk 122 billion through corruption and irregularities in banks, the share market, and financial institutions.
The anti-graft agency has called for documents from 10 CA fi</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 14:28:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bankers push for travel bans, public shaming of loan defaulters</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/bankers-push-for-travel-bans-public-shaming-of-loan-defaulters</link><description>Bangladesh’s top bankers have urged regulators to impose tougher restrictions on chronic loan defaulters, including overseas travel bans, public disclosure of identities and exclusion from trade body elections, as the country struggles with a mounting bad-loan crisis.
The Association of Bank</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 14:43:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Former CAAB chief engineer arrested for ‘corruption’ in Cox’s Bazar Airport project</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/former-caab-chief-engineer-arrested-for-corruption-in-coxs-bazar-airport-project</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission has arrested Md Habibur Rahman, a former chief engineer of the Civil Aviation Authority of Bangladesh (CAAB), on charges of corruption in the project to expand runways at Cox’s Bazar International Airport.
The arrest was confirmed by ACC Director General Akhtar</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 14:58:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Islami Bank conducts Shari‘ah Supervisory Committee meeting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/islami-bank-conducts-shariah-supervisory-committee-meeting</link><description>A meeting of the Shari‘ah Supervisory Committee of Islami Bank Bangladesh PLC was held on 27 January 2026, Tuesday at Islami Bank Tower.
Mufti Shamsuddin Zia, Chairman of the Committee, presided over the meeting, according to a media release. 
Professor Dr. Nakib Muhammad Nasrullah, Pr</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 15:13:41 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>