<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 06:34:46 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>ADR the faster way of justice dispensation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/analysis/adr-the-faster-way-of-justice-dispensation</link><description>As Bangladesh's national elections draw closer, political pressures increase -- and their wave effects are also felt in industrial areas. Especially in industry-dense zones such as Ashulia, Savar, Gazipur, and Narayanganj, a latent instability often emerges before and after elections. This directly</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 04:33:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How time changes and perception of generations follows suit</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/analysis/how-time-changes-and-perception-of-generations-follows-suit</link><description>At a time when the Generation Z or popularly known as Gen Z is making media splashes all across the globe, there are reasons to be inquisitive about what its preceding or post-generations stood for. Its immediately preceding generation is Generation Y or Millennials born between 1980 and 1994. The</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 04:48:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Maduro willing to hold 'serious' talks with US</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/maduro-willing-to-hold-serious-talks-with-us</link><description>Venezuela's President Nicolas Maduro said in a New Year's interview that his country is willing to receive US investment in its oil sector, coordinate in the fight against drug trafficking and hold serious talks with the United States.
"We must start to speak seriously, with the facts in hand," Ma</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 03:40:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>WEEKLY KITCHEN MARKET: Veg, onion prices fall; sugar rises</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/weekly-kitchen-market-veg-onion-prices-fall-sugar-rises</link><description>The prices of sugar have recorded rise increased, although the holy month of Ramadan is still about one and a half months away.
Sugar sold at Tk 105-110 a kg in the market on Friday, up from Tk 95-100 last week.
According to the Trading Corporation of Bangladesh (TCB), sugar prices increased by 5</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 03:55:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>HADI KILLING: Inqilab Mancha gives govt 30 working days to ensure justice</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hadi-killing-inqilab-mancha-gives-govt-30-working-days-to-ensure-justice</link><description>Inqilab Mancha announced that it would launch a movement to overthrow the government, if justice is not ensured for the murder of Shaheed Sharif Osman Hadi within the next 30 working days.
Abdullah Al Jaber, member secretary of Inqilab Mancha, made the announcement from a sit-in programme at Shahb</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 04:10:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump threatens Iran over protest crackdown</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-threatens-iran-over-protest-crackdown-as-deadly-unrest-flares</link><description>US President Donald Trump threatened on Friday to come to the aid of protesters in Iran if security forces fired on them, days into unrest that has left several dead and posed the biggest internal threat to Iranian authorities in years.
"We are locked and loaded and ready to go," he said in a soci</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 04:25:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ekushey Padak-winning rhymester Sukumar Barua passes away</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ekushey-padak-winning-rhymester-sukumar-barua-passes-away</link><description>CHATTOGRAM, Jan 02: Ekushey Padak-winning poet and celebrated children's rhymester Sukumar Barua passed away on Friday morning at a hospital in Chattogram. He was 87.
He breathed his last at around 6:55 AM, his daughter Anjana Barua confirmed to the media.
Family members said Sukumar Barua had be</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 04:40:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tesla loses EV crown to China's BYD</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/tesla-loses-ev-crown-to-chinas-byd</link><description>Tesla ceded its crown as the world's top electric vehicle maker to China's BYD after annual sales fell for a second year, hit by rising competition, the expiry of US tax credits and brand backlash.
With global EV sales rising 28 percent last year, BYD outsold Tesla for the first time on an annual</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 04:55:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump blocks chips deal, cites security, China-related concerns</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/trump-blocks-chips-deal-cites-security-china-related-concerns</link><description>President Donald Trump on Friday blocked US photonics firm HieFo Corp's $3 million acquisition of assets in New Jersey-based aerospace and defense specialist Emcore, citing national security and China-related concerns.
In an order released by the White House, Trump said HieFo was "controlled by a</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 05:10:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Canada asks Air India to probe pilot’s removal over alcohol influence</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/canada-asks-air-india-to-probe-incident-of-pilot-removed-from-plane-under-influence-of-alcohol-source-says</link><description>Canada's transport regulator has asked Air India to investigate an incident of a pilot who was removed from a plane before it was due to take off and found to be under the influence of alcohol, a person familiar with the matter said.
Two breathalyser tests conducted by Canadian police at Vancouver</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 05:25:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka’s temperature drops to season’s lowest 12.5°C</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dhakas-temperature-drops-to-seasons-lowest-125c</link><description>Amid shivering cold and dense fog, Dhaka recorded the season’s lowest 12.5 Degrees Celsius on Saturday morning, according to Bangladesh Metrological Department.
Dhaka and its surrounding areas may remain covered by moderate to dense fog until noon, it said.
The prevailing cold and foggy con</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 05:40:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rumeen Farhana’s income rises 22-fold in six years</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/rumeen-farhanas-income-rises-22-fold-in-six-years</link><description>The declared income and assets of Rumeen Farhana, who was recently expelled from the BNP, have changed markedly over the past six years.
A comparison of election affidavits submitted in 2019 and those filed in 2025 ahead of the 13th parliamentary polls shows that her annual income increased more t</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 05:55:04 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>