<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 06:47:26 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Why your first job salary doesn't matter and what actually does</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/article/why-your-first-job-salary-doesnt-matter-and-what-actually-does</link><description>Fresh graduates in Dhaka often find themselves trapped in a peculiar negotiation theatre. They compare offers down to the last taka, agonise over a few thousand in differences, and sometimes turn down opportunities because the salary seems inadequate compared to what their batchmates are earning. W</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 03:41:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>14 Indian fishermen held for illegal fishing in Bay</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/14-indian-fishermen-held-for-illegal-fishing-in-bay</link><description>Members of the Bangladesh Navy have detained 14 Indian fishermen along with a trawler for illegally entering Bangladesh waters and fishing in the Bay of Bengal.
They were detained on Friday night in Fairway Buoy area of the Bay and were brought to Digraj naval jetty in Mongla upazila of Bagerhat d</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 03:56:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How to score 340/340 in GRE</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/article/How-to-score-340-340-in-GRE</link><description>The Graduate Record Examination (GRE) remains one of the most significant hurdles for students pursuing postgraduate studies abroad. With its analytical writing, verbal reasoning, and quantitative sections, the test measures not just knowledge but the ability to think critically under pressure. For</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 04:11:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt raises house rent allowance for MPO-listed teachers, employees</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-raises-house-rent-allowance-for-mpo-listed-teachers-employees</link><description>The government has increased the house rent allowance for the teachers and employees of MPO-listed (Monthly Pay Order) non-government educational institutions.
A gazette notification issued on Sunday, signed by Deputy Secretary of the Ministry of Finance Mitu Mariam, revealed it. 
According</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 04:26:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Kering nears sale of beauty unit to L'Oreal, sources say</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/kering-nears-sale-of-beauty-unit-to-loreal-sources-say</link><description>French luxury group Kering, owner of fashion brand Gucci, is nearing a sale of its beauty division to L’Oreal, according to two people familiar with the situation.
One of the sources confirmed the deal would be worth around $4 billion, as per an earlier report by the Wall Street Journal, whi</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 04:56:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Smoke still rising 20 hours after fire at Dhaka airport</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/smoke-still-rising-20-hours-after-fire-at-dhaka-airport</link><description>Smoke is still rising from the cargo complex of Dhaka’s Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport, 20 hours after a fire broke out there.
Firefighters were continuing their work at the scene at 10am on Sunday, while members of other law-enforcing agencies also remained deployed in the area.
As</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 05:11:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Japan's LDP, Ishin agree to form coalition government, Kyodo says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/japans-ldp-ishin-agree-to-form-coalition-government-kyodo-says</link><description>Japan's Liberal Democratic Party and the Japan Innovation Party have broadly agreed to form a coalition government, setting the stage for the country's first female prime minister, Kyodo news agency reported on Sunday.
Sanae Takaichi, leader of the conservative LDP, and Hirofumi Yoshimura, head of</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 05:26:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The world is heading to add 57 superhot days a year, but study indicates it could have been worse</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/the-world-is-heading-to-add-57-superhot-days-a-year-but-study-indicates-it-could-have-been-worse</link><description>The world is on track to add nearly two months of dangerous superhot days each year by the end of the century, with poorer small nations hit far more often than the biggest carbon-polluting countries, a study released Thursday found.
But efforts to curb emissions of heat-trapping gases that starte</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 05:41:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Shapla’ can't be allotted as it's not on official list: EC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/shapla-cant-be-allotted-as-its-not-on-official-list-ec</link><description>Election Commissioner Md Anwarul Islam Sarker on Sunday said that the National Citizens Party (NCP) cannot be allotted ‘Shapla’ (water lily) as it is not included in the official list of symbols under the constitutional law and election rules.
He made the remark while talking to report</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 06:26:03 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>