<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 05:28:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Regulate, not ban cryptocurrency</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/regulate-not-ban-cryptocurrency</link><description>Cryptocurrency is banned in Bangladesh, but its usage is booming in the shadow of a legal grey zone and the absence of effective regulatory oversight. Bangladesh ranks 13th among 151 countries worldwide in terms of cryptocurrency usage, according to the  Global Crypto Adoption Index 2025, publ</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 19:21:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Persuading SoEs, MNCs to join stock markets</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/persuading-soes-mncs-to-join-stock-markets</link><description>If the benchmark index of a stock exchange loses 351 points in a year, its impacts on that bourse depend on its current level and typical volatility. For the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE), this margin is severe because of its current level staying below 5,000 mark. A 351-point drop in the DSE market i</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 19:36:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Revised rules put dividend-deficient mutual funds at liquidity risk</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/revised-rules-put-dividend-deficient-mutual-funds-at-liquidity-risk</link><description>Many pooled funds risk liquidation under the revised mutual fund rules if they fail to pay dividends for a third consecutive year.
Under the Bangladesh Securities and Exchange Commission (Mutual Fund Rules, 2025), trustees may convene a meeting of unitholders to decide whether they prefer liquidat</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 01:14:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Banks lift Dhaka bourse out of losing run</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/banks-lift-dhaka-bourse-out-of-losing-run</link><description>The Dhaka bourse closed Wednesday's session with a moderate gain in the broad index, driven by appreciation in blue-chip stocks, breaking the losing streak of the previous two sessions.
Bank stocks were the primary contributors to the day's positive momentum.
The market opened on a positive note,</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 01:29:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Agent licences scrapped in non-life insurance</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/agent-licences-scrapped-in-non-life-insurance</link><description>The insurance regulator has put into effect a ban on agent commissions in the non-life insurance sector this month, effectively approving the removal of agents from the segment.
On Wednesday, the Insurance Development and Regulatory Authority (IDRA) reaffirmed the decision and conveyed it to all s</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 01:44:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt hesitating for long 'in fear of impact' on present operators</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-hesitating-for-long-in-fear-of-impact-on-present-operators</link><description>The government has long been hesitating to introduce electric bus services in the capital, 'apprehending its impact' on the existing bus operators, which have hardly cooperated to bring discipline in the public transportation system, insiders said.
They also said the Road Transport and Highways Di</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 01:59:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Aviation prospects abound, but fleet proportionately undersized</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/aviation-prospects-abound-but-fleet-proportionately-undersized</link><description>Bangladesh's state-run airline feels incapacitated to increase flight frequencies and fly to potentially profitable new international destinations, belying rising passenger demand and revenue growth, sources say.
Biman Bangladesh Airlines is caught in such a paradox because the national airline ha</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 02:14:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Warrants issued against ex-minister Saifuzzaman Chy, 35 others</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/warrants-issued-against-ex-minister-saifuzzaman-chy-35-others</link><description>A Chattogram court has issued arrest warrants against former land minister Saifuzzaman Chowdhury and 35 others in connection with a case involving the embezzlement and laundering of Tk 250 million (25 crore) from United Commercial Bank Limited (UCB).
The charge sheet, submitted in relation to the</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 02:29:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Listing of 10 blue-chip cos: SoEs commit, MNCs to seek board approvals</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/listing-of-10-blue-chip-cos-soes-commit-mncs-to-seek-board-approvals</link><description>Ten state-owned enterprises (SoEs) and multinational companies (MNCs) have agreed in principle to offload a portion of their shares on the stock market, following board-level approvals or renewed commitment to seeking them.
The move is part of the government's broader effort to deepen the capital</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 02:44:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Forex reserves to stay over $32b even after ACU payments</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/forex-reserves-to-stay-over-32b-even-after-acu-payments</link><description>Bangladesh's treasury won't feel dollar stress even after settling import- payment obligations to the Asian Clearing Union (ACU) member- countries as gross foreign-exchange reserves are yet expected to stay over US$32 billion.
The latest payment of $1.5 billion is scheduled to be remitted to the A</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 02:59:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Migration from Bangladesh on rise amid poor govt support</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/migration-from-bangladesh-on-rise-amid-poor-govt-support</link><description>The number of Bangladeshi outbound migrant workers has been on the rise in recent years amidst inadequate budgetary and other technical support from the government for the key remittance earning sector.
The Refugee and Migratory Movements Research Unit (RMMRU) said this in its year-end analysis, w</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 04:00:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Auction for 700 MHz spectrum turns into single-player contest as Robi pulls out</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/auction-for-700-mhz-spectrum-turns-into-single-player-contest-as-robi-pulls-out</link><description>The planned auction for the 700-megahertz (MHz) spectrum has been reduced to a single-player contest following Robi Axiata's formal withdrawal, leaving Grameenphone as the only remaining operator in the field.
The move has left the telecom regulator with little option other than a direct allocatio</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 05:01:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>