<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 11:24:18 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Bancharampur UNO Ferdous Ara passes away</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bancharampur-uno-ferdous-ara-passes-away</link><description>Ferdous Ara, Upazila Nirbahi Officer (UNO) of Bancharampur upazila in Brahmanbaria, died on Wednesday at a hospital in Dhaka.
She breathed her last around 7:00 am, said Additional Deputy Commissioner (General) Ranjan Chandra Dey.
He said Ferdous Ara fell sick on Monday and was admitted to a hospi</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 08:00:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>FIFA World Cup trophy arrives in Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/fifa-world-cup-trophy-arrives-in-dhaka</link><description>The glittering FIFA World Cup trophy arrived in Dhaka on Wednesday morning as part of the FIFA World Cup Trophy Tour.
The trophy, accompanied by Brazilian 2002 FIFA World Cup winner and FIFA ambassador Gilberto da Silva, landed at Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport around 10:00 am.
Tabith Moh</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 08:15:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Elections will be held on Feb 12, CA reaffirms US diplomats</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/elections-will-be-held-on-feb-12-ca-reaffirms-us-diplomats</link><description>Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus has reaffirmed his government’s commitment to hold the general elections and the referendum as scheduled on February 12.
The chief adviser made the remarks when two former senior United States diplomats—Albert Gombis and Morse Tan, both of whom se</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 08:30:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Can crowdfunding democratise Bangladesh's electoral politics?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/others/can-crowdfunding-democratise-bangladeshs-electoral-politics</link><description>The 13th national parliamentary election of Bangladesh is knocking at the door. According to the Election Commission, the landmark polling day has been scheduled for 12th February of this year, following prolonged anticipation to revive the country's democratic process.
During the election period,</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 09:15:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>China's trade surplus surges 20pc to a record $1.2 trillion, even with Trump's tariffs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/chinas-trade-surplus-surges-20pc-to-a-record-12-trillion-even-with-trumps-tariffs</link><description>China’s trade surplus surged to a record of almost $1.2 trillion in 2025, the government said Wednesday, as exports to other countries made up for slowing shipments to the U.S. under President Donald Trump's onslaught of higher tariffs.
China's exports rose 5.5% for the whole of last year to</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 09:30:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Packaging industry can reach $50b exports with right policies: Amir Khasru</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/packaging-industry-can-reach-50b-exports-with-right-policies-amir-khasru</link><description>Bangladesh’s packaging industry has the potential to reach $50 billion in exports if proper policy support is provided, said Amir Khasru Mahmud Chowdhury, a BNP Standing Committee member and former commerce minister.
If the BNP is able to form the next government, adequate policies will be f</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 09:17:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Yunus asks BSC to sustain profit momentum</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/yunus-asks-bangladesh-shipping-corporation-to-maintain-earnings-after-tk-8b-in-earnings</link><description>Chief Advisor Muhammad Yunus has directed the Bangladesh Shipping Corporation (BSC) to sustain its profitability after the state-owned company earned nearly Tk 8 billion in revenue in the 2024–25 fiscal year.
He issued the instruction on Wednesday during a ceremony where a cheque worth Tk 2.</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 09:32:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mirza Abbas alleges code of conduct violations in campaign</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/mirza-abbas-alleges-code-of-conduct-violations-in-campaign</link><description>BNP senior leader Mirza Abbas on Wednesday alleged that some candidates are making provocative remarks during the mass  campaign, which he termed as a violation of the electoral code of conduct.
“Some candidates are making provocative remarks. Their behaviour and comments are extremely</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 09:47:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>'We must stop unnecessary land acquisition' : Land Adviser Ali Imam</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/we-must-stop-unnecessary-land-acquisition-land-adviser-ali-imam</link><description>Land Adviser Ali Imam Majumder on Tuesday called for responsible land acquisition in Bangladesh, warning that large tracts of land are often acquired without genuine need, putting public resources and local communities at risk.
Speaking at a seminar titled 'Strengthening Institutional Capacity and</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 10:02:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ex-ACC commissioner Jahurul questioned for 3 hours</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/acc-grills-ex-commissioner-jahurul-haque-over-bribery-abuse-of-power-allegations</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) has questioned its former commissioner Md Jahurul Haque for nearly three hours as part of an inquiry into allegations of bribery, abuse of power and forgery.
Jahurul arrived at the ACC headquarters in Segunbagicha around 10:30am on Wednesday, accompanied by his</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 10:17:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Lottery system returns to IPOs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh-restores-lottery-system-for-ipo-share-allocation-under-revised-rules</link><description>The lottery system for allocating shares to investors in initial public offerings has been reinstated in Bangladesh’s capital market.
Officials of the Bangladesh Securities and Exchange Commission (BSEC) say shares of companies coming to the market through IPOs will now be distributed throug</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 10:32:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>6 die in Rangpur over 3 days after ‘drinking bootleg alcohol’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/6-die-in-rangpur-over-3-days-after-drinking-bootleg-alcohol</link><description>Two more people have died of alcohol poisoning after drinking “bootleg alcohol” in Rangpur, leading to a tally of six deaths from alcohol over three days in the district. Two others have been hospitalised.
The bodies were recovered around midnight on Tuesday and sent to Rangpur Medical</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 10:47:37 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>