<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 05:16:54 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Shahidul Alam returns home after release from Israel</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/shahidul-alam-returns-home-after-release-from-israel</link><description>Photographer and human rights activist Shahidul Alam has returned to Bangladesh after being freed by Israeli authorities following his detention from a Gaza-bound aid flotilla on October 8.
He arrived in Dhaka early on Saturday morning from Istanbul after the Turkish government stepped in to secur</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 02:02:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Machado dared to imagine a better world, worked tirelessly: Prof Yunus</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/machado-dared-to-imagine-a-better-world-worked-tirelessly-prof-yunus</link><description>Chief Adviser Prof Muhammad Yunus has extended his hearty congratulations to María Corina Machado on receiving the 2025 Nobel Peace Prize for her courageous fight for democracy in her beloved Venezuela.
Machado has faced oppression with steadfast resolve, never wavering in her commitment to</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 02:17:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>icddr,b's children's food named among TIME's Best Inventions</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/icddrbs-childrens-food-named-among-times-best-inventions</link><description>A complementary food for undernourished children, developed jointly by icddr,b and Washington University, has been included in TIME's Best Inventions of 2025 under Social Impact category.
The gut-restoring complementary food has been developed through a long-standing collaboration between Internat</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 02:32:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DU suspends Autumn Fest over allegations of 'fascist links'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/du-suspends-autumn-fest-over-allegations-of-fascist-links</link><description>The 'Shorot Utsob' (Autumn Festival) at the Faculty of Fine Arts (Charukala) of Dhaka University (DU) has been postponed following allegations that one of the organisers has 'links to fascism'.
The decision was announced on Friday in a statement, signed by Professor Dr. Md. Azharul Islam, Dean of</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 02:47:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>RU’s five-day training for teachers ends today</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/rus-five-day-training-for-teachers-ends-today</link><description>Rajshahi University (RU) has, for the first time, launched a five-day training workshop for newly appointed teachers to enhance their teaching skills and academic orientation.
A total of 84 young faculty members from 17 departments are participating in the programme, organised by the university's</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 03:02:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>One in three child marriages ends up in divorce</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/one-in-three-child-marriages-ends-up-in-divorce</link><description>Nearly one in three child marriages ends up in divorce, often pushing children and young women towards facing stigma and financial hardship, according to a study conducted on the occasion of the International Day of Girl.
Plan International has conducted the study through interviewing girls and yo</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 03:17:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Young researchers' conf'ce at DU today</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/young-researchers-confce-at-du-today</link><description>In a bid to explore the innovative potential and nurture the creativity of school students, '10th Chintar Chash Young Researcher Conference, 2025' will take place at the Teacher-Student Centre (TSC) of Dhaka University (DU) today (Saturday).
DU Vice-Chancellor Dr Niaz Ahmed Khan will formally inau</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 03:32:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mobile, internet connections drop in August</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/mobile-internet-connections-drop-in-august</link><description>Bangladesh's mobile and internet subscriptions fell in August 2025 after showing modest gains in the previous month, according to the latest data released by the Bangladesh Telecommunication Regulatory Commission (BTRC).
The total number of active mobile connections dropped to 188.64 million in Au</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 03:47:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CMP bans public progs in Ctg port area for a month</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/cmp-bans-public-progs-in-ctg-port-area-for-a-month</link><description>The Chattogram Metropolitan Police (CMP) has banned all kinds of processions, meetings, human chains, and similar programmes in the Chattogram port area for 30 days.
As a result, nobody can arrange such events there for the next one month, starting today.
The information was revealed in a public</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 04:02:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka-Ctg highway’s 10-lane expansion shelved; focus shifts to railway</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/dhaka-ctg-highways-10-lane-expansion-shelved-focus-shifts-to-railway</link><description>The government has decided to abandon its plan to expand the Dhaka–Chattogram Highway into a 10-lane road, shifting focus instead to upgrading the country’s railway network.
The decision comes in response to growing land constraints and the need for a sustainable transport system, said</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 04:17:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>TCB seeks Tk 14.11b from govt to offset its losses against subsidised commodity sale</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/tcb-seeks-tk-1411b-from-govt-to-offset-its-losses-against-subsidised-commodity-sale</link><description>Trading Corporation of Bangladesh (TCB) has sought over Tk 14.11 billion as subsidy from the government to help offset its financial losses on account of selling essential commodities at subsidised rates, sources said.
The state-run agency in a letter recently requested the commerce ministry to ta</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 04:32:49 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>