<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 11:20:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Govt sets target to produce over 44.1m tonnes food grains</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-sets-target-to-produce-over-441m-tonnes-food-grains</link><description>The government has set a target to produce over 44.10 million tonnes of rice and wheat during the summer and winter season in the 2025-26 fiscal year. 
Along with the rice production, the government also has fixed targets to produce other crops, including summer and winter vegetables, maize,</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 08:48:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India responds after Hasina sentenced to death</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/india-responds-after-hasina-sentenced-to-death</link><description>India on Monday reacted to the death sentence verdict ordered for former Bangladesh prime minister Sheikh Hasina by a tribunal court for “crimes against humanity” against student protesters in Dhaka last year that led to her ouster, reports hindustantimes.com. Hasina had fled to In</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 09:03:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Online-based ‘Shisha’ supply ring busted in Dhaka; 18kg seized</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/online-based-shisha-supply-ring-busted-in-dhaka-18kg-seized</link><description>The Department of Narcotics Control (DNC) has arrested two members of an online-based Shisha (a kind of drug) supply ring and seized 18kg of Shisha during a special drive in Dhaka.
According to DNC, acting on secret information about a network using Facebook and WhatsApp to distribute contraband S</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 09:05:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt reviewing body camera purchase plan: Finance Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-reviewing-body-camera-purchase-plan-finance-adviser</link><description>Finance Adviser Dr Salehuddin Ahmed on Tuesday said the government is reviewing the proposed procurement of body cameras to ensure transparency, rational planning and appropriate use in sensitive operational areas.
The initial proposal sought a very large number of body cameras, prompting the comm</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 09:20:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Another 170 Bangladeshis return home from Libya</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/another-170-bangladeshis-return-home-from-libya</link><description>Another 170 Bangladeshi nationals returned home from Libya on Tuesday.
They arrived at Dhaka at 6:10 am on Burak Air chartered flight, according to the Ministry of Foreign Affairs, UNB reports. 
The repatriation was coordinated by the Bangladesh Embassy in Libya, the Ministry of Foreign Affa</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 09:35:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt okays 50,000MT rice import ahead of Ramadan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/govt-okays-50000mt-rice-import-ahead-of-ramadan</link><description>The government on Tuesday approved a proposal to import some 50,000 tonnes of non-Basmati parboiled rice through international open tender method for the current fiscal year (FY26).
The approval came from a meeting of the Advisers Council Committee on Government Purchase (CCGP) held on Tuesday at</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 09:50:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Interim govt achieves almost all its targets: Shafiqul Alam</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/interim-govt-achieves-almost-all-its-targets-shafiqul-alam</link><description>Refuting some people's claims that this interim government is "the weakest administration in Bangladesh's history", Chief Adviser's Press Secretary Shafiqul Alam today (Tuesday) said that in reality the government has achieved almost all of its targets in just 15 months.
". . . I say with confiden</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 10:05:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>E-passport booklets procurement gets CCGP nod</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/e-passport-booklets-procurement-gets-ccgp-nod</link><description>The Advisers Council Committee on Government Purchase (CCGP) on Tuesday recommended direct government-to-government procurement of e-passport booklets and related training under a project titled “Introduction of E-Passport and Automated Border Control Management in Bangladesh.”
The rec</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 10:20:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BB resets prices of commemorative gold, silver coins</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bb-resets-prices-of-commemorative-gold-silver-coins-1</link><description>Bangladesh Bank (BB) has reset the prices of commemorative gold and silver coins citing a price hike of the precious metals in local and international markets.
The prices of gold coins have been increased to Tk 1,85,000 each while the prices of silver coins have been hiked to Tk 14,000 each.</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 10:35:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DBL, Bright Ceramics host Annual Business Conference 2025</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/dbl-bright-ceramics-host-annual-business-conference-2025</link><description>DBL and Bright Ceramics successfully hosted their Annual Business Conference 2025 on November 14 &amp; 15, bringing together business partners from across the nation.
Centered on the inspiring theme “Echoes of Excellence,” the conference united dealers, distributors and partners from every</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 10:50:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Home Adviser signals zero tolerance on unrest as election in February</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/home-adviser-signals-zero-tolerance-on-unrest-as-election-in-february</link><description>Home Affairs Adviser Lt Gen (retd) Md Jahangir Alam Chowdhury on Tuesday said law-enforcement agencies are fully prepared to act against any attempt to destabilise the country, as the next national election is going to be held in the first half of February.
He made the remarks at a meeting with Ge</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 11:05:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Malaysian High commissioner visits CSE</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/malaysian-high-commissioner-visits-cse</link><description>Mohd Shuhada Othman, High Commissioner of Malaysia to Bangladesh recently visited CSE head office in Chattogram.
CSE Managing Director M. Shaifur Rahman Mazumdar, FCA, FCMA, briefed the High Commissioner in detail through a presentation about CSE’s contribution, current role and future devel</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 11:20:24 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>