<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 16:24:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>‘Plot graft’: 22 people testify against Hasina, Rehana, Tulip</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/plot-graft-22-people-testify-against-hasina-rehana-tulip</link><description>A Dhaka court has recorded testimonies of 22 witnesses in three separate cases by the Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) against deposed prime minister Sheikh Hasina and members of her family over forgery allegations in the allocation of plots in the Purbachal New Town Project.
Her sister Sheikh Reh</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 14:39:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gross forex reserves stays over $31b after ACU payment</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/gross-forex-reserves-stays-over-31b-after-acu-payment</link><description>Bangladesh’s gross foreign exchange (forex) reserves remain above the US$31 billion mark, even after settling import payment obligations worth US$1.60 billion to Asian Clearing Union (ACU) member countries on Sunday.  
After the payment for the September-October period of 2025, the</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 13:09:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DSEX falls 68 points at week’s start as CSE also declines</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/dsex-falls-68-points-at-weeks-start-as-cse-also-declines</link><description>The week started on a weak note as the Dhaka Stock Exchange’s DSEX fell 68 points to 4,899, while the Chittagong Stock Exchange’s all-share index dropped 35 points.
The DSE’s Shariah-based DSES index declined by 16 points and the blue-chip DS30 index lost 11 points.
Most stocks</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 13:24:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Police break off non-MPO teachers’ rally</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/police-disperse-non-mpo-teachers-rally-with-water-cannon-sound-grenade</link><description>Police have used water cannons and stun grenades to disperse a rally of teachers demanding the inclusion of non-MPO educational institutions under the monthly-pay-order scheme.
Several teachers were reportedly injured during the incident on Sunday afternoon.
The clash occurred when the teachers a</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 13:39:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh Bank formulating AI policy to boost security, efficiency in banking</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh-bank-formulating-ai-policy-to-boost-security-efficiency-in-banking</link><description>Bangladesh Bank is in the process of formulating a comprehensive policy to regulate the use of Artificial Intelligence (AI) in the banking sector.
The primary goal of the policy is to ensure the safe and effective deployment of AI technology for purposes including fraud prevention, risk management</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 13:54:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Abul Khair Group honours GPA-5 achievers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/abul-khair-group-honours-gpa-5-achievers</link><description>Abul Khair Group has honoured the children of its employees who achieved GPA-5 in the SSC and HSC examinations this year.
Like every year, the country’s leading and diversified industrial conglomerate organised a grand ceremony to celebrate the young achievers, according to a press release.</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 14:09:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>10 injured in BNP ‘factional clash’ during electioneering in Cumilla</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/10-injured-in-bnp-factional-clash-during-electioneering-in-cumilla</link><description>Ten people were injured in a clash allegedly between two factions of BNP during electioneering in Laksham upaizla of Cumilla district on Sunday.
Witnesses said an altercation ensued between the supporters of Samira Azim Dola, daughter of former MP Anwarul Azim and BNP-nominated candidate Abul Kala</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 14:24:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prime Bank wins ‘Fintech Innovation of the Year-Bank’ award</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/prime-bank-wins-fintech-innovation-of-the-year-bank-award</link><description>Prime Bank PLC has been awarded the ‘Fintech Innovation of the Year-Bank’ award in recognition of launching Bangladesh’s first Sign Language Call Service in the banking industry, according to a press release.
The award was presented to Prime Bank at the 3rd Bangladesh Fintech Awa</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 14:39:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Muhit Rahman joins ONE Bank as managing director</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/muhit-rahman-joins-one-bank-as-managing-director</link><description>Seasoned banker Muhit Rahman joined ONE Bank PLC as its Managing Director on Sunday, according to a press release.
Muhit brings with him more than 30 years of experience in corporate, institutional and investment banking, having served in senior leadership positions at Standard Chartered Bank and</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 14:54:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>MTB Foundation observes White Cane Safety Day 2025</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/mtb-foundation-observes-white-cane-safety-day-2025</link><description>To observe the ‘White Cane Safety Day 2025’, MTB Foundation, in partnership with Centre for Services and Information on Disability (CSID) recently celebrated this year’s theme - “Vision Beyond Sight: Celebrating Independence, Resilience, and Recognizing Achievements of the B</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 15:09:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mercantile Bank launches ‘Mercantile Priority Zenith’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/mercantile-bank-launches-mercantile-priority-zenith</link><description>Mercantile Bank PLC today launched its premium banking segment, ‘Mercantile Priority Zenith’, at MBL Centre, Satmasjid Road, Dhanmondi, according to a press release.
After speaking on the occasion, Managing Director of the bank Mati Ul Hasan formally inaugurated the priority centre by</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 15:24:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Islami Bank inks with Pundra University and TMSS institutions</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/islami-bank-inks-with-pundra-university-and-tmss-institutions</link><description>Islami Bank Bangladesh PLC and Pundra University, Bogura, along with TMSS Medical College and 14 other educational institutions operated under TMSS, signed a Memorandum of Understanding (MoU) at the university auditorium regarding fee payments through CellFin and mCash.
Under this agreement, stude</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 15:39:26 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>