<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 05:27:43 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>ACC files five cases against HBM Iqbal, others</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/acc-files-five-cases-against-hbm-iqbal-others</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) has filed five cases against former chairman of Premier Bank and Awami League leader HBM Iqbal, and others on charges of embezzlement of Tk 81.7 million in the name of advertisement promotion.
Other accused include board members of the bank, senior officials an</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 02:29:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Speakers call for integrated plan to protect ecosystem</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/speakers-call-for-integrated-plan-to-protect-ecosystem</link><description>Speakers at a workshop on Tuesday called for an urgent and integrated master plan to safeguard the Saint Martin's Island.
The Ministry of Environment, Forest and Climate Change (MoEFCC), in collaboration with the Department of Environment (DoE) and with support from the United Nations Development</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 02:44:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Japan gives Tk 13.8m for school transport, classroom expansion</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/japan-gives-tk-138m-for-school-transport-classroom-expansion</link><description>Japan has extended a grant of about BDT 13.8 million (US$ 115,723) to two Bangladeshi non-governmental organisations (NGOs) to support education-focused projects for improving safety and access for vulnerable children.
The funding, provided under Japan's Grant Assistance for Grass-Roots Human Secu</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 02:59:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Revoke decision to bear foreign observers' housing, meal costs&lt; TIB urges Election Commission</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/revoke-decision-to-bear-foreign-observers-housing-meal-costs-tib-urges-election-commission</link><description>Transparency International Bangladesh (TIB), on Tuesday, called for the revocation of the Election Commission's (EC) 'imprudent' decision to bear accommodation and meal costs of the foreign observers during the upcoming election.
TIB said, "The Election Commission's decision to bear the accommodat</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 03:14:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>What does contemporary art remember about home, water, and belonging?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/what-does-contemporary-art-remember-about-home-water-and-belonging</link><description>On the ground floor of the safeguarded enveloped Bay's Edgewater building, resides a gallery home to emerging artists trying to solidify their aims of becoming the next generation of Ranabi or Kanak Chanpa Chakma. The gallery breathes life into the quiet aspirations of painters, sculptors, and mixe</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 03:29:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A 'budget-friendly' day trip to Bandarban</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/a-budget-friendly-day-trip-to-bandarban</link><description>What if Bandarban, the hill city of Bangladesh, typically requiring multiple days to explore, could be experienced in less than 24 hours? It might sound impossible, but that's precisely what is happening today.
In recent years, several social media groups have begun organising a day trip to Bandar</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 03:44:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique meets Dhaka-17 BNP leaders</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-meets-dhaka-17-bnp-leaders</link><description>Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) Acting Chairperson Tarique Rahman on Tuesday held a view-exchange meeting with leaders and activists of the Dhaka-17 constituency.
The meeting took place at the BNP Chairperson's Gulshan office in the capital on Tuesday.
Tarique Rahman is contesting as a candida</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 03:59:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Over 1.5m Bangladeshis register for postal votes</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/over-15m-bangladeshis-register-for-postal-votes</link><description>A total of 1,533,682 Bangladeshis, both from home and abroad, have registered for postal voting for the 13th Jatiya Sangsad election and the referendum, scheduled for February 12.
Of the total, 761,140 voters reside in Bangladesh. They are unable to cast their votes in person, mainly due to their</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 04:14:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Venezuela to export $2bn worth of oil to US</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/venezuela-to-export-2bn-worth-of-oil-to-us</link><description>Caracas and Washington have reached a deal to export up to $2 billion worth of Venezuelan crude to the United States, US President Donald Trump said on Tuesday, a flagship negotiation that would divert supplies from China while helping Venezuela avoid deeper oil production cuts.
The agreement is a</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 04:29:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Venezuela under Maduro shipped gold worth $5.2 billion to Switzerland</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/venezuela-under-maduro-shipped-gold-worth-52-billion-to-switzerland</link><description>Venezuela transported gold worth almost 4.14 billion Swiss francs ($5.20 billion) to Switzerland during the early years of the leadership of ousted President Nicolas Maduro, customs data shows.
The South American country sent 113 metric tons of the precious metal to Switzerland from 2013 - when Ma</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 04:44:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gas crunch hits fertiliser output</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/gas-crunch-hits-fertiliser-output</link><description>The state-run BCIC has sought an uninterrupted supply of at least 197 million cubic feet of gas per day (MMCFD) to keep four urea fertiliser factories operational for 11 consecutive months.
The Bangladesh Chemical Industries Corporation (BCIC) recently made a proposal to the Ministry of Industries</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 04:59:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US adds more nations, including Bangladesh, to costly visa bond policy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/us-adds-more-nations-including-bangladesh-to-costly-visa-bond-policy</link><description>President Donald Trump's administration has put 25 more countries, including Bangaldesh, on a list of nations whose citizens could be required to post bonds of up to $15,000 to apply for entry into the US, the State Department website showed on Tuesday.
The list mostly included countries from Afri</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 05:14:41 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>