<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 17:20:26 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Khaleda built BNP into a major force: Monju</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/khaleda-zia-made-bnp-a-major-political-force-muzzammil-husain</link><description>Senior journalist Muzzammil Husain Monju has described the leadership of former prime minister Khaleda Zia as “extraordinary”, saying it was under her stewardship that the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) emerged as a major political force.
The political analyst made the remarks whil</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 14:00:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dialogue with journalists on technology-facilitated gender-based violence held</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dialogue-with-journalists-on-technology-facilitated-gender-based-violence-held</link><description>A dialogue with journalists on technology-facilitated gender-based violence (TFGBV), focusing on prevention, response, and the promotion of inclusive digital development, was held in the city on Tuesday.
The programme was organised by the Bangladesh NGOs Network for Radio and Communication (BNNRC)</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 14:15:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Former home minister Mahmudul Hasan passes away</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/former-home-minister-mahmudul-hasan-passes-away</link><description>Former home minister and BNP vice chairman Major General (Retd.) Mahmudul Hasan passed away on Wednesday at the age of 90.
Mahmudul Hasan, former Member of Parliament (MP) from Tangail-5 constituency, breathed his last at 3 pm at his residence in the capital due to old age complications.
Mahmudul</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 14:30:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Man dies after falling ill at Khaleda’s funeral</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/mourner-dies-after-falling-ill-at-khaleda-zias-funeral</link><description>A man has died after he fell ill after attending the funeral prayers of former prime minister and BNP chairperson Khaleda Zia.
The dead, identified as 56-year-old Nirob Hossain, hailed from Patuakhali’s Bauphal Upazila.
According to police, he fell ill and collapsed on Wednesday afternoon w</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 14:44:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gold prices drop by Tk 2,741 per bhori on year’s last trading day</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/gold-prices-drop-by-tk-2741-per-bhori-on-years-last-trading-day</link><description>Gold prices in the domestic market fell sharply on the last day of the year on Wednesday, with the price of 22-carat gold reduced by Tk 2,741 per bhori, according to the Bangladesh Jewellers Association (BAJUS).
Following the latest adjustment, the price of 22-carat gold has been fixed at Tk 224,1</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 14:59:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A defining crossroads: Bangladesh’s journey through 2025</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/a-defining-crossroads-bangladeshs-journey-through-2025</link><description>Bangladesh bade farewell to 2025 standing at a crossroads expecting to lead the South Asian nation to a new political and social transition against the backdrop of renewed public expectations. The year unfolded amid post–July Uprising realities, with governance reforms, electoral preparedness</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 15:14:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No progress of human rights in 2025: MSF</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/no-progress-of-human-rights-in-2025-msf</link><description>The rights body Manabadhikar Songskriti Foundation (MSF) has said the outgoing year 2025 saw no progress in Bangladesh’s human rights situation.
In its year-end assessment, the rights body said the overall political, social, democratic and legal climate, along with the human rights situation</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 15:29:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique declares Tk 20 million assets, cleared in 77 cases</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-declares-tk-20-million-assets-cleared-in-77-cases</link><description>Acting BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman, running from the Bogura-6 (Sadar) seat in the parliamentary elections, has submitted an affidavit declaring assets worth approximately Tk 19.7 million.
Returning to Bangladesh on Thursday after more than 17 years in the UK, the 57-year-old leader also disclosed</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 15:44:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh mission in Mauritius opens condolence book</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-mission-in-mauritius-opens-condolence-book</link><description>Bangladesh High Commission in Mauritius opened a condolence book in Port Louis today as global leaders and diplomats paid tribute to former Prime Minister Begum Khaleda Zia.
Following the death of the three-time prime minister, the condolence book was opened at the Bangladesh High Commission in Po</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 16:00:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Forex reserves hit three-year high as December remittances cross $3.0 billion mark</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/forex-reserves-hit-three-year-high-as-december-remittances-cross-30-billion-mark</link><description>Bangladesh’s foreign exchange reserves have surged to the $33 billion mark, reaching a three-year high, bolstered by a massive influx of remittances and strategic dollar purchases by the central bank.
According to the latest data from the Bangladesh Bank, expatriate Bangladeshis sent $3.04 b</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 16:15:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tasnim Jara declares assets worth Tk 19 lakh, annual income Tk 7 lakh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tasnim-jara-declares-assets-worth-tk-19-lakh-annual-income-tk-7-lakh</link><description>Tasnim Jara, the independent candidate for Dhaka-9 constituency, has assets worth some Tk 19.14 lakh and her annual income is Tk 7.14 lakh, according to the affidavit she submitted to the Election Commission ahead of the 13th National Parliament election.
The affidavit shows that she is not a dual</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 16:30:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>World begins to bid goodbye to 2025</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/world-begins-to-bid-goodbye-to-2025-with-fireworks-and-icy-plunges</link><description>As Wednesday turned to Thursday, people around the world said goodbye to a sometimes challenging 2025 and expressed hopes for the new year to come.
Midnight arrived first on the islands closest to the International Date Line in the Pacific Ocean, including Kiritimati (Christmas Island), Tonga and</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 16:45:31 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>