<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 14:22:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>BNP to ensure Bangladesh Bank’s full independence: Khosru</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-to-ensure-bangladesh-banks-full-independence-khosru</link><description>BNP standing committee member Amir Khosru Mahmud Chowdhury on Monday said his party, if voted to power, will abolish the Financial Institutions Division (FID) to grant full independence to the Bangladesh Bank.
“BNP is committed to empowering the central bank and decentralising government aut</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 10:48:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tariffs anxiety prompts US importers to place spring orders early</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/tariffs-anxiety-prompts-us-importers-to-place-spring-orders-early</link><description>Small importers for large US retailers rushed in China-made strollers and wares meant for spring and are storing the goods in their own warehouses to avoid the big tariff bills that had been threatened over the next month.
Before Sino-American talks on the sidelines of the ASEAN Summit in Kuala Lu</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 11:18:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ONE Bank publishes first Carbon Disclosure Report</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/one-bank-publishes-first-carbon-disclosure-report</link><description>ONE Bank PLC (OBPLC) has been credited with one of the pioneer banks in Bangladesh for publishing their 1st ‘Carbon Disclosure Report' in Carbon Accounting Financials (PCAF) website in accordance with the PCAF guidelines, according to a press release.
This report is prepared basing on 55 per</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 11:33:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US Navy helicopter, fighter jet crash in South China Sea in separate incidents</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-navy-helicopter-fighter-jet-crash-in-south-china-sea-in-separate-incidents</link><description>A US Navy helicopter and a fighter jet crashed separately into the South China Sea within the space of an hour during routine operations conducted from the same aircraft carrier on Sunday, the US Navy said, adding all personnel were safe.
The incidents came while President Donald Trump was on a vi</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 11:48:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh, Pakistan sign MoU to facilitate export of Halal products</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/mou-signed-between-bsti-and-pha</link><description>A Memorandum of Understanding (MoU) was signed between the Bangladesh Standards and Testing Institution (BSTI), the national standards and regulatory body of Bangladesh, and the Pakistan Halal Authority (PHA), Pakistan’s Halal certification agency, to enhance cooperation in the field of Halal</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 12:03:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nestlé Bangladesh conducts free ‘Medical Camp’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/nestle-bangladesh-conducts-free-medical-camp</link><description>Reaffirming its vision to enhance the quality of life for everyone, today and for generations to come, Nestlé Bangladesh is immensely proud to announce the successful completion of a 'Medical Camp' organized for the community near its Sreepur Factory on October 22, 2025, according to a press</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 12:18:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ACC approves case against Hasina's press secretary for failing to submit wealth statement</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/acc-approves-case-against-hasinas-press-secretary-for-failing-to-submit-wealth-statement</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) has approved the filing of a case against Md Naimul Islam Khan, former press secretary to the ousted Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina, for failing to submit his wealth statement within the stipulated time as required by law.
According to an official letter (Me</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 12:33:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Passport officer fired for ‘misconduct’, absenteeism</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/unapproved-absence-self-approved-passport-breach-lead-to-officers-dismissal</link><description>Shahinur Rahman, assistant director of the Department of Immigration and Passports, has been relieved of duty from government service for remaining absent from duty for months without approval and for alleged misconduct.
The Public Security Division under the home ministry issued a notification on</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 13:03:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CID files money laundering case against Nafisa Kamal’s firm and others</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cid-files-money-laundering-case-against-nafisa-kamals-firm-and-others</link><description>The Criminal Investigation Department (CID) has filed a case under the Prevention of Money Laundering Act against eight individuals and organisations, including Orbitals International, owned by Nafisa Kamal, for allegedly laundering around Tk 33.44 crore through manpower exports to Malaysia.
The c</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 13:18:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>King Charles unveils UK’s first LGBT armed forces memorial</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/king-charles-unveils-uks-first-lgbt-armed-forces-memorial</link><description>King Charles unveiled a memorial dedicated to lesbian, gay, bisexual and transgender military personnel on Monday, marking his first official engagement in support of the LGBT community.
The government-funded “Open Letter” memorial is designed to honour those currently serving and comm</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 13:33:23 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>