<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 14:22:37 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Govt clears draft law to establish separate a secretariat for SC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-clears-draft-law-to-establish-separate-a-secretariat-for-supreme-court</link><description>The interim government on Thursday cleared the draft of Supreme Court Secretariat Ordinance 2025 to set up a separate secretariat of the higher court, aiming to ensure the full independence of the judiciary.
The approval came from a meeting of the council of advisers held with Chief Adviser Prof M</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 11:14:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt mulls going to ICC to bring back Hasina, Kamal: Asif Nazrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-mulls-going-to-icc-to-bring-back-hasina-kamal-asif-nazrul</link><description>The government is thinking about going to the International Criminal Court (ICC) in Rome for bringing back fugitive convicts, ousted prime minister Sheikh Hasina and former home minister Asaduzzaman Khan Kamal from India.
"We will hold a meeting soon to decide whether we can approach the Internati</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 11:29:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BB stops direct public services at all offices</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bb-stops-direct-public-services-at-all-offices</link><description>Bangladesh Bank (BB) is set to discontinue several public services from tomorrow offered directly over the counter at all its offices.
The services that will stop at Bangladesh Bank offices include the sale of savings certificates and prize bonds, the exchange of torn or mutilated notes, and all r</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 11:44:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh launches Bench Book to strengthen judicial response to human trafficking</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladesh-launches-bench-book-to-strengthen-judicial-response-to-human-trafficking</link><description>In a significant milestone toward enhancing Bangladesh’s judicial response to human trafficking and promoting a victim-centred approach to justice, the Ministry of Law, Justice and Parliamentary Affairs, in collaboration with the United Nations Office on Drugs and Crime (UNODC) and the Intern</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 11:59:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>We don’t afford to allow any exogenous or indigenous forces: Dhaka tells CSC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/we-dont-afford-to-allow-any-exogenous-or-indigenous-forces-dhaka-tells-csc</link><description>Bangladesh on Thursday pledged its readiness to work hand in hand to ensure a “stable, secure, peaceful and prosperous” Indian Ocean region and to confront the common challenges, stressing that they do not afford to allow any exogenous or indigenous forces.
“We do not afford to a</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 12:29:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Spain exhumes victim of Franco-era killings in ongoing recovery effort</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/spain-exhumes-victim-of-franco-era-killings-in-ongoing-recovery-effort</link><description>Jose Luis Cubo watched as forensic scientists dug up the body of a man his grandfather had helped to bury at the start of the Spanish Civil War in 1936 after an execution by fascist forces.
The remains pulled from a muddy pit in Vegas de Matute farmland, 75 km (47 miles) north of Madrid, are</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 12:15:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Four more die of dengue</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/four-more-die-of-dengue</link><description>Four more deaths were reported from dengue in 24 hours till Thursday morning, raising the number of fatalities from the mosquito-borne disease in Bangladesh to 353 this year.
During this period, 745 more patients were hospitalised with viral fever, bringing the total number of cases to 88,457 so f</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 12:30:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Resilient Becoming’ group art exhibition begins</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/others/resilient-becoming-group-art-exhibition-begins</link><description>An art exhibition featuring paintings by over a hundred artists is set to begin in the capital. The exhibition, titled 'Resilient Becoming', is being organized by Bhumi Gallery.
The event will be held at Centrepoint, adjacent to Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport in Uttara, Dhaka, according to</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 12:45:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Referendum law within four days: Asif Nazrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/referendum-law-within-four-days-asif-nazrul</link><description>The interim government has said it will introduce the long-awaited referendum law within the next several working days.
Speaking at a press briefing at the Foreign Service Academy in Dhaka on Thursday, Law Adviser Dr Asif Nazrul said the draft legislation was in its final stages. “We are goi</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 13:00:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pedestrian dies as SUV plunges off Ctg expressway</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/man-dead-five-injured-after-suv-skids-off-chattogram-expressway-onto-road-below</link><description>A pedestrian has died at Chattogram’s Nimtala when a vehicle skidded off the expressway onto the road below, leaving five others injured as well.
The incident occurred around 4:30pm on Thursday near Nimtala Mor under Bandar Police Station, when a Toyota Harrier descending from Patenga veered</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 13:15:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Russian strikes plunge 400,000 Ukrainians into darkness, energy officials say</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/russian-strikes-plunge-400000-ukrainians-into-darkness-energy-officials-say</link><description>More than 400,000 Ukrainian consumers remained without electricity as of midday on Thursday following a recent large-scale Russian attack on Ukraine's western regions, energy officials said.
The attack led to a decrease in electricity production at Ukrainian nuclear power plants.
Russia has sharp</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 13:30:47 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>