<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 02:40:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Bangladesh, US sign reciprocal tariff agreement, cut duty to 19pc</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladesh-us-sign-reciprocal-tariff-agreement-cut-duty-to-19pc</link><description>Bangladesh has signed a tariff agreement with the United States after nine months of negotiations, reducing the supplementary duty by one percentage point.
The Chief Advisor’s Office announced on Monday night that under the new deal, Bangladeshi exports to the US market will face a 19 percen</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 17:10:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BCB asks Pakistan to play against India in ICC T20 World Cup</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/bcb-president-requests-pakistan-to-play-against-india-in-icc-t20-world-cup</link><description>Bangladesh Cricket Board (BCB) President Aminul Islam Bulbul has requested Pakistan to play the group stage match against India in the T20 World Cup.
The board chief also said Bangladesh’s “brotherhood” with Pakistan will be “strengthened”.
The announcement was made</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 17:25:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat chief Shafiqur calls on all to seize ‘great opportunity for change’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jamaat-chief-shafiqur-calls-on-all-to-seize-great-opportunity-for-change</link><description>Jamaat-e-Islami chief Shafiqur Rahman has earnestly requested the people to believe its leaders who have made numerous promises before the parliamentary polls.
He said people should vote for Jamaat’s “weighing scale” symbol, as the party would keep its promises and fulfil the dre</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 17:40:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trusting the trustees</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/trusting-the-trustees</link><description>Bangladesh’s interim government was born not at the ballot box but in the streets. The July 2024 uprising swept away a government that many citizens viewed as unaccountable and abusive, creating a dangerous vacuum that needed to be filled quickly to prevent drift or disorder. Professor Muhamm</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 17:55:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Regulatory rate unchanged at 10pc as inflation frowns</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/regulatory-rate-unchanged-at-10pc-as-inflation-frowns</link><description>Bangladesh Bank has yet again decided to be clenched-fist on money supply.



During the second half of this fiscal year, according to monetary policy statement (MPS), the policy rate will remain unchanged at 10 per cent as inflation frowns.
In the new MPS unveiled Monday, the central bank, ho</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 18:10:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NiV crossing traditional belt, seasons</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/niv-crossing-traditional-belt-seasons</link><description>A woman aged between 40 and 50 died of Nipah Virus (NiV) infection in the northern  district of Naogaon, according to  WHO Disease Outbreak News. As reported, the woman developed symptoms of NiV infection which included fever, headache, muscle cramp, loss of appetite, weakness and vomitin</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 18:25:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Foreign policy goals in manifestos of BNP, Jamaat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/foreign-policy-goals-in-manifestos-of-bnp-jamaat</link><description>As Bangladesh heads toward the February 12 parliamentary elections, foreign policy has emerged -- at least on paper -- as an important area to focus on by the two main power contenders, the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) and Jamaat-e-Islami. Both parties have devoted space in their election man</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 18:40:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The queer case of state- owned enterprises</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/the-queer-case-of-state-owned-enterprises</link><description>The report that the Bangladesh Petroleum Corporation (BPC) and the Petrobangla, two government-owned statutory corporations, have defaulted on payment of import duty and taxes to the tune of Tk 330 billion is highly disconcerting. Responsible for the bulk of the energy import, the Petrobangla has a</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 18:55:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Feb 12 vote to mark 'historic break' with past: CA</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/feb-12-vote-to-mark-historic-break-with-past-ca</link><description>Chief Adviser Prof Muhammad Yunus reassures that the forthcoming national elections will be conducted in a free, fair and transparent manner in a "historic break" with years of "mock" and "fake" polls.
Addressing senior secretaries and secretaries of the government, at his office in Dhaka Monday,</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 01:44:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh, US sign reciprocal tariff agreement</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladesh-us-sign-reciprocal-tariff-agreement</link><description>The Agreement on Reciprocal Tariff between Bangladesh and the United States was signed on Monday. On the Bangladesh side, the signatories were Commerce Adviser Sheikh Bashir Uddin and National Security Adviser Khalilur Rahman, and on US side, Ambassador Jamieson Greer, US Trade Representative.
Neg</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 01:59:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BB tightens scrutiny of large loans</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/bb-tightens-scrutiny-of-large-loans</link><description>Bangladesh Bank is set to impose stricter inspection of large loans as part of its push to rein in irregularities linked to collateral valuation and mortgage documentation.
The move targets loans exceeding Tk 500 million, which have often been associated with inflated asset values and forged docum</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 02:14:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique reaffirms BNP pledge for economic democratisation, rebound</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-reaffirms-bnp-pledge-for-economic-democratisation-rebound</link><description>BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman delivers a televised speech on Monday.
BNP Chairperson Tarique Rahman reaffirmed BNP's election pledges for economic democratisation and rebound besides restoring the phrase 'Absolute trust and faith in the Almighty Allah' at the beginning of the constitution, as it was</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 02:29:56 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>