<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 20:25:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Lions International allocates 300 development, humanitarian projects</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/lions-international-allocates-300-development-humanitarian-projects</link><description>Lions International has allocated over 300 development and humanitarian projects across Bangladesh, each valued at more than US$1.0 million, aimed at bolstering the country's socio-economic landscape.
The information was disclosed by Dr. Manoj Shah, Second International Vice President of Lions Int</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 16:10:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCP launches election theme song</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ncp-launches-election-theme-song</link><description>National Citizen Party (NCP) unveiled its election theme song at Shahbagh on Saturday, with party spokesperson Asif Mahmud Shojib Bhuyain leading the ceremony.
Speaking at the event, Asif Mahmud said, “We chose Shahbagh because it is where our political journey began and grew. That is why we</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 16:25:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shaping political socialisation in BD</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/shaping-political-socialisation-in-bd</link><description>Political preferences, loyalties, and behaviours do not emerge spontaneously in Bangladesh. They are cultivated over the years through subtle and persistent influence of social institutions and interpersonal relationships. This process, widely studied as political socialisation, encompasses how ind</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 16:40:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Growing visa restrictions: A wake-up call for Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/growing-visa-restrictions-a-wake-up-call-for-bangladesh</link><description>The United States has temporarily suspended immigrant visas for applicants from Bangladesh and 74 other countries. Effective from January 21, the restriction has been imposed citing concerns that a large number of immigrants from these countries rely on government benefits instead of entering the w</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 16:55:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Election time inflation in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/election-time-inflation-in-bangladesh</link><description>National elections critically influence economic growth and inflation across countries. Studies have examined patterns such as declining growth and rising inflation in election years. As Bangladesh prepares for the 13th parliamentary election on February 12, along with the referendum on the July Ch</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 17:10:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Stepping up banking reform efforts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/stepping-up-banking-reform-efforts</link><description>Bangladesh Bank has long been expected to act as a strong regulator without being given the legal space to do so. The latest move to amend the Bangladesh Bank Order and the Bank Company Act is an attempt to reverse that pattern by redefining who holds authority over banks and on what terms. Few now</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 17:25:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US-brokered peace talks break off without deal after overnight Russian bombardment of Ukraine</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-brokered-peace-talks-break-off-without-deal-after-overnight-russian-bombardment-of-ukraine</link><description>Ukraine and Russia ended a second day of U.S.-brokered talks in Abu Dhabi on Saturday without a deal but with future meetings mooted after overnight Russian airstrikes that knocked out power for over a million Ukrainians amid subzero winter cold.
Statements after the conclusion of the talks did no</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 17:40:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP leader shot in Keraniganj dies at DMCH</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-leader-shot-in-keraniganj-dies-at-dmch</link><description>A union-level BNP leader in Dhaka’s Keraniganj upazila, who was shot by miscreants on Thursday night, died at a hospital on Saturday afternoon.
Hasan Molla, general secretary of Hazratpur union BNP, succumbed to his injuries at around 4pm while undergoing treatment at Dhaka Medical College H</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 17:55:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Negotiable instruments law  lightened to try financial crimes</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/negotiable-instruments-law-lightened-to-try-financial-crimes</link><description>A long-overdue legal upgrading is underway to expand judicial jurisdiction to try financial offences, principally cases of cheque dishonour that undermines trust in non-cash transaction.
The council of advisers of the post-uprising government Thursday approved the Negotiable Instruments Act 2025,</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 18:12:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hadi’s brother alleges threats against himself, family amid investigation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hadis-brother-alleges-threats-against-himself-family-amid-investigation</link><description>Omar bin Hadi, the brother of Sharif Osman bin Hadi, has filed a general diary (GD) at Dhaka's Shahbagh Police Station citing “security concerns”.
He lodged the police complaint around 8pm on Saturday without mentioning any names, citing “security concerns” for himself and</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 18:27:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCP's Sarjis, BNP's Nawshad show-caused over code of conduct 'breach'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ncps-sarjis-bnps-nawshad-show-caused-over-code-of-conduct-breach</link><description>Show cause notices have been served on National Citizen Party (NCP) candidate Sarjis Alam and BNP aspirant Muhammad Nawshad Zamir for the Panchagarh-1 constituency allegedly for violating the electoral code of conduct.
The notice was issued separately to the two candidates on Saturday by Deputy Co</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 18:42:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump threatens Canada with 100pc tariff over pending trade deal with China</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-threatens-canada-with-100pc-tariff-over-pending-trade-deal-with-china</link><description>U.S. President Donald Trump said on Saturday he would impose a 100% tariff on Canada if it follows through on a trade deal with China and warned Canadian Prime Minister Mark Carney that a deal would endanger his country.
"China will eat Canada alive, completely devour it, including the destruction</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 18:57:52 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>