<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 12:52:32 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>New US ambassador presents credentials to President</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/new-us-ambassador-presents-credentials-to-president</link><description>Newly appointed US Ambassador to Bangladesh Brent Christensen on Thursday presented his credentials to President Mohammed Shahabuddin.
Welcoming the new envoy, the President expressed the hope that bilateral relations between Bangladesh and the US would further strengthen in the coming days partic</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 09:15:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UK weighs response after Russia expels British diplomat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/uk-weighs-response-after-russia-expels-british-diplomat</link><description>The British government said on Thursday it was "carefully considering" its response after Russia expelled a British diplomat who it said was an undeclared officer in Britain's intelligence services.
"This is not the first time the Kremlin has made malicious and baseless accusations against our sta</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 09:30:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US pressing Mexico to allow US forces to fight cartels, NYT reports</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/us-pressing-mexico-to-allow-us-forces-to-fight-cartels-nyt-reports</link><description>The United States is intensifying pressure on Mexico to allow US military forces to conduct joint operations to dismantle fentanyl labs inside the country, the New York Times reported on Thursday, citing US officials.
US officials want American forces, either Special Operation troops or CIA office</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 09:45:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Iran's nationwide protests feel smothered after a weeklong crackdown and internet outage</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/irans-nationwide-protests-feel-smothered-after-a-weeklong-crackdown-and-internet-outage</link><description>The nationwide protests challenging Iran’s theocracy appeared increasingly smothered Thursday, a week on from authorities shutting the country off from the world and escalating a bloody crackdown that activists say killed at least 2,615 people.
In Iran's capital, Tehran, witnesses say recent</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 10:00:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CPD for integrating regional RE trade into national plan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cpd-for-integrating-regional-re-trade-into-national-plan</link><description>The Centre for Policy Dialogue (CPD) on Thursday laid emphasis on integrating regional Renewable Energy (RE) trade into the national plan to stabilise the grid and lower costs.
The think tank made the observation at a press briefing on “Energy &amp; Power Sector Master Plan (EPSMP): 2026-2050&amp;rd</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 10:15:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP seeks candidates’ names, symbols on postal ballots</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bnp-seeks-candidates-names-symbols-on-postal-ballots</link><description>BNP on Thursday asked the Election Commission to use the constituency-based postal ballots inscribing the names of candidates and symbols for the In-Country Postal Voting in the upcoming national election scheduled for February 12 next.
The party sought a clear explanation from the Election Commis</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 10:30:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat alliance finalises seat-sharing agreement</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jamaat-alliance-finalises-seat-sharing-agreement</link><description>The 11-party alliance led by Jamaat-e-Islami has finalised a seat-sharing plan for the general election.
Specific seats have been left for Islami Andolan candidates despite concerns about the party leaving the alliance earlier in the day.
Bangladesh Khelafat Majlis chief Mamunul Haque said a pres</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 10:45:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Emirates to launch services to Helsinki from October</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/emirates-to-launch-services-to-helsinki-from-october</link><description>Emirates airline will launch a daily, year-round service between Helsinki and Dubai from 1 October 2026, marking the only direct air link between Finland and the UAE.
The service will be operated by Emirates’ newest aircraft, the A350, bringing the airline’s latest onboard products, in</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 11:00:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DNCC to organise 3-day fair on next Eid-ul-Fitr</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/dncc-to-organise-3-day-fair-on-next-eid-ul-fitr</link><description>The Dhaka North City Corporation (DNCC) has undertaken an initiative to organise Eid congregation, a jubilant procession, and a three-day fair on the occasion of the upcoming holy Eid-ul-Fitr.
The decision was taken at a meeting held this morning at the DNCC Nagar Bhaban with DNCC Administrator Mo</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 11:15:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>'Upcoming increase in LPG imports to prevent supply crisis during Ramadan'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/upcoming-increase-in-lpg-imports-to-prevent-supply-crisis-during-ramadan</link><description>The Bangladesh Energy Regulatory Commission (BERC) chairman Jalal Ahmed expressed optimism that the upcoming increase in Liquefied Petroleum Gas (LPG) imports will prevent any supply crisis during the month of Ramadan.
He has called for urgent cooperation among all stakeholders, including liquefie</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 11:30:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BCB removes Nazmul from after players’ ultimatum</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bcb-removes-nazmul-from-finance-committee-chair-after-players-ultimatum</link><description>The Bangladesh Cricket Board (BCB) has removed its Director M Nazmul Islam from his post as chairman of its finance committee, following an ultimatum from cricketers.
BCB President Aminul Islam will serve as acting chairman of the committee until further notice, the board said in a press release i</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 11:45:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ratna Patra announces purchase of 1m Square Pharma shares</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ratna-patra-announces-purchase-of-1m-square-pharma-shares</link><description>Ratna Patra, a director and vice-chairman of Square Pharmaceuticals and the daughter of the company’s late founder Samson H Chowdhury, has announced plans to buy another 1 million shares of the pharmaceutical giant at the prevailing market price.
In a disclosure to investors through the Dhak</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 12:00:47 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>