<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 06:35:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Bangladesh Bank allows partial loan write-off facility for banks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladesh-bank-allows-partial-loan-write-off-facility-for-banks</link><description>Bangladesh Bank (BB) has instructed commercial banks to go for partially writing-off the bad and loss-category of loans that are hardly recoverable.
To this effect, Banking Regulation and Policy Department (BRPD) of the central bank issued a circular on Thursday.
It said the portions of bad-and-l</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 03:08:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khaleda’s London transfer put on hold over air ambulance issues</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/khaledas-london-transfer-put-on-hold-over-air-ambulance-issues</link><description>BNP Chairperson Khaleda Zia’s planned transfer to London for advanced treatment has been delayed as the special air ambulance provided by Qatar’s emir has yet to reach Dhaka.
BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir said the air ambulance was experiencing technical issues. It</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 03:23:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Leather industry 'poised to reach full potential'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/leather-industry-poised-to-reach-full-potential</link><description>Leathertech Bangladesh 2025, the 11th edition of international technology tradeshow for leather, footwear machinery, shoe materials, chemicals and accessories sectors, kicked off in the city on Thursday.
Chowdhury Ashik Mahmud Bin Harun, executive chairman of Bangladesh Investment Development Auth</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 03:38:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ICT Division publishes draft National Source Code Policy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ict-division-publishes-draft-national-source-code-policy</link><description>The Information and Communication Technology (ICT) Division published on Thursday the draft of the National Source Code Policy 2025 on its official website, with the slogan "Public Money, Public Code".
The proposed policy aims to formally recognise the government-funded software as a national asse</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 03:53:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rebuilding trust through technology: The future of Islamic digital banking</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/rebuilding-trust-through-technology-the-future-of-islamic-digital-banking-1</link><description>Islamic banking in Bangladesh is entering a new phase of transformation shaped by evolving customer expectations, rapid technological progress and an increasingly digital financial landscape. As the market expands and customers seek more accessible, transparent and value-driven financial solutions,</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 04:08:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Training crucial for effective implementation of new public procurement rules: Moin</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/training-crucial-for-effective-implementation-of-new-public-procurement-rules-moin</link><description>The government has made electronic government procurement (e-GP) mandatory with the enactment of the Public Procurement Rules, 2025, said CEO of Bangladesh Public Procurement Authority (BPPA) SM Moin Uddin Ahmed on Thursday.
To implement the new provisions properly, it is crucial to provide adequa</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 04:23:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>SYLHET CITY: 24 buildings marked vulnerable to earthquake yet to be demolished</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/sylhet-city-24-buildings-marked-vulnerable-to-earthquake-yet-to-be-demolished</link><description>SYLHET, Dec 04: A total of 24 buildings considered to be highly vulnerable in Sylhet city would soon be demolished, official sources said.
These structures have remained in a dilapidated condition for a long period of time, although these were earlier marked as vulnerable to earthquake.
Related i</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 04:38:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two ordinances get nod to protect forest, biodiversity, wildlife</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/two-ordinances-get-nod-to-protect-forest-biodiversity-wildlife</link><description>The interim government has passed two ordinances relating to the country's forest, biodiversity, and wildlife protection. These are "Forest and Tree Conservation Ordinance 2025" and "Wildlife (Conservation and Security) Ordinance 2025".
The approval was given at a meeting of the Council of Adviser</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 04:53:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Metro card online top-ups gain traction</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/metro-card-online-top-ups-gain-traction</link><description>Metro rail passengers are increasingly embracing the new online recharge facility, introduced to spare them the long queues at station counters.
In just one week, more than 11,000 cards were topped up through the digital platform, signalling strong public acceptance of the service.
The Dhaka Tran</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 05:08:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No concrete plan of DU renovations after tremor: JCS</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/no-concrete-plan-of-du-renovations-after-tremor-jcs</link><description>Jatiya Chhatra Shakti (JCS) leaders said DU administration failed to disclose the duration and plan of the renovations-citing which the authorities closed the institution following last month's tremor.
JCS Dhaka University (DU) unit President Tahmid Al Muddassir Chowdhury made the remarks during a</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 05:23:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US widens travel ban to more than 30 countries</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-widens-travel-ban-to-more-than-30-countries</link><description>The US plans to expand the number of countries covered by its travel ban to more than 30, US Homeland Security Secretary Kristi Noem said on Thursday.
Noem, in an interview on Fox News' "The Ingraham Angle," was asked to confirm whether the administration of President Donald Trump would be increas</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 05:38:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Zubaida Rahman arrives in Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/zubaida-rahman-arrives-in-dhaka</link><description>Zubaida Rahman, the wife of Tarique Rahman and daughter-in-law of BNP chief Khaleda Zia, has arrived in Dhaka.
She landed at Dhaka’s Shahjalal International Airport on board a Biman Bangladesh Airlines flight around 10:45 am on Friday, according to Atikur Rahman Rumon, a BNP spokesman.
&amp;ldq</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 05:53:09 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>