<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 23:22:31 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>New Year party at Swiss ski resort turned into a disaster zone</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/new-year-party-at-swiss-ski-resort-turned-into-a-disaster-zone</link><description>As he approached Le Constellation bar to celebrate the New Year in a snowy Swiss ski resort bright with Christmas lights, Dominic Dubois saw flames engulfing the building.
"You could see the orange, the orange, yellow, red," Dubois told Reuters, describing chaotic scenes as bystanders and emergenc</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 16:30:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Merged banks: Depositors begin withdrawing funds</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/after-months-of-freeze-depositors-begin-withdrawing-funds-from-merged-banks</link><description>Depositors of five private Shariah-based banks, which were recently merged to form the Sammilito Islami Bank, have begun withdrawing their savings.
Depositors gaining access to their funds on Thursday marks a cautious return of liquidity after a prolonged period of financial distress.
For months,</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 16:45:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A year of growth for Chattogram Port</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/chattogram-port-sails-to-record-year-as-ship-arrivals-cargo-revenue-post-broad-based-growth</link><description>Chattogram Port has recorded gains across all key indicators over the past year, with higher volumes of containers and bulk cargo handled and a sharp rise in ship arrivals, underscoring the premier sea port’s growing role in the trade-led economy.
According to port authority data, container</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 17:00:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Consumptionscape in Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/consumptionscape-in-dhaka</link><description>Walking through the streets of Gulshan, Banani, or Dhanmondi in Dhaka, it is easy to imagine that the city has joined the ranks of global metropolises. Sleek shopping malls, international brands, trendy cafes, and luxury boutiques give the impression of a cosmopolitan urban life. Shoppers with desi</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 17:15:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No escape from Dhaka's air pollution!</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/no-escape-from-dhakas-air-pollution</link><description>While celebration of the year 2026 began earlier in some countries like New Zealand and Australia, Dhaka began its journey into the New Year with the dubious tag of one of the most polluted cities in the world. Breathing outdoors now poses serious health risks due to the high levels of toxic partic</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 17:30:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Welcome year 2026</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/welcome-year-2026</link><description>An eventful year marked by tumultuous national developments and international conflicts raising at times the spectre of a World War III has just passed. The world has already welcomed the New Year with open arms in the hope that the looming threat of global trade suffering commercial convulsions du</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 17:45:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Areas of non-existent workplace safety</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/areas-of-non-existent-workplace-safety</link><description>Workplace safety has long been a matter of serious concern but recent developments suggest that the situation has further deteriorated. Accidents and deaths arising from hazardous working conditions and compounded by persistent negligence in enforcing safety standards have cast a long shadow over t</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 18:00:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat hints at 'working with' BNP</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jamaat-tries-to-thaw-ties-with-bnp-suggests-post-poll-talks-to-work-together</link><description>The Jamaat chief commented on the election and referendum, urging a smooth, fair, and credible electoral process.
During the meeting, he recalled Jamaat’s long-term alliance with BNP, adding: “We have worked together in the past in the interest of our beloved country, and, God willing,</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 18:15:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Feroza’ stands silent, emptiness engulfs house next door too</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/feroza-stands-silent-emptiness-engulfs-house-next-door-too</link><description>A heavy, unfamiliar stillness has settled over “Feroza” in Dhaka’s Gulshan, the house where former prime minister Khaleda Zia spent the last 13 years of her life.
Even the home next door, once alive with visitors and activity, now feels drained of sound.
About one and a half mon</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 18:30:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bankers cautiously optimistic about a turnaround</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bankers-cautiously-optimistic-about-a-turnaround</link><description>Bankers sound cautiously optimistic about a turnaround in the problem-ridden banking sector on right-minded policy support following the change-making polls ahead in the new year.
Bangladesh saw so many eventful happenings in the just-past year 2025 but it was the most challenging one for banking</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 18:45:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>21 to face trial for killing Mitford scrap trader Sohag with boulder</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/21-to-face-trial-for-killing-mitford-scrap-trader-sohag-with-boulder</link><description>Months after the gruesome killing of scrap trader Lal Chand, also known as Sohag, outside Mitford Hospital in Dhaka -- where he was bludgeoned to death with a concrete boulder -- investigators have filed a chargesheet against 21 individuals at court.
The investigating officer, however, has recomme</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 19:00:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rajshahi Warriors beat Rangpur Riders in Super Over thriller</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/rajshahi-warriors-beat-rangpur-riders-in-super-over-thriller</link><description>Rajshahi Warriors staged a dramatic comeback to defeat Rangpur Riders in a Super Over after the regulation quota of overs ended in the Bangladesh Premier League (BPL).
Rangpur Riders seemed poised for victory, chasing 160 with confidence after half-centuries from Towhid Hridoy and David Malan in R</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 19:15:08 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>