<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 11:19:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Road crashes leave four dead in Magura</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/road-crashes-leave-four-dead-in-magura</link><description>Four people, including a woman, were killed in three separate road accidents in Magura district on Thursday.
The deceased were identified as Saiful Islam Tamim, 18, Shanto Pratim Mondal, 18, Sagor Ahmed, 32, and Rina Khatun. Details about Sagor Ahmed and Rina Khatun could not be immediately confir</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 07:15:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Polls to be inclusive, but AL can’t take part: Prof Yunus tells UK</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/polls-to-be-inclusive-participatory-al-wont-be-able-to-take-part-prof-yunus-tells-uk</link><description>Chief Adviser Prof Muhammad Yunus has reaffirmed his government’s commitment to ensuring that the upcoming general election will be free, fair, and inclusive.
“The election will be participatory. There will be a big turnout,” he said, adding that tens of millions of young people</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 07:30:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Suriname and Curaçao edge closer to historic World Cup qualification</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/suriname-and-curacao-edge-closer-to-historic-world-cup-qualification</link><description>Richonell Margaret scored twice in two-minute span in the second half on Thursday as Suriname defeated El Salvador 4-0 in CONCACAF qualifying to move closer to securing a spot in the World Cup for the first time.
Tjaronn Cherry opened the scoring with a penalty kick in the 44th minute and Richonel</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 08:00:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bowlers topple Ireland as Bangladesh win Sylhet Test by an innings and 47 runs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/bowlers-topple-ireland-as-bangladesh-win-sylhet-test-by-an-innings-and-47-runs</link><description>Bangladesh have outplayed Ireland with both bat and ball to deliver a comprehensive win by an innings and 47 runs in the Sylhet Test.
After declaring at 587/8 on Thursday, with a 301-run lead, the Tigers bowling attack tore into the visitors, leaving them teetering at 86/5.
The Irish batsmen show</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 08:15:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Kitchen Market: Onion prices still high, hilsa out of reach</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/kitchen-market-onion-prices-still-high-hilsa-out-of-reach</link><description>Onion prices in the capital's retail markets have remained almost unchanged for a week, still selling at Tk 110-115 per kg, while hilsa has become increasingly unaffordable, with prices rising by up to Tk 500 per kg in just seven days.
A visit to several wholesale and retail markets in on Friday s</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 08:30:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DU chemistry professor arrested over 'sexual harassment of male students'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/du-chemistry-professor-arrested-over-sexual-harassment-of-male-students</link><description>Police arrested Dhaka University Chemistry Department professor Md Ershad Halim around 11:00 pm on Thursday from his Shewrapara residence in the capital for allegedly sexually harassing male students.
Confirming the arrest on Friday, DU Proctor Associate Professor Saifuddin Ahmed said, “The</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 09:23:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Driver badly burnt as school bus torched in Manikganj</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/driver-badly-burnt-as-school-bus-torched-in-manikganj</link><description>Unidentified miscreants set fire to a parked school bus in Manikganj early Friday, seriously injuring the driver asleep inside.
The driver, Parvez Khan, 55, of Baraivikra village in Manikganj Sadar, was rescued by police as the fire quickly spread.
Suman Chakraborty, sub-inspector of Shibalaya Po</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 09:38:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hasina tells BBC she's not guilty of crimes against humanity</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hasina-tells-bbc-shes-not-guilty-of-crimes-against-humanity</link><description>Former prime minister Sheikh Hasina has denied committing crimes against humanity during a deadly crackdown on the July Mass Uprising that toppled her, days before the International Crimes Tribunal (ICT) is due to deliver a verdict.
Hasina is accused of being the main architect behind hundreds of</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 09:53:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No imposed law can interfere with parliament’s sovereignty: Salahuddin</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/no-imposed-law-can-interfere-with-parliaments-sovereignty-salahuddin</link><description>BNP senior leader Salahuddin Ahmed on Friday said no imposed law, order or forced proposal can be allowed to interfere with the sovereignty of the National Parliament.
"We do not want the sovereignty of the National Parliament to be undermined in any way. That is why we will not allow any imposed</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 10:34:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Law enforcers will stop violence on Hasina verdict date: Khosru</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/law-enforcers-will-stop-violence-on-hasina-verdict-date-not-parties-bnps-amir-khosru</link><description>BNP National Standing Committee Member Amir Khosru Mahmud Chowdhury says if there is any unrest on the day of the verdict in the crimes against humanity case against ousted prime minister Sheikh Hasina, it will be controlled by law-enforcing agencies.
It is not the responsibility of any political</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 10:49:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt appoints new DCs in 23 districts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-appoints-new-dcs-in-23-districts</link><description>The government has appointed new Deputy Commissioners (DCs) in 23 districts.
The Ministry of Public Administration issued two separate notifications on Thursday night in this regard transferring one Mohammad Zahidul Islam Miah, DC of Narayanganj to Chattogram and assigning officers of the rank of</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 11:04:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Japan's leader ready to meet North Korea's Kim Jong Un for 'new, fruitful' relations</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/japans-leader-ready-to-meet-north-koreas-kim-jong-un-for-new-fruitful-relations</link><description>Japanese Prime Minister Sanae Takaichi said on Friday she was ready to come "face-to-face" with North Korean leader Kim Jong Un in an effort to build "new, fruitful Japan-North Korea relations".
Takaichi said she "won't rule out any option" in order to make a breakthrough in the unresolved issue o</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 11:19:02 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>