<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 08:45:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Bridge Tolls: E-payment system expanded</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bridge-tolls-e-payment-system-expanded</link><description>All vehicle users will now be able to pay tolls on road bridges electronically as the Roads and Highways Department (RHD) has opened its e-payment system to all banks and mobile banking platforms, aiming for a more efficient, transparent, and faster toll collection process.
Officials said that aft</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 06:12:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India, Israel to boost defence cooperation: Modi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/india-israel-to-boost-defence-cooperation-modi</link><description>India and Israel will pursue joint development, production and transfer of technology in defence, as well as work on a free trade agreement, Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi said on Thursday.
Here are some details on what the two countries agreed upon during Modi's two-day visit to Israel.
● T</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 06:27:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US–Iran nuclear talks end without agreement</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-iran-nuclear-talks-end-without-agreement</link><description>Iran and the United States held hours of indirect negotiations Thursday over Tehran's nuclear program but walked away without a deal, leaving the danger of another Mideast war on the table as the U.S. has gathered a massive fleet of aircraft and warships in the region.
Oman's Foreign Minister Badr</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 06:42:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bus catches fire after collision with motorcycle in Gazipur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bus-catches-fire-after-collision-with-motorcycle-in-gazipur</link><description>A passenger bus caught fire after colliding with a motorcycle in the Board Bazar area of Gazipur on Friday morning.
The motorcyclist was injured in the incident.
Hiron Mia, Station Officer of Bhogra Modern Fire Service, said the Dhaka-bound bus was travelling from Tangail when it reached the Boar</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 06:57:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>171 bodies found in mass graves in eastern Congo</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/africa/171-bodies-found-in-mass-graves-in-eastern-congo</link><description>Congolese authorities and a civil society group said Thursday that mass graves were found in part of eastern Congo that the M23 rebel group has recently withdrawn from, as fighting in the region escalates despite a U.S.-mediated peace deal.
The governor of South-Kivu province, Jean-Jacques Purusi,</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 07:12:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nine injured in BNP-Jamaat clash in Jashore</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/nine-injured-in-bnp-jamaat-clash-in-jashore</link><description>At least nine people were injured in a clash between BNP and Jamaat-e-Islami activists in Bhatpara Bazar of Baghtia Union, Abhaynagar Upazila, Jashore on Thursday.
According to locals and police, the incident occurred between 4:30 pm and 5:00 pm. The tensions reportedly began on Wednesday over a f</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 06:52:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Man stabbed to death in Ctg</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/man-stabbed-to-death-in-ctg127</link><description>A man has been stabbed to death in the neighbourhood of Sagarika in Chattogram.
The incident took place at Pahartali Sagarika BITAC on Thursday night.
The victim has been identified as Akash Das, 25, who worked in a garment factory in BITAC, reports bdnews24.com.
Metropolitan Police Assistant Co</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 07:07:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>World Economic Forum CEO quits after links to Epstein revealed</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/world-economic-forum-ceo-quits-after-links-to-epstein-revealed</link><description>Borge Brende, president and CEO of the Geneva-based World Economic Forum, announced his decision to step down on Thursday after the forum launched an investigation into his relations with late U.S. financier and convicted sex offender Jeffrey Epstein.</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 07:22:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>One-stop service centres to be set up nationwide to curb corruption: Land minister</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/one-stop-service-centres-to-be-set-up-nationwide-to-curb-corruption-land-minister</link><description>Land Minister Mizanur Rahman Minu has said the government is working to establish one-stop service centres beside deputy commissioners’ offices across the country in a bid to reduce corruption and ensure transparent services in the land ministry.
He made the remarks while exchanging greeting</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 07:37:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>RMG workers demand salary, bonus before 20th Ramadan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/rmg-workers-demand-salary-bonus-before-20th-ramadan</link><description>Garment workers have demanded that their outstanding wages and a bonus equivalent to one month’s salary be paid by the 20th of Ramadan.
The demand was raised at a rally held in front of the National Press Club in the capital on Friday, organised by different garment workers’ organisati</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 07:52:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Earthquake jolts parts of country again</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/earthquake-jolts-parts-of-country-again</link><description>An earthquake was felt in several parts of the country, including the capital Dhaka, at 1:45 pm on Friday.
 
More to follow...</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 08:07:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US aims to bring in 4,500 white South Africans per month as refugees</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-aims-to-bring-in-4500-white-south-africans-per-month-as-refugees</link><description>The US aims to process 4,500 refugee applications from white South Africans per month, far above President Donald Trump's stated refugee program cap, and is installing trailers on embassy property in Pretoria to support the effort, a US contracting document said.
The new target, contained in a pre</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 08:22:01 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>