<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 04:48:28 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>ACC to sue JP leader Ranga over Tk 17m nomination scam</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/acc-to-sue-jp-leader-ranga-over-tk-17m-nomination-scam</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) has decided to file a case against Jatiya Party (JP) leader Moshiur Rahman Ranga over allegations of taking bribes worth Tk 17 million in exchange for nominations in the 2018 national election.
The commission has also decided to file a case against former Kurig</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 01:00:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Struggling BASIC Bank bid for revival falters with little gains</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/struggling-basic-bank-bid-for-revival-falters-with-little-gains</link><description>The scam-stricken BASIC Bank PLC has intensified default-loan-recovery drive against its top 20 defaulters in a struggle for revival, but actual collection stands nowhere near regulatory direction.
According to an internal bank report, the total recovery came to just Tk 48 million against outstand</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 01:15:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Islami Andolan withdraws its candidates to support Mamunul Haque</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/islami-andolan-withdraws-its-candidates-to-support-mamunul-haque</link><description>Islami Andolan has decided to withdraw its candidates from the Dhaka-13 and Bagerhat-1 constituencies and extend support to Bangladesh Khilafat Majlis Ameer Maulana Mamunul Haque in the upcoming parliamentary elections.
Sources said the decision was taken as Mamunul Haque is contesting in both Dha</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 01:30:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>RMG exporters decry withdrawal of bonded warehouse facility</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/rmg-exporters-decry-withdrawal-of-bonded-warehouse-facility</link><description>Leaders of the country's two main apparel trade bodies have blamed the Ministry of Commerce (MoC) for making a unilateral move to withdraw bonded-warehouse facilities on yarn imports.
They warned that such a decision could push Bangladesh's ready-made garment (RMG) industry into a serious crisis.</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 01:45:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC using tactics to give BNP special privileges</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ec-using-tactics-to-give-bnp-special-privileges</link><description>Students Against Discrimination, the platform that led the July mass uprising, has accused the Election Commission (EC) of adopting tactics to provide special privileges to the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP).
The allegation was made on Monday at a press conference held at Madhur Canteen, Dhaka</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 02:00:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shibir protests suspension of polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/shibir-protests-suspension-of-polls</link><description>The Dhaka metropolitan unit of Bangladesh Islami Chhatra Shibir staged a protest rally in the capital on Monday against the suspension of the Shahjalal University of Science and Technology Central Students' Union (SUCSU) and hall council elections.
The procession began from the Central Shaheed Min</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 02:15:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Owners to surrender all licensed firearms by Jan 31</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/owners-to-surrender-all-licensed-firearms-by-jan-31</link><description>The interim government directed the owners of all licensed firearms to surrender their arms to the nearest police stations by January 31 - ahead of the 13th national parliamentary election slated for February 12.
The Ministry of Home Affairs (MoHA) issued a notification in this regard on Sunday, i</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 02:30:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Using achievements matters more, advisor tells graduates</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/using-achievements-matters-more-advisor-tells-graduates</link><description>Using the achievements from university matters more than the achievements themselves, Education Advisor Professor Dr. Chowdhury Rafiqul Abrar said on Monday at the third convocation ceremony of Chittagong Independent University (CIU).
"It's not what you achieve in university, but what you do with</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 02:45:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Charges framed against 39</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/charges-framed-against-39</link><description>A Chattogram court on Monday framed charges against 39 persons, including Chinmoy Krishna Das, in the murder case of lawyer Saiful Islam Alif.
Judge Md Zahidul Haque of the Chattogram Speedy Trial Tribunal passed the order. The court set February 2 for recording witness testimonies. Of the accused</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 03:00:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sand lifting spree jeopardising environment, infrastructure</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/sand-lifting-spree-jeopardising-environment-infrastructure</link><description>Some locally influential quarters have been extracting sand illegally from three important rivers namely Karatoa, Bangali and Alai flowing through Saghata upazila of Gaibandha district for a long time threatening environment, infrastructure and agricultural land.
Unauthorised sand lifting by these</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 03:31:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Afghanistan keen to strengthen bilateral trade with Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/afghanistan-keen-to-strengthen-bilateral-trade-with-bangladesh</link><description>Afghanistan has shown interest in strengthening bilateral trade with Bangladesh, including importing readymade garments (RMG) and exporting cotton, dry fruits and various agricultural products.
The attention was expressed at a meeting between Commerce Secretary Mahbubur Rahman and Afghan Deputy Mi</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 03:46:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>HSIA 3rd Terminal: Govt-contractor dispute may drag on for long</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/hsia-3rd-terminal-govt-contractor-dispute-may-drag-on-for-long</link><description>The dispute on the expensive Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport (HSIA) third-terminal project is likely to continue for long as the first phase of hearing on the allegations from the contractor's side has just completed.
Sources say the dispute board members completed the first phase of hearin</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 04:01:23 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>