<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 05:20:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Technical textiles, machinery expos begin in Germany on April 21</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/technical-textiles-machinery-expos-begin-in-germany-on-april-21</link><description>The Techtextil and Texprocess-2026, one of leading technical textiles and machinery exhibitions, will kick off on April 21 next year in Frankfurt, Germany creating an opportunity for value-added garment producers including Bangladesh.
With changes in global demand toward specialised, high-performa</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 02:39:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>SOTSUKON: Redefining partnership and protecting children in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/analysis/sotsukon-redefining-partnership-and-protecting-children-in-bangladesh</link><description>Imagine a couple in their late 50s in a tranquil neighbourhood of Dhaka, let's call them Rina and Kamal. They have successfully raised their children, who are now pursuing careers abroad. For twenty-five years, their lives revolved around shared meals, school runs, and managing a household. Now, wi</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 02:54:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Vegetable, potato prices rise amid 'supply shortage'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/vegetable-potato-prices-rise-amid-supply-shortage</link><description>Prices of vegetables and potatoes have increased in the city markets within a week, while onion prices have remained stuck at their previous high.
Prices of almost all winter vegetables that have declined to a satisfactory level, have again increased within just a week, putting consumers in troubl</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 03:09:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>SHED proposes 53pc allocation cut in RADP</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/shed-proposes-53pc-allocation-cut-in-radp</link><description>The Secondary and Higher Education Division (SHED) has proposed a sharp contraction of its Annual Development Programme (ADP) for FY26, seeking to cut Tk 72.22 billion - more than 53 per cent of its current ADP allocation.
It recently submitted a revised ADP (RADP) proposal of Tk 64.03 billion to</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 03:24:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>RU Press Club holds 40th anniv</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ru-press-club-holds-40th-anniv</link><description>The Rajshahi University (RU) Press Club celebrated its 40th anniversary on Thursday through colourful and day-long programmes.
At 9:30am, RU Vice-Chancellor (VC) Prof Dr Saleh Hasan Naqib inaugurated the anniversary events though cutting a cake at the Press Club office. A vibrant procession then p</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 03:39:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>WEEKLY MARKET REVIEW: Bargain buying snaps three-week market downturn</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/weekly-market-review-bargain-buying-snaps-three-week-market-downturn</link><description>The benchmark equity index rebounded this week, paring more than half of the sharp losses suffered in the previous week and snapping a three-week losing streak, as bargain hunters showed renewed buying interest in beaten-down stocks.
Analysts noted that the market showed signs of recovery momentum</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 03:54:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Eastern Lubricants sees 74pc surge in profit</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/eastern-lubricants-sees-74pc-surge-in-profit</link><description>Eastern Lubricants Blenders saw its profit jump 74 per cent year-on-year to Tk 68.53 million for FY'25, driven by higher sales of base oil and a significant boost in non-operating income.
The state-run company's earnings per share (EPS) for FY'25 stood at Tk 43.18, up from Tk 24.82 in the previous</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 04:09:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Red carpet rolled out as Bhutanese PM Tobgay arrives in Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/red-carpet-rolled-out-as-bhutanese-pm-tobgay-arrives-in-dhaka</link><description>A red carpet was rolled out to welcome Bhutanese Prime Minister Tshering Tobgay as he arrived in Dhaka on Saturday for a two-day state visit, with Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus receiving him at Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport (HSIA).
Chief Adviser’s Deputy Press Secretary Moh</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 04:11:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No election campaign allowed in educational institutions, foreign lands: EC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/no-election-campaign-allowed-in-educational-institutions-foreign-lands-ec</link><description>No political party or candidate will be allowed to carry out electioneering in educational institutions, government offices or foreign lands, in addition to religious places of worship, according to the recently published electoral code of conduct.
The Election Commission has imposed a ban on camp</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 04:26:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump and Mamdani go from adversaries to allies after White House meeting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-and-mamdani-go-from-adversaries-to-allies-after-white-house-meeting</link><description>US President Donald Trump on Friday met the man who had proudly proclaimed himself “Donald Trump’s worst nightmare,” but he seemed to find the opposite.
The Republican president and New York City’s Mayor-elect Zohran Mamdani were warm and friendly, speaking repeatedly of th</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 04:41:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Farmer shot dead in Kushtia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/farmer-shot-dead-in-kushtia</link><description>A farmer has been shot dead and another man was wounded by gunfire in Bheramara upazila of Kushtia district.
The incident took place around 8:30 pm on Friday in the Rayta Notunpara area of Bahadurpur Union, according to Bheramara Police Station chief Abdur Rouf Talukder.
The dead man was identifi</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 04:56:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ukraine faces 'difficult choice' as Trump demands acceptance of peace plan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/ukraine-faces-difficult-choice-as-trump-demands-acceptance-of-peace-plan</link><description>President Volodymyr Zelenskiy warned on Friday that Ukraine risked losing its dignity and freedom — or Washington's backing — over a US peace plan that endorses key Russian demands, a proposal Donald Trump said Kyiv should accept within a week.
The US president told Fox News Radio he b</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 05:11:18 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>