<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 04:32:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Independent central bank: ideal vs illusion</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/independent-central-bank-ideal-vs-illusion</link><description>This article is inspired by recent discourses and insightful commentaries across the print media on the “Need for an Independent Central Bank (ICB).” Few would contest their arguments that political dominance over the Bangladesh Bank (BB) has undermined monetary discipline, distorted cr</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 18:11:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Single-dose vaccine against dengue</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/single-dose-vaccine-against-dengue</link><description>Brazil is learnt to have launched a single-dose anti-dengue vaccine last Wednesday (November 30) after obtaining its registration approval by the county's drug regulator, Anvisa. Developed by Butantan Institute in Sao Paulo, the vaccine called, Butantan-DV, is claimed to be the world's first single</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 18:26:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Political will a must to restore confidence in businesses</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/political-will-a-must-to-restore-confidence-in-businesses</link><description>In Bangladesh today, the central question facing the economy is not simply how to stabilise financial institutions or stimulate investment. It is whether the political leadership possesses the will to confront decades of entrenched corruption, rebuild trust in public institutions, and restore confi</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 18:41:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Correlation between energy crunch and industrial production</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/correlation-between-energy-crunch-and-industrial-production</link><description>Energy consumption has historically been a vital indicator of robust economic activities and improved living standards. But when this input turns irregular and insufficient, driving up its costs to an outrageous level, the manufacturing sector can hardly be sustainable. Bangladesh, according to sea</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 18:56:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>77 more upazilas get new UNOs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/77-more-upazilas-get-new-unos</link><description>The government has appointed Upazila Nirbahi Officers (UNOs) in 77 more upazilas.
The Ministry of Public Administration issued a gazette notification in this regard, appointing senior assistant secretaries to the posts.
This comes after the first phase of appointments on November 26, when 166 upa</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 19:11:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Factories mostly linked to US market feel strain</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/factories-mostly-linked-to-us-market-feel-strain</link><description>A survey supported by two international agencies has found jacked-up US tariff's emerging but uneven business impacts on Bangladesh's garment export as factories mostly linked to the American market are already showing signs of strain.



High market concentration with exports heavily reliant o</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 19:26:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rice, fish, meat key drivers of Oct food inflation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/rice-fish-meat-key-drivers-of-oct-food-inflation</link><description>Rice, fish, and meat remained the dominant drivers of food inflation in October, accounting for 99.78 per cent of the total, while a continued decline in vegetable prices helped temper overall price pressures, according to the General Economics Division (GED) of the Planning Commission.
The Novemb</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 02:00:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka continues attempts to revise overpriced JICA metro-rail bids</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/dhaka-continues-attempts-to-revise-overpriced-jica-metro-rail-bids</link><description>Dhaka Metro Rail Company continues its effort for negotiating over-priced quotations in various contracts of metro-rail projects and will soon send a reminder to the projects' Japanese financier.
Managing Director of Dhaka Mass Transit Company Limited (DMTCL) Faruque Ahmed explained the move durin</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 02:15:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Parts of Chattogram shaken by 4.9-magnitude quake</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/49-magnitude-earthquake-in-myanmar-shakes-parts-of-chattogram</link><description>A moderate earthquake struck near Falam in Myanmar shortly before 1:00 am on Tuesday and was felt in parts of Chattogram.
According to the US Geological Survey (USGS), the quake occurred at 12:55am Bangladesh time, registering 4.9 on the Richter scale.
The epicentre was located 81.8km east of Fal</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 02:30:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No-frill account deposits fall in Jul-Sept 2025</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/no-frill-account-deposits-fall-in-jul-sept-2025</link><description>Total deposits in the No-Frill Accounts (NFAs) designed for underprivileged people stood at Tk 49.84 billion in the July-September 2025 quarter, down 1.05 per cent from the previous quarter. Rising living costs and volatility in the country's financial sector have contributed to the decline.
Howev</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 03:23:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>VAT On Metro Rail Tickets: Passengers to get exemption for another six months</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/vat-on-metro-rail-tickets-passengers-to-get-exemption-for-another-six-months</link><description>The government has decided to extend the Vat exemption facility for Metrorail passengers by six months more, until June 30. 2026.
The facility is scheduled to expire on December 31, 2025.
Finance adviser Dr Salehuddin Ahmed recently approved the proposal on exemption of 15 per cent Vat on prices</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 03:38:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt to extend 20pc power bill rebate facility to fish, livestock, poultry farms</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/govt-to-extend-20pc-power-bill-rebate-facility-to-fish-livestock-poultry-farms</link><description>The government is set to extend the 20 per cent power bill rebate facility to the owners of marginal fish farms, hatcheries, and livestock and poultry farms.
This important inclusion in the rebate beneficiary list, spearheaded by the Ministry of Fisheries and Livestock (MoFL), aims to drastically</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 03:53:29 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>