<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 16:28:13 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>BPL action heats up with Chattogram leading the table</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bpl-action-heats-up-with-chattogram-leading-the-table</link><description>The 2025-26 Bangladesh Premier League (BPL) has reached a fever pitch after 20 matches, with vintage performances from local stars overshadowing the looming diplomatic crisis surrounding the upcoming T20 World Cup.
Mustafizur Rahman, fresh from the controversy of being removed from the IPL by the</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 14:29:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cold wave sweeping 19 districts to persist through Sunday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/cold-wave-sweeping-19-districts-to-persist-through-sunday</link><description>A cold wave is sweeping across large parts of Bangladesh, dragging nighttime temperatures down to 8.3°C in Tetulia, one of the lowest readings this season.
The Bangladesh Meteorological Department (BMD) said the cold conditions are expected to continue through Sunday, with fog likely in severa</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 14:44:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Plan for separate ‘Microcredit Bank’ threatens Bangladesh’s poorest, experts warn</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/plan-for-separate-microcredit-bank-threatens-bangladeshs-poorest-experts-warn</link><description>COAST Foundation, BDCSO Process, and EquityBD Saturday warned that the government’s plan to set up a separate microcredit bank could harm Bangladesh’s poorest people.
The proposal is being promoted as a “social innovation,” but the civil society organisations (CSOs) say it</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 14:59:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gulzar Ahmed elected as vice-chairman of Standard Bank</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/gulzar-ahmed-elected-as-vice-chairman-of-standard-bank</link><description>Mr. Gulzar Ahmed, a director of Standard Bank PLC and head of the country's renowned jewellery company Apan Jewellers, was elected as the vice-chairman of the bank at the 421st meeting of the Board of Directors of Standard Bank held on 07 January 2026, according to a press release.
Mr. Gulzar Ahme</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 14:00:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prime Bank signs payroll banking agreement with Bando Eco Apparels</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/prime-bank-signs-payroll-banking-agreement-with-bando-eco-apparels</link><description>Prime Bank PLC recently signed a Payroll Banking agreement with Bando Eco Apparels Limited, a sister concern of Teamtex Group, is a Bangladeshi Ready-made Garment (RMG) manufacturer, specialising in woven shirts and other apparel, to offer comprehensive Payroll Banking services.
According to a pre</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 14:15:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCC Bank signs agreement with DHL Express to reduce carbon emission</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ncc-bank-signs-agreement-with-dhl-express-to-reduce-carbon-emission</link><description>With the aim of strengthening environmentally responsible and sustainable banking practices, NCC Bank has entered into a strategic partnership with DHL Express under “GoGreen Plus- Carbon Reduced Service”.
According to a press release, this collaboration marks a significant milestone i</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 14:30:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamuna Bank holds Annual Business Conference 2026</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/jamuna-bank-holds-annual-business-conference-2026</link><description>Jamuna Bank PLC recently held its Annual Business Conference 2026 at a luxurious hotel in Dhaka, according to a press release.
The bank’s chairman, Md. Belal Hossain, attended the conference as the chief guest.
Chairman of the bank’s Executive Committee and Jamuna Bank Foundation, Nur</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 14:45:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Total deposits of Islami Bank reach Tk 1.83 trillion</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/total-deposits-of-islami-bank-reach-tk-183-trillion</link><description>By transforming challenges into opportunities, the total deposits of Islami Bank reached at Tk 1.83 trillion (Tk 183,000 crore) as of December 31, 2025, a press statement says.
This reflects a growth of over Tk 220.00 billion within a single year. Furthermore, deposits in the bank's Agent Banking</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 15:00:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Eastern Bank launches VISA SME Credit card</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/eastern-bank-launches-visa-sme-credit-card</link><description>Eastern Bank PLC (EBL), in collaboration with Visa, has launched the EBL Visa SME Credit Card, a dedicated credit solution designed exclusively for sole proprietorship business loan customers.
The dual-currency, EMV chip secured Visa Credit card is aimed at supporting business-related payments wit</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 15:15:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Citizens Bank signs agreement with Titas Gas Transmission and Distribution</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/citizens-bank-signs-agreement-with-titas-gas-transmission-and-distribution</link><description>Citizens Bank PLC signed an agreement with Titas Gas Transmission and Distribution PLC at Titas Bhaban, Karwan Bazar, Dhaka, recently, according to a press release.
In the presence of Mr. Alamgir Hossain, Managing Director, Citizens Bank PLC, and Mr. Shahnewaz Parvez, Managing Director, Titas Gas</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 15:30:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Three members of Chattogram family killed in Oman road crash</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/three-members-of-chattogram-family-killed-in-oman-road-crash</link><description>Three members of a Chattogram family from Fatikchhari have been killed in a road accident while travelling in Oman.
The dead are identified as Sakibul Hasan Sabuj, his mother Bilkis Akter, and his brother-in-law Didarul Alam, residents of Sundarpur Union’s Silonia.
The accident occurred lat</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 15:45:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Throat-slit teen found in Banasree home</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/throat-slit-teen-found-in-banasree-home</link><description>Police have recovered the body of a 17-year-old schoolgirl from her home in South Banasree, with her throat slit.
The teenager, identified as Fatema Akter Nili, is a 10th grader at Radiant School.
Khilgaon Police chief Mohammad Shafiqul Islam said the body was recovered from a house named Pritam</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 16:00:15 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>