<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 12:43:51 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Ministry of Home Affairs to hold emergency meeting this evening</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ministry-of-home-affairs-to-hold-emergency-meeting-this-evening</link><description>The Ministry of Home Affairs has called an emergency press conference at 5:30pm today to brief journalists on the country’s overall law and order situation.
Home Affairs Advisor Lieutenant General (retd.) Md. Jahangir Alam Chowdhury is expected to answer questions from reporters at the brief</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 08:31:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No breach attempt at Bangladesh High Commission during protest: India</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/no-breach-attempt-at-bangladesh-high-commission-during-protest-india</link><description>About the reported demonstration in front of the Bangladesh High Commission in New Delhi on December 20, official spokesperson at the Indian Ministry of External Affairs Randhir Jaiswal on Sunday said there was no attempt to breach the fence or create a security situation at any time.
India is com</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 10:00:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>RU students demand resignation of 6 ‘pro-AL’ deans</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/ru-students-demand-resignation-of-6-pro-al-deans</link><description>Students at Rajshahi University have padlocked the offices of six deans they allege are aligned with the Awami League, demanding their resignation.
The action was taken on Sunday afternoon after the university administration decided to extend the deans’ terms despite the expiry of their offi</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 09:45:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Algerian Embassy celebrates World Arabic Language Day 2025</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/algerian-embassy-celebrates-world-arabic-language-day-2025</link><description>The Embassy of Algeria in Bangladesh on Sunday, celebrated World Arabic Language Day 2025 at the Embassy premises in Dhaka.
The event brought together diplomats, academics, technologists, journalists, business leaders, Islamic scholars, students from various institutions, members of the Bangladesh</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 10:00:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP criticises attacks on newspaper offices; promises freedom of expression if it returns to power</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-criticises-attacks-on-newspaper-offices-promises-freedom-of-expression-if-it-returns-to-power</link><description>BNP Standing Committee Member Salahuddin Ahmed said that the attacks on the offices of Prothom Alo and The Daily Star were a shame for the nation.
He said the attackers burned and destroyed Prothom Alo and The Daily Star offices, and the whole world watched it.
“It is a matter of shame for</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 10:15:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nomination papers collected on behalf of Khaleda, Tarique in Bogura</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/nomination-papers-collected-on-behalf-of-khaleda-tarique-in-bogura</link><description>Nomination papers have been collected in Bogura on behalf of Bangladesh Nationalist Party chief Khaleda Zia and the party’s acting chief Tarique Rahman for the parliamentary polls scheduled for Feb 12.
Rezaul Karim Badsha, president of BNP’s Bogura district unit, said on Sunday that th</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 10:30:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Long lines at the food pantry: Inflation tests Trump’s base in Michigan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/long-lines-at-the-food-pantry-inflation-tests-trumps-base-in-michigan</link><description>On a recent snowy morning in a Trump-loving part of rural Michigan, three dozen cars idled outside a firehouse-turned-food pantry. Inside, volunteers packaged lettuce, apples and other household staples that have surged or stayed high in price this year.
Taylor Ludwig, a 35-year-old mother of thre</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 10:45:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Attacks on Prothom Alo, The Daily Star an assault on media freedom: EU envoy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/attacks-on-prothom-alo-the-daily-star-an-assault-on-media-freedom-eu-envoy</link><description>European Union Ambassador to Bangladesh Michael Miller has said that attacks on Prothom Alo and The Daily Star constitute a direct assault on media freedom and freedom of expression, terming the incidents a “terrible moment for Bangladesh’s democracy.”
He made the remarks on Sund</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 11:00:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Call for enforcing laws and supporting alternative livelihoods for affected farmers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/call-for-enforcing-laws-and-supporting-alternative-livelihoods-for-affected-farmers</link><description>Speakers at a human chain in Shyamnagar upazila of Satkhira district on Sunday called for strict enforcement of laws to stop shrimp and crab farming on agricultural land, warning that the intrusion of saline water is destroying cropland, reducing soil fertility and threatening local livelihoods and</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 11:17:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Australian Prime Minister booed as Bondi Beach attack victims honoured</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/australian-prime-minister-booed-as-bondi-beach-attack-victims-honoured</link><description>Australian Prime Minister Anthony Albanese was booed by an angry crowd gathered at the famous Bondi beach on Sunday to honour the victims of a gun attack a week earlier that targeted a seaside Jewish Hanukkah festival event.
The nation marked a day of reflection on Sunday to honour the 15 people k</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 11:32:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh envoy felt threatened during protest in New Delhi: Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-envoy-felt-threatened-during-protest-in-new-delhi-dhaka</link><description>Bangladesh on Sunday rejected remarks by India's Ministry of External Affairs over demonstrations outside the Bangladesh High Commission in New Delhi, saying the protests left the High Commissioner and his family feeling threatened.
Foreign Affairs Adviser Md Touhid Hossain came up with Bangladesh</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 11:47:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NBR chairman hints at further extension for online return submission</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/nbr-chairman-hints-at-further-extension-for-online-return-submission</link><description>National Board of Revenue (NBR) Chairman Abdur Rahman Khan has hinted at a possible further extension of the deadline for online income tax return submission, as a significant number of registered taxpayers are yet to file their returns digitally.
Indicating the possibility of an extension, he sai</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 12:02:03 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>