<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 04:21:16 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Protests held in Dhaka, JU</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/protests-held-in-dhaka-ju</link><description>Students of Jahangirnagar University (JU) on Friday staged a demonstration to condemn Israel's interception of Global Sumud Flotilla (GSF) aid boats and express solidarity with the ongoing humanitarian missions to Palestine.
The protest, organised by Jahangirnagar University Central Students' Unio</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 00:39:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Miscreants set fire to bus in city's Kazipara</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/miscreants-set-fire-to-bus-in-citys-kazipara</link><description>Miscreants set a passenger bus belonging to Alif Paribahan on fire in the capital's East Kazipara area on Friday. However, there was no report of casualties in the incident that happened at around 7:00 am.
Sources at the Kafrul Police Station said the bus came under attack when a group of individu</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 00:54:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Liberation War sculptures at Rajshahi University lie neglected</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/liberation-war-sculptures-at-rajshahi-university-lie-neglected</link><description>Rajshahi University's (RU) sculptures, which were built in the memory of the Liberation War, lie neglected, weather-worn, and have been losing their splendor due to poor maintenance and preservation.
Paint has worn off the statues as parts of the several structures remain broken. Some were left un</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 01:24:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Police arrest 29 persons from city’s Mohammadpur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/police-arrest-29-persons-from-citys-mohammadpur</link><description>Police arrested 29 individuals during a special drive in the capital's Mohammadpur area on Wednesday.
DMP Deputy Commissioner (Media and Public Relations) Muhammad Talebur Rahman said a team of Mohammadpur Police Station nabbed the arrestees during the daylong raid at different spots of Mohammadpu</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 01:39:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Revenue board to be linked to multiple public agencies</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/revenue-board-to-be-linked-to-multiple-public-agencies</link><description>The government plans to launch a new digital transformation initiative to integrate siloed, fragmented, and duplicative data from public agencies across multiple ministries and divisions, say Planning Commission sources.
The initiative aims to link the National Board of Revenue (NBR) with the nati</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 01:54:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CPA on the lookout for new berth operators</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/cpa-on-the-lookout-for-new-berth-operators</link><description>The Chittagong Port Authority (CPA) has taken an initiative to issue licences to recruit new operators.
Despite the protest by the existing berth and ship handling operators, the CPA has decided to recruit the new operators.
Sources say there are currently around 60 berth operators and ship handl</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 02:09:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP leader hacked to death in Bagerhat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bnp-leader-hacked-to-death-in-bagerhat</link><description>A BNP leader has been killed in Bagerhat town after assailants arrived on motorcycles and hacked him while he was sitting at a tea stall, police say.
The incident occurred around 6:30 pm on Friday at the three-road intersection in Uttar Harikhali, Bagerhat Sadar Model Police Station chief Md Mahmu</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 02:39:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Woman hacked to death over chicken in Mymensingh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/woman-hacked-to-death-over-chicken-in-mymensingh</link><description>A woman was hacked to death by a neighbour in Ishwarganj upazila of Mymensingh on Friday evening following a dispute over a chicken.
The deceased was identified as Rowshan Ara Begum, 50, of Khairati village under Ishwarganj union, reports UNB.
According to the police and locals, there had been a</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 02:54:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US university sold dead bodies for ‘Israeli military training’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-university-sold-dead-bodies-for-israeli-military-training</link><description>The University of Southern California (USC) has received at least $860,000 from the United States Navy since late 2017 in exchange for 89 cadavers, many of which were used to train the Israeli Defence Forces (IDF) in trauma surgery, according to a report by Annenberg Media.
The arrangement began w</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 03:09:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump orders Israel to stop bombing Gaza</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-orders-israel-to-stop-bombing-gaza</link><description>US President Donald Trump on Friday ordered Israel to stop bombing the Gaza Strip after Hamas said it had accepted some elements of his plan to end the nearly two-year war and return all the remaining hostages taken in the Oct. 7, 2023, attack. 
Hamas said it was willing to release the hostag</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 03:24:12 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>