<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 12:53:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>100 kg of venison seized in Bagerhat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/100-kg-of-venison-seized-in-bagerhat</link><description>Members of Coast Guard in a drive seized 100 kgs of deer venison from Gholer Khal in Koyra upazila of Sundarbans in Khulna district.
Tipped off, a team of Coast Guard conducted a special drive in the area around 4 pm on Monday and recovered the venison and four metres of deer poaching traps, said</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 09:33:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Over 100 children killed in Gaza since ceasefire, UNICEF says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/over-100-children-killed-in-gaza-since-ceasefire-unicef-says</link><description>The UN children's agency said on Tuesday that over 100 children have been killed in Gaza since the October ceasefire, including victims of drone and quadcopter attacks.
“More than 100 children have been killed in Gaza since the ceasefire of early October," UNICEF spokesperson James Elder tol</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 09:48:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Probashi Kallyan Bank to launch Sharia-based loan scheme soon for expatriates: Asif Nazrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/probashi-kallyan-bank-to-launch-sharia-based-loan-scheme-soon-for-expatriates-asif-nazrul</link><description>Expatriates’ Welfare and Overseas Employment Adviser Dr Asif Nazrul on Tuesday said Probashi Kallyan Bank will launch Sharia-based loan scheme soon for Bangladeshi expatriates.
“Good news for expatriate brothers. The Sharia-based loan programme is going to be launched soon from the Pro</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 10:03:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Probe report in Salman Shah killing case on Feb 22</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/probe-report-in-salman-shah-killing-case-on-feb-22</link><description>A Dhaka court on Tuesday set February 22 for submitting a probe report in a case lodged over the murder of the popular movie superstar Salman Shah.
Dhaka Metropolitan Magistrate Jewel Rana passed the order as the investigation officer (IO) failed to submit the report today.
On October 21, 2025, S</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 10:18:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>All communication channels with Bangladesh open: Indian army chief</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/all-communication-channels-with-bangladesh-open-indian-army-chief</link><description>Indian Army Chief General Upendra Dwivedi says all branches of the country’s armed forces have communication channels open with Bangladesh in order to “avoid misunderstandings”.
He made the remarks on Wednesday during an annual press conference of the Indian Armed Forces in New D</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 10:33:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gazipur scrap fabric factory fire contained</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/gazipur-scrap-fabric-factory-fire-contained</link><description>A fire at a “jhut” or waste fabric warehouse in Gazipur has been brought under control within an hour by the Fire Service.
The incident occurred around 12:30pm on Tuesday in the Kathora area of Salna, according to Hiron Mia, station officer of the Bhogra Modern Fire Service.
The fire</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 10:48:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The West Bank soccer field slated for demolition by Israel</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/the-west-bank-soccer-field-slated-for-demolition-by-israel</link><description>Israeli authorities have ordered the demolition of a soccer field in a crowded refugee camp in the occupied West Bank, eliminating one of the few spaces where Palestinian children are able to run and play.
“If the field gets demolished, this will destroy our dreams and our future. We c</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 11:03:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Iran official says 2,000 people have been killed in unrest</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/iran-official-says-2000-people-have-been-killed-in-unrest</link><description>About 2,000 people including security personnel have been killed in protests in Iran, an Iranian official said on Tuesday, the first time authorities have acknowledged the high death toll from an intense crackdown on two weeks of nationwide unrest.
The Iranian official, speaking to Reuters, said t</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 11:18:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump's Iran tariff threat risks reopening China rift</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trumps-iran-tariff-threat-risks-reopening-china-rift</link><description>Donald Trump's threat to slap a 25 per cent tariff on countries that trade with Iran risks reopening old wounds with Beijing, Tehran's top partner, challenging Chinese leader Xi Jinping's global image and resolve to defend China's commercial interests.
Iran became a major flashpoint in US-China ti</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 11:33:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Move to clear Hasina, 112 others: what PBI says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/what-pbi-says-about-urging-court-to-drop-charges-against-hasina-112-others</link><description>The Police Bureau of Investigation (PBI) has said it is “facing pressure” over its recommendation to clear former prime minister Sheikh Hasina and 112 others over “attempted murder” during the July Uprising, insisting that the case itself was riddled with factual flaws.
In</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 11:48:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Educational institutions asked to conduct extensive campaign on referendum</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/educational-institutions-asked-to-conduct-extensive-campaign-on-referendum</link><description>The Directorate of Secondary and Higher Education (DSHE) and the Directorate of Madrasha Education (DME) have instructed conducting comprehensive campaigns in all government and private schools, colleges and madrasas to create public awareness among voters about the referendum to be held on Februar</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 12:03:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Denmark, Greenland to meet Vance, Rubio on Wednesday amid Trump’s takeover threat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/denmark-greenland-to-meet-vance-rubio-on-wednesday-amid-trumps-takeover-threat</link><description>The foreign ministers of Denmark and Greenland will meet U.S. Vice President JD Vance and Secretary of State Marco Rubio on Wednesday, the Danish foreign minister said, amid President Donald Trump’s push to take control of the Arctic island.
Danish Foreign Minister Lars Lokke Rasmussen and h</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 12:18:27 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>