<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 16:34:43 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>2 shot as campaigners clash in Munshiganj</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/2-shot-as-campaigners-clash-in-munshiganj</link><description>Violence has broken out between supporters of the BNP and an independent candidate over election campaigning in Sadar Upazila of Munshiganj-3 seat, leaving at least two people with gunshot wounds.
The clash took place on Saturday afternoon in Munshikandi village, Munshiganj's Additional Superinten</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 12:36:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Privacy-first social platform ZKTOR enters Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/privacy-first-social-platform-zktor-enters-bangladesh</link><description>As ZKTOR expands beta testing from India and Nepal into Bangladesh and Sri Lanka, its design-led model raises deeper questions about data sovereignty, youth opportunity, and the future of regional digital infrastructure.
Developed by Softa Technologies Limited, ZKTOR has already undergone mass pub</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 12:53:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Md Ahteshamul Haque Khan joins Dutch-Bangla Bank as Managing Director and CEO</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/md-ahteshamul-haque-khan-joins-dutch-bangla-bank-as-managing-director-and-ceo</link><description>Md. Ahteshamul Haque Khan joined Dutch-Bangla Bank as the Managing Director and CEO on 7 February 2026.
Before joining as the Managing Director &amp; CEO, Mr. Khan was the Deputy Managing Director and Chief Business Officer (CBO) of the same bank for around 6 years. He was also the Chief Operating Off</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 13:08:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump map shows entire Kashmir as part of India</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/trump-map-shows-entire-kashmir-as-part-of-india</link><description>The Donald Trump administration has released a map showing the entire region of Kashmir as part of India, marking a major shift from previous US maps that excluded Pakistan-administered Kashmir.
The graphic, shared by the Office of the United States Trade Representative (USTR) on X, while announci</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 13:23:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh, Maldives eye direct shipping, halal food cooperation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladesh-maldives-eye-direct-shipping-halal-food-cooperation</link><description>Bangladesh and the Maldives on Saturday reaffirmed their commitment to strengthening bilateral cooperation, with a focus on direct shipping connectivity and expanded collaboration in the halal food industry to boost trade, transport efficiency and sustainable supply chains.
The commitment was made</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 13:38:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP urges EC to identify female polling agents as per laws, regulations</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-urges-ec-to-identify-female-polling-agents-as-per-laws-regulations</link><description>BNP central election steering committee spokesperson and adviser to the BNP chairman Mahdi Amin on Saturday urged the Election Commission (EC) to identify female polling agents with law and regulations.
He said, "It must be ensured that an adequate number of female polling officers are appointed i</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 13:41:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique Rahman set to hold 14 rallies in Dhaka over two days</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-rahman-set-to-hold-14-rallies-in-dhaka-over-two-days</link><description>BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman is set to hold rallies across 14 constituencies in Dhaka over two days.
This follows a whirlwind nationwide campaign by the BNP chairman for the Sheaf of Paddy symbol before the parliamentary elections.
The party's Central Election Steering Committee spokesperson Mahdi</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 13:56:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Standard Bank holds business review meeting of Dhaka region</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/standard-bank-holds-business-review-meeting-of-dhaka-region</link><description>Standard Bank PLC organised a Business Review Meeting at the bank’s head office in Dhaka on Saturday with the participation of Heads of all branches of the Dhaka region, according to a press release.
Managing Director (Acting) of the bank Mr. Md. Siddiqur Rahman presided over the meeting whi</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 14:11:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Al-Arafah Islami Bank resumes all services after upgrading its core banking system</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/al-arafah-islami-bank-resumes-all-services-after-upgrading-its-core-banking-system</link><description>Following the successful completion of the Core Banking System (CBS) upgrade at Al-Arafah Islami Bank, all banking services are set to be resumed on Sunday, 8 February 2026.
According to a press release, the upgrade was carried out to enhance technological capabilities, establish a modern banking</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 14:26:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP vows to give every child the opportunity to explore their talent</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-vows-to-give-every-child-the-opportunity-to-explore-their-talent</link><description>BNP Chairperson has set a goal to ensure that every child gets the opportunity to explore his or her inner talent, which will help build a healthy nation, said BNP Standing Committee member Nazrul Islam Khan on Saturday.
He made the remarks while speaking at a post-documentary discussion programme</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 14:41:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mother ‘strangles’ daughter on ‘lover’s prompt’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/mother-strangles-daughter-on-lovers-prompt</link><description>Police in Gopalganj recovered the body of a 3-year-old girl 20 days after she went missing from Sadar Upazila, arresting her mother, who allegedly killed the child at the prompting of her lover.
On Saturday afternoon, officers broke the lock of a room in Gobra Madhya Para and found the child&amp;rsquo</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 15:27:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Voters can find polling station information in four ways</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/voters-can-find-polling-station-information-in-four-ways</link><description>Bangladesh Election Commission (EC) has introduced four simple methods for voters to obtain their voter number and polling station information to facilitate voting in the February 12 national elections and referendum.
Using these methods, voters can quickly and accurately find their voter number a</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 15:42:53 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>