<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 03:03:40 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Looking at acts of wrongdoing</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/looking-at-acts-of-wrongdoing</link><description>Engaging in harmful activities, casually or carelessly, is being seen as a normal practice in the country. Over the years, attempting to curb or even minimise such acts has become difficult because a growing number of people do not find anything wrong with their actions that negatively affect other</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 16:47:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How to waste Tk 42.68 billion!</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/how-to-waste-tk-4268-billion</link><description>An old joke tells of an African minister who once visited his Asian friend's huge mansion and asked how he could afford it on a government salary. The Asian smiled and gestured to a half-finished bridge and a new highway outside his window. "10 per cent from each," he said. A year later, the visit</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 17:02:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fire at Mirpur Community Center Building</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fire-at-mirpur-community-center-building</link><description>A fire broke out on the sixth floor of a six-storey building that houses a garment factory at Bibah Bari Community Center on Kalshi Road in Mirpur 12 on Thursday night.
According to the Fire Service and Civil Defence, the fire was reported at 10:12 pm, and the first unit reached the scene at 10:27</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 17:17:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Carney ready to resume US-Canada trade talks halted by Trump over Reagan ad</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/carney-ready-to-resume-us-canada-trade-talks-halted-by-trump-over-reagan-ad</link><description>Prime Minister Mark Carney said on Friday that Canada stands ready to resume trade talks with the United States that President Donald Trump halted over an anti-tariff advertisement issued by Ontario's provincial government.
Trump terminated the talks on Thursday over the video which used Republica</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 17:03:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US strike against alleged drug vessel in Caribbean kills six, Pentagon says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-strike-against-alleged-drug-vessel-in-caribbean-kills-six-pentagon-says</link><description>A US strike against an alleged drug vessel killed six suspected "narco-terrorists" in the Caribbean, US Defense Secretary Pete Hegseth said on Friday, the latest operation in President Donald Trump's counter-drug campaign in the region.
In a post on X, Hegseth said this was the first strike carrie</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 17:18:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Afghanistan plans to dam river flowing into Pakistan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/afghanistan-plans-dam-on-kunar-river-follows-indias-move-to-restrict-pakistans-water-access</link><description>Afghanistan is planning to build a dam on the Kunar River to restrict the flow of water into Pakistan, following India’s example of suspending water sharing under the Indus Waters Treaty earlier this year.
The move comes under the instruction of Taliban Supreme Leader Mawlawi Hibatullah Akhu</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 17:33:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Full autonomy to empower central bank</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/full-autonomy-to-empower-central-bank</link><description>The move is on to bring an end to the legacy of bureaucratic control of and political interference in the central bank of Bangladesh. It is difficult to predict the final outcome. However, the Bangladesh Bank Board through approving the draft amendment to the Bangladesh Bank Ordinance 2025, which i</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 17:48:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>After Nassa, beleaguered Gazi Group gets loan rescheduling facility</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/after-nassa-beleaguered-gazi-group-gets-loan-rescheduling-facility</link><description>Now the beleaguered Gazi Group is also getting special opportunity to reschedule its hefty default loans, officials say.



Pursuant to government policy update, the central bank's high-powered loan-rescheduling committee has asked the 19 commercial banks and financial institutions concerned to</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 18:18:33 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>