<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 09:31:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Man dies ‘while making’ crude bomb in Shariatpur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/man-dies-while-making-crude-bomb-in-shariatpur</link><description>A man has been killed in a crude bomb explosion in Zajira upazila of Shariatpur.
Police believe the man died while making a crude bomb when it exploded early Thursday in the Mulai Beparikandi area of Bilaspur union.
The victim has been identified as Sohan Bepari, 32, son of Delwar Bepari of the n</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 06:10:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Barcelona maul Bilbao 5-0 to reach Spanish Super Cup final</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/barcelona-maul-bilbao-5-0-to-reach-spanish-super-cup-final</link><description>Fermin Lopez scored one goal and laid on two more as Barcelona tore through Athletic Bilbao to record a 5-0 victory in their Spanish Super Cup semi-final played in Jeddah, Saudi Arabia on Wednesday, extending the Catalans’ winning run to nine matches.
Raphinha scored twice while Ferran Torre</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 06:25:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC dispatches 728K postal ballots to expatriate voters</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-dispatches-728k-postal-ballots-to-expatriate-voters</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has dispatched postal ballots to 728,023 expatriate voters living in 104 countries to enable them to cast their votes in the upcoming 13th Jatiya Sangsad election and referendum.
Salim Ahmad Khan, team leader of the Out of Country Voting System and Implementation (OCV-</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 06:27:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump backs bill to sanction 500pc tariffs on India</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/global/trump-backs-bill-to-sanction-500pc-tariffs-on-india</link><description>US President Donald Trump has approved the new bill called the ‘Sanctioning of Russia Act 2025’, which aims to sharply increase pressure on Russia over the Ukraine war.
The proposed law would allow the US to impose tariffs of at least 500 per cent on countries that buy Russian oil, inc</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 06:42:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No ‘staged- managed’ election this time: CEC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/no-staged-managed-election-this-time-cec</link><description>Chief Election Commissioner (CEC) AMM Nasir Uddin on Thursday said the 13th parliamentary election won't be a 'staged-managed' one, unlike the previous ones in the past.
"Unlike before, there will be no staged election this time..... A level playing field will be ensured for everyone," he said.
T</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 06:57:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>LPG cylinder sales suspended indefinitely</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/lpg-cylinder-sales-suspended-indefinitely</link><description>LPG cylinder sales have been suspended indefinitely across the country following a call by the LP Gas Traders’ Cooperative Association, demanding a revision of prices and an end to alleged harassment and fines imposed on dealers.
The suspension came into effect on Thursday and applies nation</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 07:12:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US seizes Russian-flagged tanker as Trump widens oil push</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-seizes-russian-flagged-tanker-another-tied-to-venezuela-as-trump-widens-oil-push</link><description>The US seized two Venezuela-linked oil tankers in the Atlantic Ocean on Wednesday, one sailing under Russia's flag, as part of President Donald Trump's aggressive push to dictate oil flows in the Americas and force Venezuela's socialist government to become an ally.
After capturing Venezuelan Pres</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 07:27:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Case filed over murder of BNP volunteer wing leader Muchabbir</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/case-filed-over-murder-of-bnp-volunteer-wing-leader-muchabbir</link><description>A case has been filed with Tejgaon Police Station against unidentified individuals following the murder of 44-year-old BNP volunteer wing leader Azizur Rahman Muchabbir, who was shot dead.
The case was lodged on Thursday by Suraiya Begum, his wife, according to Ibn-e-Mizan, deputy commissioner of</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 08:12:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Unidentified man found dead in Chuadanga</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/unidentified-man-found-dead-in-chuadanga</link><description>Police recovered the body of an unidentified man from a corn field at Kayetpara in Alamdanga upazila of Chuadanga district on Thursday.
Local people first spotted the body of the man, aged about 38–40, wearing trousers and a navy-blue jacket, in the field around 9:00 am and informed the poli</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 08:27:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No election code violation in Tarique’s northern region tour: Salahuddin</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/no-election-code-violation-in-tariques-northern-region-tour-salahuddin</link><description>BNP senior leader Salahuddin Ahmed on Thursday said the upcoming four-day tour of the northern region by party Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman will not violate the election code of conduct, as it is meant to pay homage to the martyrs of the July mass uprising.
"Some people may be viewing this tour</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 08:58:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh issues Forest and Tree Conservation Ordinance 2026 with Tk 100,000 fine</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-issues-forest-and-tree-conservation-ordinance-2026-with-tk-100000-fine</link><description>The Bangladesh government has issued the Forest and Tree Ordinance 2026 with the aim of preventing the occupation of forest land, regulating the use of forest land for non-forest purposes, ensuring proper conservation of forests and forest land, preventing the reduction of forest areas, and protect</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 09:13:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Teenager killed in Madaripur road crash</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/teenager-killed-in-madaripur-road-crash</link><description>A teenager was killed and another injured in a road accident at Rajoir upazila of Madaripur district on Wednesday night.
The deceased was identified as Osman, 19, son of Billal Howlader of Uttaripara village under Rangabali Police Station in Patuakhali district. He was a student of Baitul Noor Cad</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 09:28:49 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>