<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 06:34:51 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Hasina offers no apology for July killings</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hasina-offers-no-apology-for-july-killings</link><description>Ousted prime minister Sheikh Hasina has “refused to apologise” over the deaths during the crackdown on the July Uprising, and in turn, criticised the proceedings at the International Crimes Tribunal (ICT).
In an interview with The Independent, Hasina said she would “neither be su</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 03:50:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Former IGP Mamun produced at ICT amid heightened security</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/former-igp-mamun-produced-at-ict-amid-heightened-security</link><description>Security at the International Crimes Tribunal has been beefed up ahead of the verdict in the case against ousted prime minister Sheikh Hasina and two others for their role in attempting to violently suppress the July Uprising.
Former police chief Chowdhury Abdullah Al-Mamun, the only suspect in cu</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 04:05:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Untimely rain damages Tk 1.31b crops in Rajshahi agri region</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/untimely-rain-damages-tk-131b-crops-in-rajshahi-agri-region</link><description>Two days of unseasonal rainfall in early November caused extensive crop losses across four districts in the Rajshahi agriculture region, damaging over 19,500 hectares of farmland and affecting nearly 43,000 farmers, according to the Department of Agricultural Extension (DAE).
Official sources said</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 04:20:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Implement National Logistics Policy 2024 immediately</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/implement-national-logistics-policy-2024-immediately</link><description>Bangladesh Cargo Vessel Owners' Association (BCVOA) and the Coastal Ship Owners Association of Bangladesh (COAB) Sunday urged the government to immediately implement the National Logistics Policy 2024, particularly its provisions related to cargo transport by vessels.
At a press conference held at</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 04:35:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tripartite approach can help create 'inclusive' labour market for PWDs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/tripartite-approach-can-help-create-inclusive-labour-market-for-pwds</link><description>A shared responsibility from government, companies and trade unions can help create an 'inclusive and conducive' labour market for persons with disabilities (PWDs).
In that case, government can identify legal barriers and coordinate among all legislation to address the challenges to enable a legal</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 04:50:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nat'l leaders' coop indispensable for holding free, fair JS election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/natl-leaders-coop-indispensable-for-holding-free-fair-js-election</link><description>Chief Election Commissioner (CEC) A M M Nasir Uddin on Sunday sought cooperation and suggestions from the political parties to hold the 13th National Parliamentary Election in a free, fair, and acceptable manner.
He said the Election Commission (or EC) alone cannot arrange the entire process of ho</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 05:05:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Three workers burnt in shoe factory fire in Bangshal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/three-workers-burnt-in-shoe-factory-fire-in-bangshal</link><description>Three workers sustained burn injuries after a fire broke out at a shoe factory in the Bangshal area of Dhaka early Monday.
The incident occurred around 1:40 am at the factory located in Sikkatuli Mazar Goli under Bangshal Police Station.
The injured— Ainuddin, 45, Amir Uddin, 40, and Ruman,</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 04:51:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Joy warns of violence if ban on Awami League stays</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/joy-warns-of-violence-if-ban-on-awami-league-stays</link><description>The son and adviser of ousted Bangladesh Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina said on Sunday that supporters of her Awami League would block February’s national election if a ban on the party was not lifted, warning that protests could escalate into violence.
Sajeeb Wazed's remarks to Reuters came a</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 05:06:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Five vehicles torched, crude bomb blasts overnight</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/five-vehicles-torched-crude-bomb-blasts-overnight</link><description>Several buses, a truck and a four-wheeled passenger vehicle, locally known as a “Laguna”, have been set on fire in Dhaka’s Merul Badda, Mohammadpur, Savar, Narayanganj, and Dhamrai areas.
Crude hand bombs were also detonated in parts of the capital.
Fire Service Control Room Dut</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 05:21:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bus services suspended for second day in Barishal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/bus-services-suspended-for-second-day-in-barishal</link><description>Bus services from Nathullabad Bus Terminal in Barishal remained suspended for the second consecutive day on Monday, leaving thousands of commuters grappling with the crisis.
The bus operations on 23 intra-district routes have been halted since Saturday night after students of BM College allegedly</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 05:36:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Crude bomb hurled at Grameen Industrial Park in Gazipur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/crude-bomb-hurled-at-grameen-industrial-park-in-gazipur</link><description>Miscreants hurled a crude bomb at the main gate of Grameen Industrial Park in Kaliakair upazila of Gazipur district early Monday.
Sirajul Islam, security supervisor of Grameen Industrial Park-2 in Khara Jora area, said unidentified attackers threw the crude bomb targeting the factory at dawn.
Fla</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 05:51:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Four crude bomb blasts in Manikganj</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/four-crude-bomb-blasts-in-manikganj</link><description>At least four crude bombs have reportedly exploded in an hour in Manikganj, injuring two people.
The explosions took place between 10 pm and 11 pm on Sunday in areas surrounding the city's bus stand, the United Hospital adjacent to Sadar Hospital, and the Golra Highway Police Station, according to</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 06:06:34 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>