<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 15:23:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>DBBL holds Managers’ Conference-2026</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/dbbl-holds-managers-conference-2026</link><description>The Managers’ Conference-2026 of Dutch-Bangla Bank was held on 24 &amp; 25 January 2026 in Dhaka to review the bank’s overall performance for the year 2025 and discuss the business plan and strategy for achieving targets for the year 2026, according to a press release.
The Conference was p</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 13:04:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Racket altering mobile IMEI numbers busted in Dhaka, 1 held</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/racket-altering-mobile-imei-numbers-busted-in-dhaka-1-held</link><description>The Detective Branch (DB) Cyber Division of Dhaka Metropolitan Police (DMP) has busted a major racket involved in illegally altering mobile phone IMEI numbers and arrested a man in this connection.
They also seized software, a laptop and other equipment during the drive, said DMP Deputy Commission</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 13:19:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Muggers loot Tk 24 lakh firing shots, exploding crude bombs in Gazipur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/muggers-loot-tk-24-lakh-firing-shots-exploding-crude-bombs-in-gazipur</link><description>Muggers looted Tk 24 lakh by firing gunshots and exploding crude bombs in Basan area of Gazipur on Sunday afternoon.
Witnesses said Saiful Islam, a staff of Dutch-Bangla Bank agent outlet, owned by Shafiqul Islam, was heading towards Chandona intersection around 4:00pm to deposit money at a bank,</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 13:34:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Modhumoti Bank holds workshop on Islamic banking</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/modhumoti-bank-holds-workshop-on-islamic-banking</link><description>Modhumoti Bank PLC successfully organised a comprehensive training session on ‘Islamic Banking Fundamentals: Concept, Operational &amp; Investment Methodology of Islamic Banking’ on Saturday at the bank’s head office in Gulshan.
The event was graced by the presence of Mr. Md. Shafiul</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 12:48:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP entrant Abu Sayeed quits Pabna-1 election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bnp-entrant-abu-sayeed-quits-pabna-1-election-backs-party-nominee</link><description>Abu Sayeed, a former state minister for information and a recent BNP entrant, has announced his withdrawal from the election in the Pabna-1 (Santhia) constituency.
After initially contesting in the seat as an independent candidate, Abu Sayeed joined the BNP on Jan 21.
He confirmed his decision to</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 13:03:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>RAKUB holds annual sports competition</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/rakub-holds-annual-sports-competition</link><description>The annual sports competition of 2026 of Rajshahi Krishi Unnayan Bank (RAKUB) was held at the Physical Education Playground in Rajshahi on Saturday.
Professor Dr. Moahmmad Ali, Chairman of RAKUB Board of Directors, inaugurated and distributed prizes among winners at the function as the chief guest</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 13:18:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Legal reforms key to strengthening loan recovery: NCC Bank AMD</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/legal-reforms-key-to-strengthening-loan-recovery-ncc-bank-amd</link><description>Emphasising the urgent need for comprehensive legal reforms to strengthen Bangladesh’s banking sector, Additional Managing Director of NCC Bank PLC M. Khurshed Alam has outlined a series of proposals aimed at enhancing loan recovery and improving the effectiveness of the Artha Rin Adalat Act.</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 13:33:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DUCSU, Chhatra Dal leaders trade extortion allegations over campus shops</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/ducsu-chhatra-dal-leaders-trade-extortion-allegations-over-campus-shops</link><description>Dhaka University Central Students’ Union (DUCSU) and Jatiyatabadi Chhatra Dal leaders have traded allegations over extortion involving shops on the Dhaka University campus.
On Saturday night, DUCSU executive member Sarba Mitra Chakma alleged in a Facebook post that Nurul Gani Sagir, VP candi</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 13:48:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NRBC Bank holds BIZCON2026</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/nrbc-bank-holds-bizcon2026</link><description>NRBC Bank PLC successfully hosted its Annual Business Conference, BIZCON2026 — “Leading the Change,” last Saturday at a hotel.
 Mr. Md. Ali Hossain Prodhania, Chairman of the Board, attended as Chief Guest, according to a media release. 
 The conference was chaired by Manag</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 14:03:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Market stable, prices likely to ease further in Ramadan: Commerce adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/market-stable-prices-likely-to-ease-further-in-ramadan-commerce-adviser</link><description>Bangladesh’s market remains stable with no supply crunch, and the prices of essential commodities are expected to decline further during Ramadan, Commerce Adviser Sheikh Bashir Uddin said on Sunday.
Talking to journalists after the 10th meeting of the Taskforce Committee on reviewing prices</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 14:18:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US judge blocks Trump administration's push to end legal status of 8,400 migrants</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/us-judge-blocks-trump-administrations-push-to-end-legal-status-of-8400-migrants</link><description>A federal judge has blocked the Trump administration's push to terminate the legal status of more than 8,400 family members of US citizens and green card holders who moved to the United States from seven Latin American countries.
Boston-based US District Judge Indira Talwani issued a preliminary i</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 14:33:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh’s absence from T20 WC a 'sad moment' for cricket: WCA</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/cricket/bangladeshs-absence-from-t20-wc-a-sad-moment-for-cricket-wca</link><description>The absence of Bangladesh from next month's Twenty20 World Cup is a sad moment for the game and should serve as a call for stakeholders to work towards uniting the sport, not dividing it, the international cricketers' association said on Sunday.
The Tigers were replaced by Scotland in the 20-team</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 14:48:54 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>