<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 06:38:37 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Trump says nations doing business with Iran face 25% tariff on US trade</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-says-nations-doing-business-with-iran-face-25-tariff-on-us-trade</link><description>President Donald Trump said on Monday any country that does business with Iran will face a tariff rate of 25% on trade with the US, as Washington weighs a response to the situation in Iran which is seeing its biggest anti-government protests in years.
"Effective immediately, any Country doing busi</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 03:45:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nipah virus emerges as a 'real threat' in Manikganj</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/nipah-virus-emerges-as-a-real-threat-in-manikganj</link><description>The Nipah virus risk in Manikganj, a district located near Dhaka, is no longer just a concern but has now turned into a 'real threat', following the outbreak of the disease in 35 out of Bangladesh's total 64 districts.
The surge in spread of the deadly virus has been recorded with comparatively hi</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 04:00:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sylhet farmers unhappy with price as Aman harvest ends</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/sylhet-farmers-unhappy-with-price-as-aman-harvest-ends</link><description>Farmers in Sylhet said most of them are not happy with the price they have been getting for their transplanted Aman (T-Aman), or commonly called Aman, paddy as they recently completed harvesting with good yields.
Sylhet trader Abdul Bari on Sunday said the trade of Aman paddy has been ongoing in t</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 04:15:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh-Nepal commerce secretary-level meeting today</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladesh-nepal-commerce-secretary-level-meeting-today</link><description>Bangladesh and Nepal are set to step up efforts to deepen trade, transit, and connectivity cooperation, as senior officials meet today in Dhaka for the 8th Bangladesh-Nepal Commerce Secretary-Level Meeting (CSLM), sources said.
The meeting will review progress since the 7th CSLM in Kathmandu in Ap</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 04:30:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BGMEA urges promotion of referendum</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bgmea-urges-promotion-of-referendum</link><description>Bangladesh Garment Manufacturers and Exporters Association (BGMEA) has requested all its members to display two vertical banners at each factory's entrance and head office promoting the upcoming referendum and raising voter awareness.
On January 06, the apparel apex body in a circular made the req</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 04:45:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No extensive external debt for social sectors</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/no-extensive-external-debt-for-social-sectors</link><description>Planning Adviser Professor Wahiduddin Mahmud on Monday said the government would not take foreign loans extensively for the social sectors.
Rather, it would take loans for the sectors that would attract investments, he said.
Looking ahead, he said, Bangladesh must rethink its development financin</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 05:00:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Yarn import decision draws near after delay</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/yarn-import-decision-draws-near-after-delay</link><description>After more than five months of deliberations, the Bangladesh Tariff Commission (BTC) is yet to reach a final decision on the contentious yarn-import issue, though a report is now expected within days.
Sources said the commission is likely to recommend excluding 10-30 count yarn from duty-free im</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 05:15:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sonali Bank urges repayment of Tk 70b in loans from state-run sugar mills</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/sonali-bank-urges-repayment-of-tk-70b-in-loans-from-state-run-sugar-mills</link><description>With around Tk 70 billion in loans remaining unpaid by state-run sugar mills for years, Sonali Bank has urged the government either to repay the money immediately or issue bonds or provide state-guarantees to ease the bank's classified-loan burden and capital shortage.
In a recent letter to Financ</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 05:30:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Central bank buys dollars to steady taka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/central-bank-buys-dollars-to-steady-taka</link><description>The central bank purchased an additional US$81 million through an auction from 10 banks in the interbank spot market on Monday, aiming to keep the exchange rate of the US dollar against the taka stable.
The amount was bought under the Multiple Price Auction method, with a cut-off rate of Tk 122.30</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 05:45:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh receives $17.17b as remittance in 6 months</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/bangladesh-receives-1717b-as-remittance-in-6-months</link><description>Bangladesh received a record-high $17.17 billion in inward remittances during the first six months and seven days of fiscal year 2025–26, underscoring the resilience of overseas earnings and providing crucial support to the country’s foreign exchange reserves amid global trade headwinds</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 06:00:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ACC sues 17 for Tk 590m embezzlement</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/acc-sues-17-for-tk-590m-embezzlement</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) has filed two separate cases against 17 people - including the former chairman, managing director, and directors of FAS Finance and Investment Limited - over allegations of embezzling nearly Tk 590 million by showing loans in the names of various companies.&amp;nbsp</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 06:15:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Doctor found dead in Dhaka home after burglars tie him up</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/doctor-found-dead-in-dhaka-home-after-burglars-tie-him-up</link><description>A homeopathic doctor has died after burglars broke into his house and tied him up in the Rajabazar area in Dhaka.
The incident occurred on Monday night at a second-floor flat at 58/1 Rajabazar.
The victim was identified as Anwar Ullah, 66, reports bdnews24.com.
According to police, a group of bu</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 06:30:42 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>