<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 10:25:54 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>FE celebrates 32 years of publication</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fe-celebrates-32-years-of-publication-1</link><description>The Financial Express (FE), Bangladesh's first and leading English-language financial daily, celebrated the 32nd anniversary of its publication on Monday with a festive ceremony at its office in Dhaka’s Topkhana Road.
The FE Editor, Shamsul Huq Zahid, joined by a host of corporate clients, j</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 06:46:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Verdict on appeal to restore caretaker government system set for Nov 20</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/verdict-on-appeal-to-restore-caretaker-government-system-set-for-nov-20</link><description>If the caretaker government system is reinstated, it will still not be used for the 13th national parliamentary elections, according to legal experts. They believe that if the system is used for the upcoming polls, it will give rise to constitutional complications.
The lawyers made the comments af</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 07:01:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Armed Forces' magistracy power extended again</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/armed-forces-magistracy-power-extended-again</link><description>The government has once again extended the magistracy power of commissioned officers in the Army, Navy and Air Force until February 28, 2026, with effect from November 12 (Wednesday).
The Ministry of Public Administration issued a notification to this effect on Tuesday, reports UNB.
According to</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 07:16:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ECNEC okays 12 development projects worth Tk 71.5b</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/ecnec-okays-12-development-projects-worth-tk-715b</link><description>The government on Monday gave the nod to 12 development projects, including four revised schemes, involving a total of Tk 71.50 billion.
The Executive Committee of the National Economic Council (ECNEC) approved the eight fresh projects, two revised ones and extended execution time for two others a</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 07:31:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat, allies gather at Paltan to push for 5-point demand</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-allies-gather-at-paltan-to-push-for-5-point-demand</link><description>Supporters of Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami and seven allied political parties have gathered at Paltan in the capital to press their previously announced five-point demand.
The rally is scheduled to begin at 2:00 pm.
The decision to hold the rally was announced on November 3 at a press conference by</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 07:46:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>COP30 KICKS OFF: Call for mobilising finance for forest protection and climate resilience</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/cop30-kicks-off-call-for-mobilising-finance-for-forest-protection-and-climate-resilience</link><description>The 30th edition of the United Nations' Climate Change Conference, known as COP30, kicked off in Belém, Brazil, on November 10 (Monday), bringing together global leaders, activists, and experts in a crucial gathering to address accelerating climate change.
Under Brazil's presidency, COP30 w</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 08:01:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Adopt green inclusive finance as national framework: Experts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/adopt-green-inclusive-finance-as-national-framework-experts</link><description>Experts at a programme on Monday called for adopting green inclusive finance as a national framework to link financial inclusion with climate action for Bangladesh's vulnerable populations.
They also called for making the climate change actions more people-centric and basing them on field-level re</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 08:16:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Charge sheet against ex-IGP Benazir receives ACC nod</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/charge-sheet-against-ex-igp-benazir-receives-acc-nod</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) has approved the filing of a charge sheet against former Inspector General of Police (IGP) Benazir Ahmed after uncovering evidence of wealth amassed beyond his known sources of income and concealment of information in his wealth statement.
According to the inve</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 08:31:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Power Grid swings back to profit in Q1 of FY26</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/power-grid-swings-back-to-profit-in-q1-of-fy26</link><description>Power Grid secured a profit of Tk 3.64 billion in the first quarter through September this year, marking a strong rebound compared to a loss of Tk 2.56 billion in the same quarter last year, supported by higher revenue and favourable foreign exchange rates.
The state-owned sole power transmission</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 08:46:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Orion Infusion to expand production with own funds</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/orion-infusion-to-expand-production-with-own-funds</link><description>Listed life-saving injectable producer Orion Infusion has planned to invest another Tk 205 million from its own funds to increase the production capacity of IV fluids by 30 per cent.
According to a disclosure on Monday, the company's revenue will go up by Tk 255 million after the implementation of</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 09:01:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India's Modi vows not to spare those behind Delhi car blast</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/indias-modi-vows-not-to-spare-those-behind-delhi-car-blast</link><description>Indian police are investigating a deadly car blast in the capital under a law used to fight "terrorism", an officer said on Tuesday, as Prime Minister Narendra Modi vowed to bring to justice all those responsible.
The explosion near the historic Red Fort on Monday evening killed at least eight peo</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 09:16:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Denmark partners with BD to reinforce human rights, media freedom</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/denmark-partners-with-bd-to-reinforce-human-rights-media-freedom</link><description>Denmark has launched new partnership to strengthen human rights, trauma-informed mental health, and media freedom in Bangladesh.
In this connection, it has announced its support of DKK 25 million for a consortium of Danish organisations namely DIGNITY, IMS (International Media Support), and the Da</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 09:31:11 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>