<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 21:23:04 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Police disclose special security measures for Christmas, New Year’s Eve</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/police-disclose-special-security-measures-for-christmas-new-years-eve</link><description>Police have taken special security measures ahead of the twin celebrations for Christmas and New Year’s Eve.
A meeting on security and law and order was held at the Hall of Pride of Police Headquarters on Wednesday, chaired by Inspector General of Police (IGP) Bangladesh Baharul Alam, ahead</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 16:13:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tk 661bn laundered funds ‘blocked’ at home, abroad</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh-freezes-tk-661bn-assets-to-recover-laundered-money-domestically-and-globally</link><description>The interim government has reported that immovable and movable assets worth Tk 661.46 million belonging to different industrial groups, both in Bangladesh and abroad, have been “attached or blocked” as part of efforts to recover laundered funds.
A media statement issued by the Finance</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 16:14:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Civil society, experts express deep concern over deterioration in public safety</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/civil-society-experts-express-deep-concern-over-deterioration-in-public-safety</link><description>Civil society, political leaders, and researchers expressed deep concern Wednesday over the deterioration of public safety and the weakness of the judicial system in Bangladesh.
At a dialogue titled “Security and Rights: What We Want, What We Get?” organized by Democracy International,</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 16:29:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DMP arrests 392 in 24 hours during operation Devil Hunt Phase-2</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dmp-arrests-392-in-24-hours-during-operation-devil-hunt-phase-2</link><description>Dhaka Metropolitan Police arrested 392 people in 24 hours under Operation Devil Hunt Phase-2 from 1 am to 11.59 pm on Tuesday (December 16) at various locations in the capital.
Among those arrested were 15 active leaders and activists of the Awami League and its affiliated organisations, along wit</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 16:44:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Islamic University students demand justice for murdered fellow student</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/islamic-university-students-demand-justice-for-murdered-fellow-student</link><description>Students at Islamic University staged a symbolic protest on the campus in Kushtia on Wednesday, calling for justice in the murder of Sajid Abdullah, a student of the Al-Quran and Islamic Studies department.
Protesters carried a red shroud representing his body to dramatise their demand for account</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 16:59:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nearly two-thirds of Bangladeshi child labourers work in factories: Report</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nearly-two-thirds-of-bangladeshi-child-labourers-work-in-factories-report</link><description>Nearly two-thirds of child labourers in Bangladesh are employed in industrial and factory settings, exposing them to serious health and safety risks, a report said on Wednesday.
The findings were presented at an event in Dhaka jointly organised by the International Organisation Educo Bangladesh an</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 17:14:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hadi’s condition very critical, says Singapore’s Foreign Minister</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hadis-condition-very-critical-says-singapores-foreign-minister</link><description>Singapore’s Foreign Minister Dr Vivian Balakrishnan has said that the condition of Sharif Osman Hadi, spokesperson of Inquilab Moncho, is very critical.
At around 9:40 pm on Wednesday, Dr Balakrishnan called Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus and briefed him on Hadi’s medical condi</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 17:15:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Public money at risk</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/public-money-at-risk</link><description>Non-performing loans, commonly known as NPLs, are often discussed as if they represent a moral failure of the banking system. In reality, they are a standard business outcome of lending, embedded in the structure of modern finance. Banking is not the business of certainty; it is the business of cal</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 17:30:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tax reform to reduce widening inequality</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/tax-reform-to-reduce-widening-inequality</link><description>A recent report titledm 'World inequality report 2026', published by the Paris-based World Inequality Lab, has once again laid bare the ever-widening chasm between the rich and the poor. According to the report, the richest 10 per cent of people in Bangladesh hold 58 per cent of the country's total</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 17:45:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Healthcare system under severe stress</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/healthcare-system-under-severe-stress</link><description>The United Nations World Urbanisation Prospects 2025 report reveals that Dhaka City is the second largest megacity after Jakarta. Instead of celebrating this elevated status, both experts in urban development and ordinary citizens consider this sobriquet highly concerning. Not only has the capital</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 18:00:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Russia will take more land in Ukraine: Putin</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/putin-says-russia-will-take-more-land-in-ukraine-if-europe-sinks-peace-moves</link><description>President Vladimir Putin said on Wednesday Russia would take more land in Ukraine by force if Kyiv and European politicians whom he cast as "young pigs" did not engage over US proposals for a peace settlement.
The United States has held talks with Russia, and separately with Kyiv and European lead</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 18:15:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Garment exports to EU might lose duty-free access after graduation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/garment-exports-to-eu-might-lose-duty-free-access-after-graduation</link><description>Bangladeshi-made readymade garments might not get duty-free market access to the European Union (EU) under GSP-plus facility after its graduation and related transition period up to 2029, sources say.



After the year 2029, Bangladesh will lose its duty-free market access to the EU under the c</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 20:18:21 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>