<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 19:28:18 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Army to return to barracks after new govt’s oath: Waker-Uz-Zaman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/army-to-return-to-barracks-after-new-govts-oath-waker-uz-zaman</link><description>Chief of Army Staff General Waker-Uz-Zaman on Sunday said the Army will return to barracks once the newly elected government assumes office.
He, however, said a portion of the Army will remain deployed in the field to assist in maintaining law and order until the police regain full control of the</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 15:34:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC: Take complaints to High Court</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-take-complaints-about-gazette-of-poll-results-to-high-court</link><description>Election Commissioner Anwarul Islam Sarker has dismissed allegations of “undue haste” over the publication of the official gazette following the recent general election.
He said the gazette listing the names of elected candidates was issued in due course after the announcement of unoff</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 15:49:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No handshake as Pakistan elect to field against India</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/no-handshake-as-pakistan-elect-to-field-against-india</link><description>Pakistan’s Salman Agha chose to field after winning the toss against India but there was no handshake between the captains before the Twenty20 World Cup Group A blockbuster on Sunday.
The match between the bitter rivals went ahead after Pakistan earlier reversed their decision to boycott the</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 16:04:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New Delhi Press Minister Faisal Mahmud’s appointment terminated</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/new-delhi-press-minister-faisal-mahmuds-appointment-terminated</link><description>The interim government has terminated the appointment of Faisal Mahmud as press minister at Bangladesh’s High Commission in New Delhi, seven and a half months before the end of his tenure.
A notification from the Ministry of Public Administration on Sunday said: “The remaining tenure o</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 16:21:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trade pact or template for control over Bangladesh?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/trade-pact-or-template-for-control-over-bangladesh</link><description>The cloak of secrecy has finally been lifted. The non-disclosure agreement that kept the Bangladesh-US "reciprocal tariff" deal hidden from public scrutiny has been pulled back, and Bangladeshis can now see what was negotiated in their name. On first reading, this does not look like an agreement be</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 16:36:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Stocks see big jump at opening</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/stocks-see-big-jump-at-opening</link><description>Stocks saw a big jump at opening on Sunday, the first day after the 13th parliamentary election, as investors' confidence boosted and bargain hunters favoured taking positions in potentially lucrative shares amid renewed optimism.
The market opened high, aided by the price appreciation of particul</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 16:51:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A gender-biased election system!</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/a-gender-biased-election-system</link><description>When out of 85 women contestants only seven are elected in the just concluded parliamentary polls, the message it gives is not at all savoury. Of the seven, six are from the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) and the rest one contested as an independent candidate. Yet there is a twist to the tale b</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 17:06:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat Ameer calls meeting with Tarique an important moment'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-ameer-calls-meeting-with-tarique-an-important-moment</link><description>Jamaat Ameer Dr Shafiqur Rahman has reiterated his party’s commitment to democratic governance and constitutional accountability following a meeting with BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman.
In a Facebook post on Sunday night, Dr Rahman congratulated Tarique Rahman in advance as he set to assume the</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 17:31:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AL office torched in Khulna after leaders pay floral tributes</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/al-office-torched-in-khulna-after-leaders-pay-floral-tributes</link><description>Leaders and activists of the Awami League entered the party’s district and metropolitan office in Khulna on Sunday afternoon, placed wreaths on portraits of Sheikh Mujibur Rahman and Sheikh Hasina, hoisted the national flag and chanted slogans.
The office, located in the Shankha Market area</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 17:46:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Can next govt fulfil July dreams?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/can-next-govt-fulfil-july-dreams</link><description>Undeniably, the July uprising has radically changed the public's view on what future governments should be like. The Dr Yunus-led interim administration's role has been more than just arranging the 13th parliamentary election. In fact, its job has been to do the groundwork for the next elected gove</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 18:01:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Stop market manipulation, ensure fair competition</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/stop-market-manipulation-ensure-fair-competition</link><description>Bangladesh has been in the grip of persistently high inflation for years with consequent severe hardship for low- and middle-income families. Although the interim government managed to bring the inflation rate down to an average 8.9 per cent in 2025 from the double-digit levels in 2024, the prices</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 18:16:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Taskforce for skewed trade tax restructuring</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/taskforce-for-skewed-trade-tax-restructuring</link><description>An expert body has recommended radical restructuring of anomalous trade taxes for building a dynamic and trade-oriented economy capable of generating jobs and inclusive growth.
As of the last financial year, finished consumer goods enjoyed about 2.4 times higher tariff protection than intermediate</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 19:19:20 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>