<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 11:15:49 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>'Zakir Naik’s visit to Dhaka depends on home, foreign ministries'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/zakir-naiks-visit-to-dhaka-depends-on-home-foreign-ministries-1</link><description>Adviser for Religious Affairs A.F.M. Khalid Hossain said that the possible visit of Indian Islamic preacher Dr Zakir Naik to Bangladesh will depend entirely on the decisions of the Home and Foreign Ministries.
Speaking to the reporters after a meeting at the Ministry of Religious Affairs at the Se</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 08:36:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Attempt on to create anarchy through false propaganda: Fakhrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/attempt-on-to-create-anarchy-through-false-propaganda-fakhrul</link><description>BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir today (Sunday) alleged that an attempt is underway to create anarchy in the country by spreading false propaganda on social media.
He said, "The enemies of Bangladesh are rearing their heads again and starting to rise up. As time passes, a maliciou</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 09:26:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>12-kg LPG price cut by Tk 26 per cylinder</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/12-kg-lpg-price-cut-by-tk-26-per-cylinder</link><description>Bangladesh Energy Regulatory Commission (BERC) has cut the retail price of 12 kg LPG by Tk 26 per cylinder to Tk 1,215 for November.
The commission slashed the LPG selling price for private operators in line with the existing downtrend of oil and gas prices in the international market.</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 08:51:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shafiqur re-elected as Jamaat-e-Islami chief for 2026–2028 term</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/shafiqur-re-elected-as-jamaat-e-islami-chief-for-2026-2028-term</link><description>Shafiqur Rahman has been re-elected as the Ameer, the designated chief, of the Jamaat-e-Islami, marking his return as the party’s top leader a year after the July Uprising.
According to a party statement, he will serve a three-year term as chief.
Assistant Secretary General ATM Masum announ</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 09:36:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Abdur Rahim Khan appointed FBCCI administrator</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/abdur-rahim-khan-appointed-fbcci-administrator</link><description>Additional Secretary of the Ministry of Commerce Md Abdur Rahim Khan has been appointed as the administrator of the Federation of Bangladesh Chambers of Commerce and Industry (FBCCI), the country's apex trade body.
He formally took charge as the FBCCI administrator on Sunday morning.
According to</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 10:06:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Police block Ebtedayee teachers’ Jamuna march over push for nationalisation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/police-block-ebtedayee-teachers-jamuna-march-over-push-for-nationalisation</link><description>Police have blocked the “Long March to Jamuna” by Ebtedayee teachers near the Kadam Fountain in Dhaka as they pressed for a five-point demand, including nationalisation of their institutions.
The teachers began marching towards the Chief Advisor’s official residence, the State Gu</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 10:36:50 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>