<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 15:19:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Israel urges Lebanon to disarm Hezbollah under ceasefire terms</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/israel-urges-lebanon-to-disarm-hezbollah-under-ceasefire-terms</link><description>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu warned on Sunday that Hezbollah was seeking to rearm and that Israel would exercise its right to self-defence under last year's ceasefire accord if Lebanon failed to disarm the militant group.
At the start of a cabinet meeting Netanyahu said Israel would "</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 11:47:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Algerian Revolution Day observed in Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/algerian-revolution-day-observed-in-dhaka</link><description>The Embassy of Algeria in Dhaka on Saturday commemorated the '71st Anniversary of the Start of the Glorious Liberation Revolution of November 1, 1954’, marking a defining chapter in Algeria’s struggle for independence and human dignity.
The grand event, held at Le Méridien Dhaka</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 12:02:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pope Leo decries Sudan violence, urges dialogue and relief effort</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/africa/pope-leo-decries-sudan-violence-urges-dialogue-and-relief-effort</link><description>Pope Leo on Sunday appealed for an immediate ceasefire and the opening of humanitarian corridors in Sudan, saying he was following with “great sorrow” reports of terrible brutality in the city of Al-Fashir in Darfur.
“Indiscriminate violence against women and children, attacks on</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 12:32:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh voter count hits 127.6 million</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-voter-count-hits-1276-million</link><description>The number of registered voters in Bangladesh has reached approximately 127.6 million, according to the draft updated electoral rolls released by the Election Commission (EC) on Sunday.
The total number of the country’s voters is 12,76,12,384.
Of them, 6,47,60,382 are male, 6,28,50,772 are</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 12:47:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Louvre heist work of petty criminals, not organised crime, prosecutor says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/louvre-heist-work-of-petty-criminals-not-organised-crime-prosecutor-says</link><description>The audacious daytime robbery of historical jewels worth $102 million from the Paris Louvre museum last month was executed by petty criminals, rather than professionals from the world of organised crime, the Paris prosecutor said on Sunday.
On a Sunday morning two weeks ago, two men parked a mover</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 13:17:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Union Bank holds its 185th meeting of Board of Directors</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/union-bank-holds-its-185th-meeting-of-board-of-directors</link><description>The 185th Board Meeting of the Board of the Directors of Union Bank PLC was held at the bank’s Head Office, Gulshan-1, Dhaka on 2 November, 2025.
Chairman of the Board of the Directors of the bank Mr. Md. Fariduddin Ahmed presided over the meeting, according to a media release. 
Chairm</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 13:32:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BSRF executive committee meets Mahfuj Alam</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bsrf-executive-committee-meets-mahfuj-alam</link><description>Members of the executive committee of Bangladesh Secretariat Reporters’ Forum (BSRF) met with Information and Broadcasting Adviser Md Mahfuj Alam this afternoon at his ministry in Bangladesh Secretariat.
During the meeting, BSRF President Masudul Hque informed the adviser that the Ministry o</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 13:47:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Remittance inflow increases by 7pc in October</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/remittance-inflow-increases-by-7pc-in-october</link><description>Expatriate Bangladeshis sent US$2.56 billion in remittances in October, which was around 7 per cent higher than the corresponding month of the previous year.
The wage earners sent $2.39 billion in remittances to the country in October of 2024.
According to BSS, industry insiders observed that Ban</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 14:17:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>COAST Foundation calls for empowering young entrepreneurs for inclusive growth</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/coast-foundation-calls-for-empowering-young-entrepreneurs-for-inclusive-growth</link><description>Speakers at a series of youth entrepreneurship gatherings organised by COAST Foundation on Sunday called for empowering young entrepreneurs with better access to finance, skills, and market linkages to drive inclusive and sustainable economic growth.
The assemblies, held between October 19 and Nov</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 14:32:52 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>