<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 11:22:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>DMP intensifies security check posts across Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dmp-intensifies-security-check-posts-across-dhaka</link><description>The Dhaka Metropolitan Police (DMP) has intensified its check post system at various key points across the capital to maintain law and order. 
The enhanced security measures came into effect from 4:00 pm today (Wednesday), BSS reports. 
"We have enhanced the security arrangement with se</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 10:03:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Journey to Lhasa via the world's highest railway</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/others/journey-to-lhasa-via-the-worlds-highest-railway</link><description>Some journeys are planned through logistics and infrastructure, others through faith and persistence. Both shaped our journey to Mount Kailash and Lake Mansarovar in June 2025. Travelling on the Qinghai–Tibet Railway, the highest railway journey on earth, was a lifetime experience one can wis</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 08:35:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh’s decade-long push on energy efficiency shows results: IEEFA report</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladeshs-decade-long-push-on-energy-efficiency-shows-results-ieefa-report</link><description>Bangladesh’s nearly decade-long effort to improve energy efficiency is paying off. With targeted measures, the nation can build on this momentum and achieve its energy efficiency goals ahead of time, according to a new report by the Institute for Energy Economics and Financial Analysis (IEE</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 08:50:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hadi attack: Fake number plate, motorcycle recovered</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/police-recover-fake-number-plate-motorcycle-used-in-attack-on-osman-hadi</link><description>Police have recovered the motorcycle used in the attack on Inqilab Moncho Convenor Sharif Osman Hadi.
In a statement issued on Wednesday, Dhaka Metropolitan Police said the motorcycle involved in the shooting had been recovered, along with a fake number plate that had been used at the time of the</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 09:05:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Lalbagh factory fire under control</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/lalbagh-factory-fire-under-control</link><description>A fire that broke out at a plastic product-manufacturing factory in Islambagh area in Dhaka has been brought under control.
Anwarul Islam, warehouse inspector at the Fire Service and Civil Defence (FSCD) headquarters media cell, said the fire originated from a factory in Chairmangaht area of Islam</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 09:20:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Top criminal’ Chhoto Sajjad secures bail in 3 more cases</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/top-criminal-chhoto-sajjad-secures-bail-in-3-more-cases</link><description>Sajjad Hossain, alias Chhoto Sajjad, a notorious criminal in Chattogram, has secured bail from the top court in three more cases.
With these, he has now secured bail in a total of seven cases.
The matter came to light last week when the first batch of bail documents for four cases arrived at the</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 09:35:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tribunal orders appointment of state defence to try fugitive Joy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tribunal-orders-appointment-of-state-defence-to-try-fugitive-joy</link><description>The International Crimes Tribunal (ICT)-1 on Wednesday ordered the appointment of a state defence counsel to represent ousted Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina’s son and former ICT affairs adviser Sajeeb Wazed Joy, who remains at large, in a crimes against humanity case.
The two-member tribunal,</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 09:50:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Alleged Bondi gunman charged with 15 murders as funerals of victims begin</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/alleged-bondi-gunman-charged-with-15-murders-as-funerals-of-victims-begin</link><description>A man who allegedly opened fire on a Jewish Hanukkah celebration on Sydney’s famed Bondi Beach has been charged with 59 offences, including murder and terrorism, police said on Wednesday.
The alleged father-and-son perpetrators opened fire on the celebration at Sydney’s famed Bondi Bea</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 10:05:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>China says Philippines distorted facts about incident near disputed atoll</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/china-says-philippines-distorted-facts-about-incident-near-disputed-atoll</link><description>China's defence ministry accused the Philippines on Wednesday of distorting the facts about an incident involving the Chinese coastguard and Filipino fishermen near a South China Sea shoal.
Manila's coastguard said over the weekend that three Filipino fishermen were injured and two fishing vessels</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 10:20:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>TikTok monitored Grindr activity through third-party tracker, privacy group alleges</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/tiktok-monitored-grindr-activity-through-third-party-tracker-privacy-group-alleges</link><description>A privacy advocacy group, noyb, filed complaints to Austria’s data protection authority on Wednesday against TikTok, Grindr (GRND.N), opens new tab and AppsFlyer, alleging these companies breached regional privacy laws, risking exposure of sensitive data.
Vienna-based organization None of Yo</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 10:35:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt to prepare area-based wildlife inventory</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-to-prepare-area-based-wildlife-inventory</link><description>The government has decided to prepare a countrywide area-based wildlife inventory so that locals can be made aware of these wild animals. 
The decision was taken at the 41st meeting of the Wildlife Advisory Board held recently, with Environment, Forest and Climate Change Adviser Syeda Rizwana</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 10:50:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bringing back laundered funds may take 4–5 years: BB governor</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bringing-back-laundered-funds-may-take-4-5-years-bb-governor</link><description>Bangladesh Bank Governor Dr. Ahsan H. Mansur said on Wednesday that recovering laundered money from abroad is a lengthy process and it may four to five years.
Dr. Mansur made the remarks while talking to reporters after a meeting with Finance Adviser Dr. Salehuddin Ahmed at the Secretariat.
When</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 11:05:39 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>