<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 17:25:08 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Colombia president warns of ‘real threat’ of US military action</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/colombia-president-warns-of-real-threat-of-us-military-action</link><description>Colombia’s President Gustavo Petro has warned that the country is facing what he has described as a “real threat” of US military action, following recent remarks by US President Donald Trump.
In an interview with the BBC, the Colombian leader said Washington was increasingly trea</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 13:27:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two-day photo exhibition on Begum Khaleda Zia’s eventful life begins at Zia Udyan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/two-day-photo-exhibition-on-begum-khaleda-zias-eventful-life-begins-at-zia-udyan</link><description>A two-day photo exhibition attributing the eventful and struggling life of BNP Chairperson and former Prime Minister Begum Khaleda Zia began at Zia Udyan on Friday, organised by the Bogura Media and Cultural Society–Dhaka.
BNP Standing Committee Member Nazrul Islam Khan inaugurated the exhib</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 13:42:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ex-cop among 6 arrested over Ctg gold robbery</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/ex-cop-among-6-arrested-over-ctg-gold-robbery</link><description>Police have arrested six individuals, including a former police officer, over the robbery of gold bars worth 4,081g in Chattogram city.
They also reported recovering gold bars worth 3381.4g. The robbery took place on Sunday at Aturar Depot in the city.
Panchlaish Police announced the arrest and r</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 13:57:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US job growth slows in December</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/global/us-job-growth-slows-in-december-unemployment-rate-eases-to-44-per-cent</link><description>US job growth slowed more than expected in December amid business caution about hiring because of import tariffs and rising artificial intelligence investment, but the unemployment rate dipped to 4.4 per cent, supporting expectations the Federal Reserve would leave interest rates unchanged this mon</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 14:12:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Australian high commissioner calls on Tarique Rahman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/australian-high-commissioner-calls-on-tarique-rahman</link><description>Australian High Commissioner to Bangladesh Ms Susan Ryle on Friday paid a courtesy call on BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman.
The meeting took place at the BNP Chairperson's office at Gulshan around 7:00 pm, said BNP media cell member Shayrul Kabir Khan.</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 14:27:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Defence firms seek legal advice over Trump’s clampdown on payouts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/defence-firms-seek-legal-advice-over-trumps-clampdown-on-payouts</link><description>Defence contractors are seeking legal advice after US President Donald Trump signed an executive order to tie share buybacks, dividends and executive pay to weapons delivery schedules, three sources said.
Trump’s executive order “Prioritising the Warfighter in Defence Contracting,&amp;rdqu</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 14:42:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>640 appeals filed with EC against nomination rejections</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/640-appeals-filed-with-ec-against-nomination-rejections</link><description>A total of 640 appeals have been filed with the Election Commission (EC) against returning officers’ decisions on nomination papers for the parliamentary polls.
The five-day submission period ended Friday. Hearings will begin Saturday at the commission’s Agargaon office.
Chief Electio</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 14:57:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Japan PM Takaichi considering snap election in February, Yomiuri newspaper says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/japan-pm-takaichi-considering-snap-election-in-february-yomiuri-newspaper-says</link><description>Japanese Prime Minister Sanae Takaichi is considering calling a snap election for parliament’s lower house in the first half of February, the Yomiuri newspaper reported on Friday, citing political sources.
The move would allow Takaichi, Japan’s first female prime minister, to take adva</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 15:12:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC issues directives to ensure secrecy of ballot papers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-issues-directives-to-ensure-secrecy-of-ballot-papers</link><description>In a significant move to uphold electoral integrity, the Election Commission (EC) has issued a comprehensive circular outlining mandatory protocol for handling, verification, and security of election materials for the upcoming 13th National Parliament Election and referendum.
The directive, signed</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 15:45:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Five held with illegal arms in Sylhet raid</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/five-held-with-illegal-arms-in-sylhet-raid</link><description>Members of the joint forces detained five people and recovered a large cache of illegal arms, bullets and crime tools during a raid in Osmaninagar upazila of Sylhet early Friday.
The operation was carried out at dawn on the basis of secret intelligence.
Two army patrol teams led by Lieutenant Md</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 16:00:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Musk’s AI bot Grok limits image generation on X to paid users after backlash</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/musks-ai-bot-grok-limits-image-generation-on-x-to-paid-users-after-backlash</link><description>Elon Musk’s startup xAI has restricted the image generation function on its Grok chatbot on social media platform X to paid subscribers, after the tool’s use of AI to create sexualised images sparked a widespread backlash.
The chatbot’s image generation had allowed users on X to</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 16:15:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Envoy tapped for Trump’s Gaza board meets senior Palestinian official in West Bank</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/envoy-tapped-for-trumps-gaza-board-meets-senior-palestinian-official-in-west-bank</link><description>The former UN envoy expected to help lead Donald Trump’s so-called Board of Peace for Gaza met a top Palestinian Authority official on Friday as the US president pushes ahead with his plan for the enclave’s future.
Trump is expected to announce the composition of the board this month,</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 16:30:49 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>