<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 04:09:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Agro-processing calls for strategic push</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/agro-processing-calls-for-strategic-push</link><description>Despite the popular perception that Bangladesh as an agro-based country has immense potential for exporting agro-processed foods, the reality is hardly encouraging. The country has yet to make any significant headway in harnessing its advantages in this promising field. While agriculture continues</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 18:27:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Treating road safety as an emergency</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/treating-road-safety-as-an-emergency</link><description>Bangladesh ranks among the worst nations in the world in terms of road safety. A World Economic Forum (WEF) opinion survey ranked Bangladesh's roads among the worst in Asia and 113th globally considering their poor infrastructures. In South Asia, Sri Lanka, India and Pakistan ranked significantly b</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 18:42:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Process ongoing for LNG deal with truant firm Socar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/process-ongoing-for-lng-deal-with-truant-firm-socar</link><description>Preparation is on stream to award a liquefied natural gas (LNG)-supply contract to a truant foreign firm that had previously left Bangladesh without completing a contracted drilling job, sources say, stoking fresh concerns.
Energy-industry insiders say the move towards deal-making with Socar, an A</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 18:57:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP in favor of 'Yes' vote in referendum: Nazrul Islam Khan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-in-favor-of-yes-vote-in-referendum-nazrul-islam-khan</link><description>BNP standing committee member and election conducting committee chairman Nazrul Islam Khan today said that the party will vote "Yes" in the upcoming referendum, as it supports the reform initiatives.
"We have decided that we will vote 'Yes' in the referendum. We are in favour of reforms," he told</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 19:12:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Post-IPO underperformance triggers asset inquiry into Silva Pharma</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/post-ipo-underperformance-triggers-asset-inquiry-into-silva-pharma</link><description>The securities regulator has instructed Silva Pharmaceuticals to conduct a revaluation of its machinery and equipment purchased with IPO funds and to disclose the operational status of the factory building constructed using the same proceeds.
The move aims to determine the company's accurate finan</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 01:45:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How investor exit, thin liquidity are rewriting the DSEX</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/how-investor-exit-thin-liquidity-are-rewriting-the-dsex</link><description>The latest rebalancing of the benchmark index of the Dhaka bourse has pushed out several fundamentally strong stocks in favour of junk stocks, a consequence of investors' prolonged exit from the secondary market over the past two years.
"This is a true reflection of our market and it was supposed</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 02:00:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BSC pays Tk 2.03b to govt in loan repayment, dividends</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/bsc-pays-tk-203b-to-govt-in-loan-repayment-dividendsk</link><description>Bangladesh Shipping Corporation (BSC) has handed over a cheque for Tk 2.03 billion to the government, covering loan installments and dividend payments related to six ship acquisition projects implemented under the Ministry of Shipping.Trade Fair Guide
The cheque was formally presented to the Chief</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 02:15:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Economy experiences liftoff on growth leaps in pivotal sectors</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/economy-experiences-liftoff-on-growth-leaps-in-pivotal-sectors</link><description>Bangladesh's turmoil-tossed economy shows significant signs of recovery with the July-September fiscal quarter showing a liftoff from a miasma over the last couple of years, analysts say, based on latest statistics.
The economy got a boost with the gross domestic product (GDP) having grown at a ra</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 02:30:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Final decision on joining Gaza force ‘rests on next govt’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/final-decision-on-joining-gaza-force-rests-on-next-govt</link><description>Bangladesh's participation in the proposed International Stabilisation Force (ISF) for Gaza is likely to be decided by the next elected government, as officials emphasise that current discussions are preliminary and contingent on a clear United Nations mandate and political consensus at home.
Seni</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 02:45:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>FY26 Jul-Nov current account deficit widens</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/fy26-jul-nov-current-account-deficit-widens</link><description>Bangladesh's current-account deficit widened in the first five months of the fiscal year ending November last as sluggish export growth combined with a pick-up in imports, though the overall balance of payments remained comfortably in surplus.
The current-account deficit, or the key part of the ov</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 03:00:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Action looms against auditors of five merged banks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/action-looms-against-auditors-of-five-merged-banks</link><description>The government will take action against the auditors of five recently merged banks over allegations of manipulating financial statements that encouraged small investors to buy their shares from the stock market, Finance Adviser Dr Salehuddin Ahmed said on Tuesday.
He indicated that the authorities</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 03:54:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>'Enforced disappearances extended beyond borders'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/enforced-disappearances-extended-beyond-borders</link><description>The full report of the Commission formed to investigate enforced disappearances during the Awami League regime reveals that such incidents extended beyond the country's borders.
The report, published on Tuesday, said that victims were, in some cases, "abducted in one country and delivered to the a</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 04:09:45 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>