<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 12:51:18 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Budget-friendly places to do Yoga in Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/others/budget-friendly-places-to-do-yoga-in-dhaka</link><description>Have you ever thought of having a stress-free, relaxed life after a busy day? We have our everyday struggles. Hustling here and there for our livelihoods or juggling academic pressure and personal expectations, leaving no room for mental peace. So, repetitive conditions like these make us think of</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 10:30:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>President expresses satisfaction over EC’s preparations for polls, referendum</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/president-expresses-satisfaction-over-ecs-preparations-for-polls-referendum</link><description>President Mohammed Shahabuddin expressed satisfaction over the preparations undertaken by the Election Commission (EC) ahead of the upcoming 13th parliamentary election and the national referendum, EC Senior Secretary Akhtar Ahmed said on Wednesday.
“The President expressed satisfaction afte</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 10:45:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UK finance minister Reeves says budget leaks were frustrating and unacceptable</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/uk-finance-minister-reeves-says-budget-leaks-were-frustrating-and-unacceptable</link><description>British finance minister Rachel Reeves said on Wednesday that she was frustrated with leaks about her budget before her November 26 tax and spending statement, including media reports about possible income tax rises.
Reeves had appeared to pave the way for an income tax rate hike - which would hav</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 11:00:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC to announce election schedule Thursday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-to-announce-election-schedule-thursday</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) is set to unveil the formal schedule for the upcoming 13th National Parliamentary Election and a concurrent national referendum on Thursday evening.
Chief Election Commissioner (CEC) AMM Nasir Uddin will outline the roadmap for the polls in a televised address to the n</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 10:18:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamuna Bank Loan &amp; DPS installments now payable through Nagad</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/jamuna-bank-loan-dps-installments-now-payable-through-nagad</link><description>Customers of Nagad can now easily transfer funds to Jamuna Bank PLC, one of the country’s leading commercial banks.
The new service was launched at an event held at Jamuna Bank’s Corporate Office, according to a press release.
Managing Director and CEO of Jamuna Bank PLC Mirza Elias U</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 10:33:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Indictment hearing in case against Salman, Anisul on Dec 17</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/indictment-hearing-in-case-against-salman-anisul-on-dec-17</link><description>The International Crimes Tribunal (ICT)-1 today set December 17 for holding a hearing on charge framing in a case against Salman F Rahman and Anisul Huq for allegedly inciting mass killings and other crimes against humanity by imposing curfew during the July Mass Uprising.
The two-member tribunal,</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 10:48:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCP to contest election to promote ‘Yes’ in referendum: Nahid</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ncp-to-contest-election-to-promote-yes-in-referendum-nahid</link><description>National Citizen Party (NCP) Convener Nahid Islam on Wednesday said the party is participating in the election to ensure a ‘Yes’ victory in the referendum, not to come to power, following the announcement of its candidates for 125 constituencies.
“Let us not forget, this election</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 11:03:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ACC files cases against Malaysia-bound 60 overseas companies for embezzling Tk 45b</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/acc-files-cases-against-malaysia-bound-60-overseas-companies-for-embezzling-tk-45b</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) on Wednesday filed cases against owners, chairmen, managing directors, directors, and other accused persons of 60 overseas companies, allegedly for embezzling Tk 45 billion by overcharging the Malaysian expatriates than the official rate.
The companies formed a</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 11:18:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nearly 5m people in BD internally displaced by disasters</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nearly-5m-people-in-bd-internally-displaced-by-disasters</link><description>Bangladesh is home to almost five million people living in internal displacement due to natural hazards, according to the first nationwide estimate released by the International Organisation for Migration (IOM) in Dhaka on Wednesday.
The assessment marks the most comprehensive attempt to quantify</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 11:33:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AmCham hosts focus group discussion on Bangladesh’s energy security</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/amcham-hosts-focus-group-discussion-on-bangladeshs-energy-security</link><description>The American Chamber of Commerce in Bangladesh (AmCham) hosted a focus group discussion titled "Powering Bangladesh Toward Energy Security" on Tuesday at the Sheraton Dhaka Hotel, according to a press release.
The event was supported by Chevron Bangladesh, an industry leader whose 30-year partners</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 11:48:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCP unveils first list of 125 candidates for national election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ncp-unveils-first-list-of-125-candidates-for-national-election</link><description>National Citizen Party (NCP) on Wednesday announced the names of its first batch of 125 preliminary nominees for the upcoming national parliamentary elections.
The list was disclosed by Member Secretary Akhter Hossen at a press conference held at the party’s makeshift office in the city&amp;rsqu</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 12:03:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Asif Mahmud, Mahfuj Alam resign</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/asif-mahmud-mahfuj-alam-resign</link><description>Asif Mahmud Shojib Bhuyain and Mahfuj Alam, two student representatives serving as advisers to the interim government, have resigned from their positions as advisers.
Local news portals, citing sources at the Chief Adviser’s Office, confirmed the development on Wednesday evening.</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 12:18:51 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>