<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 14:24:11 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>MTB Annual Trade Based Financial Compliance Conference-2025</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/mtb-annual-trade-based-financial-compliance-conference-2025</link><description>Mutual Trust Bank PLC (MTB) arranged the Annual Trade Based Compliance Conference 2025 on December 6, 2025 to create awareness on key deliverables for prevention of Trade Based Money Laundering.
The conference was held for MTB Officials relevant to Trade Servicing from Branches and Corporate Head</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 11:12:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>PBI finds evidence of ‘fraud’ against Toyota executives</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/pbi-finds-evidence-of-fraud-against-toyota-executives</link><description>The Police Bureau of Investigation (PBI) has found evidence of alleged fraudulent activities involving three senior Toyota Bangladesh executives, including Managing Director Premmit Singh.
Earlier this month, the probe report was submitted to the Chief Metropolitan Magistrate Court in Dhaka by PBI</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 11:27:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mercantile Bank holds cash management training in Ctg</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/mercantile-bank-holds-cash-management-training-in-ctg</link><description>Mercantile Bank PLC organised a day-long “Cash Management” training workshop in Chattogram on Saturday (20/12/2025) to strengthen operational efficiency and enhance professional competence among its cash officers.
Head of Training &amp; Development of Mercantile Bank S. M. Salim Uddin atte</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 11:42:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Inauguration of Chatkhil branch of Citizens Bank</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/inauguration-of-chatkhil-branch-of-citizens-bank</link><description>Mr. Alamgir Hossain, Managing Director, Citizens Bank PLC, formally inaugurated Chatkhil Branch at Noakhalion on December 22, 2025, in the presence of Deputy Managing Directors Mr. Md. Mostafizur Rahman and Mr. Md. Abdul Latif and other high officials of the bank.
Among others, local renowned busi</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 11:57:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>11 more arrested over Prothom Alo, Daily Star attacks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/11-more-arrested-over-prothom-alo-daily-star-attacks</link><description>Police have arrested 11 more people over attacks, vandalism, and arson at the offices of Prothom Alo and The Daily Star in Dhaka.
The Detective Branch arrested nine suspects across the capital on Monday, while Tejgaon Police held two others, according to a media statement issued by the Dhaka Metro</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 12:12:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCP backs restoring political rights of ordinary AL supporters: Nahid</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ncp-backs-restoring-political-rights-of-ordinary-al-supporters-nahid</link><description>National Citizen Party (NCP) Convener Nahid Islam on Tuesday said his party supports restoring the civic and political rights of ordinary supporters of Awami League.
“Those who support a fascist party may have committed a moral crime, but if they were not involved in mass killings during the</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 12:27:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Miscreants call man out of home, cut off his wrists in Khulna</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/miscreants-call-man-out-of-home-cut-off-his-wrists-in-khulna</link><description>Miscreants have cut off the wrists of a man in Khulna’s Batiaghata, police say.
The incident occurred on Tuesday morning at Darogar Bhita Ali Nagar, Batiaghata Police chief Khandakar Hafizur Rahman said.
The miscreants went to the victim’s house and called him out before severing his</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 12:42:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Neymar undergoes successful knee surgery</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/football/neymar-undergoes-successful-knee-surgery-1</link><description>Neymar has undergone successful arthroscopic surgery on his knee, his club Santos said on Monday, as the winger bids to get back to full fitness and earn a place in the Brazil squad for next year's World Cup.
The 33-year-old returned to his childhood club Santos in January and played a key role in</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 12:57:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Russian air attack on Ukraine kills three and sparks sweeping outages</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/russian-air-attack-on-ukraine-kills-three-and-sparks-sweeping-outages</link><description>Russian missile and drone attacks killed at least three Ukrainians including a child on Tuesday, triggering widespread emergency power cuts and prompting neighbouring Poland to scramble jets.
The attacks, days after another round of U.S.-led talks to end the nearly four-year-old war, hit energy fa</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 13:12:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh separates trade from politics in managing ties with India: Finance adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-separates-trade-from-politics-in-managing-ties-with-india-finance-adviser</link><description>Finance Adviser Dr Salehuddin Ahmed on Tuesday said Bangladesh manages its relationship with India by clearly separating economic interests from political rhetoric, stressing that trade decisions are guided by competitiveness and national interest rather than diplomatic sensitivities.
“Our t</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 13:27:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pay rise for primary headteachers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/government-approves-grade-10-pay-for-headteachers</link><description>The government has raised the salaries of headteachers at government primary schools to grade 10, granting them the rank of gazetted officers.
The Ministry of Primary and Mass Education moved their pay one step up from grade 11, according to a media statement on Tuesday.
The new pay scale will be</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 13:42:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NRBC Bank holds workshop on reporting under Bangladesh Bank’s online monitoring system</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/nrbc-bank-holds-workshop-on-reporting-under-bangladesh-banks-online-monitoring-system</link><description>NRBC Bank organized a workshop on Reporting to Online Import Monitoring System (OIMS) and Online Export Monitoring System (OEMS) introduced by Bangladesh Bank, according to a press release.
The workshop was held on Sunday, 21 December 2025, at the Human Resource and Training Development Centre (HR</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 13:57:11 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>