<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 15:36:43 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Gaza war: How close is it to ending?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/gaza-war-how-close-is-it-to-ending</link><description>President Donald Trump has urged Israel to halt its bombing of Gaza after Hamas agreed to release hostages and accepted some key parts of a US peace plan — a shift that could mean a two-year-old war is finally coming to a close.
Israel announced it would work on "immediate implementation" of</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 12:21:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Remittance hits USD 2.68 billion in Sept: BB report</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/remittance-hits-usd-268-billion-in-sept-bb-report</link><description>The inflow of remittances through formal banking channels increased in September compared to the previous two months, with Bangladesh receiving a total of USD 2.68 billion, according to data released by Bangladesh Bank.
The central bank’s Monthly Workers’ Remittance Report for Septembe</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 12:36:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US urges allies to shun Havana at UN</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/citing-cuban-fighters-in-ukraine-us-urges-allies-to-shun-havana-at-un</link><description>President Donald Trump's administration is mobilizing US diplomats to lobby against a UN resolution calling on Washington to lift its decades-long embargo on Cuba, in part by sharing details of Cuba’s support for Russia’s war in Ukraine, according to an internal State Department cable s</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 12:51:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Energy regulator to review major tariff hike Monday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/energy-regulator-to-review-major-tariff-hike-monday-as-fertiliser-sector-faces-supply-crunch</link><description>A public hearing to assess proposals for a sharp increase in gas tariffs for state-run fertiliser factories will be held on Monday, amid growing concerns over energy costs and supply shortfalls.
The Bangladesh Energy Regulatory Commission (BERC) has scheduled the hearing at the BIAM Foundation aud</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 13:06:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Lightning strikes kill 6 in Cumilla, Bogura, Jhenaidah</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/lightning-strikes-kill-6-in-cumilla-bogura-jhenaidah</link><description>Six people were killed and two others injured by lightning strikes in Cumilla, Bogura and Jhenaidah districts on Sunday.
Among the deceased, three died in Cumilla, two in Jhenaidah and one in Bogura district.
In Cumilla, three people including a student of Bangladesh Agriculture University (BAU)</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 13:36:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>3mn cattle to be vaccinated to curb anthrax</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-to-vaccinate-3mn-cattle-in-rangpur-division-amid-anthrax-concerns</link><description>Three million cattle will be vaccinated across different districts in the Rangpur Division as a part of efforts to prevent the spread of anthrax.
Of these, two million doses will be administered in Rangpur and Gaibandha districts, with the vaccines supplied by the Bangladesh Livestock Research Ins</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 13:22:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh Shilpakala Academy launches 15-day wood carving workshop</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-shilpakala-academy-launches-15-day-wood-carving-workshop</link><description>A 15-day training workshop on wood carving began on Sunday at the National Art Gallery auditorium under the auspices of Bangladesh Shilpakala Academy (BSA) and organized by its Training Division.The inaugural ceremony was held at 12 pm on Sunday, UNB reports. Sheikh Rezauddin Ahmed (poet Rezau</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 13:52:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CUCSU elections: OMR counting, polling centres finalized</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cucsu-elections-omr-counting-polling-centres-finalized</link><description>The CUCSU Election Commission has held a meeting with candidates and students to discuss polling centres and voting procedures for the upcoming CUCSU and hall council elections.
The meeting, held on Sunday, outlined the possible polling process, including the use of OMR machines for vote counting.</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 14:07:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Humayun elected president, Akik general secretary in BADC Agriculturalists’ Association poll</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/humayun-elected-president-akik-general-secretary-in-badc-agriculturalists-association-poll</link><description>In the biannual election of the Central Executive Committee of the Bangladesh Agricultural Development Corporation (BADC) Agriculturalists’ Association, Md. Humayun Kabir has been elected president, and Dr Md Akikul Islam Akik has been elected general secretary.
A total of 60 candidates from</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 14:22:24 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>