<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 03:26:51 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Bangladesh's economic growth slows but inflation reined in</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladeshs-economic-growth-slows-but-inflation-reined-in</link><description>Bangladesh's economic growth may decelerate to 4.7 per cent in the current fiscal year but inflation gets bridled with tighter monetary-policy actions, shows a mixed picture portrayed by the Asian Development Bank.



The development financier, however, paints a better scenario of South Asia</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 19:13:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CEC to declare nat’l election schedule today</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cec-to-declare-natl-election-schedule-today</link><description>Chief Election Commissioner (CEC) AMM Nasir Uddin is set to announce the formal schedule today for the upcoming 13th parliamentary election and a concurrent national referendum.
"The CEC will outline the roadmap for the polls in a televised address to the nation at 6:00pm," Election Commission (EC</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 00:40:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BD to see 5.0pc growth in 2026</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/bd-to-see-50pc-growth-in-2026</link><description>Bangladesh's economy will post a 5.0-percent growth in 2026 with easing inflation and remittance inflows helping households despite ongoing structural challenges, global agency Mastercard forecasts.

South Asia as a region continued to show solid momentum, says the Mastercard Economics Institute</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 00:55:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mahfuz, Asif resign as interim govt advisers to contest polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/mahfuz-asif-resign-as-interim-govt-advisers-to-contest-polls</link><description>Two advisers drawn in Bangladesh's interim government from the arena of student-mass uprising-Mahfuz Alam and Asif Mahmud Sojib Bhuiyan -have resigned purportedly to contest national elections.
The two submitted their resignation letters to Chief Adviser of the post-uprising government Professor M</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 01:10:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>House help Ayesha arrested from Jhalakathi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/house-help-ayesha-arrested-from-jhalakathi</link><description>Police on Wednesday arrested the domestic help, Ayesha, a prime suspect in the Mohammadpur double-murder case, from Nalchity of Jhalakhati district.
The arrestee, identified as Ayesha, confessed to her involvement in the killings during questioning, police said
Police recovered six bhoris of gold</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 01:25:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Finance Adviser hemmed in for hours</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/finance-adviser-hemmed-in-for-hours</link><description>Bangladesh Secretariat employees kept Finance Adviser Dr Salehuddin Ahmed confined to his office for five and a half hours on Wednesday, demanding a 20 per cent "secretariat allowance".
The agitated employees said the National Press Club and the Bangladesh Secretariat area was the centre of almost</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 01:40:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ACC sues 60 recruiting cos on charge of embezzling Tk 45b</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/acc-sues-60-recruiting-cos-on-charge-of-embezzling-tk-45b</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) on Wednesday filed separate cases against the owners, chairmen, managing directors, directors and others of 60 overseas recruiting companies on charge of embezzling Tk 45 billion.
They are accused of misappropriating the money by overcharging Malaysia-bound Ban</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 01:55:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>VAT paid by public often fails to reach treasury</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/vat-paid-by-public-often-fails-to-reach-treasury</link><description>Finance Adviser Dr Salehuddin Ahmed has noted with concern that VAT paid by the public often fails to reach the government treasury.
He has described this as "unfortunate" and stressed the need to simplify procedures to ensure that VAT is properly deposited.

"VAT is a modern and powerful mechan</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 02:10:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CA advises field officials to make upcoming election historic, unforgettable</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ca-advises-field-officials-to-make-upcoming-election-historic-unforgettable</link><description>Chief Adviser Prof Muhammad Yunus advises Upazila Nirbahi Officers (UNOs) across Bangladesh to get down to preparing forthwith to ensure that the upcoming general election stands out as a defining moment in the nation's history.
Describing the post-uprising twin-vote as an opportunity to rebuild B</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 02:25:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NBR in dilemma over tax benefit on edible oil import</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/nbr-in-dilemma-over-tax-benefit-on-edible-oil-import</link><description>The National Board of Revenue (NBR) is in a dilemma over offering a fresh tax benefit on import of edible oils considering revenue impact.
A proposal from the Ministry of Commerce (MoC) to consider tax benefits on the essential commodity for Ramadan is under review in the tax authority now.
A sen</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 02:40:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nothing doing if India doesn't extradite Hasina</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nothing-doing-if-india-doesnt-extradite-hasina</link><description>Bangladesh's interim foreign affairs adviser, Mohammad Touhid Hossain, has said Dhaka has little scope to force the return of deposed former prime minister Sheikh Hasina unless New Delhi agrees to extradite her.
Speaking to reporters at the foreign ministry on Wednesday, Hossain acknowledged Bangl</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 02:55:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Disasters displace 5.0m internally</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/disasters-displace-50m-internally</link><description>Bangladesh is home to almost five million people living in internal displacement due to natural hazards, according to the first nationwide estimate released by the International Organisation for Migration (IOM) in the city on Wednesday.
The assessment marks the most comprehensive attempt to quanti</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 03:10:38 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>