<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 22:33:11 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Purchase Committee approves power purchase proposals from three power plants</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/purchase-committee-approves-power-purchase-proposals-from-three-power-plants</link><description>The government on Tuesday approved power purchase proposals from three major combined cycle power plants at re-determined levelised tariffs, aiming to ensure grid stability while optimising electricity generation costs.
The approvals came from the 5th meeting of the Advisers Council Committee on G</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 15:37:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Draft education law aims to phase out coaching</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/draft-education-law-seeks-to-end-coaching-guidebooks-and-corporal-punishment-in-five-years</link><description>The interim government has come up with a draft education law that proposes a five-year plan to transform teaching and learning in Bangladesh, phasing out private tuitions, guidebooks, and corporal punishments from classrooms.
Teachers, however, may exercise reasonable disciplinary measures in the</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 15:45:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Old Dhaka Muslims observe Shab-e-Barat with traditional foods, charity and illuminated graveyards</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/old-dhaka-muslims-observe-shab-e-barat-with-traditional-foods-charity-and-illuminated-graveyards</link><description>Muslims across the country are observing the holy night of Shab-e-Barat with prayers, zikr and tasbeeh throughout the night, while graveyards have been decorated with lights as devotees seek forgiveness for the departed souls.
In villages and many urban areas, families traditionally prepare homema</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 16:00:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt warns importers over ‘floating warehouses’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/government-orders-cargo-clearance-from-lighter-vessels-within-three-days</link><description>The shipping ministry has ordered importers to clear cargo from lighter vessels within three days or face legal action.
The directive came from Shipping Advisor M Sakhawat Hussain at an inter-ministerial meeting on Tuesday at the ministry that addressed the ongoing crisis in cargo handling from mo</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 16:15:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Taiyeb urges new employees to devote to public services responsibly</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/taiyeb-urges-new-employees-to-devote-to-public-services-responsibly</link><description>Chief Adviser’s Special Assistant for Posts, Telecommunications and Information Technology Ministry Faiz Ahmad Taiyeb on Tuesday called upon the newly appointed office support staff to devote themselves to public service with utmost sincerity.
He made the call while speaking as the chief gue</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 16:30:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh shaken by second quake in a day</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-shaken-again-as-59-magnitude-quake-hits-near-myanmar-border</link><description>Bangladesh has experienced its second earthquake in a single day, this time originating near the Myanmar border.
According to GFZ Earthquake Explorer, the tremor struck at 9:34pm Bangladesh time with a magnitude of 5.9 on the Richter scale.
No immediate reports of casualties or damage have emerge</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 16:45:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UK-funded scholarships reflect strong Dhaka-London partnership: Sarah Cooke</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/uk-funded-scholarships-reflect-strong-dhaka-london-partnership-sarah-cooke</link><description>British High Commissioner to Bangladesh Sarah Cooke has congratulated the Chevening and Commonwealth scholars and said the UK government funded scholarship programmes reflect the strong partnership between Bangladesh and the UK, grounded in shared values and mutual respect.
“Our scholars hav</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 17:02:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt approves proposal to provide education in Rohingya camps through UNICEF</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-approves-proposal-to-provide-education-in-rohingya-camps-through-unicef</link><description>The government has approved a proposal to procure education services through UNICEF to improve pre-primary and primary education for forcibly displaced Myanmar nationals (Rohingyas) living in Cox’s Bazar and Bandarban districts, as well as Bhasan Char in Noakhali.
The approved proposal invol</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 17:17:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>'75pc' of Dhaka polling centres deemed 'high-risk'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/police-classify-three-quarters-of-dhaka-polling-centres-as-high-risk</link><description>With the parliamentary elections less than 10 days away, the Dhaka Metropolitan Police (DMP) has classified nearly three-quarters of the capital’s polling centres as “important”, reflecting concerns over potential “risks”, according to the home advisor.
The DMP overse</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 17:32:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tobacco costs more than twice the revenue: Official</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/tobacco-costs-bangladesh-more-than-twice-it-earns-health-official-says</link><description>Bangladesh earns about Tk 400 billion a year in revenue from the tobacco sector, but the wider costs linked to tobacco use amount to around Tk 870 billion annually, a senior health official has said.
The estimate suggests a net annual loss of at least Tk 470 billion, with the economic burden runni</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 17:47:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Petrobangla, BPC get new chiefs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/erfanul-haque-named-petrobangla-chairman-rezanur-rahman-to-lead-bpc</link><description>The government has reshuffled the leadership of two key state-owned energy corporations, appointing Md Erfanul Haque as chairman of Bangladesh Oil, Gas and Mineral Corporation (Petrobangla) and Md Rezanur Rahman as chairman of Bangladesh Petroleum Corporation (BPC).
The appointments were confirmed</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 18:42:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh, Japan sign defence equipment, technology transfer agreement</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-japan-sign-defence-equipment-technology-transfer-agreement</link><description>Bangladesh and Japan signed a defence equipment and technology transfer agreement at Dhaka Cantonment under the supervision of the Armed Forces Division (AFD) on Tuesday.
Lieutenant General S M Kamrul Hassan, Principal Staff Officer of AFD, signed on behalf of Bangladesh, while Japan's Ambassador</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 18:57:16 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>