<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 05:24:31 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Foreign fund flow into Bangladesh corporates falls to $9.80b until Nov</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/foreign-fund-flow-into-bangladesh-corporates-falls-to-980b-until-nov</link><description>Corporate external borrowing drops as persisting economic sluggishness dampens businesses' appetite for funds with the short-term overseas debt stock having declined to $9.80 billion until November.
Officials and money-market analysts see such unrelenting contraction in private-sector foreign debt</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 01:15:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Migratory birds throng Ctg seashore, riverbanks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/migratory-birds-throng-ctg-seashore-riverbanks</link><description>The weather has been chilly in the port-city for the last several days. A number of migratory and guest birds have now gathered in the seashore areas as well as on the banks of rivers including Karnaphuli, Sangu and Halda.
Bird-lovers are going to the areas along the banks of Karnaphuli River to w</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 01:30:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Temp dips to 6.8°C in Panchagarh as cold spell prevails</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/temp-dips-to-68c-in-panchagarh-as-cold-spell-prevails</link><description>The cold wave and dense fog are likely to persist for several more days across the country, according to the Bangladesh Meteorological Department (BMD).
The overall weather situation would remain dry with a temporary partly cloudy sky during the next 24 hours, commencing from 9:00am Friday, said t</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 01:45:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two-day photo exhibition on Khaleda Zia in capital</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/two-day-photo-exhibition-on-khaleda-zia-in-capital</link><description>A two-day photo exhibition focusing on the eventful and struggling life of BNP Chairperson and former prime minister Begum Khaleda Zia began at Zia Udyan in the capital on Friday.Political Biography Book
BNP Standing Committee Member Nazrul Islam Khan inaugurated the exhibition, organised by Bogur</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 02:00:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>12th Commencement Ceremony of AUW today</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/12th-commencement-ceremony-of-auw-today</link><description>The 12th Commencement Ceremony of the Asian University for Women (AUW) will be held at Radisson Blu Hotel in the port-city today (Saturday) with its Chancellor Cherie Blair in the chair. Professor Irene Tracey, Vice Chancellor of the University of Oxford, UK, will attend the function as the speaker</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 02:15:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DU holds int'l conference on Islamic Finance, Banking</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/du-holds-intl-conference-on-islamic-finance-banking</link><description>The Dhaka University (DU) has organised a two-day international conference on Islamic Finance and Banking under the theme 'Islamic Finance for Sustainable Economic Development'.
The event is jointly organised by the DU Department of Finance and the Central Shariah Board for Islamic Banks of Bangla</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 02:30:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Loan distributions: MoF asks specialised banks to stay within mandates</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/loan-distributions-mof-asks-specialised-banks-to-stay-within-mandates</link><description>The Ministry of Finance (MoF) has instructed specialised banks to distribute loans according to their mandates after it was found that they were going beyond their authorised areas.
Officials say the specialised banks were formed with the target to make loans available in some special sectors, esp</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 02:34:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Four DU professors face charge over roles during July Uprising</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/four-du-professors-face-charge-over-roles-during-july-uprising</link><description>The Dhaka University (DU) administration has decided to frame charges against four professors of the Department of Sociology and form a probe committee over their alleged roles during the July 2024 mass uprising.
The accused teachers are Prof Jinat Huda, Prof AKM Jamal Uddin, Prof Sadeka Halim, an</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 02:49:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Price of .bd domain cut by 36pc</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/price-of-bd-domain-cut-by-36pc</link><description>The price of Bangladesh's country code top-level domain .bd has been reduced by 36 per cent following a second round of review, Special Assistant to the Chief Adviser Faiz Ahmad Taiyeb announced on Friday.
In a Facebook post, Faiz Ahmad Taiyeb said the decision was taken in response to application</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 03:04:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Protests over Musabbir killing continue</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/protests-over-musabbir-killing-continue</link><description>Protests continued in the city on Friday over the killing of Jatiyatabadi Swecchasebak Dal leader Azizur Rahman Musabbir.
People from all walks of life staged protests at Farmgate and Karwan Bazar areas in the city, demanding immediate justice for the slain leader.
Supporters of Musabbir organise</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 03:19:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC begins hearing appeals against nomination decisions today</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ec-begins-hearing-appeals-against-nomination-decisions-today</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) is scheduled to begin hearing and resolving appeals today (Saturday) from candidates whose nomination papers were rejected by the returning officers.
At least 640 appeals were filed with EC over the five days from Monday to Friday. Among these, as of 8:00 pm on Friday,</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 03:34:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump urges US oil giants to repair Venezuela's 'rotting' energy industry</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-urges-us-oil-giants-to-repair-venezuelas-rotting-energy-industry</link><description>US President Donald Trump met with executives from some of the world's largest oil companies at the White House on Friday to discuss Venezuela, saying he wants them to invest $100 billion in the country to vastly expand its production.
Trump has named oil as the priority for his strategy for the S</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 04:35:53 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>