<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 13:33:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Kremlin says Putin wished Trump a Merry Christmas</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/kremlin-says-putin-wished-trump-a-merry-christmas</link><description>Russian President Vladimir Putin has wished US President Donald Trump a Merry Christmas and sent him a congratulatory message, Kremlin spokesman Dmitry Peskov said on Thursday.
Putin is not expected to speak with Trump on Thursday, no such call is scheduled, he added.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 09:59:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Abu Taleb’s long wait to see Tarique Rahman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/a-sexagenarians-hours-long-wait-for-a-glimpse-of-tarique-rahman</link><description>Abu Taleb was among thousands of Bangladeshis hoping to catch a glimpse of BNP’s acting chief Tarique Rahman on his homecoming after 17 years in exile. By the time he reached Kuril on Thursday morning, the area had already turned into a sea of people.
Unable to move any further, the 60-year-</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 10:14:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NBR to offer e-return service for election candidates over weekend</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/nbr-to-offer-online-tax-filing-service-for-election-candidates-on-public-holidays</link><description>The National Board of Revenue (NBR) will provide an online income tax return service on Friday and Saturday to assist candidates contesting the upcoming 13th general election.
In a statement issued on Thursday, the revenue authority said it had set up a special helpdesk to facilitate online return</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 10:29:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Blast at Nigeria mosque kills 5</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/africa/blast-at-nigeria-mosque-kills-5</link><description>At least five people were killed and more than 30 others injured after a bomb exploded during prayers at a mosque in the northeastern Nigerian city of Maiduguri on Wednesday night, in what police said appeared to be a suicide attack.
Police in Borno state said 35 worshippers were wounded in the bl</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 10:44:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh Polls: EC clarifies voting process for prisoners</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-polls-ec-clarifies-voting-process-for-prisoners</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has issued detailed guidelines enabling voters detained in prisons or under legal custody to cast their votes in the upcoming national election.
According to Rule 10A of the Election Conduct Rules 2008 (amended in 2025), inmates and detainees will be able to exercise t</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 10:59:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique now at Evercare to visit ailing mother</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-now-at-evercare-to-visit-ailing-mother</link><description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman went to Evercare Hospital to see his mother and former Prime Minister Begum Khaleda Zia after addressing party leaders and supporters at the 300 Feet venue in the capital on Thursday.
Tarique set off from the 300 Feet reception venue around 4:28pm and reached the</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 11:14:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique’s return will ensure ‘inclusive’ election: NDF</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ndf-describes-tariques-return-as-a-factor-in-ensuring-inclusive-election</link><description>The National Democratic Front (NDF) has said that the return of Tarique Rahman from exile will help ensure an “inclusive” election.
The observation was made in a statement issued on Thursday, signed by the front’s President Anisul Islam Mahmud and the party’s spokesperson A</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 11:29:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Credit card use jumps domestically and overseas: Bangladesh Bank</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/credit-card-use-jumps-domestically-and-overseas-bangladesh-bank</link><description>Credit card use in Bangladesh recorded a sharp rise in October, with both domestic transactions and spending by Bangladeshis overseas increasing significantly compared to the previous month, says the Bangladesh Bank.
According to its latest report, transactions within the country, expenditures by</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 11:44:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prime Bank signs payroll agreement with Fame Group</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/prime-bank-signs-payroll-agreement-with-fame-group</link><description>Prime Bank PLC, one of the leading private commercial banks in Bangladesh, renowned for its innovative and customer-centric financial solutions, has recently signed a Payroll Agreement with Fame Group at the Bank’s Corporate Office in Dhaka.
Under this agreement, employees of Fame Group will</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 11:59:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BRAC Bank installs ATMs at 5 MRT stations to provide banking convenience to commuters</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/brac-bank-installs-atms-at-5-mrt-stations-to-provide-banking-convenience-to-commuters</link><description>BRAC Bank has expanded its alternate banking footprint by installing ATMs at five key stations of Dhaka’s MRT Line-6, bringing fast and seamless banking services closer to daily commuters. 
The ATMs are now operational at Pallabi, Mirpur-10, Farmgate, Shahbagh, and Bangladesh Secretaria</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 12:14:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique Rahman: A true reformist and visionary leader</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/tarique-rahman-a-true-reformist-and-visionary-leader</link><description>The mass uprising of July-August (2024) not only led to the downfall of the fascist Awami League government, but also brought a profound transformation in the collective psyche of the people of this country. That powerful mass movement revived the mental strength of the countrymen that had been cru</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 12:29:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Driver of rickshaw on which Hadi was shot delivers court statement</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/driver-of-rickshaw-on-which-hadi-was-shot-delivers-court-statement</link><description>Kamal Hossain, the driver of the battery-powered rickshaw on which Sharif Osman bin Hadi was shot, has given a statement in court as a witness.
On Thursday, the investigation officer DB Police Inspector Faisal Ahmed produced Kamal in court and applied for recording his statement as a witness.
Acc</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 12:44:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>