<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 10:29:43 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Over 6000 killed in Sudan over 3 days: UN</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/africa/over-6000-killed-in-sudan-over-3-days-un</link><description>More than 6,000 people were killed during a three-day offensive by Sudan’s paramilitary Rapid Support Forces (RSF) on the Darfur city of El-Fasher in late October, the United Nations said in a report released Friday.
The UN Human Rights Office described the assault as a wave of violence &amp;ldq</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 06:24:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>100 crude bombs detonated amid Madaripur clash</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/100-crude-bombs-detonated-amid-madaripur-clash</link><description>At least four people have been injured in a clash stemming from a power struggle in Madaripur. Over 100 crude bombs were detonated amid the violence.
The clash lasted for three hours, from 8:00 pm to 11:00 pm on Saturday, in “Notun Madaripur” village in the Sadar Upazila, according to</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 06:39:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Father hacked to death after protesting assault on son</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/father-hacked-to-death-after-protesting-assault-on-son</link><description>A farmer was hacked to death allegedly for protesting the assault on his son in Char Fasson upazila of Bhola district on Saturday night.
The deceased has been identified as Abdur Rahim Bhutto, 45, from the Kalerhat area, reports bdnews24.com.
Fakhrul Islam, officer-in-charge (OC) of Shashibhushan</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 07:41:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangla Academy goes ahead with Ekushey Book Fair amid Ramadan boycott threat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangla-academy-goes-ahead-with-ekushey-book-fair-amid-ramadan-boycott-threat</link><description>Bangladesh’s premier literary event, Ekushey Book Fair, is set to open later this month amid mounting opposition from a large section of mainstream publishers who warn that holding the fair during Ramadan could inflict heavy financial losses on the industry.
Bangla Academy has confirmed that</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 07:14:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Six fishermen kidnapped in Sundarbans</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/six-fishermen-kidnapped-in-sundarbans</link><description>Six fishermen were allegedly kidnapped by forest robbers from Shelar Char in the eastern side of the Sundarbans on Saturday.
The abducted fishermen were identified as Khairul, 35, Faruk, 28, Samsul Islam, 25, Safrul, 32, Maruf, 28, and Milon, 30. All of them hailed from Koyra, Rampal and Morelganj</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 07:29:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mar 4 set for verdict in Rampura crimes against humanity case</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/mar-4-set-for-verdict-in-rampura-crimes-against-humanity-case</link><description>The International Crimes Tribunal has fixed Mar 4 for delivering its verdict in a crimes against humanity case over killings during the July Uprising in Dhaka's Rampura.
Five people, including former Dhaka Metropolitan Police commissioner Habibur Rahman, are facing charges in connection with the k</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 07:44:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UK pledges close cooperation with Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/uk-pledges-close-cooperation-with-bangladesh</link><description>The United Kingdom (UK) has expressed its commitment to working closely with Bangladesh on shared priorities of economic growth, migration, climate and security following the country’s parliamentary elections.
“We look forward to the new government advancing democratic, economic and so</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 07:59:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AL leader dies in hospital after falling ill in jail</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/al-leader-dies-in-hospital-after-falling-ill-in-jail</link><description>A local leader of the Bangladesh Awami League died at Rangpur Medical College and Hospital on Sunday, after falling critically ill while in custody.
The deceased, Shamikul Islam Lipon, was president of the Gaibandha district unit of the Awami League, reports UNB.
Lipon, who had been in custody fo</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 08:14:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CAO pushes back against ‘misinformation’ over cabinet secretary's exit</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cao-pushes-back-against-misinformation-over-cabinet-secretarys-exit</link><description>The Chief Advisor’s Office (CAO) has called for restraint amid “misinformation and speculative statements” surrounding the cancellation of Cabinet Secretary Sheikh Abdur Rashid’s contractual appointment.
In a statement issued on Sunday, the CAO said various media outlets ha</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 08:29:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCP preparing to form shadow cabinet as ‘watchdog’, says Asif Mahmud</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ncp-preparing-to-form-shadow-cabinet-as-watchdog-says-asif-mahmud</link><description>The National Citizen Party (NCP) is preparing to form a shadow cabinet, according to party spokesperson and former interim government advisor Asif Mahmud Shojib Bhuyain.
In a post on his Facebook page on Sunday, Asif, who also chairs the party’s central election management committee, said th</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 08:44:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh will not tolerate secret politics any longer, says Chhatra Dal’s Rakib</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bangladesh-will-not-tolerate-secret-politics-any-longer-says-chhatra-dals-rakib</link><description>Chhatra Dal President Rakibul Islam Rakib has called on Jamaat-e-Islami and its student wing Islami Chhatra Shibir to make all its committees public.
“Bangladesh will not abide secret politics any longer,” he said in a Facebook post at 1am on Sunday. “All Jamaat-e-Islami and Chha</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 09:37:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>999 receives 8,380 election-related calls during JS-polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/999-receives-8380-election-related-calls-during-js-polls</link><description>National Emergency Service 999 received a total of 8,380 phone calls related to the national election as it implemented a special operational plan to ensure a free, fair and peaceful election.
Under the special plan, 999 provided election-related emergency services through round-the-clock coordina</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 09:52:28 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>