<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 09:35:39 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Appeal proceeding on nomination papers begins</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/appeal-proceeding-on-nomination-papers-begins-today</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) began appeal proceedings on Monday over the acceptance and rejection of nomination papers for the 13th Jatiya Sangsad election.
According to a notification issued on Sunday night, 1,842 nomination papers were found valid while 723 were rejected across 300 parliamentary</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 06:27:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump warns of higher tariffs on India over Russian oil purchases</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-warns-of-higher-tariffs-on-india-over-russian-oil-purchases</link><description>The United States could raise tariffs on India if New Delhi doesn't meet Washington's demand to curb purchases of Russian oil, President Donald Trump told reporters aboard Air Force One.
"Modi is a good guy. He knew I was not happy, and it was important to make me happy," Trump said on Sunday.
"T</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 06:42:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Independents make up nearly half of election candidates rejected in screening</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/independents-make-up-nearly-half-of-election-candidates-rejected-in-screening</link><description>Independent candidates account for nearly half of all rejected nominations following the scrutiny of nomination papers for the 13th parliamentary election.
Almost 350 independent hopefuls were disqualified during the vetting process, representing about 73 per cent of those who sought to contest th</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 06:30:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Stocks edge up in early trade at DSE, CSE</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/stocks-edge-up-in-early-trade-at-dse-cse</link><description>Stocks in Bangladesh posted modest gains in the first half of trading on Monday, with key indices of both the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) and the Chittagong Stock Exchange (CSE) moving upward.
On the second trading day of the week, the DSE's benchmark index DSEX and the Shariah-based DSES each rose</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 06:45:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Maduro to appear in US court, Trump says further strikes possible</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/venezuelas-maduro-to-appear-in-us-court-trump-says-further-strikes-possible</link><description>Venezuelan President Nicolas Maduro was due to appear in a US court on Monday after his weekend capture by American forces, with US President Donald Trump leaving open the possibility of another incursion if the United States doesn't get its way with the country's interim leader.
Trump told report</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 07:00:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>FDRs up 5.53pc in Q3'25 amid rising risk aversion</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/fdrs-up-553pc-in-q325-amid-rising-risk-aversion</link><description>Banks saw a noticeable shift in deposit behaviour in the July-September quarter of 2025, with more funds flowing into term deposits as rising returns encouraged customers to lock in their savings for longer tenures.
In this period, fixed deposit receipts (FDRs) in banks rose by about 5.53 per ce</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 07:15:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Yields on T-bills fall as BB buys US$187.50m more from banks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/yields-on-t-bills-fall-as-bb-buys-us18750m-more-from-banks</link><description>Yields on treasury bills (T-bills) decreased on Sunday as the central bank purchased an additional US$187.50 million from 14 banks in an effort to maintain stability in the exchange rate.
The cut-off yield, generally known as interest rate, on the 91-Day T-bills fell to 10.42 per cent on the day</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 07:30:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ADB doubles Bangladesh financing to $2.57 billion in 2025</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/adb-doubles-bangladesh-financing-to-257-billion-in-2025</link><description>The Asian Development Bank (ADB) committed $2.57 billion in new sovereign financing to Bangladesh in 2025, more than double its 2024 commitment of $1.18 billion.
The 2025 programme targets priority investments in energy, transport, banking reforms, urban services, climate resilience, small and med</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 07:45:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt orders TV channels to suspend IPL broadcast in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-orders-tv-channels-to-suspend-ipl-broadcast-in-bangladesh</link><description>The government has instructed television channels to suspend the broadcast of Indian Premier League (IPL) matches in Bangladesh.
In a letter sent to television channels on Monday (January 5), the Ministry of Information and Broadcasting issued the directive.
According to the letter, the ministry</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 08:00:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC is confident holding a neutral election: CEC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-is-confident-holding-a-neutral-election-cec</link><description>Chief Election Commissioner A M M Nasir Uddin on Monday said the Election Commission (EC) remains confident and committed to holding a free, fair and neutral election.
He made the remarks this morning after visiting the appeal centre set up at the Election Commission building in Agargaon to receiv</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 08:30:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CID confirms identities of eight July Uprising martyrs through DNA profiling</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cid-confirms-identities-of-eight-july-uprising-martyrs-through-dna-profiling</link><description>The Criminal Investigation Department (CID) on Monday released the names and addresses of eight martyrs of the July Uprising 2024 after confirming their identities through DNA profiling and forensic examination.
The bodies were exhumed from Rayerbazar Graveyard as part of a state-led initiative to</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 08:45:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NBR launches e-VAT module for paper-based returns</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/nbr-launches-e-vat-module-for-paper-based-returns</link><description>The National Board of Revenue (NBR) has taken a step towards fully digitising the country's VAT administration by introducing a new initiative that allows taxpayers to bring all previously submitted paper-based VAT returns under the e-VAT system.
It has added a sub-module titled "Hard Copy Return</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 09:00:50 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>