<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 20:38:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Jamaat Ameer voices deep concern over Shahjalal Airport fire</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jamaat-ameer-voices-deep-concern-over-shahjalal-airport-fire</link><description>Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami Ameer Dr. Shafiqur Rahman has expressed deep concern and shock over the devastating fire that broke out at the import cargo village of Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport on Saturday afternoon.
In a Facebook post, Dr. Shafiqur wrote, “As the country's main inter</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 16:14:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pakistan and Afghanistan hold peace talks in Doha after fierce clashes</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/pakistan-and-afghanistan-hold-peace-talks-in-doha-after-fierce-clashes</link><description>Afghanistan and Pakistan were holding peace talks in Doha on Saturday, both sides said, after the South Asia neighbours extended a ceasefire following a week of fierce border clashes.
They are seeking to find a way forward after the clashes killed dozens and wounded hundreds in the worst violence</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 16:44:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CAO promises ‘swift’ action if fire incident is act of sabotage</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cao-promises-swift-action-if-fire-incident-is-act-of-sabotage</link><description>The Chief Advisor’s Office (CAO) has said security agencies are conducting “thorough” investigations into the recent fire incidents amid growing public concern over a series of blazes across Bangladesh.
“We wish to assure all citizens that the security services are investig</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 17:14:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Now big blaze burns Dhaka airport cargo section</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/now-big-blaze-burns-dhaka-airport-cargo-section</link><description>A devastating fire ravaged Dhaka's Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport cargo section Saturday, shutting down flight operations at the main gateway to Bangladesh, after two consecutive factory fires.
Incidentally, the airport blaze falls in a chain having occurred hot on the heels of two garment</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 17:29:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Civil society calls for inclusion of fisherfolk in support and AIGA programmes</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/civil-society-calls-for-inclusion-of-fisherfolk-in-support-and-aiga-programmes</link><description>Civil society representatives in Barishal have urged the government to ensure that small-scale and marginalised fishers, including the floating Manta community, are fully included in food aid and Alternative Income Generation Activities (AIGA) programmes during fishing ban periods.
The call came a</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 17:44:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Canada-US trade war &amp; expat Bangladeshis</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/canada-us-trade-war-expat-bangladeshis</link><description>The economic ties between Canada and the United States (US) are not just significant, they are among the closest and most important trading partnerships globally. In 2023, the daily goods and services trading surpassed US$2 billion, with the total annual trade reaching a record high of US$900 billi</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 17:59:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>What is hurting the business climate?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/what-is-hurting-the-business-climate</link><description>The popular expectation that the present government would take more effective and determined measures than its predecessors to improve the business climate has largely been belied. The latest Business Climate Index (BBX) for FY2024-25, jointly prepared by the Metropolitan Chamber of Commerce and In</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 18:14:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Why Bangladesh opts out of plurilateral deals</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/why-bangladesh-opts-out-of-plurilateral-deals</link><description>The multilateral trading system, under the framework of the World Trade Organization (WTO), has been facing a set of complex challenges in producing an optimal outcome over the last couple of years. Prolonged negotiations on various trade issues without any outcome have already disappointed many of</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 18:29:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hard lessons from 2025 HSC results</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/hard-lessons-from-2025-hsc-results</link><description>The sharp fall in the 2025 HSC and equivalent examinations pass rate to its lowest level in twenty years, though deeply distressing, seems to have been accepted by both educators and the public with a weary sense of inevitability. The overall pass rate of 58.83 per cent at this critical stage of ed</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 18:44:10 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>