<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 13:36:59 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>India probes possible cough syrup link to deaths of nine children</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/india-probes-possible-cough-syrup-link-to-deaths-of-nine-children</link><description>Indian authorities said on Saturday they are investigating if contaminated cough syrup caused the deaths of nine children in a central state after a batch of the medication was found to contain dangerous levels of a toxic chemical.
The Health Ministry said samples of Coldrif Cough Syrup, manufactu</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 10:51:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Yunus says Buddha’s lessons crucial for peace and harmony in turbulent world</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/yunus-says-buddhas-lessons-crucial-for-peace-and-harmony-in-turbulent-world</link><description>Global stability and peace could greatly benefit from the teachings of Gautama Buddha, Chief Advisor Muhammad Yunus says.
On Saturday, Yunus highlighted Buddha’s commitment to non-violence, equality, and fraternity, saying Buddha’s message of peace continues to shine as a beacon for hu</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 11:06:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>15 injured as bus overturns inside Karnaphuli Tunnel</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/15-injured-as-bus-overturns-inside-karnaphuli-tunnel</link><description>At least 15 passengers were injured after a bus lost control and overturned inside the Karnaphuli Tunnel in Chattogram on Saturday afternoon.
The accident occurred around 1:35pm when a passenger bus heading from Patenga to Anwara overturned on the Patenga end of the tunnel, said Golam Samdani Hime</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 11:21:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Turkey says 137 Gaza flotilla activists to arrive in Istanbul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/turkey-says-137-gaza-flotilla-activists-to-arrive-in-istanbul</link><description>Some 137 activists detained by Israel for taking part in a flotilla seeking to deliver aid to Gaza are being flown to Istanbul, Turkey’s foreign ministry said on Saturday.
The individuals include 36 Turkish nationals, as well as citizens from the United States, the United Arab Emirates, Alge</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 11:36:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two ‘extortionists’ snatched away from police custody in Narsingdi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/two-extortionists-snatched-away-from-police-custody-in-narsingdi</link><description>Two men accused of extorting money from autorickshaw drivers have been snatched away from police custody in Narsingdi Sadar after a group of up to 50 people reportedly launched an attack on officers.
Additional Superintendent of Police (ASP) Mohammad Anwar Hossain was injured in the assault on Sat</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 12:21:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>London police intervene as Palestine Action protesters gather despite synagogue attack</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/london-police-intervene-as-palestine-action-protesters-gather-despite-synagogue-attack</link><description>London police arrested six people who displayed support for a banned pro-Palestinian group on Saturday and carried away protesters who gathered for a demonstration, despite requests to call it off after a deadly attack at a synagogue in Manchester.
Two people were killed in the attack in the north</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 12:36:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>RU admission test likely to begin January 16</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/ru-admission-test-likely-to-begin-january-16</link><description>The admission test for the 2025–26 academic session at Rajshahi University (RU) is likely to begin on January 16, 2026, much earlier than previous years, university sources said yesterday.
 
The decision comes as the authorities look to adjust the schedule ahead of the national electio</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 13:06:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh-India tensions hurt Varanasi weavers; help West Bengal cotton sari traders</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladesh-india-tensions-hurt-varanasi-weavers-help-west-bengal-cotton-sari-traders</link><description>Mohammed Ahmad Ansari has spent his entire life in the narrow and congested lanes of Varanasi, a city often described as the spiritual capital of India, and the constituency of Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi.
The 55-year-old has spent decades weaving Banarasi saris and thoroughly enjoys the c</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 13:21:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Consensus Commission reviews final phase preparations for July Charter</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/consensus-commission-reviews-final-phase-preparations-for-july-charter</link><description>The National Consensus Commission has reviewed preparations for the final phase of deliberations over the July National Charter 2025, as part of its ongoing efforts to ensure effective implementation of the Charter’s objectives.
A meeting in this regard was held on Saturday at the Commission</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 13:36:59 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>