<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 04:35:49 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Day of state mourning tomorrow</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/day-of-state-mourning-tomorrow</link><description>Interim government’s Chief Adviser Prof Muhammad Yunus appealed for calm late Thursday night and pledged justice over Sharif Osman Had’s death following a sniper attack on him.



In an impromptu televised address to the nation, he also announced that the government would take the</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 23:37:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Security agencies on high alert for policing polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/security-agencies-on-high-alert-for-policing-polls</link><description>Bangladesh invites foreign election-observer missions to be deployed and says all security apparatuses have been put on high alert for holding the country's post-uprising polls in an orderly manner.
Foreign secretary Asad Alam Siam Thursday briefed foreign missions in Dhaka on the latest prepara</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 23:52:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Microcredit Bank Ordinance 2025:  Govt forms body to scrutinise draft</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/microcredit-bank-ordinance-2025-govt-forms-body-to-scrutinise-draft</link><description>The government has formed a 10-member committee to scrutinise the draft Microcredit Bank Ordinance, 2025.
The body was formed Thursday at a meeting at the Financial Institution Division (FID) with its secretary Nazma Mobarek in the chair, after many sections of the draft have been found to be in</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 00:07:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chhayanaut building vandalised, set on fire after news of Hadi's death</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/chhayanaut-building-vandalised-set-on-fire-after-news-of-hadis-death</link><description>The premises of Bengali cultural organisation Chhayanaut have been vandalised and set on fire after news of the death of Inqilab Moncho Convenor Sharif Osman bin Hadi spread.
The attack came around 2am on Friday, after Inqilab Moncho confirmed the death of Hadi, who was in treatment in Singapore.</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 00:22:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>RACE under fresh probes ahead of possible regulatory action</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/race-under-fresh-probes-ahead-of-possible-regulatory-action</link><description>The securities regulator has launched fresh probes into the management of 12 mutual funds operated by Bangladesh RACE Management to dig deeper into allegations of irregularities against the fund manager.



The Bangladesh Securities and Exchange Commission (BSEC) formed six separate inquiry c</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 00:37:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DSE gets first female MD</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/dse-gets-first-female-md</link><description>Nuzhat Anwar has been appointed as the new managing director of the Dhaka Stock Exchange.



This is the first time that a female candidate has taken over the charge of the prime bourse. The position at the Dhaka Exchange had remained vacant since May last year following the departure of the</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 00:52:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shasha Denims plans container handling to offset business slowdown</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/shasha-denims-plans-container-handling-to-offset-business-slowdown</link><description>Shasha Denims plans to diversify its business into inland container handling to sustain income amid uncertainty in denim manufacturing.
"The denim business is becoming challenging due to the unavailability of gas and other factors. That's why we have planned early to open other windows of earnin</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 01:07:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Savings certificate yields lowered twice, further cuts in Jan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/savings-certificate-yields-lowered-twice-further-cuts-in-jan</link><description>A retired banker's daughter increasingly struggles to manage the daily expenses of her parents, who are almost bed-ridden, and a downturn in receipts from investment in savings certificates worries her.
Sadia Chowdhury, daughter of former private banker Humayun Chowdhury, whose parents live in t</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 01:22:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt moves to eliminate child labour by 2030: Labour secy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-moves-to-eliminate-child-labour-by-2030-labour-secy</link><description>The government has initiated steps to formulate a national action plan to eliminate child labour from the country by 2030, said Dr Md Sanwar Jahan Bhuiyan, secretary at the Ministry of Labour and Employment, on Thursday.
"Eradication of child labour requires coordinated interventions -- particul</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 01:37:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Disappeared person's dependants can use victim's property</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/disappeared-persons-dependants-can-use-victims-property</link><description>Dependants of a victim of enforced disappearances now can use the victim's property sans any permission under provision of a draft law that remedies existing painful wait of many.
The Advisory Council of the interim government in its meeting Thursday approved the draft of two ordinances-one rela</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 01:52:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NBR launches digital truck tracking system at Benapole land port</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/nbr-launches-digital-truck-tracking-system-at-benapole-land-port</link><description>The National Board of Revenue (NBR) has introduced a new "Truck Movement" sub-module under the ASYCUDA World system to digitally track the entry of cargo-laden trucks from India and the exit of empty vehicles.
The initiative aims to strengthen monitoring, transparency and revenue protection, acc</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 02:07:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>July Revolution sought constitutional renewal, not repeal: Chief Justice</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/july-revolution-sought-constitutional-renewal-not-repeal-chief-justice</link><description>Chief Justice (CJ) Dr Syed Refaat Ahmed on Thursday said the July Revolution did not aim to overturn the Constitution, but rather to renew and strengthen the nation's engagement with it.
He made the remarks while responding to a farewell felicitation accorded to him by Attorney General Md Asaduz</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 02:22:03 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>