<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 10:26:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Stocks open year on positive note with new hope</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/stocks-open-year-on-positive-note-with-new-hope-1</link><description>Stocks opened higher on Thursday, the opening day of the New Year 2026, as bargain hunters favoured taking positions in potentially lucrative shares amid renewed optimism.
The market opened higher, aided by the price appreciation of particular large-cap stocks, as opportunistic investors are expec</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 06:15:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Indian tobacco stocks fall as new tax is imposed on cigarettes</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/indian-tobacco-stocks-fall-as-new-tax-is-imposed-on-cigarettes</link><description>Shares of Indian tobacco companies fell on Thursday after the government imposed a new tax on cigarettes, making them costlier for an estimated 100 million smokers in the world's most populous country.
ITC, maker of Gold Flake and the market leader, dropped 4.4 per cent, while Godfrey Phillips Ind</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 06:30:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fuel prices cut by Tk 2 a litre at start of 2026</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/fuel-prices-cut-by-tk-2-a-litre-at-start-of-2026</link><description>Bangladesh cut retail fuel prices by Tk 2 a litre from January 1, reversing an increase imposed a month earlier as part of its automatic fuel pricing mechanism.
The Energy and Mineral Resources Division said in a notification issued late Wednesday that the prices of diesel, octane, petrol and kero</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 06:45:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nothing secret about it: Jamaat chief on meeting with Indian diplomats</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/nothing-secret-about-it-jamaat-chief-on-meeting-with-indian-diplomats</link><description>Jamaat-e-Islami chief Shafiqur Rahman has hit out at reports that he held a “secret meeting” with Indian diplomats, saying there was “nothing confidential” about the contact.
In a Facebook post on Thursday, Shafiqur said he met two Indian diplomats around the middle of last</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 07:00:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh bans e-cigarettes, vapes under tightened tobacco law</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-bans-e-cigarettes-vapes-under-tightened-tobacco-law</link><description>The interim government has issued an ordinance banning e-cigarettes, vapes and all other emerging tobacco products as part of a sweeping overhaul of the country’s tobacco control laws.
The Smoking and Tobacco Products Use (Control) (Amendment) Ordinance, 2025, was promulgated on Wednesday by</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 08:01:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Biman's profit jumps 178pc with Tk 7.85 billion gain</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bimans-profit-jumps-178pc-with-tk-785-billion-gain</link><description>Bangladesh’s state-owned carrier Biman Bangladesh Airlines posted a net profit of Tk 7.85 billion (Tk 785.21 crore) in fiscal 2024–25, nearly tripling its earnings from a year earlier, as higher passenger traffic and tighter cost controls boosted the airline’s financial performanc</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 08:47:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Polli Kobi’ Jasimuddin’s 123rd birth anniversary today</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/polli-kobi-jasimuddins-123rd-birth-anniversary-today</link><description>The 123rd birth anniversary of famous poet and litterateur Jasimuddin, widely revered as the ‘Polli Kobi’, is being observed on Thursday.
The poet was born on this day in 1903 at his maternal uncle’s house in Tambulkhana village in Faridpur district.
UNB Faridpur correspondent r</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 09:02:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mel Gibson and Rosalind Ross part ways after nine years</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/mel-gibson-and-rosalind-ross-part-ways-after-nine-years</link><description>Oscar winner Mel Gibson and Rosalind Ross have separated after nine years together, a representative from Gibson's legal team told Reuters on Tuesday.
The representative confirmed a joint statement provided exclusively to PEOPLE on Tuesday that the couple had split about a year ago, but chose not</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 09:17:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ACC moves to prosecute Salman F Rahman, family over alleged Tk 28.57b embezzlement</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/acc-moves-to-prosecute-salman-f-rahman-family-over-alleged-tk-2857b-embezzlement</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) has approved four cases against Salman F Rahman, his brother and their sons over allegations of embezzlement and money laundering involving billions of taka from state-owned Jamuna Bank.
The cases relate to the alleged misappropriation of Tk 28.57 billion obtai</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 09:32:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sayedur Rahman returns as CA's special assistant two days after resignation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/sayedur-rahman-returns-as-cas-special-assistant-two-days-after-resignation</link><description>Prof Sayedur Rahman is set to return to his post as special assistant to the chief advisor tasked with overseeing the health ministry, just two days after he stepped down from the post following his retirement from government service.
A gazette notification issued by the Cabinet Division on Thursd</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 09:47:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NBR rolls out full online utilisation permission through CBMS</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nbr-rolls-out-full-online-utilisation-permission-through-cbms</link><description>The National Board of Revenue (NBR) has entered a new phase of digital service delivery by making the issuance of Utilisation Permission (UP) under the Customs Bond Management System (CBMS) completely online.
The use of CBMS software was made mandatory from Thursday (January 1) for receiving and i</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 10:02:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP leaders, supporters gather at Khaleda Zia’s grave to offer fateha</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-leaders-supporters-gather-at-khaleda-zias-grave-to-offer-fateha</link><description>A day after her burial, BNP leaders, activists, and common people on Thursday visited the grave of former Prime Minister and BNP Chairperson Begum Khaleda Zia to offer fateha and pay their tributes.
The entrance to Zia Udyan was opened to the public after 12 noon on Thursday, allowing people to vi</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 10:17:16 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>