<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 18:36:50 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Tarique Rahman to visit Bogura, Rangpur on Jan 11</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-rahman-to-visit-bogura-rangpur-on-jan-11</link><description>BNP leaders and activists say Acting Chairperson Tarique Rahman is preparing to visit Bogura on January 11.
The decision was taken at a meeting initiated by the Bogura district committee on Monday, said Kalam Azad, BNP spokesperson in charge of Rajshahi and Rangpur Divisions.
In addition to the d</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 16:00:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt. to recruit over 67,000 teachers to fill vacant posts: Education Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-to-recruit-over-67000-teachers-to-fill-vacant-posts-education-adviser-education-adviser</link><description>Chowdhury Rafiqul Abrar on Monday said the interim government has decided to recruit more than 67,000 teachers to fill vacant posts in schools, colleges, madrasas and technical institutions across the country.
“The current interim government will leave behind a legacy of recruiting over 67,0</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 15:48:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>300 NCP activists join BNP in Ctg</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/alliance-with-jamaat-more-than-300-ncp-members-move-to-bnp</link><description>More than 300 National Citizen Party (NCP) members in Khagrachhari have joined the BNP due to the electoral alliance with Jamaat-e-Islami.
On Monday, the activists, led by former NCP Khagrachhari district organising secretary Biplob Tripura, arrived at the district BNP office to join the party.
K</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 16:03:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Israeli airstrike kills two in Gaza including girl, hospital staff say</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/israeli-airstrike-kills-two-in-gaza-including-girl-hospital-staff-say</link><description>Israel killed at least two Palestinians including a girl, and wounded four others including other children, in an airstrike on Khan Younis in the southern Gaza Strip on Monday, officials at the city’s main Nasser Hospital said.
The Israeli military said the strike, carried out in an area con</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 16:18:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>JnUCSU on the brink of maiden vote</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jagannath-university-on-the-cusp-of-first-ever-students-union-election</link><description>The Jagannath University Central Students’ Union (JnUCSU) and hall council elections, postponed by a week following the death of BNP chief Khaleda Zia, are finally set to take place.
Two decades after its inception as a university, students of the Old Dhaka institution will exercise their fr</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 16:33:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Obaidul Quader returns home in Kolkata after hospital treatment</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/obaidul-quader-returns-home-in-kolkata-after-hospital-treatment</link><description>Awami League General Secretary Obaidul Quader has returned to his residence in Kolkata after receiving two days of treatment at a local hospital.
Quader, who has been in India since the fall of the Sheikh Hasina government, was admitted to a hospital in Kolkata’s New Town after complaining o</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 16:48:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gold prices in Bangladesh jump nearly Tk 3,000 per bhori in 24 hours</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/gold-prices-in-bangladesh-jump-nearly-tk-3000-per-bhori-in-24-hours</link><description>Gold prices in Bangladesh rose sharply again within 24 hours as the Bangladesh Jewellers Association (BAJUS) on Monday increased the price by Tk 2,916 per bhori, following a hike a day earlier.
In a notification issued in the night, BAJUS fixed the price of 22-carat gold at Tk 227,856 per bhori (1</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 17:03:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DMP transfers one joint commissioner, 13 deputy commissioners</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dmp-transfers-one-joint-commissioner-13-deputy-commissioners</link><description>The Dhaka Metropolitan Police (DMP) has transferred one Joint Commissioner and 13 Deputy Commissioner (DC).
An office order signed by DMP Commissioner Sheikh Md Sajjat Ali was issued in this regard on Monday.
According to the order, Joint Commissioner (Current Charge) ASM Shamsur Rahman has been</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 17:18:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jubo Dal leader shot dead near home in Raozan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jubo-dal-leader-shot-dead-near-home-in-raozan</link><description>A Jubo Dal leader has been shot and killed near his home in Chattogram’s Raozan.
Police said the murder took place around 8:30pm on Monday in Raozan’s Purbo Guzra union.
The victim has been identified as Jane Alam Sikder, 48, a member of the Upazila chapter of Jatiyatabadi Jubo Dal. H</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 17:33:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Move on to get 10 SoEs, MNCs listed</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/move-on-to-get-10-soes-mncs-listed</link><description>A move advances to rope in 10 more entities having public shares to the stock market long starved of good stocks and facing frequent volatilities, officials say.
 Of the ten blue-chip companies, some are solely owned by government while some are multinationals wherein government has small sta</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 17:48:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A unique mix of public-private sector  economic dev introduced by ex-PM</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/a-unique-mix-of-public-private-sector-economic-dev-introduced-by-ex-pm</link><description>Begum Khaleda Zia blended public-and private-sector development in a way uniquely suited to Bangladesh, prioritising business growth while ensuring social responsibility, a commemorative meeting recalls. 
The International Chamber of Commerce (ICC) Bangladesh organised the 'Memorial and Dua M</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 18:03:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Stocks, bonds and oil steady as investors downplay Venezuela upheaval</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/stocks-bonds-and-oil-steady-as-investors-downplay-venezuela-upheaval</link><description>Stocks edged up, bonds steadied and oil prices held firm on Monday as investors reacted calmly to potential market ramifications of the US capture of Venezuelan President Nicolas Maduro.
A STOXX benchmark of Europe's biggest companies rose 0.3 per cent while MSCI's broadest index of Asia-Pacific s</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 18:18:33 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>