<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 16:31:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Bangladesh Bank set to issue 7th investment sukuk bond worth Tk 25b</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh-bank-set-to-issue-7th-investment-sukuk-bond-worth-tk-25b</link><description>The Bangladesh Bank is preparing to issue the 7th ‘Bangladesh Government Investment Sukuk’ (Islamic bond) valued at Tk 25 billion (Tk 2,500 crore).
The Sukuk is aimed at funding the Important Rural Infrastructure Development Project for Noakhali, Feni, and Lakshmipur (IRIDPNFL) distric</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 14:43:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Probe report in BB reserve heist case on December 8</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/probe-report-in-bb-reserve-heist-case-on-december-8</link><description>A Dhaka court on Tuesday set December 8 to submit a probe report in the case lodged over the Bangladesh Bank (BB) reserve heist that took place in 2016.
Dhaka Additional Chief Metropolitan Magistrate Zakir Hossain set the new date as the investigation agency, the Criminal Investigation Department</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 13:28:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Now test Islami Andolan Bangladesh in power by voting for ‘hand-fan’: Faizul Karim</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/now-test-islami-andolan-bangladesh-in-power-by-voting-for-hand-fan-faizul-karim</link><description>With the national election approaching, Senior Naib-e-Ameer of Islami Andolan Bangladesh (IAB), Mufti Syed Muhammad Faizul Karim has called on voters to test the party's ruling process in the upcoming election by casting their vote for its symbol, the hand-fan.
He made the appeal during a mass gat</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 13:43:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EU says it could admit new members by 2030, praises Montenegro, Albania, Ukraine</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/eu-says-it-could-admit-new-members-by-2030-praises-montenegro-albania-ukraine</link><description>The European Commission said on Tuesday that the EU could welcome new members as early as 2030 as it praised Montenegro, Albania, Ukraine and Moldova for their progress on reforms needed to join the bloc.
The Commission also criticised Serbia for slowing down its reform process. It accused Georgia</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 13:58:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pubali Bank donates a microbus to Bangladesh Medical College</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/pubali-bank-donates-a-microbus-to-bangladesh-medical-college</link><description>Pubali Bank PLC has donated a microbus to Bangladesh Medical College as part of its social responsibility, according to a press release.
Mohammad Ali, Managing Director and CEO of Pubali Bank PLC, was present as chief guest at the event organised at the auditorium of Bangladesh Medical College and</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 14:13:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ONE Bank holds training on prevention of money laundering, combating financing of terrorism</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/one-bank-holds-training-on-prevention-of-money-laundering-combating-financing-of-terrorism</link><description>ONE Bank arranged a day-long training on “Prevention of Money Laundering &amp; Combating Financing of Terrorism" on November 01, 2025, at Hotel Momo Inn, Bogura, according to a press release.
The training was arranged for the executives &amp; officers of branches and sub-branches of Rajshahi Zone. M</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 14:28:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka Bank signs strategic payroll banking partnership with Sparkle Knit Composite</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/dhaka-bank-signs-strategic-payroll-banking-partnership-with-sparkle-knit-composite</link><description>Dhaka Bank PLC entered into a Payroll Banking Agreement with Sparkle Knit Composite Limited. The signing ceremony took place at the corporate head office of Sparkle Knit Composite Limited recently, according to a press release.
The agreement was formally exchanged by Mr. H. M. Mostafizur Rahaman,</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 14:43:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How a two-day insurance claim settlement secures future of Nazmun Nahar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/how-a-two-day-insurance-claim-settlement-secures-future-of-nazmun-nahar</link><description>In the BRAC Bank conference room, young Nabil sat with his face buried in his mother Nazmun Nahar's shoulder. Barely four, the child, currently recovering from a low-grade fever, occasionally looked up at his mother, seemingly unaware of the significance of the meeting.
Having lost her husband, Ar</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 15:13:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AL urges UN to halt election support</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/awami-league-calls-for-suspension-of-undp-assistance-in-parliamentary-election</link><description>The Awami League, which is banned from conducting political activities and cannot participate in the next general election, has appealed to the United Nations to refrain from supporting polls in Bangladesh.
On Saturday, the party sent a letter to Stefan Liller, representative of the United Nations</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 15:28:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bomb explodes outside NCP leader’s office</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crude-bomb-explodes-outside-ncp-leaders-office-in-shariatpur</link><description>A crude bomb has exploded outside the private office of a National Citizen Party (NCP) leader in Shariatpur, triggering panic in the locality.
The blast occurred around Monday night near the municipal Eidgah ground beside the office of Sabuj Talukder, the district NCP’s senior joint coordina</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 15:43:29 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>