<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 13:26:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Trust Bank, BFIU unite to bolster anti-money laundering efforts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/trust-bank-bfiu-unite-to-bolster-anti-money-laundering-efforts</link><description>A regional workshop titled “Proactive Transaction Monitoring – Finding Key Indicators for Detecting Money Laundering” was held on November 12, 2025, at City Hotel, Cox’s Bazar.
The event was organized by the Bangladesh Financial Intelligence Unit (BFIU) and hosted by Trust</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 10:45:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Restriction of vehicular movement inside cantonment on Nov 21</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/restriction-of-vehicular-movement-inside-cantonment-on-nov-21</link><description>Restrictions have been imposed on vehicular movement inside the Dhaka Cantonment on November 21, marking Armed Forces Day, according to a release from the Inter-Services Public Relations (ISPR) this afternoon.
To keep the roads of Dhaka Cantonment (main road from Shaheed Jahangir Gate to the Staff</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 11:00:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Robust auditing, governance crucial for future of Islamic finance: BB chief</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/robust-auditing-governance-crucial-for-future-of-islamic-finance-bb-chief</link><description>Bangladesh Bank (BB) Governor Ahsan H Mansur on Sunday said that the future growth and stability of Bangladesh’s Islamic banking sector are dependent upon the implementation of robust accounting, governance, and auditing practices.
“Adherence to high auditing standards is crucial for m</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 11:15:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No level playing field due to three advisors’ ‘misleading role’, say eight religion-based parties</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/no-level-playing-field-due-to-three-advisors-misleading-role-say-eight-religion-based-parties</link><description>The leaders of eight religion-based parties have said “misguidance” from three interim government advisors is hindering the level playing field.
On Sunday, Jamaat-e-Islami Secretary General Mia Golam Porwar, on behalf of the eight parties, announced that their movement will continue un</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 11:30:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AB Bank inaugurates its relocated Kakrail Branch</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ab-bank-inaugurates-its-relocated-kakrail-branch</link><description>AB Bank PLC. has recently relocated its Kakrail Branch to 82, Kakrail Road, Ramna, Dhaka.
Mr. Syed Mizanur Rahman, Managing Director &amp; CEO, AB Bank, inaugurated the new premises with all modern banking facilities, according to a media release. 
Officials of the bank, along with valued client</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 11:45:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt secrecy blocks disclosure: Salehuddin</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/government-secrecy-prevents-disclosure-of-many-developments-adviser-salehuddin-says</link><description>Finance Adviser Salehuddin Ahmed has responded to claims that “nothing is happening”, saying many developments cannot be revealed because of government-imposed “secrecy”.
Speaking at the national award ceremony for DRU’s Best Special Report of the Year on Sunday, he s</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 12:00:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dengue: 5 more die; 1139 hospitalised in 24 hours</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dengue-5-more-die-1139-hospitalised-in-24-hours</link><description>Five more deaths were reported from dengue in 24 hours till Sunday morning, raising the number of fatalities from the mosquito-borne disease in Bangladesh to 336 this year.
During the same period, 1139 new patients were admitted to hospitals, raising the total number of dengue cases this year to 8</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 11:45:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ULAB to host Dartmouth College Professor Dr David A Peterson as Senior Fellow in Linguistics</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/ulab-to-host-dartmouth-college-professor-dr-david-a-peterson-as-senior-fellow-in-linguistics</link><description>The University of Liberal Arts Bangladesh (ULAB) will welcome Dr. David A. Peterson, Associate Professor of Linguistics at Dartmouth College, USA, as a Senior Fellow in Linguistics at the Department of English and Humanities from 17 to 27 November 2025 in the Fall 2025 term.
Dr. Peterson is a glob</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 12:00:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DMP chief orders officers to open fire on anyone attacking police with bombs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/dmp-chief-orders-officers-to-open-fire-on-anyone-attacking-police-with-bombs</link><description>Dhaka Metropolitan Police Commissioner Sheikh Md Sazzat Ali has authorised officers to open fire on anyone throwing crude bombs at police from motorcycles.
The directive comes amid mixed reactions to a similar order issued five days ago by the chief of Chittagong Metropolitan Police.
On Sunday, t</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 12:15:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC to sit with Jamaat, 11 other political parties Monday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ec-to-sit-with-jamaat-11-other-political-parties-monday</link><description>The Election Commission is set to sit with 12 more political parties, including Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami, on Monday as part of its electoral dialogue ahead of the next general election to be held in early February 2026.
The Commission will exchange views with six parties in the morning session a</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 12:30:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Lawyer files petition seeking enhanced protection for lower court judges</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/lawyer-files-petition-seeking-enhanced-protection-for-lower-court-judges</link><description>A Supreme Court lawyer has filed a petition seeking directives to strengthen security for judges serving in the lower courts.
The petition was submitted on Sunday by lawyer Yunus Ali Akond, bdnews24.com reports.
He told bdnews24.com that the petition seeks orders to improve security at judges&amp;rsq</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 12:45:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>23.1pc growth of remittance inflow till Nov 15</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/231pc-growth-of-remittance-inflow-till-nov-15</link><description>Inflow of remittances witnessed a year-on-year growth of 23.1 percent reaching US$1,523 million in the 15 days of November, according to the latest data of Bangladesh Bank (BB) issued.
Last year, during the same period, the country’s remittance inflow was $1,237 million.
During the July to</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 13:00:45 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>