<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 16:33:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Two killed, seven injured in clash between rival groups in Cumilla</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/two-killed-seven-injured-in-clash-between-rival-groups-in-cumilla</link><description>At least two people were killed and seven others injured in a violent clash between two rival groups over local dominance in Nangalkot upazila of Cumilla on Friday. Officer-in-Charge of Nangalkot Police Station Arifur Rahman confirmed the incident.
The incident took place around 12:30pm in Aliyara</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 13:03:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Citizens' personal data is a trust deposited with entrepreneurs: Taiyeb</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/citizens-personal-data-is-a-trust-deposited-with-entrepreneurs-taiyeb</link><description>Special Assistant to the Chief Adviser on the Ministry of Posts, Telecommunications and Information Technology Faiz Ahmed Taiyeb today said that the personal data of service seekers is a trust deposited with entrepreneurs, and any uncoordinated or improper handling of such data could pose serious s</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 13:18:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Iran crisis could ‘reshape’ India’s regional calculus</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/iran-upheaval-threatens-to-weaken-india-while-strengthening-pakistan-china</link><description>India has been watching developments in Iran with growing unease as protests and economic pressures have shaken the country’s clerical leadership, raising fears that regime change could undermine New Delhi’s longstanding regional strategy, NDTV reports.
India and Iran have shared deep</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 13:33:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NPA debuts as political platform</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/npa-debuts-as-political-platform</link><description>Network for People’s Action (NPA) has made its debut in Dhaka, promising to engage youth and professionals in politics.
On Friday afternoon, former Dhaka University student Mir Hojaifa Al Mamduh formally announced the platform at the Central Shaheed Minar.
He also revealed that NPA will hav</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 13:48:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>People’s power must increase at cost of state power: Amir Khasru</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/peoples-power-must-increase-at-cost-of-state-power-amir-khasru</link><description>BNP Standing Committee member Amir Khasru Mahmud Chowdhury on Friday said that the power of the state should be reduced while empowering the people.
He warned that excessive state power creates difficulties for citizens and can lead to fascism, stressing that every citizen must be strong, UNB repo</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 14:03:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Adilur urges people to vote ‘Yes’ in referendum</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/adilur-urges-people-to-vote-yes-in-referendum</link><description>Housing and Public Works and Local Government, Rural Development and Cooperatives Adviser Adilur Rahman Khan on Friday urged people to vote 'Yes' in Referendum 2026.
"I urged everyone to vote 'Yes' in the referendum in favour of the July National Charter, so that fascism and fallen tyranny can nev</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 14:18:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Deliberate negligence’ in Khaleda’s treatment: Dr FM Siddiqui</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/deliberate-negligence-in-khaledas-treatment-dr-fm-siddiqui</link><description>Dr FM Siddiqui, one of the physicians who treated Khaleda Zia, has demanded an investigation into what he described as “deliberate negligence” in her medical care at the Bangladesh Medical University.
He raised the allegation on Friday while speaking at a citizens’ condolence mee</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 14:33:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jubo Dal leader held over petrol pump worker’s death in Rajbari</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/jubo-dal-leader-held-over-petrol-pump-workers-death-in-rajbari</link><description>Rajbari police have arrested former district Jubo Dal president Abul Hashem Sujan and his driver Kamal Hossain over the death of a petrol pump worker allegedly run over by their vehicle.
The victim, Ripon Saha, 32, worked at Karim Filling Station near Goalanda Mor.
Police said he was crushed outs</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 14:48:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Finance adviser urges patience on new pay scale, backs referendum</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/finance-adviser-urges-patience-on-new-pay-scale-backs-referendum</link><description>Finance Ministry Adviser Dr. Salehuddin Ahmed on Friday asked government officials to be patient regarding the new pay scale.
He said the pay scale has been prepared after 10 years.
“There are many calculations. A committee has been formed. They are working. After the committee submits its</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 15:03:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fire guts 26 rooms in Gazipur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/fire-guts-26-rooms-in-gazipur</link><description>A fire broke out at a residential colony in Kashimpur area of Gazipur on Friday morning, destroying at least 26 rooms.
The incident occurred in a colony owned by a man named Biplob, located near GMS Garments factory in Sardaganj area of Kashimpur.
On receiving information, a unit of DBL Fire Serv</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 15:18:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP chief Tarique holds virtual meeting with US trade delegation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-chief-tarique-holds-virtual-meeting-with-us-trade-delegation</link><description>BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman has met with a United States trade delegation to discuss bilateral trade, tariffs and future economic cooperation, the party said.
The meeting was held on Friday morning via video call from his residence in Gulshan, according to the BNP Media Cell.
The US delegation, h</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 15:33:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Africa Cup of Nations commercial revenue up by 90%, says CAF</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/africa-cup-of-nations-commercial-revenue-up-by-90-says-caf</link><description>The Confederation of African Football said it has had a 90 percent increase in commercial revenue for the Africa Cup of Nations in Morocco, calling it “the most successful commercial story in the history of African football” but without providing any figures.
CAF said on Friday this wa</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 15:48:51 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>