<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 17:18:40 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Prime Bank Partners with JBS Holdings to offer exclusive discounts on flat purchases</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/prime-bank-partners-with-jbs-holdings-to-offer-exclusive-discounts-on-flat-purchases</link><description>Prime Bank PLC has entered into a strategic partnership with JBS Holdings Limited, one of Bangladesh’s most reputed real estate developers, to offer exclusive discounts on flat purchases for its valued customers.
A formal signing ceremony marking this collaboration was recently held at JBS H</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 14:57:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Devil Hunt Phase-2: 16 arrested in Naogaon</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/devil-hunt-phase-2-16-arrested-in-naogaon</link><description>Police have arrested 16 more people in Naogaon in the last 24 hours as part of the ongoing ‘Devil Hunt Phase-2’ operation, police said on Saturday.
All the arrestees are leaders and activists of different organs and affiliated bodies of the Awami League, whose activities have been bann</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 15:28:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sirajganj man dies as boat capsizes enroute to Italy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/sirajganj-man-dies-as-boat-capsizes-enroute-to-italy</link><description>A man from Ullapara Upazila in Sirajganj has died while attempting to “illegally” migrate to Italy through the Mediterranean, with his family alleging he was killed and his body dumped at sea.
The family of Rakib Hossain Swadhin, 23, says they are still awaiting the return of his body,</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 15:43:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DUCSU demands renaming of two halls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/ducsu-demands-renaming-of-two-halls</link><description>The Dhaka University Central Students’ Union (DUCSU) has announced a programme to besiege the vice-chancellor’s office, demanding the renaming of Bangabandhu Sheikh Mujibur Rahman Hall.
It wants the hall to be rechristened as Shaheed Osman Hadi Hall.
The student body also demanded tha</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 15:58:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rally, torch procession over Udichi office attack</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rally-torch-procession-held-in-dhaka-over-attacks-on-udichi-chhayanaut-media-houses</link><description>A section of Udichi Shilpigosthi has organised a cultural rally in Dhaka in protest against what it describes as “planned criminal attacks”, vandalism and arson targeting the organisation’s central office, Chhayanaut, Prothom Alo, The Daily Star and other sites across Bangladesh.</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 15:13:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Absentee funeral prayer for Hadi in Ctg</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/absentee-funeral-prayer-protest-rally-held-for-hadi-in-chattogram</link><description>People from different walks of life, including students, have participated in the funeral prayer in absentia held for Inqilab Moncho Convenor Sharif Osman bin Hadi in Chattogram.
The biggest funeral was held at the city’s Laldighi field on Saturday, where several thousand people took part.</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 15:28:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Brazil's Lula warns US intervention in Venezuela could be catastrophic</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/brazils-lula-warns-us-intervention-in-venezuela-could-be-catastrophic</link><description>Brazilian President Luiz Inacio Lula da Silva said on Saturday that an "armed intervention in Venezuela would be a humanitarian catastrophe" in the face of escalating actions from the United States toward regional neighbor Venezuela.
On Tuesday, US President Donald Trump ordered a "blockade" of al</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 15:43:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Extremist groups attempting anarchy: education advisor</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/extremist-reckless-groups-trying-to-create-anarchy-across-bangladesh-says-education-advisor</link><description>Education Advisor CR Abrar has said some “extremist, reckless groups” are trying to create anarchy and lawlessness across Bangladesh by taking advantage of the murder of Inqilab Moncho Convenor Sharif Osman bin Hadi.
He also condemned the attack and arson on the offices of two newspape</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 15:58:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Lebanon nears Hezbollah disarmament south of Litani: PM</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/lebanon-close-to-completing-disarmament-of-hezbollah-south-of-litani-river-says-pm</link><description>Lebanon is close to completing the disarmament of Hezbollah south of the Litani River, Prime Minister Nawaf Salam said on Saturday, as the country races to fulfil a key demand of its ceasefire with Israel before a year-end deadline.
The US-backed ceasefire, agreed in November 2024, ended more than</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 16:13:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CBDCs &amp; stablecoins: set to redefine financial system</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/cbdcs-stablecoins-set-to-redefine-financial-system</link><description>Every day, millions of people and businesses send money across borders - and wait. A remittance can take days to arrive, fees quietly erode income, and trillions of dollars remain locked in correspondent banking systems designed decades ago for a slower, analogue economy. For developing countries,</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 16:28:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Impact of meditation on health</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/impact-of-meditation-on-health</link><description>There is growing interest in the application of and research on meditation observing its beneficial effects on mental and physical health. There are around 275 million people practicing meditation in the world. In the United States of America (USA), 61 million people meditate and in United Kingdom</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 16:43:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>My brief brush with Osman Hadi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/reviews/my-brief-brush-with-osman-hadi</link><description>In the aftermath of last year’s anti-Hasina uprising in Bangladesh, several student leaders emerged from obscurity, propelled by a mix of anger and a demand for justice. Sharif Osman Hadi was one of them.
I first encountered Osman Hadi in September 2024 at the TSC junction of Dhaka Universit</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 16:58:42 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>