<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 11:18:26 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Tanzania's Hassan sworn into office after deadly election violence</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/africa/tanzanias-hassan-sworn-into-office-after-deadly-election-violence</link><description>Tanzania President Samia Suluhu Hassan was sworn into office on Monday for her first elected term after winning a landslide victory in an election that set off deadly protests across the country.
 
Hassan, who came to power in 2021 following the death in office of her predecessor, was declar</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 08:18:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Worker ‘denied leave’ dies, colleagues stage blockade</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/worker-denied-leave-dies-colleagues-stage-blockade</link><description>Workers of a garment factory in Narayanganj have blocked the Dhaka-Chattogram Highway following the death of one of their female colleagues.
They allege the woman had sought leave from the factory owners due to illness, but it was not approved. She was then compelled to work while sick and died, r</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 09:03:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Police block non-MPO teachers marching to Secretariat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/police-block-teachers-marching-to-secretariat-to-demand-mpo-inclusion</link><description>Police have blocked a march toward the Secretariat by teachers demanding the inclusion of all government-recognised non-Monthly Pay Order educational institutions under the MPO system.
Police obstructed the march in the Jatiya Press Club area on Monday afternoon. The teachers had been staging a si</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 09:18:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Faith-based coalition wants Yunus as ‘referee’ in referendum talks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/eight-religious-parties-urge-yunus-to-mediate-dialogue-on-july-charter-referendum-dispute</link><description>Eight faith-based political parties have called on Chief Advisor Muhammad Yunus to act as a “referee” in a dialogue among political groups over the implementation of the July Charter and the holding of a referendum.
The parties’ appeal came during a meeting of top leaders at the</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 09:33:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Central bank launches foreign exchange-Taka swap facility</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/central-bank-launches-foreign-exchange-taka-swap-facility</link><description>Bangladesh Bank (BB) on Monday introduced a new foreign exchange-Taka swap facility aimed at providing exporters with short-term working capital without requiring them to liquidate their foreign currency earnings.
The central bank’s Foreign Exchange Policy Department issued a circular author</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 09:48:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AB Bank inaugurates collection booth at Mirpur BCIC College</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ab-bank-inaugurates-collection-booth-at-mirpur-bcic-college</link><description>AB Bank PLC has inaugurated a dedicated collection booth at Mirpur BCIC College to provide comprehensive and modern banking services.
Operated under the Bank’s Mirpur Branch, the booth will facilitate all types of financial collections for the college and offer payroll services to its teache</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 10:03:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Reform must begin at the design level: Lutfey Siddiqi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/reform-must-begin-at-the-design-level-lutfey-siddiqi</link><description>Bangladesh needs reform from the design level, said Lutfey Siddiqi, Special Envoy on International Affairs to the Chief Adviser, emphasising that fundamental flaws in administrative design continue to hold back progress despite recent achievements.
Speaking at a roundtable discussion on “Bus</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 10:18:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Charukola Animation Festival celebrates young animators</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/article/charukola-animation-festival-celebrates-young-animators-1</link><description>At Charukola, where brushes and colours ruled the whole canvas, something different has happened this time- the art began to move. Sketches turned into stories, and drawings came to life. The Faculty of Fine Arts recently came alive with colours, motions in frame, where every motion is crafted with</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 10:33:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Investment climate reforms vital for Bangladesh's growth, experts say</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/investment-climate-reforms-vital-for-bangladeshs-growth-experts-say</link><description>Strategic reforms in Bangladesh's investment climate will be pivotal for achieving sustainable higher-middle-income status, economists and business leaders agreed at a roundtable discussion hosted by The Financial Express on Monday.
The event, titled "Business Climate: Reforms, Opportunities, and</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 10:48:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UCB opens its 232nd Branch in Hajiganj</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ucb-opens-its-232nd-branch-in-hajiganj</link><description>With a commitment to providing the best and most modern banking services, United Commercial Bank PLC (UCB) has inaugurated its 232nd branch in Hajiganj, Chandpur.
UCB’s Managing Director and CEO, Mohammad Mamdudur Rashid, officially inaugurated the new branch at a gathering of distinguished</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 11:03:26 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>