<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 15:26:44 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Probe report submission on cenbank heist deferred to Jan 13</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/probe-report-submission-on-bangladesh-bank-reserve-heist-deferred-to-jan-13</link><description>A Dhaka court on Monday deferred the date for submitting the investigation report in the case filed over the Bangladesh Bank reserve heist to January 13.
Dhaka Metropolitan Magistrate Jashita Islam fixed the date as the Criminal Investigation Department failed to submit the report for the 91</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 11:45:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC’s IDEA project employees demand job regularisation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ecs-idea-project-employees-demand-job-regularisation</link><description>The employees of the Election Commission’s ‘Identification System for Enhancing Access to Services (IDEA) Project-Phase II’ on Monday formed a human chain in front of Nirbachan Bhaban, demanding their jobs to be regularised and shifted from outsourcing to the government’s re</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 12:00:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UN cuts its aid appeal for 2026 despite soaring need</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/un-cuts-its-aid-appeal-for-2026-despite-soaring-need</link><description>The United Nations appealed on Monday for a 2026 aid budget only half the size of what it had hoped for this year, acknowledging a plunge in donor funding at a time when humanitarian needs have never been greater.
By its own admission, the $23 billion U.N. appeal will shut out tens of millions of</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 12:15:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>100 abducted children ‘rescued’ in Nigeria</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nigeria-rescues-100-children-abducted-from-catholic-school-christian-group-says</link><description>Nigeria's government has rescued 100 schoolchildren who were abducted last month from St. Mary's Catholic School in central Nigeria in one of the country's biggest mass kidnappings to date, a Christian group said on Monday.
Nigerian authorities have yet to comment publicly on the rescue, and it wa</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 12:30:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nation already in ‘a form of debt trap’: NBR chairman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/nation-already-in-a-form-of-debt-trap-nbr-chairman</link><description>National Board of Revenue (NBR) Chairman Md Abdur Rahman Khan on Monday said Bangladesh has already slipped into a form of debt trap, and the nation must confront this uncomfortable truth if it wants to restore stability.
“Despite wide-ranging debates on growth, inflation and economic manage</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 12:45:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>White supremacy notion threatens South Africa's sovereignty, president says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/africa/white-supremacy-notion-threatens-south-africas-sovereignty-president-says</link><description>Ideas of white racial superiority are a threat to South Africa's post-apartheid unity, its sovereignty and its diplomatic relations, President Cyril Ramaphosa said on Monday, calling for global efforts to debunk false stories about white persecution.
Ramaphosa was speaking at a conference of the c</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 13:00:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Handset registration: Manufacturers call for NEIR implementation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/handset-registration-manufacturers-call-for-neir-implementation</link><description>The Mobile Phone Industry Owners Association of Bangladesh (MIOB) has called for the implementation of the National Equipment Identity Register (NEIR), saying it will strengthen mobile phone security and increase government revenue.
They made the demand at a media briefing at Dhaka Reporters Unity</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 13:15:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat to form national govt even if it wins 200 seats: Ameer</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-to-form-national-govt-even-if-it-wins-200-seats-ameer</link><description>Jamaat Ameer Dr Shafiqur Rahman on Monday said his party intends to form a national government if it comes to power, even if it secures 200 parliamentary seats independently, aiming to safeguard national interest and ensure political stability.
He made the remarks while briefing reporters after pa</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 13:30:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>47 Indian fishermen released from Bagerhat jail</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/47-indian-fishermen-released-from-bagerhat-jail</link><description>Forty-seven Indian fishermen released from Bagerhat District Jail will be handed over to the Indian Coast Guard on Tuesday.
Following a court order, jail authorities handed them over to the Bangladesh Coast Guard on Sunday afternoon in the presence of officials from the Indian High Commission, an</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 13:45:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Over 258,000 Bangladeshi expats already registered to vote</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/over-258000-bangladeshi-expats-already-registered-to-vote</link><description>More than 258,000 expatriate Bangladeshi voters from different countries across the world have so far registered through a mobile app, ‘Postal Vote Bd’, since November 19 last to vote in the upcoming national election and the referendum.
The Election Commission (EC) on November 19 open</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 14:00:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shakib hopes to return for a full home series before retirement</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/shakib-hopes-to-return-for-a-full-home-series-before-retirement</link><description>Shakib Al Hasan, who lives out of country after the fall of his political party Awami League from the government facing a mass uprising last year, has said he remains hopeful of playing for Bangladesh again and wants to end his international career with a full series on home soil across all three f</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 14:15:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>2 more die of dengue, 455 hospitalised in 24 hours</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/2-more-die-of-dengue-455-hospitalised-in-24-hours</link><description>Two more deaths were reported from dengue in 24 hours till Monday morning, raising the number of fatalities from the mosquito-borne disease in Bangladesh to 398 this year.
The new fatalities were reported in Dhaka South City Corporation (DSCC), according to the Directorate General of Health Servic</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 14:30:42 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>