<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 14:19:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Ex-BNP lawmaker Akhtaruzzaman calls Jamaat a ‘patriotic political party’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ex-bnp-lawmaker-akhtaruzzaman-calls-jamaat-a-patriotic-political-party</link><description>Freedom fighter and former BNP lawmaker Akhtaruzzaman has described the Jamaat-e-Islami as a “patriotic party” after joining the party.
The retired Army major made the comments in a telephone interview with bdnews24.com on Saturday.
Asked why he had joined Jamaat, he criticised statem</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 11:15:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Karnaphuli Paper Mill resumes production after 4-day shutdown</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/karnaphuli-paper-mill-resumes-production-after-4-day-shutdown</link><description>Karnaphuli Paper Mill (KPM), a nationalised paper manufacturing company located at Chandraghona in Kaptai upazila of Chattogram district, resumed its production on Saturday morning following a four-day shutdown caused by a technical fault.
KPM Managing Director (MD) Shahid Ullah confirmed the deve</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 11:30:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BGB steps up border searches to block escape of Hadi shooters</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bgb-steps-up-border-searches-to-block-escape-of-hadi-shooters</link><description>The Border Guard Bangladesh (BGB) has intensified security and search operations along the Benapole border in Jashore to prevent those involved in the attempted killing of Inquilab Mancha Convenor Sharif Osman bin Hadi from fleeing the country.
On Saturday, the Jashore-49 BGB Battalion said strict</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 11:45:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rizvi calls gun attack on Hadi a planned conspiracy, seeks fair probe</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/rizvi-calls-gun-attack-on-hadi-a-planned-conspiracy-seeks-fair-probe</link><description>BNP Senior Joint Secretary General Ruhul Kabir Rizvi on Saturday described the gun attack on Dhaka-8 independent candidate Sharif Osman Hadi as a well-planned conspiracy and demanded exemplary punishment for the real perpetrators through a proper investigation.
“This is a planned conspiracy</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 12:00:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>All students nationwide will get new textbooks on Jan 1: Advisor Bidhan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/all-students-nationwide-will-get-new-textbooks-on-jan-1-advisor-bidhan</link><description>Students across Bangladesh will receive new textbooks on Jan 1, Primary and Mass Education Advisor Bidhan Ranjan Roy Poddar has said.
He confirmed the development on Saturday after attending a ceremony at the National Academy for Primary Education (NEP) in Mymensingh, bdnews24.com reports.</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 12:15:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Arsonists attempt to set Pirojpur EC office on fire</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/arsonists-attempt-to-set-pirojpur-ec-office-on-fire</link><description>An attempt was made to set the office of the Upazila election officer on fire in Pirojpur’s Mathbaria on Saturday morning.
Mathbaria Police chief Sheikh Helal Uddin confirmed media about the attempt.
Some unidentified individuals tried to pour petrol into the office by breaking a window on</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 12:30:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CA meets family of Hadi, vows justice and full medical support</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ca-meets-family-of-hadi-vows-justice-and-full-medical-support</link><description>Bangladesh’s interim chief adviser, Professor Muhammad Yunus, has met the family of Sharif Osman Hadi, a political activist and prospective parliamentary candidate who was critically wounded in a shooting widely seen as a test of the country’s fragile post-uprising transition.
The meet</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 12:45:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique warns of 'ongoing' election conspiracy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-says-conspiracies-are-under-way-to-disrupt-parliamentary-polls</link><description>Tarique Rahman has warned that the conspirators have not stopped and that holding the parliamentary elections will "not be easy".
The BNP acting chief made the remarks while attending a workshop virtually from London.
“I have said earlier that holding an election will not be so easy. The co</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 13:00:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>With Fed independence in crosshairs, will Supreme Court back Trump again?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/with-fed-independence-in-crosshairs-will-supreme-court-back-trump-again</link><description>The US Supreme Court's conservative justices appear ready to endorse President Donald Trump's power to fire a regulatory agency official despite job protections given by Congress. But they have signaled reluctance to give him similar authority over the Federal Reserve in a major case set to be argu</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 13:15:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mirza Abbas calls attack on Hadi part of wider conspiracy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/mirza-abbas-calls-attack-on-hadi-part-of-wider-conspiracy</link><description>BNP senior leader Mirza Abbas on Saturday described the gun attack on Inqilab Mancha convener Sharif Osman bin Hadi ahead of the election as a small part of a larger conspiracy, not an isolated incident.
“This is not an isolated incident. First Ershad Ullah was attacked in Chattogram, now Ha</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 13:30:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US, Ukraine to discuss ceasefire in Berlin ahead of European summit</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-ukraine-to-discuss-ceasefire-in-berlin-ahead-of-european-summit</link><description>Germany will host US and Ukrainian delegations over the weekend for talks on a ceasefire in Ukraine, ahead of a summit with European leaders and President Volodymyr Zelensky in Berlin on Monday, a German official said on Saturday.
A US official said overnight that President Donald Trump's envoy St</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 13:45:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Midland Bank inaugurates Saidpur Sub Branch</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/midland-bank-inaugurates-saidpur-sub-branch</link><description>Midland Bank PLC (MDB) inaugurated its Saidpur Sub-Branch at Sahid Dr. Zikrul Haque Plaza (1st floor), Dr. Zikrul Haque Road, Saidpur, Nilphamari on December 11, 2025, according to a press release.
Md. Ahsan-uz Zaman, Managing Director &amp; CEO of the bank, inaugurated the Branch as Chief Guest along</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 14:00:45 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>