<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 09:16:38 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>BNP leader Gayeshwar Chandra Roy acquitted in graft case</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-leader-gayeshwar-chandra-roy-acquitted-in-graft-case</link><description>A Dhaka court has acquitted BNP National Standing Committee Member Gayeshwar Chandra Roy in a case over illegal acquisition of assets filed 16 years ago.
The court of Dhaka Special Judge Kamrul Hasan Khan delivered its verdict on Sunday, clearing Gayeshwar as the charges against him were not prove</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 07:30:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Israel continues heavy bombardment in Gaza despite Trump’s call to halt strikes;70 dead</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/israel-continues-heavy-bombardment-in-gaza-despite-trumps-call-to-halt-strikes70-dead</link><description>Israeli airstrikes across the Gaza Strip killed at least 70 Palestinians on Saturday, according to medical sources, even after US President Donald Trump urged Israel to stop its assault following Hamas's partial acceptance of his 20-point plan to end the war.
At least 45 of those killed died in Ga</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 07:11:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>22 bhories of gold looted from Manikganj shop, owner assaulted</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/22-bhories-of-gold-looted-from-manikganj-shop-owner-assaulted</link><description>Robbers looted around 22 bhories of gold from a jewellery shop in the Paschim Dashra area of Manikganj Sadar upazila and assaulted the jeweller late Saturday night.
Police said two robbers entered the ground-floor shop, ‘Abhi Alankar,’ located in Pandav Bhaban, around 12:15 am.
They t</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 07:41:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Multiple proposals in pipeline if July Charter not agreed: Prof Riaz</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/multiple-proposals-in-pipeline-if-july-charter-not-agreed-prof-riaz</link><description>NCC Vice-Chair Prof Ali Riaz said on Sunday that the Commission will submit several proposals to the government on implementing the July National Charter 2025 if political parties fail to reach a consensus.
"If the political parties cannot agree on how to implement the July Charter, the Commission</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 08:11:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fascist, their cohorts behind conspiracy to unsettle CHT: Home adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fascist-their-cohorts-behind-conspiracy-to-unsettle-cht-destroy-communal-harmony-home-adviser</link><description>Adviser to the Ministry of Home Affairs Lt Gen (Retd) Md Jahangir Alam Chowdhury on Sunday said that fascist elements and their cohorts are behind the conspiracy to create unrest in the Chittagong Hill Tracts (CHT) region and to ruin communal harmony by adding a beard to the face of ‘Oshur&amp;rs</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 08:41:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Petition filed to detain NSU student Apurbo in jail</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/petition-filed-to-detain-nsu-student-apurbo-in-jail</link><description>Police have petitioned to have North South University (NSU) student Apurbo Pal detained in jail over allegations of “insulting the Quran”.
Sub-Inspector Chand Mia of Vatara Police Station, the investigating officer in the case, filed the petition in court on Sunday, reports bdnews24.co</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 09:11:03 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>