<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 05:28:37 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>BNP forms 41-member election steering committee</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-forms-41-member-election-steering-committee</link><description>The BNP on Thursday formed a 41-member election steering committee to run its campaign for the upcoming 13th Jatiya Sangsad election.
According to a press release issued on Thursday night, BNP Standing Committee member Nazrul Islam Khan has been made the chairman of the committee, while Senior Joi</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 03:00:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka welcomes Beijing's statement on national election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dhaka-welcomes-beijings-statement-on-national-election</link><description>Bangladesh on Thursday warmly welcomed a recent statement by the Chinese government expressing its wish for a smooth general election in the country, reaffirming that the election is Bangladesh’s internal affair.
In a press statement, the Ministry of Foreign Affairs said Bangladesh deeply va</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 04:15:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IDRA overhauls CEO appointment rules to end leadership vacancies</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/idra-overhauls-ceo-appointment-rules-to-end-leadership-vacancies</link><description>The insurance sector regulator has amended rules to ease the appointment of chiefs to insurance companies, as the earlier eligibility criteria were tough to meet.
Insurance company representatives have welcomed the amendment to the Insurance Company (Chief Executive Officer Appointment and Removal</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 03:13:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ferry services resume on Paturia–Daulatdia route after 7-hour suspension</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ferry-services-resume-on-paturia-daulatdia-route-after-7-hour-suspension</link><description>Ferry operations on the Paturia–Daulatdia river route resumed at around 10:00 am on Friday after remaining suspended for seven hours due to dense fog.
Two ferries anchored mid-river during the suspension safely reached the terminals as visibility improved, allowing stranded vehicles to begin</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 03:28:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prof Yunus eyes return to professional life after polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/prof-yunus-eyes-return-to-professional-life-after-polls</link><description>Chief Adviser Muhammad Yunus has said he intends to return to his previous professional role following the general election.
Professor Yunus conveyed this desire to Sardar Ayaz Sadiq, speaker of Pakistan’s National Assembly, during a courtesy meeting at the State Guest House Jamuna on Wednes</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 03:43:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pakistan sees deadliest year in a decade as combat deaths surge 74pc in 2025: Report</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/pakistan-sees-deadliest-year-in-a-decade-with-combat-deaths-surging-74pc-in-2025-report</link><description>Pakistan experienced its deadliest year in over a decade in 2025 as combat-related deaths surged 74 per cent, with militants accounting for more than half the death toll, according to a new report released by an independent think tank.
Islamabad often accuses Kabul of turning a blind eye to cross-</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 03:58:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh stock market opens 2026 on positive note</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh-stock-market-opens-2026-on-positive-note</link><description>After a challenging year, the stock market entered the New Year on high hopes, as bargain hunters placed fresh bets on lucrative stocks on Thursday amid renewed optimism.
Market analysts said investors' optimism over evolving political developments offered some relief to the broadly subdued market</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 04:13:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Biman decides to buy 14 aircraft from Boeing</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/biman-decides-to-buy-14-aircraft-from-boeing</link><description>The Biman Bangladesh Airlines authorities have decided, in principle, to purchase 14 aircraft from the US aviation giant Boeing.
The decision was taken at the board meeting of the state-run airlines on Tuesday (December 30), according to a statement, issued by General Manager (public relations) of</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 04:28:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt lowers mobile handset duties from 25pc to 10pc, enforces NEIR</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/govt-lowers-mobile-handset-duties-from-25pc-to-10pc-enforces-neir</link><description>The government has slashed customs duty on mobile phone imports from 25 per cent to 10 per cent, marking a nearly 60 per cent reduction, as the National Equipment Identity Register (NEIR) officially came into operation on Thursday.
The decision was taken at a meeting of the Advisory Council, which</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 04:43:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ctg Port breaks all previous records in 2025</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ctg-port-breaks-all-previous-records-in-2025</link><description>CHATTOGRAM, Jan 01: Chittagong Port, the maritime gateway of Bangladesh, has achieved a historic milestone by handling the highest number of containers in 2025.
The prime seaport handled a total of 3.40 million (34,09,069) TEUs (20-foot equivalent units) of containers, 138.15 million (13,81,51,812</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 04:58:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>SAVINGS CERTIFICATE YIELDS CUT: Pensioners, elderly citizens see much-needed pittance squeeze</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/savings-certificate-yields-cut-pensioners-elderly-citizens-see-much-needed-pittance-squeeze</link><description>Pensioners and elderly citizens see red as their much-needed earnings from savings certificates squeeze for yield-rate cutbacks under government debt-servicing pressures, sources say.
The public debt buildups prompt the government to further lower yields on savings certificates in a belt-tightenin</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 05:13:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt cuts prices of diesel, kerosene, petrol, octane by Tk 2.0 per litre each</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/govt-cuts-prices-of-diesel-kerosene-petrol-octane-by-tk-20-per-litre-each</link><description>The government has cut the prices of diesel, kerosene, petrol and octane by Tk 2.0 per litre each to Tk 102 per litre, Tk 114 per litre, Tk 118 per litre and Tk 122 per litre respectively for the month of January under the automatic fuel pricing formula.
The previous pump price of diesel, kerosene</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 05:28:37 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>