<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 14:24:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Hasina responsible for Khaleda Zia’s critical condition: Rizvi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/hasina-responsible-for-khaleda-zias-critical-condition-rizvi</link><description>BNP Senior Joint Secretary General Ruhul Kabir Rizvi has alleged that BNP Chairperson and former Prime Minister Khaleda Zia’s deteriorating health is largely the result of actions taken by Awami League President and deposed Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina.
Rizvi said, “Begum Khaleda Zia i</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 11:36:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trust Bank signs MoU with CG Runner BD Limited</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/trust-bank-signs-mou-with-cg-runner-bd-limited</link><description>Trust Bank PLC. and CG Runner BD Limited, the official distributor of BYD Bangladesh recently signed an agreement at CG Runner BD Limited corporate office.
Under this agreement, BYD customers could avail Trust Bank Auto Loans at a special rate and waived processing fee along with other special val</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 11:51:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prime Bank hosts Annual Risk Conference 2025 to strengthen proactive risk culture</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/prime-bank-hosts-annual-risk-conference-2025-to-strengthen-proactive-risk-culture</link><description>Prime Bank successfully hosted its Annual Risk Conference 2025, reaffirming its commitment to fostering a proactive risk culture and ensuring sustainable growth in alignment with regulatory standards.
The conference took place recently at the Marina Yasmin Chowdhury Conference Hall at Prime Tower</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 12:21:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rafah crossing to open soon to let Gazans cross into Egypt, Israel says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/rafah-crossing-to-open-soon-to-let-gazans-cross-into-egypt-israel-says</link><description>Gaza's main gateway will open in the next few days, Israel said on Wednesday, allowing thousands of Palestinians who are in need of medical care to leave the war-ravaged enclave through Egypt.
COGAT, the Israeli military arm that oversees humanitarian matters, said the opening of the Rafah crossin</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 12:36:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ACC pushes back at criticism over Tulip Siddiq's conviction</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/acc-pushes-back-at-criticism-over-tulip-siddiqs-conviction</link><description>Bangladesh’s Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC), on Wednesday, issued a detailed response to concerns raised over the trial and sentencing of Tulip Siddiq, the daughter of Sheikh Rehana and niece of former prime minister Sheikh Hasina, insisting that her conviction was grounded in extensive evi</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 12:07:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Former BTRC top officials accused of Tk 90.1 billion telecom forgery</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/former-btrc-top-officials-accused-of-tk-901-billion-telecom-forgery</link><description>A group of former senior officials of the Bangladesh Telecommunication Regulatory Commission (BTRC) have been accused of causing a staggering Tk 90.1 billion loss to the state through deliberate misuse of power, illegal decisions, and revenue manipulation in favour of private International Gateway</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 12:22:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Students call sit-in over DCU push</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/students-call-sunday-sit-in-at-shikkha-bhaban-over-dhaka-central-university-demands</link><description>Students from the seven colleges have announced a continuous sit-in outside Shikkha Bhaban on Abdul Gani Road this Sunday, demanding the issuance of the Dhaka Central University Ordinance.
The declaration came around 4:15pm on Wednesday during a briefing outside Dhaka College, delivered by Abdur R</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 12:37:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>MPPA framework to transform industrial renewable energy procurement: Experts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/mppa-framework-to-transform-industrial-renewable-energy-procurement-experts</link><description>Experts and sector insiders on Wednesday at a discussion said that the imminent Merchant Power Purchase Agreement (MPPA) framework would transform how industries in Bangladesh procure renewable energy.
The possible transition of the renewable energy sector would also help Bangladesh prepare for it</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 12:52:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shimanto Bank launches 'NARI Shanchoy Account' for women</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/shimanto-bank-launches-nari-shanchoy-account-for-women</link><description>Shimanto Bank PLC has launched the “NARI Shanchoy Account,” a specialized savings product offering exclusive benefits for women.
The product was inaugurated at the bank’s Corporate Head Office in presence of all female officials, according to a media release. 
The NARI</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 13:07:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khaleda led from the streets, not from palaces: Moyeen Khan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/khaleda-led-from-the-streets-not-from-palaces-moyeen-khan</link><description>BNP Standing Committee member Abdul Moyeen Khan has said that despite being a national leader, Khaleda Zia built her political legacy on the streets alongside millions of supporters, not from any position of comfort or privilege.
Speaking at a prayer gathering organised by the Jatiyatabadi Palli C</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 13:22:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shahjalal Islami Bank provides financial assistance to a blood cancer patient for his treatment</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/shahjalal-islami-bank-provides-financial-assistance-to-a-blood-cancer-patient-for-his-treatment</link><description>As part of Corporate Social Responsibility (CSR) Program, Shahjalal Islami Bank PLC provided financial assistance of Tk 5.00 (Five Lac) to Md. Shahin Mollah, a resident of Shuktail Village, Gopalganj district, on 02nd December 2025, for the treatment of his blood cancer.
The Deputy Managing Direct</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 13:37:44 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>