<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 02:00:30 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Bangladesh Bank buys $45m from two banks to bolster reserves</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh-bank-buys-45m-from-two-banks-to-bolster-reserves</link><description>In its continued effort to stabilize the foreign exchange market and build up national reserves, Bangladesh Bank (BB) purchased an additional $45 million from two commercial banks on Tuesday (January 20).
The dollars were bought at a fixed exchange rate of Tk 122.30, with the cut-off rate also set</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 15:43:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>About 150,000 police receiving election training ahead of national polls: IGP</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/about-150000-police-receiving-election-training-ahead-of-national-polls-igp</link><description>Inspector General of Police (IGP) Baharul Alam on Tuesday said that around 150,000 police personnel are being provided with election-related training for the first time ahead of the upcoming national parliamentary elections.
He said the training programme will be completed within this month.
The</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 16:00:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>SJF leaders discuss SAARC rejuvenation with foreign ministry official</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/sjf-leaders-discuss-saarc-rejuvenation-with-foreign-ministry-official</link><description>Leaders of the SAARC Journalist Forum (SJF) held a meeting with S.M. Mahbubul Alam, Director General of the SAARC &amp; BIMSTEC Wing of the Ministry of Foreign Affairs, on Tuesday at the latter’s office to discuss ways to rejuvenate the South Asian Association for Regional Cooperation (SAARC) and</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 16:15:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Independent candidate Sarwar pulls out of Dhaka‑17 race to support Tarique</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/independent-candidate-sarwar-pulls-out-of-dhaka17-race-to-support-tarique</link><description>Lawyer M Sarwar Hossain has withdrawn his candidacy from Dhaka‑17 in support of BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman.
Speaking at the Supreme Court premises on Tuesday, Sarwar said he made the decision out of respect for Tarique and his nationalist ideals, bdnews24.com reports. 
Sarwar had initially</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 16:30:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Choosing reform, remembering July, securing the Republic</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/choosing-reform-remembering-july-securing-the-republic</link><description>On February 12, Bangladesh faces a question of profound historical importance one that goes beyond the usual trappings of election politics and into the very moral foundations of the republic itself. The people will not only elect their representatives; they will also be called upon to respond to a</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 16:45:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BR in need of electric traction for transition</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/br-in-need-of-electric-traction-for-transition</link><description>The Bangladesh Railway (BR) continues to lag far behind global trends in railway electrification, despite adopting a formal policy more than a decade ago for transition from diesel-powered trains to electric traction. While many countries have successfully modernised their rail networks through ele</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 17:00:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Developing advanced healthcare facilities at home</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/developing-advanced-healthcare-facilities-at-home</link><description>With fewer than one hospital bed available per 1,000 patients and still fewer doctors to attend them, the need for more hospital beds and healthcare professionals in the country has been a long-felt demand. Yet, progress in this important sector has been limited so far. That explains why before the</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 17:15:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>27 candidates withdraw candidature from 20 constituencies in Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/27-candidates-withdraw-candidature-from-20-constituencies-in-dhaka</link><description>A total of 27 candidates, both party-backed and independent, out of 162 have withdrawn their candidatures in the 20 constituencies of Dhaka district ahead of the 13th parliament election scheduled for February 12.
They withdrew their candidacies at the offices of three returning officers – D</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 17:30:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Police recover 9 locally made guns from Fatikchhari in Chattogram</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/police-recover-9-locally-made-guns-from-fatikchhari-in-chattogram</link><description>Police recovered nine locally made single-barrel guns during a special drive in Bhujpur area of Fatikchhari upazila early Tuesday.
A team from Bhujpur Police Station, acting on a tip-off, conducted the operation in the Baromasia Tea Garden area under Ward No. 4 of Suabil Union to recover illegal f</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 17:45:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Advisor expects LPG crisis to ease before Ramadan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/advisor-expects-lpg-crisis-to-ease-before-ramadan</link><description>Power and Energy Advisor Fouzul Kabir Khan hopes that the liquefied petroleum gas (LPG) crisis, which has seen supplies dwindle and prices double, will be resolved before the start of Ramadan.The advisor shared this expectation following an emergency meeting with private LPG operators on Tuesday, b</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 18:00:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump calls UK's Chagos deal with Mauritius 'stupid' and 'weak''</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-calls-uks-chagos-deal-with-mauritius-stupid-and-weak</link><description>U.S. President Donald Trump lambasted Britain's deal to cede sovereignty of the Chagos Archipelago - including an island with an important U.S.-UK air base - as an act of "total weakness" and "great stupidity" that underlines why he wants to acquire Greenland.
Washington last year gave its blessin</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 18:56:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt approves administrative  restructuring at NICAR meet</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-approves-administrative-restructuring-at-nicar-meet</link><description>The interim government on Tuesday approved some administrative-restructuring decisions with a view to improving "transparency, efficiency and accountability" across key state institutions.
At a meeting of the National Implementation Committee on Administrative Reorganisation (NICAR) at the state g</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 19:11:43 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>