<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 07:37:41 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Potholed roads woes for Pabna, Manikganj commuters</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/potholed-roads-woes-for-pabna-manikganj-commuters</link><description>One key road in Ishwardi upazila of Pabna district and a few others in Manikganj municipality have fallen into disrepair with innumerable potholes developing making them impassible for the regular commuters.
Travelling has become difficult, with asphalt, bricks, stones and gravels coming off the r</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 05:05:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Grape cultivation brings Gaibandha youth a rare success</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/grape-cultivation-brings-gaibandha-youth-a-rare-success</link><description>A young grower, Ashikur Rahman, has seen success after starting grape fruit cultivation for the first time in Gaibandha district at his orchard in Tepa Pudamshahar village of Saghata Upazila.
He is cultivating thirty-six varieties of the fruit on three spots, comprising a total eight acres of land</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 05:20:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Coast Guard seeks incentives to curb smuggling, tax evasion</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/coast-guard-seeks-incentives-to-curb-smuggling-tax-evasion</link><description>The Bangladesh Coast Guard has sought financial incentives for its personnel under the Customs Act for seizing contrabands and uncovering duty evasion, according to an official communication.
In a letter sent to the National Board of Revenue (NBR) on September 18, the paramilitary force pointed ou</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 05:35:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BDCCL seeks major revisions to Oracle cloud contract, demands $3.68m refund</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bdccl-seeks-major-revisions-to-oracle-cloud-contract-demands-368m-refund</link><description>Bangladesh Data Centre Company Limited (BDCCL) has moved to revise what it terms a 'one-sided' cloud service agreement with tech giant Oracle, seeking a refund of USD 3.68 million and sweeping changes to protect national interests.
Acting on directives from the government high-ups, the state-run c</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 05:50:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladeshi start-up partners with Malaysian firm to tap fintech and animation sectors</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladeshi-start-up-partners-with-malaysian-firm-to-tap-fintech-and-animation-sectors</link><description>A Bangladeshi start-up has teamed up with a Malaysian production house to break into two fast-growing sectors -- digital finance and animation -- in a move its backers say could transform access to credit and diversify the country's exports beyond garments.
Brave Horse Ventures Ltd, a Dhaka-based</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 06:05:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bualoi death toll rises to 51 in Vietnam, banks told to support affected firms</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/bualoi-death-toll-rises-to-51-in-vietnam-banks-told-to-support-affected-firms</link><description>The death toll in Vietnam from Typhoon Bualoi and the floods it triggered has risen to 51, according to a Friday government report, as the central bank urged banks to support affected businesses.
Bualoi made landfall on Monday in northern central Vietnam, bringing huge sea swells, strong winds and</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 06:20:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Kaliakoir boat capsize: One of two missing children found dead</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/kaliakoir-boat-capsize-one-of-two-missing-children-found-dead</link><description>The body of one of two children who went missing after a boat capsized during Bijoya Dashami celebrations in the Turag River in Kaliakoir upazila has been recovered.
A diving team from the Fire Service retrieved the body of Ankita Moni Das, a resident of Dakshin Hijaltoli village, after a 14-hour</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 06:35:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Apple removes ICE tracking apps after pressure by Trump administration</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/apple-removes-ice-tracking-apps-after-pressure-by-trump-administration</link><description>Apple said on Thursday that it had removed ICEBlock, the most popular ICE-tracking app, and other similar apps from its App Store after it was contacted by President Donald Trump's administration.
The app alerts users to Immigration and Customs Enforcement agents in their area. ICE has been a cent</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 06:50:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Light to moderate rain, thundershowers likely</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/light-to-moderate-rain-thundershowers-likely-11137</link><description>The Bangladesh Meteorological Department (BMD) on Friday forecasted light to moderate rain or thundershowers accompanied by temporary gusty wind is likely to occur at many places across the country over the next 24 hours, beginning at 9:00 am today.
"Light to moderate rain or thundershowers accomp</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 07:05:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Munich airport reopens after drone sightings halt flights</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/munich-airport-reopens-after-drone-sightings-halt-flights</link><description>Germany's Munich airport reopened on Friday after shutting overnight due to drone sightings that forced the cancellation or diversion of dozens of flights on the eve of a national holiday and heightened concerns about the vulnerability of critical infrastructure in Europe.
As operations resumed ea</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 07:20:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two killed in Gazipur road accident</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/two-killed-in-gazipur-road-accident-1490</link><description>Two autorickshaw passengers have died after a dump truck crashed head-on into their three-wheeler in Gazipur’s Kaliganj upazila.
Three others were injured in the accident that occurred around 8:30 am on Friday at Deopara on the Tongi-Dhorashal Bypass Road, according to Sub-Inspector Maksudul</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 07:35:15 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>