<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 16:56:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Cultural Ministry takes elaborate programs on Shahid dibash</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cultural-ministry-takes-elaborate-programs-on-shahid-dibash</link><description>Cultural Affairs Ministry has taken elaborate programmes marking the Shahid Dibash and International Mother Language Day.
On the day the national flag will remain half mast at all government, semi-government, autonomous and private buildings and educational institutes on February 21.
Bangladesh T</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 13:59:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pakistan, US sign pact to redevelop New York's Roosevelt Hotel</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/pakistan-us-sign-pact-to-redevelop-new-yorks-roosevelt-hotel</link><description>Pakistan has signed an agreement with the United States to jointly redevelop New York's Roosevelt Hotel, according to four official documents reviewed by Reuters and two sources, in a deal between the two governments that will allow Islamabad to unlock the value of one its most prized overseas inve</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 14:14:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two killed, 10 injured in Madaripur road accident</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/two-killed-10-injured-in-madaripur-road-accident</link><description>Two people were killed and 10 others injured in a road accident in Melkai area of Dasar upazila in Madaripur district on Thursday afternoon.
According to eyewitnesses and police, a passenger bus of Imran Paribahan, traveling from Dhaka to Barishal, collided head-on with a BRTC bus coming from the</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 14:29:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Health Minister for on-site monitoring to ensure quality healthcare services</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/health-minister-for-on-site-monitoring-to-ensure-quality-healthcare-services</link><description>Health and Family Welfare Minister Sardar Md Sakhawat Hossain today (Thursday) announced that the government will conduct on-site monitoring at hospitals to ensure that doctors are providing proper and timely services to patients.
He made the announcement while speaking as the chief guest at an or</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 14:44:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Russia warns of escalating Iran tensions amid US military build up</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/russia-warns-of-escalating-iran-tensions-amid-us-military-build-up</link><description>Russia warned against an “unprecedented escalation of tension” around Iran on Thursday and urged restraint amid a US military build-up in the region that a senior American official said should be complete by mid-March.
US threats to bomb Iran, with the two sides far apart in talks on T</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 15:01:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>After Milano Cortina, Veneto's former governor pushes Venice bid for 2036, 2040 Games</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/after-milano-cortina-venetos-former-governor-pushes-venice-bid-for-2036-2040-games</link><description>In the wake of the Milano Cortina Olympics, the former governor of the Veneto region wants to put forward the city of Venice and the surrounding Italian regions as candidates to host the 2036 or 2040 Summer Olympics, with a focus on preserving the lagoon city.
The Winter Olympics were the first ex</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 15:16:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Consensus collections not extortion’: Rabiul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/consensual-roadside-collections-not-extortion-transport-minister</link><description>Road Transport and Communications Minister Shaikh Rabiul Alam has said that money collected from transport operators “on a consensual basis” should not be considered extortion.
Speaking to reporters at his office in the Secretariat on Thursday, he clarified: “What is called extor</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 15:31:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt initiates 'family card' pilot in 8 divisions</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/government-launched-family-card-pilot-in-8-divisions</link><description>The government has moved to launch the “family card” programme on a pilot basis across eight Upazilas in as many divisions of the country, fulfilling a key electoral pledge to strengthen social security for low-income households.
A 15-member ministerial committee, headed by New Finance</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 15:46:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India's Kaur becomes highest-capped woman in international cricket</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/indias-kaur-becomes-highest-capped-woman-in-international-cricket</link><description>Harmanpreet Kaur became the highest-capped player in women’s international cricket when she made her 356th appearance for India in Thursday’s Twenty20 match against Australia, surpassing New Zealand great Suzie Bates.
Indian captain Kaur, 36, has now played six Tests, 161 One-Day</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 16:02:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>King Charles visits London fashion show after brother's arrest</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/king-charles-visits-london-fashion-show-after-brothers-arrest</link><description>Britain's King Charles appeared at a fashion show in London on Thursday just hours after his brother Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor was arrested on suspicion of misconduct in public office.
Charles greeted onlookers with a wave when he arrived at Tolu Coker's London Fashion Week show and was met with</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 16:17:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Asif Nazrul vacates govt residence</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/asif-nazrul-bids-farewell-to-hare-road-residence-in-emotional-facebook-post</link><description>Former law advisor Asif Nazrul has announced that he is leaving his official residence on Hare Road, sharing an emotional message on social media about his attachment to the place.
In a Facebook post on Thursday, he wrote, “Goodbye Hare Road!” while describing the mixed feelings surrou</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 16:32:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>HSC form fill-up fees rise as registration set to begin Mar 1</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/hsc-form-fill-up-fees-rise-as-registration-set-to-begin-mar-1</link><description>The cost of appearing for the Higher Secondary Certificate (HSC) and equivalent examinations has increased this year, with the maximum fee for filling out the form for the exams fixed at Tk 2,995.
A notice issued on Thursday by the Board of Intermediate and Secondary Education, Dhaka informed that</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 16:47:52 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>