<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 11:19:34 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Fish export to India halted through Akhaura land port</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fish-export-to-india-halted-through-akhaura-land-port</link><description>Fish export to India through Akhaura land port in Brahmanbaria has been suspended due to complications over certification from the Fisheries Department.
Traders said the unresolved issue could cut export earnings by at least Tk 1.5 crore each day, UNB reports. 
According to officials and tra</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 08:34:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shakib Al Hasan, Hiru under ACC scrutiny for stock market manipulation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/shakib-al-hasan-hiru-under-acc-scrutiny-for-stock-market-manipulation</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) has initiated a major investigation into an extensive stock market manipulation and money laundering scheme allegedly led by Md Abul Khayer (alias Hiru), a deputy registrar at the Department of Cooperatives, Dhaka.
The inquiry also involves former lawmaker and</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 08:49:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh, other CSC members discuss regional security, counterterrorism</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-other-csc-members-discuss-regional-security-counterterrorism</link><description>Bangladesh, India and other member states on Thursday sat together in New Delhi to promote closer cooperation on vital matters of security and strengthen partnership for enhancing regional security in the Indian Ocean region.
India hosted the 7th meeting of the National Security Advisers (NSAs) of</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 09:04:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Israeli airstrikes kill 25 Palestinians in Gaza, rattling ceasefire, medics say</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/israeli-airstrikes-kill-25-palestinians-in-gaza-rattling-ceasefire-medics-say</link><description>At least 25 Palestinians were killed in four Israeli airstrikes on Wednesday in a part of Gaza under Hamas control since a shaky ceasefire took effect in October, health authorities said.
The Israeli military said its forces struck Hamas targets across Gaza after members of the Palestinian militan</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 09:19:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Europeans push back at US plan that would force concessions from Ukraine</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/europeans-push-back-at-us-plan-that-would-force-concessions-from-ukraine</link><description>European countries pushed back on Thursday against a US-backed peace plan for Ukraine that sources said would require Kyiv to give up more land and partially disarm, conditions long seen by Ukraine's allies as tantamount to capitulation.
Two people familiar with the matter told Reuters on Wednesda</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 09:34:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh to roll out red carpet to welcome Bhutanese PM on Saturday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-to-roll-out-red-carpet-to-welcome-bhutanese-pm-on-saturday</link><description>Bangladesh will roll out the red carpet on Saturday to welcome Bhutanese Prime Minister Tshering Tobgay, who will arrive here on a three-day state visit aimed at taking bilateral relations to a new level through enhanced connectivity, trade and investment.
The Bhutanese Prime Minister is scheduled</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 09:49:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Kremlin says it wonders why Airbus chairman is making 'provocative' statements about nuclear weapons</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/kremlin-says-it-wonders-why-airbus-chairman-is-making-provocative-statements-about-nuclear-weapons</link><description>The Kremlin on Thursday criticised comments on Russian nuclear weapons made by the chairman of Airbus and asked why someone like him was making them in the first place, saying that "more and more Europeans were "losing their restraint".
Airbus chairman Rene Obermann on Wednesday called on European</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 10:04:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Being cautious about cryptocurrencies, stablecoins, India cenbank chief says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/global/being-cautious-about-cryptocurrencies-stablecoins-india-cenbank-chief-says</link><description>India's central bank is adopting a cautious approach towards cryptocurrencies and stablecoins, the Reserve Bank of India governor said on Thursday.</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 10:19:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IAEA board passes resolution demanding answers and access from Iran</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/iaea-board-passes-resolution-demanding-answers-and-access-from-iran</link><description>The UN nuclear watchdog's 35-nation Board of Governors passed a resolution on Thursday saying Iran must inform the watchdog "without delay" of the status of its enriched uranium stock and bombed atomic sites, diplomats at the closed-door meeting said.
The resolution's purpose was primarily to rene</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 10:34:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ukraine says it received 1,000 bodies from Russia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/ukraine-says-it-received-1000-bodies-from-russia</link><description>Ukraine received 1,000 bodies of what Russia says are fallen Ukrainian servicemen, Kyiv's prisoner-of-war coordination centre said on Thursday.
"Investigators from law enforcement bodies, together with expert agencies of the Ministry of Internal Affairs, will soon conduct all necessary examination</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 10:49:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Three entities under Health Ministry to be strengthened</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/three-entities-under-health-ministry-to-be-strengthened</link><description>The government has presented a major development initiative aimed at strengthening the operational capacity, administrative efficiency, and educational quality of three key government agencies under the Medical Education and Family Welfare Division.
A development project, titled “Integrated</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 11:04:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>From food to fashion, how we feel in winter in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/others/from-food-to-fashion-how-we-feel-in-winter-in-bangladesh</link><description>What comes to your mind when we hear the word 'Winter'? A lazy morning filled with fog, a man cycling somewhere, wearing a muffler and a shirt that barely covers his body to keep warm? Or the smell of freshly made Pitha by our mothers and grandparents? A long time care-free vacation when exams come</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 11:19:34 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>