<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 14:44:26 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Modhumoti Bank donates Tk 2 million to 'Inspiration Welfare Society'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/modhumoti-bank-donates-tk-2-million-to-inspiration-welfare-society</link><description>Modhumoti Bank PLC donated Tk 2 million (20 Lac) to “Inspiration Welfare Society” recently under the bank’s CSR program for conducting social welfare programs and educational programs for Special Children across the country.
Mr. Shahnawaj Chowdhury, Managing Director (Current Cha</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 13:29:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Japanese JERA opens Dhaka office to boost energy collaboration in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/japanese-jera-opens-dhaka-office-to-boost-energy-collaboration-in-bangladesh</link><description>JERA Co., Inc., Japan’s largest power generation company and a global leader in energy innovation, has officially launched its new office in Dhaka, Bangladesh—marking a strategic milestone in its expansion across Asia.
The move aims to deepen collaboration with key stakeholders in Bang</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 12:14:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>14 ‘criminals’ held at Dhaka’s Mohammadpur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/14-criminals-held-at-dhakas-mohammadpur</link><description>Police have arrested 14 people for their suspected involvement in various criminal activities from different parts of Mohammadpur area.
They were arrested during a daylong special anti-crime drive conducted by Mohammadpur thana police in several crime-prone spots on Monday, said Deputy Commissione</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 12:29:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh, Egypt sign MoU on judicial cooperation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-egypt-sign-mou-on-judicial-cooperation</link><description>The Supreme Courts of Bangladesh and Egypt have signed a memorandum of understanding (MoU) to enhance mutual cooperation in the judicial sector.
Bangladesh Chief Justice Dr Syed Refaat Ahmed, now on an official visit to Egypt at the invitation of the Chief Justice Boulos Fahmy of the Supreme Const</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 12:59:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>30 women entrepreneurs in Chattogram complete BRAC Bank’s ‘Amrai TARA’ training</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/30-women-entrepreneurs-in-chattogram-complete-brac-banks-amrai-tara-training</link><description>BRAC Bank, in collaboration with the Bangladesh Open Source Network (BdOSN), organised a three-day training programme titled 'Amrai TARA' to empower 30 promising women entrepreneurs with the knowledge, skills, and networks needed to expand their businesses, according to a press release.
The traini</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 13:14:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CEC Nasir aims to hold ‘gender-friendly’ national election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cec-nasir-aims-to-hold-gender-friendly-national-election</link><description>Chief Election Commissioner AMM Nasir Uddin has expressed a desire to make the parliamentary polls “gender-friendly”, citing previous gaps in female voter registration.
Speaking on Tuesday afternoon at the Nirbachan Bhaban in Dhaka’s Agargaon, during a dialogue with women’s</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 13:29:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Three to die for killing woman over dowry in Barguna</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/three-to-die-for-killing-woman-over-dowry-in-barguna</link><description>A Barguna court has sentenced three people to death for murdering a housewife in Pathorghata Upazila over dowry demands.
The verdict was delivered on Tuesday by Judge Begum Lailatul Ferdous of Barguna’s Women and Children Repression Prevention Tribunal, said Public Prosecutor Ronjuara Sipu.</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 13:44:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique urges teachers to back BNP for reform-focused govt</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-urges-teachers-to-back-bnp-for-reform-focused-govt</link><description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman on Tuesday urged teachers to extend their support to BNP in the upcoming national election so that the party can form a government to build a knowledge and merit-based state and implement its plans for national and political reforms.
“To implement all the p</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 13:59:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Next TV, Live TV receive broadcast licenses under interim government</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/next-tv-live-tv-receive-broadcast-licenses-under-interim-government</link><description>For the first time under the interim government, two news-based television stations have been granted broadcasting licenses.
The stations, named Next TV and Live TV, are linked to prominent figures from the National Citizen Party (NCP) and the National Citizens’ Committee, bdnews24.com repor</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 14:29:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BGB detains 24 in Sherpur for attempting ‘illegal’ border crossing into India</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bgb-detains-24-in-sherpur-for-attempting-illegal-border-crossing-into-india</link><description>The Border Guard Bangladesh (BGB) has detained 24 people, allegedly attempting to illegally enter India through the Jhenaigati border in Sherpur.
They were detained around 9:30pm on Monday under the Haldigram Border Outpost, said Lieutenant Colonel Mehedi Hasan, captain of BGB Battalion-39 in Myme</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 14:44:26 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>