<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 12:47:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Hadi’s death an irreparable loss to nation: Rizwana</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hadis-death-an-irreparable-loss-to-nation-rizwana</link><description>The tragic demise of Sharif Osman Bin Hadi, a frontline activist of the July Uprising and spokesperson of Inquilab Moncho, is an irreparable loss to the country and its people, Environment Adviser Syeda Rizwana Hasan said on Friday.
In a condolence message, Rizwana, also Adviser to the Ministry of</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 08:43:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt condemns mob violence, vows justice for attacks on journalists</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-condemns-mob-violence-vows-justice-for-attacks-on-journalists</link><description>The interim government has urged citizens to resist all forms of mob violence and has condemned acts of intimidation, arson and destruction of property, describing the current period as a critical moment in the country’s democratic transition.
In a statement issued on Thursday, the governmen</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 08:58:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US, EU express condolences over Osman Hadi’s death</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/us-eu-express-condolences-over-osman-hadis-death</link><description>The United States and European Union missions in Dhaka have expressed condolences over the death of political activist Sharif Osman Bin Hadi, who was shot in the capital last week.
Both missions posted messages on social media on Friday mourning his death and offering sympathies to his family and</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 09:58:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>'Criminal offence': Attack on Chhayanaut goes against spirit of July Uprising, says Farooki</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/criminal-offence-attack-on-chhayanaut-goes-against-spirit-of-july-uprising-says-farooki</link><description>Cultural Affairs Advisor Mostofa Sarwar Farooki has denounced the attack on the Chhayanaut cultural complex in Dhaka as a “criminal offence” and said it goes against the spirit of the July Uprising.
In a statement issued on Friday, Farooki said the vandalism and arson at the institutio</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 09:45:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Long March to Border’ for Hadi held at Benapole</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/long-march-to-border-for-hadi-held-at-benapole</link><description>Students and general people staged a protest march titled ‘Long March to Border’ at the Benapole international checkpost zero point on Friday, demanding the arrest of the killers of Iquilab Moncho spokesperson Sharif Osman Hadi.
The protest procession began around 11am from Benapole mu</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 10:00:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Russia's Putin warns of risks for top oil producers' reserves in EU</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/russias-putin-warns-of-risks-for-top-oil-producers-reserves-in-eu</link><description>Russian President Vladimir Putin warned on Friday of risks for international reserves held by the world’s top oil producers in the European Union, following discussions by EU leaders about using Russian assets to finance Ukraine.
Putin’s remarks were aimed at some of the world’s</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 10:15:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sister blames company officials after mob lynches man over 'blasphemy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/sister-blames-company-officials-after-man-killed-by-mob-over-blasphemy-in-mymensingh</link><description>The sister of a 28-year-old worker, who was beaten to death by a mob in Mymensingh’s Bhaluka Upazila over allegations of blasphemy, has accused company personnel of pushing him to his death.
Speaking on Friday, Champa Das said she had heard that her brother, Dipu Chandra Das, had a row with</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 10:30:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump says he is not ruling out war with Venezuela, NBC News reports</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-says-he-is-not-ruling-out-war-with-venezuela-nbc-news-reports</link><description>U.S. President Donald Trump said he was leaving the possibility of war with Venezuela on the table, according to an interview with NBC News published on Friday.
“I don’t rule it out, no,” he told NBC News in a phone interview.
Trump also said there would be additional seizures o</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 10:45:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Investors react to EU funding deal for Ukraine</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/investors-react-to-eu-funding-deal-for-ukraine</link><description>European Union leaders decided on Friday to borrow cash to fund Ukraine's defence against Russia rather than use frozen Russian assets, sidestepping divisions to secure a 90 billion euro loan.
German 10-year government bonds , which serve as a benchmark for the wider euro zone market, came under m</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 11:00:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Staff calls off strike at Paris Louvre museum for now - union</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/culture/staff-calls-off-strike-at-paris-louvre-museum-for-now-union</link><description>Staff at France's Louvre museum in Paris has voted to call off a strike they began on Monday over pay and working conditions, union representatives said on Friday.
"At a general meeting held today, Louvre Museum staff unanimously decided to pause their action in order to allow the museum to reopen</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 11:30:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Border guards deployed across Dhaka to maintain order</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/border-guards-deployed-across-dhaka-to-maintain-order</link><description>Border Guard Bangladesh (BGB) personnel have been deployed at several key locations in the capital to help maintain law and order following the return of slain political activist Sharif Osman Hadi’s body from Singapore.
In a statement issued on Friday, the BGB announced the deployment of tro</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 11:45:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Protest over Hadi’s death blocks Dhaka-Barishal highway</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/protest-over-hadis-death-blocks-dhaka-barishal-highway</link><description>Students and general people blocked Dhaka-Barishal highway for several hours demanding arrest of killers of Inquilab Moncho spokesman Osman Hadi on Friday afternoon.
The disruption caused immense suffering of commuters and transport workers. 
The protesters gathered at Nathullabad Bus Termin</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 12:00:54 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>