<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 10:26:57 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>How digital power is strengthening industrial resilience in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/how-digital-power-is-strengthening-industrial-resilience-in-bangladesh</link><description>Bangladesh's industrial sector is entering a critical phase in its energy transition. The central question is no longer whether renewable energy will be adopted, but how reliably it can support industrial operations in the long run. Rising fuel costs, grid instability, and sustainability expectatio</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 07:08:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Top court clears way for Nagorik Oikko's Manna to contest polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/loan-default-top-court-clears-way-for-nagorik-oikkos-manna-to-contest-polls</link><description>The Supreme Court has cleared the way for Nagorik Oikko President Mahmudur Rahman Manna to contest the upcoming parliamentary election by suspending a High Court order that had barred him from running.
The Appellate Division’s Chamber Court stayed the High Court ruling that had denied Manna&amp;</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 07:23:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Severe cold wave persists in Gaibandha, Naogaon, Barishal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/severe-cold-wave-persists-in-gaibandha-naogaon-barishal</link><description>A severe cold wave, marked by dense fog and icy winds from the Himalayas, has been sweeping through the northern district of Gaibandha, Naogaon, and Barishal for the past several days.
Our Correspondent from Gaibandha writes: The temperature in this region, surrounded by rivers and canals, is drop</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 08:09:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ministry requests airlines to publish Hajj flight schedule between Jan 5–7</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ministry-requests-airlines-to-publish-hajj-flight-schedule-between-jan-5-7</link><description>The Ministry of Religious Affairs has requested airlines to publish their Hajj flight schedules on their official websites and the Hajj portal between January 5 and 7.
The ministry sent letters to the Managing Director and CEO of Biman Bangladesh Airlines, the Country Manager of Saudi Arabian Airl</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 08:24:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DITF 2026 to kick off on Jan 1</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ditf-2026-to-kick-off-on-jan-1</link><description>The month-long 30th Dhaka International Trade Fair (DITF) 2026 will begin at the Bangladesh-China Friendship Exhibition Centre in Purbachal on Thursday (January 1, 2026).
Commerce Secretary Mahbubur Rahman disclosed the information at a press briefing at the venue on Monday (December 29, 2025). Ch</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 08:39:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>JnUCSU election: Students asked to vacate campus by 3:30pm</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/jnucsu-election-students-asked-to-vacate-campus-by-330pm</link><description>The Jagannath University administration has asked general students to vacate the campus by 3:30 pm on Monday for the university’s Central Students’ Union (JnUCSU) and Hall Students’ Union elections.
The directive was issued through an emergency notice signed by the university&amp;rsq</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 08:54:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No polythene bags at Dhaka trade fair, says commerce secretary</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/no-polythene-bags-at-dhaka-trade-fair-says-commerce-secretary</link><description>Single-use plastics, including polythene and plastic shopping bags, will be banned at the upcoming Dhaka International Trade Fair, according to Commerce Secretary Mahbubur Rahman.
Only plastic bottles for drinking water will be allowed at the event starting on January 1, he said on Monday.
Partic</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 09:09:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique to visit BNP’s Nayapaltan central office on Monday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-to-visit-bnps-nayapaltan-central-office-on-monday</link><description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman is set to visit the party's Nayapaltan central office on Monday afternoon, a day after visiting the BNP Chairperson's Gulshan office.
BNP Media Cell member Sayrul Kabir Khan said Tarique is expected to go to the Nayapaltan office in the afternoon.
This will be h</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 09:24:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Traders staged protest with sticks in front Kawrab Bazar against attack on their human chain</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/traders-staged-protest-with-sticks-in-front-kawrab-bazar-against-attack-on-their-human-chain</link><description>A group of miscreants attacked a human chain organised by traders against extortion at Karwan Bazar in the capital on Monday, triggering clashes and a brief chase between the two sides.
Following the attack, traders staged a protest with sticks in front of the Kitchen Market, while police and army</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 09:41:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Low speed prevents disaster after train derails in Gafargaon due to track removal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/low-speed-prevents-disaster-after-train-derails-in-gafargaon-due-to-track-removal</link><description>Bangladesh Railway officials say the low speed of a Dhaka-bound passenger train prevented casualties after it derailed in Mymensingh’s Gafargaon.
The locomotive and two carriages of the Agnibina Express ran off the tracks early on Monday morning after sections of the railway line were allege</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 09:56:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat Ameer submits nomination papers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-ameer-submits-nomination-papers</link><description>The nomination papers of Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami Ameer Dr Shafiqur Rahman was submitted to the returning officer concerned on Monday to contest the national election from Dhaka-15 constituency.
Besides, BNP nominated Bobby Hajjaj and Shafiqul Islam Khan submitted their respective nomination pap</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 10:11:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dubai to host FIFA Best Awards next year</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/dubai-to-host-fifa-best-awards-next-year</link><description>FIFA President Gianni Infantino said on Monday that Dubai would host the global governing body’s Best Awards ceremony next year.
The FIFA Best Awards honour the top men’s and women’s players, as well as coaches and teams, as voted for by fans, media representatives, captains and</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 10:26:08 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>