<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 11:15:59 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>12 killed in stampede at Andhra Pradesh temple</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/12-killed-in-stampede-at-andhra-pradesh-temple</link><description>At least 12 devotees, most of them women and children, have died in a stampede at the Sri Venkateswara Swamy temple in Srikakulam district of Andhra Pradesh, India, during the observance of Ekadashi.
According to NDTV, the stampede occurred early Friday when a massive crowd gathered at the Kasibug</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 08:45:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Primary assistant teachers announce strict programmes with deadline</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/primary-assistant-teachers-announce-strict-programmes-with-deadline</link><description>Assistant teachers from government primary schools have given the government a deadline until Nov 15 to resolve long-standing disputes over pay grades and promotions.
They have announced events such as work stoppages, continuous sit-ins, exam boycotts, and a fast unto death if their three-point ch</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 09:00:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Journalists across Bangladesh demonstrate for 39-point demand</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/journalists-across-bangladesh-demonstrate-for-39-point-demand</link><description>Journalists across the country held protest rallies on Saturday, demanding the implementation of the 'No Wage Board, No Media' policy, formulation of a journalist protection law, introduction of two weekly holidays, and repeal of all anti-media black laws.
 
The protests were organised under</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 09:15:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fakhrul slams Jamaat for ‘spreading lies’ to mislead people ahead of election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/fakhrul-slams-jamaat-for-spreading-lies-to-mislead-people-ahead-of-election</link><description>BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir on Saturday accused Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami of misleading the public by spreading lies about the upcoming national election.
“A party is saying BNP wants to delay the election… but it is they who are actually trying to derail the po</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 09:30:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Election should be held in early February: Amir Khasru</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/election-should-be-held-in-early-february-amir-khasru</link><description>BNP standing committee member and former minister of commerce Amir Khasru Mahmud Chowdhury today (Saturday) said the upcoming national election should be held in early February.
He, however, blamed that a conspirator's circle has been intending to delay the election. All of the peace-loving people</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 10:15:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tanzania's Hassan declared landslide winner in election marred by violence</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/africa/tanzanias-hassan-declared-landslide-winner-in-election-marred-by-violence-1</link><description>Tanzania's electoral commission declared on Saturday that President Samia Suluhu Hassan had won, with nearly 98 per cent of the votes, an election that set off violent protests across the country this week.
The result hands Hassan, who took power in 2021 after the death in office of her predecesso</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 10:30:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Apex court heaving under logjam of half-million cases</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/apex-court-heaving-under-logjam-of-half-million-cases</link><description>A decade of steady case disposal falls short of a pace warranted to deal with a logjam of cases Bangladesh's apex court faces amid a rush of litigants in courts across the country, sources say.
A predominant feature in the piling up of pending cases is numerous cases implicating several hundred ac</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 11:00:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>RAB arrests eight in Narsingdi with 11 firearms</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/rab-arrests-eight-in-narsingdi-with-11-firearms</link><description>The Rapid Action Battalion has arrested eight people with 11 firearms from the riverine areas of Raipura in Narsingdi, saying the weapons were kept to “assert territorial dominance”.
According to the RAB, the arms were smuggled in from a neighbouring country through river routes, while</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 11:15:59 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>