<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 05:55:44 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Import of capital machinery and export diversification are integral</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/import-of-capital-machinery-and-export-diversification-are-integral</link><description>It is premature to conclude that import of capital machinery has peaked up in the first half of the fiscal year 2025-26 riding on the assumption of economic and political stability during this elected government. But the 24 per cent rise in the opening of letters of credit (LCs) year on year during</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 18:33:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Deregulation and reduction of cost of business</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/deregulation-and-reduction-of-cost-of-business</link><description>The statement by the newly appointed finance and planning minister that his immediate priorities are deregulation and lowering the cost of doing business is both timely and pragmatic. Speaking to the media shortly after being sworn in, he underscored that restoring momentum to the country's fragile</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 18:48:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump stresses executing trade, defence deals</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/trump-stresses-executing-trade-defence-deals</link><description>President Donald Trump has urged Bangladesh's newly elected Prime Minister, Tarique Rahman, to move swiftly on trade and defence agreements, using a congratulatory letter to underline Washington's strategic expectations from the new administration in Dhaka.



In a letter dated February 18, Tru</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 19:48:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>5.0pc fall in Jul-Jan exports to India</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/50pc-fall-in-jul-jan-exports-to-india</link><description>Bangladesh's merchandise exports to neighbouring India have suffered a setback, with growth declining during the first seven months of the current fiscal year, mainly due to trade restrictions imposed by India.
According to official data from the state-run Export Promotion Bureau (EPB), Bangladesh</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 02:05:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Call to scrap source tax on exports</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/call-to-scrap-source-tax-on-exports</link><description>Bangladesh should phase out the source tax on exports at the earliest opportunity, as it undermines competitiveness and distorts trade, according to a national taskforce on revenue reform.
The panel argues that taxing manufacturing exports contradicts fundamental tax principles and weakens the cou</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 02:20:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New govt faces fiscal space squeeze</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/new-govt-faces-fiscal-space-squeeze</link><description>A total of 86 development projects, stalled for more than a decade despite having an approved estimated cost of Tk 4.76 trillion, significantly squeezed the previous government's fiscal space, potentially limiting the new administration's ability to take up fresh schemes, officials at the Planning</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 02:35:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Positive real returns draw savings into banks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/positive-real-returns-draw-savings-into-banks</link><description>Savers have been earning positive real returns since June 2025 as deposit rates on the financial market have remained above the pace of inflation, according to the latest central bank data.
The widening gap has encouraged households to channel more funds into the formal banking system.
After a ne</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 02:50:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cautious, evidence-based approach needed</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/cautious-evidence-based-approach-needed</link><description>Citizen's Platform for SDGs, Bangladesh on Thursday called for strict fiscal discipline for the rest of the current fiscal year, alongside a cautious, evidence-based approach to preparing a realistic and implementable budget for FY27.
It advised deferring the rollout of the BNP's election- manifes</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 03:05:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>City buzzes with iftar buying</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/city-buzzes-with-iftar-buying</link><description>The traditional iftar market at Chawkbazar in Old Dhaka came alive on Thursday, the first day of Ramadan, with crowds filling the main road near Shahi Mosque from noon.
By 3:00pm, vendors were calling out to attract customers, offering items such as "Boro Baper Polay Khay" kebab, lacchi, faluda, d</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 03:31:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Firm foreign policy to be pursued</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/firm-foreign-policy-to-be-pursued</link><description>State Minister for Foreign Affairs Shama Obaed has said the BNP-led government intends to move forward with a "strong backbone", signalling a more confident and inclusive diplomatic approach following its electoral mandate.
Speaking at the foreign ministry on Thursday, she said Bangladesh would en</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 03:46:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Robi earns record profit in 2025 on lower operating costs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/robi-earns-record-profit-in-2025-on-lower-operating-costs</link><description>Robi Axiata secured a record profit of Tk 9.37 billion in 2025, riding on the lower impact of currency devaluation and reduced operating expenses amid a challenging business environment.
The second-largest telecom operator's profit jumped more than 33 per cent year-on-year despite a marginal 1 per</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 04:01:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Olympic Industries' chairman to buy 10m shares from market</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/olympic-industries-chairman-to-buy-10m-shares-from-market</link><description>The chairman of Olympic Industries is set to acquire more than five per cent of the company's shares from the market.
According to a disclosure on Thursday, Aziz Mohammad Bhai plans to purchase 10 million shares from the block market at the prevailing market price, amounting to nearly Tk 1.553 bil</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 04:16:06 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>