<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 06:34:29 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Undoing biddings for 2 contracts on MRT-5: JICA rejects proposal pointblank on 'disappointment'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/undoing-biddings-for-2-contracts-on-mrt-5-jica-rejects-proposal-pointblank-on-disappointment</link><description>Japan international cooperation agency (JICA) has rejected outright Dhaka metro-rail company's request to cancel entire biddings on two contract packages for MRT-5 North, on a note of "disappointment with the request",
"Jica will not concur on any such request," Yoshida Hirosh of the agency says i</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 03:00:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Meghna Petroleum logs record profit on higher margins, bank income</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/meghna-petroleum-logs-record-profit-on-higher-margins-bank-income</link><description>Meghna Petroleum posted a record profit of Tk 6.64 billion in FY25, driven by higher sales margins and substantial income from bank deposits.
The annual profit grew by 23 per cent year-on-year for the year ended in June this year, according to a stock exchange filing on Monday. With that, the comp</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 04:00:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fires on three buses in Dhaka overnight</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fires-on-three-buses-in-dhaka-overnight</link><description>Fires have broken out in buses in at least three separate locations in Dhaka overnight.
The incidents occurred between 12:45 am to 4:00 am on Tuesday, according to Fire Service Control Room Duty Officer Md Shahjahan.
He said, "A fire broke out in a Rajdhani Paribahan bus in Rayerbagh at 12:45 am,</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 04:15:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump threatens to sue BBC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-threatens-to-sue-bbc-as-uk-broadcaster-admits-error-in-editing-his-january-6-speech</link><description>US President Donald Trump has threatened legal action against the BBC for its editing of a speech he made in 2021 on the day his supporters overran the Capitol, which the British broadcaster admitted on Monday was an "error of judgement".
In the letter sent on Sunday and seen by Reuters, the presi</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 04:30:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Experts urge structural reforms and trade resilience ahead of LDC graduation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/experts-urge-structural-reforms-and-trade-resilience-ahead-of-ldc-graduation</link><description>Economists and experts have stressed that Bangladesh's upcoming graduation from the Least Developed Country (LDC) status in 2026 requires urgent and comprehensive preparation, bold policy reforms, and effective coordination among stakeholders to ensure a smooth transition.
They also warned that bo</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 04:45:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sonali Bank eyes end to capital shortfalls, boosts digital transformation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/sonali-bank-eyes-end-to-capital-shortfalls-boosts-digital-transformation</link><description>Amid what is arguably the most challenging period for the banking sector, Sonali Bank PLC is aiming to fully overcome its longstanding capital and provisioning shortfalls by the end of the year.
Leveraging growing deposits and investment portfolios despite ongoing economic sluggishness, the countr</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 05:00:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New joint coalition of TUs, CSOs launched for migrant workers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/new-joint-coalition-of-tus-csos-launched-for-migrant-workers</link><description>A new joint coalition of trade unions (TUs) and civil society organisations (CSOs) was launched on Monday to ensure rights, dignity, safety and welfare of the country's migrant workers.
The coalition - Trade Union-Civil Society Action Alliance (TUCSAA) - is expected to re-integrate and strengthen</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 05:15:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DU launches special professional comms course for students</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/du-launches-special-professional-comms-course-for-students</link><description>Students of Dhaka University's undergraduate final year and any master's programme are eligible to apply for a special professional communication course launched by the university to improve career readiness.
The course will be jointly conducted by the university's Institutional Quality Assurance</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 05:30:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two British lawyers submit ‘urgent appeal’ to UN over Hasina’s ‘fair trial’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/two-british-lawyers-submit-urgent-appeal-to-un-over-hasinas-fair-trial</link><description>Two British lawyers have submitted an urgent appeal to the United Nations, raising concerns over fair trial rights and due process in the trial of ousted prime minister Sheikh Hasina before Bangladesh’s International Crimes Tribunal (ICT).
Hasina is facing charges of crimes against humanity</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 05:45:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Man burns to death as criminals torch bus in Mymensingh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/man-burns-to-death-as-criminals-torch-bus-in-mymensingh</link><description>A man has burnt to death after a parked bus was set on fire in Mymensingh’s Fulbaria Upazila.
Police believe that he was the driver of the bus, according to bdneews24.com.
The incident occurred in front of the Bhalukjan Bazar Petrol Pump in the Fulbaria municipality around 3:15am on Tuesday</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 06:00:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>PURBACHAL PLOT GRAFT CASE : Testimonies against Hasina, 11 others conclude</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/purbachal-plot-graft-case-testimonies-against-hasina-11-others-conclude</link><description>Testimonies in a corruption case filed against ousted prime minister Sheikh Hasina and 11 others on charges of abusing power to acquire plots in the Rajdhani Unnayan Kartripakkha's (RAJUK) Purbachal New Town project concluded on Monday.
Judge of the Special Court 5 in Dhaka Md Abdullah Al Mamun th</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 06:15:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh stands by India at this distressful hour</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-stands-by-india-at-this-distressful-hour</link><description>The Bangladesh High Commission in New Delhi on Monday expressed deep condolences over the tragic death of at least 10 people and injuries to many others in a car blast near the Red Fort in Delhi.
“Our earnest thoughts and prayers remain with all those impacted, including their families,&amp;rdqu</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 06:30:47 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>