<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 10:42:46 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>BCB plans to launch a cricket program for madrasah students</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/bcb-plans-to-launch-a-cricket-program-for-madrasah-students</link><description>Aminul Islam, the newly elected president of the Bangladesh Cricket Board (BCB), said they are planning to bring cricket to the hundreds of thousands of madrasa students.
There was no such organised plan to do so in the past. If it takes shape, it will be a first in the board’s history</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 07:18:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka’s forecast shows several more days of rain on the way</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dhakas-forecast-shows-several-more-days-of-rain-on-the-way</link><description>Dhaka saw rain on Wednesday morning under the influence of the active monsoon winds. These showers are likely to continue over the next few days, according to a forecast by the Bangladesh Meteorological Department (BMD).
Meteorologist Md Omar Faruk said on Wednesday afternoon: “The active mo</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 07:33:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fakhrul urges govt to ensure Shahidul Alam’s safe return</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fakhrul-urges-govt-to-ensure-shahidul-alams-safe-return</link><description>BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir on Wednesday urged the government to take immediate steps to ensure the safe return of Bangladeshi photographer and writer Shahidul Alam, who has reportedly been intercepted and detained by Israeli forces.
“Free Shahidul Alam,” Fakhrul</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 07:48:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Who is Paul Kapur, the new US assistant secretary of state for South Asia?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/who-is-paul-kapur-the-new-us-assistant-secretary-of-state-for-south-asia</link><description>Paul Kapur, a distinguished Indian-origin academic, has been appointed as the new US assistant secretary of state for South and Central Asian Affairs, a key diplomatic post overseeing relations with countries including India and Bangladesh.
The US Senate Committee on Foreign Relations approved his</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 08:03:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Transport advisor visits Brahmanbaria for road inspection, gets stuck in traffic congestion</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/transport-advisor-visits-brahmanbaria-for-road-inspection-gets-stuck-in-traffic-congestion</link><description>Road Transport Advisor Fouzul Kabir Khan has got stuck in a traffic jam on his way to inspect the Brahmanbaria section of the Dhaka-Sylhet highway.
He reached Bhairab Railway Station in Kishoreganj by train on Wednesday morning. Later, on his way to Brahmanbaria by road, he stopped at Hotel &amp;ldquo</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 08:33:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hostel director detained after female Dhaka University student 'confined and beaten'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/hostel-director-detained-after-female-dhaka-university-student-confined-and-beaten</link><description>Police have detained the director of a private women’s hostel in the capital for allegedly assaulting a Dhaka University student who was visiting a friend there.
Razia Begum, director of Swapnonibas Women’s Hostel near Tejgaon College, was taken into custody around 10pm on Tuesday, acc</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 09:18:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Press Secretary demands release of Shahidul Alam, others</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/press-secretary-demands-release-of-shahidul-alam-others</link><description>Chief Adviser’s Press Secretary Shafiqul Alam on Wednesday demanded the immediate release of Shahidul Alam, a world-renowned photographer and human rights activist and all others from the flotilla.
"Shahidul stands as a shining embodiment of the unyielding spirit of Bangladesh. May Allah pro</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 09:48:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Kitagawa, Robson and Yaghi win 2025 Nobel Prize in Chemistry</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/kitagawa-robson-and-yaghi-win-2025-nobel-prize-in-chemistry</link><description>Scientists Susumu Kitagawa, Richard Robson and Omar Yaghi won the 2025 Nobel Prize in Chemistry "for the development of metal–organic frameworks", the award-giving body said on Wednesday.
 
The more than a century-old prize is awarded by the Royal Swedish Academy of Sciences and the wi</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 10:03:33 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>