<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 06:33:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Ancillaries dominate spending in WB-funded BBS capacity upgrade project</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ancillaries-receive-most-allocation-in-wb-funded-bbs-capacity-upgrade-project</link><description>Most money for a World Bank-funded development project for Bangladesh Bureau of Statistics (BBS) has been allocated for operational expenses on ancillaries that range from toiletries to foreign trainings, raising questions about justification.
On the wish-list are toilet tissues, toilet cleaning d</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 02:29:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh can stop 11pc GDP erosion if no child drops out of school: UNESCO Report</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh-can-stop-11pc-gdp-erosion-if-no-child-drops-out-of-school-unesco-report</link><description>Bangladesh could avert an economic loss equivalent to 11 per cent of its gross domestic product (GDP) by ensuring that no child drops out of school, according to a report by the United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization (UNESCO).
The potential gain could increase to as much</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 02:44:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Padma Oil logs record profit, declares highest-ever dividend</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/padma-oil-logs-record-profit-declares-highest-ever-dividend</link><description>Padma Oil has posted a record annual profit of Tk 5.63 billion for FY25, driven by higher sales and substantial non-operating income from bank deposits.
The state-run oil distributor also registered a 38 per cent year-on-year profit growth for the year, according to price-sensitive information pub</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 02:59:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>HC upholds fines on Beximco, BD Finance stock manipulators</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/hc-upholds-fines-on-beximco-bd-finance-stock-manipulators</link><description>The High Court (HC) has upheld the securities regulator's decision to impose fines on 22 investors, including individuals, for manipulating stock prices of Beximco and BD Finance.
In an order issued on Thursday, an HC bench comprising Justice Kazi Zinat Hoque and Justice Aynun Nahar Siddiqua valid</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 03:26:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP pledges to implement signed July Charter, urges parties not to derail polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-pledges-to-implement-signed-july-charter-urges-parties-not-to-block-polls-with-new-issues</link><description>BNP on Thursday reaffirmed its full commitment to implementing the “July National Charter”, signed on October 17, and urged all political parties not to raise new issues or create crises that could hinder the upcoming election.
The party made its position clear on the ongoing political</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 03:41:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No new licences for MFIs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/no-new-licences-for-mfis</link><description>No new licences will be issued to microfinance institutions (MFIs), as the microfinance sector in Bangladesh is now overcrowded, said Dr Mohammad Helal Uddin, Executive Vice Chairman of the Microcredit Regulatory Authority (MRA).
He made the remarks while speaking as the chief guest at an event or</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 03:56:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Consensus Commission bins claims of Tk 830m expenditure on hospitality</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/consensus-commission-bins-claims-of-tk-830-million-expenditure-on-hospitality</link><description>The National Consensus Commission (NCC) has refuted claims that it spent Tk 830 million on hospitality, stating that its total expenditure was Tk 17.1 million, of which Tk 4.5 million was spent on hospitality.
“A very recent campaign by a certain quarter has falsely alleged that the National</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 04:11:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tea yield in Sylhet feared to face a massive shortfall</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/tea-yield-in-sylhet-feared-to-face-a-massive-shortfall</link><description>Tea production in Sylhet region is apprehended to suffer a massive shortfall this year due to drought-induced foul weather and high prices of fertilisers.
Industry insiders anticipate the fall in tea yield while there's no chance to achieve the year's target as the main season of production has al</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 05:20:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Friendship receives Earthshot Prize 2025</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/friendship-receives-earthshot-prize-2025</link><description>Friendship, a Bangladeshi social purpose organisation, has been named the winner of the Earthshot Prize 2025 in the "Fix Our Climate" category.
The Earthshot is a global environmental award that was distributed first in 2021. The local NGO has been given the prestigious award for its integrated an</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 05:35:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>National Revolution and Solidarity Day being observed</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/national-revolution-and-solidarity-day-being-observed</link><description>The National Revolution and Solidarity Day is being observed today (Friday) across the country in a befitting manner.
On this day 50 years ago, Bangladesh began a new journey through a joint revolution of the members of the armed forces and mass people emerging from a state of chaos and uncertaint</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 05:50:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Four arrested over murder of BNP activist in Raozan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/four-arrested-over-murder-of-bnp-activist-in-raozan</link><description>Police have arrested four people in connection with the murder of a BNP activist in Chattogram’s Raozan upazila last month.
The arrestees are Abdullah Khokon alias Langra Khokon, Md Maruf, Saqlain Hossain, and Ziaur Rahman. Among them, Saqlain Hossain has been shown arrested in a separate ca</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 06:05:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Recently returned expatriate worker shot dead in Khulna</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/recently-returned-expatriate-worker-shot-dead-in-khulna</link><description>A Bangladeshi expatriate worker has been shot dead in Khulna’s Rupsha only a few days after he returned to the country.
The incident occurred next to a field owned by Manik Sardar in the Ramnagar area of Noihati Union around 9:00 pm on Thursday, bdnews24.com reports.
Mahfuzur Rahman, chief</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 06:20:58 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>