<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 09:20:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Digital addiction induces tech-violence against women</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/digital-addiction-induces-tech-violence-against-women</link><description>Digital addiction has become a serious problem in the country, especially for children and adolescents, as a large number of them are already trapped in depression and frustration, leading to self-destructive attitudes. The frequent appearance of new smartphone models, coupled with the rise in vari</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 04:54:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Small businesses in a time of strain</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/small-businesses-in-a-time-of-strain</link><description>It is hard to keep up with the dizzying pace at which the country is changing. Cityscapes are evolving every day. In almost every neighbourhood, new buildings have gone up in the last decade and, wherever space allows, more are still going up. These are the years of growth and modernisation that ha</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 05:09:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Getting back nation's stolen assets</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/getting-back-nations-stolen-assets</link><description>Though recovery of money and other assets laundered out of the country by those in power during the tenure of the ousted autocracy and their crony oligarchs was declared a priority by the interim government, yet, it has proved to be a very complex and audacious task. Despite efforts by the differen</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 05:24:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fardin’s father accuses Bushra of involvement, suspect’s family denies allegation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fardins-father-accuses-bushra-of-involvement-suspects-family-denies-allegation</link><description>The mystery behind the death of the Bangladesh University of Engineering and Technology (BUET) student Fardin Noor Parash remains unresolved nearly three years after the incident, as fresh disputes have emerged over the role of Amatullah Bushra, the sole suspect in the case.
Following political sh</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 05:39:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>James Watson, co-discoverer of DNA's double helix, dead at 97</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/james-watson-co-discoverer-of-dnas-double-helix-dead-at-97</link><description>James D Watson, the brilliant but controversial American biologist whose 1953 discovery of the structure of DNA, the molecule of heredity, ushered in the age of genetics and provided the foundation for the biotechnology revolution of the late 20th century, has died at the age of 97.
His death was</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 05:54:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>President Mohammad Shahabuddin reaches Pabna on two-day visit</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/president-mohammad-shahabuddin-reaches-pabna-on-two-day-visit</link><description>President Mohammad Shahabuddin reached his home district of Pabna on Saturday morning for a two-day official visit.
The President landed at Pabna Stadium by helicopter at 9:40 am, where he was received by Deputy Commissioner Mohammad Mofizul Islam and Pabna Police Superintendent Mortoza Ali Khan.</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 06:09:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Deaf woman crushed under train in Lalmonirhat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/deaf-woman-crushed-under-train-in-lalmonirhat</link><description>A 54-year-old deaf woman was crushed under the wheels of a train at the Burimari rail route in Hatibandha upazila of Lalmonirhat district on Saturday.
The deceased was identified as Janiron Begum, wife of Osman Goni of Singimari union, UNB reports.
Quoting witnesses, Mahmudur Nabi, officer-in-cha</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 06:24:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Iranian plot to kill Israel's ambassador to Mexico contained, US official says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/iranian-plot-to-kill-israels-ambassador-to-mexico-contained-us-official-says</link><description>Iran's Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps plotted to assassinate Israel's ambassador to Mexico starting late last year, but the effort was contained and there is no current threat, a US official said on Friday.
Mexico's government said later in the day it had "no information regarding an alleged at</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 07:25:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Türkiye issues arrest warrants for Netanyahu over Gaza 'genocide' charges</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/turkiye-issues-arrest-warrants-for-netanyahu-others-over-gaza-genocide-charges</link><description>Türkiye's Istanbul Chief Public Prosecutor's Office on Friday issued arrest warrants for 37 people, including Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu, on charges of "genocide" and "crimes against humanity."
The prosecutor's office said in a statement that the warrants followed an investigat</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 07:40:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC to begin political dialogues this week</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-to-begin-political-dialogues-this-week</link><description>Moving into the election mode, the Election Commission will start a series of dialogues with registered political parties this week to lay the groundwork for the upcoming national election scheduled for February.
But the political parties would be invited in groups to join the discussions due to t</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 07:55:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US sold sniper rifles to Brazil police unit tied to deadly raid</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-sold-sniper-rifles-to-brazil-police-unit-tied-to-deadly-raid</link><description>The US government approved a sale of sniper rifles to a deadly police unit in Brazil last year, overriding concerns from the US ambassador and other diplomats that the arms could be used in extrajudicial killings, according to three current and former US officials and documents seen by Reuters.
Th</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 08:10:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Primary teachers begin nonstop sit-in for 10th grade pay</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/primary-teachers-begin-nonstop-sit-in-for-10th-grade-pay</link><description>Assistant teachers from government primary schools have launched a continuous sit-in in Dhaka, demanding salaries under the 10th pay grade, along with two other demands.
The programme began on Saturday morning at the Central Shaheed Minar, where teachers from across the country converged to press</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 08:25:37 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>