<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 07:29:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>50 injured as supporters of ex-UP chairman, member clash in Habiganj</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/50-injured-as-supporters-of-ex-up-chairman-member-clash-in-habiganj</link><description>More than 50 people, including policemen, have been injured in a clash between supporters of a former Union Parishad chairman and a sitting member in Habiganj’s Ajmiriganj over a pre-existing dispute involving a waterbody lease.
The violence broke out around 8pm on Friday in Ujan Para villag</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 04:25:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Restoring law and order, investors' confidence biggest challenge for Bangladesh business</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/restoring-law-and-order-investors-confidence-biggest-challenge-for-bangladesh-business</link><description>Restoring law and order and rebuilding investor confidence remain the most pressing challenges for Bangladesh’s business sector, as the BNP-led government seeks to steer the economy out of a prolonged slowdown, business leaders and economists said.
They stressed that sustained stability and</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 04:40:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Vast web of cold gas observed at the heart of the Milky Way</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/vast-web-of-cold-gas-observed-at-the-heart-of-the-milky-way</link><description>Astronomers have produced the largest and most detailed map ever made of the vast web of cold cosmic gas stretching across the heart of our galaxy, showing thread-like filaments resembling rivers of material flowing through space that sometimes converge into bright clouds where new stars form.
Usi</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 04:55:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gold prices rise again in local market</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/gold-prices-rise-again-in-local-market</link><description>Gold prices in the local market have been increased again, with the price of the highest quality 22-carat gold rising by Tk 4,374 per bhori (11.664 grams) to Tk 265,414, according to the Bangladesh Jewellers Association (BAJUS).
The new prices came into effect from 10:30 am on Saturday, following</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 05:10:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>OIC to campaign for Bangladesh's UNGA bid: FM</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/oic-to-campaign-for-bangladeshs-unga-bid-fm</link><description>Member states of the Organisation of Islamic Cooperation (OIC) will actively campaign worldwide in support of Bangladesh's candidature for the presidency of the 81st session of the United Nations General Assembly (UNGA), Foreign Minister Dr Khalilur Rahman said on Saturday.
Speaking to reporters a</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 05:25:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rock band Radiohead urges US ICE to take down video using its song</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/rock-band-radiohead-urges-us-ice-to-take-down-video-using-its-song</link><description>British rock band Radiohead said on Friday it wanted a promotional video for the US Immigration and Customs Enforcement agency that used their song to be taken down.
ICE, whose immigration enforcement tactics have been widely condemned by human rights advocates during President Donald Trump's hard</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 05:40:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP activist killed over ‘enmity between two factions’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/bnp-activist-killed-over-enmity-between-two-factions</link><description>A BNP activist was beaten to death allegedly over enmity between two factions of the party at Sipaipara in Charghat upazila of Rajshahi district on Friday.
The deceased was identified as Ershad Ali, 65, a member of Yusufpur union unit BNP.
Sirajul Islam, Officer-in-Charge of Charghat Police Stati</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 05:55:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Elderly woman hacked to death, teenage granddaughter raped and killed in Pabna</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/elderly-woman-hacked-to-death-teenage-granddaughter-raped-and-killed-in-pabna</link><description>Police have recovered the bodies of a woman and her teenage granddaughter from Pabna's Ishwardi Upazila.
The 65-year-old grandmother's bloodied body was found in her home's courtyard on Saturday, while her 15-year-old granddaughter's naked body was discovered in a nearby mustard field, according t</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 06:10:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tram derails in central Milan leaving two dead, 40 injured</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/tram-derails-in-central-milan-leaving-two-dead-40-injured</link><description>Two people were killed and around 40 injured when a tram derailed in central Milan on Friday, a spokesperson for local firefighters said.
The tram, one of the newest models in operation in Milan, came off the tracks in Vittorio Veneto street, close to the city's Central Station, crashing into the</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 06:25:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rashed Akhtar elected president, Rashid-un-Nabi general secretary of Bankers Club of Bangladesh Limited</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/rashed-akhtar-elected-president-rashid-un-nabi-general-secretary-of-bankers-club-of-bangladesh-limited</link><description>Md. Rashed Akhtar and Rashid-un-Nabi were elected President and General Secretary, respectively, of Bankers Club of Bangladesh Limited on February 27, 2026, following the organization's executive committee elections.
Forty-seven candidates contested across two panels, the Bankers' Unity Council an</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 06:40:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladeshi arrested in US over ‘police impersonation scam’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladeshi-arrested-in-us-over-police-impersonation-scam</link><description>A suspected member of an organised fraud ring has been arrested in the United States over allegations of extorting money by posing as a law enforcer over the phone.
The expatriate Bangladeshi, Niamat Ullah, 31, a native of Chandpur who resides in Buffalo, New York, was held following a raid in U</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 06:55:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Israel says it has launched preventative attack against Iran</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/israel-has-launched-preventative-attack-against-iran-defence-minister-says</link><description>Israel has launched a preventative missile attack against Iran, the Israeli defence minister said on Saturday.
Israel’s military on Saturday said it had protectively sounded air raid sirens in areas across the country “to prepare the public for the possibility of missiles being launche</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 07:10:44 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>