<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 04:49:52 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Manikganj printing presses suffer loss amid election-time ban on posters</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/manikganj-printing-presses-suffer-loss-amid-election-time-ban-on-posters</link><description>Owners and workers of printing presses in Manikganj said they have lost a huge amount of income due to the ban on election related posters and if the ban prevails small presses will not survive.
After the Election Commission directed printing presses across the country not to print any posters for</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 02:09:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Foreign airliners make most of BD's aviation business as hosts falter</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/foreign-airliners-make-most-of-bds-aviation-business-as-hosts-falter</link><description>Passenger traffic on international routes from Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport (HSIA) in Dhaka is rising steadily but domestic airlines' market share stays stymied at a modest 40 per cent amid a descent.
The closure of several airlines over the past decades due to inadequate infrastructure</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 02:24:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Grameenphone profit hits 8-year low amid cost pressure</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/grameenphone-profit-hits-8-year-low-amid-cost-pressure</link><description>Grameenphone earned its lowest profit in eight years in 2025-Tk 29.6 billion-largely driven by cost pressure linked to recent investments in spectrum and the network, currency depreciation, and heavy taxes.
Its profit plunged 19 per cent year-on-year last year, reaching the record-low level.
Due</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 02:39:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BRAC Bank aims to boost financial inclusion with technology and trust</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/brac-bank-aims-to-boost-financial-inclusion-with-technology-and-trust</link><description>BRAC Bank aims to expand its financial inclusion footprint in the country's banking landscape by combining cutting-edge technology with institutional trust.
With a clear focus on broadening access to financial services, the leading commercial bank plans to target key areas such as school banking a</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 02:54:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt's overall borrowing soars Tk 50.10b in Q1</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/govts-overall-borrowing-soars-tk-5010b-in-q1</link><description>The government's overall debt stock stood at Tk 21.49 trillion at the end of the first quarter (Q1) of the current fiscal year, up by less than 1.0 per cent from June 2025, according to data from the finance ministry.
While the quarter-to-quarter increase appears modest, the year-on-year growth po</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 03:09:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BTRC drops plan to cut SIM limit to five</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/btrc-drops-plan-to-cut-sim-limit-to-five</link><description>Bangladesh's telecom regulator has withdrawn a proposal to reduce the maximum number of SIM cards per national identity (NID) from 10 to five following opposition from two mobile operators, reigniting debate over regulatory neutrality and the competitive consequences of policy interventions in the</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 02:41:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Israeli strikes kill 24 in Gaza</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/israeli-strikes-kill-24-in-gaza</link><description>Israeli tank shelling and airstrikes killed 24 Palestinians including seven children in Gaza on Wednesday, health officials said, the latest violence to undermine the nearly four-month-old ceasefire in the enclave.
Among the dead was a medic who rushed to help victims of a strike in the southern c</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 02:56:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Experts push for overhaul of tax system to boost investment</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/experts-push-for-overhaul-of-tax-system-to-boost-investment</link><description>Experts and economists have raised concerns over the complexities and inefficiencies within the supplementary duty (SD) and excise framework, calling for urgent business-friendly reforms to modernise the tax system and improve domestic resource mobilisation.
Speaking at a workshop on Tuesday, the</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 03:11:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Strong institutions key amid economic uncertainties’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/strong-institutions-key-amid-economic-uncertainties</link><description>Bangladesh urgently needs competent and resilient institutions to navigate mounting global and domestic pressures, including geopolitical tensions and the imminent challenges of graduating from least developed country (LDC) status, prominent businessman Mahbubur Rahman has said.
At a time of heigh</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 03:26:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>RU holds Div Youth Startup Summit</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ru-holds-div-youth-startup-summit</link><description>‘Rajshahi Divisional Youth Startup Summit 2026’ was held at the Rajshahi University (RU) to promote innovative thinking among young entrepreneurs and strengthen startup culture.
The day-long event was jointly organised by YOUReach and DEIED.
Held at Kazi Nazrul Islam Auditorium on the</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 03:41:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Survey signals high turnout, shifting votes</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/survey-signals-high-turnout-shifting-votes</link><description>With the 13th national parliamentary election approaching, a new nationwide survey suggests that voters are not only paying close attention but are also prepared to turn out in large numbers.
Nearly nine in ten respondents said they intend to cast their ballots, reflecting a level of enthusiasm th</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 03:56:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>July Charter written in blood: Ali Riaz</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/july-charter-written-in-blood-ali-riaz</link><description>Prof Ali Riaz, special assistant to the Chief Adviser, said although the printed copies appear in black ink, every letter of the July National Charter was written with the blood of the people of Bangladesh.
He made the remarks while speaking at a discussion titled "Public Awareness Campaign on the</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 04:11:50 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>