<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 11:25:52 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Evaly's Rassel, Shamima arrested again</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/evalys-rassel-shamima-arrested-again</link><description>Detectives have arrested Evaly Managing Director Mohammad Rassel and its Chairperson Shamima Nasrin in Dhaka.
A team of the Detective Branch (DB) detained them in the city’s Dhanmondi area early Tuesday, said Saiful Islam, officer-in-charge of Dhanmondi Police Station.
He said a total of 39</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 07:15:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Coordinated bid underway to manipulate election results, says Abbas</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/coordinated-bid-underway-to-manipulate-election-results-says-abbas</link><description>BNP Standing Committee member Mirza Abbas has alleged that a major party and a small one are making coordinated attempts to influence the outcome of the national election in several constituencies.
Speaking at a discussion meeting on Tuesday at the Diploma Engineers’ Institute in the capital</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 07:30:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Russia, Norway, Sweden, Denmark envoys hold talks with Tarique</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/russia-norway-sweden-denmark-envoys-hold-talks-with-tarique</link><description>The Ambassadors of Russia, Norway, Sweden and Denmark in Dhaka met BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman on Tuesday and discussed various issues related to bilateral interests and ways to strengthen future ties with Bangladesh.
The envoys of Norway, Sweden and Denmark in Dhaka first met Tarique around 11:00</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 07:35:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>4th BIMSTEC meeting on environment and climate change held in Thimphu</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/4th-bimstec-meeting-on-environment-and-climate-change-held-in-thimphu</link><description>The fourth meeting of the BIMSTEC Joint Working Group on Environment and Climate Change (JWG-ECC) was held in Bhutanese capital Thimphu recently, emphasising regional cooperation and the mobilisation of climate finance.
The two-day meeting was hosted by Bhutan, the lead country for the Environment</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 07:50:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Students firm on SUCSU polls as SUST plans chamber court move</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/students-firm-on-sucsu-polls-as-sust-plans-chamber-court-move</link><description>Shahjalal University of Science and Technology (SUST) students have remained firm in their demand for the long-awaited central students’ union (SUCSU) elections, following a High Court order suspending the vote.
In response to the mounting pressure, the university administration confirmed it</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 08:05:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Students protest for SUST polls, issue warning</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/students-protest-for-sust-polls-issue-warning</link><description>Students at the Shahjalal University of Science and Technology (SUST) and the candidates vying for seats in its central student union (SUCSU) are continuing protests pushing for the polls.
They organised a protest outside the Administration Building-1 from 12:45 pm on Tuesday, demanding a hearing</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 08:20:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh not to accept any illogical ICC conditions under Indian pressure: Sports Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/bangladesh-not-to-accept-any-illogical-icc-conditions-under-indian-pressure-sports-adviser</link><description>Youth and Sports Adviser Asif Nazrul on Tuesday said Bangladesh will not accept any unreasonable conditions if the ICC creates pressure on the country under the influence of the Indian Cricket Board.
"If the International Cricket Council (ICC) bows to pressure from the Indian Cricket Board and tri</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 08:35:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP awaits landslide victory; some parties don’t want election: Fakhrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-awaits-landslide-victory-some-parties-dont-want-election-fakhrul</link><description>BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir on Tuesday claimed that his party is set for a landslide victory in the national election and alleged this is why some parties are trying to block it.
“Only 23 days are left before the election. In these few days, many parties are saying they</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 09:37:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Court orders seizure of 463 decimals of land owned by S Alam Group</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/court-orders-seizure-of-463-decimals-of-land-owned-by-s-alam-group</link><description>A Dhaka court ordered the seizure of 463 decimals of land owned by Mohammed Saiful Alam, chairman of the S Alam Group, accused of being a bank defaulter.
The order was passed by the Metropolitan Senior Special Judge and Metropolitan Sessions Judge Court, Dhaka, following applications filed by the</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 09:52:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>University of Asia Pacific shuts down indefinitely amid protests over 'blasphemy'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/university-of-asia-pacific-shuts-down-indefinitely-amid-protests-over-blasphemy</link><description>The University of Asia Pacific (UAP) has declared an indefinite shutdown following days of student protests over allegations of “blasphemy” and the dismissal of two teachers.
The university has remained shut since Tuesday, bdnews24.com reports.
Although academic activities were formal</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 10:07:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Grief grips slain RAB officer’s Cumilla village home</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/grief-grips-slain-rab-officers-cumilla-village-home</link><description>A wave of sorrow swept through Alipur village in Cumilla’s Adarsha Sadar upazila as family members, relatives, and neighbours were left in shock following the killing of RAB officer Motaleb Hossain.
Motaleb, Deputy Assistant Director (DAD) of RAB-7, was shot dead and three others were injure</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 10:22:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CA orders recovery of ‘looted weapons’ before election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ca-orders-quick-recovery-of-looted-weapons-ahead-of-election</link><description>Chief Advisor Muhammad Yunus has directed authorities to quickly recover illegal firearms and weapons looted from police stations ahead of the 13th general election.
He issued the directive at a meeting of the National Implementation Committee on Administrative Reorganisation (NICAR) at the State</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 10:37:49 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>