<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 09:21:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Dry weather likely</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dry-weather-likely-16000</link><description>The Bangladesh Meteorological Department (BMD) has forecasted dry weather with partly cloudy sky across the country for the next 24 hours, beginning at 9:00 am today (Tuesday).
"Light rain is likely to occur at one or two places over the Chattogram division. Weather may remain mainly dry with part</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 05:54:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Man stabbed dead in Chuadanga clash</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/man-stabbed-dead-in-chuadanga-clash</link><description>A man was killed and three others were injured in a clash between two groups of villagers at Gobindahuda village in Damurhuda upazila of Chuadanga district on Tuesday.
The deceased was identified as Joynur, 53 of the village, reports UNB.
Quoting local people, Humayun Kabir, officer-in-charge of</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 06:09:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Businesses raise edible oil prices without government approval: Commerce Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/businesses-raise-edible-oil-prices-without-government-approval-commerce-adviser</link><description>Commerce Adviser Sk Bashir Uddin on Tuesday said businesses have increased edible oil prices without the government's approval, which is beyond their authority.
"The government has not raised edible oil prices, nor has it given any permission to businesses to do so. Businesses do not have the auth</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 06:39:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No scope for NCP to get ‘shapla’ symbol: EC Secretary</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/no-scope-for-ncp-to-get-shapla-symbol-ec-secretary</link><description>Election Commission (EC) Senior Secretary Akhtar Ahmed has said that the National Citizen Party (NCP) will not be allotted the ‘Shapla’ (water lily) symbol. The party has been asked to select an alternative symbol and inform the commission by October 19.
“If the NCP fails to choo</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 08:09:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Process to receive bail bonds online begins Wednesday: Asif Nazrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/process-to-receive-bail-bonds-online-begins-wednesday-asif-nazrul</link><description>Law, Justice and Parliamentary Affairs Adviser Dr Asif Nazrul on Tuesday said the process of receiving bail bonds online will begin on a trial basis tomorrow (Wednesday), enabling bail documents to reach prisons directly with a single click.
“After a person secures bail, there are reportedly</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 08:24:26 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>