<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 08:32:13 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Teachers announce 'complete shutdown' of primary schools</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/teachers-announce-complete-shutdown-of-primary-schools</link><description>Government primary school teachers in Bangladesh have announced a nationwide “complete shutdown” from Wednesday as part of their ongoing protest over pay and promotion demands.
The Primary Teachers’ Demand Implementation Council, which is leading the movement, made the announceme</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 05:32:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tetulia continues to witness lowest temperature</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tetulia-continues-to-witness-lowest-temperature</link><description>Tetulia continued to record the lowest temperature of the day at 11.1 degrees Celsius on Wednesday, while the Bangladesh Meteorological Department (BMD) has forecast generally dry weather with temporarily partly cloudy skies over most parts of the country during the next 24 hours, beginning at 9:00</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 05:47:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New-look Tk 500 banknote set to hit the market</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/new-look-tk-500-banknote-set-to-hit-the-market</link><description>Bangladesh Bank is releasing a new design for the Tk 500 note in the market. These new notes feature depictions of Bangladesh’s historic and archaeological landmarks
After the 2024 student-led mass uprising, the interim government decided to redesign all denominations of currency in circulat</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 06:02:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Arbitrary pricing’ turns Barapukuria coal into ‘windfall’ for staff, ‘financial burden’ for PDB</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/arbitrary-pricing-turns-barapukuria-coal-into-windfall-for-staff-financial-burden-for-pdb</link><description>For nearly a year, a domestic coal pricing dispute between Bangladesh’s Power Division and Energy Division has created friction between the state-owned Bangladesh Power Development Board (PDB) and the Barapukuria Coal Mining Company Limited (BCMCL).
At the heart of the conflict lies the pric</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 06:19:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Culvert repair forces single-track train movement, disrupting schedules at Kamalapur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/culvert-repair-forces-single-track-train-movement-disrupting-schedules-at-kamalapur</link><description>Services at Dhaka’s Kamalapur Railway Station have faced widespread delays after repair work on a culvert in Tejgaon forced all trains to operate on a single track for several hours.
Passengers arriving at the station on Wednesday said they were not informed of the disruption when purchasing</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 06:34:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India's Congress seeks parliament debate on state-run app for smartphones</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/indias-congress-seeks-parliament-debate-on-state-run-app-for-smartphones</link><description>India's main opposition party said on Wednesday that a government plan to preload a state-run app on smartphones violates the privacy of users and the government needed to explain itself, escalating tensions on a matter that has sparked surveillance fears.
The Indian government has confidentially</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 06:49:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Killing of 8 puppies: Ishwardi govt officer's wife arrested</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/killing-of-8-puppies-ishwardi-govt-officers-wife-arrested</link><description>Police have arrested a government officer's wife suspected of killing eight puppies that were stuffed into a sack and drowned in a pond in Pabna’s Ishwardi Upazila.
Nishi Rahman, 38, was detained on Tuesday in connection with a case filed by livestock officials under the Animal Welfare Act,</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 07:04:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>28th anniversary of CHT accord celebrated</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/28th-anniversary-of-cht-accord-celebrated</link><description>The 28th anniversary of the historic Chittagong Hill Tracts (CHT) Peace Accord was observed on Tuesday with a renewed call for harmony, cooperation, and inclusive development in the hill region.
The Ministry of Chittagong Hill Tracts Affairs marked the occasion by organising a seminar titled &amp;ldqu</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 07:04:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cloth on overhead cable halts Metro Rail for 16 minutes</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cloth-on-overhead-cable-halts-metro-rail-for-16-minutes</link><description>Metro rail services were suspended for 16 minutes on Wednesday after a piece of cloth got entangled in the overhead electric cable between Uttara North and Uttara South stations.
According to Dhaka Mass Transit Company Limited (DMTCL), train movement came to a halt at 12:22 pm when the cloth fell</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 07:19:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Miscreants hack woman to death at her house</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/miscreants-hack-woman-to-death-at-her-house</link><description>A woman was killed, and her niece was injured in an attack by miscreants at their house in Joypurhat Sadar upazila early Wednesday.  
The deceased was identified as Nurunnahar Begum, 47, a resident of Chirla village under Chak Barkat union of the upazila, and her injured niece is Khatija Khat</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 07:34:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Eden College students block road over 5-point demand</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/eden-college-students-block-road-over-5-point-demand</link><description>Students of Dhaka's Eden Mohila College have taken to the streets to press home a five-point demand that includes greater autonomy for the institution.
The protesters descended on the road in front of the college around 11:00 am on Wednesday, chanting slogans to emphasise their demands, reports bd</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 07:49:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Over 156,000 Bangladeshi expats register to vote so far</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/over-156000-bangladeshi-expats-register-to-vote-so-far</link><description>More than 156,000 expatriate Bangladeshi voters from different countries have so far registered through the mobile app ‘Postal Vote Bd’ since November 19 to vote in the upcoming national election and the referendum, both to be held on a single day in early February 2026.
The Election C</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 08:04:35 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>