<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 06:38:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Maduro pleads not guilty to US drug charges</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/maduro-pleads-not-guilty-to-us-drug-charges</link><description>Toppled Venezuelan President Nicolas Maduro pleaded not guilty on Monday to narcotics charges after President Donald Trump's stunning capture of him rattled world leaders and left officials in Caracas scrambling to regroup.
"I am innocent. I am not guilty. I am a decent man. I am still president o</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 02:59:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Beacon Pharma under probe over alleged illicit transactions with sister concerns</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/beacon-pharma-under-probe-over-alleged-illicit-transactions-with-sister-concerns</link><description>The stock market watchdog has launched an investigation into Beacon Pharmaceuticals based on an intelligence report from the central bank alleging money laundering and market fraud.
The Bangladesh Securities and Exchange Commission (BSEC) has directed the three-member investigation committee to co</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 03:14:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Square Pharma MD to purchase 2m shares from market</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/square-pharma-md-to-purchase-2m-shares-from-market</link><description>The managing director of Square Pharmaceuticals, Tapan Chowdhury, is set to buy 2 million shares of the company at the current market price, according to a market filing on Monday.
Shares would be purchased from both the main board and block market of the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) within the next</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 03:27:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Voting underway in maiden JnUCSU elections</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/voting-underway-in-maiden-jnucsu-elections-amid-festive-atmosphere</link><description>Voting in the Jagannath University Central Students’ Union (JnUCSU) and Hall Students’ Union elections began on Tuesday in a festive and peaceful atmosphere.
Polling started at around 9:00 am and will continue uninterrupted until 3:30 pm.
Students began casting their votes in the morn</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 03:42:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Apparel leaders fear major challenges in 2026</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/apparel-leaders-fear-major-challenges-in-2026</link><description>Apparel sector leaders fear the industry will continue to face major challenges in 2026, followed by relatively weak consumer demands amid sluggish economic growth and persistent inflationary pressures in the major markets, including the US and the European Union (EU).
They, however, believe the u</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 03:57:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>After Line-6, other MRT projects stall</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/after-line-6-other-mrt-projects-stall</link><description>Despite significant interest from global lenders, the development of the Mass Rapid Transit (MRT) network in the capital remains largely at a standstill.
With the exception of the operational MRT Line-6, the five other projects have been deferred as the government scrutinises their high costs and</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 04:12:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Courtroom shortage forces 200 lower court judges to share facilities</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/courtroom-shortage-forces-200-lower-court-judges-to-share-facilities</link><description>At least 200 lower court judges across the country are being forced to share courtrooms due to an acute shortage of facilities, according to officials of the Supreme Court (SC) Registry.
The situation has led to a significant loss of judicial productivity and is ultimately denying litigants timely</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 04:27:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Whole incident involving Tahrima fabricated: Nahid</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/whole-incident-involving-tahrima-fabricated-nahid</link><description>National Citizen Party (NCP) Convener Nahid Islam on Monday said the entire incident involving Tahrima Jannat Surovi, popularly known as a “July warrior”, was false and fabricated.
Tahrima, who was granted bail and released from jail on Monday night, did not receive justice, Nahid said</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 04:42:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>At least 35 people killed and 1,200 detained in Iran’s economic protests</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/at-least-35-people-killed-and-1200-detained-in-irans-economic-protests</link><description>The death toll in violence surrounding protests in Iran has risen to at least 35 people, activists said Tuesday, as the demonstrations showed no signs of stopping.
The figure came from the US-based Human Rights Activists News Agency, which said more than 1,200 people have been detained in the prot</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 04:57:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A third of Americans support US strike on Venezuela, Reuters poll finds</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/a-third-of-americans-support-us-strike-on-venezuela-reuters-poll-finds</link><description>One in three Americans approves of the US military strike on Venezuela that toppled the country's president and 72% worry the US will become too involved in the South American country, according to a Reuters/Ipsos poll that concluded on Monday.
The two-day poll showed 65% of Republicans back the m</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 05:12:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Over a dozen media workers detained in Venezuela</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/over-a-dozen-media-workers-detained-in-venezuela-says-national-press-association</link><description>More than a dozen media workers were detained on Monday while covering events in the Venezuelan capital Caracas, including a march in support of ousted President Nicolas Maduro and the swearing-in of the country's new legislature, the South American nation's press association said.
All 14 of those</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 05:27:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CIA concludes regime loyalists best suited to lead Venezuela after Maduro</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/cia-concludes-regime-loyalists-best-suited-to-lead-venezuela-after-maduro</link><description>A classified CIA assessment presented to US President Donald Trump concluded senior Maduro loyalists, including Vice President Delcy Rodriguez, were best positioned to maintain stability if the Venezuelan leader lost power, two sources briefed on the matter said on Monday.
The sources, speaking on</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 05:42:20 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>