<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 16:25:39 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>AB Bank wins Mastercard Excellence Award</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ab-bank-wins-mastercard-excellence-award</link><description>AB Bank won the `Mastercard Excellence Award- 2025’ in the category of Mastercard Credit Business (Domestic) for the year 2024-2025.
Mr. Syed Mizanur Rahman, Managing Director &amp; CEO of AB Bank, received this honor on behalf of the bank from Mr. Md. Zakir Hossain Chowdhury, Deputy Governor of</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 12:45:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>MoU signing ceremony between Trust Bank &amp; Chuti Group</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/mou-signing-ceremony-between-trust-bank-chuti-group</link><description>A Memorandum of Understanding (MoU) has been signed between Trust Bank PLC and Chuti Group where Md Mostafa Musharrof, Head of Card Division, Trust Bank PLC and Md Mostofa Mahmud Arifee, Chairman, Chuti group, have signed the MoU on behalf of their respective organisations.
Under this agreement, a</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 13:00:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Four injured in Manikganj clash over Baul Abul Sarkar’s arrest</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/four-injured-in-manikganj-clash-over-baul-abul-sarkars-arrest</link><description>At least four people, including three followers of Baul Abul Sarkar Moharaj, were injured on Sunday after clashes broke out in Manikganj over rival programmes announced by two groups following the singer’s arrest on charges of hurting religious sentiment.
The three injured followers are Abdu</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 13:15:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khaleda admitted to Evercare Hospital for medical tests</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/khaleda-admitted-to-evercare-hospital-for-medical-tests-1</link><description>BNP Chairperson Khaleda Zia has been admitted to Evercare Hospital for medical examinations.
Her personal physician AZM Zahid Hossain confirmed the matter on Sunday.
Following the advice of her medical board, she is staying in a private cabin for a series of tests, he said.
 “The boar</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 13:30:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat team meets Bhutan PM</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-team-meets-bhutan-pm</link><description>A Jamaat-e-Islami delegation, led by its chief Shafiqur Rahman, has met with Bhutanese Prime Minister Tshering Tobgay in Dhaka.
The meeting took place on Sunday at the InterContinental Dhaka.
In a media statement, Jamaat said the discussion was held in a cordial and friendly atmosphere.
The dele</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 13:45:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Day-long 'Anti Money Laundering' conference held in Khulna region</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/day-long-anti-money-laundering-conference-held-in-khulna-region</link><description>A day-long “Anti-Money Laundering Conference” was held in the Khulna region, organized by the Association of Anti-Money Laundering Compliance Officers of Banks in Bangladesh (AACOBB) in collaboration with the Bangladesh Financial Intelligence Unit (BFIU) on Saturday, November 22, 2025.</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 14:00:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh Election: Over 18,000 expatriates registered to vote</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-election-over-18000-expatriates-registered-to-vote</link><description>More than 18,000 expatriate Bangladeshis from 53 countries have registered through a mobile app titled ‘Postal Vote Bd’ to vote in the 13th parliamentary election, likely to be held in early February 2026.
As of 8:45 pm on Sunday, a total of 18,374 expatriates—16,765 males and 1,</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 14:15:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>401st board meeting of Shahjalal Islami Bank held</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/401st-board-meeting-of-shahjalal-islami-bank-held</link><description>The 401st meeting of the Board of Directors of Shahjalal Islami Bank PLC was held on 19th November 2025 at the Corporate Head Office of the bank.
The meeting was presided over by the Chairman Mr. A. K. Azad. The Board approved a number of investment proposal, according to a press release.
Among o</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 14:30:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IGP leaves for Morocco to attend Interpol General Assembly</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/igp-leaves-for-morocco-to-attend-interpol-general-assembly</link><description>Inspector General of Police (IGP) Baharul Alam left Dhaka on Sunday morning for Morocco to attend the 93rd General Assembly of Interpol.
The four-day conference, scheduled from November 24–27 in Marrakech, will bring together high-level representatives from 196 member countries.
The IGP is</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 14:45:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pubali Bank holds ‘Annual Risk Conference 2025’ to uphold excellence, innovation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/pubali-bank-holds-annual-risk-conference-2025-to-uphold-excellence-innovation</link><description>Committed to its tradition of excellence and innovation, Pubali Bank PLC strives to provide the best banking services to its customers, according to a press release.
To ensure robust risk management and regulatory compliance, the bank organized the ‘Annual Risk Conference 2025’ recentl</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 15:00:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Islami Bank receives MasterCard Excellence Awards-2025</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/islami-bank-receives-mastercard-excellence-awards-2025</link><description>Islami Bank Bangladesh PLC received MasterCard Excellence Awards-2025 in three categories, according to a press release.
The bank won the “Excellence in MasterCard Prepaid Business (Cross-Border), “Excellence in MasterCard Debit Business (Cross-Border) and “Excellence in MasterCa</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 15:15:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EXIM Bank holds Business Development Conference in Cumilla Region</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/exim-bank-holds-business-development-conference-in-cumilla-region</link><description>EXIM Bank held a Business Development Conference for the Cumilla Region on Saturday, according to a press release.
Administrator of EXIM Bank and Executive Director of Bangladesh Bank Md. Sawkatul Alam attended the conference as the Chief Guest. Regional Manager of the Cumilla Region Md. Maksudul</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 15:30:53 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>