<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 04:11:33 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Chasing wild goose of siphoned money</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/chasing-wild-goose-of-siphoned-money</link><description>Industrial stagnation and shrinking private investment have resulted in 1.4 million people's loss of jobs, who are now out on the streets, said former FBCCI president A.K. Azad, also, Managing Director of the Ha-Meem Group, while speaking at a discussion event styled, "Bangladesh Economic Conferenc</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 16:11:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Danger of population growth beyond limits</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/danger-of-population-growth-beyond-limits</link><description>At a time when election, referendum and lease of seaports hog newspaper headlines, some highly important issues receive scant attention. One such issue is population growth in a country that is already gasping for breath under the weight of an outsize people. According to a survey, "Multiple Indica</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 16:26:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Population control in reverse gear</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/population-control-in-reverse-gear</link><description>It is highly alarming that after decades of steady progress, the country's population control is now in reverse gear. Government agencies appear to have lost control of population growth, leading to an undesirable increase in the birth rate. A nationwide survey, jointly conducted by the UNICEF and</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 17:45:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Government hikes fuel prices by Tk 2 per litre</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/government-hikes-fuel-prices-by-tk-2-per-litre</link><description>In step with global trends, the government has hiked the domestic price of all fuel types by Tk 2 per litre.
The Ministry of Power, Energy and Mineral Resources announced the revision in a statement on Sunday, confirming that the new rates will take effect from midnight, bdnews24.com reports.
Und</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 18:00:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>SC upholds HC bail for DU Prof Karzon</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/sc-upholds-hc-bail-for-du-prof-karzon</link><description>The Supreme Court on Sunday upheld a High Court order granting bail to Dhaka University professor Hafizur Rahman Karzon in a case filed under the Anti-Terrorism Act, 2009.
Justice Md Rezaul Haque, chamber judge of the Appellate Division, passed “no order” on a petition filed by the sta</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 18:15:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Public may take to streets again if election malpractices continue: Badiul Alam Majumdar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/public-may-take-to-streets-again-if-election-malpractices-continue-badiul-alam-majumdar</link><description>Prominent election reformer Dr. Badiul Alam Majumdar warned on Sunday that the public may be forced back into streets if upcoming national elections are conducted without curbing deep-rooted corruption and malpractices.
Dr. Majumdar, head of the Election Reform Commission and Secretary of SUJON, m</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 18:30:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>1.4m manufacturing jobs lost in a decade</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/14m-manufacturing-jobs-lost-in-a-decade</link><description>Bangladesh's productive sector has seen an impressive average annual growth rate of 10 per cent over a decade, spanning 2013-2023, but failed to translate into a corresponding rise in employment.



In fact, the manufacturing sector has shed 1.4 million jobs during this period. Economists are</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 19:30:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>People pay dearly for high health cost</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/people-pay-dearly-for-high-health-cost</link><description>People pay through their nose for high health cost as government hospitals in Bangladesh serve only 11.2 per cent of the population by an official count.
Of the rest, more than half of the population depends on pharmacy or dispensary or rural doctors for treatment, Bangladesh Bureau of Statistics</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 02:00:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>China's EXIM Bank warns Payra power plant over delayed repayment</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/exim-bank-warns-payra-power-plant-over-delayed-repayment</link><description>China's EXIM Bank has warned the Bangladesh-China Power Company Ltd (BCPCL) that its failure to repay a US$129 million loan instalment due in early December could trigger a formal default event, potentially affecting other projects in Bangladesh financed by the bank.
The bank issued the caution af</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 02:15:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh Bank buys $54m to stabilise exchange rate</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladesh-bank-buys-54m-to-stabilise-exchange-rate</link><description>The Bangladesh Bank (BB) purchased an additional US$54 million through an auction from four banks in the interbank spot market on Sunday, aiming to stabilise the exchange rate of the US dollar against the local currency.
The amount was bought under the Multiple Price Auction method, with the cutof</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 02:30:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Recast policy redefines compensation to landowners in Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/recast-policy-redefines-compensation-to-landowners-in-dhaka</link><description>A major policy change in land acquisition envisages abolishing compensation to the city landowners and instead encouraging them to get engaged in the development activities with revised property rights staying within respective areas.
Rajdhani Unnayan Kartripakkhya (RAJUK) has made the move to ame</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 03:15:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Debt servicing surpasses foreign aid commitments</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/debt-servicing-surpasses-foreign-aid-commitments</link><description>Bangladesh's debt servicing has exceeded foreign aid commitments in the first four months of the current fiscal year, as both interest and principal repayments on external loans have risen, according to official data.
Economic Relations Division (ERD) figures show that the government repaid US$1.5</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 03:30:50 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>