<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 16:29:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Another 174 Bangladeshis return home from Libya</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/another-174-bangladeshis-return-home-from-libya</link><description>Another 174 Bangladeshi nationals returned home from Libya on Tuesday. They arrived at Dhaka at 2:30 pm aboard a Burak Air chartered flight, according to a press release from the Ministry of Foreign Affairs.
The repatriation was coordinated by the Bangladesh Embassy in Libya, the Ministry of Forei</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 13:22:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Senior lecturer post abolished in revised MPO policy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-abolishes-senior-lecturer-post-in-updated-mpo-policy</link><description>The government has abolished the senior lecturer post in higher secondary schools and colleges by amending the MPO policy for private educational institutions.
Alongside this, the Ministry of Education’s Secondary and Higher Education Division has issued a circular revising the eligibility c</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 13:52:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP raises objection over RPO amendments</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-writes-to-law-ministry-over-rpo-provision-on-contesting-under-party-symbol</link><description>The Bangladesh Nationalist Party has written to the law ministry objecting to a clause in the amended Representation of the People Order (RPO) that obliges candidates in alliances to contest under their own party symbol, after earlier raising the issue with the Election Commission.
The party wants</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 14:22:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Global commitments on climate finance must be fulfilled: Rizwana</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/global-commitments-on-climate-finance-must-be-fulfilled-rizwana</link><description>Ensuring climate justice requires Bangladesh to revisit its development vision by prioritising mitigation and transforming unsustainable patterns of consumption, said Syeda Rizwana Hasan, Advisor to the Ministry of Environment, Forest and Climate Change, and the Ministry of Water Resources.
She em</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 14:37:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Canada to work with G7 partners to secure critical mineral supply deals, minister says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/canada-to-work-with-g7-partners-to-secure-critical-mineral-supply-deals-minister-says</link><description>Canada will focus on securing supplies of critical minerals when it hosts its Group of Seven partners this week at a meeting of energy and environment ministers in Toronto, Natural Resources Minister Tim Hodgson said in an interview on Tuesday.
G7 countries, except Japan, are heavily or exclusivel</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 14:52:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ADB-funded entrepreneur development training launched in Manikganj</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/adb-funded-entrepreneur-development-training-launched-in-manikganj</link><description>A month-long Entrepreneur Development Training Program has been launched in Manikganj under the ‘Skills for Industry Competitiveness and Innovation Program (SICIP)’, implemented by the Finance Division of the Ministry of Finance with financial support from the Asian Development Bank (AD</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 15:07:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BUET undergraduate applications open on Nov 16</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/buet-undergraduate-applications-open-on-nov-16</link><description>Applications for admission to undergraduate programmes at the Bangladesh University of Engineering and Technology (BUET) for the 2025-26 academic year will run from Nov 16 through to Dec 2.
According to the admission circular issued on Monday, applicants will be able to submit the fees until Dec 4</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 15:22:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Community Bank launches Community SME 360° to empower SMEs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/community-bank-launches-community-sme-360-to-empower-smes</link><description>Community Bank Bangladesh PLC has announced the official launch of “Community SME 360°,” a pioneering, all-in-one platform designed to accelerate the growth and success of small and medium enterprises (SMEs) across Bangladesh.
This landmark initiative represents a transformative st</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 15:37:27 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>