<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 08:36:32 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Aviation safety a concern as stray dogs on prowl</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/aviation-safety-a-concern-as-stray-dogs-on-prowl</link><description>Unhindered movement of stray dogs on the runway of Cox's Bazar Airport has emerged as a serious aviation safety concern, putting aircraft operations at risk and causing growing anxiety among passengers and airlines.
Over the past five months, at least two accidents were reported in which stray dog</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 03:50:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>RAB arrests suspect in murder of schoolgirl in Banasree</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rab-arrests-suspect-in-murder-of-schoolgirl-in-banasree</link><description>The Rapid Action Battalion (RAB) has arrested Milon, a suspect in the murder of a schoolgirl whose body was found with its throat slit at a house in Dhaka’s South Banasree.
The elite police unit says Milon, a restaurant worker, was arrested from the Boro Singha area of Bagerhat Sadar Thana e</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 04:34:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Draft import policy awaits cabinet approval</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/draft-import-policy-awaits-cabinet-approval</link><description>The draft of a new Import Policy Order (IPO) for 2025-2028 has been prepared, featuring major changes in the existing IPO for 2021-2024, Commerce Adviser Sk Bashir Uddin said on Sunday.
"We are trying to bring significant changes to the import policy order. Once these are finalised through the cab</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 04:49:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NEIR rollout being rushed without adequate consultation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/neir-rollout-being-rushed-without-adequate-consultation</link><description>Mobile phone traders have alleged that the implementation of the National Equipment Identity Register (NEIR) is being rushed without adequate consultation, potentially causing hardship for small traders and raising concerns among consumers.
At a press conference on Sunday afternoon at the Dhaka Re</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 05:04:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>RCCI polls to be held Jan 15</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/rcci-polls-to-be-held-jan-15</link><description>The Rajshahi Chamber of Commerce and Industry (RCCI) elections will be held on January 15.
Local traders are now feeling enthusiastic about the biennial polls, as they are eagerly waiting to exercise their franchise.
On Saturday, independent president candidate, Abdul Awal Khan Chowdhury Jyoti, w</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 05:19:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mild cold wave may continue in eight districts: Met Office</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/mild-cold-wave-may-continue-in-eight-districts-met-office</link><description>The Meteorological Department on Monday reported that a mild cold wave is currently sweeping Rajshahi, Pabna, Dinajpur, Panchagarh, Nilphamari, Jashore, Chuadanga, and Kushtia, and is expected to continue.
Weather is expected to remain generally dry with temporary partly cloudy skies over the coun</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 05:34:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh rolls out nationwide campaign to raise referendum awareness</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-rolls-out-nationwide-campaign-to-raise-referendum-awareness</link><description>The government has launched a series of nationwide programmes aimed at raising public awareness about the upcoming referendum, according to the Chief Advisor’s Office (CAO).
In a statement issued on Monday, the CAO said the initiative is intended to address confusion about the referendum at</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 05:49:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>First Hajj flights take off on Apr 18</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/first-hajj-flights-take-off-on-apr-18</link><description>The first flights carrying Bangladeshi pilgrims to Saudi Arabia for Hajj will depart on Apr 18.
On the opening day, eight flights are scheduled to transport 3,255 pilgrims from Bangladesh, according to officials.
Under new instructions from Saudi authorities, pilgrims registered under the same Ha</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 06:04:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Youth killed in motorcycle accident in Maheshpur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/youth-killed-in-motorcycle-accident-in-maheshpur</link><description>A motorcyclist was killed after his motorcycle went out of control and crashed into a tree in Maheshpur upazila of the district on Sunday evening.
The deceased was identified as Rakibul Hasan Azad, 20, son of Abdur Rashid of Natima Bogapara village under Maheshpur upazila.
According to eyewitness</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 06:19:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat’s Fazlul loses bid to regain Ctg-9 candidacy over dual citizenship</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaats-fazlul-loses-bid-to-regain-ctg-9-candidacy-over-dual-citizenship</link><description>Jamaat-e-Islami's AKM Fazlul Haque has failed to win back his candidacy for the Chattogram-9 constituency after the Election Commission (EC) rejected his appeal, citing dual citizenship.
Fazlul's nomination papers were rejected after scrutiny as he failed to provide documents proving that he had f</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 08:00:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Youth found dead in Dhaka’s Kuril</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/youth-found-dead-in-dhakas-kuril</link><description>The body of an unidentified young man, aged over 20, was recovered from a footpath behind the BRTA counter on Kuril Biswa Road in Dhaka on Monday.
Pedestrians took the youth to Dhaka Medical College Hospital in an unconscious state around 10:45 am, where doctors at the emergency department pronoun</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 08:15:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BB allows 270-day credit for LPG imports</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bb-allows-270-day-credit-for-lpg-imports</link><description>Bangladesh Bank (BB) has relaxed import rules for liquefied petroleum gas, permitting importers to use credit facilities of up to 270 days, a move aimed at easing dollar liquidity pressure and ensuring steady LPG supplies in the domestic market.
Under the new arrangement, LPG imports will now be t</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 08:30:41 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>