<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 23:18:29 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Frequent fires prompt govt probe</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/government-forms-core-committee-to-examine-three-major-fires-prevent-future-disasters</link><description>Following several major fires recently, the interim government has formed a seven-strong “core committee” to investigate their causes, helmed by the home secretary.
Disaster Management Advisor Faruk E Azam confirmed the development on Sunday, adding that the committee may expand in the</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 16:21:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Buendia seals comeback win for Villa at Spurs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/buendia-seals-comeback-win-for-villa-at-spurs</link><description>Emiliano Buendia came off the bench to secure Aston Villa an impressive 2-1 comeback win at Tottenham Hotspur in the Premier League on Sunday after Morgan Rogers struck a superb equaliser for the visitors.
Spurs made a flying start when Rodrigo Bentancur put them in front with a close-range finish</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 15:51:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Various dimensions of renewable energy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/various-dimensions-of-renewable-energy</link><description>Renewable energy has overtaken coal as the world's leading source of electricity in the first half of this year -- a historic first, according to new data from the global energy think tank 'Ember'.
Electricity demand, as we all know,  is growing around the world but the growth in solar and wi</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 16:21:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Market volatility beyond demand-supply rules</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/market-volatility-beyond-demand-supply-rules</link><description>Rain was the pretext for green chilli hitting the Tk 400 a kilo mark. Other vegetables, except green papya, did not lag far behind to the consternation of consumers. Now after the rain has been replaced by sunny days, eggs have suddenly registered a price hike of Tk 10 for a dozen from Tk 140 to Tk</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 16:36:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Barriers to a cashless economy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/barriers-to-a-cashless-economy</link><description>The government has been encouraging people to conduct financial transactions digitally using debit and credit cards, mobile financial service(MFS), mobile wallet, etc., and thus fast move towards a cashless economy. Still, the use of cash is showing no sign of declining in Bangladesh. At a discussi</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 16:51:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Making money loan court effective</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/making-money-loan-court-effective</link><description>The classified loans in the country's banking sector have soared to an all-time high of Tk 4.20 trillion as of March 2025, now accounting for 24.13 per cent of total outstanding loans. This staggering volume of Non-Performing Loans (NPLs) and its continued rise are weighing heavily on the financial</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 17:06:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>What led to Swarnamoyee’s death?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dhaka-stream-staffer-swarnamoyees-death-highlights-alleged-abuse-toxic-media-office</link><description>The recent death of a 28-year-old Dhaka Stream employee, Swarnamoyee Biswas, has sparked widespread discussion on social media.
Relatives and police believe she took her own life. Some, however, point to alleged misconduct by a senior official at the media outlet -- against whom Swarnamoyee and 26</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 18:10:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ex-MP AK Azad’s campaign attacked in Faridpur, vehicles vandalised</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ex-mp-ak-azads-campaign-attacked-in-faridpur-vehicles-vandalised</link><description>Former MP and ex-FBCCI chief AK Azad has come under attack during his campaign in Faridpur, allegedly by the Jatiyatabadi Jubo Dal activists.
The attackers reportedly vandalised two vehicles during the incident.
Timely police intervention, however, prevented a major confrontation.
Police later r</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 18:25:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Storing valuable imports sans fire detection-protection system alleged</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/storing-valuable-imports-sans-fire-detection-protection-system-alleged</link><description>Storing huge imports that include combustible chemicals in Dhaka airport's cargo section sans effective fire-detection-and protection systems is what caused Saturday's devastating blaze, according to a fireman.
Several counts of equipment of Rooppur Nuclear Power Plant were among the import cargos</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 19:49:32 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>