<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 11:22:29 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Injustice, discriminations led people to revolt in 1971: Jamaat Ameer</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/injustice-discriminations-led-people-to-revolt-in-1971-jamaat-ameer</link><description>Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami Ameer Dr Shafiqur Rahman on Tuesday the people of the then East Pakistan rose in revolt as the Pakistani ruling elite perpetrated injustice and created discriminations against them.
He made the remarks while speaking as the chief guest at the inauguration of a youth mara</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 07:59:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Victory Day tributes overshadowed by 'electioneering' at National Memorial</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/election-code-under-scrutiny-as-national-memorial-becomes-campaign-stage-on-victory-day</link><description>Supporters of several political leaders have been accused of breaching the electoral code of conduct by chanting slogans and displaying campaign material while paying tribute at Savar’s National Martyrs’ Memorial on Victory Day.
The incidents occurred just days after the Election Commi</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 08:14:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CJ, judges pay tribute to martyrs at National Memorial</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/chief-justice-sc-judges-pay-tribute-to-liberation-war-martyrs-at-national-memorial</link><description>Chief Justice Syed Refaat Ahmed has led the judges of the Supreme Court in paying tribute to the martyrs of Bangladesh’s 1971 Liberation War at the National Martyrs’ Memorial in Savar.
The head of the judiciary and fellow judges laid wreaths at the memorial at 7:05am on Tuesday, markin</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 08:29:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>February election to lay strong foundation for democracy: Rizwana</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/february-election-to-lay-strong-foundation-for-democracy-rizwana</link><description>Environment adviser Syeda Rizwana Hasan on Tuesday said the election scheduled for February would lay a strong foundation for democracy by strengthening accountability to people.
“The election would help solidify democracy and bring the government under public scrutiny. The journey toward bu</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 08:45:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UK minister urges BBC to stand firm against Trump lawsuit</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/uk-minister-urges-bbc-to-stand-firm-against-trump-lawsuit</link><description>A British government minister said on Tuesday he believed the BBC was right to stand firm against Donald Trump after the US President sued the broadcaster for defamation over edited clips of a speech linked to the Jan 6 Capitol attack.
The BBC, Britain’s publicly funded broadcaster, has apol</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 09:00:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India greets Bangladesh on Victory Day</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/india-greets-bangladesh-on-victory-day</link><description>India has greeted Bangladesh and people of the country on the occasion of Victory Day being celebrated across the country on Tuesday.
Indian External Affairs Minister Dr. S Jaishnkar conveyed the greetings to Bangladesh and its people.
“Greetings to Foreign Affairs Adviser Md Touhid Hossain</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 09:15:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP candidate quits Narayanganj-5 race over security fears</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bnp-candidate-pulls-out-of-narayanganj-5-race-over-security-concerns</link><description>A BNP candidate has announced his withdrawal from the election in the Narayanganj-5 constituency, citing concerns over his personal and family security.
Masuduzzaman, the BNP-nominated candidate for the seat comprising Narayanganj Sadar and Bandar Upazilas, made the announcement at a media briefin</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 09:30:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>We stand against ‘brokers’ of 1971 and 2024: Nahid</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/we-stand-against-brokers-of-1971-and-2024-says-ncps-nahid</link><description>Expressing his determination to take Bangladesh forward on the path of reform, National Citizen Party (NCP) Convenor Nahid Islam says, “Bangladesh will never return to where it was before Aug 5.”
He said, “We are united against the brokers of 1971. We, the people of Bangladesh, t</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 09:30:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Can Bangladesh’s election reset democracy post uprising?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/can-bangladeshs-upcoming-election-reset-democracy-post-uprising</link><description>Bangladesh is facing its first election since Sheikh Hasina was ousted in an uprising. However, the ongoing cycle of “revenge politics” and economic uncertainty are dimming hopes for democratic reforms, says British journalist James Orr.
In an article published on the website of London</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 09:45:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Kader Siddiqui pledges to uphold independence despite ‘ups and down’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/kader-siddiqui-pledges-to-uphold-independence-no-matter-what-ups-and-down-come</link><description>Krishak Sramik Janata League President Abdul Kader Siddique has pledged to uphold independence no matter what “ups and down” come along the way.
He said, “No matter what ups and downs come, we can protect our independence. It’s our misfortune that we couldn’t raise ou</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 10:00:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Yunus to address the nation on Tuesday evening</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/yunus-to-address-the-nation-on-tuesday-evening</link><description>Chief Advisor Muhammad Yunus is set to address the nation on the occasion of Victory Day.
The speech will be broadcast simultaneously on state-run Bangladesh Television, BTV News and Bangladesh Betar at 6:30pm on Tuesday, the Chief Advisor's Office said.</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 10:15:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CA enjoys Victory Day fly past, parajump</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ca-enjoys-victory-day-fly-past-parajump</link><description>Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus on Tuesday enjoyed Victory Day Fly Past, parajump and band display at the National Parade Ground in the city.
To mark the country’s 54 years of independence, 54 paratroopers from the Bangladesh Army, Navy and Air Force performed a national flag-bearing</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 10:30:48 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>