<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 15:21:50 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Govt creates 2,258 posts in BGB organogram</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-creates-2258-posts-in-bgb-organogram</link><description>The government has created 2,258 posts in the Border Guard Bangladesh (BGB) structure at different levels of the paramilitary force, a home ministry official said on Tuesday.
“The newly created posts ranged from director to sepoy (soldiers) level in line with the BGB requirement,” an o</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 12:36:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pornography charge: Couple put on 5-day remand</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/pornography-charge-couple-put-on-5-day-remand</link><description>A Dhaka court on Tuesday afternoon placed a couple on a five- day remand each in a case over creating adult contents on an international website.
Dhaka Chief Metropolitan Magistrate Md Jewel Rana passed the order after hearing a petition seeking a seven-day remand for Azim and Brishti, said Shamsu</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 13:06:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Titas disconnects gas to Ananta Jalil’s factory over Tk 15.6m arrears, and gas theft</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/titas-disconnects-gas-to-ananta-jalils-factory-over-tk-156m-arrears-and-gas-theft</link><description>Titas Gas Transmission and Distribution PLC has disconnected two industrial gas connections and seized meters at a factory belonging to celebrated Bangladeshi actor and producer Ananta Jalil in Savar.
Titas cited Tk 15.6 million in outstanding bills and evidence of gas theft via meter tampering, t</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 13:21:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP calls for caretaker-style interim government</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bnp-urges-yunus-to-ensure-interim-government-follows-caretaker-model</link><description>With the general election approaching, the Bangladesh Nationalist Party has called for the interim government to be structured along the lines of a caretaker administration.
After a nearly one-hour meeting with Chief Advisor Muhammad Yunus at the state residence Jamuna on Tuesday, BNP Secretary Ge</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 13:36:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IRI delegation meets CA, confirms plans to send observers for Feb polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/iri-delegation-meets-ca-confirms-plans-to-send-observers-for-feb-polls</link><description>The US-based International Republican Institute (IRI) today confirmed Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus that the organization will send at least 10 international observers for Bangladesh’s national election in February next.
The confirmation came at a meeting between the Chief Adviser a</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 14:06:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Islami Bank holds board meeting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/islami-bank-holds-board-meeting-1111222</link><description>A meeting of the board of directors of Islami Bank Bangladesh PLC was held on Tuesday at Islami Bank Tower, according to a press release.
Professor Dr. M. Zubaidur Rahman, chairman of the bank, presided over the meeting.Mohammad Khurshid Wahab, chairman of the executive committee, Md. Abdus Salam,</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 14:36:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Late drama: Bangladesh - West Indies go to Super Over</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/late-drama-bangladesh-west-indies-go-to-super-over</link><description>In the last over of the innings, West Indies needed five runs to win, but they managed four, and the second ODI of the three-match series went to the super over to decide the winner.
Saif Hassan bowled superbly in the last over and managed to defend 5 runs. He also scalped the wicket of Akeal Hose</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 14:51:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Solar power projects face delays amid challenges: Adviser Fouzul Kabir</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/solar-power-projects-face-delays-amid-challenges-adviser-fouzul-kabir</link><description>Bangladesh’s solar power projects have failed to gain momentum despite several government initiatives, mainly due to multiple challenges and non-cooperation from certain power distribution agencies, said Power, Energy and Mineral Resources Adviser Fouzul Kabir Khan on Tuesday.
Speaking at th</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 15:21:50 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>