<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 15:22:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Yemen's main separatist group denies it is disbanding</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/yemens-main-separatist-group-denies-it-is-disbanding</link><description>Yemen's main separatist group, the Southern Transitional Council, denied on Saturday it was disbanding, contradicting a statement by one of its members that the group had decided to dissolve itself.
The conflicting statements highlight a split in the STC, a group backed by the United Arab Emirates</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 12:30:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>7,359 killed in road crashes last year: report</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/road-crashes-claim-7359-lives-in-2025-with-motorcycles-involved-in-more-than-a-third-says-report</link><description>Bangladesh’s roads have exacted a grim toll in 2025, claiming 7,359 lives and leaving 16,476 injured, according to the Road Safety Foundation.
The figures, drawn primarily from media reports, reveal a persistent and deadly pattern that continues to haunt highways and city streets alike.
Mot</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 12:29:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Iran's Guards declare 'red line' on security as Tehran seeks to quell unrest</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/irans-guards-declare-red-line-on-security-as-tehran-seeks-to-quell-unrest</link><description>Iran's Revolutionary Guards warned on Saturday that safeguarding security was a "red line" and the military vowed to protect public property, as the clerical establishment stepped up efforts to quell the most widespread protests in years.
 
The statements came after U.S. President Donal</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 12:44:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCP to announce seats in Jamaat alliance ‘soon’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ncp-to-announce-seats-in-jamaat-alliance-soon</link><description>The National Citizen Party (NCP) will announce within a day or two how many constituencies its candidates will contest in as part of the Jamaat-e-Islami-led alliance for the parliamentary election, according to Convenor Nahid Islam.
Although the final distribution of seats among partners in the 11</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 12:59:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>60 people questioned over Muchabbir murder</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/60-people-questioned-over-muchabbir-murder</link><description>The Detective Branch of Police has questioned 60 people over the murder of Jatiotabadi Swecchasebak Dal leader Azizur Rahman Muchabbir.
Dhaka Metropolitan Police Additional Commissioner Md Shafiqul Islam revealed details amid rumours that the suspected shooter in the murder had been arrested.
&amp;nb</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 13:14:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>LPG retailers blame government for LPG crisis since mid-Nov</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/lpg-retailers-blame-government-for-lpg-crisis-since-mid-nov</link><description>An LPG station and conversion owners’ association has sharply criticised the government over the ongoing liquefied petroleum gas (LPG) shortage, which has been causing widespread disruption since mid-November.
Hasin Pervez, general secretary of the Bangladesh LPG Autogas Station and Conversi</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 13:29:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bankers Club of Bangladesh holds 4th AGM</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bankers-club-of-bangladesh-holds-4th-agm</link><description>The fourth Annual General Meeting (AGM) of Bankers Club of Bangladesh Limited (BCBL) was held on Saturday morning.
BCBL President Mohammed Emtiaz Uddin presided over the AGM at the BCBL office in the Uttara area of Dhaka in the presence of BCBL Senior Vice President Md Rashed Akter and members of</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 13:44:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump says capture of Putin ‘not necessary’ despite Zelensky’s hint</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-says-capture-of-putin-not-necessary-despite-zelenskys-hint</link><description>The United States has ruled out a mission to capture Russia’s Vladimir Putin, following the dramatic arrest of Venezuelan President Nicolás Maduro last week.
NDTV said Donald Trump differed with Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky, who suggested that the US could consider a similar</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 13:59:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Indian envoy meets Tarique Rahman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/indian-envoy-meets-tarique-rahman</link><description>Indian High Commissioner to Bangladesh Pranay Verma on Saturday paid a courtesy call on BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman and discussed matters of bilateral interest between the two countries.
The Indian envoy came to BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman’s Gulshan office around 5:00 pm and held a nearly ho</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 14:14:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BPL action heats up with Chattogram leading the table</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bpl-action-heats-up-with-chattogram-leading-the-table</link><description>The 2025-26 Bangladesh Premier League (BPL) has reached a fever pitch after 20 matches, with vintage performances from local stars overshadowing the looming diplomatic crisis surrounding the upcoming T20 World Cup.
Mustafizur Rahman, fresh from the controversy of being removed from the IPL by the</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 14:29:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cold wave sweeping 19 districts to persist through Sunday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/cold-wave-sweeping-19-districts-to-persist-through-sunday</link><description>A cold wave is sweeping across large parts of Bangladesh, dragging nighttime temperatures down to 8.3°C in Tetulia, one of the lowest readings this season.
The Bangladesh Meteorological Department (BMD) said the cold conditions are expected to continue through Sunday, with fog likely in severa</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 14:44:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Plan for separate ‘Microcredit Bank’ threatens Bangladesh’s poorest, experts warn</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/plan-for-separate-microcredit-bank-threatens-bangladeshs-poorest-experts-warn</link><description>COAST Foundation, BDCSO Process, and EquityBD Saturday warned that the government’s plan to set up a separate microcredit bank could harm Bangladesh’s poorest people.
The proposal is being promoted as a “social innovation,” but the civil society organisations (CSOs) say it</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 14:59:07 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>