<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 06:56:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>AL leaders in India ‘plot’ political return as Bangladesh nears election: Guardian</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/awami-league-leaders-in-india-plot-political-return-as-bangladesh-nears-election-guardian</link><description>Exiled Awami League members have been plotting a political return from India as Bangladesh prepares for its first national election since Sheikh Hasina’s government was toppled by mass protests, The Guardian reports.
Writing on Tuesday, the UK-based newspaper said senior party leaders now li</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 02:40:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangabhaban programmer held over alleged hack of Jamaat chief's X account</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bangabhaban-programmer-held-over-alleged-hack-of-jamaat-chiefs-x-account</link><description>Police have confirmed the detention of Sarowar Alam, an assistant programmer at Bangabhaban, following allegations that he 'hacked' the X account of Jamaat-e-Islami chief Shafiqur Rahman.
On Tuesday night, a senior Dhaka Metropolitan Police official said that Sarowar was apprehended at Motijheel.</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 02:55:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sherpur-3 Jamaat MP candidate Nuruzzaman Badal dies</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/sherpur-3-jamaat-mp-candidate-nuruzzaman-badal-dies</link><description>Mohammad Nuruzzaman Badal, Jamaat-e-Islami’s MP candidate from Sherpur-3 constituency and the party's district secretary, passed away early Wednesday.
He breathed his last at around 1:30 am while undergoing treatment for kidney complications at Swadesh Hospital in Mymensingh, said Sherpur di</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 03:10:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC revises BNCC deployment decision following BNP's objection</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-revises-bncc-deployment-decision-following-bnps-objection</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has revised its earlier decision on deploying Bangladesh National Cadet Corps (BNCC) cadets during the upcoming 13th national parliamentary election and referendum, limiting their role only to maintaining discipline at postal ballot vote-counting centres following objec</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 03:25:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Spain, Greece’s teen social media ban plans draw fury from Elon Musk</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/spain-greeces-teen-social-media-ban-plans-draw-fury-from-elon-musk</link><description>Spain and Greece on Tuesday proposed bans on social media use by teenagers as attitudes hardened in Europe against technology some say is designed to be addictive and the measures announced by Spain's Prime Minister, Pedro Sánchez, drew fury from Elon Musk.
Spain wants to prohibit social me</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 04:12:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Badol, Jamaat’s candidate for the Sherpur-3 parliamentary race, dies of health complications</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/badol-jamaats-candidate-for-the-sherpur-3-parliamentary-race-dies-of-health-complications</link><description>Md Nuruzzaman Badol, Jamaat-e-Islami’s candidate for the Sherpur-3 (Sreebordi-Jhenaigati) parliamentary race in the 13th national election, has died at the age of 52.
Badol, the secretary of the district’s Jamaat unit, had been suffering from kidney disease for a long time. He died at</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 04:27:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>July Charter is a pledge signed in blood letters: Ali Riaz</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/july-charter-is-a-pledge-signed-in-blood-letters-ali-riaz</link><description>Chief Adviser’s Special Assistant Professor Ali Riaz has said that the July Charter is a pledge signed in letters of blood.
“We owe a great debt to everyone—the young people who took to the streets, the youths who left their work to join the protests, the fathers who sent their s</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 05:29:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP could benefit from internal rift in Jamaat alliance in Savar race</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-could-benefit-from-internal-rift-in-jamaat-alliance-in-savar-race</link><description>The Dhaka-19 constituency, which comprises Savar and Ashulia, has long held special importance for all major parties in national parliamentary elections.
As an industrial hub, the area is home to people from across the country, who make up its residents and voters.
For a long time, the constituen</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 05:27:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>14 migrants die off Greece after boat collision with coast guard</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/14-migrants-die-off-greece-after-boat-collision-with-coast-guard</link><description>Fourteen migrants died in the Aegean Sea off Greece on Tuesday after their boat collided with a coast guard vessel off the island of Chios, the coast guard said.
A coast guard official said they spotted a dingy transporting migrants towards Chios, which lies a few miles off the coast of Turkey, an</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 05:42:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Holy Shab-e-Barat observed</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/holy-shab-e-barat-observed</link><description>The Holy Shab-e-Barat, the night of fortune, was observed throughout the country on Tuesday night with due religious fervour and devotion.
On the occasion, the Islamic Foundation chalked out programmes at the Baitul Mukarram National Mosque in Dhaka.
The foundation held waz (religious sermons), d</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 05:57:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New York, New Jersey sue Trump administration over tunnel funding halt</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/new-york-new-jersey-sue-trump-administration-over-tunnel-funding-halt</link><description>New York and New Jersey late on Tuesday sued the Trump administration seeking an emergency court order to force the restoration of funding for the massive $16 billion Hudson River tunnel before construction is set to halt on Friday.
US President Donald Trump said in October he had terminated the p</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 06:12:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US says it has returned to Venezuela all $500 million of initial oil sale</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/us-says-it-has-returned-to-venezuela-all-500-million-of-initial-oil-sale</link><description>The United States has now returned to the Venezuelan government all $500 million from the initial sale of oil that was part of a deal reached between Caracas and Washington last month, a US official said on Tuesday.
The last $200 million from the sale has been sent to Venezuela, the official said,</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 06:27:13 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>