<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 07:21:26 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>ACC to examine affidavits of political party candidates</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/acc-to-examine-affidavits-of-political-party-candidates</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) will verify the wealth information provided in the affidavits of candidates for the upcoming national election if the Election Commission (EC) sends a request.
ACC Director General Md Akhter Hossain said this while talking to reporters at a regular press briefi</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 04:28:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat chief says party will announce candidates ‘when it’s time’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-chief-says-party-will-announce-candidates-when-its-time</link><description>Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami will announce its “final” list of candidates for the 13th national parliamentary elections when “it’s time,” according to party chief Shafiqur Rahman.
Ending a 15-day foreign tour, he met the reporters at Hazrat Shahjalal International Airpo</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 04:43:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Four BNP leaders expelled over nomination-related violence</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/four-bnp-leaders-expelled-over-nomination-related-violence</link><description>BNP has expelled four local leaders in Sitakunda upazila of Chattogram for their alleged involvement in violence, clashes, and road blockades following the announcement of the party’s nominations for the upcoming 13th parliamentary election.
In a press release issued early Tuesday, the party</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 04:58:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rain, thundershowers likely in Ctg division</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rain-thundershowers-likely-in-ctg-division</link><description>Rain or thundershowers are likely to occur at many places in Chattogram division and at a few places in Barishal and Sylhet divisions, the Bangladesh Meteorological Department (BMD) said in a forecast issued on Tuesday morning.
The weather may remain mainly dry with partly cloudy skies elsewhere a</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 05:13:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump tells Ilhan Omar to leave US</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/trump-tells-ilhan-omar-to-leave-us</link><description>US President Donald Trump has reignited his attacks on Congresswoman Ilhan Omar, telling her to “go back” to her native Somalia in a social media post.
POLITICO reported that Trump shared a video of Omar addressing a crowd on his Truth Social on Saturday, writing: “She should go</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 05:28:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>RPO amendment brings new provisions for polls, fugitives barred from voting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rpo-amendment-brings-new-provisions-for-polls-fugitives-barred-from-voting</link><description>Several new provisions have been introduced in the amended Representation of the People Order (RPO) ordinance for the upcoming parliamentary election.
A key addition stipulates that any person declared a fugitive by a court will be disqualified from voting.
After one and a half decades, the defin</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 05:58:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Woman killed in Dhaka road crash</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/woman-killed-in-dhaka-road-crash</link><description>A 55-year-old woman was killed when a bus ran over her in the Shahjahanpur area of the capital on Monday night.
The deceased was identified as Sathia Begum, 55, wife of Hazrat Ali of Shahjahanpur Railway Water Tank colony, reports UNB. 
Quoting witnesses, SM Rashedul Islam, sub-inspector of</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 06:13:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Aramco's Q3 net profit slips on lower crude prices</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/aramcos-q3-net-profit-slips-on-lower-crude-prices</link><description>Saudi Arabian oil company Aramco, the world's top oil exporter, reported a 2.3 per cent decline in its quarterly profit on Tuesday, citing lower revenue resulting from a drop in crude and product prices.
Aramco reported a net profit of 101.02 billion riyals ($26.94 billion) in the three-month peri</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 06:43:20 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>