<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 16:32:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Daraz Bangladesh wins Digital Commerce of the Year Award</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/daraz-bangladesh-wins-digital-commerce-of-the-year-award</link><description>Daraz Bangladesh, the country's leading e-commerce platform, has been awarded the prestigious Digital Commerce of the Year Award at the 10th BRAC Bank-The Daily Star ICT Awards, cementing its position as the country's most influential e-commerce platform.
The 10th edition of the Awards highlighted</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 13:15:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fires break out at five locations in Gazipur within five hours</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fires-break-out-at-five-locations-in-gazipur-within-five-hours</link><description>Fires have broken out at five locations in Gazipur within five hours, causing extensive damage to property, according to the Fire Service.
Officials said the incidents occurred between 5am and 10am on Monday in Sreepur, Pubail Majukhan, Chandona Chowrasta of the city, Konabari’s Ambag neighb</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 13:30:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NBR makes digital bond management mandatory from 2026</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/nbr-makes-digital-bond-management-mandatory-from-2026</link><description>The National Board of Revenue (NBR) has made the use of the Customs Bond Management System (CBMS) compulsory for all bonded warehouse licence-holding export-oriented industries from January 1, 2026, requiring businesses to obtain Utilisation Permission (UP) exclusively through digital submission.</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 13:45:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mutual Trust Bank signs agreement with East West University for Payroll Banking &amp; Cash Management Services</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/mutual-trust-bank-signs-agreement-with-east-west-university-for-payroll-banking-cash-management-services</link><description>Mutual Trust Bank PLC (MTB) has recently signed an agreement with East West University to provide comprehensive Payroll Banking and Cash Management Services for the University’s teaching and non-teaching staff as well as for its students.
Professor Dr. Mohammed Farashuddin, Chairperson, Boar</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 14:00:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>12 Bangladesh political parties pledge investments, policy reforms</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/12-bangladesh-political-parties-pledge-investments-policy-reforms</link><description>Political parties on Monday united to sign a Child Rights Manifesto, responding to the powerful voices of children and young people who have demanded a future where their rights are better respected and protected.
The Child Rights Manifesto, seen as a historic moment for the nation’s childre</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 14:15:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sammilito Islami Bank listed as scheduled bank</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/sammilito-islami-bank-listed-as-scheduled-bank</link><description>Bangladesh Bank has listed the newly-formed ‘Sammilito Islami Bank PLC’ as a scheduled bank, according to a notification signed by the central bank’s deputy governor, Dr Md Kabir Ahmed, on Monday.
Earlier on Sunday, a meeting of the Board of Directors of Bangladesh Bank approved</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 14:30:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shahjalal Islami Bank wins Bronze Award from South Asian Federation of Accountants</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/shahjalal-islami-bank-wins-bronze-award-from-south-asian-federation-of-accountants</link><description>Shahjalal Islami Bank PLC. has won the Bronze Award in Private Sector Banks Category from the South Asian Federation of Accountants (SAFA) for the best presented annual report 2024.
The Chief Financial Officer of Shahjalal Islami Bank PLC. Mr. Md. Jafar Sadeq, FCA, received the award from the Pres</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 14:45:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>HC issues rule questioning legality of RPO provision on alliance candidates’ symbols</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hc-issues-rule-questioning-legality-of-rpo-provision-on-alliance-candidates-symbols</link><description>The High Court on Monday issued a rule asking why the provision in the Representation of the People Order (RPO) that requires candidates in an electoral alliance to use their respective party symbols while contesting elections should not be declared illegal.
The bench of Justice Fatema Najib and J</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 15:00:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Remittances cross $13 billion in first 5 months of fiscal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/remittances-cross-13-billion-in-first-5-months-of-fiscal</link><description>Bangladesh received its highest monthly remittance inflow of the current fiscal year FY 2025-26, crossing US $2.88 billion November.This substantial inflow translates to an average daily remittance of approximately $96.3 million. In the five month of the current fiscal year Bangladeshi expatriates</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 15:15:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ctg Port suspension lifted, higher fees return</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/high-court-revokes-stay-clearing-way-for-collection-of-increased-chattogram-port-charges</link><description>The High Court has lifted its stay on the increased fees at Chattogram Port, removing any legal barrier to their collection, according to port officials.
The chamber judge of the Supreme Court revoked the injunction last Tuesday, prompting the Chittagong Port Authority’s chief finance and ac</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 15:30:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>GPH Ispat declares 5pc cash dividend despite losses</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/gph-ispat-declares-5pc-cash-dividend-despite-losses</link><description>GPH Ispat has declared a 5 per cent cash dividend for FY25 despite the company suffering a loss of Tk 247 million for the year, owing to costlier raw materials and higher finance expenses.
The Chittagong-based steel manufacturer has reported earnings per share (EPS) of Tk 0.51 in the negative in F</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 15:45:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>WHO backs use of GLP-1 therapies for obesity, warns access will remain limited</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/who-backs-use-of-glp-1-therapies-for-obesity-warns-access-will-remain-limited</link><description>The World Health Organisation on Monday issued its first guideline on the use of GLP-1 therapies for obesity, conditionally recommending them as part of long-term treatment for the condition, which affects more than 1 billion people globally according to the agency.
The guidance comes as demand fo</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 16:00:49 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>