<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 11:47:32 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>ASI dies in Thakurgaon while attempting to arrest suspect</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/asi-dies-in-thakurgaon-while-attempting-to-arrest-suspect</link><description>An assistant sub-inspector (ASI) of police has died after suffering a heart attack while attempting to arrest a suspect in Pirganj Upazila of Thakurgaon.
Pirganj Police Station chief (OC) Mazharul Islam said the incident occurred around 1:00 am on Monday in Senua village under Bhomradaha Union.
S</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 09:12:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BB warns against sample notes, misleading social media content</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bb-warns-against-sample-notes-misleading-social-media-content</link><description>Bangladesh Bank (BB) has cautioned the people against using paper or objects resembling bank notes for marketing and social media content, warning that such activities are punishable offences under existing laws.
In a press release issued on Monday by the Department of Communications and Publicati</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 09:27:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CA delivers farewell address as interim govt prepares to hand over power</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/chief-adviser-delivers-farewell-address-as-interim-govt-prepares-to-hand-over-power</link><description>Chief Adviser Prof Muhammad Yunus on Monday delivered a farewell address to officers and staff at the Chief Adviser’s Office, marking the end of the interim administration’s tenure.
Following his speech, he joined officials and employees for a photo session at the office, UNB reports.</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 09:42:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CBCB congratulates BNP on election victory</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cbcb-congratulates-bnp-on-election-victory</link><description>The Catholic Bishops’ Conference of Bangladesh (CBCB) has congratulated the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) on its decisive victory in the 13th National Parliamentary Election.
President of the CBCB, Archbishop Bejoy N. D’Cruze, OMI, conveyed his greetings to the party’s Chair</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 09:57:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Will put in best efforts as Cabinet Secretary: Nasimul Gani</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/will-put-in-best-efforts-as-cabinet-secretary-nasimul-gani</link><description>Newly appointed Cabinet Secretary Nasimul Gani on Monday said he would discharge the immense responsibility entrusted to him with utmost sincerity and dedication.
“Alhamdulillah, at a crucial moment for the country, a huge responsibility has been placed on my shoulders. InshAllah, I will try</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 09:14:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Haseeb named first VC of Dhaka Central University</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/haseeb-appointed-as-first-vice-chancellor-of-dhaka-central-university</link><description>Prof ASM Abdul Haseeb, a professor at the Bangladesh University of Engineering and Technology (BUET), has been appointed as the first vice-chancellor of the newly-formed Dhaka Central University, which is composed of seven government colleges in Dhaka.
The appointment was made in a notice from the</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 09:29:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Claims of 21.4pc fake votes misleading: TIB</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/claims-of-214pc-fake-votes-misleading-tib</link><description>Transparency International Bangladesh (TIB) on Monday said false and misleading information is being circulated in its name regarding allegations of fake votes in the 13th parliamentary election.
In a press release, the organisation said information presented at a press conference marking the rele</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 09:44:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Constitution Reform Council members to take oath after MPs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/swearing-in-of-constitution-reform-council-members-to-follow-parliaments-oath</link><description>The newly elected members of the 13th National Parliament will first take their oaths as members of parliament (MPs), followed by their swearing-in as members of the Constitution Reform Council.
The Parliament Secretariat announced in a press release that the oath-taking ceremony will be held on T</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 09:59:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>4 of a family among 5 Bangladeshis killed in Saudi road crash</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/4-of-a-family-among-5-bangladeshis-killed-in-saudi-road-crash</link><description>Five Bangladeshi nationals including four members of a family have been killed in a road crash in Saudi Arabia.
The deceased were identified as Mizanur Rahman, 42, his wife Meher Afroz Sumi, 30, their two-daughters—Mohna, 13 and Subah of Ramganj upazila and Hossain Mohammad Jilani alias Babo</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 10:14:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Body of ex-Jagannath University student found hanged in Old Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/body-of-ex-jagannath-university-student-found-hanged-in-old-dhaka</link><description>The body of a former Jagannath University student has been found hanged at a shared accommodation in Old Dhaka’s Dhupkhola area.
The body was identified as that of Imran Nobel Pramanik, a student in the Department of Islamic Studies from the 2016-17 academic year. He hailed from Gaibandha&amp;rs</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 10:29:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>China grants UK and Canada visa-free entry, raising total to 79 countries</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/china-grants-uk-and-canada-visa-free-entry-raising-total-to-79-countries</link><description>British and Canadian citizens can enter China without a visa starting Tuesday, bringing to 79 the number of countries granted visa-free access in a bid to boost tourism and business.
China has expanded eligibility for the program significantly in the last two years. Visitors can stay for up to 30</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 10:44:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Taking on ‘huge responsibility’ at ‘critical juncture’: Ghani</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/taking-on-huge-responsibility-at-critical-juncture-says-new-cabinet-secretary-ghani</link><description>New Cabinet Secretary Nasimul Ghani has shared details of his preparations for conducting the swearing-in ceremony for the incoming cabinet.
Speaking to reporters after being appointed cabinet secretary on Monday, Ghani discussed various aspects of the preparations.
He formally assumed the role o</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 10:59:38 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>