<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 14:18:08 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Advisory Council to close work in November: Adviser Mahfuj</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/advisory-council-to-close-work-in-november-adviser-mahfuj</link><description>The Advisory Council of the interim government will wrap up its meetings within November, Information Advisor Mahfuj Alam has said.
Speaking at a “Meet the Reporters” event organised by the Dhaka Reporters Unity (DRU) on Sunday, he highlighted the progress made in implementing reforms</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 11:25:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Top Japanese entrepreneur to establish driving school in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/top-japanese-entrepreneur-to-establish-driving-school-in-bangladesh</link><description>Prominent Japanese entrepreneur and politician Miki Watanabe has announced plans to establish a driving school in Bangladesh to help recruit thousands of skilled drivers for employment in Japan.
Watanabe, founder of the Watami Group, made the announcement during a meeting with Chief Adviser Profes</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 11:40:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Workshop on AI in journalism held by TMGB and GIGABYTE</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/workshop-on-ai-in-journalism-held-by-tmgb-and-gigabyte</link><description>A special workshop on the use of Artificial Intelligence (AI) in journalism was held in the capital on Saturday. The event was jointly organized by Technology Media Guild Bangladesh (TMGB) and Gigabyte, with the cooperation of the Bangladesh Computer Society (BCS).The workshop, titled “Artifi</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 11:55:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘It’s unrealistic to expect complete eradication of corruption right now, but it can certainly be reduced’- ACC Chairman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/its-unrealistic-to-expect-complete-eradication-of-corruption-right-now-but-it-can-certainly-be-reduced-acc-chairman</link><description>Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) Chairman Dr. Mohammad Moinul Momen on Sunday said that expecting the ACC to completely eradicate corruption from Bangladesh at this moment would be unrealistic, though it is certainly possible to reduce it significantly.
“It would be a bit too much to expect</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 12:10:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Migration, trade key focus in Italian PM’s visit to Dhaka in December</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/migration-trade-key-focus-in-italian-pms-visit-to-dhaka-in-late-december</link><description>Migration and trade will be the main focus of the Italian Prime Minister’s upcoming visit to Dhaka, scheduled for late December, Italian Ambassador to Bangladesh Mr. Antonio Alessandro said on Sunday.
Speaking to reporters after a meeting at the Ministry of Foreign Affairs, the envoy noted t</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 12:25:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Most shares slide as DSE and CSE start week in red</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/most-shares-slide-as-dse-and-cse-start-week-in-red</link><description>Both Dhaka and Chattogram stock markets opened the week on a downward trend on Monday, with most company shares declining and overall trading activity falling.
At the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE), the benchmark index lost 22 points.
The Shariah-based DSES index fell by 4 points, while the selective</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 12:40:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Netanyahu says Israel to decide which international forces in Gaza acceptable</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/netanyahu-says-israel-to-decide-which-international-forces-in-gaza-acceptable</link><description>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said on Sunday Israel would determine which foreign forces it would allow as part of a planned international force in Gaza to help secure an end to its warunder US President Donald Trump’s plan.
It remains unclear whether Arab and other states will b</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 12:55:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Kremlin: Wrong to talk about cancellation of Putin-Trump summit, agencies report</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/kremlin-wrong-to-talk-about-cancellation-of-putin-trump-summit-agencies-report</link><description>The Kremlin said on Sunday it was wrong to talk about cancellation of a meeting between Russian President Vladimir Putin and US President Donald Trump, but added that preparation for it was needed, state television Vesti reported on its Telegram channel.
"Presidents cannot meet for the sake of mee</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 13:10:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Three officials of Aramit PLC taken on five days remand</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/three-officials-of-aramit-plc-taken-on-five-days-remand</link><description>The Anti Corruption Commission (ACC) has taken three officials of Aramit PLC on a five-day remand for interrogation in connection with a corruption case, official sources said.
The officials of the company are Md Abdul Aziz, Mohammad Jahangir Alam and Utpal Paul.
Deputy Director (DD) of the Publi</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 13:40:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shoeb Chowdhury meets Nobel laureate Joseph Stiglitz in Vienna</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/shoeb-chowdhury-meets-nobel-laureate-joseph-stiglitz-in-vienna</link><description>Nobel Laureate in Economics Joseph E Stiglitz has recently delivered a speech at an international assembly in the Austrian capital of Vienna.
The event, titled “Formulating a Work Strategy, Free Opinion and Unsolicited Interference in Journalism,” took place on October 23-25. It was or</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 13:55:38 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>