<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 08:27:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Telescope in Chile captures stunning new picture of a cosmic butterfly</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/telescope-in-chile-captures-stunning-new-picture-of-a-cosmic-butterfly</link><description>A telescope in Chile has captured a breathtaking new image of a planetary nebula that resembles a graceful cosmic butterfly. The stunning picture, released by the National Science Foundation’s NOIRLab on Wednesday, was taken last month by the Gemini South telescope.
The nebula, officially kn</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 05:25:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Four shot dead at birthday party in California</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/four-shot-dead-at-birthday-party-in-california</link><description>Four people died after 14 people were shot at a family gathering in Stockton city in northern California on Saturday night, police said.
The shooting took place at a child's birthday party, Stockton's Vice Mayor Jason Lee said in a Facebook post.
"I am in contact with staff and public safety offi</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 05:40:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladeshi dies after UAE road crash</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladeshi-dies-after-uae-road-crash</link><description>A Bangladeshi migrant has died in the United Arab Emirates, 10 days after being critically injured in a road accident while delivering food.
Rubel Ahmed, 35, from Sylhet's Moglabazar, died on Friday night at Abu Dhabi's Mafraq Hospital, where he had been in intensive care since the collision, acco</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 05:45:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Maritime ports asked to keep hoisted signal No 2</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/maritime-ports-asked-to-keep-hoisted-signal-no-2</link><description>Maritime ports of Chattogram, Cox's Bazar, Mongla and Payra have been advised to keep hoisted distant warning signal No 2 as the cyclonic storm ‘Ditwah’ over the southwest Bay of Bengal and adjoining coastal Sri Lanka moved northwards over the southwest Bay of Bengal and adjoining Tamil</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 06:00:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two killed as bus rams motorcycle in Jashore</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/two-killed-as-bus-rams-motorcycle-in-jashore</link><description>Two motorcyclists were killed after a bus hit their motorcycle on Saturday night while they were on their way to visit a patient at Jashore General Hospital.
The accident occurred around 8:00 pm at Jagahati area on the Jashore-Chaugachha road, reports BSS.
The deceased were identified as Selim Ho</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 06:15:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Factory worker killed after being hit by train in Ctg</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/factory-worker-killed-after-being-hit-by-train-in-ctg</link><description>A factory worker was killed after being hit by a train in Mirsarai upazila of Chattogram on Saturday evening.
The accident occurred around 7:00 pm at the Chinki Astana Railway Station area on the Dhaka-bound track of the Dhaka-Chattogram rail line.
The deceased was identified as Tutul Kanti Dhar,</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 06:30:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Stocks edge up in early trading</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/stocks-edge-up-in-early-trading15983</link><description>The country’s bourses saw a positive start on Sunday as key indices in both Dhaka and Chattogram moved up during the first hour of trading, with most companies posting gains.
At the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE), the benchmark DSEX index rose by 3 points in early trading.
While the Shariah-bas</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 06:45:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Burnt body of woman found at roadside in Ctg</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/burnt-body-of-woman-found-at-roadside-in-ctg</link><description>Police have recovered the burnt body of an unidentified woman from the side of a road in Chattogram's Sitakunda.
The incident took place on Saturday night in the Abdullahghata area, close to the Dhaka–Chattogram Highway.
Police said that the initial accounts from witnesses suggest the woman</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 07:00:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>3 injured as motorcyclists attack Bangladesh-China Friendship Bridge toll plaza officers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/3-injured-as-motorcyclists-attack-bangladesh-china-friendship-bridge-toll-plaza-officers</link><description>At least three people have been injured after a group of young men have attacked toll plaza officers of the “Seventh Bangladesh-China Friendship Bridge” over the Arial Kha River in Madaripur after they asked them to pay a toll for their motorcycles.
The incident took place around 7pm o</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 07:20:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>One killed, another critically injured in Khulna court shooting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/one-killed-another-critically-injured-in-khulna-court-shooting</link><description>A man was shot dead and another critically injured when unidentified gunmen opened fire outside the Khulna District and Sessions Judge Court on Sunday. 
The deceased was identified as Rajon, while the injured victim as Hasib. 
Shafiqul Islam, officer-in-charge of Sadar Police Station, s</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 07:35:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Young man found hanging at Rajshahi hotel</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/young-man-found-hanging-at-rajshahi-hotel</link><description>Police recovered the body of a 28-year-old man from a hotel room in New Market area in Rajshahi city on Saturday afternoon.
The deceased was identified as Sabuj Kumar Adhikari, hailed from Atgharia village in Raiganj upazila of Sirajganj district.
Hotel authorities said Sabuj was scheduled to che</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 07:50:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Deprived’ state-owned bank officers stage human chain</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/deprived-state-owned-bank-officers-stage-human-chain</link><description>Officers ‘deprived of promotion’ at state-owned Sonali, Agrani, Janata and Rupali banks formed a human chain in front of the Bangladesh Bank on Sunday, demanding an end to what they described as longstanding discrimination in career advancement.
The aggrieved officials alleged th</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 08:05:38 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>