<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 15:29:32 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Govt appoints 102 magistrates for security oversight of BCS exams</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-appoints-102-magistrates-for-security-oversight-of-bcs-exams</link><description>The government has appointed 102 executive magistrates for security oversight of preliminary exams of the Bangladesh Civil Service (BCS) on January 30.
The preliminary examination (MCQ type) of the 50th BCS will be held on January 30 from 10:00 am to 12:00 pm at 92 educational institutions in the</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 12:45:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mercantile Bank promotes Tapash Paul, Sohel Khurshid to DMDs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/mercantile-bank-promotes-tapash-paul-sohel-khurshid-to-dmds</link><description>Mercantile Bank PLC has promoted Tapash Chandra Paul, PhD, and Shah Md. Sohel Khurshid to the position of Deputy Managing Director.
According to a press release, the new role recognized their long-standing contributions, leadership excelence, and strategic impact on the Bank’s growth and gov</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 13:00:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Summit Group sets sights on Bangladesh’s first data center</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/summit-group-sets-sights-on-bangladeshs-first-data-center</link><description>Summit Group, one of Bangladesh’s largest business conglomerates, is preparing to enter the country’s fast-emerging data center market. Sources say the company aims to partner with an external business entity by next year, marking a significant step toward building what could become Ban</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 13:15:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nahid, Patwary respond to show-cause notices</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ncps-nahid-patwary-respond-to-show-cause-notices-over-early-yes-vote-push</link><description>National Citizen Party (NCP) Convenor Nahid Islam and Chief Coordinator Nasiruddin Patwary have responded to show-cause notices issued against them by returning officers for alleged violations of the electoral code of conduct.
The notice followed alleged campaigning in favour of a “Yes&amp;rdquo</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 13:30:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka Bank donates bus, coaster to Shahid Ziaur Rahman Medical College under CSR programme</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/dhaka-bank-donates-bus-coaster-to-shahid-ziaur-rahman-medical-college-under-csr-programme</link><description>Dhaka Bank has donated a bus and a coaster to Shahid Ziaur Rahman Medical College, Bogura under the Corporate Social Responsibility of the bank, according to a press release.
Mr. Abdul Hai Sarker, Chairman, formally handed over the keys to Professor Dr. Md. Wadudul Hoque Tarafder, Principal of Sha</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 13:45:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump links Greenland dispute to not getting Nobel Peace Prize</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-links-greenland-dispute-to-not-getting-nobel-peace-prize</link><description>US President Donald Trump has said he no longer feels obliged to think only of peace after he did not receive the Nobel Peace Prize, as he again repeated his demand for control of Greenland.
In a message to Norway’s prime minister, Trump blamed the country for not giving him the prize, repor</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 14:00:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>JCD withdraws sit-in after EC assurance on postal ballots</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jcd-withdraws-sit-in-after-ec-assurance-on-postal-ballots</link><description>Bangladesh Jatiyatabadi Chhatra Dal (JCD), the student wing of BNP, on Monday evening withdrew its sit-in programme from in front of the Election Commission (EC) after receiving assurances that steps would be taken over alleged ‘irregularities’ in postal ballots.
Concluding the demonst</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 13:45:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sayed Abul Hashem appointed as new DMD at Al-Arafah Islami Bank</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/sayed-abul-hashem-appointed-as-new-dmd-at-al-arafah-islami-bank</link><description>Sayed Abul Hashem FCA, FCMA has joined Al-Arafah Islami Bank PLC, one of the country's leading Shariah-based banks, as Deputy Managing Director (DMD) and Chief Financial Officer (CFO).
Prior to this, he was working as DMD and CFO at The Premier Bank PLC.
According to a press release, he started h</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 14:00:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Alif killing: key developments in charge framing</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/what-transpired-during-charge-framing-hearing-over-lawyer-alifs-murder</link><description>Chinmoy Krishna Das, spokesperson of the Sammilita Sanatan Jagaran Jote, has claimed innocence in the murder case of lawyer Saiful Islam Alif murder case, a stance echoed by other defendants.
The plaintiff and prosecution lawyers argued that the chargesheet, postmortem report, statements, and conf</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 14:15:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pakistan dismisses rumours of World Cup boycott over Bangladesh row</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/cricket/pakistan-dismisses-rumours-of-world-cup-boycott-over-bangladesh-row</link><description>Uncertainty over Bangladesh’s participation in the T20 World Cup persists, with reports suggesting the Bangladesh Cricket Board (BCB) must confirm its decision by a set deadline.
Amid this, some media speculated that Pakistan might boycott the tournament if Bangladesh withdrew. Gulf News, ho</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 14:30:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Feb-12 polls must be fair, with no room for bias: Prof Yunus</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/feb-12-polls-must-be-fair-with-no-room-for-bias-prof-yunus</link><description>Chief Adviser Prof Muhammad Yunus on Monday said it is the responsibility of all stakeholders - the government, the Election Commission, and political parties - to ensure that the election scheduled for February 12 is held in a ‘fair and festive’ atmosphere.
“I seek the cooperati</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 14:45:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC set to sit with political parties Tuesday over postal ballots</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-set-to-sit-with-political-parties-tuesday-over-postal-ballots</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) will hold a meeting on Tuesday with the representatives of political parties contesting the national election to discuss issues and concerns related to postal ballots.
The meeting is scheduled to be held at 4:00 pm at the Election Commission, and officials from Banglad</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 15:00:51 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>