<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 07:38:34 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>To return home ‘soon’, Tarique Rahman tells BBC Bangla</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/to-return-home-soon-tarique-rahman-tells-bbc-bangla</link><description>BNP’s Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman has said he intends to return to Bangladesh “soon,” marking his first on-camera interview with the media in two decades. In an exclusive conversation with BBC Bangla, he discussed his possible return, the party’s strategy for the upcoming</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 05:09:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>'Moderate' air quality persists in Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/moderate-air-quality-persists-in-dhaka</link><description>Dhaka has ranked 33rd on the list of cities with the worst air quality with an AQI score of 66 at 9:20 am on Monday (October 6, 2025).
Dhaka's air was classified as 'moderate,' referring to a light health threat, according to the AQI index. Such air quality continued for the past few days as Dhaka</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 05:24:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Elderly woman dies in Natore after her face is smashed in</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/elderly-woman-dies-in-natore-after-her-face-is-smashed-in</link><description>Police have recovered the body of an elderly woman who had her face smashed in from Natore’s Baraigram. Law enforcers say they suspect murder.
The incident occurred in the Bonpara Sardarpara area of the Upazila around 8:30pm on Sunday, according to Md Ifte Khayer Alam, additional superintend</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 05:21:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India says ready to work with any elected government in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/india-says-ready-to-work-with-any-elected-government-in-bangladesh</link><description>India is ready to work with any political party that comes to power in Bangladesh through the people’s mandate, Indian Foreign Secretary Vikram Misri said on Monday.
Speaking at an interactive session with a visiting delegation from the Diplomatic Correspondents Association of Bangladesh (DC</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 05:51:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Share market trading of listed firms with halted production raises a red flag</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/share-market-trading-of-listed-firms-with-halted-production-raises-a-red-flag</link><description>Share market analysts have raised a red flag over potential manipulation, with four listed companies with halted or suspended production continuing to trade on the market.
Halted or suspended production implies a status in which firms are not generating any revenue. Investing in such firms should</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 06:21:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India's services growth eases in September as demand cools, PMI shows</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/indias-services-growth-eases-in-september-as-demand-cools-pmi-shows</link><description>Growth in India's services sector cooled in September due to weaker overseas orders, yet it remained strong and optimism improved, a survey showed.
The HSBC India Services Purchasing Managers' Index, compiled by S&amp;amp;P Global, fell to 60.9 in September from a 15-year high of 62.9 in August, lower tha</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 06:36:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Preparations for national election near completion in Khulna division</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/preparations-for-national-election-near-completion-in-khulna-division</link><description>Preparations for the upcoming national election are nearing completion in Khulna division, with the Election Commission (EC) almost finalising the draft list of polling centres and updated voter rolls across its 10 districts.
According to EC data, the number of voters in the division has increased</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 06:51:49 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>