<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 06:11:06 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Tarique casts vote under tight security in Dhaka-17</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-casts-vote-under-tight-security-in-dhaka-17</link><description>BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman cast his vote amid tight security at Gulshan Model School and College on Thursday at 9:36 am.
He was accompanied by his wife, Zubaida Rahman, and daughter, Zaima Rahman. Members of the army and police were deployed around the polling centre to ensure strict security, ac</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 03:54:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka-9 candidate Jara casts vote in Dhaka-11</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/dhaka-9-candidate-jara-casts-vote-in-dhaka-11</link><description>Dr Tasnim Jara, the independent candidate from Dhaka-9, cast her vote at 8:40 am on Thursday at the Taltala Prime School and College polling centre in Khilgaon under Dhaka-11 constituency.
Although she is contesting from Dhaka-9, Jara’s residential address falls under Dhaka-11, so she was un</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 04:09:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>It'll send tremendous signal to world: Commonwealth about Bangladesh polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/itll-send-tremendous-signal-to-world-commonwealth-about-bangladesh-polls</link><description>Chairperson of the Commonwealth Observer Group Nana Akufo-Addo on Thursday expressed satisfaction over the smooth beginning of vote casting at Viqarunnisa Noon School and College and hoped that this trend would continue throughout the day.
"So far so good," the Chairperson and former President of</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 04:24:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hasnat casts ballot in Cumilla-4, urges voters to turn out without fear</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/hasnat-casts-ballot-in-cumilla-4-urges-voters-to-turn-out-without-fear</link><description>Hasnat Abdullah, the 11-party alliance candidate for the Cumilla-4 constituency, has cast his vote and encouraged the public to exercise their franchise freely.
The National Citizen Party (NCP) leader joined the queue at Gopalnagar High School centre in Debidwar Upazila at 8am on Thursday to deliv</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 04:39:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tasnim Jara alleges obstruction of polling agents in Dhaka-9</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tasnim-jara-alleges-obstruction-of-polling-agents-in-dhaka-9</link><description>Independent candidate Tasnim Jara on Thursday alleged widespread non-cooperation with her polling agents across several centres in the Dhaka-9 constituency, raising concerns over the voting process.
Speaking to reporters in front of Khilgaon Model University College, Jara said her agents were faci</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 03:54:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>National Election: Nahid Islam casts his vote</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/national-election-nahid-islam-casts-his-vote</link><description>Convenor of (National Citizens Party) and a candidate of Jamaat-led alliance Nahid Islam cast his vote at Derai AKM Rahmatullah Degree College this morning
 
Voting at polling centres in the Dhaka-11 constituency is progressing peacefully.
 
Nahid reached the polling centre at about 7</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 04:09:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Voting opens across Sylhet-1 as female voters form long lines at multiple centres</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/voting-opens-across-sylhet-1-as-female-voters-form-long-lines-at-multiple-centres</link><description>Women voters have turned out in large numbers at polling stations across Sylhet as voting has got under way.
At 7:45am on Thursday, long queues of female voters formed at Shahjalal Jameya Islamia Kamil Madrasah centre in the Madina Market area of the Sylhet-1 constituency.
A similar scene played</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 04:24:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Yunus casts vote in parliamentary election, referendum</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/yunus-casts-vote-in-parliamentary-election-referendum</link><description>Muhammad Yunus, head of the interim government, has cast his vote in the parliamentary elections.
According to the Chief Advisor’s Office (CAO), Yunus voted at the Gulshan Model School and College polling centre in the capital around 10:30am on Thursday.
At the same centre, he also took par</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 04:39:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Voting underway in Dhaka-8 in festive atmosphere</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/voting-underway-in-dhaka-8-in-festive-atmosphere</link><description>Voting for the 13th National Parliamentary Election began at 7:30am on Thursday, with a large turnout of voters observed at polling centres in the Dhaka-8 constituency.
From early morning, voters were seen lining up in front of polling stations, creating a festive atmosphere in the area.
A visit</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 04:54:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique confident of BNP's victory after casting vote</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-confident-of-bnps-victory-after-casting-vote</link><description>BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman on Thursday expressed satisfaction after casting his vote, saying he is fully confident about his party’s victory.
He cast his vote in the morning at Gulshan Model High School and College centre in the capital around 9:40pm.
Talking to reporters afterwards, Tariq</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 05:09:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Absence of rival polling agents noted at Dhaka-15 centres</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/absence-of-rival-polling-agents-noted-at-dhaka-15-centres</link><description>Despite eight candidates contesting the Dhaka-15 constituency, visits to more than a dozen polling centres on Thursday found no polling agents from most rival contenders.
On the ground, only agents representing the BNP, Jamaat and Aam Janatar Dol were visibly present at the centres. Polling agents</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 05:24:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Turnout gathers pace as Bangladesh voters cast ballots with enthusiasm</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/turnout-gathers-pace-as-bangladesh-voters-cast-ballots-with-enthusiasm</link><description>After going through three controversial elections during the Awami League’s tenure, many voters expressed enthusiasm as they cast their ballots in the 13th parliamentary election and referendum.
Voting began across the country at 7:30 am on Thursday and will continue uninterrupted until 4:30</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 05:39:14 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>