<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 13:35:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>New AI club to bestow nuclear-like power, says Russian tech boss</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/new-ai-club-to-bestow-nuclear-like-power-says-russian-tech-boss</link><description>Artificial intelligence will bestow influence on a par with nuclear technology to countries able to get ahead now, a top Russian AI executive said, giving them superiority this century.
Alexander Vedyakhin, first deputy CEO of Sberbank, which is evolving from a major lender into an AI-focused tech</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 11:36:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt approves re-fixed tariff for seven power plants</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-approves-re-fixed-tariff-for-seven-power-plants</link><description>The government on Monday approved a re-fixed levelized power tariff for seven power plants to ensure their sustainable operations.
The approval came from the 47th meeting of the Advisers Council Committee on Government Purchase in this year held at the Cabinet Division Conference Room at Banglades</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 11:51:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US, Ukraine work on 'refined' peace plan to end war with Russia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-ukraine-work-on-refined-peace-plan-to-end-war-with-russia</link><description>The United States and Ukraine pressed on with talks in Switzerland on Monday to come up with a mutually acceptable peace plan, after agreeing to modify a U.S. proposal that Kyiv and its European allies saw as a Kremlin wish list.
Washington and Kyiv said in a joint statement they had drafted a "re</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 10:45:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Government seeks damage reports from schools after earthquake</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/government-seeks-damage-reports-from-schools-after-earthquake</link><description>The government has asked for detailed reports on the damage to educational institutions following the recent earthquakes.
The Education Engineering Department (EED) has requested information from high schools, colleges, madrasas and technical institutions that were affected. The Directorate of Pri</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 11:00:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CA calls urgent meeting on quake readiness</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ca-yunus-convenes-emergency-meeting-on-earthquake-preparedness-amid-nationwide-alarm</link><description>Chief Advisor Muhammad Yunus has convened an emergency meeting with experts and senior officials on earthquake preparedness
He chaired the session at his Tejgaon office around 5pm on Monday, according to the Chief Advisor's Office.
The meeting came amid alarm after four earthquakes struck on Frid</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 11:15:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Advisor Rizwana calls for urgent coordinated action to reduce earthquake impact</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/advisor-rizwana-calls-for-urgent-coordinated-action-to-reduce-earthquake-impact</link><description>Environment Advisor Syeda Rizwana Hasan has stressed the need for an immediate and coordinated action to minimise the potential impact of a major earthquake in Bangladesh.
Speaking at a seminar in Dhaka on Monday, organised by urban planning authority Rajdhani Unnayan Kartripakkha (RAJUK), she sai</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 11:30:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DSA used as a tool to harass, intimidate journalists: Report</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dsa-used-as-a-tool-to-harass-intimidate-journalists-report</link><description>The Centre for Governance Studies (CGS) and the Clooney Foundation for Justice on Monday launched a research report examining the impact of the Digital Security Act (DSA) on media freedom in Bangladesh and the lessons the country must draw for the future.
The report, launched at a publication even</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 11:45:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt’s ‘apathy’ to non-MPO teachers ‘shameful’: Rizvi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govts-apathy-to-non-mpo-teachers-shameful-rizvi</link><description>BNP Senior Joint Secretary General Ruhul Kabir Rizvi on Monday said the interim government’s indifference to the movement of non-MPO teachers is shameful.
“Education in Bangladesh is no longer the backbone of the nation; rather, it has become the nation’s illness. That is exactly</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 12:00:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>E-family courts will reduce suffering, corruption: Asif Nazrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/e-family-courts-will-reduce-suffering-corruption-asif-nazrul</link><description>The introduction of e-family courts across Bangladesh will not only ease public suffering but also help curb corruption, Law Adviser Asif Nazrul said on Monday.
“The litigants will no longer have to run from place to place as before due to the e-family court system,” he said while spea</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 12:15:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Media must take firm stand against misinformation: Mahfuj Alam</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/media-must-take-firm-stand-against-misinformation-mahfuj-alam</link><description>Information and Broadcasting Adviser Md. Mahfuj Alam has said the media must take a firm stance against rumors and misinformation to restore public trust.
“People’s distrust of the media must be removed,” he said while addressing a training workshop titled ‘Prevention of Me</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 12:30:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fire erupts at DU’s Bijoy Ekattor Hall</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fire-erupts-at-dus-bijoy-ekattor-hall</link><description>A fire has broken out at a shop in Bijoy Ekattor Hall at Dhaka University following a gas cylinder explosion amid a closure for earthquake precaution, Fire Service officials and students have said.
The flames ignited around 6:30pm on Monday, though no casualties were reported.
Student Asif Khan s</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 12:45:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ExchangeKori, Star Tech launch gaming and graphics PC exchange service</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/exchangekori-star-tech-launch-gaming-and-graphics-pc-exchange-service</link><description>For the first time in Bangladesh, consumers can now trade in their old laptops or desktop computers to purchase new gaming and graphics PCs.
The special campaign, titled “Power Up Your Game,” has been introduced by device exchange platform ExchangeKori Limited, with leading gaming hard</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 13:00:50 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>