<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 10:25:26 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Night temperatures may drop by 1–2°C: Met office</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/night-temperatures-may-drop-by-1-2c-met-office</link><description>Bangladesh Meteorological Department (BMD) has forecast a slight fall in night temperatures across the country, with readings expected to drop by 1–2°C.
“Night temperatures may fall by 1–2°C, while day temperatures are likely to remain nearly unchanged across the country,</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 07:00:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cash moving back to vaults amid higher rates</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/cash-moving-back-to-vaults-amid-higher-rates</link><description>The currency held outside banks has been flowing back into vaults in greater volumes in recent months, providing some sort of respite to commercial lenders amid persisting liquidity tightness.
Deposits amounting to Tk 260 billion that flowed out returned to the banking sector in the last four mont</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 07:22:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bringing back killers of July Uprising is our main goal: Press Secretary</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bringing-back-killers-of-july-uprising-is-our-main-goal-press-secretary</link><description>Chief Adviser’s Press Secretary Shafiqul Alam on Friday reaffirmed the government’s commitment to bringing back those responsible for the July killings, calling it a “pledge to the martyrs.”
Speaking at the inauguration of an inter-college football tournament at Magura Gove</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 07:37:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Israel sets 2026 defence budget at $34 billion despite ceasefire in Gaza</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/israel-sets-2026-defence-budget-at-34-billion-despite-ceasefire-in-gaza</link><description>The Gaza war has been costly for Israel, which spent $31bn in 2024 on its military conflicts with Hamas and with Hezbollah
Israel's defence budget for 2026 has been set at 112 billion shekels ($34.63 billion), the defence minis
"We will continue to act decisively to reinforce the IDF and to fully</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 07:52:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>One dies, five get injured as pickup, microbus collide in Chattogram</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/one-dies-five-get-injured-as-pickup-microbus-collide-in-chattogram</link><description>At least one person has died and five others, including women and children, have been injured in a road crash involving a pickup truck and a microbus in Chattogram’s Hathazari.
The accident occurred on the Chattogram-Khagrachhari regional highway in the Farhadabad area of the Upazila on Frid</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 08:07:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh Bank steps up dollar purchases</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladesh-bank-steps-up-dollar-purchases</link><description>The Bangladesh Bank has strengthened its intervention in the foreign exchange market, purchasing US$132 million from five banks in the interbank spot market on Thursday to help stabilise the dollar-taka exchange rate.
The move comes amid continued pressure on the local currency and a broader effor</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 08:22:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh to drill 3 new gas wells as govt clears Tk 11.36 billion exploration plan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-to-drill-3-new-gas-wells-as-govt-clears-tk-1136-billion-exploration-plan</link><description>In a major push to boost domestic energy production and reduce reliance on costly imports, the government has approved a Tk 11.36 billion plan to drill three new gas wells.
The project, to be implemented by Bangladesh Petroleum Exploration and Production Company Limited (BAPEX) under the Energy an</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 09:25:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>July Uprising spotlighted students as democracy’s drivers: Ambassador Mushfique</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/july-uprising-spotlighted-students-as-democracys-drivers-ambassador-mushfique</link><description>Bangladesh's Ambassador to Mexico, Mushfiqul Fazal Ansarey, has said that the student-led uprising in August demonstrated that young people are the true drivers of democracy and accountability in Bangladesh.
Talking to a group of International Relations students from the National Autonomous Univer</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 09:25:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>All looted heavy weapons recovered: Home Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/all-looted-heavy-weapons-recovered-home-adviser</link><description>All heavy weapons looted from law enforcement agencies have now been recovered, Home Affairs Adviser Lt Gen (retd) Jahangir Alam Chowdhury said on Friday.
"There is no failure on the government's part in recovering weapons looted from the police. They are being recovered and will continue to be re</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 09:40:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Asim Munir appointed Pakistan’s first Chief of Defence Forces</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/asim-munir-appointed-pakistans-first-chief-of-defence-forces</link><description>Pakistan has appointed Field Marshal Syed Asim Munir as the country’s first Chief of Defence Forces (CDF), further consolidating his authority at the top of the military hierarchy.
President Asif Ali Zardari approved Prime Minister Shehbaz Sharif’s recommendation to name Munir both chi</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 09:55:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No positive response from India yet on Hasina’s extradition: Foreign Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/no-positive-response-from-india-yet-on-hasinas-extradition-foreign-adviser</link><description>Foreign Affairs Adviser Md Touhid Hossain on Friday said the government of India has not yet given any positive response to Bangladesh's request to extradite ousted Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina.
"We want Sheikh Hasina to be sent back. She is convicted, and the highest judicial institution has sent</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 10:10:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Political roadmap will be drawn up in next few weeks: Mahi B Chowdhury</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/political-roadmap-will-be-drawn-up-in-next-few-weeks-mahi-b-chowdhury</link><description>A long-term political roadmap and the fate of the nation will be determined in the next few weeks, says Mahi B Chowdhury, the son of late president AQM Badruddoza.
Mahi’s comment appeared on his Facebook page on Friday, reports bdnews24.com.
A spokesman for Bikalpa Dhara, Bangladesh, Mahi</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 10:25:25 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>