<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 01:50:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Netanyahu's coalition skips parliamentary vote backing Trump's Gaza plan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/netanyahus-coalition-skips-parliamentary-vote-backing-trumps-gaza-plan</link><description>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu's governing coalition skipped a parliamentary vote on Wednesday endorsing US President Donald Trump's plan to end the two-year war in Gaza.
The vote, proposed by opposition leader Yair Lapid, was largely symbolic as Netanyahu had already publicly backed th</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 15:10:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Writ petition filed seeking stay on election activities</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/writ-petition-filed-seeking-stay-on-election-activities</link><description>A writ petition was filed on Wednesday with the High Court seeking its directives to issue a stay order on the activities related to the upcoming national election.
General Secretary of the Bangladesh Congress Md. Earul Islam filed the writ petition with the HC bench concerned.
The petition also</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 15:25:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Primary teachers asked to withdraw work abstention, exam boycott programmes</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/primary-teachers-asked-to-withdraw-work-abstention-exam-boycott-programmes</link><description>Primary and Mass Education Ministry has directed the several organizations of assistant teachers of government primary schools to withdraw their work abstention and examination boycott programmes and return to duty.
An official handout issued here said the ministry has been informed about the work</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 15:40:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Woman sent to jail on charges of killing 8 puppies in Pabna</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/woman-sent-to-jail-on-charges-of-killing-8-puppies-in-pabna</link><description>A court in Pabna has sent a woman to jail on charges of killing eight puppies in Ishwardi upazila.
The accused, Nishi Rahman, is the wife of an official at the Small Farmers Development Foundation (SFDF) in the area.
She was produced before the Senior Judicial Magistrate Court-1 on Wednesday arou</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 15:41:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>For Bangladesh, a weak WTO is not an option</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/for-bangladesh-a-weak-wto-is-not-an-option</link><description>Bangladesh owes much of its economic rise to the predictability and stability of global trade rules. For decades, the World Trade Organization (WTO) provided exactly that: a system where a young, export-driven country could trust that its garments, pharmaceuticals, and services would be traded on t</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 15:56:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>When teachers hold students hostage!</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/when-teachers-hold-students-hostage</link><description>Annual examinations in most government primary and secondary schools across the country have been thrown into disarray and uncertainty as several groups of teachers launched an indefinite strike on Monday to press home their various demands, including upgrading their posts and securing a pay hike.&amp;</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 16:11:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fazlur Rahman submits unconditional apology over contempt of court allegations</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/fazlur-rahman-submits-unconditional-apology-over-contempt-of-court-allegations</link><description>BNP leader Advocate Fazlur Rahman has tendered an unconditional apology after being accused of contempt of court for making disparaging remarks about the International Crimes Tribunal (ICT).
Chief Prosecutor Mohammad Tajul Islam confirmed the development on Wednesday during a press briefing at the</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 16:26:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Protecting child rights</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/protecting-child-rights</link><description>Endorsement of the Child Rights Manifesto (CRM)--- prepared jointly by children and young people with UNICEF support---by 12 political parties including the major ones likely to come to power through the upcoming election is quite a positive development. By signing the document, these political par</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 16:41:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC moves to amend RPO again ahead of election, referendum schedules</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-moves-to-amend-rpo-again-ahead-of-election-referendum-schedules</link><description>As preparations advance for the general and the national referendum, the Election Commission (EC) is bringing yet another round of amendments to electoral laws and rules.
Following the inclusion of postal voting, the EC says the Representation of the People Order (RPO) needs to be aligned with the</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 17:59:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Krishna Nandi named Jamaat candidate in Khulna-1</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/krishna-nandi-named-jamaat-candidate-in-khulna-1</link><description>The Jamaat-e-Islami has declared Krishna Nandi as its candidate for the Khulna-1 seat for the parliamentary election.
To make this change, the party replaced its earlier nominee in the constituency formed by the minority-dominated Upazilas of Dakope and Batiaghata.
Nandi currently serves as presi</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 18:14:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>High Court orders halt to hill-cutting at Rangamati university site</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/high-court-orders-halt-to-hill-cutting-at-rangamati-university-site</link><description>The High Court has ordered an immediate stop to the hill-cutting carried out for the construction of the Rangamati Science and Technology University building.
The bench of Justice Sikdar Mahmudur Razi and Justice Raziuddin Ahmed issued the directive on Wednesday following a writ petition filed by</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 18:29:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A slew of 7,379 BD products getting free market access</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/a-slew-of-7379-bd-products-getting-free-market-access</link><description>Bangladesh's maiden bilateral free-trade agreement is being signed this month with Japan that will accord 7,379 Bangladeshi products duty-free quota-free (DFQF) market access to world's third-largest economy immediate after the deal-making, officials say.



The deal, coming under the umbrella</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 18:44:04 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>