<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 13:38:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Trump's push to end Ukraine war raises fears of 'ugly deal' for Europe</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trumps-push-to-end-ukraine-war-raises-fears-of-ugly-deal-for-europe</link><description>However Donald Trump’s latest push to end the war in Ukraine pans out, Europe fears the prospect of a deal – sooner or later – that will not punish or weaken Russia as its leaders had hoped, placing the continent’s security in greater jeopardy.
Europe may well even have to</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 11:31:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dengue claims 2 more lives, 565 hospitalised in 24 hours</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dengue-claims-2-more-lives-565-hospitalised-in-24-hours</link><description>Two more deaths were reported from dengue in 24 hours till Tuesday morning, raising the number of fatalities from the mosquito-borne disease in Bangladesh to 386 this year.
During the period, 565 more patients were hospitalised with viral fever, raising the total infected-case to 95, 577 this year</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 10:20:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Coordination, data-sharing stressed to build digital ecosystem</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/coordination-data-sharing-stressed-to-build-digital-ecosystem</link><description>Speakers at a discussion on Tuesday underscored the need for greater coordination and collaboration among ministries, the National Board of Revenue (NBR), business associations, and global brands to enhance data sharing and support the development of a digital ecosystem for the apparel sector.
The</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 10:35:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Former England batter Robin Smith dies at 62</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/former-england-batter-robin-smith-dies-at-62</link><description>Former batter Robin Smith, a World Cup finalist with England in 1992, has died at the age of 62, his former club Hampshire said on Tuesday.
Smith, born in South Africa to British parents, played 62 tests and 71 one-day internationals (ODIs) for England, scoring 13 centuries.
He suffered from depr</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 10:50:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hearing on money laundering case charge-sheets against Salman on Wednesday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/hearing-on-money-laundering-case-charge-sheets-against-salman-on-wednesday</link><description>The Dhaka Chief Metropolitan Magistrate Court is scheduled to hold a hearing on Wednesday on the acceptance of charge sheets in nine money laundering cases against Beximco Group Vice-chairman Salman F Rahman and others.
The Financial Crime Unit of the Criminal Investigation Department (CID) submit</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 11:05:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Now Jamaat replaces election candidate in Lalmonirhat-3</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/now-jamaat-replaces-election-candidate-in-lalmonirhat-3</link><description>Jamaat-e-Islami has changed its candidate for the Lalmonirhat-3 (Sadar) constituency, a day after announcing a similar reshuffle in Habiganj-4.
Advocate Abu Taher, the party’s Lalmonirhat district Ameer, has been nominated to contest the election for the seat in place of former Rangpur Metro</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 11:20:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Expats sent remittance over 5 million times to loved  ones’ bKash via Pubali Bank</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/expats-sent-remittance-over-5-million-times-to-loved-ones-bkash-via-pubali-bank</link><description>Bangladeshi expatriates have sent remittances to their loved ones’ bKash accounts more than 5 million times within 10 months via Pubali Bank.
This hassle-free and secure service, offered by two of the country’s leading financial institutions, has earned the trust of expatriates and the</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 11:35:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sammilito Islami Bank begins operations</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/sammilito-islami-bank-begins-operations</link><description>Marking a major consolidation in the financial sector, Sammilito Islami Bank PLC officially commenced operations on Tuesday following the merger of five Shariah-based banks.
Former secretary Mohammad Ayub Miah has taken office as the chairman of the new bank following a meeting with Bangladesh Ban</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 11:50:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BRAC Bank and Water.org partner to expand WASH financing through Social Bond</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/brac-bank-and-waterorg-partner-to-expand-wash-financing-through-social-bond</link><description>BRAC Bank and Water.org have entered into a partnership to expand access to safe water and sanitation across Bangladesh.
The partnership strengthens BRAC Bank’s Social Bond initiative and marks a significant step in scaling Water, Sanitation and Hygiene (WASH) financing nationwide, according</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 12:05:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BSEC extends deadline for provisioning of 11 market intermediaries</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bsec-extends-deadline-for-provisioning-of-11-market-intermediaries</link><description>The Bangladesh Securities and Exchange Commission (BSEC), the country’s capital market regulator, has decided to conditionally extend the deadline for provision conservation and adjustment for 11 additional intermediary institutions.
This decision aims to provide relief to firms struggling w</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 12:20:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Islami Bank's CellFin app adds fully voice-driven service</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/islami-banks-cellfin-app-adds-fully-voice-driven-service</link><description>Islami Bank has launched the country’s first artificial-intelligence-based voice assistant CellFin Echo, inside the CellFin app.
It is a fully voice-driven virtual assistant that allows users to perform their banking activities through voice commands. When a user gives a voice command in Eng</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 12:35:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt approves import of 220,000 metric tonnes of wheat from US</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-approves-import-of-220000-metric-tonnes-of-wheat-from-us</link><description>The Advisers Council Committee on Government Purchase on Tuesday approved a proposal to procure 220,000 metric tonnes of wheat from the United States under a Government-to-Government (G2G) arrangement.
The approval came from a meeting of the Advisers Council Committee on Government Purchase held v</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 12:50:03 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>