<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 19:14:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>EC warns of action over vote‑buying</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/election-commission-vows-strict-action-if-proof-of-vote-trading-emerges</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has warned of “strict action” if evidence of vote buying emerges in the national election and referendum.
The warning came in a media statement issued around 9pm on Wednesday, a day before polling, amid widespread discussion over alleged cash transactions a</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 16:55:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Iran says it won't negotiate over its missile capabilities</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/iran-says-it-wont-negotiate-over-its-missile-capabilities</link><description>Iran's missile capabilities are its red line and are not a subject to be negotiated, an adviser to Iran's supreme leader said on Wednesday, as Tehran and Washington eye a new round of talks to avert conflict.
US and Iranian diplomats held indirect talks last week in Oman, amid a regional naval bui</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 17:10:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>From uprising  to exclusion</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/from-uprising-to-exclusion</link><description>In Bangladesh's much-anticipated February 12 national elections, one contradiction stands out: the striking exclusion of women from the electoral contest in the democratic transition following the fall of the autocratic regime of Sheikh Hasina. Women played a visible and critical role in the studen</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 16:27:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Choices matter more than promises</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/reviews/choices-matter-more-than-promises</link><description>This article outlines a proactive policy agenda that goes beyond crisis control to promote purposeful growth. It emphasises the need for a more balanced macroeconomic strategy that controls inflation without choking investment, alongside realistic exchange rate management and stronger market govern</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 16:42:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Factors likely to influence the outcome of JS polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/factors-likely-to-influence-the-outcome-of-js-polls</link><description>The Thirteenth Jatiya Sangsad (JS) Election is being held in Bangladesh today amid much expectation and apprehension. The political contenders have concluded their weeks-long campaign and are now eagerly waiting for the outcome of their labour. Some opinion surveys have also been conducted that pre</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 16:57:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Election thoughts: The rebirth of democracy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/election-thoughts-the-rebirth-of-democracy</link><description>As Bangladesh goes to the polls today, a whiff of fresh air dispels the gloom. Lingering speculation and conspiracy theories over the fate of the election are finally giving way to cautious optimism. Hope surges for the revival of democracy. Since the country's independence in 1971, the journey to</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 17:12:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A decisive moment for nation's future direction</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/a-decisive-moment-for-nations-future-direction</link><description>As the country goes to the world's first Generation Z or Gen Z-influenced polls today, the people are both hopeful and apprehensive of the tidings of the day. The nation is not at peace with itself and the interim government has not particularly helped the cause. There have been a number of politic</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 17:27:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique visits hospitalised Rizvi on eve of election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-visits-hospitalised-rizvi-on-eve-of-election</link><description>BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman on Wednesday night visited Square Hospital in the capital to enquire about the health of his party’s Senior Joint Secretary General Advocate Ruhul Kabir Rizvi.
Tarique went to the hospital around 9:15 pm and met Rizvi, who has been undergoing treatment there since</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 17:42:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>800,000 officials to remain on election duty: EC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/800000-officials-to-remain-on-election-duty-ec</link><description>About 800,000 officials will be engaged in election duty in the 13th parliamentary elections and referendum to be held tomorrow.
According to the Election Commission (EC), a total of 69 returning officers and 598 assistant returning officers will remain on duty during the polls.
Voting will take</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 06:21:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Three imprisoned candidates contest in JS polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/three-imprisoned-candidates-contest-in-js-polls</link><description>Three candidates are contesting in the parliamentary election from behind bars, highlighting an unusual facet of the race as voting approaches.
Two of the contenders are being held in Faridpur District Jail, while the third remains in custody at the Special Central Jail in Keraniganj, reports bdne</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 17:57:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Historic 13th parliamentary polls today</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/historic-13th-parliamentary-polls-today</link><description>Bangladesh heads to the Jatiya Sangsad (JS) polls Thursday amid a changed political ambience in a consequential election in its recent history as rebuilding the country's upended democratic institutions is an onerous stake.



Many see the vote--arranged against the backdrop of an uprising that</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 18:12:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two BNP activists held with cash in Barishal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/two-bnp-activists-held-with-cash-in-barishal</link><description>Two BNP activists were detained with more than Tk 100,000 in Babuganj upazila of Barishal on Wednesday, hours before the national election.
Commanding Officer of Army’s 62 East Bengal, Lieutenant Colonel Faiz Ahmed, said that as part of ongoing law and order and election security operations,</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 18:27:34 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>