<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 16:29:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Zubaida, Zaima see Khaleda at Evercare Hospital</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/zubaida-zaima-at-khaledas-bedside-on-evercare-hospital-visit</link><description>After about two hours of rest at their Gulshan residence, Zubaida Rahman, the daughter-in-law of former prime minister Khaleda Zia, and her daughter Zaima Rahman have arrived at Evercare Hospital in Dhaka.
Khaleda has been receiving intensive care at the hospital since Nov 23.
The mother and daug</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 13:01:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique Rahman’s return expected to boost confidence in democracy: Mahfuj Alam</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-rahmans-return-expected-to-boost-confidence-in-democracy-mahfuj-alam</link><description>Former adviser and a frontline July uprising leader Mahfuj Alam, on Thursday said the return of BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman is expected to strengthen public trust and confidence in Bangladesh’s democratic system.
“Tarique Rahman’s return after 17 years of exile is expected</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 13:16:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>My grandfather encouraged me to play for Algeria, Luca Zidane says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/football/my-grandfather-encouraged-me-to-play-for-algeria-luca-zidane-says</link><description>Luca Zidane, son of French World Cup-winner Zinedine, said his grandfather had supported him in switching international allegiance to Algeria, after playing for France at junior level.
Zinedine Zidane is widely regarded as one of the greatest French footballers, inspiring his country to their firs</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 13:31:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>China accuses US of trying to thwart improved China-India ties</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/china-accuses-us-of-trying-to-thwart-improved-china-india-ties</link><description>China accused the US on Thursday of distorting its defence policy in an effort to thwart an improvement in China-India ties.
Foreign ministry spokesperson Lin Jian was responding to a question at a press briefing on whether China might exploit a recent easing of tensions with India over disputed b</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 13:46:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cold wave continues, affecting normal life in northern region</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cold-wave-continues-affecting-normal-life-in-northern-region</link><description>Although the minimum temperatures remained mostly unchanged and maximum temperatures increased slightly, the mild cold wave blowing over the northern region continued affecting the normal life for the third consecutive day.
The sky remained partly cloudy and misty till noon with cold winds blowing</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 13:49:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Serbia supports talks with Hungary's Mol over sale of sanctioned NIS oil firm</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/serbia-supports-talks-with-hungarys-mol-over-sale-of-sanctioned-nis-oil-firm</link><description>Serbia supports talks over the sale of a majority stake in the country's sanctioned NIS oil company currently taking place between its Russian owners and Hungary's MOL, the Tanjug news agency reported on Thursday, citing Serbia's energy minister.
"The Hungarian government supported those talks, an</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 14:04:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh Election: 740,000 registered for postal voting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-election-740000-registered-for-postal-voting</link><description>Some 740,000 voters, including more than 534,000 expatriates from different countries across the world, have been registered to vote through postal ballots in the national election scheduled for February 12, 2026.
The Election Commission (EC) opened the ‘Postal Vote Bd’ app for the Out</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 14:19:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique’s homecoming not a party victory but democratic achievement: Hasnat Abdullah</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tariques-homecoming-not-a-party-victory-but-democratic-achievement-hasnat-abdullah</link><description>Tarique Rahman’s return to Bangladesh after nearly one and a half decades in exile should be seen not as a personal or party achievement, but as a significant milestone in the country’s continued democratic struggle, said Hasnat Abdullah, chief coordinator (Southern) of the National Cit</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 14:34:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique’s return will ensure peaceful coexistence: GM Quader</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tariques-return-to-bangladesh-will-ensure-peaceful-political-coexistence-says-gm-quader</link><description>Jatiya Party Chairman GM Quader has welcomed the return of BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman, suggesting that his homecoming after over 17 years in exile will serve as a catalyst for political harmony.
In a message issued on Thursday, he said: “[Tarique’s] return will help consolidate</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 14:49:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP to launch cleaning drive at July 36 Expressway (300-feet) on Friday morning</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bnp-to-launch-cleaning-drive-at-july-36-expressway-300-feet-on-friday-morning</link><description>Dhaka Metropolitan North unit of Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) will conduct a voluntary clean-up drive tomorrow morning to remove waste generated following the massive public gathering held to mark the ‘historic homecoming’ of BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman.
BNP Media Cell Con</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 15:20:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Syria to start currency swap on January 1, central bank governor says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/syria-to-start-currency-swap-on-january-1-central-bank-governor-says</link><description>Syria will start swapping old banknotes for new ones from January 1, 2026, Central Bank Governor Abdelkader Husrieh said on Thursday, under a plan to replace Assad-era notes to try to strengthen the currency's value.
Syria’s new government, led by Syrian President Ahmed al-Sharaa, is seeking</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 15:35:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Forest great Robertson, ‘Picasso of our game’, dies at 72</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/football/forest-great-robertson-picasso-of-our-game-dies-at-72</link><description>John Robertson, the Nottingham Forest winger described by his manager Brian Clough as “a Picasso of our game”, has died at the age of 72, the Premier League club said on Thursday.
He was a key member of Clough’s all-conquering Forest team, assisting Trevor Francis’s winner</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 15:50:44 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>