<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 17:56:46 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Will the president reconcile his words? Shafiqur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/shafiqur-asks-whether-president-will-reconcile-conflicting-accounts-on-hasinas-resignation</link><description>Jamaat-e-Islami chief Shafiqur Rahman has accused President Mohammed Shahabuddin of “withholding key details” about the dramatic events of Aug 5, 2024, and the resignation of Sheikh Hasina as prime minister.
Shafiqur raised questions over “contradictions” in the president&amp;r</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 14:06:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New US tariffs come in at lower 10pc rate</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/new-us-tariffs-come-in-at-lower-10pc-rate</link><description>The United States imposed a new tariff from Tuesday of 10 percent on all goods not covered by exemptions, the US Customs and Border Protection said, the rate first announced by President Donald Trump on Friday rather than the 15 percent he promised a day later.
Reacting to the US Supreme Court rul</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 14:21:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>2 secretaries reshuffled, Sanwar returns to PSC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/2-secretaries-reshuffled-sanwar-returns-to-psc</link><description>The government has reassigned Md Sanwar Jahan Bhuiyan, secretary at the Ministry of Labour and Employment, back to the Public Service Commission (PSC) Secretariat after five months.
In a corresponding move, Abdur Rahman Tarafder, who had been serving as secretary at the PSC Secretariat, was appoin</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 14:36:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BD-Japan defence deal: Decision on implementation after review</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bd-japan-defence-deal-decision-on-implementation-after-review</link><description>Japan has urged Bangladesh’s new government to uphold a defence agreement signed with the previous interim administration, even as Dhaka signalled it would review the deal based on national interest.
The issue was raised on Tuesday during a courtesy call by Japan’s ambassador to Bangla</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 14:51:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangla Academy assures inclusive, safe Amar Ekushey Book Fair</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangla-academy-assures-inclusive-safe-amar-ekushey-book-fair</link><description>Bangla Academy on Tuesday assured that this year’s Amar Ekushey Book Fair will be held in a more organised, inclusive and secure manner from February 26, despite various challenges, with the participation of the highest number of publishers.
Director General Dr Mohammad Azam made the remarks</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 15:06:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Court asks freezing bank account of ex-Rab DG, wife</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/court-asks-freezing-bank-account-of-ex-rab-dg-wife</link><description>A Dhaka court on Monday asked the authorities concerned to freeze the bank accounts of former director general (DG) of Rapid Action Battalion (RAB) Barrister Md Harun Ar Rashid, his wife Fatema Pervin Luna on graft charges.
Judge of the Dhaka Senior Special Judge Court, Md Sabbir Faiz passed the o</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 15:25:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Four policemen ‘removed’ over assault on student, journalists at Suhrawardy Udyan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/four-policemen-removed-over-assault-on-student-journalists-at-suhrawardy-udyan</link><description>Four policemen have been withdrawn from their duties following the alleged assault on a Dhaka University student and two journalists during a raid at the Suhrawardy Udyan.
The incident, which occurred on Monday night, sparked protests outside the Shahbagh Police Station on Tuesday.
Dhaka Universi</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 15:40:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Three BB officials ‘immediately transferred’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/three-central-bank-officials-immediately-transferred-after-show-cause-notices</link><description>The Bangladesh Bank has ordered immediate transfer (stand release) of three officials who received show cause notices for breach of discipline.
The central bank had served them the notices two days ago for calling a press briefing alleging that digital banks were getting approval before the format</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 15:55:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Magura clash over local dominance leaves 10 injured</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/magura-clash-over-local-dominance-leaves-10-injured</link><description>At least 10 people were injured in a clash between two groups over local dominance in Shrikol Union, Shreepur Upazila, Magura, late Monday night.
The confrontation involved retaliatory attacks and a grenade explosion in the villages of Chonogacha and Doshtina.
The injured were admitted to Magura</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 16:10:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No financial transaction or broker needed to get family card</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/no-financial-transaction-or-broker-needed-to-get-family-card</link><description>The government today said that any financial transaction through brokers or other intermediaries to obtain the Family Card is illegal.
The Family Card is a priority programme of the present government and it is firmly committed to implementing the initiative. 
The information was disclosed i</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 16:40:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Korean FM greets Khalilur Rahman; eyes enhanced ties with Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/korean-fm-greets-khalilur-rahman-eyes-enhanced-ties-with-dhaka</link><description>South Korean Foreign Minister Cho Hyun has said he looks forward to working closely with his newly appointed Bangladesh counterpart Dr Khalilur rahman to further enhance the bilateral relations in the years to come.
“I would like to extend my heartfelt congratulations on your appointment as</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 16:55:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>'Family Card' completely free, no scope for demanding money: Zahid</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/family-card-completely-free-no-scope-for-demanding-money-zahid</link><description>Social Welfare and Women and Children Affairs Minister Dr AZM Zahid today (Tuesday) said the government's 'Family Card' programme will be implemented entirely free of cost, with no scope for anyone to demand money in exchange for the card.
"If anyone attempts to commit fraud in this regard, legal</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 17:10:59 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>