<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 17:17:04 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Film Institute to launch training courses for July victims soon: Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/film-institute-to-launch-training-courses-for-july-victims-soon-adviser</link><description>Information and Broadcasting Adviser Md. Mahfuj Alam on Tuesday said an integrated training course will soon be launched at the Bangladesh Cinema and Television Institute (BCTI) for the July Mass Uprising injured who are interested in art, culture, and film.
He made the remarks while addressing a</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 14:32:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Following Facebook exchange, Asif declares Shakib 'will never play for Bangladesh again'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/following-facebook-exchange-asif-declares-shakib-will-never-play-for-bangladesh-again</link><description>Bangladesh’s youth and sports adviser Asif Mahmud Sajib Bhuiyan says Shakib Al Hasan will not be allowed to play for the national team again, escalating a two-day online spat that began with the cricketer’s birthday greeting to former prime minister Sheikh Hasina, who was ousted last ye</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 14:47:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Farhad Mazhar accuses Yunus of leading Bangladesh to ‘very dangerous’ place</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/farhad-mazhar-accuses-yunus-of-leading-bangladesh-to-very-dangerous-place</link><description>Poet and political thinker Farhad Mazhar has criticised Chief Advisor Muhammad Yunus for taking Bangladesh to a “very dangerous place” by prioritising elections without sincerely implementing the aims of the July Uprising.
Speaking at a discussion titled “Fascist state system and</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 15:17:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Can Bangladesh turn carbon into cash?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/can-bangladesh-turn-carbon-into-cash</link><description>As the world’s climate crisis escalates, Asia is playing a significant role due to its highest contribution to CO2 emissions, accounting for around 60 per cent of the total 40 billion metric tons of carbon emissions. According to the emission index, Bangladesh ranks 35th globally in terms of</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 15:32:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Doctors find ‘no evidence of rape’ in Khagrachhari victim’s medical tests</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/doctors-find-no-evidence-of-rape-in-khagrachhari-victims-medical-tests</link><description>The medical examination of the Marma victim-survivor in Khagrachhari has found “no signs of rape”, said the lead doctor of the examining team.
On Tuesday, Dr Joya Chakma of Khagrachhari Modern District Hospital, who headed the three-member medical board, said: “We have submitted</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 16:17:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Parts of Dhaka waterlogged after evening showers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/parts-of-dhaka-waterlogged-after-evening-showers</link><description>Intense rainfall on Tuesday evening led to waterlogging in some parts of Dhaka, causing immense suffering for commuters.
Streets in areas such as Mouchak, Malibagh, Shantinagar, Moghbazar, Dainik Bangla Intersection, and Kakrail were submerged, forcing residents to wade through water while trying</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 16:32:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Reversing the slide in service export</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/reversing-the-slide-in-service-export</link><description>While a lack of government initiative is often blamed for the sluggish performance of the country's export of services, absence of innovative approaches by the private sector is considered no less responsible. The combined effect of these two factors appears to be keeping the country's service expo</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 16:47:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tackling irregularities, corruption in health sector</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/tackling-irregularities-corruption-in-health-sector</link><description>Hospitals and other health service providers in the public sector have long earned infamy for corruption as well as substandard services. Reports on such irregularities abound. One might recall here the Transparency International Bangladesh (TI,B)'s study report of November 2020 during the outbreak</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 17:02:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khagrachhari blockade suspended until Oct 5</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/khagrachhari-blockade-suspended-until-oct-5</link><description>The Jumma Chhatra Janata has suspended its blockade in Khagrachhari until Oct 5, following four days of protests.
In a media statement issued at 9pm on Tuesday via their Facebook page, the group announced the decision, bdnews24.com reports. 
The statement said the suspension came after recei</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 17:17:04 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>