<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 15:23:37 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Special Business Review Meeting 2025 of Union Bank</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/special-business-review-meeting-2025-of-union-bank</link><description>The Special Business Review Meeting 2025 of Union Bank PLC held on 02 November, 2025 in the bank’s Head Office, Gulshan-1, Dhaka.
The Managing Director &amp; CEO of the bank Mr. Mohd. Humayun Kabir presided over the meeting, according to a press release.
Chairman of the Board of the Directors o</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 12:14:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Syed Zubayer Ahmed new DMD of National Bank</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/syed-zubayer-ahmed-new-dmd-of-national-bank</link><description>Mr. Syed Zubayer Ahmed joined National Bank PLC as Deputy Managing Director on November 3, 2025.
Before joining National Bank, Mr. Ahmed served as Vice President &amp; Head of International Regulatory Reporting, Group Financial Control Department at Qatar National Bank (QNB), Doha—the largest ba</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 12:44:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Modhumoti Bank inaugurates its relocated Gopalganj Branch</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/modhumoti-bank-inaugurates-its-relocated-gopalganj-branch</link><description>To bring more people within the coverage of financial services, Modhumoti Bank PLC inaugurated its relocated Gopalganj Branch and the new Gopalganj Eye Hospital Sub-Branch under the control of Gopalganj Branch on Monday, November 3, 2025.
The relocated Branch is situated at Harun Tower in the Madr</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 12:59:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>15th MTB Foundation ‘Bravery and Courage Award’ presented to victims of Milestone Tragedy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/15th-mtb-foundation-bravery-and-courage-award-presented-to-victims-of-milestone-tragedy</link><description>MTB Foundation has recently presented its 15th Bravery and Courage Award to Maherin Chowdhury, Mashuka Begum, Mahfuza Khatun and Masuma Begum, who sacrificed their lives while trying to save the students from the raging fire at the Milestone School and College tragedy on July 21, 2025.
Their selfl</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 13:29:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dengue: 5 deaths, 1,147 hospital admissions reported in 24 hours</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dengue-5-deaths-1147-hospital-admissions-reported-in-24-hours</link><description>Bangladesh has reported 1,147 new hospitalisations due to dengue in the past 24 hours with five fatalities.
According to the Directorate General of Health Services (DGHS) count on Monday, this year, as many as 72,822 dengue patients have been admitted to hospitals across the country, of whom 288 h</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 13:59:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Election must be held on time, reforms must be implemented: Akhter</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/election-must-be-held-on-time-reforms-must-be-implemented-akhter</link><description>Member Secretary of National Citizen Party (NCP) Akhter Hussain today (Monday) said the upcoming national election must be held on time alongside full implementation of the agreed reforms, warning that any attempt to derail either would endanger the country's stability.
"We see a tendency to derai</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 14:14:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pubali Bank launches co-branded credit card in partnership with CMC, CMCH</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/pubali-bank-launches-co-branded-credit-card-in-partnership-with-cmc-cmch</link><description>The country’s one of the leading private commercial banks, Pubali Bank PLC, through its Anderkilla Branch initiative, is launching a co-branded credit card in collaboration with Chittagong Medical College and Chittagong Medical College Hospital.
According to a press release, the unveiling ce</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 14:29:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt rejects Netra News photo feature on CHT as 'misleading'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-rejects-netra-news-photo-feature-on-cht-as-misleading</link><description>The government has rejected what it described as a misleading portrayal of the Chittagong Hill Tracts (CHT) in a recent photo feature published by Netra News, which indicated the region as ‘occupied,’ ‘militarised, or ‘under military rule.”
In a statement issued by th</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 14:59:17 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>