<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 15:22:28 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>IFIC Bank hands over Startup Fund Cheque to Bangladesh Bank</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ific-bank-hands-over-startup-fund-cheque-to-bangladesh-bank</link><description>As part of the initiatives undertaken in accordance with Bangladesh Bank’s directives on the formation and operational activities of Bangladesh Startup Investment Company PLC, IFIC Bank PLC has formally handed over a cheque amounting Tk 80,057,080 (BDT Eight Crore Fifty-Seven Thousand and Eig</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 12:21:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tribunal orders arrest of Taposh, Nanok</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/tribunal-orders-arrest-of-taposh-nanok</link><description>The International Crimes Tribunal has issued arrest warrants against former Dhaka South mayor Sheikh Fazle Noor Taposh, Awami League leader Jahangir Kabir Nanok, and 26 others over charges of crimes against humanity during the July Uprising.
The order came on Sunday from Tribunal‑1, headed by Just</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 12:36:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Islami Bank's sub-branch business development conference held</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/islami-banks-sub-branch-business-development-conference-held</link><description>Islami Bank Bangladesh PLC organized business development conference for its sub-branches on January 17, 2026, at Hotel Intercontinental, Dhaka.
Professor Dr. M. Zubaidur Rahman, chairman of Board of Directors of the bank attended the closing program as chief guest, according to a media release.&amp;n</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 12:51:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mahfuz Anam calls for strict editorial oversight to protect journalism</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/mahfuz-anam-calls-for-strict-editorial-oversight-to-protect-journalism</link><description>The Daily Star Editor Mahfuz Anam on Sunday highlighted the crucial role of personal self-filtering and robust institutional editorial oversight in preserving objective journalism and responsible freedom of expression in Bangladesh.
Speaking at the Professor Sitara Parveen Award Ceremony&amp;nda</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 13:06:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fakhrul accuses EC of ‘questionable acts’ in many cases</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/fakhrul-accuses-ec-of-questionable-acts-in-many-cases</link><description>BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir on Sunday alleged that the Election Commission (EC) is showing questionable conduct in a number of areas through its actions.
“The Election Commission, through its activities, is engaging in questionable conduct in many cases,” Fakhrul</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 13:21:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Swiss, Brazilian envoys meet Tarique</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/swiss-brazilian-envoys-meet-tarique</link><description>Swiss Ambassador Reto Renggli and Brazilian Ambassador Paulo Fernando Dias Feres separately paid courtesy calls on BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman on Monday.
The Brazilian Ambassador to Bangladesh first met Tarique Rahman at the party chairman’s Gulshan political office around 5pm, said BNP Medi</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 13:36:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>'Be in no doubt' EU will retaliate to any new US tariffs, Ireland says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/be-in-no-doubt-eu-will-retaliate-to-any-new-us-tariffs-ireland-says</link><description>The European Union will retaliate if US tariff threats against European allies over Greenland materialise, but it is premature to consider using the bloc's "Anti-Coercion Instrument", Ireland's prime minister said on Sunday.
"The tempo here has increased very dramatically, very quickly. Be in no d</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 13:51:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pubali Bank’s ADC Division holds Annual Business Conference-2026</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/pubali-banks-adc-division-holds-annual-business-conference-2026</link><description>Pubali Bank PLC's ADC Division holds Annual Business Conference-2026 at the bank’s head office auditorium on Sunday.
Mohammad Ali, Managing Director and CEO of Pubali Bank, was present as chief guest. Mohammad Esha, Mohammad Shahadat Hossain, Ahmed Enayet Manzur, Md. Shahnewaz Khan and Moham</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 14:06:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>2 burnt bodies recovered from abandoned community centre at Savar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/2-burnt-bodies-recovered-from-abandoned-community-centre-at-savar</link><description>Police recovered two charred bodies from an abandoned community centre in Savar municipality area on Sunday.
Local people spotted the bodies at the community centre, about 500 yards away from Savar Model Police Station premises and informed police through national emergency number 999 who recovere</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 14:21:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Uttara Bank inaugurates one stop service</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/uttara-bank-inaugurates-one-stop-service</link><description>Uttara Bank PLC has inaugurated its ‘One Stop Service’ at a function at its corporate branch in Dhaka on Sunday, according to a press release.
Mr. Md. Abul Hashem, Managing Director &amp; CEO of Uttara Bank PLC, inaugurated the service.
Additional Managing Director Mr. Maksudul Hasan, Dep</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 14:36:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rumeen Farhana show-caused over ‘mob creation’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rumeen-farhana-show-caused-over-mob-creation</link><description>Rumeen Farhana, the independent candidate for Brahmanbaria-2, has been served a show-cause notice over allegations that she incited a mob and obstructed a mobile court during an official operation.
The government has asked her to explain her actions in connection with the incident.</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 14:51:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ICMAB elects new committee for 2026, with Kausar Alam as president</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/icmab-elects-new-committee-for-2026-with-kausar-alam-as-president</link><description>The Institute of Cost and Management Accountants of Bangladesh (ICMAB) has announced its new executive committee for the year 2026.
In the first meeting of the 19th Council, Md. Kausar Alam FCMA was elected as the President of the Institute. The council also elected a distinguished panel of profes</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 15:06:28 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>