<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 15:22:31 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Inqilab Moncho ends blockade in Chattogram after more than three hours</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/inqilab-moncho-ends-blockade-in-chattogram-after-more-than-three-hours</link><description>The Inqibal Moncho platform has withdrawn its blockade of the Shah Amanat Bridge in Chattogram after three and a half hours of demonstrations.
The platform’s activists had obstructed the bridge around 2:00 pm on Sunday, demanding the arrest and trial of the killers of their slain leader Shar</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 11:53:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fascist allies, terrorists lurking inside political parties: Home Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fascist-allies-terrorists-lurking-inside-political-parties-home-adviser</link><description>Home Affairs Adviser Lt Gen (retd) Md Jahangir Alam Chowdhury on Sunday voiced concern over the growing presence of fascist allies, terrorists and miscreants within political parties, highlighting the potential threat to national stability.
“The government has information that some leaders a</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 12:08:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>All students will receive new textbooks by mid-January</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/all-students-will-receive-new-textbooks-by-mid-january</link><description>Education Advisor Chowdhury Rafiqul Abrar has said all of the new textbooks for both primary and secondary students will be distributed before the middle of January next year.
Speaking at the launch of uploading soft copies of the new textbooks online at the National Curriculum and Textbook Board</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 12:23:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CA for enhanced trade with Pakistan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ca-for-enhanced-trade-with-pakistan</link><description>Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus stressed the need for boosting bilateral trade between Bangladesh and Pakistan when Pakistan High Commissioner, Imran Haider, paid a courtesy call on him at the State Guest House in Dhaka.
During the meeting, both sides discussed ways to expand cooperation in</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 12:38:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Meghalaya Police reject claims on Hadi murder suspects’ arrest</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/meghalaya-police-reject-claims-on-hadi-murder-suspects-arrest</link><description>India’s Meghalaya Police and the Border Security Force (BSF) have rejected claims by the Dhaka Metropolitan Police (DMP) that the two main suspects in the murder of Sharif Osman bin Hadi fled to India and that two of their alleged abetters were arrested across the border.
Around 11:30am on S</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 12:53:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat postpones Jan 3 grand rally</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-postpones-jan-3-grand-rally</link><description>Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami on Sunday announced the postponement of its previously scheduled grand rally slated for January 3.
The announcement was made in a statement issued by the party’s Secretary General Mia Golam Parwar.
Parwar said the decision was taken as the admission tests for firs</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 13:08:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Al-Arafah Islami Bank signs agreement with Provati Insurance</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/al-arafah-islami-bank-signs-agreement-with-provati-insurance</link><description>Al-Arafah Islami Bank PLC, country’s one of the leading Shariah-based banks, has signed a Memorandum of Understanding with Provati Insurance PLC.
According to a press release, the agreement will enable seamless premium collection, enhanced data security, real-time reporting, and efficient fi</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 13:23:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BRAC Bank wins Remittance Award from expatriates’ welfare ministry</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/brac-bank-wins-remittance-award-from-expatriates-welfare-ministry</link><description>The Ministry of Expatriates’ Welfare &amp; Overseas Employment has awarded BRAC Bank the prestigious Remittance Award for the second consecutive year.
According to a press release, this recognition from the government of Bangladesh demonstrates BRAC Bank's strong commitment to bolstering the eco</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 13:38:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Islami Bank holds meeting of board of directors</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/islami-bank-holds-meeting-of-board-of-directors</link><description>A meeting of the board of directors of Islami Bank Bangladesh PLC was held on Sunday at Islami Bank Tower, according to a press release.
Professor Dr. M. Zubaidur Rahman, chairman of the bank, presided over the meeting. Mohammad Khurshid Wahab, chairman of the executive committee, Md. Abdus Salam,</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 13:53:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Modhumoti Bank signs MoU with World Famous Tours and Travels</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/modhumoti-bank-signs-mou-with-world-famous-tours-and-travels</link><description>Modhumoti Bank PLC signed an MoU with World Famous Tours &amp; Travels (WFTT) on Tuesday at the Bank’s Head Office, Gulshan, Dhaka.
Mr. Arab Fazlur Rahman, Deputy Managing Director &amp; Chief Business Officer of Modhumoti Bank, and Mr. Shohan Mahmud, CEO and Founder of World Famous Tours &amp; Travels,</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 14:08:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>MTB distributes loans to participants of SICIP at Jashore</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/mtb-distributes-loans-to-participants-of-sicip-at-jashore</link><description>Mutual Trust Bank PLC (MTB) has distributed loan sanction letters to selected participants of the Skills for Industry Competitiveness and Innovation Program (SICIP) at the concluding ceremony of a month-long capacity-building workshop held in Jashore, according to a press release.
Nawshad Mustafa,</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 14:23:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh Polls: Nomination paper submission closes Monday; 99pc yet to file</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-polls-nomination-paper-submission-closes-monday-99pc-yet-to-file</link><description>With the deadline for submitting nomination papers for the upcoming national election falling on Monday, nearly 99 percent of aspirants who collected the forms have yet to file them as they are waiting for the last day.
“A total of 2,780 nomination papers were collected to contest the electi</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 14:38:39 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>