<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 07:31:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Return of gold as safest asset</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/return-of-gold-as-safest-asset</link><description>Precious metals including gold and silver have turned pricier recently. This was the trend last year when central banks around the world added hundreds of tons of gold to their reserves, according to the World Gold Council trade association. Similarly, price of silver has also seen a significant ri</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 19:20:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Poor management of traffic system</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/poor-management-of-traffic-system</link><description>The interim government has apparently failed to bring about any perceptible change in the atrocious traffic congestion and road safety.  On the contrary, the city's traffic situation appears to have worsened as Dhaka has literally become a city of road blockades. Since the government assumed o</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 19:35:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Export on decline, deeper dip in Dec</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/export-on-decline-deeper-dip-in-dec</link><description>Bangladesh's merchandise exports have been on the decline for five consecutive months to December when the dip was the deepest at 14.25 per cent year on year in terms of earning.
The sharp decline in December 2025, by official count, also put the overall export growth in negative territory during</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 02:15:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt reverses cut in savings returns</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/govt-reverses-cut-in-savings-returns</link><description>The government has backtracked on a decision taken last week to reduce returns on savings instruments, following criticism from various quarters.
In a notification issued on Sunday, the Internal Resources Division (IRD) under the Ministry of Finance said the existing profit rates on government sav</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 02:30:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Experts warn of risks to economic growth despite stabilisation gains</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/experts-warn-of-risks-to-economic-growth-despite-stabilisation-gains</link><description>Experts warned on Sunday that while Bangladesh has achieved some level of macroeconomic stabilisation, the economy remains vulnerable to being trapped in a sub-optimal low-growth equilibrium due to weak investment, high interest rates, inflation and unemployment.
They suggested converting short-te</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 04:21:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NEIR rollout triggers protests; govt firmly rules out suspension</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/neir-rollout-triggers-protests-govt-firmly-rules-out-suspension</link><description>Bangladesh's newly launched National Equipment Identity Register (NEIR) system has sparked widespread protests by mobile phone traders, leading to clashes on the streets of Dhaka.
While traders have demanded the withdrawal or postponement of the system, the government has firmly ruled out shutting</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 04:36:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cuba says 32 of its officers were killed in US action in Venezuela</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/cuba-says-32-of-its-officers-were-killed-in-us-action-in-venezuela</link><description>An American military operation in Venezuela killed 32 Cuban officers over the weekend, the Cuban government said Sunday in the first official acknowledgement of the deaths.
The Cuban military and police officers were on a mission the Caribbean country’s military was carrying out at the reque</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 04:51:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Risk-free appeal lifts T-bond trading in secondary market</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/risk-free-appeal-lifts-t-bond-trading-in-secondary-market</link><description>Secondary market trading in Treasury bonds surged 53 per cent year-on-year to Tk 1.95 billion in 2025, driven by falling yields and investors' preference for risk-free assets.
Bond prices are inversely related to interest rates. As a result, sellers booked capital gains, while buyers parked funds</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 05:06:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Parts of Bangladesh feel tremor as 5.4 quake strikes Assam</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/parts-of-bangladesh-feel-tremor-as-54-quake-strikes-assam</link><description>An earthquake measuring 5.4 on the Richter scale struck India’s Assam early Monday, with tremors felt across Bangladesh and five other countries.
According to the United States Geological Survey (USGS), the earthquake occurred at 4:47 am Bangladesh time.
The epicentre was located 10 kilomet</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 05:21:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khaleda Zia’s passing: Business leaders pay condolence visit to Tarique Rahman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/khaleda-zias-passing-business-leaders-pay-condolence-visit-to-tarique-rahman</link><description>A delegation of leading manufacturers and business leaders has paid a condolence visit to BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman to express sympathy over the death of former prime minister Begum Khaleda Zia, while also holding an extended discussion on key economic challenges facing the country.
The d</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 05:36:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Appeal proceeding on nomination papers begins</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/appeal-proceeding-on-nomination-papers-begins-today</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) began appeal proceedings on Monday over the acceptance and rejection of nomination papers for the 13th Jatiya Sangsad election.
According to a notification issued on Sunday night, 1,842 nomination papers were found valid while 723 were rejected across 300 parliamentary</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 06:27:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump warns of higher tariffs on India over Russian oil purchases</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-warns-of-higher-tariffs-on-india-over-russian-oil-purchases</link><description>The United States could raise tariffs on India if New Delhi doesn't meet Washington's demand to curb purchases of Russian oil, President Donald Trump told reporters aboard Air Force One.
"Modi is a good guy. He knew I was not happy, and it was important to make me happy," Trump said on Sunday.
"T</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 06:42:38 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>