<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 18:31:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Syrian forces advance deeper into the US‑backed, Kurdish‑controlled northeast</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/syrian-forces-advance-deeper-into-the-usbacked-kurdishcontrolled-northeast</link><description>Syrian government troops are pushing towards Raqqa and Hasakah in the northeast of the country, the last strongholds of the US-backed autonomous Kurdish-led administration, government officials and security sources said on Sunday.
They had earlier taken control of the Deir al-Zor’s main oil</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 14:51:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ashanur Rahman wins The International Creative Arts Award 2025</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ashanur-rahman-wins-the-international-creative-arts-award-2025</link><description>Novelist and essayist Md. Ashanur Rahman has been awarded The International Creative Arts Award 2025 by the International Creative Arts, Language &amp; Development Research Centre of the University of Dhaka for his outstanding contribution to literature and its role in “Enriching Minds and Inspir</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 15:06:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BRAC Bank accelerates loan recovery through real-time digital litigation tools</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/brac-bank-accelerates-loan-recovery-through-real-time-digital-litigation-tools</link><description>BRAC Bank has strengthened its loan recovery drive by equipping frontline officials with an advanced digital tab integrated with a mobile-enabled Litigation Management System (LMS), enabling real-time access to lawsuit information at the field level.
According to a press release, the initiative is</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 15:21:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>100 pc textbook print of Ebtedayee completed, 99pc in secondary level</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/100-pc-textbook-print-of-ebtedayee-completed-99pc-in-secondary-level</link><description>Printing and distribution of free new textbooks at all levels in the 2026 academic year is almost completed.
Chairman of National Curriculum and Textbook Board (NCTB) Mahbubul Hoque Patwary told BSS on Sunday.
He said overall progress of textbook printing for secondary level (Class VI-IX) and Ebt</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 15:36:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Libya’s security authorities free more than 200 migrants from ‘secret prison’, two security sources say</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/africa/libyas-security-authorities-free-more-than-200-migrants-from-secret-prison-two-security-sources-say</link><description>Libya’s security authorities have freed more than 200 migrants from what they described as a secret prison in the town of Kufra in the southeast of the country after they were held captive in inhuman conditions, two security sources from the city told Reuters on Sunday.
The security sources,</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 15:51:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rooppur targets fuel loading by February</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rooppur-nuclear-plant-aims-to-complete-fuel-loading-by-february-end</link><description>The first unit of Rooppur Nuclear Power Plant in Pabna’s Ishwardi is targeting completion of fuel loading by the end of February.
Project officers told Salehuddin Ahmed, science and technology and finance advisor, of the timeline, according to a media statement from the Chief Advisor’s</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 16:06:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Motorcyclist sticks envelope to Tarique Rahman’s car and speeds off</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/motorcyclist-sticks-envelope-to-tarique-rahmans-car-and-speeds-off</link><description>A motorcyclist has ridden into BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman’s convoy and swiftly affixed a white envelope to his moving bulletproof car with tape before speeding away.
Tarique was inside the vehicle at the time, accompanied by his personal security detail, police said.
The incident occurred</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 16:52:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Government to campaign for ‘Yes’ vote in referendum across classrooms</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/government-to-campaign-for-yes-vote-in-referendum-across-classrooms</link><description>A nationwide campaign has been planned across all schools, colleges, universities, and madrasas to encourage students to vote ‘Yes’ in the referendum.
As part of the campaign, leaflets and booklets titled “Yes for Change” will be distributed among students.
Documentary fil</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 17:07:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chief prosecutor, CPB's Prince clash over ‘mob’ label for July Uprising</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/chief-prosecutor-tajul-cautions-over-mob-label-for-july-uprising-cpbs-ruhin-prince-calls-remarks-a-threat</link><description>Chief Prosecutor Mohammad Tajul Islam has warned against using the word “mob” to describe the July Uprising, saying it risks questioning the legitimacy of the movement.
Speaking at a policy dialogue on “Judicial Independence and Rule of Law” organised by the Centre for Gove</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 17:23:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP alleges ‘voter transfer’ to Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bnp-asks-ec-for-data-on-transferred-voters-raises-postal-ballot-concerns</link><description>BNP has alleged that “a political party” is bringing in voters from outside areas to Dhaka in an attempt to secure victories for its candidates.
In a meeting with Chief Election Commissioner AMM Nasir Uddin at the Election Commission headquarters in Agargaon on Sunday, the party demand</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 17:38:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>35 Bangladeshi workers sent back from Russia within six months of migration</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/35-bangladeshi-workers-sent-back-from-russia-within-six-months-of-migration</link><description>Within six months of migration, 35 Bangladeshi workers have been sent back from Russia.
A media statement issued by BRAC, citing the workers, said they were sacked without any valid reason.
The workers alleged that 120 people who migrated from Bangladesh in July were dismissed. They alleged that</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 17:53:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCP weighs election boycott over ‘one-sided’ EC decisions: Asif Mahmud</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ncp-reconsiders-election-participation-over-one-sided-ec-decisions-asif-mahmud</link><description>National Citizen Party (NCP) reconsiders whether it should participate in the upcoming national election, citing what it described as one-sided decisions by the Election Commission (EC), party spokesperson Asif Mahmud Shojib Bhuiyan said on Sunday.
Speaking at an emergency press conference at the</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 18:08:29 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>