<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 19:18:59 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Prison sentence during AL tenure responsible for Khaleda’s illness: Fakhrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/prison-sentence-during-al-tenure-responsible-for-khaledas-illness-fakhrul</link><description>BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir has alleged that party chief Khaleda Zia’s long-running health complications began during her two-year imprisonment under the Awami League government.
He described it as the result of “criminal negligence” and a lack of proper med</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 15:54:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Officers attacked for seizing falsely declared goods: NBR</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/officers-attacked-for-seizing-falsely-declared-goods-nbr</link><description>The National Board of Revenue (NBR) believes a group angered by recent measures to prevent the release of falsely declared goods may have been behind the attack on two customs officers in Chattogram.
In a statement issued on Friday, the NBR said it appeared that “officers have come under att</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 16:15:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP supporters block bridge over Munshiganj-3 ticket</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bnp-supporters-block-bridge-over-munshiganj-3-ticket</link><description>Supporters of Mahiuddin Ahmed, member-secretary of the Munshiganj district BNP, blocked the Mukterpur Bridge for an hour and a half on Friday, demanding a change in the party’s nomination for the Munshiganj-3 (Sadar–Ghazaria) constituency.
The BNP has nominated Kamruzzaman Ratan, the p</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 16:30:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>8 injured in BNP factional clashes over Munshiganj-3 nomination</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/8-injured-in-bnp-factional-clashes-over-munshiganj-3-nomination</link><description>At least eight people, including a woman, were injured in clashes between two factions of the BNP in Gazaria on Friday evening over the party’s nomination for the Munshiganj-3 constituency. Several vehicles and a private office were vandalised during the violence, prompting authorities to dep</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 16:45:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The digital manufacture of dreams</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/the-digital-manufacture-of-dreams</link><description>Across the developing world, migration has long been a pathway to economic mobility, a strategy for families seeking stability or upward movement. But in recent years, a new force has reshaped how young people think about leaving home. Social media platforms such as TikTok, YouTube and Facebook are</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 17:00:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Lingering curse of autocracy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/lingering-curse-of-autocracy</link><description>Three and a half decades ago, people of Bangladesh ousted the country's first autocratic regime through a mass uprising that reached its climax during the last three months of 1990. The united stance of all the students' organisations, keeping aside their political rivalry for the time being, on Oc</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 16:45:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fake note and the honest man's loss</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/fake-note-and-the-honest-mans-loss</link><description>Counterfeiting is a crime that has existed for millennia, but in contemporary Bangladesh it has evolved into one of the most sophisticated forms of financial deception. Detecting the newest generation of fake notes has become extraordinarily difficult, even bordering on impossible for the untrained</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 17:00:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Managing farm productivity risks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/managing-farm-productivity-risks</link><description>With close to 9.0 million hectares of available cultivable land, which too is shrinking by around 2,500 hectares annually, thanks mainly to urbanisation, feeding some 175 million mouths is a challenge of miraculous proportions. But the farming community of the country has been successfully meeting</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 17:15:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC urges caution against creating confusion over election schedule, voting date</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-urges-caution-against-creating-confusion-over-election-schedule-voting-date</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has urged all concerned not to spread confusion regarding the announcement of the election schedule and polling date for the upcoming national election.
EC Senior Secretary Akhtar Ahmed told the media on Friday evening that no decision has yet been taken on the schedul</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 17:30:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khaleda Zia’s condition unchanged, Zubaida back at hospital</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/khaleda-zias-condition-unchanged-zubaida-back-at-hospital</link><description>BNP Chairperson Khaleda Zia’s health remains unchanged, according to doctors.
Her daughter-in-law Zubaida Rahman again visited her at Evercare Hospital in Dhaka on Friday night after meeting her mother.
BNP Media Cell member Atikur Rahman Rumon said, “[She] visited her mother in Dhanm</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 17:45:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Factor Khaleda’s illness into polls schedule: NCP to EC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ncp-again-pushes-ec-to-factor-khaledas-illness-into-election-timeline</link><description>The National Citizen Party (NCP) has renewed calls for the Election Commission to factor in the critical illness of BNP chief Khaleda Zia when finalising the schedule for the general election slated for February.
At a policy discussion on Friday titled “The Future of Investment in Bangladesh</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 18:00:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Regular liquidity feeding to banks stops, call money market vibrant</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/regular-liquidity-feeding-to-banks-stops-call-money-market-vibrant</link><description>Bangladesh Bank finally discards a major regular liquidity-feeding instrument for primary dealer (PD) banks, eight months after the decision made to tidy the money market under a reform recipe.



As part of the central bank's decision to bring vibrancy in the interbank spot market through le</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 19:18:59 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>