<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 17:21:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>BDR mutiny case: 35 freed on bail from Kashimpur Jail</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bdr-mutiny-case-35-freed-on-bail-from-kashimpur-jail</link><description>A total of 35 former Bangladesh Rifles (BDR) personnel were released on bail from Kashimpur Jail in Gazipur on Monday evening in connection with the BDR mutiny case.
Relatives of the accused received them at the main gate of the prison.
Earlier, on Thursday, 53 others had been granted bail by a s</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 15:25:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Largest-ever Pakistan Education Expo held in Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/largest-ever-pakistan-education-expo-held-in-dhaka</link><description>FE REPORT
The Pakistan High Commission in Dhaka, in collaboration with the Higher Education Commission (HEC) of Pakistan, organised the largest-ever Pakistan Education Expo in Dhaka on Monday, bringing together representatives from over 15 top-ranked Pakistani universities.
The Expo is part of th</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 13:55:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump weighing advanced Nvidia chip sales to China, Bloomberg News reports</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-weighing-advanced-nvidia-chip-sales-to-china-bloomberg-news-reports</link><description>US President Donald Trump is weighing whether to allow Nvidia to sell advanced artificial intelligence chips to China, Commerce Secretary Howard Lutnick said in an interview to Bloomberg News on Monday.
The president is consulting “lots of different advisors” in deciding on the potenti</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 14:10:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Islami Bank holds board meeting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/islami-bank-holds-board-meeting-111111</link><description>A meeting of the board of directors of Islami Bank Bangladesh PLC was held on November 24, 2025 Monday at Islami Bank Tower, according to a press release.
Professor Dr. M. Zubaidur Rahman, chairman of the bank, presided over the meeting.Mohammad Khurshid Wahab, chairman of the executive committee,</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 14:25:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IFIC Bank holds open credit disbursement program for marginal clients in Munshiganj</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ific-bank-holds-open-credit-disbursement-program-for-marginal-clients-in-munshiganj</link><description>Under the refinancing initiative of Bangladesh Bank, an open credit disbursement program was organized as part of the Tk. 7.50 billion revolving Refinancing Scheme designed for marginal and landless farmers, low-income professionals, school banking account holders and small businessmen maintaining</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 14:40:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Community Bank signs business partnership with Hotel Agrabad</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/community-bank-signs-business-partnership-with-hotel-agrabad</link><description>Community Bank Bangladesh PLC and Hotel Agrabad signed agreements regarding Businesses. The agreement was signed recently at Hotel Agrabad Conference Room in Chattogram.
The signing ceremony was graced by Kimiwa Saddat, Managing Director (Current Charge) of Community Bank, according to a press rel</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 14:55:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>City Bank launches first-ever credit card under Mastercard network</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/city-bank-launches-first-ever-credit-card-under-mastercard-network</link><description>City Bank in partnership with Mastercard has launched its first-ever credit card under the Mastercard network—the City Bank Mastercard World Elite Credit Card—marking a new milestone in premium banking.
According to a press release, this exclusive card is tailored for the country&amp;rsquo</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 15:10:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BRAC Bank launches platinum multicurrency debit card under Mastercard network</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/brac-bank-launches-platinum-multicurrency-debit-card-under-mastercard-network</link><description>BRAC Bank has launched a new Platinum Multicurrency debit card on the Mastercard network, offering customers a convenient and secure way to manage both local and international transactions.
Officially unveiled on November 23, 2025, the new card combines flexibility, safety, and rewarding features</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 15:25:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Al-Arafah Islami Bank achieves MasterCard Excellence Award 2025</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/al-arafah-islami-bank-achieves-mastercard-excellence-award-2025</link><description>Al-Arafah Islami Bank PLC has been awarded the ‘MasterCard Excellence Award 2025’ for achieving excellence in MasterCard Debit Business (Domestic), according to a press release.
Bangladesh Bank Deputy Governor Md. Zakir Hossain Chowdhury handed over the award to the bank’s Managi</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 15:40:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Zaima’s ‘first speech’ at BNP meeting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tariques-daughter-zaima-delivers-first-speech-at-bnp-meeting</link><description>BNP’s Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman’s daughter Zaima Rahman has officially spoken “for the first time” at a party meeting.
She participated in a virtual meeting of leaders and activists living abroad on Sunday, a clip of which later went viral on social media.
The meeting</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 15:55:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The state of global economy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/the-state-of-global-economy</link><description>The world economy has been subjected to destiabilisation and uncertainty for quite some time. Factors contributing to this unforeseen situation are: (a) Lingering effects of supply chain disruptions caused by the 2020 Covid pandemic; (b) the Russia-Ukraine war adding to the already frayed supply ch</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 16:10:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>An engine hotter than the sun</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/an-engine-hotter-than-the-sun</link><description>Scientists have made an engine that is hotter than the sun's core. But how hot is the sun's core? The temperature of the sun's core is around 15 million degrees Celsius. Usually, the temperature of a typical star's (our sun is also a star) centre is between 10 to 20 million degrees Celsius. To have</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 16:25:58 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>