<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 13:24:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nation will never forgive if fascism returns for disunity: Salahuddin</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/nation-will-never-forgive-if-fascism-returns-for-disunity-salahuddin</link><description>BNP Standing Committee member Salahuddin Ahmed on Saturday warned that the nation will not forgive political parties if fascism returns to Bangladesh because of their divisions.
“If our disunity and divisions ever open the door for the return of fascism, the nation will never forgive us. We</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 10:30:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Left-wing Connolly set to win Irish presidency as opponents concede</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/left-wing-connolly-set-to-win-irish-presidency-as-opponents-concede</link><description>Catherine Connolly, a veteran lawmaker on the far-left of the Irish political spectrum, was set to be elected the country's next president on Saturday as members of the governing parties conceded defeat.
Early tallies of votes after counting began at 0800 GMT showed a wide lead for Connolly, 68, a</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 10:45:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tens of thousands brave rain at east Asia's largest Pride march in Taiwan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/living/tens-of-thousands-brave-rain-at-east-asias-largest-pride-march-in-taiwan</link><description>Almost 150,000 people braved blustery rain in a boisterous and colourful celebration of LGBTQ+ equality in Taiwan on Saturday at east Asia's largest Pride march, thronging the streets of the capital city Taipei.
Taiwan legalised same-sex marriage in 2019 in a first for Asia and is a bastion of tol</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 11:00:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A ghost in the Oval Office: How Reagan looms over Trump presidency</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/a-ghost-in-the-oval-office-how-reagan-looms-over-trump-presidency</link><description>Since February, a large, smiling portrait of Ronald Reagan has loomed over the Oval Office, watching Donald Trump each time he settles behind the Resolute Desk long used by US presidents.
The painting - provided by the Ronald Reagan Presidential Foundation &amp; Institute and prominently installed by</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 11:01:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Syria signs landing deal for first international submarine cable with Medusa</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/syria-signs-landing-deal-for-first-international-submarine-cable-with-medusa-state-run-tv-reports</link><description>Syria's telecommunications ministry has signed an agreement for the landing of the first international submarine cable to the country with Barcelona-based Medusa Submarine Cable System, state-run Ikhbariya TV reported on Saturday.
The submarine cable system is intended to connect 12 countries acro</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 11:16:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prime Bank partners with JAMS Construction &amp; JAMS Development</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/prime-bank-partners-with-jams-construction-jams-development</link><description>Prime Bank PLC has entered into a strategic partnership with JAMS Construction &amp; JAMS Development Ltd, one of Bangladesh’s most reputed real estate developers, to offer exclusive discounts on flat purchases for its valued customers.
A formal signing ceremony marking this collaboration was re</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 11:31:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shariatpur woman killed for 70g of gold: RAB</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/shariatpur-woman-killed-for-70g-of-gold-rab</link><description>Rapid Action Battalion has said a woman in Shariatpur town was strangled to death for 6 tolas (around 70 grams) of gold ornaments and cash.
RAB said this on Saturday after arresting a suspect, Shahidul Islam Ripon Molla, 50, from Keraniganj, Dhaka, on Friday night -- three days after the murder.</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 12:16:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Eastern Bank signs agreement with CliniCall</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/eastern-bank-signs-agreement-with-clinicall</link><description>Eastern Bank has signed an Online Payment Gateway and ZIP agreement with CliniCall Ltd., a leading telemedicine platform in Bangladesh.
M. Khorshed Anowar, Deputy Managing Director and Head of Retail and SME Banking of EBL and Parvez Ahmad, Chief Operating Officer of Clinicall, signed the agreemen</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 12:31:23 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>