<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 10:21:32 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Indonesia's biggest Islamic group asks chief to resign over invitation to pro-Israeli speaker</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/indonesias-biggest-islamic-group-asks-chief-to-resign-over-invitation-to-pro-israeli-speaker</link><description>Indonesia's biggest Islamic organisation, Nahdlatul Ulama, has asked its chief to resign for inviting a US scholar known for his support of Israel during the Gaza war to an internal event in August, according to meeting minutes reviewed by Reuters.
The leadership of NU, which is also the world's b</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 06:44:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Over 200 Catholic students kidnapped in Nigeria</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/africa/over-200-catholic-students-kidnapped-in-nigeria</link><description>Gunmen in Nigeria kidnapped at least 227 students and teachers at a Catholic school in the northwest on Friday, the Christian Association of Nigeria (CAN) said, the latest in a spate of school attacks this week that has forced the government to shut 47 colleges.
Friday's incident in Niger state wa</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 06:59:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Income tax return deadline likely to be extended to December 31</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/income-tax-return-deadline-likely-to-be-extended-to-december-31</link><description>The government is likely to extend the deadline for submitting individual income tax returns until December 31, according to senior officials familiar with matter. The current deadline is set to expire on November 30.
Officials at the National Board of Revenue (NBR) said the proposal is under acti</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 07:14:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BBC board member Banerji resigns after Trump documentary edit</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/bbc-board-member-banerji-resigns-after-trump-documentary-edit</link><description>An independent director on the BBC's board, Shumeet Banerji, has quit on Friday in the wake of what the public broadcaster said was an incorrect edit of a speech by President Donald Trump and which has prompted the threat of a $5 billion lawsuit.
Banerji, who also serves on the board of Indian con</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 07:46:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Lilly reaches $1 trillion market value</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/lilly-reaches-1-trillion-market-value</link><description>Eli Lilly hit $1 trillion in market value on Friday, making it the first drugmaker to enter the exclusive club dominated by tech giants and underscoring its rise as a weight-loss powerhouse.
A more than 35 per cent rally in the company's stock this year has largely been driven by the explosive gro</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 08:01:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bhutanese PM pays homage to Liberation War martyrs in Savar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bhutanese-pm-pays-homage-to-liberation-war-martyrs-in-savar</link><description>Bhutanese Prime Minister Tshering Tobgay paid tribute to the Liberation War martyrs by placing a wreath at the National Memorial in Savar, on the outskirts of Dhaka, shortly after his arrival for a two-day state visit on Saturday.
After placing the wreath at the memorial’s altar, he stood in</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 08:16:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC Sanuallah hopes for ‘record number’ of foreign poll observers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ec-sanuallah-hopes-for-record-number-of-foreign-poll-observers</link><description>Election Commissioner Abul Fazal Md Sanaullah has expressed hope that a record number of international observers will oversee the upcoming parliamentary election, slated for February next year.
The election will mark the "re-commencement of the country's democratic journey", he said while speaking</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 08:18:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two siblings die from electrocution in Kishoreganj</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/two-siblings-die-from-electrocution-in-kishoreganj</link><description>Two siblings died from electrocution at Galachipa village in Hossainpur upazila of Kishoreganj district on Saturday.
The deceased were identified as Nurul Islam alias Nuru Khan, 60 and Shamsul Islam alias Fazlu Khan, 55—two sons of Abul Hossain Khan of the village, reports UNB.
Nahid Eva, U</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 08:33:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt prepares NEIR to block illegal mobile phones</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/govt-prepares-neir-to-block-illegal-mobile-phones</link><description>Amid rising concerns over the national security risks posed by cloned and tampered mobile devices, the government is preparing to launch the National Equipment Identity Register (NEIR), a central system designed to block the use of illegal phones.
Officials, however, say the initiative is facing r</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 08:48:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Women's Kabaddi World Cup: Bangladesh reach semifinal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/womens-kabaddi-world-cup-bangladesh-reach-semifinal</link><description>Bangladesh has reached the semifinal of the 2nd Women's World Cup, beating Thailand by 40-31 points held at Shaheed Suhrawardy Indoor Stadium at Mirpur.
The winners stretched the first period of play as they took a narrow 14-12 points lead at the breather. 
Bangladesh will now play the semif</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 09:03:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>China takes spat with Japan over Taiwan to UN</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/china-takes-spat-with-japan-over-taiwan-to-un-vows-to-defend-itself</link><description>China has taken its widening spat with Japan to the United Nations, accusing Tokyo of threatening "an armed intervention" over Taiwan and vowing to defend itself in its strongest language yet in the two-week-old dispute.
Japanese Prime Minister Sanae Takaichi committed "a grave violation of intern</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 09:18:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>July Revolution did not propose to overturn constitution: CJ</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/july-revolution-did-not-propose-to-overturn-constitution-cj</link><description>Chief Justice Syed Refaat Ahmed today (Saturday) said the July Revolution did not propose to overturn the constitution; rather, it sought to "purify our engagement with it" by reinstating transparency, accountability and responsiveness at the heart of public life.  Speaking at the Bay of</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 10:19:33 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>