<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 04:25:49 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>IMF sceptical about 35pc-higher revenue target, bank overhauls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/imf-sceptical-about-35pc-higher-revenue-target-bank-overhauls</link><description>International Monetary Fund creditworthiness-review mission appears unsatisfied with Bangladesh finance officials' explanation over ramped-up revenue target handed to the revenue board for the current fiscal year, and the means of mobilisation.



Finance Division sources said the visiting IMF</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 19:57:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Only 32.9pc of Bangladeshis fully food secure, BBS survey shows</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/only-329pc-of-bangladeshis-fully-food-secure-bbs-survey-shows</link><description>Only 32.9 per cent of Bangladesh's population is fully food secure in terms of daily intake, with millions facing vulnerability in their everyday nutrition, according to a new survey by the Bangladesh Bureau of Statistics (BBS).
The survey, titled "Food Security Situation and Coping Mechanism in B</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 01:34:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>'Fast transition to elected govt will restore investor trust'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/fast-transition-to-elected-govt-will-restore-investor-trust</link><description>Experts have underscored more major reforms to remove the existing hurdles and enable Bangladesh to tap the emerging business opportunities, calling for faster democratic transition to accelerate the system-recast process.
Speaking at a roundtable Monday in Dhaka, they also said reforms aligned wi</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 01:49:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Future of megaprojects funded by JICA remains clouded</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/future-of-megaprojects-funded-by-jica-remains-clouded</link><description>Six major infrastructure projects involving an investment worth nearly Tk 1.94 trillion--- 76 per cent of which is funded by the Japan International Cooperation Agency (JICA)--- are now encountering problems of varied nature.
Behind the glossy images of progress surrounding these projects lie disp</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 02:04:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh Bank allows taka-foreign currency swap for exporters</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladesh-bank-allows-taka-foreign-currency-swap-for-exporters</link><description>The Bangladesh Bank has allowed exporters to obtain Taka liquidity by swapping their foreign currency funds with commercial banks.
In a circular issued on Monday, it allowed the authorised dealer (AD) banks to enter into Taka-foreign currency swap arrangements with exporters against balances held</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 02:19:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh logs 19.13pc FDI growth in FY 2024-25</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladesh-logs-1913pc-fdi-growth-in-fy-2024-25</link><description>Bangladesh has logged 19.13 per cent growth in attracting foreign direct investment (FDI) in the last fiscal year 2024-25.
The country reported FDI worth $1686.24 million in the fiscal year (FY) 2024-25 which was $1415.46 million in the previous FY.
Bangladesh Investment Development Authority (BI</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 02:34:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>'Vibrant capital, bond markets vital to lessen pressure on banking sector'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/vibrant-capital-bond-markets-vital-to-lessen-pressure-on-banking-sector</link><description>Bangladesh urgently needs to frame a long-term financing policy guideline along with developing a vibrant bond market to lessen the mounting pressure on the country's reeling banking sector, speakers at a roundtable have said.
To ensure a sustainable financial market, they also called upon the aut</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 02:52:59 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>