<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 21:20:38 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Envoy stresses stronger trade, energy and tourism ties with Nepal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/envoy-stresses-stronger-trade-energy-and-tourism-ties-with-nepal</link><description>Bangladesh Ambassador to Nepal Md Shafiqur Rahman has called for deepening economic cooperation between Bangladesh and Nepal through enhanced trade, connectivity, and investment in joint ventures, particularly in the sectors of energy and tourism.
The envoy made the remarks this afternoon during a</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 16:12:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BGMEA briefs IMF on RMG risks, urges govt to prioritize FTAs to counter LDC graduation challenge</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bgmea-briefs-imf-on-rmg-risks-urges-govt-to-prioritize-ftas-to-counter-ldc-graduation-challenge</link><description>A delegation from the International Monetary Fund (IMF) met with the Bangladesh Garment Manufacturers and Exporters Association (BGMEA) on Wednesday to discuss the current state and future risks of the country's ready-made garment (RMG) sector, aiming to ensure macroeconomic stability.
The meeting</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 16:42:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BUBT Economics Department hosts workshop on report writing</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/bubt-economics-department-hosts-workshop-on-report-writing</link><description>The Department of Economics at Bangladesh University of Business and Technology (BUBT) has organised a workshop on report writing and project work.
They organised the workshop, titled 'Report Writing and Project Work – A Guide for Beginners', to strengthen the students’ research and ac</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 17:12:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Worker dies after falling from under-construction building in Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/worker-dies-after-falling-from-under-construction-building-in-dhaka</link><description>A construction worker was killed after falling from the third floor of an under-construction building in the Borotech area of the city's Badda area on Wednesday.
The deceased, identified as Al Amin, 26, was a mason, reports BSS.
According to the victim's elder brother, Nazrul Islam, the family ha</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 17:42:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nachol UNO made OSD</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nachol-uno-made-osd</link><description>The government has made Upazila Nirbahi Officer (UNO) Md Kamal Hossain of Nachol, Chapainawabganj an Officer on Special Duty (OSD) for allegedly using fake information to get a government job under the freedom fighter quota.
The Ministry of Public Administration issued a notification on Wednesday</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 17:44:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Inflation &amp; wage dynamics in BD</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/inflation-wage-dynamics-in-bd</link><description>Bangladesh Bank, as a forward-looking central bank, is dedicated to maintaining price stability and a robust financial system by promoting inclusive and broad-based economic growth, job creation, and poverty reduction. A sound comprehension of the fundamental elements that influence price level mov</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 17:59:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Election campaigning must go greenElection campaigning must go green</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/election-campaigning-must-go-greenelection-campaigning-must-go-green</link><description>Candidates from different political parties for the 13th parliamentary elections have already started trying to make their presence felt, even before announcement of election schedules by the Election Commission. They are quite eager to reach the voters, and their supporters have already started di</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 18:14:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shareholders return empty-handed with NAV nullified</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/shareholders-return-empty-handed-with-nav-nullified</link><description>Shareholders return empty-handed with net asset value (NAV) of their shares turning zero as the merger of five liquidity-crisis-ridden commercial banks into a big-dream Islamic bank begins.



The central bank Wednesday officially started the merger process through dissolving boards of the bank</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 18:29:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Food security remains elusive</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/food-security-remains-elusive</link><description>No nation can be proud if only 32.9 per cent of its population have full food security. Of the rest, 22.75 face extreme food insecurity and 44.57 per cent people enjoy marginal food security which otherwise translates into vulnerability of food availability. Their fragile food availability can dete</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 18:44:39 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>