<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 11:20:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Tk 10b loan granted to ICB to revitalise stock market</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/tk-10b-loan-granted-to-icb-to-revitalise-stock-market</link><description>The government has provided a loan of Tk 10 billion to the Investment Corporation of Bangladesh (ICB), a state-owned investment institution, to overcome its liquidity crisis and increase its investment capacity in the stock market.
ICB Chairman Abu Ahmed told bdnews24.com on Wednesday that the loa</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 09:12:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Backtracking on Airbus purchases will impact Bangladesh’s trade relations with Europe’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/backtracking-on-airbus-purchases-will-impact-bangladeshs-trade-relations-with-europe-says-german-ambassador</link><description>Germany’s Ambassador to Bangladesh Rüdiger Lotz has warned that Dhaka’s trade relations with Europe could be strained if it rows back on its commitment to purchase aircraft from Airbus.
He also hinted that the Airbus decision could impact the EU’s decision on allowing Bangla</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 09:27:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rizvi slams Hasina over reported gold recovery from bank vaults</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/rizvi-slams-hasina-over-reported-gold-recovery-from-bank-vaults</link><description>BNP Senior Joint Secretary General Ruhul Kabir Rizvi on Wednesday criticised deposed Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina, saying the reported recovery of a large quantity of gold ornaments from bank vaults registered under her name exposed how big a ‘thief’ she was.
“I saw in the newspa</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 09:42:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Wahiduddin for coordinated efforts for livestock sector growth</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/wahiduddin-for-coordinated-efforts-for-livestock-sector-growth</link><description>Planning Adviser Wahiduddin Mahmud today (Wednesday) underscored the need for technical support and coordinated initiatives to accelerate the development of the country’s livestock sector.
Speaking at the opening of the National Livestock Week 2025 as the chief guest, he said that researcher</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 09:57:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BGMEA expresses deep shock over fire at Korail slum</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bgmea-expresses-deep-shock-over-fire-at-korail-slum</link><description>The Bangladesh Garment Manufacturers and Exporters Association (BGMEA) has expressed deep shock over the fire incident at the Korail slum in the capital, which destroyed numerous homes and left many families homeless.
The BGMEA conveyed heartfelt sympathy to all the affected families and wished a</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 10:12:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ICT prosecutors file contempt of court plea against BNP leader Fazlur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ict-prosecutors-file-contempt-of-court-plea-against-bnp-leader-fazlur</link><description>Prosecutors at the International Crimes Tribunal (ICT) have filed a contempt of court petition against senior lawyer and BNP Chairperson’s Advisor Fazlur Rahman, accusing him of making disparaging remarks about the tribunal during a television talk show.
A hearing on the petition was held on</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 09:44:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>31 police officers promoted to DIG</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-promotes-31-police-officers-to-dig-in-major-pre-election-reshuffle</link><description>The government has promoted 31 police officers to the rank of deputy inspector general (DIG) as part of a major shake-up of the force ahead of the national election.
The Ministry of Home Affairs made the announcement in a statement on Wednesday.
The decision comes on the same day the government r</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 09:59:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Deer poacher held with 32 kgs of deer venison, trap in Bagerhat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/deer-poacher-held-with-32-kgs-of-deer-venison-trap-in-bagerhat</link><description>Members of Coast Guard in a drive arrested a deer poacher along with two deer heads, 32 kgs of venison, eight deer legs and 2000 metres of deer-hunting traps from a house at Kanainagar in Mongla upazila of Bagerhat district early Wednesday.
The arrestee was identified as Akter Biswas, 40, a member</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 10:14:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka expects answer from Delhi on Hasina’s extradition: Foreign Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dhaka-expects-answer-from-delhi-on-hasinas-extradition-foreign-adviser</link><description>Foreign Affairs Adviser Md Touhid Hossain on Wednesday said Bangladesh expects an answer from India on its latest request for extradition of convicted former Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina.
“I do not expect that they will answer within a week of Dhaka’s request but we expect we will get</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 10:29:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India protests China’s detention of citizen at Shanghai airport</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/india-protests-chinas-detention-of-citizen-at-shanghai-airport</link><description>India on Tuesday protested to China over what it described as the “arbitrary detention” of an Indian citizen at Shanghai airport, after Chinese authorities reportedly refused to recognize her passport.
The woman, Pem Wang Thongdok from the northeastern state of Arunachal Pradesh, was s</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 10:44:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two more Baul artistes injured in attack in Thakurgaon</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/two-more-baul-artistes-injured-in-attack-in-thakurgaon</link><description>At least two Baul artistes were injured in an attack ahead of a protest against the repression of Bauls and the arrest of Baul artiste Abul Sarkar.
The incident took place on Wednesday afternoon on the premises of the Thakurgaon court, said Thakurgaon Sadar Police chief Sarwar Alam Khan.
Sarwar s</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 10:59:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Police block teachers’ march towards Jamuna</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/police-block-teachers-march-towards-jamuna-demanding-mpo-inclusion</link><description>Police have blocked a teachers’ march towards the State Guest House Jamuna, the official residence of the chief advisor, demanding the inclusion of all recognised non-MPO educational institutions under the government’s monthly payment scheme.
The teachers, who have been holding a sit-i</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 11:14:38 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>