<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 07:21:41 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Former principal secretary Kamal Uddin Siddiqui dies</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/former-principal-secretary-kamal-uddin-siddiqui-dies</link><description>Kamal Uddin Siddiqui, former principal secretary to former prime minister Khaleda Zia, has died.
He passed away at his residence in Dhaka’s Gulshan early on Monday morning, the government said in a statement.
The funeral prayers will be held at Gulshan Azad Mosque after Asr prayers, reports</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 04:54:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP to finalise nomination list Monday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-to-finalise-nomination-list-monday</link><description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman has called a meeting of the party’s Standing Committee at noon on Monday at the BNP Chairperson’s office in Gulshan.
The meeting will begin at 12:30 pm, followed by a press conference at 3:00 pm at the same venue, said BNP media cell member Sayrul Kab</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 05:09:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rubaba Dowla joins BCB board as director</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/cricket/rubaba-dowla-joins-bcb-board-as-director</link><description>Rubaba Dowla, corporate leader and sports organiser, has officially been named a director of the Bangladesh Cricket Board (BCB), weeks after her selection was first approved following the board elections last month.
The National Sports Council (NSC) on Monday issued a letter confirming her as one</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 05:24:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>20 killed after bus collides with truck in southern India</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/20-killed-after-bus-collides-with-truck-in-southern-india</link><description>A truck loaded with concrete stone chips rammed into a passenger bus in southern India early Monday, killing at least 20 people and injuring about two dozens, local authorities said.
The state-run transport bus was carrying around 70 passengers en route to Hyderabad city in southern Telangana stat</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 05:39:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rain, thundershowers likely in three divisions</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rain-thundershowers-likely-in-three-divisions-14545</link><description>The Bangladesh Meteorological Department (BMD) forecast rain or thundershowers is likely to occur at a few places over Chattogram division and at one or two places over Barishal and Sylhet divisions, beginning at 9:00 am today (Monday).
"Rain or thundershowers are likely to occur at a few places o</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 05:54:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two killed in Tangail road crash</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/two-killed-in-tangail-road-crash-1545</link><description>Two people were killed when a truck hit a CNG-run auto-rickshaw at the Gharinda underpass area on the Dhaka–Tangail highway in Tangail district on Monday. 
The deceased were identified as CNG driver Saheb Ali, 45, son of Kashem Uddin of Akua area and passenger Abdul Alim, 60, son of Nur</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 06:24:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DCCI chief emphasises predictable governance, energy security for sustainable growth</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/dcci-chief-stresses-predictability-energy-security-and-sectoral-support-for-sustainable-growth</link><description>Dhaka Chamber of Commerce and Industry (DCCI) President Taskeen Ahmed on Monday said that discussions on business reforms cannot reach a meaningful conclusion until Bangladesh has a predictable, mandate-backed government. Speaking at a roundtable organised by The Financial Express, he highlighted t</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 06:39:47 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>