<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 10:29:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Postal ballots of 420,000 expatriates reach Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/postal-ballots-of-420000-expatriates-reach-bangladesh</link><description>More than 420,000 postal ballots cast by expatriate Bangladeshis have arrived in the country ahead of next week’s parliamentary election.
Salim Ahmad Khan, team leader of the Election Commission’s OCV-SDI project, said 422,960 ballots had been received by 10:15 am on Saturday.
Electio</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 07:16:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh PM front-runner rejects unity govt offer, says his party set to win: Reuters</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-pm-front-runner-rejects-unity-govt-offer-says-his-party-set-to-win-reuters</link><description>Bangladesh’s leading prime ministerial contender, Tarique Rahman, on Friday rejected a proposal from his main rival for a unity government after elections next week, saying his party was confident of winning on its own.
Rahman, 60, who heads the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP), returned h</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 07:31:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India, US release framework for interim trade agreement</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/india-us-release-framework-for-interim-trade-agreement</link><description>India and the United States released a framework for an interim trade agreement to lower tariffs on Indian goods, which Indian opposition accused of favouring Washington.
The joint statement, released Friday, came after US President Donald Trump announced his plan last week to reduce import tariff</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 07:46:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>SAARC journalists meet at Delhi University</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/saarc-journalists-meet-at-delhi-university-1</link><description>SAARC Journalists Forum (SJF) on Friday organised an international conference and tree plantation programme at the historic Gandhi Bhawan, located in the North Campus of Delhi University, in India.
Journalist leaders from various SAARC countries, university teachers, and a large number of students</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 08:01:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jailed Awami League leader Ramesh Chandra Sen dies in custody</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jailed-awami-league-leader-ramesh-chandra-sen-dies-in-custody</link><description>Former water resources minister and senior Awami League leader Ramesh Chandra Sen has died while in jail.
The 85-year-old passed away at 9:30am on Saturday, said Taufiq Hasan, a doctor at the emergency department of Dinajpur Medical College Hospital.</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 08:16:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Teknaf child injured by Myanmar gunfire dies</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/teknaf-child-injured-by-myanmar-gunfire-dies</link><description>A child from Teknaf who was seriously injured by gunfire originating from Myanmar has died under hospital care.
Huzaifa Sultana Afnan suffered a critical head injury in the incident in Whykong Union on Jan 11. She died around 9:50 am on Saturday while receiving treatment at the National Institute</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 08:31:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump refuses to apologise for video depicting Obamas as apes</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-refuses-to-apologise-for-video-depicting-obamas-as-apes</link><description>US President Donald Trump condemned but did not apologise for a video on his social media account depicting Democratic former President Barack Obama and first lady Michelle Obama as apes, a post that triggered swift, bipartisan criticism for dehumanising people of African descent.
The White House</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 08:17:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt expects responsible journalism: Shafiqul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-expects-responsible-journalism-shafiqul</link><description>Expressing deep concern over misleading reports carried out by different media outlets on Friday centering clashes between police and Inquilab Moncho, demanding justice for Shaheed Sharif Osman Hadi, Chief Adviser's Press Secretary Shafiqul Alam, Saturday said that the government expected responsib</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 08:32:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP alleges plot to manipulate national election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-alleges-plot-to-manipulate-national-election</link><description>BNP Central Election Steering Committee Spokesperson Mahdi Amin on Saturday alleged that a political party is systematically preparing for “election engineering” to influence the national election and its results.
“Some recent incidents indicate a well-planned attempt to manipula</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 08:47:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Port workers announce fresh strike at Chattogram Port from Sunday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/port-workers-announce-fresh-strike-at-chattogram-port-from-sunday</link><description>Port workers have announced a fresh indefinite work stoppage at Chattogram Port from Sunday, protesting the proposed leasing of the New Mooring Container Terminal (NCT) to foreign operator DP World and pressing four other demands.
Humayun Kabir, coordinator of Chattogram Port Protection Movement C</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 09:02:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique pledges swift reopening of Thakurgaon airport if elected</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-pledges-swift-reopening-of-thakurgaon-airport-if-elected</link><description>Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) chief Tarique Rahman has promised to make Thakurgaon Airport operational swiftly if his party forms the next government.
Speaking at an election rally on Saturday, Tarique said work on the airport was already at an advanced stage and could be completed soon after</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 09:17:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Afghanistan among world's dangerous places for mothers, newborns: UN</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/afghanistan-among-worlds-dangerous-places-for-mothers-newborns-un</link><description>Afghanistan remains one of the most perilous countries in the world for mothers and newborns due to extremely high mortality rates and persistent funding constraints, the United Nations Population Fund (UNFPA) said, according to local media reports on Saturday.
The UNFPA reported that the country</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 09:32:51 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>