<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 01:48:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Hamas to hand over another body after Israel says remains were not of missing hostage</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/hamas-to-hand-over-another-body-after-israel-says-remains-were-not-of-missing-hostage</link><description>Hamas said it would hand over to Israel on Tuesday the body of a missing hostage found in a tunnel in Gaza, after Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu accused the militant group of violating the ceasefire in the enclave by turning over the wrong remains.
Netanyahu earlier on Tuesday said tests had sh</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 16:20:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EU to send major observation team for Bangladesh election, ambassador says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/eu-to-send-major-observation-team-for-bangladesh-election-ambassador-says</link><description>The European Union will deploy a large team of observers to monitor Bangladesh’s general elections in February, Ambassador Michael Miller told Chief Advisor Muhammad Yunus.
He confirmed the development at the State Guest House Jamuna on Tuesday, a statement from the Chief Advisor’s Off</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 16:35:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump's 'hot truck' becomes symbol of Japan trade talks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trumps-hot-truck-becomes-symbol-of-japan-trade-talks</link><description>Long associated with American ruggedness, pickup trucks such as Ford's top-selling F-150 have now become a symbol of international trade talks, showing how far countries such as Japan will go to win over US President Donald Trump.
When Trump met Japan's new prime minister and first female premier,</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 16:50:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gold price falls below Tk 200 thousand per bhori after fourth consecutive cut</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/gold-price-falls-below-tk-200-thousand-per-bhori-after-fourth-consecutive-cut</link><description>The price of gold in Bangladesh has fallen below Tk 200 thousand per bhori (11.664 grams) after the Bangladesh Jewellers Association (BAJUS) announced its fourth consecutive price reduction.
According to a BAJUS press release issued on Tuesday night, the price of 22-carat gold has been reduced by</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 17:20:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Depositors' money - a clarion call for full protection</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/depositors-money-a-clarion-call-for-full-protection</link><description>Ever-increasing events of bank failures, bankruptcies and distresses have been occurring home and abroad. In many situations, they are being   brought   under   resolution by the central regulatory body. Despite   resolution steps, the worst   victims   are the deposit</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 17:11:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Reviewing FDI policies for a stronger apparel value chain</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/reviewing-fdi-policies-for-a-stronger-apparel-value-chain</link><description>The question of whether Foreign Direct Investment (FDI) in Bangladesh's readymade garment (RMG) sector is ultimately beneficial remains unresolved. Industry stakeholders and policymakers have yet to provide a definitive stance. There are foreign collaborations, but not in the form of large-scale FD</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 17:26:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Implementing new pay scale for public servants</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/implementing-new-pay-scale-for-public-servants</link><description>There is no question that workers' pay hike or demand for it is part of the job culture. But such a hike is always based on the increase in the earnings of the organisation concerned. In the case of the government, it is from the revenue earnings that demands for such pay raises are met. From that</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 17:41:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>42 per cent of paint samples in Bangladesh contain ‘high lead levels’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/42-per-cent-of-paint-samples-in-bangladesh-contain-high-lead-levels</link><description>A recent study has found lead concentrations as high as 190,000ppm in decorative paints sold in Bangladesh, far exceeding the legal limit of 90ppm set for safe use.
The research, conducted by the Environment and Social Development Organization (ESDO) with support from the Lead Exposure Elimination</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 17:56:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Israel's Netanyahu orders 'powerful attacks' in Gaza</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/israels-netanyahu-orders-powerful-attacks-in-gaza</link><description>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said on Tuesday he had ordered the military to "carry out powerful attacks" in Gaza after accusing the militant group Hamas of violating a ceasefire agreement in the Palestinian territory.
A statement by Netanyahu's office did not specify the reason for th</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 18:11:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>July charter ratification by referendum during or before general election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/july-charter-ratification-by-referendum-during-or-before-general-election</link><description>General reforms not related to constitutional changes can immediately be executed by executive orders while the July National Charter has to be incorporated into the constitution by referendum on the national-election day or before.



The National Consensus Commission has made the recommendati</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 18:26:50 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>