<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 19:37:31 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Cheap labour built the industry, can clean energy save it?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/reviews/cheap-labour-built-the-industry-can-clean-energy-save-it</link><description>More often than not, a T-shirt bought from countries like the United States of America (USA) and Australia will have a tag saying, "Made in Bangladesh", reflecting the position Bangladesh's RMG sector holds in the international market. The RMG sector contributes to 81 per cent of the country's expo</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 16:05:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Budding researchers put their merits on display</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/budding-researchers-put-their-merits-on-display</link><description>Tanim Asjad
 
All of them, students from schools, studying between classes seven and ten, and hailing from different parts of the country, gathered in Dhaka to present their research papers or concept notes. Though sound puzzling, their dedication was evident as they expressed various though</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 16:35:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Breaking the silence around ADHD</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/breaking-the-silence-around-adhd</link><description>Dedicating an entire month to a single issue demonstrates the profound seriousness of the cause. It recognises that a single day of lip service is not enough to cut through the noise and a longer effort is needed to make people truly pay attention. This is precisely why October has been designated</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 17:05:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Reining in defiant edible oil companies</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/reining-in-defiant-edible-oil-companies</link><description>Unilaterally announcing a fresh hike in edible oil prices last week, the refining companies have clearly defied the government's position on the issue as the Commerce Adviser on Tuesday last denied having approved any such price hike. This hike in oil prices has taken place exactly three weeks afte</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 17:20:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A deep dive into Pahartali locomotive shed</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/a-deep-dive-into-pahartali-locomotive-shed</link><description>“There goes the Meghna Express power,” says Anik Bal, pointing at the blue-yellow locomotive slowly moving away.  
Standing at a safe distance from the tracks, I notice the locomotive number - 2938. Built by South Korea’s Hyundai Rotem, it is a 1,500-horsepower, metre-g</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 17:46:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two nabbed, legal action under way over police-‘July Warrior’ clashes</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/two-nabbed-legal-action-under-way-over-police-july-warrior-clashes</link><description>Two “July Warriors” were detained following clashes between police and protesters at the parliament premises, shortly before the July National Charter signing ceremony.
According to police, at least five vehicles were vandalised during the clashes on Friday, and parts of a temporary co</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 18:16:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat sees risk of 'political crisis' if implementation of July Charter delayed</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jamaat-sees-risk-of-political-crisis-if-implementation-of-july-charter-delayed</link><description>The Jamaat-e-Islami has warned that a delay in implementing the July National Charter could trigger a “political crisis”.
The BNP says the charter will help build a democratic state within “constitutional boundaries”.
The reactions came on Friday following the signing of t</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 18:31:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>July Charter signed for 'new Bangladesh'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/july-charter-signed-for-new-bangladesh</link><description>Head of interim government Prof Muhammad Yunus and major political parties' leaders Friday signed on the July National Charter 2025 stipulating institutional reforms for rebuilding Bangladesh in spirit of the uprising that toppled the past 'fascist' regime.



"We're now newborns-it marks the b</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 18:46:42 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>