<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 14:24:37 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Mahfuz Alam will not contest in polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/mahfuz-alam-will-not-contest-in-polls</link><description>Former Information Adviser Mahfuz Alam has said he will not contest the upcoming national parliamentary election. He confirmed the decision in an interview with BBC Bangla on Monday (December 29).
Mahfuz Alam said he had made up his mind not to run for office from the outset and that this was the</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 11:28:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nomination submission deadline closes for Bangladesh elections</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nomination-submission-deadline-closes-for-bangladesh-elections</link><description>The submission deadline for nomination papers for Bangladesh’s upcoming national election closed at 5:00 pm on Monday, with most candidates filing their papers on time.
Most of the aspirants submitted their nomination papers today as only 166 nomination papers were filed till Sunday to conte</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 11:43:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Kolkata's iconic trams face final stop as modernization rolls in</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/kolkatas-iconic-trams-face-final-stop-as-modernization-rolls-in</link><description>For more than a century, trams have rumbled past Kolkata's crumbling colonial facades, with their chiming bells contributing to the city's soundtrack as they ferried generations of commuters.
Now, Asia's oldest tram network is on the brink of disappearing as authorities consider pulling the plug o</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 11:58:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Winter bites without cold wave</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/winter-bites-without-cold-wave</link><description>Morning fog has erased the sun from much of Bangladesh, leaving winter to bite deeper than expected. With the gap between day and night temperatures shrinking to near record lows, the cold is being felt more sharply -- even without a cold wave.
The Bangladesh Meteorological Department (BMD) has fo</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 12:13:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bank Asia celebrates 17th anniversary of its Islamic Banking Services</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bank-asia-celebrates-17th-anniversary-of-its-islamic-banking-services</link><description>Bank Asia PLC organised a discussion meeting and Dua Mahfil on the occasion of the 17th anniversary of its Islamic Banking Services on Wednesday (24 December 2025) at Bank Asia Tower, Karwan Bazar, Dhaka.
Former Chairman of the Shariah Supervisory Committee Mufti Shahed Rahmani, former Member Secr</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 12:28:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>China stages record drills designed to encircle Taiwan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/china-stages-record-drills-designed-to-encircle-taiwan</link><description>China launched its most extensive war games around Taiwan on Monday to showcase Beijing's ability to cut off the island from outside support in a conflict, testing Taipei's resolve to defend itself and its arsenal of US-made weapons.
The Eastern Theatre Command said it had deployed troops, warship</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 12:00:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Time to be extended to submit paper-based income tax returns</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/time-to-be-extended-to-submit-paper-based-income-tax-returns</link><description>The National Board of Revenue (NBR) has allowed individual taxpayers to seek a conditional time extension to submit paper-based income tax returns, provided they apply with valid justification within a specified deadline, officials said.
Under a recent directive issued in line with the Income Tax</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 12:15:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC secretary rules out further extension for nomination submission</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-secretary-rules-out-further-extension-for-nomination-submission</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) will not grant any further extension for the submission of nomination papers for the upcoming national election, EC Senior Secretary Akhtar Ahmed said on Monday.
“The time for submission of nomination papers will not be extended anymore,” he told reporters</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 12:30:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>JaSaD boycotts February polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jasad-rejects-february-elections-terms-vote-unilateral-unconstitutional</link><description>The Jatiya Samajtantrik Dal (JaSaD), a key partner in the ousted Awami League-led 14-Party Alliance, announced its boycott of the February national election, describing it as “unilateral and one-sided”, while calling the accompanying referendum “unconstitutional”.
The party</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 12:45:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tasnim Jara calls for easier election process for independent candidates</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tasnim-jara-calls-for-easier-election-process-for-independent-candidates</link><description>Tasnim Jara, an independent candidate of Dhaka-9, on Monday urged the Election Commission to simplify the electoral process for independent contenders, saying the existing requirement of securing signatures from one percent of voters is unnecessarily difficult and discriminatory.
She called the ru</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 13:00:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ACC submits CS against PK Halder, 18 others</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/acc-submits-cs-against-pk-halder-18-others</link><description>Anti Corruption Commission (ACC) on Monday submitted charge sheet against PK Halder and 18 others for embezzling Tk 4.4 billion in the name of a fictitious company.
Mohammad Tanjir Ahmed, Assistant Director of the ACC told this to journalists at the commission headquarters.
According to the ACC,</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 13:15:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Asif Mahmud joins NCP as spokesperson, to skip elections</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/asif-mahmud-joins-ncp-as-spokesperson-to-skip-elections</link><description>Former interim government advisor Asif Mahmud Shojib Bhuyain has joined the National Citizen Party (NCP), taking on the responsibilities of party spokesperson and head of the election management committee.
Speaking at a press conference on Monday at the party’s Bangla Motor office, Asif also</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 13:30:47 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>