<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 13:49:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>IMF sees steady global growth in 2026 as AI boom offsets trade headwinds</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/imf-sees-steady-global-growth-in-2026-as-ai-boom-offsets-trade-headwinds</link><description>The International Monetary Fund again edged its 2026 global growth forecast higher on Monday as businesses and economies adapt to US tariffs that have eased in recent months and a continued AI investment boom that has fueled asset wealth and expectations of productivity gains.
The IMF in its World</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 10:24:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nearly 25,000 polling centres classified as ‘risky’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-classifies-nearly-25000-polling-centres-as-risky-for-general-election</link><description>The Bangladesh government has identified nearly 25,000 polling centres for the general election that are “at risk”.
Home Advisor Jahangir Alam Chowdhury made the announcement after an advisor-level meeting on law and order on Monday.
After the meeting held by the Ministry of Home Affa</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 10:39:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ICCB for banking sector resilience of Bangladesh’s economic future</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/iccb-for-banking-sector-resilience-of-bangladeshs-economic-future</link><description>As Bangladesh advances toward upper-middle-income status, the resilience and credibility of its banking sector will define the nation’s growth trajectory, according to the editorial of the latest News Bulletin (Oct-December 2025) released today by the International Chamber of Commerce-Banglad</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 10:54:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Politics must move beyond blame, focus on people’s lives: Tarique</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/politics-must-move-beyond-blame-focus-on-peoples-lives-tarique</link><description>BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman on Monday said politics must move beyond decades of blame and confrontation, and instead focus on improving the lives of ordinary people and standing by them in times of need.
“Those of us who are in politics—who do we do it for? We do it for the people of t</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 11:09:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New US envoy meets Tarique Rahman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/new-us-envoy-meets-tarique-rahman</link><description>Newly appointed US Ambassador to Bangladesh Brent T. Christensen paid a courtesy call on BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman on Monday.
The meeting began at 4:00pm at the BNP Chairman’s Gulshan office in the capital, said BNP Media Cell member Sayrul Kabir Khan.
BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 11:24:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCP goes for centralised crowdfunding ahead of election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ncp-goes-for-centralised-crowdfunding-ahead-of-election</link><description>National Citizen Party (NCP) on Monday announced the launch of a centrally managed crowdfunding initiative ahead of the 13th national parliamentary election, seeking financial support directly from the public.
Speaking at a press conference at the party’s temporary office in Banglamotor, NCP</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 11:39:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trust Bank inaugurates Alikadam Branch</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/trust-bank-inaugurates-alikadam-branch</link><description>Trust Bank PLC. launched its Alikadam Branch at 16, Mujib Market Alikadam Bazar, Alikadam, Bandarban.
Ahsan Zaman Chowdhury, Managing Director &amp; CEO of the bank, inaugurated the branch as Chief Guest, according to a media release. 
Along with others, Md. Mahboob Hossain, Senior Executive Vic</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 11:54:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>School bus crash in South Africa kills at least 13 children, police say</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/school-bus-crash-in-south-africa-kills-at-least-13-children-police-say</link><description>A truck collided with a school minibus in South Africa’s Gauteng province, killing at least 13 children, authorities said Monday.
Preliminary reports indicated at least 11 schoolchildren died at the scene, with two others succumbing to their injuries in the hospital.
The private vehicle was</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 11:54:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BIDA signs MoUs with 11 institutions to integrate OSS portal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/bida-signs-mous-with-11-institutions-to-integrate-oss-portal</link><description>To further facilitate domestic and foreign investment and make business operations easier, faster and more dynamic, the Bangladesh Investment Development Authority (BIDA) signed Memorandums of Understanding (MoUs) with 11 service-providing institutions for integration with its One Stop Service (OSS</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 12:09:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>T20 World Cup: PCB suspends preparations, Pakistan signals Support for Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/t20-world-cup-pcb-suspends-preparations-pakistan-signals-support-for-bangladesh</link><description>The ICC T20 World Cup faces fresh uncertainty as the Pakistan Cricket Board (PCB) reportedly halted all national team preparations on Monday, with the board instructing team management to develop a ‘contingency plan’ in case Pakistan decides to withdraw from the tournament.
Geo News, a</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 12:24:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Election Commission releases gazette for Feb 12 polling centres</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/election-commission-releases-gazette-for-feb-12-polling-centres</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has begun publishing the gazette of polling centres for all constituencies ahead of the general elections slated for Feb 12.
EC Deputy Secretary Monir Hossain said the gazette publication started on Jan 15, following approval of the final list for each constituency by</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 12:39:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EU plans 'made in Europe' rules for public purchases of green tech</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/eu-plans-made-in-europe-rules-for-public-purchases-of-green-tech</link><description>The European Union plans to impose minimum "made in Europe" requirements on public purchases of key green technologies to bolster local industry and cut dependence on Chinese imports, a draft European Commission proposal seen by Reuters showed.
The EU is racing to shore up its industrial base as h</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 12:54:21 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>