<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 08:40:38 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Heavy rains kill at least 22 in Nepal, block roads</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/heavy-rains-kill-at-least-22-in-nepal-block-roads</link><description>Heavy rains triggered landslides and flash floods, blocking roads, washing away bridges and killing at least 22 people in the last 36 hours in Nepal, officials said on Sunday.
Eighteen people were killed in separate landslides in the Ilam district in the east bordering India, police spokesperson B</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 06:00:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fire guts 19 shops in Khagrachhari’s Guimara</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/fire-guts-19-shops-in-khagrachharis-guimara</link><description>At least 19 shops have been destroyed after a fire ripped through a market in Khagrachhari’s Guimara Upazila.
The fire broke out around 1:45 am on Sunday at the "Hajji Ismail Market" in the Jaliapara area, according to Md Enamul Haque Chowdhury, chief of Guimara Police Station.
Witnesses sa</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 06:30:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Indices up in early trading at Dhaka, Chattogram bourses</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/indices-up-in-early-trading-at-dhaka-chattogram-bourses</link><description>Indices at both the Dhaka and Chattogram stock exchanges witnessed an upward trend in the first hour of trading on Sunday, the first working day of the week, as most companies saw gains in their share prices.
At the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE), the benchmark DSEX index rose by 43 points, while the</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 06:45:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Attack on police by extortionists: Seven arrested in Narsingdi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/attack-on-police-by-extortionists-seven-arrested-in-narsingdi</link><description>Seven suspects have been arrested in connection with the attack on an Additional Police Superintendent after a team attempted to resist extortion from vehicles in Narsingdi Sadar upazila.
Earlier, the in-charge of the town police outpost, Sohel Ahmed, filed a case naming five people and 25 to 30 u</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 06:00:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UN Resident Coordinator meets Fakhrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/un-resident-coordinator-meets-fakhrul</link><description>UN Resident Coordinator in Bangladesh Gwyn Lewis has met BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir and discussed various issues related to the upcoming national election and human rights.
The hour-long meeting, which began at 11:00 am on Sunday, was held at the BNP Chairperson’s offi</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 06:15:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Yunus happy over National Consensus Commission’s progress</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/yunus-happy-over-national-consensus-commissions-progress</link><description>Chief Adviser Prof Muhammad Yunus on Sunday expressed satisfaction with the progress made by the National Consensus Commission, which is expected to submit its final report soon.
Prof Yunus, who also serves as the chief of the Commission, thanked all its members for their dedication and directed t</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 06:45:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DNCC moves to reclaim Dhaka’s walkways with armed Ansar deployment</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dncc-moves-to-reclaim-dhakas-walkways-with-armed-ansar-deployment</link><description>Footpaths are meant to provide safe and accessible spaces for pedestrians, but in Dhaka, they often serve a very different purpose.
Street vendors and hawkers occupy much of the space, selling everything from fruits and snacks to clothes and shoes.
Construction materials are frequently piled up,</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 07:00:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP leader Gayeshwar Chandra Roy acquitted in graft case</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-leader-gayeshwar-chandra-roy-acquitted-in-graft-case</link><description>A Dhaka court has acquitted BNP National Standing Committee Member Gayeshwar Chandra Roy in a case over illegal acquisition of assets filed 16 years ago.
The court of Dhaka Special Judge Kamrul Hasan Khan delivered its verdict on Sunday, clearing Gayeshwar as the charges against him were not prove</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 07:30:59 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>