<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 09:23:49 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Dhaka condemns so-called “Israeli sovereignty” over West Bank</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dhaka-condemns-so-called-israeli-sovereignty-over-west-bank</link><description>Bangladesh has strongly condemned the recent approval by the Israeli Knesset of draft laws aimed at imposing so-called “Israeli sovereignty” over the occupied territories in the West Bank of the State of Palestine.  “Bangladesh reaffirms that Israel has no sovereignty ov</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 07:11:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Student group BGCS renames itself as ‘Jatiya Chhatra Shakti’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/student-group-bgcs-renames-itself-as-jatiya-chhatra-shakti</link><description>Eight months after its formation, the Bangladesh Ganatantrik Chhatra Sangsad (BGCS) has renamed itself "Jatiya Chhatra Shakti", unveiling a new motto as part of its reorganisation strategy.
The organisation announced the change at a meeting held on Thursday at the Abu Sayed Convention Hall near th</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 07:41:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bus catches fire after being hit by a motorcycle in southern India, killing at least 25</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/bus-catches-fire-after-being-hit-by-a-motorcycle-in-southern-india-killing-at-least-25</link><description>A passenger bus erupted into flames after a motorcycle crashed into it early Friday, killing at least 25 people and injuring several others in southern India, police said.
The fire tore through the bus within minutes, trapping dozens of passengers as it sped along a highway near Kurnool district i</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 08:26:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cyclone threat looms as fresh low forms over Bay of Bengal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cyclone-threat-looms-as-fresh-low-forms-over-bay-of-bengal</link><description>A low-pressure area has formed over the southeast Bay of Bengal, which may intensify into a depression before potentially developing into a cyclone, according to the Bangladesh Meteorological Department (BMD).
In a special weather bulletin issued on Friday, the Met Office advised fishing boats and</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 08:41:39 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>