<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 11:24:47 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>PM Tarique begins work at Tejgaon PMO</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/pm-tarique-begins-work-at-tejgaon-pmo</link><description>Prime Minister Tarique Rahman on Saturday began work at the Prime Minister’s Office in Tejgaon for the first time after assuming office.
He arrived at the office at 10:10 am, where Principal Secretary ABM Abdus Sattar and Additional Press Secretary Atikur Rahman Rumon received him.
Before e</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 07:31:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>PM releases commemorative postage stamp on Int’l Mother Language Day</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/pm-releases-commemorative-postage-stamp-on-intl-mother-language-day</link><description>Prime Minister Tarique Rahman has released a commemorative postage stamp, an opening envelope and a canceller on the occasion of the great Martyrs’ Day and the International Mother Language Day.
He released the commemorative postage stamp at the Prime Minister’s Office (PMO) in the cit</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 07:46:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rohingya refugee held with yaba pills in Bandarban</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rohingya-refugee-held-with-yaba-pills-in-bandarban</link><description>Members of Border Guard Bangladesh (BGB) arrested a Rohingya man and seized 330,000 Yaba tablets in separate anti-narcotics operations along the Ghumdhum border in Naikhongchhari upazila of Bandarban.
The arrestee was identified as Bashir Ahmed, 50, a Rohingya resident of Balukhali Camp-09 in Ukhi</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 08:54:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rumeen warns BNP over activist ‘misconduct’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/failure-to-rein-in-bnp-activists-will-bring-dire-consequences-warns-rumeen</link><description>Rumeen Farhana has warned that the consequences will be dire if the BNP fails to control its grassroots activists, after she faced obstruction while attempting to pay tribute to Language Movement martyrs at a Shaheed Minar.
Speaking at her Shahbazpur home in Sarail around 1:45am on Saturday, the B</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 08:41:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No need for separate oath over ‘Yes’ vote: Anee</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/no-need-for-separate-oath-over-yes-vote-anee</link><description>Water Resources Minister Shahid Uddin Chowdhury Anee has said there is no need for a separate oath regarding the “Yes” vote in the recent referendum.
Speaking after paying tribute to the language martyrs at the Lakshmipur Central Shaheed Minar on Saturday, the BNP joint secretary gener</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 08:56:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Macron says US Supreme Court tariff ruling shows it is good to have counterweights to power in democracies</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/macron-says-us-supreme-court-tariff-ruling-shows-it-is-good-to-have-counterweights-to-power-in-democracies</link><description>French President Emmanuel Macron said on Saturday that the U.S. Supreme Court ruling on President Donald Trump's trade tariffs shows that it is good to have counterweights to power and the rule of law in democracies.
"It is not bad to have a Supreme Court and, therefore, the rule of law," he said</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 09:11:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hong Kong plans to buy homes devastated in deadly high-rise fire</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/hong-kong-plans-to-buy-homes-devastated-in-deadly-high-rise-fire</link><description>Hong Kong proposes to spend about HK$4 billion ($512 million) to buy out the owners of homes in a high-rise housing complex ravaged by a massive fire that killed more than 160 in November, authorities said on Saturday.
The prices offered will be HK$8,000 per sq. ft. without a land premium payment,</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 09:26:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Meeting on education system, job creation held</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/meeting-on-education-system-job-creation-held</link><description>A meeting on establishing a cheerful and career-oriented education system, creating employment opportunities, and expanding sports infrastructure and training facilities was held at the Prime Minister's Office (PMO) in the city's Tejgaon area.
Prime Minister Tarique Rahman chaired the meeting, PM'</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 09:41:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prime Bank partners with Wecon Properties Ltd to offer special benefits for home loan customers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/prime-bank-partners-with-wecon-properties-ltd-to-offer-special-benefits-for-home-loan-customers</link><description>Prime Bank PLC has recently signed a strategic partnership agreement with one of the country’s leading real estate companies, Wecon Properties Ltd. 
The agreement was formally signed at a ceremony held at the bank’s Head Office in Gulshan, according to a media release. 
Under thi</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 09:56:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump says considering limited strike on Iran</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-says-considering-limited-strike-on-iran</link><description>U.S. President Donald Trump said Friday that he is considering a limited military strike to pressure Iran to make a deal.
"I guess I can say I am considering that," Trump told reporters at the White House.
The Wall Street Journal reported Thursday that Trump is weighing "an initial limited milita</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 10:27:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>3 dead in helicopter crash in Russia's Amur Oblast</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/3-dead-in-helicopter-crash-in-russias-amur-oblast</link><description>All three people on board a helicopter that went missing on Thursday have been confirmed dead, the Ministry of Emergency Situations of Russia for the Amur Oblast said on Saturday.
The helicopter vanished from radar on Thursday evening after taking off from a logging site in the Romnensky municipal</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 10:42:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Child abuse’: Ex-Biman MD’s wife gives statement</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/former-biman-mds-wife-gives-statement-over-domestic-child-worker-abuse</link><description>The wife of former Biman Bangladesh Airlines managing director and chief executive officer Shafiqur Rahman has given a statement before a Dhaka court in a case over the alleged abuse of a minor domestic worker.
After completing seven days of remand, Bithi was produced before the court on Saturday</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 10:57:55 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>