<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 21:20:13 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Finance adviser explains rise in millionaire bank accounts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/finance-adviser-attributes-rise-in-millionaire-bank-accounts-to-hidden-money</link><description>Finance Adviser Salehuddin Ahmed has said the Bangladesh Bank’s report showing a rise in millionaire bank accounts is due to “money hidden at home for a long time” now being deposited.
He made these comments after a meeting of the Advisery Council Committee on Government Procurem</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 15:45:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NRBC Bank arranged a workshop on IFRS-9</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/nrbc-bank-arranged-a-workshop-on-ifrs-9</link><description>NRBC Bank arranged a workshop on International Financial Reporting Standards (IFRS-9) on Tuesday at their Human Resource and Training Development Centre (HRTDC), according to a press release.
Dr. Md Touhidul Alam Khan, Managing Director &amp; CEO, was the chief guest at the workshop. Raditha Alahakoon</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 16:00:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Army officer commanded TV channels to alter Uprising coverage, Hasnat tells ICT</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/army-officer-commanded-tv-channels-to-alter-uprising-coverage-hasnat-tells-ict</link><description>The National Citizen Party (NCP) leader Hasnat Abdullah alleged that an Army officer controlled television broadcasts to manipulate coverage of the July Uprising.
Hasnat, former coordinator of the Students Against Discrimination and now NCP’s chief organiser for the southern region, gave tes</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 16:05:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Some unpleasant arithmetic</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/some-unpleasant-arithmetic</link><description>Bangladesh’s economy is often acclaimed for its remarkable resilience despite recurrent global disruptions — pandemics, energy shortages, supply-chain shocks, regional conflicts, and internal political instability. Observers frequently point to four powerful “engines” behind</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 16:20:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Reviving Bangladesh's shrimp sector</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/reviving-bangladeshs-shrimp-sector</link><description>Bangladesh's once-thriving shrimp sector has been languishing for quite some time and the situation appears to be worsening. Export orders for the country's prime shrimp varieties have continued to fall, driven primarily by waning demand in Europe and the United States-markets that together account</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 16:35:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Adopting policies to build a climate-resilient society</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/adopting-policies-to-build-a-climate-resilient-society</link><description>Bangladesh is placed among the world's top 10 climate-vulnerable nations, thanks to its geomorphological low-lying deltaic plain and exposure to severe floods, cyclones and encroachment by the sea on its coastal region. Evidently, measures to adapt to climate change impacts have been among the key</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 16:50:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP plans universal 'Family Card' for all women: Tarique Rahman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-plans-universal-family-card-for-all-women-tarique-rahman</link><description>BNP’s Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman on Tuesday announced that all women across the country will be brought under a universal 'Family Card' scheme if the party forms the next government, aiming to make four crore families economically self-reliant.
Speaking at a views-exchange event with ret</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 17:05:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP leader Shimul Biswas, 3 others injured in Paban road accident</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/bnp-leader-shimul-biswas-3-others-injured-in-paban-road-accident</link><description>Four people, including Shamsur Rahman Shimul Biswas, special assistant to BNP Chairperson and party-nominated candidate for Pabna-5 seat, were injured in a collision between a truck and a microbus in Atgharia upazila of Pabna on Tuesday evening.
The accident occurred around 6pm in Ekdanto area whi</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 17:30:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DU Faculty of Fine Arts admission results released with 11.25pc pass rate</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/du-faculty-of-fine-arts-admission-results-released-with-1125pc-pass-rate</link><description>For the 2025-2026 academic year, 602 students have passed the admission test for Dhaka University's Faculty of Fine Arts undergraduate programme from 5,352 test-takers.
The results released on Tuesday evening show a pass rate of 11.25 percent, bdnews24.com reports. 
Among those who passed, 1</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 17:45:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt on bank borrowing spree for bailout funds</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/govt-on-bank-borrowing-spree-for-bailout-funds</link><description>Government bank borrowing goes ballooning with the fundraising through special auction of bonds and bills to pay for five-in-one Sammilito Islami Bank and possible liquidation of nine hard-up nonbanks.
To meet the fresh financing challenges, amid less-than-expected level of revenue-mobilisation dr</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 18:00:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>PSC overhauls marks structure for 50th BCS preliminary exam</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/psc-overhauls-marks-structure-for-50th-bcs-preliminary-exam</link><description>The Public Service Commission (PSC) has revised the marks distribution for the BCS preliminary examination, releasing the updated syllabus and allocation for the 50th BCS with the changes incorporated.
On Tuesday, the commission published the syllabus and the full breakdown for the 200-mark exam o</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 18:15:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CA greets U-21 hockey team for winning challenger trophy of Junior Hockey World Cup</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/ca-greets-u-21-hockey-team-for-winning-challenger-trophy-of-junior-hockey-world-cup</link><description>Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus today congratulated Bangladesh Youth Hockey team for winning the Challenger Trophy of Junior Hockey World Cup.
In a congratulatory message, he said this achievement has made the nation proud, BSS reports. 
Through hard work, discipline, team solidarity</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 18:30:51 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>