<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 15:29:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Israel says Lebanon is not doing enough to disarm Hezbollah</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/israel-says-lebanon-is-not-doing-enough-to-disarm-hezbollah</link><description>Israel said Lebanon's efforts to disarm Hezbollah are far from sufficient after the Lebanese army declared that it had established operational control in the south, raising pressure on Lebanese leaders who fear Israel could escalate strikes.
In line with US demands, the Lebanese government has bee</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 12:15:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka to seek exemption from US visa bond: Touhid</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dhaka-to-seek-exemption-from-us-visa-bond-touhid</link><description>Bangladesh will pursue diplomatic efforts to seek exemption from the United States' newly imposed visa bond requirement, Foreign Adviser Md Touhid Hossain said today (Thursday), describing the measure as unfortunate but not abnormal.
"It is certainly unfortunate and painful for us, but it is not a</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 12:30:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Experts urge overhaul of SRO 384 to ease duty-free imports</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/experts-urge-overhaul-of-sro-384-to-ease-duty-free-raw-material-imports</link><description>Business leaders and policy experts on Thursday raised concern over the recently issued SRO 384/2025, warning that the current framework for duty-free import of raw materials beyond the bonded warehouse facility could discourage small exporters.  The concerns were voiced at a high-level dialog</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 12:45:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Saudi Arabia alleges UAE smuggled wanted Yemen separatist leader out of the country</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/saudi-arabia-alleges-uae-smuggled-wanted-yemen-separatist-leader-out-of-the-country</link><description>Saudi Arabia has accused the United Arab Emirates of secretly helping a wanted Yemeni separatist leader flee the country, deepening an already serious rift between the two Gulf allies over Yemen.  In a statement Thursday, the Saudi military alleged that Aidarous al-Zubaidi, head of Yemen's Sou</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 13:00:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Street renamed after Khaleda in US</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/us-city-hamtramck-honours-khaleda-zia-with-street-name</link><description>The Hamtramck City Council in Michigan, United States has approved a proposal to rename “Carpenter Street” as “Khaleda Zia Street” in honour of the late BNP chairperson.
The party’s media cell confirmed the decision via its official Facebook page, noting that the stre</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 13:15:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Arrest Muchabbir’s killers in 24 hours: Swecchasebak Dal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/swecchasebak-dal-issues-24-hour-ultimatum-for-arrest-of-muchabbirs-killers</link><description>The Jatiotabadi Swecchasebak Dal has said it will launch rigorous protests if the killers of its slain leader Azizur Rahman Muchabbir are not arrested within the next 24 hours.
Yasin Ali, senior vice-president of the BNP’s volunteer wing, and Vice-President Fakhrul Islam Robin issued the war</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 13:30:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh capital market ends week higher despite lower turnover</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh-capital-market-ends-week-higher-despite-lower-turnover</link><description>Bangladesh’s capital market closed the week on Thursday with marginal gains in key indices on both the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) and the Chittagong Stock Exchange (CSE), although overall turnover declined and prices of most listed companies fell.
At the end of the session, the DSE’s b</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 13:45:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump calls for $1.5t military budget in 2027, up from $901b in 2026</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-calls-for-15t-military-budget-in-2027-up-from-901b-in-2026</link><description>President Donald Trump said on Wednesday the 2027 U.S. military budget should be $1.5 trillion, significantly higher than the $901 billion approved by Congress for 2026, boosting defense stocks, but sparking skepticism among budget experts.
Any such increase in the military budget would require co</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 14:00:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fire at Gazipur jhut warehouse</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/gazipur-factory-fire-spreads-to-nearby-warehouses-six-units-deployed</link><description>A fire has erupted at a “jhut” or waste fabric warehouse in Gazipur city, prompting a large response from the Fire Service to bring the blaze under control.
The incident occurred around 4:15pm on Thursday in Kathaltala of Dewaliabari in the city, said Saiful Islam, warehouse inspector</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 14:15:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Coast Guard arrests leader of gang abducting tourists in Sundarban</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/coast-guard-arrests-leader-of-gang-abducting-tourists-in-sundarban</link><description>The Bangladesh Coast Guard has arrested Masum Mridha, the alleged ringleader of a tourist abduction gang in the Sundarbans. It also recovered firearms, sharp weapons and ammunition during the operation.
Masum, 23, was detained on Wednesday in Dhanakhali, Terokhada upazila, Khulna, following intell</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 14:30:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Remittance funds to be credited in a day</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh-bank-orders-remittances-credited-within-one-working-day</link><description>Bangladesh Bank has directed banks to credit remittances sent by expatriates to customers’ accounts within one working day.
Any remittance received after banking hours must be credited on the following working day, according to instructions issued on Thursday.
Banks have been given until Ma</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 14:45:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique to visit Cox’s Bazar, Ctg Jan 18</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-rahman-to-travel-to-coxs-bazar-chattogram-on-jan-18</link><description>Tarique Rahman is set to visit Chattogram for the first time in nearly two decades.
The BNP acting chief will attend a prayer gathering for his mother Khaleda Zia at the premises of Jamiyatul Falah National Mosque on the afternoon of Jan 18, said Chattogram city BNP member secretary Nazimur Rahman</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 15:00:53 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>