<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 23:27:47 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Siraz Uddin Miah named new cabinet secretary</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/siraz-uddin-miah-named-new-cabinet-secretary</link><description>The government has terminated the contract of cabinet secretary Sheikh Abdur Rashid and appointed M Siraz Uddin Miah as his successor, days before the new administration is sworn in.
The decision was announced in two separate official notifications issued on Friday.
One notification said the rema</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 16:29:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UK, allies say they’re convinced Kremlin critic Navalny was poisoned</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/uk-allies-say-theyre-convinced-kremlin-critic-navalny-was-poisoned</link><description>Britain, France, Germany, Sweden and the Netherlands are convinced that late Kremlin critic, Alexei Navalny, was poisoned with a lethal toxin in an Arcticpenal colony two years ago, they said in a joint statement on Saturday.
The five governments said their findings were based on analyses of sampl</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 16:44:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Newly elected MPs, new cabinet to be sworn in on Tuesday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/newly-elected-mps-new-cabinet-to-be-sworn-in-on-tuesday</link><description>The oath-taking ceremony of the newly elected members of parliament and new cabinet members will take place on Tuesday.
News portals said Chief Election Commissioner AMM Nasir Uddin will administer the oath of office to the newly elected members of parliament at Jatiya Sangsad on Tuesday morn</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 16:59:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>African Union summit clouded by Saudi-UAE rivalry in Horn of Africa</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/african-union-summit-clouded-by-saudi-uae-rivalry-in-horn-of-africa</link><description>A feud between Saudi Arabia and the United Arab Emirates across the Horn of Africa is overshadowing this weekend’s African Union summit, though most of the continent’s leaders will try to avoid taking sides, nine diplomats and experts said.
What began as a rivalry in Yemen has spread a</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 17:14:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Convincing people was BNP’s ‘engineering’, says Tarique Rahman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/convincing-people-was-bnps-engineering-says-tarique-rahman</link><description>BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman on Monday said convincing people to get two-thirds majority in the national election was their ‘engineering’ and no other manipulative tactics.“Convincing the people of the country and bringing them over to our side was our engineering. Alhamdulillah, w</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 17:29:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Post-poll violence: Supporter of independent candidate killed in Bagerhat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/post-poll-violence-supporter-of-independent-candidate-killed-in-bagerhat</link><description>A supporter of an independent candidate died on Saturday after being injured in a post-election clash with BNP supporters in Kachua upazila of Bagerhat.
The victim was identified as Osman Sardar, 29, son of Shahjahan Sardar of Par Nawapara village in Bagerhat Sadar upazila. He died around 11</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 17:44:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Inflation and cost of living crisis</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/inflation-and-cost-of-living-crisis</link><description>Bangladesh is facing its most severe cost-of-living crisis in recent history, characterised by the highest inflation in South Asia, projected at roughly 8.9 per cent in 2025 and expected to remain high in 2026. According to the Bangladesh Bureau of Statistics (BBS) data, inflation in Bangladesh inc</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 17:59:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A rocky road awaits  next government</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/a-rocky-road-awaits-next-government</link><description>The dust has finally settled on the 13th parliamentary elections, with the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) securing a landslide two-thirds majority in a 300-seat parliament. The election not only restored democracy but also paved the way for the formation of a government with a genuine popular m</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 18:00:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>LDCs' key challenges decoded</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/ldcs-key-challenges-decoded</link><description>Though the services sector has become a leading source of growth and employment in the least developed countries (LDCs), it has yet to provide adequate, productive, and formal jobs. Instead, service-centric jobs in these countries are clustered in low-productivity and informal sectors, leading to l</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 18:15:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Unity, economic reforms, rule of law main goals</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/unity-economic-reforms-rule-of-law-main-goals</link><description>Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) and prime minister-apparent Tarique Rahman prioritizes national unity, economic reforms and the rule of law under is upcoming government.
He explains that national unity is the collective strength of the country and both the government and the opposition must wor</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 18:30:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New leadership and the quest for liveability</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/new-leadership-and-the-quest-for-liveability</link><description>The long awaited national election, held 17 years after the last genuinely contested vote, has brought with it a wave of public expectation. For many residents of Dhaka, some of those expectations are surprisingly simple, though no less reasonable for it. People in the megacity want a clean and ord</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 18:45:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mamata sends sweets, flowers to Tarique Rahman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/mamata-sends-sweets-flowers-to-tarique-rahman</link><description>West Bengal Chief Minister Mamata Banerjee on Saturday sent floral greetings and sweets to BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman following the party's landslide victory in the 13th national election.
BNP Media Cell member Atiqur Rahman Ruman received the flowers and sweets in the evening at the party chairm</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 19:00:39 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>