<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 05:20:28 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Bangladesh's struggle to make trade sustainable</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/bangladeshs-struggle-to-make-trade-sustainable</link><description>Can the trade and environmental policies interact? If yes, what will be its influence on climate change, biodiversity loss, pollution, and global trade flows? The questions are not new, and the answer to the first question is a resounding 'yes': it is both possible and necessary to interact with tr</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 18:59:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bridging the startup funding gap</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/bridging-the-startup-funding-gap</link><description>An enabling environment for young businesses is vital to any economy seeking sustainable growth. When entrepreneurs are given access to capital and institutional backing, they can turn ideas into initiatives that generate jobs and innovation. As such, the forthcoming public company for start-up inv</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 19:14:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Improvisation with Dhaka's metro rail has a cost</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/improvisation-with-dhakas-metro-rail-has-a-cost</link><description>Liabilities of Dhaka metro -rail company are likely to multiply as it has to bear the cost of mending many defects and deficiencies recently identified in all systems and sub -systems in the under-operation overhead rail.
A recent tragic accident of bearing-pad crash of the metro that killed a you</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 02:29:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP won't take liability for 'unsigned' parts of July Charter</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-wont-take-liability-for-unsigned-parts-of-july-charter</link><description>BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir has reiterated that his party will not take responsibility for any portion of the July National Charter that it did not sign, reaffirming the BNP's firm stance on its "notes of dissent."
Speaking at a rally in Dhaka on Saturday, he accused the auth</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 02:44:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ADB seeks govt nod to issue taka bond</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/adb-seeks-govt-nod-to-issue-taka-bond</link><description>The Asian Development Bank (ADB) has sought the government's permission to issue bonds through mobile money to mobilise investment for Bangladesh's development, officials said on Saturday.
The Manila-based lender plans to introduce the bond in local currency in the domestic market first and, upon</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 02:59:31 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>