<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 04:23:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Chinese, Indian firms eye Bangladesh to invest in RMG sector</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/chinese-indian-firms-eye-bangladesh-to-invest-in-rmg-sector</link><description>A growing wave of Chinese and Indian companies is eyeing Bangladesh's textile and garment sector as an emerging alternative for relocation, driven by steep US tariffs and rising production costs.
Industry insiders say global buyers, particularly from the United States, have been scouting for new s</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 01:38:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>68.2pc females, 45.9pc males unaware of PR: Survey</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/682pc-females-459pc-males-unaware-of-pr-survey</link><description>A large segment of Bangladesh's voters remains unaware of the widely-discussed proportional representation (PR) electoral system for the upper house, according to a latest survey.
The survey revealed that 68.2 per cent of females and 45.9 per cent of males had never heard of PR or did not know eno</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 01:53:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Redoubled exploration in south coast, releasing Bhola gas caches accelerate</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/redoubled-exploration-in-south-coast-releasing-bhola-gas-caches-accelerate</link><description>Curing Bangladesh's economic development-limiting fuel crunch gets under focus as exploration in the south coast and releasing locked Bhola gas caches gather speed.
Sources say the government has fielded agencies to carry out feasibility study on pipeline setting to carry the stranded Bhola gas to</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 02:08:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fully paperless customs in Bangladesh by 2028</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/fully-paperless-customs-in-bangladesh-by-2028</link><description>Bangladesh is advancing towards a fully paperless customs system by 2028 with the move to expand the digital window for the clearance of imports.
Recently, the Chief Adviser's Office instructed the National Board of Revenue (NBR) to include 18 more public and private bodies in the digital platform</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 02:38:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Strong growth in farm loan as disbursement hits Tk 26.72b</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/strong-growth-in-farm-loan-as-disbursement-hits-tk-2672b</link><description>Disbursement of agricultural loans rose notably in August of the current fiscal year, reflecting higher demand for seasonal credit amid ongoing efforts to boost rural productivity.
According to the latest data from Bangladesh Bank (BB), farm-loan disbursement stood at Tk48.26 billion during July-A</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 03:23:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>China detains dozens of underground church pastors in crackdown</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/china-detains-dozens-of-underground-church-pastors-in-crackdown</link><description>Police in China detained dozens of pastors of one of its largest underground churches over the weekend, a church spokesperson and relatives said, in the biggest crackdown on Christians since 2018.
The detentions, which come amid renewed China-US tensions after Beijing dramatically expanded rare ea</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 03:53:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>WHO warns of contaminated India cough syrups</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/who-warns-of-contaminated-india-cough-syrups</link><description>The World Health Organization on Monday issued a health advisory warning about three contaminated cough syrups identified in India, urging authorities to report any detection of these medicines in their countries to the health agency.
The WHO said the affected medicines are specific batches of Col</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 04:08:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Google to invest $10 billion in data centre and AI project in India</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/google-to-invest-10-billion-in-data-centre-and-ai-project-in-india</link><description>Alphabet Inc's Google will invest $10 billion to set up a massive data centre and artificial intelligence hub in Andhra Pradesh, officials from the southern Indian state said, marking its biggest such investment in the South Asian nation.
Google will build a 1-gigawatt data centre campus in the po</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 04:23:27 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>