<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 13:30:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Bangladesh reaffirms commitment to rules-based global order: Touhid</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-reaffirms-commitment-to-rules-based-global-order-touhid</link><description>Foreign Affairs Adviser Md Touhid Hossain, on Saturday, reaffirmed Bangladesh’s commitment to a rules-based international order and collective global action, emphasising dialogue and cooperation to address shared economic challenges.
“As a responsible neighbour and an active member of</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 10:16:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hindu Mohajote leader Gobinda regains candidacy in Gopalganj-3</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/hindu-mohajote-leader-gobinda-regains-candidacy-in-gopalganj-3</link><description>Gobinda Chandra Pramanik, secretary general of the Bangladesh Jatiya Hindu Mohajote, has had his nomination reinstated for the Gopalganj-3 constituency after filing an appeal with the Election Commission (EC).
On Friday, following a hearing on his appeal, the EC declared the independent candidate&amp;</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 10:31:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khamenei calls Trump criminal for causing casualties, damage, slander on Iranians</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/khamenei-calls-trump-criminal-for-causing-casualties-damage-slander-on-iranians</link><description>Iran's supreme leader Ali Khamenei said on Saturday that Iran considers US President Donald Trump a "criminal" for inflicting casualties, damage, and slander on the Iranian people during the protests.
"The latest anti-Iran sedition was different in that the US President personally became involved,</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 10:46:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC cancels BNP candidate’s nomination in Hasnat Abdullah’s constituency</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ec-cancels-bnp-candidates-nomination-in-hasnat-abdullahs-constituency</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has cancelled the nomination of Manjurul Ahsan Munshi, the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) candidate in the Cumilla-4 constituency, over allegations of loan default.
The decision was announced on Saturday (January 17) after a hearing held at 4:00 pm at the Basement-</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 11:00:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Strong editorial institutions vital for journalistic standards: Mahfuz Anam</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/strong-editorial-institutions-key-to-upholding-journalistic-standards-mahfuz-anam</link><description>A robust editorial institution is essential for maintaining journalistic integrity in Bangladesh, said The Daily Star Editor Mahfuz Anam on Saturday.
“Now is the right time to practise ethical journalism in Bangladesh. If media editors can maintain the standards of editorial institutions, jo</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 11:15:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>American CEOs push back on Trump ... mildly</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/american-ceos-push-back-on-trump-mildly</link><description>Speaking before a darkened ballroom on Thursday, US Chamber of Commerce CEO Suzanne Clark called on executives to be "fearless" in defense of free markets over government control and said the US must remain "open to the world, open to the global exchange of talent and goods and ideas and innovation</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 11:30:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Assault on intern doctor at Syhet hospital sparks work stoppage</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/assault-on-intern-doctor-at-syhet-hospital-sparks-work-stoppage</link><description>An intern doctor has been assaulted at Sylhet MAG Osmani Medical College Hospital, prompting junior doctors to launch an indefinite work stoppage in protest.
The attack took place on Friday night. Police said three relatives of a patient had been detained in connection with the incident.
Intern d</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 11:45:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt tightens public asset oversight to curb fiscal risks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-tightens-oversight-of-public-assets-to-curb-long-term-fiscal-risks</link><description>The government has introduced a new Property, Plant and Equipment (PPE) and Lease Manual aimed at strengthening asset governance and curbing long-term liabilities.
The move comes as the Finance Division revealed that Bangladesh’s total contingent liabilities have reached Tk 6.398 trillion (T</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 12:00:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Police bar 330 people from Chattogram</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/police-invoke-ordinance-powers-to-bar-330-people-from-chattogram</link><description>The Chattogram Metropolitan Police (CMP) has imposed a ban on the entry and residence of 330 people in the city, publishing a list of those it applies to.
The CMP issued the directive on Saturday afternoon.
Signed by CMP Commissioner Hasib Aziz, the CMP said the action was taken under Sections 40</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 12:27:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>July Charter could usher in a new Bangladesh, says Ali Riaz</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/july-charter-could-usher-in-a-new-bangladesh-says-ali-riaz</link><description>Prof Ali Riaz has said the July Charter, which the government plans to put to a referendum, was written through sacrifice and loss, and could help shape a "new Bangladesh".
Riaz, who is a special assistant to the chief advisor and the government’s chief coordinator for referendum outreach, s</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 12:42:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Business-friendly policies vital to build sustainable packaging sector: Experts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/business-friendly-policies-vital-to-build-sustainable-packaging-sector-experts</link><description>Experts have emphasised the need for business-friendly policies to develop a sustainable packaging sector in Bangladesh, saying that with proper policy support and incentives from the government, the sector has the potential to surpass even the ready-made garment (RMG) industry in the future.
They</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 12:57:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fire at Mymensingh Medical College under control</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fire-in-mymensingh-medical-colleges-childrens-ward-brought-under-control</link><description>A fire that broke out on the sixth floor of the new building at Mymensingh Medical College Hospital, in the children’s ward, has been contained.
The Fire Service deployed nine units to contain the blaze within 30 minutes on Saturday.
Senior Station Officer Sanowar Hossain confirmed that no</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 13:12:11 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>