<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 05:21:34 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>EC urges caution against creating confusion over election schedule, voting date</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-urges-caution-against-creating-confusion-over-election-schedule-voting-date</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has urged all concerned not to spread confusion regarding the announcement of the election schedule and polling date for the upcoming national election.
EC Senior Secretary Akhtar Ahmed told the media on Friday evening that no decision has yet been taken on the schedul</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 17:30:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khaleda Zia’s condition unchanged, Zubaida back at hospital</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/khaleda-zias-condition-unchanged-zubaida-back-at-hospital</link><description>BNP Chairperson Khaleda Zia’s health remains unchanged, according to doctors.
Her daughter-in-law Zubaida Rahman again visited her at Evercare Hospital in Dhaka on Friday night after meeting her mother.
BNP Media Cell member Atikur Rahman Rumon said, “[She] visited her mother in Dhanm</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 17:45:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Factor Khaleda’s illness into polls schedule: NCP to EC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ncp-again-pushes-ec-to-factor-khaledas-illness-into-election-timeline</link><description>The National Citizen Party (NCP) has renewed calls for the Election Commission to factor in the critical illness of BNP chief Khaleda Zia when finalising the schedule for the general election slated for February.
At a policy discussion on Friday titled “The Future of Investment in Bangladesh</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 18:00:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Regular liquidity feeding to banks stops, call money market vibrant</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/regular-liquidity-feeding-to-banks-stops-call-money-market-vibrant</link><description>Bangladesh Bank finally discards a major regular liquidity-feeding instrument for primary dealer (PD) banks, eight months after the decision made to tidy the money market under a reform recipe.



As part of the central bank's decision to bring vibrancy in the interbank spot market through le</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 19:18:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tight-fisted govt spending narrows budget deficit, curtails works</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/tight-fisted-govt-spending-narrows-budget-deficit-curtails-works</link><description>A slowdown in public works following the regime-changing political upheavals has narrowed Bangladesh's budget deficit as a blessing in disguise as the interim government couldn't utilise much of the budgetary outlay, official statistics show.
The budget deficit contracted to 3.30 per cent of the G</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 02:28:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Constant product lab tests a must-do to accelerate trade</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/constant-product-lab-tests-a-must-do-to-accelerate-trade</link><description>A government instruction makes it a must-do for key scientific agencies to keep their laboratory-testing services open round the clock, weekends and public holidays no exception, to cut the cost of doing business and accelerate trade facilitation.
Officials say the Ministry of Science and Technolo</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 02:43:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Government, AIIB in talks over $400m budget support credit</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/government-aiib-in-talks-over-400m-budget-support-credit</link><description>The government is discussing with the Asian Infrastructure Investment Bank (AIIB) a $400 million fund in budget support credit to advance policy and institutional reforms, focusing on climate adaptation in the urban and water sectors.
The programme aims to support the government in implementing cr</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 02:58:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Internet subscriptions see major drop, mobile usage also down</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/internet-subscriptions-see-major-drop-mobile-usage-also-down</link><description>Bangladesh has recorded a significant decline in internet subscriptions over the past four months, with official figures showing a continuous drop from the mid-2025 high, according to the latest data released by the Bangladesh Telecommunication Regulatory Commission (BTRC).
The number of total int</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 04:00:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Weekly Market Review: Stocks sink as NBFI liquidation move triggers sell-off</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/weekly-market-review-stocks-sink-as-nbfi-liquidation-move-triggers-sell-off</link><description>The benchmark index of the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) tumbled this week, snapping a two-week gaining streak, as the move to liquidate nine scam-tainted non-bank financial institutions (NBFIs) unnerved investors.
The Bangladesh Bank officially approved the liquidation this week as the these NBFIs -</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 04:15:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pakistan, Afghanistan exchange heavy fire along border</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/pakistan-afghanistan-exchange-heavy-fire-along-border</link><description>Pakistan and Afghanistan exchanged heavy fire along their border late on Friday, officials from both countries said, amid heightened tensions following failed peace talks earlier this week.
There were no immediate reports of casualties.
Afghan Taliban spokesman Zabihullah Mujahid said Pakistani f</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 04:30:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Putin, Modi agree to expand and widen India-Russia trade</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/putin-modi-agree-to-expand-and-widen-india-russia-trade-strengthen-friendship</link><description>Russian President Vladimir Putin offered India uninterrupted fuel supplies on Friday, eliciting a cautious response even as he and Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi agreed to expand trade and defence ties between countries with decades-old ties.
India, the world's top buyer of Russian arms and s</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 04:45:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Six of a family suffer burns in Dhaka blast from ‘gas leak’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/six-of-a-family-suffer-burns-in-dhaka-blast-from-gas-leak</link><description>Six members of a family, including a child, suffered burn injuries in an explosion apparently from a gas line leak at a house in the Agargaon area of the capital early Saturday.
The victims were identified as Jalil Mia, 50, Aneza Begum, 40, Asif Mia, 19, Sakib Mia, 16, Monira, 17 and Eva, 6, UNB r</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 05:00:48 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>