<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 11:35:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Memories of vote: How it feels returning to the ballot</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/others/memories-of-vote-how-it-feels-returning-to-the-ballot</link><description>On a February evening in Dhaka, Neza Mahmud, a young, promising lawyer, is planning a journey she once thought she might never make again. The journey is not to a vacation where physical presence is needed, but to something more ideological, mental, and self-expression; it is about voting in the el</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 10:00:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New oppressors have emerged, says Tarique Rahman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/new-oppressors-have-emerged-says-tarique-rahman</link><description>BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman has called on voters to be wary of Jamaat-e-Islami, referring to it as a “secret organisation”.
He said, "The people of this secret organisation have emerged as new oppressors of the people of Bangladesh."
The BNP chief made these remarks at a party rally a</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 10:15:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP complains of election officer appointment from ‘Jamaat school’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bnp-complains-over-appointment-of-election-officer-from-jamaat-run-school</link><description>At least 14 teachers from an unregistered educational institution “run with the patronage of Jamaat-e-Islami” have been appointed as election officials in Sunamganj’s Tahirpur for the 13th parliamentary election, BNP has complained.
Tahirpur Upazila Nirbahi Officer (UNO) and Assi</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 10:30:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Japan's Takaichi rides youth-led craze into election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/handbags-and-hashtags-japans-takaichi-rides-youth-led-craze-into-election</link><description>The handbag she carries is sold out, her pink pen has gone viral and even her favourite snacks are in hot demand: Japan's 64-year-old leader Sanae Takaichi has sparked an unlikely youth-led craze that could propel her to a big election win.
Polls suggest 'sanakatsu', roughly translated as 'sanaman</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 09:30:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BB buys $171m, total purchases hit $4.32b in FY2025-26</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bb-buys-171m-total-purchases-hit-432b-in-fy2025-26</link><description>Bangladesh Bank (BB) purchased an additional US $171 million from 16 commercial banks on Wednesday as part of ongoing efforts to stabilise the country’s foreign exchange market.
The dollars were bought at a cut-off rate of Tk 122.30 per US dollar, a central bank official said.
This interven</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 09:45:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No credible challenger in national election, says Nahid</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/no-credible-challenger-in-national-election-says-nahid</link><description>National Citizen Party (NCP) Convener and Jamaat-led 11-party alliance candidate for the Dhaka-11 constituency Nahid Islam on Wednesday said the BNP has failed to field any ‘credible challenger’ in the national election scheduled for February 12.
Talking to reporters during electioneer</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 10:00:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Next Bangladesh govt will need to navigate tricky foreign policy issues: Crisis Group</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/next-bangladesh-govt-will-need-to-navigate-tricky-foreign-policy-issues-crisis-group</link><description>The International Crisis Group has said the incoming administration in Bangladesh will need to address a raft of challenges, from weak institutions to a sluggish economy heavily dependent on garment exports and remittances to the growing effects of climate change in one of the world’s most de</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 10:15:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump's India pact to make big dent in Russian oil revenue</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trumps-india-pact-to-make-big-dent-in-russian-oil-revenue</link><description>Russia faces a steep drop in oil income if US President Donald Trump successfully pressures India to stop importing Russian crude, because losing its top purchaser of seaborne exports would force Moscow to slash prices to find other buyers, analysts and traders said.
Trump on Monday cut US tariffs</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 10:30:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fake Facebook page imitating The Financial Express detected</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fake-facebook-page-imitating-the-financial-express-detected</link><description>A fake Facebook page imitating The Financial Express has recently come to the notice of the authorities of the newspaper, prompting concerns over possible misinformation and misuse of the organisation’s name and identity.
The fraudulent page, operating under the name “The Bangladesh Ex</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 10:45:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Know before you vote: Bangladesh launches 333 Helpline</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/know-before-you-vote-bangladesh-launches-333-helpline</link><description>The government has launched a special information service through national helpline 333 in collaboration with the Bangladesh Election Commission.
The initiative aims to make the election process more transparent, participatory, and citizen-friendly.
Citizens can call the toll-free number 333 from</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 11:00:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US hosts countries for talks to weaken China's grip on critical minerals</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-hosts-countries-for-talks-to-weaken-chinas-grip-on-critical-minerals</link><description>The United States will host more than 50 countries on Wednesday for talks aimed at boosting their access to critical minerals, in a bid to loosen China's grip over vital industrial inputs that has allowed it to control global supply chains.
The gathering comes after President Donald Trump on Monda</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 11:15:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Strike brings Chattogram Port to a standstill</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/strike-brings-chattogram-port-to-a-standstill</link><description>Operations at Chattogram Port, the country’s busiest trade hub, have come to a standstill as a strike by port workers and employees drags on, triggering significant delays in imports and exports, as talks are underway between labour representatives and port authorities to resolve the crisis.</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 11:30:48 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>