<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 06:36:29 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>RENEWABLE ENERGY: Experts call for urgent reforms to procurement framework</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/renewable-energy-experts-call-for-urgent-reforms-to-procurement-framework</link><description>Experts have called for urgent reforms to Bangladesh's renewable energy procurement framework after a new study by the Centre for Policy Dialogue (CPD) revealed that many of the recently advertised solar power tenders received little to no participation.
The study, presented on Monday at a dialogu</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 03:25:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Twelve parties sign Child Rights Manifesto with ten commitments</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/twelve-parties-sign-child-rights-manifesto-with-ten-commitments</link><description>Political parties have united to sign a Child Rights Manifesto (CRM), responding to the powerful voices of children and young people, who have demanded a future where their rights are better respected and protected.
Ahead of the upcoming national election, 12 political parties signed the manifesto</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 03:40:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>White House defends US attack on boat from Venezuela as lawful</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/white-house-defends-us-attack-on-boat-from-venezuela-as-lawful</link><description>The White House on Monday defended a US admiral's decision to conduct multiple strikes on an alleged Venezuelan drug-smuggling vessel in September, saying he had Defense Secretary Pete Hegseth's authorisation, even as critics questioned the legality of a strike on survivors.
The Washington Post ha</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 03:55:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique will return ‘soon’, says Salahuddin</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-will-return-soon-says-salahuddin</link><description>Tarique Rahman will return to Bangladesh soon, BNP leader Salahuddin Ahmed has said.
The member of the party's Standing Committee made this comment in response to reporters' questions following an emergency meeting at the chairperson's Gulshan office on Monday night.
The BNP leader, however, did</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 04:10:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Plying of cruise ships resumes on Cox's Bazar-St Martin waterway</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/plying-of-cruise-ships-resumes-on-coxs-bazar-st-martin-waterway</link><description>COX'S BAZAR, Dec 01: After a nine-month closure, movement of vessels transporting tourists resumed on the Cox's Bazar-Saint Martin's route on Monday (December 1).
Cruise ships MV Bar Aulia, MV Karnaphuli and Keary Sindabad set off for Saint Martin's Island from the Nuniarachara BIWTA jetty in Cox'</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 04:25:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump rejected Maduro requests on call, options narrow for Venezuela leader</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-rejected-maduro-requests-on-call-options-narrow-for-venezuela-leader-sources-say</link><description>Venezuela's President Nicolas Maduro is running out of options to step down and leave his country under US-guaranteed safe passage, following a short call with US President Donald Trump last month where Trump refused a series of requests from the Venezuelan leader, according to four sources briefed</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 04:40:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Throat-slit body of man recovered in Chuadanga</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/throat-slit-body-of-man-recovered-in-chuadanga</link><description>A 25-year-old young man was found dead with his throat slit at Belgachi in the Chuadanga municipality area on Tuesday. 
The deceased was identified as Sohel, son of Asabul Haque of Bakcharpara area of the village, reports UNB.
Md Shahidur Rahman, officer-in-charge of Sadar Police Station, sa</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 04:55:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Three killed in Madaripur road crash</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/three-killed-in-madaripur-road-crash</link><description>Three people have been killed after a bus and a truck collided near the Arial Khan Bridge on the Dhaka-Bhanga Expressway in Shibchar upazila of Madaripur district.
Zarirul Islam, chief of Shibchar Police Station, said the accident occurred around 9:45 am on Tuesday, reports bdnews24.com
One perso</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 05:00:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CHANDPUR FARMERS IN ABJECT POVERTY: 200 acres of land remain inundated since 2016</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/chandpur-farmers-in-abject-poverty-200-acres-of-land-remain-inundated-since-2016</link><description>CHANDPUR, Dec 01: More than a hundred marginal farmers of Hajiganj Upazila's Badarpur remain in acute poverty as they are unable to utilise 200 acres of their farmland since 2016 due to waterlogging.
Water could not be drained from their land as a culvert under a village road was blocked with soil</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 05:15:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Samsung unveils first multi-folding phone as competition set to heat up</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/samsung-unveils-first-multi-folding-phone-as-competition-set-to-heat-up</link><description>Samsung Electronics unveiled on Tuesday its first multi-folding smartphone, in a bid to strengthen its position in a sector of the phone market where competition is expected to intensify.
The launch of the Galaxy Z TriFold marks Samsung's bid to reinforce its footing in a segment where Chinese riv</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 05:30:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India rice imports suspended at Hili Land Port</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/india-rice-imports-suspended-at-hili-land-port</link><description>Rice imports from India have been suspended at Dinajpur’s Hili Land Port. Other goods are, however, being imported and exported as usual.
The land port stopped importing rice completely on Monday, reports bdnews24.com.
Over the past four months, 234,270 tonnes of rice have been imported thr</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 05:45:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UN chief proposes 18pc job cuts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/un-chief-proposes-slashing-2026-budget-by-577-million-cutting-18pc-of-jobs</link><description>United Nations Secretary-General Antonio Guterres on Monday formally proposed slashing the core UN budget for next year by $577 million and cutting more than 18 per cent of jobs.
Guterres is seeking ways to improve efficiency and cut costs as the world body turns 80 this year amid a cash crisis, d</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 06:00:46 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>