<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 15:16:51 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Trump officials weigh possible Kim Jong Un meeting during Asia trip, CNN reports</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-officials-weigh-possible-kim-jong-un-meeting-during-asia-trip-cnn-reports</link><description>Trump administration officials are privately discussing a potential meeting between Donald Trump and North Korean leader Kim Jong Un during the US president's upcoming Asia visit, CNN reported on Saturday, citing sources familiar with the matter.
Officials have not begun logistical arrangements or</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 12:31:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Recent fire incidents highlight safety challenges in Bangladesh: Experts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/recent-fire-incidents-highlight-safety-challenges-in-bangladesh-experts</link><description>Three major fire incidents in Dhaka and the port city of Chattogram have raised serious concerns over Bangladesh’s safety standards and emergency preparedness, experts said.
The latest incident occurred at Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport, leading to the suspension of flight operations</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 13:01:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fire at Dhaka airport started in ‘courier section’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fire-at-dhaka-airport-started-in-courier-section</link><description>An official of the Dhaka Customs Agents Association has said the fire at Shahjalal International Airport broke out in the section of the Cargo Village where courier operations are carried out.
According to the association’s vice president, Khairul Alam Bhuiyan Mithu, the Cargo Village had be</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 13:16:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>HSIA cargo village fire under control partially</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hsia-cargo-village-fire-under-control-partially</link><description>The fire that broke out at the Cargo Village of Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport (HSIA) in Dhaka was brought under control partially, with the blaze remaining confined to the cargo area, officials said on Saturday evening.
Confirming the development, the airport’s Executive Director&amp;rs</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 13:46:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>25 Ansar members injured in Dhaka airport fire</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/25-ansar-members-injured-in-dhaka-airport-fire</link><description>At least 25 members of the Ansar force have been injured in the fire that erupted at the import cargo complex of Dhaka’s Shahjalal International Airport.
The injured were taken to the Combined Military Hospital (CMH) and Kurmitola General Hospital, said Ansar’s North Zone Commander Md</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 14:01:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Airport fire damages imported goods worth millions</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/airport-fire-damages-imported-goods-worth-millions</link><description>A catastrophic fire ripped through the imported goods section of the cargo village at Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport on Saturday afternoon, causing extensive damage worth millions and forcing the suspension of flight operations at the country's busiest airport.
The blaze, which broke out a</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 14:16:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>All-out efforts underway to resume flight operations at HSIA: Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/all-out-efforts-underway-to-resume-flight-operations-at-hsia-adviser</link><description>Civil Aviation and Tourism Adviser Sheikh Bashir Uddin this evening visited the site of the fire that broke out at the Cargo Village of Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport (HSIA) in Dhaka, assuring that all-out efforts are underway to resume flight operations as soon as possible.
“We will</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 14:31:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Security services investigate each fire incident thoroughly: CA Press Wing</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/security-services-investigate-each-fire-incident-thoroughly-ca-press-wing</link><description>The government, in a statement on Saturday, said that the security services are investigating each fire incident thoroughly and protecting lives and property with utmost vigilance.
"The Interim Government is aware of public concern regarding some major fires in several locations across the country</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 15:01:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique Rahman expresses concern over HSIA fire incident</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-rahman-expresses-concern-over-hsia-fire-incident</link><description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman on Saturday expressed concern over the incident of fire at the Cargo Village of Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport (HSIA) in the city.
In his verified Facebook page, Tarique Rahman said, "I am deeply concerned at the fire that broke out at the Cargo Village o</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 15:16:51 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>