<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 09:46:20 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Md Sanaullah Shahid elected chairman of exec committee of Shahjalal Islami Bank</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/md-sanaullah-shahid-elected-chairman-of-exec-committee-of-shahjalal-islami-bank</link><description>Md Sanaullah Shahid has been elected chairman of the executive committee of Shahjalal Islami Bank PLC at the bank’s 404th meeting of the board of directors.

At the same meeting, Mr. Khandaker Sakib Ahmed elected as vice-chairman of Executive Committee of the bank.
Mr Sanaullah was born in</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 06:56:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Election code violations lead to 176 cases, over Tk 1.8m in fines</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/election-code-violations-lead-to-176-cases-over-tk-18m-in-fines</link><description>Field-level officials of the Election Commission (EC) have lodged 176 cases and imposed fines totalling Tk 1.83 million for violations of the electoral code of conduct in the run-up to the parliamentary polls.
The figures were shared on Tuesday by Md Saiful Islam, member secretary of the central c</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 07:36:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fireworks, lanterns banned in Dhaka ahead of Shab-e-Barat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fireworks-lanterns-banned-in-dhaka-ahead-of-shab-e-barat</link><description>The Dhaka Metropolitan Police (DMP) has imposed a temporary ban on fireworks, lanterns and explosives in the capital to ensure peaceful observance of the holy Shab-e-Barat.
According to a notice issued by DMP Commissioner SM Sazzat Alid, all types of fireworks, bursting of crackers, flying lantern</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 07:51:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Diploma engineers’ blockade halts Dhaka’s rail links with Mymensingh, Rajshahi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/diploma-engineers-blockade-halts-dhakas-rail-links-with-mymensingh-rajshahi</link><description>Diploma engineers and diploma students blocked railway tracks in Gazipur on Monday to protest the 33 percent quota for BSc engineers in the recruitment of sub-assistant engineers and to press their five-point demand.
The protesters blocked the railway tracks at Bhurulia in the city, halting train</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 08:06:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hajj pilgrims' visa applications to begin Sunday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hajj-pilgrims-visa-applications-to-begin-sunday</link><description>Registered Hajj pilgrims under both government and private initiatives will be able to apply for visas from Sunday (February 8) through the Saudi Nusuk Masar system, with the process continuing until March 20.
A recent press release signed by Mohammad Safiuzzaman Bhuiya, Deputy Secretary of the Ha</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 08:21:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>RAB to be renamed as SIF</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rab-to-be-renamed-as-sif</link><description>The government has decided to rename the Rapid Action Battalion (RAB) as Special Intervention Force (SIF).
 
Home Affairs Adviser Lt Gen (retd) Jahangir Alam Chowdhury announced the decision on Tuesday following a meeting of the law-and-order core committee at the Bangladesh Secretariat.
RA</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 08:08:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No more unfair elections in Bangladesh: Jamaat Ameer</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/no-more-unfair-elections-in-bangladesh-jamaat-ameer</link><description>Jamaat-e-Islami Ameer Dr Shafiqur Rahman on Tuesday warned that unfair elections would no longer be tolerated in Bangladesh and that any attempt to follow such paths would be resisted.
“There will be no more elections through backdoor means, nor will such elections be allowed. All backdoor p</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 08:23:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Polls: BTV set to air party chiefs' addresses</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/polls-btv-set-to-air-party-chiefs-addresses</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has taken steps to resume the tradition of broadcasting speeches by heads of political parties taking part in the parliamentary polls.
Officials are currently drafting a formal letter to Bangladesh Television (BTV) to facilitate the recorded addresses.
While 51 partie</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 08:38:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Election situation better than ever before: Jahangir Alam</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/election-situation-better-than-ever-before-says-adviser-jahangir-alam</link><description>Home Affairs Adviser Lt Gen (retd) Md Jahangir Alam Chowdhury on Tuesday said the overall situation surrounding the national election in Bangladesh is significantly better than in previous elections, despite a few isolated incidents of clashes.
“Two or four incidents are happening, that is t</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 08:53:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Smooth power handover after Feb-12 election: Shafiqul Alam</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/smooth-power-handover-after-feb-12-election-shafiqul-alam</link><description>Chief Adviser’s Press Secretary Shafiqul Alam on Tuesday said Bangladesh is set to witness a credible and inclusive election on February 12, followed by a smooth and orderly transfer of power.
After that, he said there would be a smooth handover of power, reports UNB.
"And I will return to</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 09:08:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladeshi traveller Najmun Nahar receives Global Legacy Award</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/others/bangladeshi-traveller-najmun-nahar-receives-global-legacy-award</link><description>Renowned Bangladeshi world traveler Najmun Nahar has been honored with Global Legacy Award in recognition of her outstanding contribution to elevating Bangladesh’s image on the global stage.
The award was presented by the social and cultural organization Alokkhô for her lifelong dedica</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 09:23:11 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>