<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 15:25:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>TIB holds environment-focused training for judges</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tib-holds-environment-focused-training-for-judges</link><description>Transparency International Bangladesh (TIB) organised a day-long training on Thursday aimed at enhancing judges’ capacity to enforce environmental laws and ensure justice.
The workshop, held at TIB’s Dhanmondi office in consultation with the Supreme Court and supported by the Law Minis</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 13:13:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US admiral leading US troops in Latin America to step down</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-admiral-leading-us-troops-in-latin-america-to-step-down</link><description>The admiral in charge of US military forces in Latin America will retire two years early on Friday, amid rising tensions with Venezuela that include Wednesday's seizure of an oil tanker and more than 20 deadly strikes on suspected drug-smuggling boats.
Three US officials and two people familiar wi</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 13:28:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Man admits to ‘killing’ freedom fighter to steal Tk 8,000</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/man-confesses-to-killing-freedom-fighter-wife-in-rangpur-for-tk-8000</link><description>A man has confessed to killing a freedom fighter and his wife in Rangpur’s Taraganj after planning to steal money from their home to repay a debt of around Tk 8,000, police say.
Rangpur Superintendent of Police Marufat Hossain shared the information during a media briefing on Friday after th</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 13:43:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fakhrul sees Hadi shooting as ‘plot to derail election'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fakhrul-sees-hadi-shooting-as-plot-to-derail-election</link><description>BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir has described the shooting of Sharif Osman bin Hadi, a potential independent contender for Dhaka-8 and convenor of the Inquilab Mancha platform, as “a conspiracy to derail the general election”.
On Friday afternoon, during a discussion</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 13:58:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC reinstates 4 seats in Bagerhat, 5 seats in Gazipur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-reinstates-4-seats-in-bagerhat-5-seats-in-gazipur</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has reinstated four parliamentary seats in Bagerhat and five in Gazipur following an Appellate Division order, ahead of the 13th parliamentary election and the referendum on the July National Charter (Constitutional Reform) Implementation Order 2025, both scheduled for</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 14:13:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique Rahman to file his nomination in person for Feb 12 polls: Amir Khosru</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-rahman-to-file-his-nomination-in-person-for-feb-12-polls-amir-khosru</link><description>BNP Standing Committee member Amir Khosru Mahmud Chowdhury has said Tarique Rahman will soon return to file his nomination in person for the Feb 12 parliamentary election.
After a meeting with his party leaders in Chattogram amid speculations over the return of Tarique, Khosru told reporters the a</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 13:49:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Osman Hadi is being taken to Evercare from DMCH</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/osman-hadi-is-being-taken-to-evercare-from-dmch</link><description>Sharif Osman bin Hadi, convenor of Inquilab Mancha and a potential independent candidate for Dhaka-8, is being transferred from Dhaka Medical College Hospital (DMCH) to Evercare Hospital following a gunshot wound to the head.
On Friday evening, an ambulance carrying Hadi departed for the private h</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 14:04:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Malaysia jails Bangladeshi for 10 years over IS links</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladeshi-man-in-malaysia-gets-10-year-jail-sentence-for-supporting-is</link><description>The Malaysian High Court has sentenced a Bangladeshi man to 10 years in prison after he admitted to supporting the militant group Islamic State (IS) on Facebook, according to a report by Free Malaysia Today.
Justice Azhar Abdul Hamid delivered the verdict on Friday.
The sentence for the 29-year-o</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 14:19:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Election 2026: EC clarifies what would disqualify MP aspirants</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/election-2026-ec-clarifies-what-would-disqualify-mp-aspirants</link><description>The Election Commission has clarified the provisions related to qualifications and disqualification for an MP aspirant ahead of the upcoming national election scheduled to be held on February 12 next.
The commission, in the election circular-1 issued following the announcement of election schedule</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 14:34:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DUCSU sets 24-hour deadline for arrest of Hadi’s assailants</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ducsu-sets-24-hour-deadline-for-arrest-of-hadis-assailants</link><description>Dhaka University Central Students’ Union (DUCSU) leaders have given the government 24 hours to arrest the attackers of Sharif Osman bin Hadi.
The convenor of Inquilab Mancha and a potential independent candidate for Dhaka-8 remains in critical condition after being shot.
The leaders threate</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 14:49:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Metro rail services resume</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/metro-rail-services-resume</link><description>Metro rail services resumed on Friday night following a five-hour suspension due to a strike called by officers and employees of Dhaka Mass Transit Company Limited (DMTCL).
The DMTCL gave the information after the resumption of the service from Uttara North station at 8:15 pm, according to local n</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 15:04:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hadi shifted to Evercare Hospital after surgery</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hadi-shifted-to-evercare-hospital-after-surgery</link><description>Sharif Osman Hadi, the independent candidate for Dhaka-8 and spokesperson of Inqilab Mancha who was wounded in a gun attack, has been moved from Dhaka Medical College Hospital (DMCH) to Evercare Hospital.
About Osman Hadi’s latest physical condition, Dhaka Medical College Hospital Director B</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 15:19:47 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>