<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 09:24:40 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Ronaldo shown first red card for Portugal in 22 years</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/football/ronaldo-shown-first-red-card-for-portugal-in-22-years</link><description>Portugal's long-time talisman Cristiano Ronaldo was asked to walk off after he was shown a red card for elbowing Ireland defender Dara O'Shea in the second half of the FIFA World Cup 2026 qualifier on Thursday night.
As a result of this, the 40-year-old is now in some serious danger of being banne</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 04:16:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pickup van torched in Dhaka’s Ashulia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/pickup-van-torched-in-dhakas-ashulia</link><description>A pickup van parked on the side of the road in Dhaka’s Ashulia has been set on fire.
The incident occurred in front of Modular Garments in Ashulia’s Sarkar Market area around 5:00 am on Friday, according to Abu Sayem Masum, senior station officer of the Zirabo Modern Fire Service.
No</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 04:31:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US approves potential $330m military sale to Taiwan, first under Trump</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-approves-potential-330-million-military-sale-to-taiwan-first-under-trump</link><description>The US approved the possible sale to Taiwan of fighter jet spare and repair parts for $330 million, the Pentagon said late on Thursday, marking the first such potential transaction since President Donald Trump took office in January.
"The proposed sale will improve the recipient's capability to me</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 04:46:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DU chemistry professor accused of sexually harassing male students</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/du-chemistry-professor-accused-of-sexually-harassing-male-students</link><description>Students of Dhaka University’s Chemistry Department have accused Professor Md Ershad Halim of sexually harassing several male students.
The allegations were raised at a press conference held on Thursday night at the Dhaka University Journalists’ Association (DUJA) office, where student</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 05:01:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BBC apologises to Trump over speech edit but rejects defamation claim</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/bbc-apologises-to-trump-over-speech-edit-but-rejects-defamation-claim</link><description>The British Broadcasting Corporation sent a personal apology to US President Donald Trump on Thursday but said there was no legal basis for him to sue the public broadcaster over a documentary his lawyers called defamatory.
The documentary, which aired on the BBC's "Panorama" news programme just b</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 06:12:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Türkiye bans 102 footballers over betting scandal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/football/turkiye-bans-102-footballers-over-betting-scandal</link><description>Türkiye's football authorities have handed temporary bans to 102 professional players as part of a widening investigation into illegal betting activities.
The Professional Football Disciplinary Board of the Turkish Football Federation (TFF) on Thursday suspended 25 players from the Super Lig</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 06:27:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Unemployment emerging as major concern for Bangladesh: Apex MD</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/unemployment-emerging-as-key-challenge-for-bangladesh-apex-footwear-md</link><description>Unemployment is emerging as a serious concern for Bangladesh, warned Syed Nasim Manzur, Managing Director of Apex Footwear Limited.
He made the observation during his presentation at the Industry Talk session of the International Conference on Economics, Business and Technology Management (ICEBTM</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 07:00:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Road crashes leave four dead in Magura</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/road-crashes-leave-four-dead-in-magura</link><description>Four people, including a woman, were killed in three separate road accidents in Magura district on Thursday.
The deceased were identified as Saiful Islam Tamim, 18, Shanto Pratim Mondal, 18, Sagor Ahmed, 32, and Rina Khatun. Details about Sagor Ahmed and Rina Khatun could not be immediately confir</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 07:15:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Polls to be inclusive, but AL can’t take part: Prof Yunus tells UK</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/polls-to-be-inclusive-participatory-al-wont-be-able-to-take-part-prof-yunus-tells-uk</link><description>Chief Adviser Prof Muhammad Yunus has reaffirmed his government’s commitment to ensuring that the upcoming general election will be free, fair, and inclusive.
“The election will be participatory. There will be a big turnout,” he said, adding that tens of millions of young people</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 07:30:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Suriname and Curaçao edge closer to historic World Cup qualification</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/suriname-and-curacao-edge-closer-to-historic-world-cup-qualification</link><description>Richonell Margaret scored twice in two-minute span in the second half on Thursday as Suriname defeated El Salvador 4-0 in CONCACAF qualifying to move closer to securing a spot in the World Cup for the first time.
Tjaronn Cherry opened the scoring with a penalty kick in the 44th minute and Richonel</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 08:00:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bowlers topple Ireland as Bangladesh win Sylhet Test by an innings and 47 runs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/bowlers-topple-ireland-as-bangladesh-win-sylhet-test-by-an-innings-and-47-runs</link><description>Bangladesh have outplayed Ireland with both bat and ball to deliver a comprehensive win by an innings and 47 runs in the Sylhet Test.
After declaring at 587/8 on Thursday, with a 301-run lead, the Tigers bowling attack tore into the visitors, leaving them teetering at 86/5.
The Irish batsmen show</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 08:15:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Kitchen Market: Onion prices still high, hilsa out of reach</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/kitchen-market-onion-prices-still-high-hilsa-out-of-reach</link><description>Onion prices in the capital's retail markets have remained almost unchanged for a week, still selling at Tk 110-115 per kg, while hilsa has become increasingly unaffordable, with prices rising by up to Tk 500 per kg in just seven days.
A visit to several wholesale and retail markets in on Friday s</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 08:30:45 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>