<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 16:27:49 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>DIG Ehsanullah ‘missing’ from Sardah Police Academy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dig-ehsanullah-mysteriously-absent-from-police-academy-in-rajshahi</link><description>Deputy Inspector General of Police AKM Ehsanullah has gone missing from the Bangladesh Police Academy in Sardah, Rajshahi, in what police sources described as a “mysterious disappearance”.
Though he had been absent for two days, the matter came to light on Friday.
Superintendent Saifu</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 13:28:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Drafting crisis: Vessel stranded in Padma for eight days</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/drafting-crisis-vessel-stranded-in-padma-for-eight-days</link><description>A fertiliser-carrying cargo vessel has been stranded for eight days in the Padma River near the Harirampur point of Manikganj due to a navigability crisis.
The vessel MV Ambu Halima-4, which departed from Chattogram port carrying fertiliser for Pabna’s Nagarbari, has been stuck about 2km fro</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 13:58:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh, Algeria eye major energy deal and direct flights</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-algeria-eye-major-energy-deal-and-direct-flights</link><description>Bangladesh and Algeria are moving closer to sealing a major cooperation agreement in the energy sector, a step that could deepen economic ties between the two nations, according to Algerian Ambassador to Bangladesh Dr Abdelouahab Saidani.
In an exclusive interview with The Financial Express, Dr Sa</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 14:28:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tanzid 89 as Tigers post 151</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/tanzids-fluent-89-helps-bangladesh-post-151-against-west-indies-in-third-t20</link><description>Tanzid Hasan’s sparkling 89 off 62 balls anchored Bangladesh as they posted 151 for the West Indies in the third T20.
Apart from Tanzid’s fluency and Saif Hassan’s 23, the Tigers’ batting struggled once again, with no other player reaching double figures at the Bir Sreshtho</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 14:43:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sirajganj man stabbed, beaten to death by mob over alleged cattle theft</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/sirajganj-man-stabbed-beaten-to-death-by-mob-over-alleged-cattle-theft</link><description>A 60-year-old man was killed in a mob attack in Sirajganj on Thursday night after being accused of attempting to steal a cow.
The incident took place in Muktargati village of Sirajganj Sadar upazila.
The deceased was identified as Sanowar Hossain Sanu, son of Md. Badullah Sheikh of Alampur villag</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 14:59:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Russia uses missile in Ukraine that led Trump to quit nuclear treaty, Kyiv says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/russia-uses-missile-in-ukraine-that-led-trump-to-quit-nuclear-treaty-kyiv-says</link><description>Russia has in recent months attacked Ukraine with a cruise missile whose secret development prompted Donald Trump to abandon a nuclear arms control pact with Moscow in his first term as U.S. president, Ukraine’s foreign minister said.
Andrii Sybiha’s comments are the first confirmation</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 15:14:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Woman ‘commits suicide’ under loan pressure in Demra</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/woman-commits-suicide-under-loan-pressure-in-demra</link><description>A 50-year-old woman allegedly took her own life in Demra, Dhaka, after facing pressure and humiliation from lenders, on Friday.
The incident occurred around noon on Friday at a rented house in Demra.
She was taken unconscious to Dhaka Medical College Hospital, where the duty doctor at the emergen</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 15:29:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US lawmakers want response after Sudan ‘horrors’ by paramilitaries</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-lawmakers-want-response-after-sudan-horrors-by-paramilitaries</link><description>Republican and Democratic US senators called for a strong response from President Donald Trump’s administration after the paramilitary Rapid Support Forces seized new territory in Sudan, reportedly attacking civilians.
Republican Senator Jim Risch of Idaho, chairman of the Senate Foreign Rel</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 15:59:27 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>