<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 15:49:43 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>National Bank launches remittance operations with dLocal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/national-bank-launches-remittance-operations-with-dlocal</link><description>National Bank PLC, one of Bangladesh’s leading remittance procuring banks, has launched Remittance operations with dLocal Limited, a globally recognized Electronic Money Institution (EMI) based in Malta.
According to a press release, this launching aims to strengthen cross-border remittance</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 12:35:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump renews attack on US Supreme Court, vows other tariffs, licenses</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-renews-attack-on-us-supreme-court-vows-other-tariffs-licenses</link><description>President Donald Trump renewed his condemnation of the US Supreme Court on Monday after it ruled against his sweeping tariff program last week, vowing to turn to other tariff powers and licenses but giving no details.
"The court has also approved all other Tariffs, of which there are many, and the</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 12:50:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt warns of disciplinary action over irregular office attendance</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-warns-of-disciplinary-action-over-irregular-office-attendance</link><description>The Ministry of Law has taken a strict stance against irregularities in office attendance, warning officials and employees of disciplinary action for late arrival, unauthorised absence, or leaving office early without permission.
In an office order issued on Monday, the Law and Justice Division of</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 13:05:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Modhumoti Bank celebrates milestone of achieving Tk 100.00 billion in deposits</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/modhumoti-bank-celebrates-milestone-of-achieving-tk-10000-billion-in-deposits</link><description>Modhumoti Bank PLC has achieved the milestone of Tk 100.00 billion in deposits, according to a press release.
This success was celebrated through an informal ceremony held at the bank’s Head Office on Sunday.
The event was attended by Mr. Md. ShafiulAzam, Managing Director &amp; CEO of the bank</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 13:20:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Midland Bank launches MDB Digital Nano Loan for existing MDB customers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/midland-bank-launches-mdb-digital-nano-loan-for-existing-mdb-customers</link><description>Midland Bank PLC (MDB) launched “MDB Digital Nano Loan” for all existing customers, marking a significant step in its digital banking journey.
According to a press release, the initiative aligns with Bangladesh Bank’s directive under BRPD Circular No. 11 dated June 02, 2022, whic</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 13:35:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Islami Bank holds board meeting on Monday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/islami-bank-holds-board-meeting-on-monday</link><description>A meeting of the board of directors of Islami Bank Bangladesh PLC was held on Monday at the Islami Bank Tower, according to a press release.
Professor Dr. M. Zubaidur Rahman, chairman of the bank, presided over the meeting. Mohammad Khurshid Wahab, chairman of the executive committee, Professor Dr</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 13:50:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘TARA Uddokta Mela 2026’ to showcase all-women entrepreneur products</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/tara-uddokta-mela-2026-to-showcase-all-women-entrepreneur-products</link><description>BRAC Bank is hosting ‘TARA Uddokta Mela 2026’, a three-day fair, to promote locally made products by women entrepreneurs and create a market for these products, according to a press release.
The fair will take place from February 27 to March 1, 2026, every day from 10:00am to 11:00pm d</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 14:05:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Amar Ekushey Book Fair 2026 set to begin on February 26</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/amar-ekushey-book-fair-2026-set-to-begin-on-february-26</link><description>The Amar Ekushey Book Fair 2026 has been postponed by a day and will now commence on February 26 instead of the earlier scheduled February 25.
The date is rescheduled for the second time as it was scheduled on February 20 earlier.
The inauguration ceremony will be held at Rabindra Chattar, Bangla</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 14:20:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ishraque to contest election for mayor of Dhaka South</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ishraque-to-contest-election-for-mayor-of-dhaka-south</link><description>State Minister for Liberation War Affairs and Dhaka-6 MP Ishraque Hossain has announced that he will contest the mayoral election of Dhaka South City Corporation.
“I will contest the city election from Dhaka South, InshaAllah,” he wrote in a brief Facebook post on Monday.
Ishraque was</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 14:36:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Three secretaries transferred to public administration ministry</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/three-secretaries-transferred-to-public-administration-ministry</link><description>The government has transferred three secretaries to the Ministry of Public Administration.
A notification on Monday announced the administrative reshuffle.
The transferred officers are Secondary and Higher Education Secretary Rehana Perven, Religious Affairs Secretary Kamal Uddin and Prime Minist</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 14:51:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ctg blast victim dies on way to Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/woman-dies-on-way-to-dhaka-after-suffering-burns-in-chattogram-blast</link><description>A woman who suffered burns in a gas explosion at a Chattogram Halishahar flat has died on the way to Dhaka.
The victim, 40-year-old Nurjahan Akter Rani, had suffered 100 percent burns, doctors said.
On Monday evening, nine burn victims were transferred from Chattogram Medical College Hospital to</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 15:06:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>President accepts resignations of HC judges Mamnoon Rahman, Naima Haider</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/president-accepts-resignations-of-hc-judges-mamnoon-rahman-naima-haider</link><description>President Mohammed Shahabuddin has accepted the resignations of two judges of the High Court Division of the Supreme Court, according to separate notifications issued by the Ministry of Law on Monday.
The notifications said that Justice Mamnoon Rahman and Justice Naima Haider submitted their signe</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 15:21:47 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>