<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 12:48:59 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Malaysian floods affect 11,000 people across seven states</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/malaysian-floods-affect-11000-people-across-seven-states</link><description>More than 11,000 people in seven Malaysian states have been affected by flooding caused by torrential rain, the national disaster agency said on Monday.
Floods are common on the eastern coast of Malaysia during the annual monsoon season from October until March, with thousands of people displaced</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 10:49:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tk 109.79b refined fuel oil import gets govt nod</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/tk-10979b-refined-fuel-oil-import-gets-govt-nod</link><description>The Advisers Council Committee on Government Purchase on Monday approved a major proposal involving Tk 109.79 billion (Tk 10,979 crore) for the import of refined fuel oil for January–June, 2026 period.
The approval came from a meeting of Advisers Council Committee on Government Purchase at t</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 09:21:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt okays procurement of 50,000mt non-Basmati par-boiled rice</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/govt-okays-procurement-of-50000mt-non-basmati-par-boiled-rice</link><description>The government on Monday approved the procurement of 50,000 metric tonnes of non-Basmati par-boiled rice.
The approval came from a meeting of the Advisers Council Committee on Government Purchase held at the Cabinet Division Conference Room at the Secretariat with Finance Adviser Dr Salehuddin Ahm</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 09:36:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Court seizes plots of NASSA Group chairman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/court-seizes-plots-of-nassa-group-chairman</link><description>A Dhaka court on Monday ordered to seize a 39-katha plot in Gulshan and 14-bigha plot in Sonargaon, owned by NASSA Group chairman Nazrul Islam Mazumder.
Judge Md Sabbir Faiz of Dhaka Metropolitan Senior Judge Court passed the order, allowing a plea of the Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC), reports</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 09:51:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Norway's wealth tax trades millionaires for equality</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/norways-wealth-tax-trades-millionaires-for-equality</link><description>Sitting in his lakeside villa in the Swiss city of Lucerne, Borger Borgenhaug misses his grandchildren and the smell of the Nordic sea on a clear summer night.
The carpenter turned real-estate tycoon says that is the price he pays to escape Norway's beefed-up wealth tax – an annual lev</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 10:06:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mirza Fakhrul calls out partisan journalism</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/mirza-fakhrul-calls-out-partisan-journalism</link><description>Senior BNP leader Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir has urged journalists to stick to their professional ethics and refrain from aligning with political parties to fulfil their professional commitment to the people.
Speaking at a discussion on media reform at the Bangladesh-China Friendship Conference C</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 10:21:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Voter registration for Bangladeshis in 16 countries begins</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/voter-registration-for-bangladeshis-in-16-countries-begins</link><description>Voter registration for Bangladeshi expatriates living in 16 countries including the United States, Canada and Australia, began on Monday.
Registration can be completed through the “Postal Vote BD” mobile app.
The process will continue until November 28, said a PID handout, reports UNB</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 10:36:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>G20 declaration in defiance of US marks rare victory for multilateralism</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/g20-declaration-in-defiance-of-us-marks-rare-victory-for-multilateralism</link><description>Born of crisis but torn by years of tensions among its members, the Group of 20 major economies scored a rare victory this weekend for multilateralism after overcoming the boycott and objections of its most powerful member, the United States.
South Africa, this year's G20 president, rallied all bu</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 10:51:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Only 3,252 out of 21 lakh buildings assessed for earthquake safety: RAJUK</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/only-3252-out-of-21-lakh-buildings-in-dhaka-gazipur-assessed-for-earthquake-safety-rajuk</link><description>Rajdhani Unnayn Kartipakkha (RAJUK) has assessed the earthquake resilience and risk of only 3,252 structures among 21 lakh buildings in Dhaka and Gazipur so far.
RAJUK Executive Engineer Khandaker Md Wahid Sadiq shared the information on Monday at a views-exchange meeting titled "Preparedness and</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 11:06:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dengue: 2 more dead, 705 hospitalised in 24 hours</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dengue-2-more-dead-705-hospitalised-in-24-hours</link><description>Two more dengue-related deaths were reported in the 24 hours till Monday morning, raising this year’s death toll from the mosquito-borne disease in Bangladesh to 366, according to the Directorate General of Health Services (DGHS).
In the same period, 705 new dengue patients were admitted to</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 11:21:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New AI club to bestow nuclear-like power, says Russian tech boss</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/new-ai-club-to-bestow-nuclear-like-power-says-russian-tech-boss</link><description>Artificial intelligence will bestow influence on a par with nuclear technology to countries able to get ahead now, a top Russian AI executive said, giving them superiority this century.
Alexander Vedyakhin, first deputy CEO of Sberbank, which is evolving from a major lender into an AI-focused tech</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 11:36:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt approves re-fixed tariff for seven power plants</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-approves-re-fixed-tariff-for-seven-power-plants</link><description>The government on Monday approved a re-fixed levelized power tariff for seven power plants to ensure their sustainable operations.
The approval came from the 47th meeting of the Advisers Council Committee on Government Purchase in this year held at the Cabinet Division Conference Room at Banglades</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 11:51:28 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>