<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 12:45:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>IPDC provides free eye check-up and spectacles for support staff</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ipdc-provides-free-eye-check-up-and-spectacles-for-support-staff</link><description>IPDC Finance PLC. successfully completed a free eye check-up campaign as part of its recently concluded Wellness Week.
Based on the assessment of the check-up, 17 support staff received free spectacles, according to a media release.  
During the campaign, all employees and support staff</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 11:19:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka Bank signs strategic partnership with Rangs Limited</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/dhaka-bank-signs-strategic-partnership-with-rangs-limited</link><description>Dhaka Bank PLC has signed a strategic partnership with RANGS Limited, the official distributor of Mitsubishi Motors in Bangladesh, through a Memorandum of Understanding (MoU).
The MoU was signed by Mr. H.M. Mostafizur Rahaman, SEVP &amp; Head of Retail Business Division, Dhaka Bank PLC, and Mr. Mohamm</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 09:51:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Misinformation big threat to democracy: Shafiqul Alam</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/misinformation-big-threat-to-democracy-shafiqul-alam</link><description>Chief Adviser's Press Secretary Shafiqul Alam has warned that the future of democracy could be in jeopardy if the incoming government fails to effectively combat misinformation and disinformation.
"The government that will run the country should brainstorm about tackling misinformation. Otherwise,</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 10:06:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A slice of school life that stays forever</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/others/a-slice-of-school-life-that-stays-forever</link><description>It always began with the bell. The piercing metallic noise broke the morning cacophony of lectures and classes. For a few seconds, everything stayed still. Then the benches moved, shoes tapped the floor, and students rushed out of the classroom. Some ran to the field, some to the corridors, clutchi</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 10:21:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BGB thrashes false social media post on occupying borderland by India</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bgb-thrashes-false-social-media-post-on-occupying-borderland-by-india</link><description>Border Guard Bangladesh (BGB) has condemned a false and malicious rumour circulating on the social media, titled “India occupies 62 kilometres in Lalmonirhat,” calling it a deliberate attempt to mislead the public and undermine the national security.
In a statement, the BGB clarified t</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 10:36:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BEPZA seals $111m deals for Mirsarai industries; 7,600 jobs expected</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bepza-seals-111m-deals-for-mirsarai-industries-7600-jobs-expected</link><description>Bangladesh Export Processing Zones Authority (BEPZA) has signed agreements with four companies to set up industries at the BEPZA Economic Zone in Mirsarai, Chattogram, involving a total investment of US$111.26 million and creating employment for 7,607 Bangladeshis.
The agreements were signed on Th</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 10:51:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Martyrs’ families demand legal basis for July Charter before election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/martyrs-families-demand-legal-basis-for-july-charter-before-election</link><description>Members of families of those killed and injured during the July Uprising have demanded the July National Charter be given a legal basis before the general election.
They questioned, since the revolution did not adhere to the Constitution, why is the Charter's implementation being delayed “by</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 11:06:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Afghanistan and Pakistan return to Istanbul for more peace talks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/afghanistan-and-pakistan-return-to-istanbul-for-more-peace-talks</link><description>Afghanistan and Pakistan will resume peace talks in Istanbul on Thursday, both nations said, after a previous round ended without agreeing on a lasting truce.
Militaries from the South Asian neighbours clashed last month, with dozens killed in the worst such violence since the Taliban returned to</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 11:21:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat, allies submit memo to CA, warn of ‘Different Dhaka’ on Nov 11</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-allies-submit-memo-to-ca-warn-of-different-dhaka-on-nov-11</link><description>Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami, along with seven other political parties, on Thursday submitted a five-point memorandum to Chief Adviser Dr Muhammad Yunus, urging the implementation of the July Charter and calling for a national referendum ahead of the next general election scheduled for February.
A j</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 11:36:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Police couple sentenced to death in Mymensingh for murder of co-worker over affair</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/police-couple-sentenced-to-death-in-mymensingh-for-murder-of-co-worker-over-affair</link><description>A Mymensingh court has sentenced both members of a police couple to death for the murder of a fellow policeman over an extramarital affair.
After a lengthy investigation and trial, Additional Sessions Judge Court Judge Harun-or Rashid delivered the verdict in the sensational murder case on Wedne</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 12:06:23 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>