<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 15:22:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>20 cops injured as bus loses control inside CMP headquarters</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/20-cops-injured-as-bus-loses-control-inside-cmp-headquarters</link><description>At least 20 policemen, including female members of the force, were injured when a bus carrying the law enforcers lost control inside Chattogram Metropolitan Police (CMP) headquarters in the Dampara area on Friday afternoon.
The police team was on its way to Bir Sreshtho Shaheed Flight Lt Matiur Ra</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 12:46:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh takes part in first-ever UN session on biodiversity convention</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/bangladesh-takes-part-in-first-ever-un-session-on-biodiversity-convention</link><description>Bangladesh participated in the first-ever meeting of the Subsidiary Body on Article 8(j) and Related Provisions (SB8j-1) under the UN Convention on Biological Diversity (CBD), held from October 27 to 30 in Panama City.
The meeting marked a historic step to formally recognise the rights of Indigeno</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 13:01:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IU suspends 19 teachers, 11 officials, expels 33 students over alleged anti-uprising role</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/iu-suspends-19-teachers-11-officials-expels-33-students-over-alleged-anti-uprising-role</link><description>The authorities of Islamic University (IU) in Kushtia have decided to suspend its 19 teachers, 11 officials, and expel 33 students for their involvement in the last year’s anti-uprising movement that ousted Sheikh Hasina-government. 
Those faced music are suspected to be followers of Aw</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 12:58:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nearly 3,000 people arrested from AL flash rallies in 10 months</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/nearly-3000-people-arrested-from-al-flash-rallies-in-10-months</link><description>Dhaka Metropolitan Police have arrested 46 activists of the Awami League and its affiliated bodies during flash rallies across the city.
According to police, the arrests were made on Friday from different parts of the capital.
With these latest detentions, nearly 3,000 people have been arrested f</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 13:13:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DIG Ehsanullah ‘missing’ from Sardah Police Academy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dig-ehsanullah-mysteriously-absent-from-police-academy-in-rajshahi</link><description>Deputy Inspector General of Police AKM Ehsanullah has gone missing from the Bangladesh Police Academy in Sardah, Rajshahi, in what police sources described as a “mysterious disappearance”.
Though he had been absent for two days, the matter came to light on Friday.
Superintendent Saifu</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 13:28:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Drafting crisis: Vessel stranded in Padma for eight days</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/drafting-crisis-vessel-stranded-in-padma-for-eight-days</link><description>A fertiliser-carrying cargo vessel has been stranded for eight days in the Padma River near the Harirampur point of Manikganj due to a navigability crisis.
The vessel MV Ambu Halima-4, which departed from Chattogram port carrying fertiliser for Pabna’s Nagarbari, has been stuck about 2km fro</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 13:58:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh, Algeria eye major energy deal and direct flights</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-algeria-eye-major-energy-deal-and-direct-flights</link><description>Bangladesh and Algeria are moving closer to sealing a major cooperation agreement in the energy sector, a step that could deepen economic ties between the two nations, according to Algerian Ambassador to Bangladesh Dr Abdelouahab Saidani.
In an exclusive interview with The Financial Express, Dr Sa</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 14:28:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tanzid 89 as Tigers post 151</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/tanzids-fluent-89-helps-bangladesh-post-151-against-west-indies-in-third-t20</link><description>Tanzid Hasan’s sparkling 89 off 62 balls anchored Bangladesh as they posted 151 for the West Indies in the third T20.
Apart from Tanzid’s fluency and Saif Hassan’s 23, the Tigers’ batting struggled once again, with no other player reaching double figures at the Bir Sreshtho</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 14:43:15 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>