<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 06:51:32 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>ACC files case against ex-MP HBM Iqbal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/acc-files-case-against-ex-mp-hbm-iqbal</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) has approved the filing of a case against Dr. HBM Iqbal, a former Bangladesh Awami League lawmaker, and his family on charges of amassing Tk 680 million in wealth from undisclosed sources.
According to ACC findings, Dr. Iqbal, also a former chairman of Premier</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 03:44:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>4 more deaths reported from dengue, 871 hospitalised</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/4-more-deaths-reported-from-dengue-871-hospitalised</link><description>Four more deaths were reported from dengue while 781new patients were hospitalised across the country during the last 24 hours until Thursday morning,
The new deaths were reported in Dhaka South City Corporation (DSCC) and Dhaka North City Corporation (DNCC), according to the Directorate General o</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 03:59:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Court orders freezing three A/Cs of ex-DSCC mayor Taposh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/Court-orders-freezing-three</link><description>A Dhaka Court has ordered the concerned government authorities to freeze three bank accounts owned by former Dhaka South City Corporation (DSCC) Mayor Sheikh Fazle Noor Taposh.
Judge Md Sabbir Faiz of the Metropolitan Senior Special Judge's Court in Dhaka passed the order on Thursday after hearing</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 04:14:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BD's gross forex reserve crosses $27b mark anew</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/bds-gross-forex-reserve-crosses-27b-mark-anew</link><description>The country's gross foreign exchange (forex) reserve in IMF's (International Monetary Fund) arithmetic crossed $27 billion mark on Thursday.
It was the highest figure since Bangladesh stepped into sixth edition of Balance of Payments and International Investment Position Manual, generally known as</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 04:29:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DUCSU, TIKA take Tk 27.5m project to modernise DUMC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ducsu-tika-take-tk-275m-project-to-modernise-dumc</link><description>The Dhaka University Central Students' Union (DUCSU), in collaboration with the Turkish Cooperation and Coordination Agency (TIKA), has taken up a project worth approximately Tk 27.5 million (2.75 crore) to modernise the DU Medical Centre (DUMC).
On Wednesday, a delegation from DUCSU met with TIKA</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 04:44:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jute price tops Tk 4,000 per maund in Rajshahi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jute-price-tops-tk-4000-per-maund-in-rajshahi</link><description>Once known as the 'golden fibre' of Bangladesh, jute seems to be regaining its long-lost glory in Rajshahi. On Thursday, the price of raw jute reached a record high at Tk 4,000 per maund across several local markets - the highest in recent memory.
The sharp rise in price has brought cheer to farme</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 04:59:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>More media licences to be issued: Adviser Mahfuj</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/more-media-licences-to-be-issued-adviser-mahfuj</link><description>Information and Broadcasting Adviser Md Mahfuj Alam on Thursday reiterated plans to issue licences to more media outlets, emphasising that his ministry has not shut down any media during the interim government's tenure.
He made the remarks as the chief guest at a book unveiling and discussion orga</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 05:14:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Students immensely suffer as Manikganj pry school waterlogged</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/students-immensely-suffer-as-manikganj-pry-school-waterlogged</link><description>Students of a primary school in Manikganj face immense sufferings during the time of rain as even a light shower is enough to leave the nearby roads and schoolground waterlogged.
Water run-off from nearby houses fills the area with a foul smell, making the class atmosphere difficult for students a</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 05:29:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Concern mounts among locals as gunshots reverberate near Ukhiya border</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/concern-mounts-among-locals-as-gunshots-reverberate-near-ukhiya-border</link><description>The sound of heavy gunfire has been heard from across the border in Myanmar has unsettled residents in Cox’s Bazar’s Ukhiya and Bandarban’s Ghumdhum.
The gunshots were reported from at least seven villages near the border from 11pm on Thursday.
The residents of Rahmater Bil, Dha</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 05:44:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh working to free photographer Shahidul Alam from Israeli custody by Friday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-working-to-free-photographer-shahidul-alam-from-israeli-custody-by-friday</link><description>Efforts are under way, with Turkey’s assistance, to secure the release of Bangladeshi photographer and activist Shahidul Alam, who was detained by Israeli forces from a Gaza-bound aid flotilla earlier this week, the Chief Advisor's Office (CAO) has revealed.
In a statement issued on Friday m</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 05:59:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Former British PM Sunak joins Microsoft, Anthropic in advisory roles</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/former-british-pm-sunak-joins-microsoft-anthropic-in-advisory-roles</link><description>Former British Prime Minister Rishi Sunak said on Thursday he has joined US tech giant Microsoft and AI startup Anthropic as a senior adviser.
Sunak, who stepped down as the leader of the opposition Conservative Party following a defeat in the general election last July, continues to serve as a me</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 06:14:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>More than 300,000 to sit for special BCS exams on Friday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/more-than-300000-to-sit-for-special-bcs-exams-on-friday</link><description>More than 312,000 candidates are sitting for the written MCQ-based 49th Special Bangladesh Civil Service (BCS) examinations for appointments to 683 teachers’ posts at government colleges.
The exams are to be held from 10am to 12pm on Friday at 184 centres in Dhaka. About 460 students are com</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 06:29:29 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>