<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 11:18:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Seven Bangladeshis arrested in Singapore anti-drug raid</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/seven-bangladeshis-arrested-in-singapore-anti-drug-raid</link><description>Seven Bangladeshi nationals, aged between 20 and 40, were detained from migrant worker dormitories in Singapore for suspected drug-related offences.
Singapore’s Central Narcotics Bureau (CNB) conducted a series of operations at several migrant worker dormitories across the country over the p</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 07:59:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gun attack on Hadi: RAB detain motorbike owner</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/gun-attack-on-hadi-rab-detain-motorbike-owner</link><description>Rapid Action Battalion (RAB) has detained Abdul Hannan, the owner of the motorbike which was used in the gun attack on Inquilab Moncho spokesperson Osman Hadi, from the Mohammadpur area of Dhaka.
Tipped off, a special team of RAB-2 conducted a drive in the area in the early hours of Sunday and det</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 08:14:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two arrested over attack on ‘July Rebels’ activist in Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/two-arrested-over-attack-on-july-rebels-activist-in-dhaka</link><description>Police have arrested two suspects in connection with the attack on 'July Rebels' activist Md Rezaowan.
The arrestees were identified as Md Masum and Md Fahim Khan.
Some unidentified people attacked Rezaowan at Sector 6 of Uttara around 7:30 pm on Saturday, leaving him critically injured, Md Taleb</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 08:29:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>bKash agent’s sales representative shot, Tk 1.5m robbed in Tongi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/bkash-agents-sales-representative-shot-tk-15m-robbed-in-tongi</link><description>A sales representative of a bKash agent has been shot in the chest and robbed of nearly Tk 1.5 million in Tongi.
The victim - Arif, identified by a single name - was shot around 7:15 pm on Saturday in the Anarkali Road area and was taken to Dhaka Medical College Hospital in critical condition, sai</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 08:52:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two killed in Sitakunda truck accident</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/two-killed-in-sitakunda-truck-accident</link><description>Two people were killed, and another was injured after a truck carrying betel leaves veered off the road and crashed in Sitakunda upazila of Chattogram.
The accident occurred in the early hours of Sunday on the Dhaka-Chattogram Highway in the Bashbaria area of the upazila, police said.
The dead we</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 08:59:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UN chief condemns Sudan drone attack that resulted in deaths of Bangladeshi peacekeepers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/un-chief-condemns-sudan-drone-attack-that-resulted-in-deaths-of-bangladeshi-peacekeepers</link><description>UN Secretary General António Guterres has condemned the drone attacks in Sudan that led to the deaths of several Bangladeshi UN peacekeepers.
The UN chief expressed his condolences to the families of the dead and wished those injured a speedy recovery in a post on X, reports bdnews24.com.</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 09:14:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Authorities remove street paintings of Ghulam Azam, others in front of Jagannath Hall</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/authorities-remove-street-paintings-of-ghulam-azam-others-in-front-of-jagannath-hall</link><description>The authorities at Jagannath Hall have erased road paintings of Ghulam Azam, Motiur Rahman Nizami, and Abdul Quader Molla – who were convicted of war crimes - from the streets in front of the dormitory.
The paintings were created to mark Martyred Intellectuals Day, observed across Banglade</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 09:07:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Politicians, bureaucrats failed to learn from July Uprising: Iftekharuzzaman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politicians-bureaucrats-failed-to-learn-from-july-uprising-iftekharuzzaman</link><description>Transparency International Bangladesh (TIB) Executive Director Iftekharuzzaman on Sunday said politicians and bureaucrats have failed to draw lessons from the July 2024 mass uprising.
“Although the interim government formed several task forces, including six major commissions, with the aim o</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 09:22:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Foreign ministry summons Indian High Commissioner over security concerns</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/foreign-ministry-summons-indian-high-commissioner-over-security-concerns</link><description>The Ministry of Foreign Affairs on Sunday summoned Indian High Commissioner Pranay Verma, expressing deep concern over allegations that former prime minister Sheikh Hasina, now staying in India, is inciting terrorist activities in Bangladesh and trying to disrupt the upcoming national election.
Th</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 09:37:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Online news portal sued over ‘fake news’ against Mirza Abbas</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/online-news-portal-sued-over-fake-news-against-mirza-abbas</link><description>An online news portal, Dainik Ajker Kantho, has been accused in a case over publishing “fake news” linking Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) leader Mirza Abbas to the attack on Inqilab Moncho Convenor Sharif Osman bin Hadi.
Mohammad Sadikur Rahman Bhuiyan, a member of the Dhaka Bar As</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 09:52:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>After fleeing fighting, Cambodian woman fears giving birth in border camp</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/after-fleeing-fighting-cambodian-woman-fears-giving-birth-in-border-camp</link><description>At nine months pregnant, 27-year-old Suang Sreang fears she will have to give birth in a rudimentary displacement camp after fleeing fighting between Cambodian and Thai troops along their disputed border.
The Cambodian national is among tens of thousands of civilians on both sides who have fled th</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 10:07:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh summons Indian envoy over Hasina’s statements</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-summons-indian-envoy-over-hasinas-statements</link><description>The Ministry of Foreign Affairs on Sunday summoned the Indian High Commissioner to convey the government of Bangladesh’s serious concern to the government of India over former PM Sheikh Hasina.
The ministry expressed its objection over India allowing fugitive Sheikh Hasina to continue making</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 10:22:33 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>