<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 16:26:18 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Reality of 'interdependence, mutual benefit' to keep driving Dhaka-Delhi ties forward: Verma</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/reality-of-interdependence-mutual-benefit-to-keep-driving-dhaka-delhi-ties-forward-verma</link><description>Reiterating India's support for an inclusive nation, Indian High Commissioner to Bangladesh Pranay Verma on Saturday evening said they are confident that the reality of their 'interdependence and mutual benefit' will continue to keep driving the relationship between Bangladesh and India forward.
"</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 14:26:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EXIM Bank’s special meeting on investment recovery held</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/exim-banks-special-meeting-on-investment-recovery-held</link><description>A special meeting on strengthening investment recovery initiatives held on Saturday at the head office of EXIM Bank with 10 important branches of Dhaka Division.
Administrator of EXIM Bank and Executive Director of Bangladesh Bank Md. Sawkatul Alam attended the program as the Chief Guest, accordin</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 14:41:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat chief claims those who pushed for elections are shifting stance</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-chief-claims-those-who-pushed-for-elections-are-shifting-stance</link><description>Jamaat-e-Islami chief Shafiqur Rahman has claimed that those who demanded elections are now “speaking differently”, reflecting a shift in their stance.
He said some parties initially opposed holding a referendum but later “pressured the government” to organise it on the sam</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 14:56:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Exhumation of 114 unidentified July martyrs to begin at Rayerbazar Graveyard</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/exhumation-of-114-unidentified-july-martyrs-to-begin-at-rayerbazar-graveyard</link><description>The bodies of 114 unidentified martyrs of the July Uprising will be exhumed from Rayerbazar Graveyard in the capital starting Sunday for identification through post-mortem and DNA testing.
"We are preparing for exhumation of bodies of July Martyrs buried in Rayerbazar Graveyard tomorrow following</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 15:11:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt says it facilitates requests for Khaleda Zia’s treatment</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-says-it-facilitates-requests-for-khaleda-zias-treatment</link><description>The interim government on Saturday said it continues to facilitate the requests made by former Prime Minister Begum Khaleda Zia’s family regarding her medical treatment, including matters related to sending her abroad.
Responding to a question on whether the government is assisting with arra</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 15:26:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh Development Bank holds workshop on NPL Management</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladesh-development-bank-holds-workshop-on-npl-management</link><description>Bangladesh Development Bank PLC organised a workshop titled “Non-Performing Loan (NPL) Management” on Thursday, December 04, 2025 in the Board room, according to a press release.
Nazma Mobarek, Secretary of the Financial Institutions Division under the Ministry of Finance, inaugurated</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 14:56:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India ‘always seeks stability’ in Dhaka-Delhi ties: Envoy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/india-always-seeks-stability-in-dhaka-delhi-ties-envoy</link><description>Describing the bond between Bangladesh and India as “eternal”, Indian High Commissioner to Dhaka Pranay Verma said mutual benefit and interdependence will advance the relationship.
He made the remarks at an event organised to mark India-Bangladesh Friendship Day or Maitri Diwas at Guls</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 15:11:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka-Mymensingh rail link restored</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dhaka-mymensingh-rail-link-restored</link><description>Train services between Dhaka and Mymensingh have resumed nearly three hours after the engine of the “Balaka Commuter” train broke down in Gazipur’s Sreepur.
According to Sreepur Railway Station Master Md Shamim, services restarted around 7:15pm on Saturday after a replacement eng</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 15:26:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Energy efficiency is Bangladesh's invisible power plant</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/energy-efficiency-is-bangladeshs-invisible-power-plant</link><description>Every unit of energy saved carries more value than one produced, because imported fuel travels long distances, accumulates technical losses and costs the country twice over. A kilowatt hour conserved at the source prevents the need for two kilowatt-hours of costly generation later. The Internationa</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 15:41:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Traders raise oil price defying govt order</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/traders-raise-oil-price-defying-govt-order</link><description>As the saying goes, old habits die hard. This is particularly true for market manipulators in Bangladesh, who have once again resorted to their familiar tactic of creating artificial crises to drive up the prices of essential commodities such as edible oil and onions.
In a move that reflects braze</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 15:56:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Global scrutiny of agricultural trade</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/global-scrutiny-of-agricultural-trade</link><description>International trade in agricultural products has remained static over the last few years, as reflected in global export trends. The combined share of these products is still less than one-tenth of the international merchandise trade. Nevertheless, the rule on trade in agricultural products has been</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 16:11:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Missed opportunity for police reform</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/missed-opportunity-for-police-reform</link><description>The recently approved Police Commission Ordinance stands as a missed opportunity to reform a critically important institution, with its final version betraying a deliberate unwillingness to loosen the government's control over law enforcement. By stripping away provisions that would have allowed th</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 16:26:18 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>