<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 08:34:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Packaging industry can reach $50b exports: Amir Khasru</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/packaging-industry-can-reach-50b-exports-amir-khasru</link><description>Bangladesh's packaging industry has the potential to reach $50 billion in exports if proper policy support is provided, said BNP Standing Committee member and former commerce minister Amir Khasru Mahmud Chowdhury on Wednesday.
"If the BNP is able to form the next government, adequate policies will</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 05:15:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Zant Accessories Limited to invest Tk 800m in NSEZ in Ctg</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/zant-accessories-limited-to-invest-tk-800m-in-nsez-in-ctg</link><description>Foam manufacturer Zant Accessories Limited is set to invest Tk 800 million in the National Special Economic Zone (NSEZ) in Chattogram.
It will establish a plant on five acres of land to manufacture polyurethane foam, polyethylene foam, recycled foam, mattress, pillow, comforter and shoe insole.</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 05:30:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Iran has 'no plan' to execute protesters: Trump</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/iran-has-no-plan-to-execute-protesters-trump</link><description>US President Donald Trump says Tehran has "no plan" to execute protesters, but still hasn't ruled out US military action against the country over its violent crackdown on anti-government demonstrators.
The US and UK are both reducing the number of personnel at the Al-Udeid air base in Qatar, while</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 05:45:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BD, Nepal map deeper trade, transit ties</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bd-nepal-map-deeper-trade-transit-ties</link><description>The two-day 8th Bangladesh-Nepal commerce secretary level meeting (CSLM) concluded on Wednesday, focusing on deepening trade, transit and connectivity cooperation between the two neighbouring countries amid evolving regional and global trade dynamics.
The meeting reviewed progress since the 7th CS</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 06:00:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Venezuela’s Delcy vows to continue releasing prisoners detained under Maduro</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/venezuelas-acting-president-vows-to-continue-releasing-prisoners-detained-under-maduro</link><description>Venezuela’s acting President Delcy Rodríguez said Wednesday her government would continue releasing prisoners detained under former President Nicolás Maduro’s rule in what she described as “a new political moment” since his ouster by the United States earlier t</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 06:15:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt borrowing jumps 619pc</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/govt-borrowing-jumps-619pc</link><description>Bangladesh’s private sector risks a tightening credit environment as government borrowing from the banking system has surged to nearly Tk 600 billion in the first half of the current fiscal year, raising concerns about reduced lending capacity for businesses.
According to Bangladesh Bank dat</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 07:00:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Another crane collapses in Thailand killing 2 people</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/another-crane-collapses-in-thailand-killing-2-people</link><description>A crane collapsed in Thailand on Thursday, crushing two vehicles and killing two people, police said, a day after a crane accident in the northeast caused the deaths of 32 train passengers.
The latest incident took place in Samut Sakhon province near the capital Bangkok, where a crane involved in</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 07:15:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hadi murder: Indictment hearing in court today</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hadi-murder-indictment-hearing-in-court-on-thursday</link><description>A Dhaka court will hold an indictment hearing on Thursday over the chargesheet submitted by the Detective Branch police in the murder case of Inquilab Moncho Convener Sharif Osman Bin Hadi.
The hearing will be held in the court of Dhaka Additional Chief Metropolitan Magistrate Jashita Islam, says</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 07:30:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP Chair Tarique to meet CA Yunus today</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bnp-chair-tarique-to-meet-chief-adviser-yunus-on-thursday</link><description>BNP Chariman Tarique Rahman is scheduled to meet with Chief Adviser Muhammad Yunus on Thursday.
The meeting will be held at the State Guest House Jamuna, the official residence of the chief adviser, according to a senior official in the Chief Adviser’s Office.
The meeting between the head o</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 07:45:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Players refuse to relent on BPL boycott as BCB president silent</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/players-refuse-to-relent-on-bpl-boycott-as-bcb-president-silent</link><description>Cricketers have remained firm in their decision to boycott Bangladesh Premier League (BPL) matches, despite the Bangladesh Cricket Board (BCB) issuing a show-cause notice to Director M Nazmul Islam over recent disputes.
One player, speaking on condition of anonymity, said: “It is upsetting</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 08:00:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>185 of 203 polling centres in Khagrachhari identified as ‘risky’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/185-of-203-polling-centres-in-khagrachhari-identified-as-risky</link><description>Of the 203 polling centres in Khagrachhari, 185 have been identified as “risky”, with 63 of them classified as “highly risky”, says the district’s Election Officer SM Shahadat Hossain.
The centres were identified based on observations by the police’s Special B</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 08:15:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hadi murder: Petitioner ‘dissatisfied’ with DB police chargesheet</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hadi-murder-petitioner-dissatisfied-with-db-police-chargesheet</link><description>The plaintiff in the murder case of Sharif Osman bin Hadi has expressed dissatisfaction with the charge sheet submitted by the Detective Branch (DB) of police, saying it fails to identify the main suspects or planners behind the killing.
Inqilab Moncho Member Secretary Abdullah Al Jaber submitted</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 08:30:44 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>