<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 03:43:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Five vehicles plunge into Dhaleshwari from ferry</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/man-missing-as-ferry-mishap-sends-truck-four-other-vehicles-into-dhaleshwari-river</link><description>A ferry mishap has seen five vehicles, including a truck, plunge into the Dhaleshwari River while crossing in Narayanganj, leaving one person missing.
The incident occurred around 9pm on Saturday in the middle of the river, according to Inspector Md Rakibuzzaman, chief of the Boktabali River Polic</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 18:45:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Uprising warrior buried beside Poet Nazrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/uprising-warrior-buried-beside-poet-nazrul</link><description>Mass-uprising warrior and national electoral candidate martyr Sharif Osman Bin Hadi was laid to eternal rest beside National Poet Kazi Nazrul Islam following mass funeral in Dhaka on Saturday afternoon, amid a renewed pledge for building an equitable Bangladesh.



His janaza was held at the So</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 19:00:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hadi will live on in hearts of people: CA</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hadi-will-live-on-in-hearts-of-people-ca</link><description>Slain Inqilab Mancha spokesperson Sharif Osman Hadi would live on in the hearts of the people of Bangladesh, Chief Adviser Prof Dr Muhammad Yunus said on Saturday.
"Brave Osman Hadi, we have not come here to bid farewell to you. You are inside our hearts. As long as Bangladesh exists, you will rem</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 00:54:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AK Khandkar passes away</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ak-khandkar-passes-away</link><description>Deputy Chief of Staff of the Bangladesh Liberation War and former Chief of Air Staff, Air Vice Marshal AK Khandkar, Bir Uttam passed away on Saturday morning.
An Inter-Services Public Relations (ISPR) release said that the war hero breathed his last at 10:35 am on the day (Saturday) due to old age</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 01:09:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Inqilab Mancha gives 24hr to arrest Hadi’s killers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/inqilab-mancha-gives-24hr-to-arrest-hadis-killers</link><description>In a sharp escalation of protests, Inqilab Mancha issued a 24-hour ultimatum to the Home Affairs Adviser on Saturday, demanding the arrest of those responsible for the killing of its spokesperson, Sharif Osman Hadi.
During a protest at Shabagh in the city, member-secretary of the platform Abdullah</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 01:24:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mobile, internet access expand despite ownership, gender gaps: BBS survey</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/mobile-internet-access-expand-despite-ownership-gender-gaps-bbs-survey</link><description>Mobile phone and internet access in Bangladesh continued to expand during the July-September quarter of 2025, reflecting steady progress in digital connectivity, although gaps persist in personal device ownership, internet use, gender parity, computer access and the urban-rural divide, according to</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 01:39:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Grieving admirers bid teary bye to Osman Hadi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/grieving-admirers-bid-teary-bye-to-osman-hadi</link><description>By the time Sharif Osman Hadi was laid to rest, grief had already spilled far beyond the grave.
On Saturday afternoon, beneath a winter sky heavy with silence, the spokesperson of the Inqilab Mancha was buried beside the grave of Bangladesh's national poet Kazi Nazrul Islam, near the central mosqu</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 01:54:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt urges Meta to curb violence-inciting content</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-urges-meta-to-curb-violence-inciting-content</link><description>The interim government has formally called on Meta, the parent company of Facebook, to take immediate steps to curb Bangladesh-related content that it says is fuelling violence, undermining the electoral process, and encouraging attacks on media institutions.
In a letter issued on Friday, the Nati</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 02:09:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Winter slump cuts power generation sharply</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/winter-slump-cuts-power-generation-sharply</link><description>Electricity generation across Bangladesh has fallen to nearly one-third of installed capacity as winter sets in and demand drops sharply.
While the seasonal slump has eased the chronic supply pressures typically seen during summer, it has also exposed the financial burden of maintaining surplus ge</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 02:24:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Expansion of technical school, colleges stalls as costs soar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/expansion-of-technical-school-colleges-stalls-as-costs-soar</link><description>A flagship government initiative to expand technical and vocational education across Bangladesh has stalled badly, with construction of Technical School and Colleges (TSCs) yet to begin in hundreds of upazilas despite repeated deadline extensions and sharp cost escalations.
Officials say the prolo</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 02:39:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Train fares rise via bridge charge</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/train-fares-rise-via-bridge-charge</link><description>Bangladesh Railway (BR) has increased train fares by up to Tk 226 on six key routes, including Dhaka-Cox's Bazar, with the revised rates taking effect on Saturday.
A senior BR official said the hike has been imposed in the form of a pontage charge to cover the maintenance costs of railway bridges,</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 02:54:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Lack of tax incentives deters RMG firms from going public</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/lack-of-tax-incentives-deters-rmg-firms-from-going-public</link><description>Readymade garment (RMG) companies are among the major targets for new listings to help the secondary market grow, but they have not been offered any incentives to go public.
A major purpose of listing is to get tax benefits but RMG companies, irrespective of their status as listed or non-listed, p</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 03:09:52 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>