<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 08:53:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Mexico deploys 2,000 soldiers after cartel leader's death</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/mexico-sends-2000-soldiers-to-jalisco-after-cartel-leaders-death</link><description>Mexican authorities on Monday deployed an additional 2,000 military troops to the western state of Jalisco following violence in the wake of the capture and death of Mexico's most-wanted cartel leader Nemesio Oseguera, known as "El Mencho."
At least 62 people were killed in the early Sunday raid a</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 05:53:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NBR introduces email OTP system for overseas taxpayers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/nbr-introduces-email-otp-system-for-overseas-taxpayers</link><description>The National Board of Revenue (NBR) has introduced a special email verification system allowing Bangladeshi expatriates to file their income tax returns online without relying on mobile-based OTP authentication.
The tax authority announced the measure in a statement on Tuesday, saying the initiati</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 06:08:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Four of a family injured in Cumilla gas cylinder blast</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/four-of-a-family-injured-in-cumilla-gas-cylinder-blast</link><description>Four members of a family, including a woman and a child, have suffered burn injuries after an explosion triggered by a suspected gas cylinder leak in Cumilla’s Daudkandi.
The incident occurred around 6:00 am on Tuesday on the ground floor of a three-storey building in West Maijpara of Ladakh</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 06:23:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>PM to confer 'Ekushey Padak 2026' Thursday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/pm-to-confer-ekushey-padak-2026-thursday</link><description>Prime Minister Tarique Rahman is expected to distribute the 'Ekushey Padak 2026' at a ceremony on Thursday. 
The award distribution ceremony will be held at the Osmani Memorial Auditorium in the capital at 11:00 a.m. on February 26, a handout stated. 
The government has already announce</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 06:38:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chinese envoy invites PM to visit China</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/chinese-envoy-invites-pm-to-visit-china</link><description>Chinese Ambassador to Bangladesh Yao Wen has invited Prime Minister Tarique Rahman to visit China and conveyed warm congratulations and greetings from Chinese President Xi Jinping and Premier Li Qiang.
The Chinese envoy extended the invitation when he paid a call on the premier at his Cabinet Divi</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 06:53:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC transfers 112 officials to upazila level</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-transfers-112-officials-to-upazila-level</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has transferred 112 officials from its secretariat and subordinate offices to various upazila and thana-level postings across the country.
An official order in this regard was issued today, signed by Assistant Secretary Mohammad Shahidur Rahman.
According to the order</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 06:24:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt approves withdraw of 1,202 more politically motivated cases</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-approves-withdraw-of-1202-more-politically-motivated-cases</link><description>Home Minister Salahuddin Ahmed has said the government has approved the withdrawal of 1,202 more politically motivated cases filed against opposition party leaders and activists during the 17-year rule of the fascist Awami League (AL).
The decision came after a thorough review process to assess al</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 06:39:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mexican cartel clashes fuel worries in lead up to FIFA World Cup</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/mexican-cartel-clashes-fuel-worries-in-lead-up-to-fifa-world-cup</link><description>Maria Dolores Aguirre's family corner store has lived off tourism that has flowed into her charming cobblestoned town of Tapalpa, tucked away in the mountains of Jalisco state.
That was until gunshots erupted and helicopters flew overhead as the Mexican army killed the country's most powerful drug</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 06:54:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Foreign investors keen on Nagad, Jamaat MP tells BB governor</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/foreign-investors-keen-on-nagad-jamaat-mp-tells-bb-governor</link><description>Barrister Mir Ahmad Bin Quasem Arman, a newly elected lawmaker from Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami, held discussions with the central bank governor on bringing global investors to the mobile financial service provider Nagad.
Barrister Arman arrived at the Bangladesh Bank (BB) headquarters at around 11</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 07:09:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Government to form commission to probe 2009 BDR mutiny: Salahuddin</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/government-to-form-commission-to-probe-2009-bdr-mutiny-salahuddin</link><description>Home Minister Salahuddin Ahmed has said the government will constitute a commission to reinvestigate the 2009 BDR carnage inside Pilkhana in the capital.
“We will constitute another enquiry commission to investigate the BDR carnage as per our decision to ensure justice,” he said.
The</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 07:24:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nepali video falsely circulated against BNP: BanglaFact</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nepali-video-falsely-circulated-against-bnp-banglafact</link><description>BanglaFact, the fact-checking and media research wing of the Press Institute of Bangladesh (PIB), has identified a misleading campaign on social media using a video from Nepal to target the BNP.
According to BanglaFact, the video being circulated with claims that a BNP leader beat an elderly man i</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 07:39:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Court orders seizure of Sheikh Rehana’s husband Shafiq’s tax records</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/court-orders-seizure-of-sheikh-rehanas-husband-shafiqs-tax-records</link><description>A Dhaka court has ordered the seizure of income tax records of Shafiq Siddiqi, husband of Sheikh Rehana, in connection with an investigation into alleged illicit wealth amounting to nearly Tk 87.5 million.
Dhaka Metropolitan Senior Special Judge Sabbir Faiz passed the order on Tuesday after a peti</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 07:54:22 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>