<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 19:45:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Russia says sending British troops to Ukraine would prolong war, not end it</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/russia-says-sending-british-troops-to-ukraine-would-prolong-war-not-end-it</link><description>Russia's foreign ministry spokeswoman Maria Zakharova said on Thursday that any deployment of British troops in Ukraine would prolong the war, not end it.
France and Britain have said they intend to send troops to Ukraine once a ceasefire in the war with Russia is reached.
British Defence Ministe</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 15:34:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>HC grants former NCC mayor Ivy bail in five cases</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hc-grants-former-ncc-mayor-ivy-bail-in-five-cases</link><description>The High Court has granted six months’ interim bail to former Narayanganj City Corporation (NCC) mayor Selina Hayat Ivy in five cases, including ones filed over murder allegations.
The bench of Justice KM Zahid Sarwar and Justice Sheikh Abu Taher passed the order with a rule on Thursday.
Se</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 15:49:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>175 stranded Bangladeshis repatriated from Libya</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/175-bangladeshis-return-from-libya-after-trafficking-ordeal</link><description>A group of 175 Bangladeshi nationals, who were stranded in Libya while attempting to reach Europe illegally, have returned to Dhaka.
The returnees arrived at Shahjalal International Airport at 8am on Thursday on a chartered Buraq Air flight, according to a media statement from the foreign ministry</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 16:04:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Confusion over ‘2 Akrams’: ICT prosecutor clears the air</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/namesake-war-crimes-convicts-create-confusion-ict-prosecutor-clarifies</link><description>International Crimes Tribunal (ICT) Chief Prosecutor Mohammad Aminul Islam has clarified the identities of two war crimes convicts named Akram to resolve confusion following a Supreme Court acquittal.
The clarification came on Thursday after the Appellate Division overturned the 2014 ICT judgement</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 16:19:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Commerce minister threatens fresh crackdown on high LPG prices</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/commerce-minister-threatens-fresh-crackdown-on-high-lpg-prices</link><description>The government has announced plans to deploy local administration teams to monitor retail markets following widespread reports that 12kg liquefied petroleum gas (LPG) cylinders are being sold at rates significantly higher than the state-fixed price.
Commerce Minister Khandaker Abdul Muktadir issue</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 16:34:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Repairing the broken promise of banking</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/repairing-the-broken-promise-of-banking</link><description>Public trust in Bangladesh's banking system has been gradually weakening. Not through sudden panic, but through steady hesitation. Over the past decade, structural weaknesses within the sector have eroded the fundamental promise of safety that depositors rely upon. Rising non-performing loans, gove</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 16:49:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>TT queen's comeback from the brink</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/reviews/tt-queens-comeback-from-the-brink</link><description>Munira Rahman Helen was the first table tennis queenof Bangladesh. She first won the women’s singles crownat the Second Bangladesh Open Table Tennis Tournament organised by BUET in 1973 while still a student of class ten; and then she won the women’s singles title in the First National</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 17:04:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Reviving trauma centres for emergency care</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/reviving-trauma-centres-for-emergency-care</link><description>Thousands of lives are lost prematurely on the roads in Bangladesh every year. Some die when the crashes take place but many others in the critical hours when they are rushed to Dhaka, hoping to get specialised emergency care in time. Sadly, they often fail to make it before the tragedy strikes.
T</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 17:19:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Why Trump's tariff policy suffers reversal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/why-trumps-tariff-policy-suffers-reversal</link><description>In his State of the Union address, President Donald Trump of America presented an update of the United States, highlighting his successes in the first year of his second term. But amid the rising tension over the conflict between the USA and Iran, he stopped short of mentioning the exact time for a</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 17:34:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Healing the health sector: A daunting challenge</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/healing-the-health-sector-a-daunting-challenge</link><description>The country's health sector has long been languishing due to chronic under-funding, weak governance and systemic inefficiencies, posing a formidable challenge to the new government as it seeks to honour its electoral commitments. Beyond fulfilling ambitious campaign pledges, the administration's fo</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 18:21:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Debt repayments exceed foreign aid inflow in 7 months</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/debt-servicing-outpaces-foreign-aid-inflow-in-first-seven-months</link><description>Bangladesh’s foreign debt servicing has outpaced the inflow of overseas aid in the first seven months of the current fiscal year, reflecting a growing strain on the country's economy.
According to the latest data released by the Economic Relations Division (ERD) on Thursday, development part</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 18:36:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rate reset, reopening factories key priorities</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/rate-reset-reopening-factories-key-priorities</link><description>Resetting higher interest rates and helping in reopening closed factories through default loan rescheduling and fresh working-capital lending are among first priorities set by the newly appointed Bangladesh Bank governor.



Explaining Governor Mostaqur Rahman's directions to the central bank's</description><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 19:39:10 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>