<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 16:31:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Vehicular movement to be restricted while Khaleda Zia’s body transported in city</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/vehicular-movement-to-be-restricted-while-khaleda-zias-body-transported-in-city</link><description>Traffic will remain restricted on several roads in the capital on Wednesday due to the movement of the convoy carrying the body of former Prime Minister and BNP Chairperson Begum Khaleda Zia, according to Dhaka Metropolitan Police (DMP).
The funeral prayer (Namaj-e-Janaja) of Begum Khaleda Zia is</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 13:45:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fireworks, open-air events banned on New Year’s Eve in Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fireworks-open-air-events-banned-on-new-years-eve-in-dhaka</link><description>Police have banned fireworks, crackers, and open-space events on the night of Dec 31, marking the final day of the Gregorian calendar.
The government has declared three days of state mourning following the death of former prime minister and BNP chairperson Khaleda Zia, along with a one-day general</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 14:00:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fireworks, gatherings banned on New Year's Eve in Ctg</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/chattogram-police-bans-fireworks-lanterns-and-gatherings-in-chattogram-on-new-years-eve</link><description>Burning fireworks, firecrackers and flying lanterns have been prohibited in Chattogram city on the last day of the Gregorian calendar.
Chattogram Metropolitan Police (CMP) Commissioner Hasib Aziz has issued six instructions imposing strict restrictions on public movement and gatherings, particular</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 14:15:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>MTB Foundation commemorates 26th anniversary by distributing bicycles in Chattogram</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/mtb-foundation-commemorates-26th-anniversary-by-distributing-bicycles-in-chattogram</link><description>To commemorate the bank’s 26th Anniversary, MTB Foundation distributed free bicycles to the underprivileged female meritorious students of different schools in the Chattogram region under its ‘Swapno Sarathi’ (The Dream Chariot) program.
The motto of the campaign, ‘schoole</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 14:30:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EBL opens a sub-branch at Kansat, Chapainawabganj</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ebl-opens-a-sub-branch-at-kansat-chapainawabganj</link><description>Eastern Bank (EBL) has expanded its retail footprint with opening of its sub-branch at Al Hajj Mohammad Abdul Kayum Market, Kansat, Chapainawabganj, according to a press release.
EBL Deputy Managing Director and Head of Retail and SME Banking M. Khorshed Anowar along with Acting Branch Area Head -</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 14:45:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Power failure halts Channel Tunnel rail traffic, causing travel mayhem</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/power-failure-halts-channel-tunnel-rail-traffic-causing-travel-mayhem</link><description>Train services through the Channel Tunnel linking Britain and continental Europe were suspended on Tuesday following a power supply failure, disrupting peak winter holiday travel.
A spokesperson for Eurostar, which operates high-speed trains linking London to Paris, Brussels, Amsterdam and Disneyl</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 15:00:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bank Asia launches ten Islamic Banking Windows simultaneously</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bank-asia-launches-ten-islamic-banking-windows-simultaneously</link><description>Bank Asia PLC has inaugurated ten Islamic Banking Windows simultaneously across the country on the occasion of the 17th anniversary of its Islamic Banking Services, according to a press release.
The inauguration ceremony was held on 24 December 2025 at Bank Asia Tower, Karwan Bazar, Dhaka. Deputy</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 15:15:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Al-Arafah Islami Bank’s Bandarban Branch distributes blankets among helpless people</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/al-arafah-islami-banks-bandarban-branch-distributes-blankets-among-helpless-people</link><description>Bandarban Branch of Al-Arafah Islami Bank PLC has distributed blankets to the underprivileged people, according to a press release.
Muhammad Ali, Bandarban District Representative of Al-Arafah Islami Bank PLC, Bandarban branch organised the blanket distribution program for helpless people amid the</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 15:17:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Agrani Bank mourns death of Khaleda Zia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/agrani-bank-mourns-death-of-khaleda-zia</link><description>Agrani Bank PLC has expressed deep sorrow at the death of former Prime Minister and BNP Chairperson Begum Khaleda Zia.
According to a press release, a prayer gathering (Doa Mahfil) was held after Zuhr prayers on Tuesday at the Central Prayer Hall of Agrani Bank’s Head Office, seeking eternal</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 15:32:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh Polls: Registration time for postal voting extended till Jan 5</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-polls-registration-time-for-postal-voting-extended-till-jan-5</link><description>The Election Commission has extended the registration time by five days till January 5 next for expatriates and other entitled voters to vote through the postal ballots during the upcoming national election and referendum, slated for February 12, 2026.
“Now the deadline for the postal ballot</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 15:47:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ICC Bangladesh president condoles death of Khaleda Zia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/icc-bangladesh-president-condoles-death-of-khaleda-zia</link><description>ICC Bangladesh President Mr Mahbubur Rahman has expressed deepest condolences at the demise of former Prime Minister of Bangladesh and BNP Chairperson Begum Khaleda Zia.
In a condolence letter sent to BNP’s Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman, also the son of Begum Khaleda Zia, on Wednesday, the</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 16:02:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>3 million submit income tax returns online</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/3-million-submit-income-tax-returns-online</link><description>More than 3 million individual taxpayers have so far submitted their income tax returns online for the current 2025–26 tax year, reflecting a sharp rise in the use of Bangladesh’s e-return system, according to the National Board of Revenue (NBR).
The NBR said around 4.5 million taxpaye</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 16:17:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>