<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 04:22:40 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nassa's Tk 40b loan being rescheduled</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/nassas-tk-40b-loan-being-rescheduled</link><description>On an avowed purpose of facilitating production and protecting jobs in beleaguered Nassa Group, the defaulter kingpin's loan worth nearly Tk 40 billion out of its accumulated debts is set to be rescheduled.



One of the giant apparel makers in Bangladesh, NASSA's loans have been taken from fiv</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 20:07:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Safety at stake as many RMG units run sans affiliation with trade bodies</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/safety-at-stake-as-many-rmg-units-run-sans-affiliation-with-trade-bodies</link><description>Several hundred apparel factories that export directly or partly are not associated with any of the two apparel apex bodies -- BGMEA and BKMEA -- thus posing safety risks to their workers.
The workers' safety issues of those factories remain either less or properly monitored, industry insiders hav</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 01:06:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dithering clouds solar power future</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/dithering-clouds-solar-power-future</link><description>Bangladesh's solar ambitions seem losing steam as 17 recently proposed solar-power plants, each offering the reduced tariffs ever, have been left waiting for approval while some previously contracted ones lie in limbo.
Sources say the "bureaucratic dithering" is frustrating sponsors, foreign inves</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 01:21:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two shipping lines backtrack on surcharges amid CPA’s tough stance</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/two-shipping-lines-backtrack-on-surcharges-amid-cpas-tough-stance</link><description>Two major shipping lines which announced Port Cost Recovery (PCR) Surcharge and Emergency Cost Recovery Surcharge to and from Chittagong have backtracked on realising those following the port authority's tough stand, officials say.
They announced the surcharges to adjust the rise in operation cost</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 01:36:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khaleda Zia hospitalised at midnight</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/khaleda-zia-hospitalised-at-midnight</link><description>BNP Chairperson Khaleda Zia has been admitted to Evercare Hospital in Dhaka for health examinations.
She left her Gulshan residence “Feroza” at 12:40 am on Thursday and reached the hospital at 12:25 am. 
Her personal physician Prof AZM Zahid Hossain told bdnews24.com said that up</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 01:51:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UN calls for prompt civil trial for detained Army officers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/un-calls-for-prompt-civilian-court-trial-for-detained-army-officers</link><description>The Office of the UN High Commissioner for Human Rights has called on Bangladeshi authorities to swiftly produce the army officers held in military custody before a “competent” civilian court.
The appeal came on Wednesday in an OHCHR media statement, days after Bangladesh’s Inter</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 02:36:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Universal Ticketing Service: DMTCL to invite fresh tenders</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/universal-ticketing-service-dmtcl-to-invite-fresh-tenders</link><description>The Dhaka metro rail company has decided to invite fresh tenders for the universal ticketing service (UTS) at all stations by cancelling the previous one.
It says the decision has been made to avoid complications that arose over receiving applications by the deadline due to the Milestone school pl</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 02:51:12 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>