<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 09:22:36 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Arms manufacturing den busted in Khulna, 3 held</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/arms-manufacturing-den-busted-in-khulna-3-held</link><description>Detectives have detained three suspects with a huge quantity of materials used in producing arms after busting a den (in disguise of factory) in Khulna city.
The discovery was made on Saturday at 7:30pm in a lane beside HRC Bhaban in the Joragate area of the city.
Those detained are Nazrul, owner</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 06:29:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Five-storey building tilts in Mymensingh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/five-storey-building-tilts-in-mymensingh</link><description>A five-storey building tilted in Mymensingh city during piling work for a nearby 20-storey building, triggering panic among the building's owner and tenants. For safety reasons, they vacated the building overnight.
The incident occurred on Saturday night in the Gulkibari area of the city.
At arou</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 06:44:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nvidia considers increasing H200 chip output due to robust China demand, sources say</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/nvidia-considers-increasing-h200-chip-output-due-to-robust-china-demand-sources-say</link><description>Nvidia has told Chinese clients it is evaluating adding production capacity for its powerful H200 AI chips after orders exceeded its current output level, according to two sources briefed on the matter.
The move comes after US President Donald Trump said on Tuesday the US government would allow Nv</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 06:59:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hadi shooting: Border patrols intensified in Mymensingh, Sherpur to stop suspects fleeing</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hadi-shooting-border-patrols-intensified-in-mymensingh-sherpur-to-stop-suspects-fleeing</link><description>The Border Guard Bangladesh (BGB) has strengthened security measures in the border areas of Sherpur and Mymensingh following the shooting of Sharif Osman bin Hadi, a potential independent candidate for the Dhaka-8 constituency and convenor of Inqilab Mancha.
The information was disclosed in a pres</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 07:14:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BKash agent’s sales representative shot, Tk 1.5mn robbed in Tongi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bkash-agents-sales-representative-shot-tk-15mn-robbed-in-tongi</link><description>A sales representative of a bKash agent has been shot in the chest and robbed of nearly Tk 1.5 million in Tongi.
The victim - Arif, identified by a single name - was shot around 7:15pm on Saturday in the Anarkali Road area and was taken to Dhaka Medical College Hospital in critical condition, said</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 07:29:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NBR freezes bank accounts of Hadi’s suspected attacker Masud and his firm</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nbr-freezes-bank-accounts-of-hadis-suspected-attacker-masud-and-his-firm</link><description>The National Board of Revenue (NBR) has frozen the bank accounts of Faisal Karim Masud, who is suspected of attacking Sharif Osman Hadi.
Hadi is the spokesperson of Inquilab Mancha and a probable independent candidate for the Dhaka-8 constituency.
Besides, the bank accounts of Masud’s IT fi</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 07:44:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Seven Bangladeshis arrested in Singapore anti-drug raid</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/seven-bangladeshis-arrested-in-singapore-anti-drug-raid</link><description>Seven Bangladeshi nationals, aged between 20 and 40, were detained from migrant worker dormitories in Singapore for suspected drug-related offences.
Singapore’s Central Narcotics Bureau (CNB) conducted a series of operations at several migrant worker dormitories across the country over the p</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 07:59:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gun attack on Hadi: RAB detain motorbike owner</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/gun-attack-on-hadi-rab-detain-motorbike-owner</link><description>Rapid Action Battalion (RAB) has detained Abdul Hannan, the owner of the motorbike which was used in the gun attack on Inquilab Moncho spokesperson Osman Hadi, from the Mohammadpur area of Dhaka.
Tipped off, a special team of RAB-2 conducted a drive in the area in the early hours of Sunday and det</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 08:14:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two arrested over attack on ‘July Rebels’ activist in Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/two-arrested-over-attack-on-july-rebels-activist-in-dhaka</link><description>Police have arrested two suspects in connection with the attack on 'July Rebels' activist Md Rezaowan.
The arrestees were identified as Md Masum and Md Fahim Khan.
Some unidentified people attacked Rezaowan at Sector 6 of Uttara around 7:30 pm on Saturday, leaving him critically injured, Md Taleb</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 08:29:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BKash agent’s sales representative shot, Tk 1.5m robbed in Tongi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/bkash-agents-sales-representative-shot-tk-15m-robbed-in-tongi</link><description>A sales representative of a bKash agent has been shot in the chest and robbed of nearly Tk 1.5 million in Tongi.
The victim - Arif, identified by a single name - was shot around 7:15 pm on Saturday in the Anarkali Road area and was taken to Dhaka Medical College Hospital in critical condition, sai</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 08:44:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two killed in Sitakunda truck accident</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/two-killed-in-sitakunda-truck-accident</link><description>Two people were killed, and another was injured after a truck carrying betel leaves veered off the road and crashed in Sitakunda upazila of Chattogram.
The accident occurred in the early hours of Sunday on the Dhaka-Chattogram Highway in the Bashbaria area of the upazila, police said.
The dead we</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 08:59:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UN chief condemns Sudan drone attack that resulted in deaths of Bangladeshi peacekeepers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/un-chief-condemns-sudan-drone-attack-that-resulted-in-deaths-of-bangladeshi-peacekeepers</link><description>UN Secretary General António Guterres has condemned the drone attacks in Sudan that led to the deaths of several Bangladeshi UN peacekeepers.
The UN chief expressed his condolences to the families of the dead and wished those injured a speedy recovery in a post on X, reports bdnews24.com.</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 09:14:52 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>