<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 14:22:40 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>447th board meeting of Al-Arafah Islami Bank held</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/447th-board-meeting-of-al-arafah-islami-bank-held</link><description>The 447th board meeting of Al-Arafah Islami Bank PLC was held on Wednesday, December 24, 2025, at the Bank’s Head Office.
Chairman of the Board of Directors Khwaja Shahriar presided over the meeting, according to a press release.
The overall business performance of the Bank was reviewed and</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 11:34:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hadi murder: Suspect’s 'associate' held with firearm</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hadi-murder-probe-motorcycle-riders-associate-held-with-firearm-in-motel-raid</link><description>Police have arrested an alleged associate of the rider of the motorcycle used in the drive-by of Sharif Osman bin Hadi, seizing a foreign firearm and ammunition.
Himon Rahman Shikdar, 32, was arrested on Wednesday morning at a local motel.
Acting on his information, officers later recovered a for</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 11:49:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shimanto Bank inks MoU with Dhaka Central International Medical College &amp; Hospital</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/shimanto-bank-inks-mou-with-dhaka-central-international-medical-college-hospital</link><description>Shimanto Bank PLC has recently signed a Memorandum of Understanding (MoU) with Dhaka Central International Medical College &amp; Hospital at the Bank’s Head Office.
Under this agreement, all Debit and Credit Card holders, as well as employees of Shimanto Bank, will be entitled to enjoy exclusive</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 12:04:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rumin Farhana collects nomination papers as independent candidate</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rumin-farhana-picks-up-nomination-papers-for-brahmanbaria-2-as-independent-candidate</link><description>Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) leader Rumin Farhana has collected nomination papers for Brahmanbaria-2 to contest the parliamentary polls as an independent candidate.
The seat has been ceded by her party to its alliance partner Jamiat Ulama-e-Islam Bangladesh.
Sarail Upazila Jubo Dal’s</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 12:19:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>90th meeting of Shari'ah Supervisory Committee of Shahjalal Islami Bank held</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/90th-meeting-of-shariah-supervisory-committee-of-shahjalal-islami-bank-held</link><description>The 90th meeting of Shari'ah Supervisory Committee of Shahjalal Islami Bank PLC (SJIBPLC) was held on 24th December 2025 at the Board meeting room of the Corporate Head Office of the Bank.
The Chairman of Shari'ah Supervisory Committee of Shahjalal Islami Bank PLC Mufti Shamsuddin Zia, presided ov</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 12:34:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sohel from Mymensingh wins a scooter through Nagad transactions</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/sohel-from-mymensingh-wins-a-scooter-through-nagad-transactions</link><description>Shafiqul Islam Sohel of Mymensingh has won a Hero Pleasure Refresh 102cc scooter by making transactions through Nagad.
He received the prize by participating in Nagad’s campaign titled “Asha Aar Fera, Surprise Sera” [Come back or start fresh, surprises at their best].
Popular te</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 12:49:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Russia plans nuclear power plant on the moon</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/russia-plans-a-nuclear-power-plant-on-the-moon-within-a-decade</link><description>Russia plans to put a nuclear power plant on the moon in the next decade to supply its lunar space programme and a joint Russian-Chinese research station, as major powers rush to explore the earth's only natural satellite.
Ever since Soviet cosmonaut Yuri Gagarin became the first human to go into</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 12:45:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Banks, stock markets to remain closed for three days</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/banks-stock-markets-to-remain-closed-for-three-days</link><description>All banks, financial institutions and the country’s two stock exchanges will remain closed for three consecutive days from Thursday due to Christmas and the weekly holidays on Friday and Saturday.
The Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) and the Chittagong Stock Exchange (CSE) said on Wednesday that t</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 13:00:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Unequal VVIP facilities violate polls code: Jamaat tells EC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/unequal-vvip-facilities-violate-polls-code-jamaat-tells-ec</link><description>Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami on Wednesday told the Election Commission (EC) that providing VVIP facilities to someone while denying these to others is the violation of a level playing field in the election.
“If someone gets many facilities, even VVIP facilities, while others do not, that canno</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 13:15:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Keep Feb 12 election unchanged: NCP to EC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/keep-feb-12-election-unchanged-ncp-to-ec</link><description>National Citizen Party (NCP) on Wednesday urged the Election Commission (EC) to reconsider the dates for the submission of nomination papers and withdrawal of candidacies, keeping the voting date unchanged for the upcoming national election and the referendum scheduled for February 12.
“They</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 13:30:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Internet shutdowns ruled out as NTMC dissolved</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/internet-shutdowns-ruled-out-as-ntmc-dissolved</link><description>The interim government has approved the final draft of the Bangladesh Telecommunications (Amendment) Ordinance 2025, paving the way for the dissolution of the National Telecommunications Monitoring Centre (NTMC).
The amendment explicitly says internet and telecommunications services cannot be shut</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 13:45:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC calls on banks to stay open on Saturday for nomination deposits</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-calls-on-banks-to-stay-open-on-saturday-for-nomination-deposits</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has asked the Bangladesh Bank to keep banks open across the country on the weekly holiday of Saturday.
In a letter sent on Wednesday, the EC said banks need to remain open for candidates to deposit money through pay orders for nomination deposits and the purchase of vo</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 14:00:49 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>