<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 07:19:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Tarique says cooling of Bangladesh-India relations reflects 'people's decision'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-says-cooling-of-bangladesh-india-relations-reflects-peoples-decision</link><description>BNP’s Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman has stressed that if his party comes to power in the upcoming national election, its foreign policy will be predicated on the principle of “Bangladesh first”.
He also believes that the chill in relations between India and Bangladesh since the</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 05:23:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BCB polls went 'beyond fixing', says former cricketer Debabrata</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/bcb-polls-went-beyond-fixing-says-former-cricketer-debabrata</link><description>Former cricketer Debabrata Pal, a losing candidate in the Bangladesh Cricket Board (BCB) elections, has alleged widespread government interference and manipulation in the voting process.
Struggling to hold back tears, Debabrata, who secured just seven votes in the race for director in Category-3,</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 05:38:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique Rahman vows return for polls, preditcts BNP landslide</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/in-interview-with-ft-tarique-rahman-vows-return-for-polls-confident-of-bnp-landslide</link><description>Tarique Rahman has said he will return home to take part in the upcoming national elections.
In an interview with the Financial Times (FT), his first face-to-face English language interview with the British daily, the BNP's acting chairman expressed firm confidence that his party will secure a lan</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 05:23:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Interim government approves two new private TV channels under old licensing process</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/interim-government-approves-two-new-private-tv-channels-under-old-licensing-process</link><description>Bangladesh’s interim government has approved two new private satellite television channels — Next TV and Live TV — following the same procedure used by the ousted Awami League administration, which faced criticism for politically influenced licensing.
According to the Ministry of</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 05:53:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Probe launched into Awami League over alleged crimes against humanity</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ict-launches-probe-into-awami-league-over-alleged-crimes-against-humanity</link><description>The International Crimes Tribunal (ICT) has officially opened a probe into the Awami League for alleged involvement in crimes against humanity, with an investigating officer now appointed.
The tribunal’s Chief Prosecutor Mohammad Tajul Islam confirmed the development on Tuesday (October 7).</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 06:38:49 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>