<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 12:49:38 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Significant progress in Hadi murder probe: Home Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/significant-progress-in-hadi-murder-probe-home-adviser</link><description>Home Affairs Adviser Jahangir Alam Chowdhury on Monday said investigators have made ‘significant progress’ in the probe into the murder of Inquilab Moncho spokesperson Sharif Osman Bin Hadi, warning that no one involved in the killing would be spared.
“The interim government, inc</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 09:21:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Assets of Benazir’s 4 flats transferred to CA’s relief fund</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/assets-of-benazirs-4-flats-transferred-to-cas-relief-fund</link><description>The government has transferred all assets of four flats seized from former Inspector General of Police Benazir Ahmed to the Chief Adviser’s Relief and Welfare Fund.
Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) deputy director Akther Hossain disclosed the information to the media on Monday.
The ACC earl</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 09:36:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gunmen assigned to Prothom Alo, Daily Star editors: advisor</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-assigns-gunmen-to-prothom-alo-daily-star-editors-amid-security-concerns</link><description>Gunmen have been assigned to 20 people, including the editors of Prothom Alo and The Daily Star, following the attacks on the offices of the newspapers, according to Home Advisor Jahangir Alam Chowdhury.
“The DMP has arrested 17 people in connection with the attacks on the offices of Prothom</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 09:51:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique to register as voter on Dec 27</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-leader-tarique-rahman-set-to-register-as-voter-on-dec-27</link><description>BNP leader Tarique Rahman is expected to register as a voter on Dec 27, two days after returning to the country following 17 years in exile.
BNP Standing Committee member Salahuddin Ahmed told reporters on Monday that the party’s acting chairman would return on Dec 25 and complete his voter</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 10:06:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh, ADB ink $688m loan deals to upgrade Ctg-Dohazari railway</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladesh-adb-ink-688m-loan-deals-to-upgrade-ctg-dohazari-railway</link><description>Bangladesh and Asian Development Bank (ADB) on Monday signed loan agreements totaling $688 million to upgrade the 35-kilometer railway line from Chattogram to Dohazari.  A 2.5-kilometer bypass enabling direct train services from Dhaka to Cox's Bazar without stopping at Chattogram station will</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 10:21:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AB Bank opens its sub-branch at Companiganj</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ab-bank-opens-its-sub-branch-at-companiganj</link><description>AB Bank PLC inaugurated its Companiganj sub-branch as the 59th sub-branch of the bank.
The sub-branch is located at Bhaskar Plaza, Nabipur (West) Union, Muradnagar, Cumilla, according to a press release.
Mr. Reazul Islam, Managing Director and CEO (Acting), AB Bank, inaugurated the sub-branch thr</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 10:36:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EBL Digital Excellence Awards 2025 honor partner organizations</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ebl-digital-excellence-awards-2025-honor-partner-organizations</link><description>Eastern Bank PLC (EBL) organized the second edition of the SKYSPHERE: EBL Digital Excellence Awards 2025.
The exclusive event celebrated the bank’s partners and merchants whose contributions have played a significant role in EBL’s growth and digital transformation journey over the past</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 10:51:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bank Asia Partners with Heidelberg Materials Bangladesh for Integrated Cash Management Solution</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bank-asia-partners-with-heidelberg-materials-bangladesh-for-integrated-cash-management-solution</link><description>Bank Asia PLC and Heidelberg Materials Bangladesh PLC have entered into a strategic partnership to introduce an integrated cash management solution for further strengthening the collaboration between the two organisations.
The agreement was formally signed by Mr. Sohail R K Hossain, Managing Direc</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 11:06:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt to cut savings certificate profit rates from January</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/govt-to-cut-savings-certificate-profit-rates-from-january</link><description>The government is set to slash profit rates on national savings certificates (Sanchaypatra) from January 1, 2026, marking the second reduction in six months, following calls from the banking sector.
The Finance Division of the Ministry of Finance has drafted a proposal outlining the new profit rat</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 11:21:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sonali Bank holds ALCO meeting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/sonali-bank-holds-alco-meeting-1</link><description>The 255th Asset - Liabilities Committee (ALCO) meeting of Sonali Bank PLC was held at the bank’s head office conference room on 22 December, Monday.
ALCO Chairman and MD &amp; CEO of Sonali Bank, Md. Shawkat Ali Khan presided over the meeting, according to a press release.
Deputy Managing Direc</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 11:36:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shaheed Minar sit-in ends as Inqilab Moncho demands justice for Hadi within 24 hours</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/shaheed-minar-sit-in-ends-as-inqilab-moncho-demands-justice-for-hadi-within-24-hours</link><description>Inqilab Moncho has concluded its protest at the Central Shaheed Minar after issuing a 24-hour ultimatum to the government, seeking justice for the killing of Sharif Osman bin Hadi.
The platform demanded the formation of a speedy judicial tribunal and two other measures over the killing of Hadi, re</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 11:51:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Modhumoti Bank holds 141th meeting of executive committee</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/modhumoti-bank-holds-141th-meeting-of-executive-committee</link><description>The 141st meeting of the Executive Committee of Modhumoti Bank PLC was held on Monday, 22nd December 2025 at Bank’s Head Office premises.
The meeting was presided over by EC Chairman, Mr. Salahuddin Alamgir, according to a press release.
Among others, Mr. Mostafa Kamal, Mr. Mohammad Ismail</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 12:06:21 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>