<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 11:13:51 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Bangladesh making significant efforts to eliminate trafficking: US</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-making-significant-efforts-to-eliminate-trafficking-us-1</link><description>The government of Bangladesh has demonstrated overall increasing efforts to deal with the trafficking in persons compared with the previous reporting period, says the United States (US).
The US, in its recently released '2025 Trafficking in Persons Report,' said the government of Bangladesh does n</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 07:43:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh braces for cyclone risk, possible floods in October</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-braces-for-cyclone-risk-possible-floods-in-october</link><description>The Bangladesh Meteorological Department (BMD) has flagged the possibility of up to three low-pressure systems forming in the Bay of Bengal in October, one of which may intensify into a depression or a cyclone.
The Met Office made the forecast in its long-term weather outlook issued on Saturday,</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 07:58:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How the Gaza aid flotilla used cameras and data to win global attention</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/how-the-gaza-aid-flotilla-used-cameras-and-data-to-win-global-attention</link><description>When armed Israeli soldiers boarded a flotilla of boats trying to deliver food and medicine to Gaza on Wednesday night, two web developers in Glasgow scrambled to keep track of the vessels as millions of people worldwide tuned in to monitor their fate.
As grainy footage from onboard cameras broadc</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 08:31:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nation bids farewell to Language Movement veteran Ahmad Rafiq</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nation-bids-farewell-to-language-movement-veteran-ahmad-rafiq</link><description>The body of Ahmad Rafiq has been taken to the Central Shaheed Minar in Dhaka, where people from all walks of life are paying their last respects to the Language Movement veteran.
Following the tributes on Saturday, his coffin will be carried in a funeral procession to Ibrahim Medical College Hospi</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 08:46:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Islami Bank employees block Chattogram highway for almost an hour</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/islami-bank-employees-block-chattogram-highway-for-almost-an-hour</link><description>Employees of Islami Bank have staged a blockade on the Dhaka–Chattogram Highway at Faujdarhat, halting traffic for nearly an hour in protest against the bank's “special competency evaluation” programme.
Around 11am on Saturday, they formed a human chain near the Faujdarhat Police</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 09:01:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prime Bank signs deal with Go Girls to offer travel package for women customers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/prime-bank-signs-deal-with-go-girls-to-offer-travel-package-for-women-customers</link><description>Prime Bank PLC. has signed a strategic agreement with Go Girls, enabling the bank’s Women Customers to enjoy exclusive discounts on travel packages.
In this regards a signing ceremony was held recently at the bank’s corporate office in Gulshan, according to a media release. 
As p</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 09:17:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Salahuddin accuses Jamaat of backing vested quarter trying to disrupt election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/salahuddin-accuses-jamaat-of-backing-vested-quarter-trying-to-disrupt-election</link><description>BNP senior leader Salahuddin Ahmed, on Saturday, in an oblique reference, accused Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami of siding with a vested quarter trying to create political unrest and obstruct the next national election.
"We are suspecting that this political party (Jamaat) is working in support of for</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 09:32:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Midland Bank signs MoU with Ifad Auto</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/midland-bank-signs-mou-with-ifad-auto</link><description>Midland Bank PLC. signed a Memorandum of Understanding (MoU) with IFAD Motors Ltd., the country’s authorized distributor and manufacturer of Royal Enfield motorcycles in Bangladesh.
The MoU signing ceremony was held at the Bank’s Head Office in Gulshan-2, Dhaka on September 23, 2025, a</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 10:02:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gill takes charge as India’s new ODI captain, Rohit stays in squad</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/gill-takes-charge-as-indias-new-odi-captain-rohit-stays-in-squad</link><description>India have appointed Shubman Gill as the new captain of the ODI side, replacing Rohit Sharma. The decision came right ahead of the series against Australia.
Despite losing the captaincy, Rohit remains in the squad alongside Virat Kohli.
Both senior batters are returning to international cricket f</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 10:17:10 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>