<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 04:22:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>US begins troop drawdown in Iraq under agreement with Baghdad</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-begins-troop-drawdown-in-iraq-under-agreement-with-baghdad</link><description>The United States has begun reducing its military presence in Iraq under a deal signed with Baghdad last year, with troop levels set to be cut by about 20 percent as responsibility for countering the Islamic State (IS) shifts to Iraqi forces, officials confirmed Wednesday.
Pentagon spokesman Sean</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 18:34:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bank directors, top brass to be on a monitoring platform</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bank-directors-top-brass-to-be-on-a-monitoring-platform</link><description>All directors and top brass of the country's commercial banks are to be on a hold-all platform called key performance indicator (KPI) in a latest reform measure meant for ensuring good governance in the banking industry, reeling from past misrule, official sources say.
As part of the reform innova</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 18:49:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chittagong seaport finally enforces hiked tariffs from midnight Oct 14</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/chittagong-seaport-finally-enforces-hiked-tariffs-from-midnight-oct-14</link><description>Ramped-up tariffs across 23 services categories at Chittagong seaport are set to be enforced from midnight October 14, following the end of a one-month suspension conceded amid strong port-user opposition.
The enforcement date is confirmed in Chittagong Port Authority (CPA) notification issued on</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 01:23:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mid-year tax hike: Sudden fiscal measure draws more ire than revenues</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/mid-year-tax-hike-thru-ordinance-sudden-fiscal-measure-draws-more-ire-than-revenues</link><description>A much-debated mid-year fiscal measure hiking taxes earns more ire than additional revenue income to uplift Bangladesh's low tax-to-GDP ratio in the past fiscal year.
Fearing a large shortfall in tax-revenue collection in the bygone year, the interim government imposed increased taxes on a range o</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 01:38:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Israeli military boards several Sumud flotilla aid boats bound for Gaza</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/israeli-military-boards-several-sumud-flotilla-aid-boats-bound-for-gaza</link><description>Israeli forces boarded several boats carrying foreign activists and aid bound for Gaza and took them to an Israeli port on Wednesday, disrupting a protest that had become one of the most high-profile symbols of opposition to Israel's blockade of the enclave.
A video from the Israeli foreign minist</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 02:08:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Forex swap deals shrink as BB pushes spot market</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/forex-swap-deals-shrink-as-bb-pushes-spot-market</link><description>Foreign-exchange swap transactions on the interbank market dropped in August compared with the previous month, even as the Bangladesh Bank pressed ahead with its strategy to promote spot-market trading over swaps.
The move is intended to make the market more transparent and reflective of real dema</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 02:23:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Move underway to import refined soybean oil in bulk</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/move-underway-to-import-refined-soybean-oil-in-bulk</link><description>A move is underway to import refined soybean oil in the bulk form to be sold in bottles at subsidised prices under the TCB's sale drives.
The state-run Trading Corporation of Bangladesh (TCB) in a recent letter sought consent from the Ministry of Commerce to this effect.
The corporation has initi</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 02:38:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Puja holiday fuels boom in domestic tourism</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/puja-holiday-fuels-boom-in-domestic-tourism</link><description>This year's Durga Puja holiday has turned into a windfall for domestic tourism industry.
With an unusually long break on offer, families, friends, and office groups packed their bags and headed for beaches, forests, and hill tracts rather than looking abroad.
Travel agents say the rush has been h</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 03:38:52 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>