<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 20:41:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Tarique visits hospitalised Rizvi on eve of election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-visits-hospitalised-rizvi-on-eve-of-election</link><description>BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman on Wednesday night visited Square Hospital in the capital to enquire about the health of his party’s Senior Joint Secretary General Advocate Ruhul Kabir Rizvi.
Tarique went to the hospital around 9:15 pm and met Rizvi, who has been undergoing treatment there since</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 17:42:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>800,000 officials to remain on election duty: EC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/800000-officials-to-remain-on-election-duty-ec</link><description>About 800,000 officials will be engaged in election duty in the 13th parliamentary elections and referendum to be held tomorrow.
According to the Election Commission (EC), a total of 69 returning officers and 598 assistant returning officers will remain on duty during the polls.
Voting will take</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 06:21:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Three imprisoned candidates contest in JS polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/three-imprisoned-candidates-contest-in-js-polls</link><description>Three candidates are contesting in the parliamentary election from behind bars, highlighting an unusual facet of the race as voting approaches.
Two of the contenders are being held in Faridpur District Jail, while the third remains in custody at the Special Central Jail in Keraniganj, reports bdne</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 17:57:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Historic 13th parliamentary polls today</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/historic-13th-parliamentary-polls-today</link><description>Bangladesh heads to the Jatiya Sangsad (JS) polls Thursday amid a changed political ambience in a consequential election in its recent history as rebuilding the country's upended democratic institutions is an onerous stake.



Many see the vote--arranged against the backdrop of an uprising that</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 18:12:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two BNP activists held with cash in Barishal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/two-bnp-activists-held-with-cash-in-barishal</link><description>Two BNP activists were detained with more than Tk 100,000 in Babuganj upazila of Barishal on Wednesday, hours before the national election.
Commanding Officer of Army’s 62 East Bengal, Lieutenant Colonel Faiz Ahmed, said that as part of ongoing law and order and election security operations,</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 18:27:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Turkish observers meet Tarique ahead of polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/turkish-observers-meet-tarique-ahead-of-polls</link><description>A delegation of Turkish election observers met BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman at his Gulshan office on Wednesday night ahead of tomorrow’s national election.
The delegation, visiting Bangladesh to observe the 13th National Parliament election and concurrent referendum, arrived at the chairman&amp;r</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 18:58:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Police to wear hidden cameras during polls: EC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/police-to-wear-hidden-cameras-during-polls-ec</link><description>Police personnel deployed at polling centres for the 13th National Parliamentary Elections and referendum tomorrow will wear hidden cameras as part of enhanced security measures, the Election Commission (EC) said on Wednesday.
The information was disclosed in a statement signed by EC Director (Pub</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 19:13:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>T20 WC boycott was govt’s  decision, I remain firm on this: Asif Nazrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/cricket/t20-wc-boycott-was-govts-decision-i-remain-firm-on-this-asif-nazrul</link><description>Youth and Sports Adviser Dr. Asif Nazrul has clarified that the decision for Bangladesh not to play the T20 World Cup matches in India was taken solely by the government due to security concerns, dispelling confusion arising from his recent remarks.
In a Facebook post on Wednesday, the Adviser add</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 19:28:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat Ameer to cast vote in Monipur Centre</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-ameer-to-cast-vote-in-monipur-centre</link><description>Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami Ameer Dr Shafiqur Rahman will cast his vote at 8:00 am on Thursday.
He will vote at the Monipur High School (Boys’ Branch) polling centre in his constituency, Dhaka-15, located at 60 feet area, Jamaat said in a statement on Wednesday, reports UNB.
Meanwhile, Chief</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 19:43:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Result sheet irregularity: Presiding officer removed from duty in Jhenaidah</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/result-sheet-irregularity-presiding-officer-removed-from-duty-in-jhenaidah</link><description>The presiding officer of Salimunnesa Girls’ School polling centre under Jhenaidah-4 constituency was removed from election duty on Wednesday night following the seizure of 23 signed result sheets.
The removed officer, Jasmine Ara, was serving as presiding officer at Centre No. 5 of Kaliganj</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 19:58:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Five arrested in Dhaka for breaching election code</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/five-arrested-in-dhaka-for-breaching-election-code</link><description>A summary trial court on Wednesday detained and sentenced five people, including a Jamaat-e-Islami activist, for violating the election code of conduct in different areas of the capital.
In Sutrapur, a Jamaat worker, Habibur Rahman, 63, was caught red-handed while allegedly preparing to distribute</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 20:13:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Krishak Dal leader’s veins severed in Rajshahi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/krishak-dal-leaders-veins-severed-in-rajshahi</link><description>A local leader of Krishak Dal sustained critical injuries after miscreants severed the veins of both his hands and legs in Charghat upazila of Rajshahi on Wednesday afternoon.
The injured was identified as Biraj Ali, 47, son of late Amir Mollah of Ramchandrapur village. He is the general secretary</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 20:28:32 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>