<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 15:23:16 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>LC openings rise amid dollar stability, settlements face hurdles</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/lc-openings-rise-amid-dollar-stability-settlements-face-hurdles</link><description>Import activity in Bangladesh showed signs of a modest recovery in the first five months of the current fiscal year (FY26), supported by a stable dollar market and preparations for Ramadan.
However, the recovery remains fragile as businesses adopt a cautious ‘wait-and-see’ approach ahe</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 11:45:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ICC replaces Bangladesh with Scotland at T20 World Cup: Report</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/icc-replaces-bangladesh-with-scotland-at-t20-world-cup-report</link><description>The ICC has replaced Bangladesh with Scotland at the 2026 T20 World Cup, the decision coming after nearly three weeks of negotiations with the BCB over its refusal to send a team to India due to security concerns, according to a report by ESPN Cricinfo.
 
The ICC is understood to have sent t</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 12:00:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Media must be strengthened to check rumours: Ali Imam</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/media-must-be-strengthened-to-check-rumours-ali-imam</link><description>Food and Land Adviser Ali Imam Majumdar on Saturday called upon the mainstream media to play an effective role in curbing rumours spread through social media.
He said in the current era of information technology, print and electronic media are facing big challenges.
“Especially through soci</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 12:15:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Russian Oscar hopeful believes in the power of animation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/entertainment/russian-oscar-hopeful-believes-in-the-power-of-animation</link><description>Konstantin Bronzit may be one of Russia's most celebrated animators, but he still gets the jitters during awards season.
The 60-year-old writer-director is nominated for an Academy Award for Best Animated Short Film this year for the 15-minute "Three Sisters", competing alongside productions from</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 12:30:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Political party reform more important than state reform: Experts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/political-party-reform-more-important-than-state-reform-experts</link><description>Reforming political parties is more important than reforming the state itself if transparency, accountability and good governance are to be ensured in Bangladesh, according to experts.
They said this at a policy dialogue organised by the Centre for Governance Studies (CGS) on Saturday, UNB reports</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 12:45:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat to form inclusive government if voted to power: Dr Shafiqur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-to-form-inclusive-government-if-voted-to-power-dr-shafiqur</link><description>Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami Ameer Dr Shafiqur Rahman today (Saturday) said his party would form an inclusive government involving all sections of people if it comes to power.
"If we get the opportunity to govern, Insha'Allah we will form a government taking everyone along. United efforts are needed</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 13:00:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP feud sparks attacks on 11 homes in Shariatpur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-feud-sparks-attacks-on-11-homes-in-shariatpur</link><description>At least 11 houses have been vandalised, three set on fire, and more than 500 crude bombs exploded during attacks in Shariatpur Sadar, allegedly triggered by a dispute over joining the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP).
The incident took place around 11:00 pm on Friday in Chargayghar village of S</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 13:15:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No legal bar for govt officials to campaign for ‘Yes’ vote: Ali Riaz</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/no-legal-bar-for-govt-officials-to-campaign-for-yes-vote-ali-riaz</link><description>Professor Ali Riaz, Special Assistant to the Chief Adviser and Chief Coordinator of the referendum campaign, on Saturday said there is no legal bar for government officials from taking part in the campaign in favor of “Yes” vote in the referendum.
He said those who laid down their live</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 13:30:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US envoys in Israel to discuss future of Gaza, sources tell Reuters</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-envoys-in-israel-to-discuss-future-of-gaza-sources-tell-reuters</link><description>US envoys Steve Witkoff and Jared Kushner were in Israel on Saturday to meet with Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu, mainly to discuss Gaza, two people briefed on the matter said, as local authorities reported further violence in the enclave.
The US on Thursday announced plans for a &amp;ldquo</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 13:45:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Keraniganj BNP leader dies after shooting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/keraniganj-bnp-leader-dies-after-shooting</link><description>A union-level BNP leader, who was shot by miscreants on Thursday night in Keraniganj, has died after two days of hospitalisation.
Hasan Mollah, general secretary of Hazratpur Union BNP, died on Saturday around 4:00 pm while receiving treatment at Holy Family Hospital, police said.</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 14:00:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>After two decades, Ctg’s Polo Ground awaits Tarique’s return</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/after-two-decades-ctgs-polo-ground-awaits-tariques-return</link><description>After nearly 21 years, the historic Polo Ground in the port city of Chattogram is once again set to witness a defining political moment as BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman prepares to address a major election rally on Sunday.
The port city is buzzing with excitement as BNP leaders, activists and suppor</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 14:15:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tasnim Jara promises ‘no service, no bill’ gas policy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tasnim-jara-promises-no-service-no-bill-gas-policy</link><description>Tasnim Jara, an independent candidate of Dhaka-9 seat, on Saturday unveiled her election manifesto, pledging to stop billing residents for undelivered gas and ensure local issues are tracked through a transparent digital dashboard.
In a post on her verified Facebook page, the former National Citiz</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 14:30:43 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>