<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 08:31:49 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Sarjis welcomes Tarique's return with call for unity</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/sarjis-welcomes-tariques-return-with-call-for-unity</link><description>NCP leader Sarjis Alam has welcomed Tarique's return to Bangladesh, saying he hopes political forces will work “together” to rebuild the country.In a Facebook post on Thursday, Sarjis said Tarique was returning at a critical juncture for Bangladesh's political landscape as the country g</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 05:15:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Red bus with ‘Bangladesh first’ slogan ready at Dhaka airport for Tarique</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/red-bus-with-bangladesh-first-slogan-ready-at-dhaka-airport-for-tarique</link><description>A red bus bearing the slogan ‘Bangladesh First’ has been kept ready in front of the VIP terminal of Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport ahead of BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman’s onward journey.
Party sources said Tarique Rahman will travel on the bus to the stage set up on</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 05:30:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman arrived in Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-rahman-lands-in-dhaka</link><description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman arrived at Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport in the city on Thursday morning at around 11:40 am.
Earlier, the Bangladesh Biman flight carrying Tarique Rahman from London landed him at Sylhet airport, then another landed him in Dhaka airport.
BNP leaders and</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 05:45:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Unforgettable event awaits in country's history, says Salahuddin</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/unforgettable-event-awaits-in-countrys-history-says-salahuddin</link><description>BNP Standing Committee member Salahuddin Ahmed has said an unforgettable event is going to take place in the country's 55-year history with the return of Tarique Rahman.
He said BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman's return to the country is a historic and outstanding moment in the Bangladesh's demo</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 06:00:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique to contest election from Bogura-6</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-to-contest-election-from-bogura-6</link><description>The BNP has announced that its Acting Chairman, Tarique, will contest the 13th national election from the Bogura-6 (Sadar) constituency, a seat previously held by his mother, former prime minister Khaleda Zia.
After returning to Bangladesh, Tarique is expected to complete voter registration, pavin</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 06:15:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique's schedule for the first three days back home</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tariques-schedule-for-the-first-three-days-back-home</link><description>Thursday
The flight carrying BNP leader Tarique Rahman landed at Dhaka's Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport at 11:11 am.
From the airport, he will travel to the 300 Feet Road in Purbachal, where a reception has been organised, reports bdnews24.com.
After the reception, he will go to Evercare</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 06:30:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cold wave felt in Dhaka as temperature drops to seasonal low</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cold-wave-felt-in-dhaka-as-temperature-drops-to-seasonal-low</link><description>Dhaka experienced a marked spell of winter on Thursday as dense fog and cold winds swept across the capital from early morning, intensifying the chill that had so far been more pronounced in rural areas.
The city recorded a minimum temperature of 14.2 degrees Celsius on Thursday (December 25), the</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 06:17:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Christmas being celebrated across country</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/christmas-being-celebrated-across-country</link><description>The Christmas Day commemorating the birthday of Jesus Christ is being celebrated today with religious fervour and festivity across the country, as elsewhere in the world.
Special prayers are being offered at churches, which are illuminated for the occasion, while makeshift Christmas trees are set</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 06:32:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP senior leaders welcome Tarique at Dhaka airport</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-senior-leaders-welcome-tarique-at-dhaka-airport</link><description>Senior leaders of the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) on Thursday welcomed the party’s Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman upon his arrival in Dhaka after a decade and a half in exile.
The party Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir and members of the party’s standing committee g</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 06:47:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique leaves for 300 feet area from airport</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-leaves-for-300-feet-area-from-airport</link><description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman left Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport on Thursday afternoon for the reception venue in 300 feet area in a bulletproof bus.
The bus carrying Tarique Rahman and others departed the airport for the reception venue at 12:40 pm, where he is scheduled to briefly</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 07:02:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chattogram Royals owners withdraw on eve of BPL over unpaid dues</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/chattogram-royals-owners-withdraw-on-eve-of-bpl-over-unpaid-dues</link><description>The owners of Chattogram Royals have relinquished control of the franchise just a day before the start of the Bangladesh Premier League (BPL).
They failed to meet financial obligations to players, leaving BCB to step in and take temporary charge of the team.
The franchise owner, Abdul Kaiyum, inf</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 07:17:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique calls Yunus from airport</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-calls-yunus-from-airport</link><description>BNP leader Tarique Rahman spoke by phone with Chief Advisor Muhammad Yunus shortly after landing in Dhaka.
During the conversation, Tarique thanked the interim government for the arrangements made for his return, particularly the security measures, reports bdnews24.com.
“On my behalf and on</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 07:32:47 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>