<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 04:12:51 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Bangladesh's telecom sector 'designed to fail'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/bangladeshs-telecom-sector-designed-to-fail</link><description>Grameenphone Chief Executive Officer Yasir Azman has issued a blunt warning that Bangladesh's telecommunications sector is becoming commercially unviable due to excessive taxation, unresolved audit disputes and restrictive regulation, saying the overall environment is "designed to fail".
In an int</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 00:31:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Lovello Ice-cream's profit up 107pc in Q2</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/lovello-ice-creams-profit-up-107pc-in-q2</link><description>Listed ice-cream producer Taufika Foods and Lovello Ice-cream experienced a 107.14 per cent increase in profit in the second quarter of FY26 to Tk 113.88 million, as sales increased significantly compared to the same quarter of the previous year.
In the second quarter (October-December) of FY25, t</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 00:46:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cancel draft energy-power master plan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cancel-draft-energy-power-master-plan</link><description>Civil society organisations have strongly objected to the interim government's 25-year Energy and Power Sector Master Plan (EPSMP 2025).
At a press conference held in the Dhaka Reporters Unity auditorium on Sunday, they demanded the immediate suspension and complete cancellation of the draft Energ</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 01:01:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Foreign investors’ interest declining due to tax burden, financial disputes</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/foreign-investors-interest-declining-due-to-tax-burden-financial-disputes</link><description>Grameenphone CEO Yasir Azman has said foreign investors are losing interest in Bangladesh as a telecom sector investment destination due to the “tax burden and long-standing financial disputes.”
He said the negative sentiment is affecting not only the telecom sector but also other sect</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 01:16:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>T-bill yields mixed as banks turn cautious</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/t-bill-yields-mixed-as-banks-turn-cautious</link><description>The yields on treasury bills (T-bills) showed a mixed trend on Sunday as banks opted to place their excess liquidity in shorter-tenure securities rather than longer-dated ones, amid uncertainty ahead of the national polls.
According to auction results, the cut-off yield, generally regarded as the</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 01:31:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gender equality can't be a sideline issue but a nat'l issue</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/gender-equality-cant-be-a-sideline-issue-but-a-natl-issue</link><description>Gender equality cannot be a sideline issue but be an economic and national issue and women's dignity cannot be kept as a topic within policies, offices and classrooms and it must be recognised both privately and publicly, observes Barrister Zaima Rahman.
"When women are welcomed rather than sideli</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 01:46:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Finalise house rental for Hajj pilgrims by Feb 1’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/finalise-house-rental-for-hajj-pilgrims-by-feb-1</link><description>The Ministry of Religious Affairs (MoRA) has directed the country's lead Hajj agencies to finalise the house rental formalities for the intending Bangladeshi Hajj pilgrims by February 1.
The ministry issued the directive following the Saudi government's concern as most of the country's Hajj agenci</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 02:01:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat coalition faces questions over sharing 47 remaining seats, manifesto</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-coalition-faces-questions-over-sharing-47-remaining-seats-manifesto</link><description>How will the 47 seats be divided in the alliance led by Jamaat-e-Islami now that Islami Andolan Bangladesh has quit?
Although it’s called an 11-party alliance, there are only 10 parties -- will another party be brought into the coalition?
Will the alliance issue a joint manifesto after the</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 02:16:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>At least 21 dead as two high-speed trains derail in Spain</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/at-least-21-dead-as-two-high-speed-trains-derail-in-spain</link><description>A high-speed train derailed and smashed into another oncoming train in southern Spain on Sunday, pushing the second train off the tracks and down an embankment in a collision that police sources confirmed to Reuters had killed at least 21 people.
The cause for the crash is not yet known, Spanish T</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 02:31:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>10 DU journalism students receive 'Sitara Parveen Award'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/10-du-journalism-students-receive-sitara-parveen-award</link><description>Ten students of the Department of Mass Communication and Journalism at the University of Dhaka (DU) have received the 'Professor Sitara Parveen Award' in recognition of their outstanding academic performance in the 2023 undergraduate examinations.
The award-giving ceremony was held on Sunday (Janu</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 02:46:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ishwardi Upazila Health Complex itself in bad health</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/ishwardi-upazila-health-complex-itself-in-bad-health</link><description>Proper healthcare service is being hampered at the Ishwardi Upazila Health Complex in the district's Ishwardi upazila due to poor infrastructure and unhealthy environment stemming from lack of supervision and renovation by the authorities.
A spot visit found that used tissues, saline packets, band</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 03:01:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC clears prominent figures as appeal hearing ends</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-clears-prominent-figures-as-appeal-hearing-ends</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) on Sunday concluded its final day of appeal hearings clearing the way for several prominent candidates, including BNP Vice-Chairman Abdul Awal Mintoo and leader Aslam Chowdhury, to contest the upcoming National Parliament election.
However, the commission disqualified</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 03:16:58 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>