<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 17:24:08 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>HC issues rule questioning legality of RPO provision on alliance candidates’ symbols</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hc-issues-rule-questioning-legality-of-rpo-provision-on-alliance-candidates-symbols</link><description>The High Court on Monday issued a rule asking why the provision in the Representation of the People Order (RPO) that requires candidates in an electoral alliance to use their respective party symbols while contesting elections should not be declared illegal.
The bench of Justice Fatema Najib and J</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 15:00:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Remittances cross $13 billion in first 5 months of fiscal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/remittances-cross-13-billion-in-first-5-months-of-fiscal</link><description>Bangladesh received its highest monthly remittance inflow of the current fiscal year FY 2025-26, crossing US $2.88 billion November.This substantial inflow translates to an average daily remittance of approximately $96.3 million. In the five month of the current fiscal year Bangladeshi expatriates</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 15:15:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ctg Port suspension lifted, higher fees return</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/high-court-revokes-stay-clearing-way-for-collection-of-increased-chattogram-port-charges</link><description>The High Court has lifted its stay on the increased fees at Chattogram Port, removing any legal barrier to their collection, according to port officials.
The chamber judge of the Supreme Court revoked the injunction last Tuesday, prompting the Chittagong Port Authority’s chief finance and ac</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 15:30:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>GPH Ispat declares 5pc cash dividend despite losses</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/gph-ispat-declares-5pc-cash-dividend-despite-losses</link><description>GPH Ispat has declared a 5 per cent cash dividend for FY25 despite the company suffering a loss of Tk 247 million for the year, owing to costlier raw materials and higher finance expenses.
The Chittagong-based steel manufacturer has reported earnings per share (EPS) of Tk 0.51 in the negative in F</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 15:45:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>WHO backs use of GLP-1 therapies for obesity, warns access will remain limited</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/who-backs-use-of-glp-1-therapies-for-obesity-warns-access-will-remain-limited</link><description>The World Health Organisation on Monday issued its first guideline on the use of GLP-1 therapies for obesity, conditionally recommending them as part of long-term treatment for the condition, which affects more than 1 billion people globally according to the agency.
The guidance comes as demand fo</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 16:00:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt declares Khaleda Zia a 'VIP'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-declares-khaleda-zia-a-vip</link><description>The government has declared BNP Chairperson and former Prime Minister Begum Khaleda Zia a ‘very important person’ (VIP).
A notification in this regard was issued on Monday.
Mohammad Abdul Wadud Chowdhury, Director General (Administration) at the office of the Chief Adviser, signed the</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 15:54:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tulip calls Bangladesh plot corruption verdict ‘predictable’, ‘farcical’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tulip-calls-bangladesh-plot-corruption-verdict-predictable-farcical</link><description>British MP Tulip Siddiq has rejected her sentence in Bangladesh on corruption charges, branding the verdict “flawed and farcical” and “as predictable as it is unjustified.”
Speaking to the press, Tulip alleged that Bangladeshi authorities attempted to discredit her using &amp;l</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 16:09:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Modi expresses concern over Khaleda's health, offers support</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/modi-expresses-concern-over-khaledas-health-offers-support</link><description>Expressing deep concern over BNP Chairperson Begum Khaleda Zia's health condition, Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi on Monday said India stands ready to extend all possible support in whatever way they can.
"Deeply concerned to learn about the health of Begum Khaleda Zia, who has contributed to</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 16:24:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prof Yunus, KOICA president discuss LDC transition support</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/prof-yunus-koica-president-discuss-ldc-transition-support</link><description>Chief Adviser Prof Muhammad Yunus and President of the Korea International Cooperation Agency (KOICA) Chang Won-sam on Monday discussed enhancing development cooperation, investment, skills training and support for Bangladesh’s smooth graduation from LDC status.
“It’s truly great</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 16:39:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP Standing Committee rushes meeting on Khaleda’s health</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bnp-standing-committee-rushes-meeting-on-khaledas-health</link><description>The BNP's highest policy-making body, the National Standing Committee, is in an emergency meeting over the party’s Chairperson Khaleda Zia’s health.
The meeting began at 9am on Monday at her Gulshan office.
Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman is presiding over the brainstorming from London</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 16:54:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>FIFA to broadcast World Cup match schedule unveiling on Saturday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/fifa-to-broadcast-world-cup-match-schedule-unveiling-on-saturday</link><description>FIFA said it will reveal the updated match schedule for the 2026 World Cup in a live global broadcast from Washington on Saturday, nearly 24 hours after the final draw determines the tournament’s unprecedented 12 groups of four.
The show, set for 12:00pm EST (1700 GMT), will confirm venues a</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 17:09:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cold waves may sweep parts of Bangladesh after middle of December</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/cold-waves-may-sweep-parts-of-bangladesh-after-middle-of-december</link><description>One or two mild to moderate cold waves may sweep across the western and northern parts of Bangladesh in the second half of December, the Bangladesh Meteorological Department (BMD) has forecast.
The prediction came in a long-term weather forecast for the current month, issued on Monday.
It warned</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 17:24:08 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>