<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 06:34:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Sugar-laden truck set on fire in Madaripur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/sugar-laden-truck-set-on-fire-in-madaripur</link><description>A group of miscreants set fire to a sugar-laden truck and vandalised a police vehicle in Shibchar upazila of Madaripur on Thursday morning.
The incident occurred around 8:30 am in the border area of Shibchar upazila, reports UNB.
According to highway police, activists of the banned student organi</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 03:10:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>President Trump signs government funding bill, ending shutdown after a record 43-day disruption</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/president-trump-signs-government-funding-bill-ending-shutdown-after-a-record-43-day-disruption</link><description>President Donald Trump signed a government funding bill Wednesday night, ending a record 43-day shutdown that caused financial stress for federal workers who went without paychecks, stranded scores of travelers at airports and generated long lines at some food banks.
The shutdown magnified partisa</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 03:25:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCP leaders beaten up in Mymensingh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ncp-leaders-beaten-up-in-mymensingh</link><description>Three people, including two leaders of the National Citizen Party (NCP), have been beaten up as they attempted to form a human chain at Ishwarganj Upazila Health Complex in Mymensingh, alleging “irregularities, corruption, broker misconduct, and syndicates”.
Police arrested one person</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 03:40:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Miscreants set fire to passenger bus in Tangail</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/miscreants-set-fire-to-passenger-bus-in-tangail</link><description>A passenger bus was set on fire by unidentified miscreants in Basail upazila of Tangail on Wednesday night.
The incident took place around 12:30 am on the Dhaka-Tangail highway in the Baikhola area.
According to police and local sources, the bus — named Bangla Star— was travelling fro</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 03:55:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tight security at ICT as tribunal prepares to set verdict date in Hasina Case</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tight-security-at-ict-as-tribunal-prepares-to-set-verdict-date-in-hasina-case</link><description>Security forces have been deployed in large numbers around the International Crimes Tribunal as it prepares to announce the date of the verdict in the crimes against humanity case against former prime minister Sheikh Hasina and two others over the July mass uprising, reports local media.Internation</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 04:10:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bus set on fire in Pallabi at midnight</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bus-set-on-fire-in-pallabi-at-midnight</link><description>Unidentified miscreants set fire to a Trust Transport Service bus while it was parked on Sagupta Road in the capital’s Pallabi area on Wednesday night.
According to the Fire Service and Civil Defence, they received the fire report at 12:10 am on Wednesday. Two firefighting units from the Pal</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 04:25:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tehran taps run dry as water crisis deepens across Iran</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/tehran-taps-run-dry-as-water-crisis-deepens-across-iran</link><description>Iran is grappling with its worst water crisis in decades, with officials warning that Tehran — a city of more than 10 million — may soon be uninhabitable if the drought gripping the country continues.
President Masoud Pezeshkian has cautioned that if rainfall does not arrive by Decembe</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 04:40:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Australian state signs country's first treaty with Indigenous people into law</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/australian-state-signs-countrys-first-treaty-with-indigenous-people-into-law</link><description>The Australian state of Victoria on Thursday signed into law the country’s first treaty with Indigenous people, hailed by advocates as a major step towards reconciliation by giving first inhabitants more oversight on decisions that concern them.
The treaty, which will take effect on Dec 12,</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 04:55:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India asks UN wildlife body to not curb its animal imports amid Ambani zoo furore</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/india-asks-un-wildlife-body-to-not-curb-its-animal-imports-amid-ambani-zoo-furore</link><description>India has urged a UN wildlife trade body not to curb its imports of endangered species, saying it has tightened oversight amid growing allegations of irregular animal shipments to a large private zoo run by Asia's richest family.
Vantara, a 3,500-acre zoo in Gujarat state run by the philanthropic</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 05:10:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>7 vehicles on fire over 7 hours since midnight</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/7-vehicles-on-fire-over-7-hours-since-midnight</link><description>Fires have reportedly broken out on seven vehicles in the seven hours after midnight on Wednesday in Dhaka, Tangail, Munshiganj, Gopalganj, and Shariatpur.
Rashedul Khalid, officer-on-duty at the Fire Service Control Room, confirmed the incidents had taken place from 12 am to 7:20 am on Thursday,</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 05:25:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Petrol bombs hurled at Grameen Bank branch in Gopalganj</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/petrol-bombs-hurled-at-grameen-bank-branch-in-gopalganj</link><description>Unidentified miscreants hurled petrol bombs at a branch of Grameen Bank in Gopalganj early Thursday.
According to police, the attack took place late at night targeting the Ulipur branch of Grameen Bank in Gopalganj Sadar upazila.
The miscreants reportedly threw five to six petrol bombs from a bla</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 05:40:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Oil prices edge down</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/oil-prices-edge-down</link><description>Oil prices edged lower on Thursday, extending losses from the previous session, after a report showing rising crude inventories in the US reinforced concerns that the global supply is more than sufficient to meet current fuel demand.
Brent crude futures fell 9 cents, or 0.1%, to $62.62 a barrel at</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 05:55:06 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>