<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 16:41:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Islamic clerics will lead nation: Jamaat chief</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-e-islami-chief-shafiqur-urges-islamic-clerics-to-lead-bangladesh-alongside-mosques</link><description>Jamaat-e-Islami chief Shafiqur Rahman has expressed hope that the country’s Islamic scholars, known as Ulama, will provide leadership not only in mosques but also in national affairs.
On Saturday, he said involvement of ulama in societal governance could “eliminate” all forms of</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 12:58:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fire breaks out at scrap warehouse in Chattogram</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/fire-breaks-out-at-scrap-warehouse-in-chattogram</link><description>A fire has broken out at a scrap warehouse in the Kalpolok residential area of Bakalia in Chattogram.
According to the Fire Service control room, four units from Chandanpura and Lamarbazar stations were deployed around 5:30pm to douse the flames.
Firefighters are attempting to contain the blaze,</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 13:13:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bayer’s innovative ways of boosting farm output while preserving environment</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bayers-innovative-ways-of-boosting-farm-output-while-preserving-environment</link><description>To meet the consumption need of an ever-expanding population across the globe it is important to increase production of food, feed and fibre. However, while doing so, it is equally important to refrain from harming the ecosystems. Natasha Santos, Global Head of Sustainability and Strategic Engageme</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 13:43:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt takes plan to honour country’s living legends: Farooki</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-takes-plan-to-honour-countrys-living-legends-farooki</link><description>Cultural Affairs Adviser Mostofa Sarwar Farooki has said the government has a plan to honour and celebrate the life and works of the country’s living legends.
He said this in a Facebook post on Saturday, responding to the question raised on the social media about why noted writers an</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 13:58:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sitakunda clash: 1 killed, 16 injured in Jungle Salimpur gang fight</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/sitakunda-clash-1-killed-16-injured-in-jungle-salimpur-gang-fight</link><description>One person was killed and 16 others injured in a clash between two criminal gangs over territory in the hilly area of Jungle Salimpur in Sitakunda upazila of Chattogram on Saturday evening.
The incident took place around 6pm.
The identity of the deceased has not yet been confirmed.
Jungle Salimp</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 14:28:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Russian strike hits passenger train in Ukraine, injuring dozens</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/russian-strike-hits-passenger-train-in-ukraine-injuring-dozens</link><description>A Russian drone strike hit a passenger train at a station in Ukraine’s northern Sumy region, injuring dozens of people, officials said on Saturday.
“A brutal Russian drone strike on the railway station in Shostka, Sumy region,” Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky wrote on Tele</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 14:43:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UK PM Starmer to visit India on 8-9 October, says Indian foreign ministry</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/uk-pm-starmer-to-visit-india-on-8-9-october-says-indian-foreign-ministry</link><description>British Prime Minister Keir Starmer will make his first official visit to India on 8-9 October, India's Ministry of External Affairs said in a statement on Saturday.
Britain and India signed a free trade agreement in July during a visit by Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi, sealing a deal to cut</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 15:13:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC dialogue with media persons on Monday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-dialogue-with-media-persons-on-monday</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) will hold a dialogue with journalists on Monday ahead of the upcoming 13th National Parliamentary Election.
The dialogue will take place at the conference room of the EC Secretariat in Agargaon, Dhaka, said Ashadul Haque, Assistant Director (Public Relations) of EC.
E</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 15:28:57 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>