<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 09:34:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>First session of parliament likely in March: Home Minister</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/first-session-of-parliament-likely-in-march-home-minister</link><description>The first session of the 13th national parliament is expected to be held next month, possibly beginning on March 12 or a day or two earlier.
Home Minister Salahuddin Ahmed shared the information in a post on his verified Facebook account tonight, reports BSS. 
In the post, he wrote that the</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 06:14:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladeshi among 8 arrested over alleged India terror plot: NDTV</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/bangladeshi-among-8-arrested-over-alleged-india-terror-plot-ndtv</link><description>India has arrested eight people, including a Bangladeshi national, suspected of plotting a major terror conspiracy with alleged backing from Pakistan’s Inter-Services Intelligence (ISI) and Bangladesh-based extremist groups.
Six suspects, identified as Mizanur Rahman, Mohammed Shabat, Umar,</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 06:29:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Saudi Ambassador meets PM Tarique Rahman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/saudi-ambassador-meets-pm-tarique-rahman</link><description>Saudi Arabia’s Ambassador to Dhaka Dr Abdullah ibn Dhafer ibn Ubayya paid a courtesy call on Prime Minister Tarique Rahman on Sunday.
The meeting was held at 11am at the Cabinet Division of the Secretariat, said Prime Minister’s Additional Press Secretary Atikur Rahaman Rumon.
Foreign</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 06:44:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Selima Rahman remains hospitalised with cardiac complications</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/selima-rahman-remains-hospitalised-with-cardiac-complications</link><description>BNP Standing Committee Member and former minister Selima Rahman remained under treatment at the Coronary Care Unit (CCU) of United Hospital in the capital with cardiac complications.
She was taken to the hospital on February 19 after experiencing sudden chest pain, said BNP Media Cell member Sayru</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 06:59:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Five held over alleged extortion-linked attack on Dhaka embroidery factory</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/five-held-over-alleged-extortion-linked-attack-on-dhaka-embroidery-factory</link><description>Five people have been arrested over an attack on an embroidery factory in Dhaka’s Adabor after workers surrounded the local police station at midnight, demanding action.
Adabor Police Station chief (OC) Abdul Malek said the factory owner, Mustafizur Rahman, filed a case naming eight people</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 07:45:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>PM chairs meeting on Dhaka airport's third terminal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/pm-chairs-meeting-on-dhaka-airports-third-terminal</link><description>Prime Minister Tarique Rahman has chaired a meeting on the long-delayed third terminal at Dhaka's Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport, with a focus on bringing the facility into operation as quickly as possible.
The meeting began on Sunday afternoon at the Secretariat, according to bdnews24.com</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 08:00:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Veteran journalist Saleem Samad passes away</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/veteran-journalist-saleem-samad-passes-away</link><description>Saleem Samad, an award-winning investigative journalist, writer and media rights defender, died at his residence in the capital on Sunday.
Saleem, also a member of the Jatiya Press Club, was Special Correspondent of English dailies The News Times, The Bangladesh Observer and The Asian Age.
His fi</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 07:45:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How information on social media shapes our thoughts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/others/how-information-on-social-media-shapes-our-thoughts</link><description>Human beings can't live without being affected by its surrounding, people, institutions, culture, technology, beliefs, and religious values; the practices, habits, and norms they inherit are derived from these. 
The information we learn, practice, and hold to thrive comes from institutions, religi</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 08:00:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DU VC Professor Niaz Ahmed Khan resigns</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/du-vc-professor-niaz-ahmed-khan-resigns</link><description>Dhaka University (DU) Vice-Chancellor Professor Dr Niaz Ahmed Khan has resigned from his post.He formally handed over the resignation letter to Education Minister ANM Ehsanul Haq Milon on Saturday (February 22). According to sources, he stepped down from his post citing personal and administrative</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 08:15:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Complaints lodged with ACC over ‘irregularities’ in foreign concession deals at Ctg port</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/complaints-lodged-with-acc-over-irregularities-in-foreign-concession-deals-at-ctg-port</link><description>Three complaints have been filed with the Anti-Corruption Commission(ACC), seeking an investigation into alleged irregularities and corruption in leasing key terminals of the Chattogram Port to foreign companies under concession agreements.
Md Al Amin Hossain, spokesperson of civil society organis</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 08:30:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Food we return to when life becomes tough</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/food/food-we-return-to-when-life-becomes-tough</link><description>In Bangladesh, comfort does not come on a silver spoon. It does not require coverage and buzz on the internet. It is more usually served and quietly eaten alongside a heap of hot rice, a ladle of dal, a spoonful of bhorta, maybe a fried chilli on the side. 
These are the foods people reach for whe</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 08:45:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two sentenced to death over 2023 murder of Tejgaon College student</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/two-sentenced-to-death-over-2023-murder-of-tejgaon-college-student</link><description>A Dhaka court has sentenced two men to death for the murder of Tejgaon College student Ikram Hossain Molla in 2023.
Dhaka Metropolitan Sessions Judge Md Sabbir Fayez delivered the verdict on Sunday, according to court official Md Riaz Hossain.
The convicts are Shanto Mia, a friend of the victim,</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 09:00:45 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>