<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 12:39:34 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Apex court heaving under logjam of half-million cases</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/apex-court-heaving-under-logjam-of-half-million-cases</link><description>A decade of steady case disposal falls short of a pace warranted to deal with a logjam of cases Bangladesh's apex court faces amid a rush of litigants in courts across the country, sources say.
A predominant feature in the piling up of pending cases is numerous cases implicating several hundred ac</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 11:00:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>RAB arrests eight in Narsingdi with 11 firearms</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/rab-arrests-eight-in-narsingdi-with-11-firearms</link><description>The Rapid Action Battalion has arrested eight people with 11 firearms from the riverine areas of Raipura in Narsingdi, saying the weapons were kept to “assert territorial dominance”.
According to the RAB, the arms were smuggled in from a neighbouring country through river routes, while</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 11:15:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP to revoke power sector indemnity provision if voted to power: Rizvi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-to-revoke-power-sector-indemnity-provision-if-voted-to-power-rizvi</link><description>BNP Senior Joint Secretary General Ruhul Kabir Rizvi on Saturday said their party would abolish the indemnity provision in the power sector if it returns to power.
Speaking at the ‘CAB Youth Parliament 2025’ organised by the Consumers Association of Bangladesh (CAB) at Dhaka University</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 10:22:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BRAC Bank partners with ACI Godrej Agrovet to offer advanced Transaction Banking solutions</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/brac-bank-partners-with-aci-godrej-agrovet-to-offer-advanced-transaction-banking-solutions</link><description>BRAC Bank has entered into a partnership agreement with ACI Godrej Agrovet Private Limited to implement an advanced transaction banking solution that optimises payment operations and operational efficiency.
With smart and efficient receivable management, the strategic partnership will streamline d</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 10:52:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Community Bank holds AML &amp; CFT Conference 2025</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/community-bank-holds-aml-cft-conference-2025</link><description>Community Bank Bangladesh PLC. organized its Annual AML &amp; CFT Conference 2025 with the active participation of officials from across the Bank. The day-long conference was held on Saturday (1 November 2025).
Mr. Md. Mofizur Rahman Khan Chowdhury, Head (Acting) of the Bangladesh Financial Intelligen</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 11:22:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Suha Travels Thailand brings surprise to medical tourism</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/suha-travels-thailand-brings-surprise-to-medical-tourism</link><description>Suha Travels Thailand has brought a new surprise to medical tourism at the 13th Bangladesh Travel and Tourism Fair (BTTF) being held at Bangladesh-China Friendship Conference Center in the capital.
The company has brought the services of 15 renowned hospitals in Thailand to its fingertips. It has</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 11:37:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UN chief calls for justice for crimes against journalists</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/un-chief-calls-for-justice-for-crimes-against-journalists</link><description>United Nations Secretary-General António Guterres has said that journalists around the world face growing dangers while searching for the truth, including verbal abuse, legal threats, physical attacks, imprisonment, and torture.
“Some are even killed,” he said in his message mar</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 11:52:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UGC and British Council sign agreement at House of Lords to improve quality of education</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ugc-and-british-council-sign-agreement-at-house-of-lords-to-improve-quality-of-education</link><description>A partnership agreement has been signed between the Higher Education Acceleration and Transformation (HEAT) project, being implemented by University Grants Commission (UGC) of Bangladesh and the British Council to enhance the quality of education in Bangladesh’s higher education sector.
This</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 12:07:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>'Poor governance' led to regime changes in Bangladesh: India's security chief</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/poor-governance-led-to-regime-changes-in-bangladesh-indias-security-chief</link><description>India’s National Security Advisor Ajit Doval has said changes of government in Bangladesh, Nepal, and Sri Lanka over the past three and a half years stemmed from “poor governance”, reports bdnews24.com, citing The Hindu.
On Friday, he described governance as the central pillar of</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 12:22:05 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>