<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 17:36:35 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>ICT has no plan to issue warrants against additional defence personnel: Shafiqul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ict-has-no-plan-to-issue-warrants-against-additional-defence-personnel-shafiqul</link><description>Chief Adviser's Press Secretary Shafiqul Alam today said the International Crimes Tribunal (ICT) Chief Prosecutor informed that currently there are no plans to issue warrants against additional defence personnel.
"We have been informed by the Office of the Chief Prosecutor of the ICT that there ar</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 14:50:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>At least 60 killed in attack on Sudan’s Al-Fashir</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/africa/at-least-60-killed-in-attack-on-sudans-al-fashir</link><description>Drone and artillery strikes by the paramilitary Rapid Support Forces on a shelter in the Sudanese city of Al Fashir killed at least 60 people on Friday night and Saturday morning, according to local activists.
Al-Fashir is under siege by the RSF as it struggles to wrest control of the army's last</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 15:05:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Should Bangladesh Bank be buying dollars right now?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/should-bangladesh-bank-be-buying-dollars-right-now</link><description>Not so long ago, just over a year, Bangladesh Bank (BB) was criticised for failing to meet the rising demand for US dollars. Foreign exchange reserves had fallen from a peak of about $48 billion to less than $20 billion, and panic about dollar shortages dominated headlines. In a striking reversal,</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 15:35:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Inflation that defies reason</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/inflation-that-defies-reason</link><description>After showing a downward trend for a month or two, inflation rose again in September, renewing concerns among consumers who have been severely affected by high prices over the past three years. Taming this persistent inflation has been one of the top priorities of the interim government. In pursuit</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 15:50:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The saga of plurilateral trade deals</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/the-saga-of-plurilateral-trade-deals</link><description>Over the last couple of years, several members of the World Trade Organisation (WTO) have been negotiating issues still not covered by the multilateral trade negotiations under the WTO framework, thereby bypassing the multilateral approach. The result of the move is a rise in talks on plurilateral</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 16:05:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Will this Gaza ceasefire hold?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/will-this-gaza-ceasefire-hold</link><description>The guns have fallen silent in Gaza, at least for the time being. After two ruinous years of Israel's bombing, starvation and deprivation in Gaza, the first phase of a US-brokered ceasefire between Israel and Hamas has come into force. As the Israeli Defence Forces (IDF) withdraw to predetermined l</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 16:20:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DU treasurer upholds vital role of Islamic banking in global economy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/du-treasurer-upholds-vital-role-of-islamic-banking-in-global-economy</link><description>Dhaka University Treasurer Professor M. Jahangir Alam Chowdhury on Saturday said Islamic banking and finance continue to play an increasingly vital role in the global economy — not merely for being interest-free, but also for their ethical and socially responsible principles.
He made the rem</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 16:35:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ties with India must be based on equality: Fakhrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bnp-seeks-friendship-with-india-on-equal-footing-says-mirza-fakhrul</link><description>BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir has said the party seeks friendly relations with India, but only on the principle of equality.
Speaking on Saturday afternoon at a memorial event in Gazipur’s Kapasia, he said India must refrain from “interfering” in Bangladesh's</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 17:05:54 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>