<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 04:41:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>A new dawn for democratic media</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/a-new-dawn-for-democratic-media</link><description>The print media in Bangladesh is going through one of the most critical periods in its history. Advertisements shrinking in number, production costs rising, and readership dwindling have pushed newspapers, especially ones that carry serious and public interest-based content, to the point of extinct</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 16:31:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A market run by non-market forces</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/a-market-run-by-non-market-forces</link><description>A former lead economist of the World Bank (WB)'s Dhaka office, Dr Zahid Hussain recently said what Bangladesh economy is experiencing at the moment is a form of stagflation. Stagflation in developed economies like in the UK is characterized by high inflation, low growth and rising unemployment. The</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 16:46:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Textile sector needs urgent support</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/textile-sector-needs-urgent-support</link><description>The country's textile sector, the backbone of export economy and the foundation on which the garment industry stands, is facing an existential crisis. Nowhere is this more evident than in the country's spinning mills, where mounting losses, policy inertia and external pressures are pushing an entir</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 17:01:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Why agro-processing remains timid</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/why-agro-processing-remains-timid</link><description>If agro-processing is value-addition to farm outputs such as crops, livestock, fish, timber etc., Bangladesh has a long way to go before it economically transforms the raw versions of produce into products. The country has to its credit surplus production of certain vegetables and fruits but most v</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 17:16:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Man held with ‘toy pistol’ at Inqilab Moncho rally</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/man-detained-at-inqilab-moncho-rally-for-carrying-firearm-later-found-to-be-toy-pistol</link><description>Police have detained a youth at the Inqilab Moncho’s rally in Shahbagh, initially reported by some protesters on social media as an “armed individual”.
The incident occurred around 8pm, but by 9pm, Ramna Division Deputy Commissioner Masud Alam clarified that the detainee, identif</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 17:31:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Death rates in hybrids ‘three times higher’ than petrol cars, data shows</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/death-rates-in-hybrids-three-times-higher-than-petrol-cars-data-shows</link><description>UK newspapers have reported, citing official data, that motorists in hybrid cars are three times more likely to die than those in petrol cars.
Analysing figures from the Department of Transport, the newspapers said 122 people died in collisions involving hybrid vehicles and 777 in petrol car crash</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 17:46:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khaleda Zia’s condition turns extremely critical, say physicians</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/khaleda-zias-condition-turns-extremely-critical-say-physicians</link><description>The health condition of BNP Chairperson and former Prime Minister Begum Khaleda Zia, who is being treated in the Critical Care Unit (CCU) of Evercare Hospital, has worsened and become extremely critical, members of her medical board said on Monday night.
“Khaleda Zia’s condition is ext</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 18:01:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Remittances hit $2.93 billion in 28 days of December</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/remittances-hit-293-billion-in-28-days-of-december</link><description>The upward trend in remittances sent by expatriate Bangladeshis has continued in December, with receiving over US $ 2.93 billion in 28 days of the month.
Bangladesh received $15.97 billion inward remittance so far in the current fiscal year FY 2025-26.
According to the latest update from Banglade</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 19:18:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khaleda Zia no more</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/khaleda-zia-no-more</link><description>Khaleda Zia, the country’s first female prime minister and chairperson of the BNP, has died aged 79.
Her personal physician Dr AZM Zahid Hossain said she breathed her last early on Tuesday while receiving treatment at Evercare Hospital in Dhaka.
Members of her family were present at the hos</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 02:21:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>15 years of investment, little modal shift</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/15-years-of-investment-little-modal-shift</link><description>An enormous amount of money had been invested in developing Bangladesh's communications system over the past 15 years but modal transport share remained heavily skewed toward overburdened roads for no significant shift to rail, water, or air transport.
A baseline study carried out under the Nation</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 02:36:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nearly 200 BNP leaders file as independents, defying party decision</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/nearly-200-bnp-leaders-file-as-independents-defying-party-decision</link><description>After seven years off the ballot, hundreds of Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) leaders sought the party’s "sheaf of paddy" symbol – and many were refused. Now, in open defiance of the high command, just under 200 of them have filed nomination papers to run against BNP’s own cand</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 03:36:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP announces seven days of mourning</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/khaleda-zias-death-bnp-announces-seven-days-of-mourning</link><description>The Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) has announced seven days of mourning following the death of its chairperson and former prime minister Khaleda Zia.
The party’s Senior Joint Secretary General Ruhul Kabir Rizvi announced the decision on Tuesday at Dhaka’s Evercare Hospital, bdnews2</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 04:37:10 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>