<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 07:02:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Robi earns record profit in 2025 on lower operating costs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/robi-earns-record-profit-in-2025-on-lower-operating-costs</link><description>Robi Axiata secured a record profit of Tk 9.37 billion in 2025, riding on the lower impact of currency devaluation and reduced operating expenses amid a challenging business environment.
The second-largest telecom operator's profit jumped more than 33 per cent year-on-year despite a marginal 1 per</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 04:01:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Olympic Industries' chairman to buy 10m shares from market</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/olympic-industries-chairman-to-buy-10m-shares-from-market</link><description>The chairman of Olympic Industries is set to acquire more than five per cent of the company's shares from the market.
According to a disclosure on Thursday, Aziz Mohammad Bhai plans to purchase 10 million shares from the block market at the prevailing market price, amounting to nearly Tk 1.553 bil</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 04:16:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>'EC hastily issued gazette to avoid responsibility'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-hastily-issued-gazette-to-avoid-responsibility</link><description>Shushashoner Jonno Nagorik (SHUJAN) Secretary Badiul Alam Majumder has accused the Election Commission (EC) of hurriedly publishing the gazette of winners of the 13th Jatiya Sangsad election at midnight to avoid accountability.
He made the accusation while speaking at a press conference titled 'an</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 04:05:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ensure use of Bangla at all levels, says Jamaat ameer</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ensure-use-of-bangla-at-all-levels-says-jamaat-ameer</link><description>Jamaat-e-Islami Ameer and Leader of the Opposition Shafiqur Rahman on Thursday called for observance of the Ekushey February -- the Language Martyrs' Day and International Mother Language Day -- with due dignity and solemnity.
He also stressed the need to ensure the use of Bangla at all levels o</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 04:20:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Restricting yarn imports could cost $2.4b, put 0.4m jobs at risk</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/restricting-yarn-imports-could-cost-24b-put-04m-jobs-at-risk</link><description>The country's apparel makers have warned that restrictive measures on imported cotton yarn could trigger a staggering US$ 2.4 billion annual cost shock for the country's export-oriented apparel sector and put up to 0.4 million jobs at risk.
They have urged the government to adopt a phased 10-year</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 04:35:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Abul Kasem Khan new chairperson of BUILD</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/abul-kasem-khan-new-chairperson-of-build</link><description>Abul Kasem Khan, vice chairman of AK Khan and Company Limited, has been appointed chairperson of Business Initiative Leading Development (BUILD) for the 2026-27 tenure.
Mr Khan, a member of the BUILD trustee board since 2020, assumed the leadership role following a formal resolution at the 39th tr</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 04:50:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BTRC adds new frequency bands for NGSO satellite</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/btrc-adds-new-frequency-bands-for-ngso-satellite</link><description>The Bangladesh Telecommunication Regulatory Commission (BTRC) has appended new frequency bands for Non-Geostationary Orbit (NGSO) satellite services, signalling a significant regulatory move to meet the growing demand for next-generation satellite connectivity in Bangladesh.
In a circular issued r</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 05:05:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DU completes preparations to observe Amar Ekushey tomorrow</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/du-completes-preparations-to-observe-amar-ekushey-tomorrow</link><description>Dhaka University (DU) has completed all preparations for observing Amar Ekushey and International Mother Language Day tomorrow (Saturday), as announced in a press release from the university's Public Relations Office on Thursday.
The release states that strict entry regulations will be enforced on</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 05:20:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ICT proceedings to continue as usual: Tajul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ict-proceedings-to-continue-as-usual-tajul</link><description>Chief Prosecutor Muhmmad Tajul Islam, at a press briefing on Thursday, stated that trial proceedings of the International Crimes Tribunal (ICT) in Dhaka would continue at the same pace as before.
He noted that although the government had not made any formal announcement, the ICT had been informed</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 05:35:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>18 researchers receive PhD, 10 MPhil from DU</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/18-researchers-receive-phd-10-mphil-from-du</link><description>Eighteen researchers have received PhD degree and ten others MPhil from Dhaka University (DU) in recent times.
The degrees were approved at a Syndicate meeting on February 1, presided over by DU Vice-Chancellor Professor Niaz Ahmed Khan. The information was confirmed in a press release, issued by</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 05:50:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>MANIKGANJ, SYLHET: Too many brick kilns put public health, environment in crisis</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/manikganj-sylhet-too-many-brick-kilns-put-public-health-environment-in-crisis</link><description>An excessive number of brick klins have been polluting the environment in a union in Manikganj, while pollution from unauthorised brick klins deteriorates public health and the environment across four districts in the Sylhet division.
Our correspondent from Manikganj writes, Singair Upazila's Bald</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 06:05:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gaza deaths in war's first 15 months higher than reported, study says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/gaza-deaths-in-wars-first-15-months-higher-than-reported-study-says</link><description>More than 75,000 Palestinians were killed in the first 15 months of Israel's military assault in Gaza, a figure far higher than the 49,000 deaths local health officials announced at the time, says a new study by The Lancet Global Health medical journal.
The peer-reviewed study, published on Wednes</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 06:20:17 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>