<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 02:23:59 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Bangladesh Bank shuffles top officials following leadership change</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/bangladesh-bank-shuffles-top-officials-following-leadership-change</link><description>Bangladesh Bank has announced the immediate transfer and reassignment of five senior officials in the wake of Wednesday’s leadership change, according to an official directive.
The central bank’s official directive, signed by Director (HRD-1) Md Tarikul Islam, shuffled four directors a</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 16:42:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Parliament should impeach President Shahabuddin, says Nahid</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/parliament-should-impeach-president-shahabuddin-says-opposition-leader-nahid</link><description>Opposition Chief Whip Nahid Islam has demanded the impeachment and arrest of President Mohammed Shahabuddin.
He made the remarks on Wednesday afternoon after visiting the graves of those killed in the BDR mutiny at the Banani Military Graveyard on National Martyred Army Day.
Nahid, also National</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 16:59:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ekushey Book Fair 2026: Dhaka’s literary heartbeat returns</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/after-delays-and-disputes-ekushey-book-fair-opens-thursday-with-bangla-academy-awards</link><description>Bookworms are ready to welcome back the beloved literary festival as the Amar Ekushey Book Fair 2026 opens Thursday afternoon after repeated postponements.
Publishers rush to complete their stalls, while Bangla Academy prepares to host the official ceremony that will mark the start of a month-long</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 17:14:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DGFI gets a battle-tested chief</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/dgfi-gets-a-battle-tested-chief</link><description>Whenever a powerful appointment drops in Bangladesh, one question pops up like clockwork: Was this about merit or was this about quota?
The appointment of Major General Kaiser Rashid as the Director General of Directorate General of Forces Intelligence (DGFI) lands squarely in that debate. But a l</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 17:29:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Action taken over Barishal courtroom chaos: SC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/action-taken-over-barishal-courtroom-chaos-sc</link><description>The Supreme Court has said that necessary legal action has been taken over the disorderly incident during a session at the Barishal Additional Chief Metropolitan Court on Tuesday.
In a statement on Wednesday, the Appellate Division of the Supreme Court said that on February 24, a group of lawyers</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 17:44:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>From ballot revolution to democratic renewal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/from-ballot-revolution-to-democratic-renewal</link><description>February 12, 2026 marks a historic inflexion point in the political evolution of Bangladesh. It is not merely the date of the 13th National Parliament election but a moment that encapsulates the collective aspirations of a nation longing for renewal, justice, and participatory governance. After the</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 17:29:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Normalising extortion?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/normalising-extortion</link><description>The allegation of sponsoring extortion dogged the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) as a whole, and many of its leaders in particular, throughout the 13th parliamentary election campaign. The charges were so persistent that the party leaders are supposed to think twice, or even thrice, before sayi</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 17:44:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh's inflation puzzle</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/bangladeshs-inflation-puzzle</link><description>A recent analysis by economist Dr Zahid Hussain in an English Daily (TBS, January 31, 2026) offers a useful perspective on Bangladesh's inflation dynamics. He argues that food inflation largely operates independently of monetary policy, yet contributes to persistence in headline inflation. He furth</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 17:59:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Micro and macroeconomic sustainability</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/micro-and-macroeconomic-sustainability</link><description>The outcome of the February 12 general election, according to the British-American Ratings agency Fitch Ratings, has assuaged to a large degree the growing political and policy uncertainties during the last leg of the interim government. A turnaround in the political arena marked by the Bangladesh</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 18:14:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mansur makes unceremonious exit as govt appoints new governor</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/mansur-makes-unceremonious-exit-as-govt-appoints-new-governor</link><description>In an abrupt shakeup in the central bank's top echelon, the new government Wednesday appointed accountant-businessman Md. Mostaqur Rahman as new governor of the Bangladesh Bank (BB).



Dr Ahsan H. Mansur made an unceremonious exit as the government terminated his job contract as governor, amid</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 18:29:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Magnitude 5.1 earthquake in Myanmar shakes Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/magnitude-51-earthquake-in-myanmar-shakes-bangladesh</link><description>A magnitude 5.1 earthquake in Myanmar have shaken Dhaka and several other parts of Bangladesh.
The tremor struck at 10:51pm on Wednesday, according to the Bangladesh Meteorological Department’s earthquake monitoring centre.
Assistant Meteorologist Farzana Sultana said the epicentre was in M</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 18:44:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>14-year-old schoolgirl hacked to death outside home in Rayerbazar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/14-year-old-schoolgirl-hacked-to-death-outside-home-in-rayerbazar</link><description>A 14-year-old schoolgirl has been hacked to death in Dhaka’s Rayerbazar.
The attack took place outside her home around 9pm on Wednesday.
Her relatives took her to Dhaka Medical College Hospital (DMCH) around 10:15pm, where doctors declared her dead.
The victim Shahriar Sharmin Binti was th</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 19:45:39 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>