<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 13:15:32 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Surayya Akhtar Jahan made DNCC administrator</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/surayya-akhtar-jahan-made-dncc-administrator</link><description>The government has appointed Surayya Akhtar Jahan, additional secretary of the Local Government Division, as the administrator of Dhaka North City Corporation (DNCC).
The Local Government Division under the Local Government, Rural Development and Cooperatives Ministry, issued a gazette notificatio</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 09:56:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique promises 10m jobs if elected</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-promises-10m-jobs-if-elected</link><description>Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) chief Tarique Rahman has pledged to create 10 million jobs if his party is elected to govern.
He made the promise at a street rally in the Dhaka-8 constituency on Monday, the final day of campaigning ahead of Wednesday’s parliamentary election and referendu</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 10:11:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UAE eye upset in T20 World Cup group of death</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/cricket/uae-eye-upset-in-t20-world-cup-group-of-death</link><description>The United Arab Emirates are dreaming big as they prepare for the start of their third Twenty20 World Cup campaign on Tuesday, hoping for a famous win in what looks a very strong group.
The Gulf nation, who have won only one match in their previous two World Cups, failed to qualify for the last ed</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 10:26:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Journalists, observers can carry mobile phones inside polling stations: EC Sanaullah</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/journalists-observers-can-carry-mobile-phones-inside-polling-stations-ec-sanaullah</link><description>Election Commissioner Brig Gen (retd) Abul Fazal Md Sanaullah on Monday said journalists and election observers can carry mobile phones inside polling stations on the polling day on February 12, except for four personnel.
“Journalists and observers with mobile phones will face no problem to</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 10:41:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US Vice-President Vance heads to Armenia, Azerbaijan to push peace, trade</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/us-vice-president-vance-heads-to-armenia-azerbaijan-to-push-peace-trade</link><description>US Vice-President JD Vance will visit Armenia and Azerbaijan this week to push a Washington-brokered peace agreement that could transform energy and trade routes in the strategic South Caucasus region.
His two-day trip to Armenia, which begins later on Monday, comes just six months after the Armen</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 10:56:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IDCOL and Square Group celebrate rooftop solar partnership</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/idcol-and-square-group-celebrate-rooftop-solar-partnership</link><description>Infrastructure Development Company Limited (IDCOL), in partnership with Square Group, celebrated the successful implementation of rooftop solar power projects across Square Textiles PLC and Square Food &amp; Beverage Limited, marking a significant milestone in the group’s sustainability journey.</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 11:11:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Lebanon’s Tripoli building collapse kills 14</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/lebanons-tripoli-building-collapse-kills-14</link><description>The death toll from the collapse of residential buildings in the Lebanese city of Tripoli rose to 14 after search and rescue operations ended, Lebanon’s National News Agency said on Monday citing the civil defence chief.
Civil defence director general Imad Khreiss said rescue teams recovered</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 11:26:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NSU holds Grand Finale of its Indoor Badminton Tournament</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/nsu-holds-grand-finale-of-its-indoor-badminton-tournament</link><description>North South University (NSU) organized the Grand Finale of its Indoor Badminton Tournament on Sunday evening, February 08, 2026, at the NSU Indoor Ground.
The week-long tournament was organized to strengthen relationships and promote teamwork among the university’s senior leadership, faculty</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 11:41:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique Rahman congratulates Japan’s PM on election win</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-rahman-congratulates-japans-pm-on-election-win</link><description>BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman on Monday congratulated Japan’s Prime Minister Sanae Takaichi and her party on their decisive win in Japan’s parliamentary elections, saying the result demonstrated the Japanese people’s trust in democratic participation and accountable governance.
&amp;ld</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 11:56:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Police cover Sabina’s mouth outside court</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ex-mp-sabina-akter-tuhin-silenced-as-she-attempts-to-speak-en-route-to-prison</link><description>Former member of parliament Sabina Akter Tuhin, who was elected for the seat reserved for women in the 2024 national election, have failed to speak to the media as police covered her mouth while escorting her to prison from the court.
The incident took place on Monday in front of Revati Mansion of</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 12:11:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fifty-three migrants dead or missing after boat capsizes off Libya, IOM says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/fifty-three-migrants-dead-or-missing-after-boat-capsizes-off-libya-iom-says</link><description>Fifty-three migrants, including two babies, were dead or missing after a rubber boat carrying 55 people capsized off the coast of Libya, the International Organization for Migration said on Monday.
The boat departed from Zawiya on Thursday and then overturned off Zuwara on Friday, the IOM said in</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 12:26:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CA says ‘Yes’ vote would prevent return of misgovernance</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ca-says-yes-vote-would-prevent-return-of-misgovernance</link><description>Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus has voiced confidence that the country’s forthcoming national election will be conducted in a free, fair and transparent manner, describing it as a decisive moment after years of what he called “mock” and “fake” polls.
Addressing</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 12:41:56 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>