<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 12:55:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Bangladeshi trapped in Milan bank vault for nine hours during failed robbery</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladeshi-man-trapped-in-milan-bank-vault-for-nine-hours-during-failed-robbery</link><description>A 24-year-old Bangladeshi man has been arrested in Italy's Milan after spending nine hours trapped inside a bank vault during a failed robbery attempt, Euronews reports.
According to Italian police, the man entered a UniCredit branch on Viale Certosa during normal business hours on Thursday evenin</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 09:18:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Burimari Express train to start operation within 180 days: Minister</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/burimari-express-train-to-start-operation-within-180-days-minister</link><description>New Burimari Express train service will begin operating from Burimari within the next 180 days, Disaster Management and Relief Minister Asadul Habib Dulu said on Sunday.
He made the announcement while speaking to journalists after a meeting with administrative officials at the Deputy Commissioner&amp;</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 09:33:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IGP orders strict action against extortion, drugs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/igp-orders-strict-action-against-extortion-drugs</link><description>Inspector General of Police (IGP) Baharul Alam on Sunday instructed field-level police officers to take tough action against extortion, robbery and drug-related crimes.
Speaking at a virtual meeting from Police Headquarters with all unit chiefs, metropolitan police commissioners, range DIGs and di</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 09:48:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No protests needed for teachers’ legitimate demands: Minister Milon</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/no-protests-needed-for-teachers-legitimate-demands-minister-milon</link><description>Education Minister ANM Ehsanul Hoque Milon on Sunday said teachers would no longer need to take to the streets to realise their legitimate demands, as the government is giving the highest priority to the education sector and will implement justified claims of teachers and employees in phases.
Spea</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 10:03:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt. committed to ensure transparency, accountability in education sector: Milon</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-committed-to-ensure-transparency-accountability-in-education-sector-milon</link><description>Education Minister ANM Ehsanul Haque Milon has said the new government is committed to ensuring transparency and accountability in the country’s education sector.
“We will not indulge in corruption and we will not allow anyone to adopt corruption. It is our commitment to keep the educa</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 10:18:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ACC files 2 cases against ex-Jessore-1 MP Sheikh Afil Uddin, wife</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/acc-files-2-cases-against-ex-jessore-1-mp-sheikh-afil-uddin-wife</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) on Sunday filed two separate cases against former Jessore-1 MP Sheikh Afil Uddin and his wife Tahera Sobha, accusing them of amassing wealth worth about Tk 623.1 million.
The cases were lodged at the ACC’s Dhaka Integrated District Office by Assistant Dir</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 10:33:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Yunus returns to Yunus Centre after 18 months</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/yunus-returns-to-yunus-centre-after-18-months-1</link><description>Muhammad Yunus has returned to the Yunus Centre after 18 months following his stint as chief advisor to the interim government.
In a Facebook post on Sunday, the Yunus Centre said he was received by long-time colleagues when he arrived at its office at Telecom Bhaban in Mirpur in the morning.
He</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 10:48:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ICT opens trial of 11 over Taim killing during July Uprising</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ict-opens-trial-of-11-over-taim-killing-during-july-uprising</link><description>The International Crimes Tribunal (ICT) has ordered the trial of 11 people on charges of crimes against humanity over the killing of Imam Hasan Taim, the son of a policeman, during the July 2024 mass uprising in Dhaka's Jatrabari.
The order was issued on Sunday by a three-member bench of ICT-2 hea</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 11:03:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pakistan says it has launched border strikes in Afghanistan. The Red Crescent reports 18 killed</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/pakistan-says-it-has-launched-border-strikes-in-afghanistan-the-red-crescent-reports-18-killed</link><description>Islamabad said it carried out strikes along the border with Afghanistan early Sunday, targeting what it called hideouts of Pakistani militants it blamed for recent attacks inside Pakistan. The Afghan Red Crescent Society said more than a dozen people were killed.
Pakistan didn't specify the locati</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 11:18:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Parliament sits Mar 12, speaker vote first order</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/parliament-to-convene-mar-12-with-speaker-deputy-speaker-elections-topping-agenda</link><description>The first session of the 13th Parliament will convene on Mar 12, when lawmakers will also elect the speaker and deputy speaker to formally set the legislative machinery in motion.
On Sunday, Home Minister Salahuddin Ahmed disclosed the date while at the Secretariat after a meeting chaired by Prime</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 11:33:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh Bank extends loan rescheduling deadline for raw jute exporters</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh-bank-extends-loan-rescheduling-deadline-for-raw-jute-exporters</link><description>Bangladesh Bank on Sunday extended the deadline for raw jute exporters to apply for loan rescheduling, aiming to support businesses facing liquidity challenges and help regularise defaulted loans.
According to a circular issued by the Banking Regulation and Policy Department (BRPD) of the central</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 11:48:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>By-polls to Bogura-6, polls to Sherpur-3 likely before Apr 14: EC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/by-polls-to-bogura-6-polls-to-sherpur-3-likely-before-apr-14-ec</link><description>Election Commissioner (EC) Abdur Rahmanel Machud on Sunday said by-elections to Bogura-6 constituency and polls to Sherpur-3 constituency are likely to be held before April 14 next.
He said the Commission is trying to take all preparations so that the by-elections and election could be held before</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 12:03:49 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>