<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 07:34:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Iran names three-member body to manage transition after Khamenei’s death</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/iran-names-three-member-body-to-manage-transition-after-khameneis-death</link><description>Iran has said that its president, the head of the judiciary and a senior jurist from the Guardian Council will jointly oversee the country’s transition period following the death of Ayatollah Ali Khamenei.
Under Iran’s constitution, the task of selecting a new supreme leader now falls</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 04:34:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt to provide accommodation for passengers of cancelled flights</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-to-provide-accommodation-for-passengers-of-cancelled-flights</link><description>The government will provide overnight accommodation for passengers whose flights have been cancelled due to the ongoing situation in the Middle East, the Ministry of Expatriate Welfare and Overseas Employment said on Saturday.
In a statement, the ministry said several flights were cancelled,</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 04:12:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Industrial workers' wages, salaries to be paid before Eid: Minister</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/industrial-workers-wages-salaries-to-be-paid-before-eid-minister</link><description>SYLHET, Feb 28: Minister for Textiles and Jute and Industries Khandaker Abdul Muktadir said that the outstanding wages and salaries of industrial workers would be paid before Eid.
He also said that taxes would not be increased in the private sector.
In response to a question from journalists on S</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 04:27:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How Bangladesh's Gen-Z can unlock the multi-trillion dollar halal economy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/youth-and-entrepreneurship/how-bangladeshs-gen-z-can-unlock-the-multi-trillion-dollar-halal-economy</link><description>As the holy month of Ramadan unfolds in Bangladesh, it brings with it a familiar rhythm of spiritual reflection, community gatherings, and a palpable shift in the nation's economic tempo. Beyond the evening iftar bazaars and festive shopping, a much larger, globally connected economic force is quie</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 04:42:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh's youths reimagining Ramadan 2026</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/youth-and-entrepreneurship/bangladeshs-youths-reimagining-ramadan-2026</link><description>Across Bangladesh, Ramadan 2026 has drawn young people into its centre in ways that go well beyond routine observance. In Dhaka, student clubs and volunteer groups have taken on community dinners and charity drives with a seriousness that stands out. Students at International School Dhaka, for inst</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 04:57:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The fix Bangladesh's start-up ecosystem needs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/youth-and-entrepreneurship/the-fix-bangladeshs-start-up-ecosystem-needs</link><description>Bangladesh's universities are churning out more and more start-ups. Jam-packed demo days and booming business plan competitions often spark celebration on social media. However, behind all this outward momentum is a sobering fact: around 90 per cent of start-ups fail within the first five years wor</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 05:12:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tying the knot, breaking the bank: lavish weddings in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/analysis/tying-the-knot-breaking-the-bank-lavish-weddings-in-bangladesh</link><description>Traditionally, weddings are a form of celebration where family, friends enjoy food and music, following the custom while two people get married. Nonetheless, within the recent past, the nature of wedding ceremonies within South Asia has been changing from being mere cultural events to, basically, c</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 05:27:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DSE plunges after Middle East escalation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/dse-plunges-after-middle-east-escalation</link><description>The benchmark index of the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) lost more than 100 points at opening on Sunday as investors dumped their holdings, fearing further fall amid the intensified Middle East crisis.
US-Israel jointly launched a strike on Iran on Saturday that killed Iranian supreme leader Ayatolla</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 05:42:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DUCSU, JCS protest BCL posters pasted at DU, demand action</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ducsu-jcs-protest-bcl-posters-pasted-at-du-demand-action</link><description>Dhaka University Central Students' Union (DUCSU) and Jatiya Chhatra Shakti (JCS) on Saturday staged demonstrations, protesting activities of the banned organisation Bangladesh Chhatra League (BCL) on the Dhaka University (DU) campus.
The two student platforms claimed that posters of BCL were found</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 05:57:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>WASA raises prepaid water price to Tk 1.0 per litre</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/wasa-raises-prepaid-water-price-to-tk-10-per-litre</link><description>Residents in Dhaka have expressed frustration after the Dhaka Water Supply and Sewerage Authority (WASA) once again increased the price of water from its prepaid Water ATM booths, heightening concerns about the affordability of safe drinking water amid mounting economic pressures.
Under the latest</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 06:12:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Grameen Bank retirees demand unpaid benefits</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/grameen-bank-retirees-demand-unpaid-benefits</link><description>Retired officials and employees of Grameen Bank (GB) have threatened to launch a tougher movement after Eid-ul-Fitr unless their demands for monthly pensions, medical allowances and festival allowances are met immediately.
They made the announcement at a rally held in front of the National Press C</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 06:27:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>JCD issues show-cause notice on DU hall leader Tanvir</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jcd-issues-show-cause-notice-on-du-hall-leader-tanvir</link><description>The central body of Bangladesh Jatiyatabadi Chhatra Dal (JCD) has served a show-cause notice on Sheikh Tanvir Bari Hamim, convener of Kabi Jasimuddin Hall unit at Dhaka University (DU, on charges of violating organisational discipline.
The notice was issued on Friday night through a press release</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 06:42:06 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>