<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 16:44:28 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Ctg Port workers call another 24-hour strike</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/chittagong-ports-staff-workers-call-fresh-24-hour-strike-against-nct-lease-to-foreign-handler</link><description>The Chittagong Port workers and employees have called another 24-hour strike in protest against the lease of the New Mooring Container Terminal (NCT) to a foreign company.
The Chittagong Port Protection Struggle Committee announced the industrial action on Tuesday morning, with the strike schedule</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 13:54:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>10-taka banknote featuring ‘Graffiti-2024’ to hit market on Tuesday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/10-taka-banknote-featuring-graffiti-2024-to-hit-market-on-tuesday</link><description>Bangladesh Bank (BB) is set to release a new 10-taka denomination banknote on Tuesday as part of its new series titled “Historical and Archaeological Architecture of Bangladesh.”
The new note, bearing the signature of Bangladesh Bank Governor Dr. Ahsan H. Mansur, will be issued initial</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 14:09:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat wants to push Bangladesh back, says Fakhrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-wants-to-push-bangladesh-back-says-fakhrul</link><description>BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir on Monday alleged that Jamaat-e-Islam aims to turn Bangladesh into an Afghanistan-like state, raising concerns over the party’s political agenda and its potential impact on national stability.
“They want to take Bangladesh backward. The</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 14:24:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fourth Board Meeting of Sammilito Islami Bank PLC held</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/fourth-board-meeting-of-sammilito-islami-bank-plc-held</link><description>The fourth meeting of the Board of Directors of Sammilito Islami Bank PLC was held on 2 February 2026 at City Centre, Motijheel.
The meeting was chaired by Mr. Mohammad Ayub Mia, PhD, Chairman of Sammilito Islami Bank PLC, according to a press release. 
Members of the Board of Directors of S</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 14:15:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Vanguard announces new round of sweeping fund fee cuts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/vanguard-announces-new-round-of-sweeping-fund-fee-cuts</link><description>Vanguard, the world's second-largest asset manager and a pioneer of low-cost funds, said on Monday it is cutting fees on 53 of its index-based mutual funds and exchange-traded funds, marking its second sweeping fee reduction in the past 12 months.
The move underscores how even Vanguard is facing i</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 14:30:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>274 violent incidents since poll schedule: CAO</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/chief-advisors-office-reports-274-incidents-of-violence-five-killings-since-election-schedule</link><description>The Chief Advisor’s Office (CAO) has recorded 274 violent incidents and five killings nationwide following the announcement of the parliamentary election schedule, according to data covering Dec 12 to Feb 1.
Clashes between rival supporters were the most frequent form of violence, accounting</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 14:45:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Defence sector talks with other countries an ‘ongoing process’: Dr Khalilur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/defence-sector-talks-with-other-countries-an-ongoing-process-dr-khalilur</link><description>National Security Adviser (NSA) Dr Khalilur Rahman on Monday described negotiations with multiple countries in the areas of defence and other sectors, taking place towards the end of the interim government’s tenure, as an ‘ongoing process.’
“This is an ongoing process,&amp;rdqu</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 15:00:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Journalists must not compromise on professionalism: Information adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/journalists-must-not-compromise-on-professionalism-information-adviser</link><description>Information and Broadcasting Adviser Syeda Rizwana Hasan on Monday said journalists must remain uncompromising on professionalism and refrain from partisan allegiance under any circumstances.
She made the remarks while addressing the “Media Festival 2026”, organised by the July Revolut</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 15:15:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCP files complaints against BNP</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ncp-lodges-formal-complaints-against-bnp-to-election-commission</link><description>The National Citizen Party (NCP) has lodged a series of formal complaints against the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) with the Election Commission as campaigning intensifies nationwide.
Sometimes naming BNP and hinting at the party, and at other times naming its chief and other leaders, NCP&amp;rsq</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 15:30:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Vote for ‘sheaf of paddy’ to serve people: Gayeshwar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/vote-for-sheaf-of-paddy-to-serve-people-gayeshwar</link><description>BNP senior leader Gayeshwar Chandra Roy on Monday urged citizens to vote for his party’s ‘Sheaf of Paddy’ symbol, saying it would allow him to continue serving the people.
“Go to the polling station with mothers and sisters on the morning of February 12 and vote for the &amp;ls</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 16:00:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Syrian state forces deploy in Kurdish-run city under ceasefire deal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/syrian-state-forces-deploy-in-kurdish-run-city-under-ceasefire-deal</link><description>Syrian government security forces deployed in a Kurdish-controlled city in the northeast on Monday, a first step towards implementing a US-backed ceasefire deal that foresees the Kurdish-run regions being merged with Damascus.
The deal, declared on Friday, staved off the prospect of further confro</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 16:15:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Truck traffic at Cargill facility in northern Brazil blocked by protesters</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/truck-traffic-at-cargill-facility-in-northern-brazil-blocked-by-protesters</link><description>Protesters have been blocking truck traffic at Cargill's Santarem grain terminal in northern Brazil, according to a company statement in response to Reuters questions on Monday.
Cargill denied any occupation of its facilities by protesters, whom local media identified as Indigenous groups.
Cargil</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 16:30:46 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>