<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 01:56:35 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>High Court orders reservation of 8,501 BCS non-cadre positions</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/high-court-orders-reservation-of-8501-bcs-non-cadre-positions</link><description>The High Court has ordered the reservation of 8,501 non-cadre posts under the Bangladesh Civil Service (BCS).
The bench of Justice Md Mozibur Rahman Miah and Justice Md Hamidur Rahman issued the order on Sunday after hearing a petition filed by 773 43rd BCS candidates.
Lawyer Mohammad Humayun Kab</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 15:55:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique Rahman vows to ensure law &amp; order, fight corruption</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-rahman-vows-to-ensure-law-order-fight-corruption</link><description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman on Sunday said his party will prioritise ensuring law and order and tackling corruption if voted to power.
“Those who will form the government after winning the election must first ensure one thing, and that is the rule of law. In simple terms, it means peo</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 16:10:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UN chief calls CA to mourn Bangladeshi peacekeepers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/un-secretary-general-calls-yunus-to-condole-bangladeshi-peacekeepers-deaths</link><description>United Nations Secretary-General António Guterres has called Chief Advisor Muhammad Yunus to express his condolences over the death of six Bangladeshi peacekeepers in a drone attack in Sudan.
The Chief Advisor’s Office said the conversation took place at 7pm on Sunday.
“I am ca</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 16:25:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>SC restricts ‘unexpected’ entry to courtrooms</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/sc-restricts-unexpected-entry-to-courtrooms</link><description>The Supreme Court has barred the entry of anyone other than lawyers, including litigants or any “unexpected individuals”, into the courtrooms of both its divisions.
The restriction was announced on Sunday, citing security concerns.
A notice from the apex court emphasises that, as the</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 16:40:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Artificial intelligence is good but needs to be better and safer</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/artificial-intelligence-is-good-but-needs-to-be-better-and-safer</link><description>In the landmark G20 Summit on African soil, world leaders converged on digital innovations as a force for inclusive growth, urging ethical Artificial Intelligence (AI) governance to bridge global divides. Despite the absence of the U.S. in this meeting, the Declaration recommitted to "responsible a</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 16:55:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rule of law is key to holding peaceful polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/rule-of-law-is-key-to-holding-peaceful-polls</link><description>With the announcement of the polls schedule, the nation is in the throes of expectation. Barely two months away from the 13th national election, peace-loving people of this country are not all expectant of a smooth holding of polls and referendum on the July charter on February 12. Many keep their</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 17:10:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Potato can be a lucrative export crop</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/potato-can-be-a-lucrative-export-crop</link><description>While speaking at an event on the second day of the two-day (December12-13) potato festival 2025 held in the city, experts highlighted the potential of potato as an exportable agricultural commodity of Bangladesh. Notably, the country exported over 62,000 tonnes of potato worth US$14 million last f</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 17:25:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Apparel sector's stake in climate adaptation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/apparel-sectors-stake-in-climate-adaptation</link><description>The findings of a new study conducted by the Global Labor Institute (GLI) of Cornell University, USA could trigger both optimism and concern. The study suggests investing in climate adaptation can help Bangladesh fetch US$122.01 billion in apparel exports by the year 2030. On the flip side, however</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 17:40:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hadi will be flown to Singapore on Monday: CAO</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hadi-will-be-airlifted-to-singapore-on-monday-says-chief-advisors-office</link><description>The Inqilab Moncho platform spokesperson Sharif Osman bin Hadi, who was shot in the head by assailants, will be flown to Singapore on Monday, the Chief Advisor’s Office has confirmed.
On Sunday, Muhammad Yunus’s office said Hadi, a potential independent candidate for the Dhaka-8 consti</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 18:12:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Singer Noble's marriage 'no shield' from rape trial</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/entertainment/singer-nobles-prison-marriage-to-complainant-cannot-erase-rape-charges-police-say</link><description>Marriage cannot absolve singer Mainul Ahsan Noble of rape charges, Demra Police Inspector Murad Hossain has said.
Murad, the investigating officer, submitted a charge sheet against the musician on Nov 29, accusing him of raping the complainant, filming the assaults and physically abusing her while</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 18:27:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC bars early election campaigning</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/election-commission-orders-halt-to-early-campaigning-for-february-polls</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has ordered an immediate halt to early campaigning for the parliamentary elections.
It also instructed authorities to ensure compliance with the election code of conduct at religious, social and national programmes.
The EC issued the directive to all returning officer</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 18:42:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Levying fees on state guarantees against risk-laden loans likely</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/levying-fees-on-state-guarantees-against-risk-laden-loans-likely</link><description>A government move gets underway for revising the fee structure for state guarantees against both foreign and domestic loans to introduce a risk-based pricing mechanism to reduce fiscal exposure and strengthen financial discipline in borrowing institutions.



Officials say the move is intended</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 19:43:23 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>