<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 08:47:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Stock indices see mixed trading in early hours</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/stock-indices-see-mixed-trading-in-early-hours456</link><description>Bangladesh’s stock indices witnessed mixed trading in the early hours of transactions on Wednesday, with a slight rise in Dhaka and a marginal fall in Chattogram, as most companies saw their share prices edge up.
During the first hour of trading on the last working day of the week, the key i</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 05:12:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pathao marks 10 years with month-long celebrations and rewards</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/pathao-marks-10-years-with-month-long-celebrations-and-rewards</link><description>Pathao, Bangladesh’s one of the leading super apps, is celebrating its 10th anniversary this October. Since its launch in 2015, the platform has expanded from a ride-hailing service to a comprehensive digital ecosystem, offering services in rides, food delivery, logistics, and digital payment</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 05:42:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Embankment collapses in Khulna: Tidal waters inundate low-lying areas</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/embankment-collapses-in-khulna-tidal-waters-inundate-low-lying-areas</link><description>Vast low-lying areas in Dacope upazila of Khulna have been flooded after a 100-metre stretch of an embankment on the Dhaki River collapsed early Wednesday, allowing tidal waters to rush in and inundate nearby villages, triggering panic among local residents.
The embankment breach occurred near Har</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 05:57:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>German ambassador meets Fakhrul; discusses election, trade issues</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/german-ambassador-meets-fakhrul-discusses-election-trade-issues</link><description>Newly appointed German Ambassador to Bangladesh Dr Rüdiger Lotz met BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir on Thursday and discussed issues related to the upcoming national election, trade, investment and broader bilateral cooperation.
The hour-long meeting, which began around 10:3</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 06:27:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A few more days of rain to come before monsoon eases</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/a-few-more-days-of-rain-to-come-before-monsoon-eases</link><description>As autumn draws to a close, a few final days of rain are likely to precede the retreat of the monsoon winds, yielding to a drier season ahead.
The Bangladesh Meteorological Department (BMD) has forecast that the winds will shift direction and the humidity will begin to drop around mid-October.
Ra</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 06:57:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Burka-wearing robbers steal ‘5.8kg’ of jewellery from store in Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/burka-wearing-robbers-steal-58kg-of-jewellery-from-store-in-dhaka</link><description>Shampa Jewellers claims that nearly 500 Bhori (approximately 5.83kg) of gold jewellery has been stolen from its store in the Fortune Shopping Mall at Dhaka’s Mouchak intersection.
CCTV camera footage from the scene early on Thursday morning shows two burka-wearing individuals cutting the loc</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 07:12:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Israeli hostages may be released Saturday after Gaza ceasefire deal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/israeli-hostages-may-be-released-saturday-after-gaza-ceasefire-deal</link><description>Israeli hostages may be released as early as Saturday under a US plan to end the war in Gaza and the country's military will complete the first part of a partial withdrawal from the enclave within 24 hours of the deal being sealed, said a source briefed on details of the agreement.
The signing of</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 07:27:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ex-MP of Naogaon-6 Omar Faruk held in Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ex-mp-of-naogaon-6-omar-faruk-held-in-dhaka</link><description>The Detective Branch (DB) of police has arrested a former member of parliament (MP) for Naogaon-6 constituency Md Omar Faruk, and four activists of the Awami League (AL)- whose activities remain banned- and its affiliated organisations from different parts of Dhaka in the last 24 hours.
Deputy Com</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 07:57:58 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>