<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 07:07:08 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Agent banking lending jumps to Tk 350b</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/agent-banking-lending-jumps-to-tk-350b</link><description>Lending through agent banking rose sharply to Tk 350.23 billion by the end of December 2025, underscoring the rapid expansion of this alternative delivery channel, particularly in rural Bangladesh. 
The latest data from Bangladesh Bank (BB) show strong quarterly growth in credit, deposits and</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 03:39:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Polls termed as 'great success'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/polls-termed-as-great-success</link><description>Interim government's council of advisers Sunday billed the national elections under their stewardship as a "great success" at its final meeting before their exit after a new government assumes office tomorrow.
The outgoing post-uprising interim cabinet formally adopted a vote of thanks for what me</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 04:42:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Stocks down at opening amid cautious trading</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/stocks-down-at-opening-amid-cautious-trading-156428</link><description>After a big jump in the previous day, the market opened lower on Monday, the second day after the parliamentary election, as investors followed a cautious stance.
The market index surged 200 points on Sunday, the biggest single-day gain in more than 18 months, the first day after the national</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 05:32:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Madrasha student stabbed dead in Jatrabari</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/madrasha-student-stabbed-dead-in-dhakas-jatrabari</link><description>A madrasha student was stabbed to death by some unidentified people in the capital’s Jatrabari area on Sunday night.
The deceased was Mahim Mia, 15, a resident of Kajla area in Jatrabari and son of Din Islam from Kishoreganj Sadar.
He studied in the hifz section of a local madrasha, accordi</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 05:47:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bourses cut trading by 40 minutes during Ramadan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/bourses-cut-trading-by-40-minutes-during-ramadan</link><description>The stock exchanges-- Dhaka Stock Exchange and Chittagong Stock Exchange-- have reduced share trading time by 40 minutes during the Holy month of Ramadan.
Share trading on the bourses will begin at 10:00 am as usual and continue until 1:50 pm, including a 10-minute post-closing session during the</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 05:05:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>T-bill yields fall as liquidity swells</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/t-bill-yields-fall-as-liquidity-swells</link><description>Yields on treasury bills (T-bills) declined further on Sunday as banks channelled surplus liquidity into risk-free government securities, reflecting subdued private sector credit demand.
The downward movement in yields comes amid improved liquidity conditions, supported by strong remittance inflow</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 05:20:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New office-bearers elected for ICMAB Dhaka Branch Council for 2026</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/new-office-bearers-elected-for-icmab-dhaka-branch-council-for-2026</link><description>Mannan Bapari CERM, FCMA, Shahana Parvin FCMA, Md Iqbal Hossain ACMA, CFA, FRM and Md Kamruzzaman FCMA have been elected Chairman, Vice-Chairman, Secretary and Treasurer respectively of the Dhaka Branch Council (DBC) of the Institute of Cost and Management Accountants of Bangladesh (ICMAB) for the</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 05:35:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>13 candidates lose deposits in three Manikganj constituencies</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/13-candidates-lose-deposits-in-three-manikganj-constituencies</link><description>Thirteen out of twenty candidates contesting in Manikganj's three constituencies have lost their security deposits in the 13th national parliamentary election as they failed to obtain at least 12.5 per cent of the total valid votes cast.
Candidates who fell short of getting the required votes will</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 05:50:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Online VAT returns submission deadline extended</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/online-vat-returns-submission-deadline-extended</link><description>The National Board of Revenue (NBR) has extended the deadline for submitting online VAT returns through its e-VAT system until February 22, 2026, citing public interest and recent technical disruptions.
According to an official order, the extension was granted due to a prolonged spell of governmen</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 06:05:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP leader, nephew hacked in Pirojpur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-leader-nephew-hacked-in-pirojpur</link><description>A BNP leader and his nephew have been hacked at and injured in Pirojpur’s Sadar Upazila.
The victims are former Sadar Upazila BNP convenor Mohiuddin Mallik Nasir aka Nasir Mallik, and his nephew Riaz Uddin Mallik Nipu.
The incident took place around midnight on Monday near the Parerhat Bus</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 06:20:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bolster post-election security arrangements</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bolster-post-election-security-arrangements</link><description>Four election observation organisations have described the 13th national election as largely orderly and transparent, but recommended strengthening post-poll security measures.
They say the measures are needed in light of several incidents of violence, intimidation, technology-facilitated gender-b</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 06:35:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Azizur Rahman Ripon elected FERB chairman, Sirajul Islam ED</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/azizur-rahman-ripon-elected-ferb-chairman-sirajul-islam-ed</link><description>M Azizur Rahman (Ripon) was elected chairman and Serajul Islam Siraj executive director (ED) of the Forum for Energy Reporters Bangladesh (FERB).
The election was held at Bijoy Hall of Bidyut Bhaban in the city on Sunday. Prior to the election, the biennial meeting of the organisation was held wit</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 06:50:52 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>