<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 09:33:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Language compatibility in an age of AI-driven automation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/analysis/language-compatibility-in-an-age-of-ai-driven-automation</link><description>Political hegemony often imposes language and cultural hegemonies. The dismantling of colonial power following the World War II may have withdrawn the political stranglehold across the continents but the influence of the two others refuses to go. This subcontinent and the French colonies in Africa</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 03:04:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mismanagement and banking sector reform</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/analysis/mismanagement-and-banking-sector-reform</link><description>For nearly two decades, Bangladesh's banking sector has remained under persistent public scrutiny. While weaknesses in governance and financial discipline are not new, the scale and frequency of mismanagement have intensified markedly over the last 10 to 15 years. Rising non-performing loans, repea</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 03:19:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How to ensure peaceful work environment</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/analysis/how-to-ensure-peaceful-work-environment</link><description>Ramadan is a holy month for Muslims, marked by self-control, spiritual purification, and worship. However, this period also presents special challenges for industrial establishments in safeguarding workers' well-being and maintaining a healthy and balanced work environment. Long abstinence from foo</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 03:34:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Youth killed in Jhenaidah road crash</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/youth-killed-in-jhenaidah-road-crash</link><description>A truck collision in Pobhati Kalarhat area of Jhenaidah district town on Friday night left one young man dead and another seriously injured.
The accident occurred around 11:00 pm when a truck hit a motorcycle, reports UNB.
The deceased has been identified as Shanto Shahriar Rahman Shanto (31), so</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 03:53:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US Supreme Court strikes down Trump’s global tariffs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/global/us-supreme-court-strikes-down-trumps-global-tariffs</link><description>The U.S. Supreme Court on Friday struck down President Donald Trump’s sweeping global tariffs, delivering a significant setback to a central pillar of his economic agenda.
In a 6-3 ruling, the court said Trump’s use of an emergency powers law to impose wide-ranging import duties, inclu</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 04:08:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump imposes 10pc tariff on all countries</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/global/trump-imposes-10pc-tariff-on-all-countries</link><description>U.S. President Donald Trump has signed an executive order to impose 10 per cent tariffs on imported goods from all countries, according to a social media post on Friday.
The move came hours after the Supreme Court ruled in a 6-3 vote that his tariff policy under the International Emergency Economi</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 04:23:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nation remembers language heroes on Amar Ekushey</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nation-remembers-language-heroes-on-amar-ekushey</link><description>The nation is observing 'Amar Ekushey', the Language Martyr's Day and the International Mother Language Day early Saturday, marking the supreme sacrifice of the language heroes for upholding the dignity of the mother tongue, Bangla.
The day is also being observed around the world as UNESCO recogni</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 04:38:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Low pressure over equatorial Indian Ocean, Southeast Bay: BMD</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/low-pressure-over-equatorial-indian-ocean-southeast-bay-bmd</link><description>A low pressure area has formed over the Equatorial Indian Ocean and adjoining southeast Bay of Bengal.
It is likely to move west-northwestwards and intensify, according to the latest Met ofocr bulletin.
Meanwhile, the ridge of Sub-continental high extends up to Bihar and adjoining areas, influenc</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 06:27:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Three killed in Moulvibazar road accident</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/three-killed-in-moulvibazar-road-accident</link><description>Three people have been killed and another injured after a pickup truck collided head-on with a CNG-run autorickshaw in Moulvibazar Sadar.
The crash occurred around 1:45am on Saturday in Giasnagar Shahpur along the Dhaka–Moulvibazar road, according to Moulvibazar Model Police Station chief (O</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 06:42:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>PM Tarique begins work at Tejgaon PMO</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/pm-tarique-begins-work-at-tejgaon-pmo</link><description>Prime Minister Tarique Rahman on Saturday began work at the Prime Minister’s Office in Tejgaon for the first time after assuming office.
He arrived at the office at 10:10 am, where Principal Secretary ABM Abdus Sattar and Additional Press Secretary Atikur Rahman Rumon received him.
Before e</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 07:31:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>PM releases commemorative postage stamp on Int’l Mother Language Day</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/pm-releases-commemorative-postage-stamp-on-intl-mother-language-day</link><description>Prime Minister Tarique Rahman has released a commemorative postage stamp, an opening envelope and a canceller on the occasion of the great Martyrs’ Day and the International Mother Language Day.
He released the commemorative postage stamp at the Prime Minister’s Office (PMO) in the cit</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 07:46:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rohingya refugee held with yaba pills in Bandarban</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rohingya-refugee-held-with-yaba-pills-in-bandarban</link><description>Members of Border Guard Bangladesh (BGB) arrested a Rohingya man and seized 330,000 Yaba tablets in separate anti-narcotics operations along the Ghumdhum border in Naikhongchhari upazila of Bandarban.
The arrestee was identified as Bashir Ahmed, 50, a Rohingya resident of Balukhali Camp-09 in Ukhi</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 08:54:49 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>