<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 18:36:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Terminal driveway closed at Ctg airport</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/vehicles-visitors-barred-from-shah-amanat-international-airport-terminal-over-security-concerns</link><description>Vehicles and visitors have been barred from entering the terminal driveway of Chattogram’s Shah Amanat International Airport, citing security concerns ahead of the general election.
The decision was taken at the airport security committee’s monthly coordination meeting on Tuesday, acco</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 15:00:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tofazzal death: 28 face charges for beating over ‘theft’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/tofazzal-death-28-face-charges-for-beating-over-theft</link><description>A chargesheet accusing 28 people, including former Bangladesh Chhatra League leader, has been filed 15 months after mentally-ill Toffazzal Hossain was beaten to death on suspicion of theft at Fazlul Huq Muslim Hall of Dhaka University.
Additional Superintendent Hannanul Islam of the Police Bureau</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 15:15:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>122 more appeals against EC decisions</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/122-more-appeals-against-ec-decisions</link><description>On the second day of appeals over nominations for the parliamentary polls, the Election Commission (EC) has received 122 applications challenging returning officers’ decisions.
Senior Assistant Secretary of the EC’s legal division Mainul Islam said confirmed the development on Tuesday.</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 15:30:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Vote discrepancy halts counting at JnU</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/vote-discrepancy-halts-counting-at-jnu</link><description>Jagannath University’s Central Student Union (JnUCSU) election has run into trouble during vote counting following a peaceful polling process.
A discrepancy in a single vote has suspended the counting for over two hours as the authorities work to verify results.
“We have encountered a</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 15:45:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>G7 finance ministers to meet in Washington to discuss rare earths, three sources say</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/g7-finance-ministers-to-meet-in-washington-to-discuss-rare-earths-three-sources-say</link><description>Finance ministers from the Group of Seven nations will meet in Washington on January 12 to discuss rare earths supplies, three sources familiar with the matter said on Tuesday.
One of the sources added that price floors for rare earths would be a point of discussion, among other critical mineral t</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 16:00:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rana Pratap Bairagi killing in Jashore not linked to religion, journalism: Govt</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rana-pratap-bairagi-killing-in-jashore-not-linked-to-religion-journalism-govt</link><description>The government today clarified that the killing of Rana Pratap Bairagi in Jashore was not linked to religion or any journalistic matter, saying that local police have confirmed the victim was already an accused in a murder case.
“You know that a murder took place in Jashore yesterday (Monday</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 16:44:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh has no plan to import beef: Adviser Farida</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladesh-has-no-plan-to-import-beef-adviser-farida</link><description>Bangladesh has no plan to import beef, as it could hurt domestic farmers and pose potential health risks, said Fisheries and Livestock Adviser Farida Akhter on Tuesday.
“Beef import requires careful consideration. It is not like soap or shampoo that can be brought in at will. The government</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 16:59:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Limits of monetary policy independence</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/limits-of-monetary-policy-independence</link><description>The issue of central bank independence has two elements. First— governance, how is the central bank governed? Are its leadership appointments merit-based? Are its internal decisions insulated from day-to-day political interference? The prevailing wisdom around the world is that management sys</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 17:14:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>War on sovereignty of Venezuela not narcotics</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/war-on-sovereignty-of-venezuela-not-narcotics</link><description>The U.S. military operation resulting in the capture of Venezuelan President Nicolás Maduro and his wife represents a defining moment in the Trump administration's fight against alleged drug trafficking. The administration swiftly framed the action as a lawful criminal enforcement against na</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 17:29:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Completing NBR reform</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/completing-nbr-reform</link><description>Splitting the National Board of Revenue (NBR) between its policymaking and  revenue management  functions has been one of the major reform agendas of the post-July 2024 interim government. The aim was to render the tax regulator more efficient, transparent and accountable. Though the inte</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 17:44:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EU Ambassador meets Tarique Rahman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/eu-ambassador-meets-tarique-rahman</link><description>European Union (EU) Ambassador to Bangladesh Michael Miller today (Tuesday) held a courtesy meeting with BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman. 
The meeting took place at the BNP Chairperson's office in Gulshan at 6:30pm, according to BNP Media Cell member Shayrul Kabir Khan, BSS reports.</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 17:59:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Corruption corrodes  ICT-powered  knowledge economy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/corruption-corrodes-ict-powered-knowledge-economy</link><description>sector steeped in misdealing sending billions of fast bucks into pockets of a small group of politically and commercially favoured firms.
Such unholy practice happened in the fastest-growing knowledge economy as licensing decisions taken during the Awami League government between 2009 and 2024 fav</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 18:14:28 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>