<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 14:28:20 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Russia, Ukraine and US set to hold security talks in Abu Dhabi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/russia-ukraine-and-us-set-to-hold-security-talks-in-abu-dhabi</link><description>Russia said it will hold security talks with the US and Ukraine in Abu Dhabi on Friday, but warned after a late-night meeting between President Vladimir Putin and three US envoys that a durable peace would not be possible unless territorial issues were resolved.
Kremlin aide Yuri Ushakov told repo</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 11:15:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dinajpur to have city corporation if Jamaat wins: Shafiqur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dinajpur-to-be-upgraded-to-city-corporation-if-jamaat-comes-to-power-shafiqur</link><description>Jamaat-e-Islami chief Shafiqur Rahman has given assurances that Dinajpur will be converted into a city corporation if his party gets the opportunity to form a government.
He said, “For a larger district, city corporations have become district headquarters in many places. Do you have a city c</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 11:30:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Joint forces arrest 278 across Bangladesh in weeklong drive: ISPR</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/joint-forces-arrest-278-across-bangladesh-in-weeklong-drive-ispr</link><description>-Members of the joint forces, led by the Bangladesh Army, arrested 278 suspected criminals in a nationwide drive between Jan 16 and Jan 22, said the Inter-Services Public Relations (ISPR) on Friday.
The operations were conducted in different parts of the country, including the capital, by units un</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 11:45:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Heathrow's new scanners end dreaded rummage for liquids and laptops</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/heathrows-new-scanners-end-dreaded-rummage-for-liquids-and-laptops</link><description>Passengers will no longer be forced to dig around in their hand luggage to extract shampoos, water bottles and laptops when travelling through security at Heathrow, Europe's busiest airport, thanks to new specialist scanners.
Heathrow said on Friday that all security lanes across its four terminal</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 12:00:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AL ban strips Feb 12 vote of democratic legitimacy, Hasina</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/awami-league-ban-strips-feb-12-vote-of-democratic-legitimacy-hasina-tells-theprint</link><description>Sheikh Hasina has launched a stinging political broadside against the interim government, accusing Chief Advisor Muhammad Yunus of replacing constitutional rule with what she calls “authoritarianism dressed up as transition” by sidelining her party Awami League ahead of the Feb 12 gener</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 12:15:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh, Costa Rica eye stronger ties</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-costa-rica-eye-stronger-ties</link><description>Costa Rica has expressed its support for Bangladesh’s upcoming candidacy as a non-permanent member of the UN Security Council, as the two countries seek to strengthen relations across all potential areas.
Mushfiqul Fazal Ansarey, Ambassador of Bangladesh to Mexico with concurrent accreditati</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 12:30:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat chief sets three conditions for 'collaborative’ governance</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jamaat-chief-shafiqur-sets-three-conditions-for-collaborative-governance</link><description>Jamaat-e-Islami chief Shafiqur Rahman has promised to build the nation inclusively if his party is given the chance to form the government, while laying out three conditions for governance.
He addressed a large election rally of the 10-party alliance at Thakurgaon Government Boys’ High Schoo</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 12:16:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CA for building democratic social system with spirit of 1969 Mass Uprising</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ca-for-building-democratic-social-system-with-spirit-of-1969-mass-uprising</link><description>Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus today urged all to come forward towards building a truly democratic social system, imbued with the values of the 1969 mass uprising.
"Let us all dedicate ourselves to building a truly democratic social system respecting the values of the 1969 mass uprising,"</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 12:31:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP to solve salt industry problems, if voted to power: Salahuddin</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-to-solve-salt-industry-problems-if-voted-to-power-salahuddin</link><description>BNP Standing Committee member Salahuddin Ahmed on Friday assured salt workers of resolving existing problems in the country’s salt industry once BNP is voted to power through the upcoming general elections.
He made the assurance during his surprise visit to a salt field located in Magnama La</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 12:46:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Child not beaten that way’: teacher in court</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/child-not-beaten-that-way-says-dhaka-school-teacher-facing-abuse-allegations</link><description>A teacher at Dhaka’s Sharmin Academy has appeared in court after being arrested over allegations of child abuse, with police seeking five days to question him.
Pabitra Kumar was arrested in Mirpur early on Friday and presented before a Dhaka Metropolitan Magistrate over accusations of abusin</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 13:01:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Farooki highlights Bangladesh cricket team's security concerns in India</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/cricket/farooki-highlights-bangladesh-cricket-teams-security-concerns-in-india</link><description>Cultural Affairs Adviser Mostofa Sarwar Farooki has raised concerns over the security of the national cricket team ahead of upcoming matches in India, citing recent attacks on people suspected to be Bangladeshis and political remarks warning against hosting Bangladesh in certain cities.
He urged t</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 13:16:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>LafargeHolcim Bangladesh gets Top Employer certification for 2026</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/lafargeholcim-bangladesh-gets-top-employer-certification-for-2026</link><description>LafargeHolcim Bangladesh Plc (LHB) has been certified as a Top Employer for 2026, the company said in a press release.
The certification was awarded by the Top Employers Institute, which describes itself as a global authority on HR strategies and certification, the release said.
The recognition r</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 13:31:46 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>