<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 14:15:20 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Consensus Commission to submit final report to Chief Adviser soon: Ali Riaz</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/consensus-commission-to-submit-final-report-to-chief-adviser-soon</link><description>The National Consensus Commission will soon submit its final report to the interim government, Commission Vice-Chairman Professor Ali Riaz said on Sunday.
He made the remark during a meeting of the Commission.
Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus, who is also the Chairman of the Commission, pre</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 11:06:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Stocks open week, higher amid lower turnover</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/stocks-open-week-higher-amid-lower-turnover</link><description>After a four-day holiday, both bourses of the country opened the week on a positive note Sunday, with major indices edging up though turnover declined compared to the previous session.
At the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE), the key index DSEX gained 31 points, while the Shariah-based DSES rose by 2 po</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 11:36:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pope hopes Gaza plan achieves 'desired results' soon</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/pope-hopes-gaza-plan-achieves-desired-results-soon</link><description>Pope Leo hopes that a plan to end the war in Gaza would soon reach the "desired results", he said on Sunday after acknowledging the significant steps made in negotiations to end the conflict between Israel and Hamas.
Speaking during his weekly Angelus prayer, the pontiff asked all relevant parties</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 11:51:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt. procures 10 LNG filled cargos in Sept to meet demand in Sept</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/govt-procures-10-lng-filled-cargos-in-sept-to-meet-demand-in-sept</link><description>Ten cargo loads of LNG reached Bangladesh as part of government procurement process for the past month to meet demands for the liquefied gas, officials said on Sunday.
State-run Petrobangla Director AKM Mizanur Rahman said in line with the government’s long and short term agreements with ove</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 12:06:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gaza war: How close is it to ending?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/gaza-war-how-close-is-it-to-ending</link><description>President Donald Trump has urged Israel to halt its bombing of Gaza after Hamas agreed to release hostages and accepted some key parts of a US peace plan — a shift that could mean a two-year-old war is finally coming to a close.
Israel announced it would work on "immediate implementation" of</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 12:21:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Remittance hits USD 2.68 billion in Sept: BB report</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/remittance-hits-usd-268-billion-in-sept-bb-report</link><description>The inflow of remittances through formal banking channels increased in September compared to the previous two months, with Bangladesh receiving a total of USD 2.68 billion, according to data released by Bangladesh Bank.
The central bank’s Monthly Workers’ Remittance Report for Septembe</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 12:36:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US urges allies to shun Havana at UN</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/citing-cuban-fighters-in-ukraine-us-urges-allies-to-shun-havana-at-un</link><description>President Donald Trump's administration is mobilizing US diplomats to lobby against a UN resolution calling on Washington to lift its decades-long embargo on Cuba, in part by sharing details of Cuba’s support for Russia’s war in Ukraine, according to an internal State Department cable s</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 12:51:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Energy regulator to review major tariff hike Monday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/energy-regulator-to-review-major-tariff-hike-monday-as-fertiliser-sector-faces-supply-crunch</link><description>A public hearing to assess proposals for a sharp increase in gas tariffs for state-run fertiliser factories will be held on Monday, amid growing concerns over energy costs and supply shortfalls.
The Bangladesh Energy Regulatory Commission (BERC) has scheduled the hearing at the BIAM Foundation aud</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 13:06:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Lightning strikes kill 6 in Cumilla, Bogura, Jhenaidah</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/lightning-strikes-kill-6-in-cumilla-bogura-jhenaidah</link><description>Six people were killed and two others injured by lightning strikes in Cumilla, Bogura and Jhenaidah districts on Sunday.
Among the deceased, three died in Cumilla, two in Jhenaidah and one in Bogura district.
In Cumilla, three people including a student of Bangladesh Agriculture University (BAU)</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 13:36:17 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>