<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 17:39:08 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Italy must be wary of Israel's quality in World Cup qualifier, Gattuso says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/italy-must-be-wary-of-israels-quality-in-world-cup-qualifier-gattuso-says</link><description>Italy must beware Israel's quality in a match that could secure a World Cup playoff berth, coach Gennaro Gattuso said on Monday, vowing not to repeat the errors that turned last month's meeting into a frantic end-to-end game.
With a 3-1 win in Estonia last week, Italy boosted their hopes of finish</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 14:54:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India, US to hold trade talks as New Delhi seeks higher energy imports</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/india-us-to-hold-trade-talks-as-new-delhi-seeks-higher-energy-imports</link><description>India and the United States are set to hold trade talks this week, with New Delhi pledging to import US energy and gas as it aims to address Washington's concerns over its Russian oil purchases, an official said.
Talks were suspended briefly in August after the Trump administration announced tarif</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 15:24:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump says he may tell Putin he may send Tomahawks to Ukraine if war not settled</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-says-he-may-tell-putin-he-may-send-tomahawks-to-ukraine-if-war-not-settled</link><description>President Donald Trump said on Sunday that he may tell Russian President Vladimir Putin that he could supply Ukraine with long-range Tomahawk missiles if the war is not settled.
Speaking to reporters aboard Air Force One as he flew to Israel, Trump said he is looking to ensure Ukraine gets a fresh</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 15:39:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Injured BGB personnel airlifted to Dhaka CMH</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/injured-bgb-personnel-airlifted-to-dhaka-cmh</link><description>The injured member of Border Guard Bangladesh (BGB), who was injured in a land mine explosion in Bandarban, was airlifted to Dhaka Combined Military Hospital (CMH) by a BGB helicopter on Monday.
The BGB men identified as Nayek Md Akhtar Hossain, injured in a mine explosion along Tumbru border in N</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 15:54:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>China's victory in the battle against poverty</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/chinas-victory-in-the-battle-against-poverty</link><description>Eradicating poverty is a shared aspiration of all nations and a pressing need that resonates widely across the Global South. After sustained efforts, China solemnly declared to the world at the centenary of the Communist Party of China in 2021: it had historically resolved the issue of absolute pov</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 16:24:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How Bangladesh's Nano SMEs can conquer global markets</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/reviews/how-bangladeshs-nano-smes-can-conquer-global-markets</link><description>Trade and competition are fundamentally linked, with exports serving as an important component of the gross domestic product (GDP) and a key driver of global economic integration. Export competitiveness refers to a country's ability to produce goods and services that can compete effectively in inte</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 16:39:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh Bank at crossroads</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/bangladesh-bank-at-crossroads</link><description>Bangladesh today stands at a monetary and financial crossroads. The country is grappling with persistent inflation, exchange rate volatility, dwindling reserves, and external debt obligations that feel heavy in a fragile global economy. At the centre of these challenges is the Bangladesh Bank (BB),</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 16:54:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A baby formula that can heal acute malnutrition</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/a-baby-formula-that-can-heal-acute-malnutrition</link><description>International Centre for Diarrheal Disease Research, Bangladesh (icddr,b), which first started as Cholera Research Laboratory (CRL) in 1960 in Dhaka to study the microbiology of cholera, earned international fame by innovating Oral Rehydration Therapy (ORT) in mid-1960s.The findings of the first la</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 17:09:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CA's Italy Visit: Settling the migration issue</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/cas-italy-visit-settling-the-migration-issue</link><description>Every year, thousands of Bangladeshis risk their lives crossing the Mediterranean Sea, driven by the hope of higher earning opportunities in Europe. For many, that dream ends in tragedy. Their overcrowded boats capsize; some names could be known and some remain unknown. The latter vanish into stati</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 17:24:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>VAT waiver on local procurement</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/vat-waiver-on-local-procurement</link><description>When competition is a key to staying in business, Bangladesh is in a dire need for exploring all the avenues for enhancing its competitive edge as much as possible. The scenario following graduation from the Least Developed Countries (LDC) makes it further incumbent on this country to go whole hog</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 17:39:08 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>