<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 07:18:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Winter is on its wings to land in Bangladesh soon</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/analysis/winter-is-on-its-wings-to-land-in-bangladesh-soon</link><description>On Tuesday morning last, temperature in Tentulia, the country's northern most point, was 14.5 degree Celsius. The indication is clear enough: winter has arrived and soon the country's middle and southern parts are gradually going to experience the fall of the mercury. The arrival of spring, king of</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 03:45:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rural tourism integrates backwoods household production units into China's mammoth mainstream economy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/analysis/rural-tourism-integrates-backwoods-household-production-units-into-chinas-mammoth-mainstream-economy</link><description>A special model of development parity with tourism as the pivot unlocks untapped potential in the backwoods and integrates rural-household production units into world's most dynamic economic powerhouse, yielding quantum leaps in income.
This is how China pulled up millions of people from under pov</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 04:00:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ministry seeks Tk 330b to upgrade primary schools</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ministry-seeks-tk-330b-to-upgrade-primary-schools</link><description>The Ministry of Primary and Mass Education (MoPME) has sought nearly Tk 330 billion in government funding, entirely from domestic sources, to implement six major development projects aimed at improving infrastructure and learning environments in primary schools across Bangladesh over the next three</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 04:15:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prices of winter vegetables, eggs drop amid rise in supply</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/prices-of-winter-vegetables-eggs-drop-amid-rise-in-supply</link><description>Rise in supply has helped to ease the prices of early winter vegetables and eggs in last one week, while onion prices have remained static at the previous high.
Traders said the supply of vegetables, like cauliflower, cabbage, beans, radish and turnip, has increased in the city markets, as the win</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 04:30:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BEZA hands over NSEZ land to Delta Life Sciences</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/beza-hands-over-nsez-land-to-delta-life-sciences</link><description>The Bangladesh Economic Zones Authority (BEZA) on Friday formally handed over 30 acres of land to the Delta Life Sciences PLC at National Special Economic Zone (NSEZ) in Chattogram.
Director General (Investment Development) of BEZA Ahsan Ullah and Managing Director of Delta Life Sciences PLC. Dr.</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 04:45:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Wearing spectacles can bring substantial economic returns</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/wearing-spectacles-can-bring-substantial-economic-returns</link><description>A little investment to help improve the blurry vision of people all across through eye glasses can bring substantial social and economic returns.
This is not merely a vague preconceived idea but it has been evident in several studies, according to a top official of the Bangladesh chapter of an int</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 05:00:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BECPS recognises four of DU as professional psychologists</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/becps-recognises-four-of-du-as-professional-psychologists</link><description>The Bangladesh Educational and Counselling Psychology Society (BECPS) has officially recognised four psychologists as full-fledged professional psychologists for completing their MS and MPhil degrees in educational psychology and counselling psychology.
The recognition was announced at the society</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 05:15:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bus torched on Dhaka-Chattogram highway in N’ganj</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/bus-torched-on-dhaka-chattogram-highway-in-nganj</link><description>Miscreants set a bus on fire on Dhaka-Chattogram Highway at Shimrail in Siddhirganj upazila of Narayanganj district early Saturday.
Shahinur Alam, officer-in-charge of Siddhirganj Police Station, said the miscreants set the stationary bus of ‘Naf Paribahan’ on fire around 6 am near the</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 05:30:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Extramarital affair’ led to trader Ashraful’s murder: DB, RAB</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/extramarital-affair-led-to-trader-ashrafuls-murder-db-rab</link><description>‘Extramarital affair’ was behind the murder of trader Ashraful Haque, according to Dhaka Metropolitan Police’s Detective Branch (DB) and the Rapid Action Battalion (RAB).
Law enforcement agencies arrest two suspects on Friday in connection with the murder, said DC (media) of DMP</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 05:45:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump says Cambodia, Thailand going to be fine after calls over conflict</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/trump-says-cambodia-thailand-going-to-be-fine-after-calls-over-conflict</link><description>US President Donald Trump said on Friday he thought Thailand and Cambodia were "going to be fine" after holding phone calls with the leaders of the two nations to help mediate the most recent flare-up in the conflict between them.
Thailand this week suspended a US-brokered ceasefire deal and deman</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 06:00:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Apple intensifies succession planning for CEO Tim Cook, FT reports</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/apple-intensifies-succession-planning-for-ceo-tim-cook-ft-reports</link><description>Apple is stepping up its succession planning efforts as it prepares for Tim Cook to step down as chief executive as soon as next year, the Financial Times reported on Friday.
John Ternus, Apple's senior vice president of hardware engineering, is widely seen as Cook's most likely successor, the FT</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 06:15:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump says he will likely sue the BBC for up to $5 billion</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-says-he-will-likely-sue-the-bbc-for-up-to-5-billion-over-edited-speech</link><description>US President Donald Trump said on Friday he would likely sue the BBC next week for as much as $5 billion after the British broadcaster admitted it wrongly edited a video of a speech he gave but insisted there was no legal basis for his claim.
The British Broadcasting Corporation has been plunged i</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 06:30:30 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>