<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 11:17:44 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Election schedule to be declared in second week of Dec: CEC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/election-schedule-to-be-declared-in-second-week-of-dec-cec</link><description>Chief Election Commissioner AMM Nasir Uddin has said the Election Commission will announce the schedule for the next general election in the second week of December. 
“Hopefully, what we expect is that it will be declared in the second week of December. When the schedule is announced, t</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 07:05:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mock voting drill under way in Dhaka ahead of national election, referendum</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/mock-voting-drill-under-way-in-dhaka-ahead-of-national-election-referendum</link><description>A mock voting exercise is being held in Dhaka as the Election Commission (EC) tests its preparations for the upcoming 13th national election and a nationwide referendum, both scheduled to take place on the same day in February next year.
The drill began at 8:00 am on Saturday at the Sher-e-Bangla</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 07:20:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No dollar shortage ahead of Ramadan imports, says BB chief</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/no-dollar-shortage-ahead-of-ramadan-imports-says-bb-chief</link><description>Bangladesh Bank Governor Ahsan H Mansur has played down concerns over a US dollar shortage and said that he saw no obstacles to paying for essential Ramadan imports.
Speaking at the Fourth Bangladesh Economic Conference in Dhaka on Saturday, the governor said the external sector had “stabili</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 08:28:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Advisory Council offers prayers for BNP chief Khaleda’s recovery</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/advisory-council-offers-prayers-for-bnp-chief-khaledas-recovery</link><description>The interim government's Advisory Council has held a special prayer session for the recovery of BNP Chairperson Khaleda Zia, who remains in critical condition in the hospital.
The session took place on Saturday at the office of Chief Advisor Muhammad Yunus, who presided over the meeting. Religious</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 08:31:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Over 2m taxpayers file returns online in 5 months: NBR</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/over-2m-taxpayers-file-returns-online-in-5-months-nbr</link><description>More than two million taxpayers have filed their income tax returns online so far in the 2025–26 fiscal year, marking a major increase in the use of Bangladesh’s electronic tax filing system, the National Board of Revenue (NBR) said on Saturday.
Finance Adviser Dr Salehuddin Ahmed laun</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 08:46:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mirza Abbas alleges ‘slow poisoning’ of Khaleda during imprisonment</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/mirza-abbas-alleges-slow-poisoning-of-khaleda-during-imprisonment</link><description>BNP Standing Committee Member Mirza Abbas on Saturday claimed that BNP Chairperson Khaleda Zia’s illness is ‘not natural’, alleging that she was subjected to ‘slow poisoning’ while in prison under the Awami League government.
“Begum Khaleda Zia’s illness i</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 09:01:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh election: Voter registration in KSA, six other countries resumes</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-election-voter-registration-in-ksa-six-other-countries-resumes</link><description>Voter registration for Bangladeshi expatriates living in Saudi Arabia, Bahrain, Kuwait, Malaysia, Oman, Qatar and the United Arab Emirates, which was suspended due to incomplete address information, resumed on Saturday.
The registration of expatriate Bangladeshi voters in the seven countries resum</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 09:16:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IGP returns home after attending Interpol General Assembly</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/igp-returns-home-after-attending-interpol-general-assembly</link><description>Inspector General of Police (IGP) Baharul Alam returned home on Saturday after attending the 93rd General Assembly of Interpol held in Morocco.
Police chiefs and delegates from Interpol’s 196 member countries participated in the global gathering, reports UNB.
The high-level meeting discusse</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 09:31:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka University to resume classes online eight days after earthquake closure</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/dhaka-university-to-resume-classes-online-eight-days-after-earthquake-closure</link><description>Dhaka University will begin online classes on Sunday, eight days after announcing a 15-day closure in the wake of the deadliest earthquake to hit Bangladesh in decades.
The move aims to keep academic activities running “at all levels”, the university’s Public Relations Office sai</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 09:52:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Well-known faces to join the royals for Princess Kate's annual carol service</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/well-known-faces-to-join-the-royals-for-princess-kates-annual-carol-service</link><description>Actors Kate Winslet, Hannah Waddingham and Chiwetel Ejiofor will be among the stars joining the British royals for the annual Christmas carol service at London's Westminster Abbey hosted by Kate, the Princess of Wales, her office said on Saturday.
The 'Together At Christmas' service, which will be</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 10:07:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pope removes shoes but doesn't pray on visit to Istanbul's Blue Mosque</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/pope-removes-shoes-but-doesnt-pray-on-visit-to-istanbuls-blue-mosque</link><description>Pope Leo visited Istanbul's Blue Mosque on Saturday, removing his shoes in a sign of respect but not appearing to pray in his first visit as leader of the Catholic Church to a Muslim place of worship during his four-day visit to Turkey.
The first US pope bowed slightly before entering the mosque a</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 10:22:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khaleda may be taken to London for treatment, says Mahdi Amin</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/khaleda-may-be-taken-to-london-for-treatment-says-mahdi-amin</link><description>BNP Chairperson and former Prime Minister Khaleda Zia may be taken to London for treatment once her health shows slight improvement, said BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman’s adviser Mahdi Amin.
In a post on his verified Facebook page on Saturday, Mahdi said, “From what we have heard,</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 10:37:50 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>