<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 06:39:17 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Process of implementing new pay scale starts forthwith</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/process-of-implementing-new-pay-scale-starts-forthwith</link><description>Take-home pay packet of public service-holders begins to fatten soon as officials at the Ministry of Finance are learnt to have started the process of implementing the just-recommended new pay scale.
People familiar with the development said the work began just after the members of the Pay Commiss</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 02:08:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>'Jamaat to build a society based on justice, dignity'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-to-build-a-society-based-on-justice-dignity</link><description>The Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami has formally launched its campaign for the upcoming national elections in the capital.
Its Ameer Dr Shafiqur Rahman inaugurated the campaign on Thursday in the Dhaka-15 constituency (Mirpur-Kafrul) as a nominated candidate.
He started the campaign through a rally at</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 02:23:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A project that ended but did not really end</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/a-project-that-ended-but-did-not-really-end</link><description>The government is yet to find ways to close one of the troubled projects of the Awami League regime, though the proposal for extending its deadline and increasing the cost was rejected in July last year.
Sources say a meeting chaired by Muhammad Fouzul Kabir Khan, adviser for rail and road transpo</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 02:38:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Control of Land Utilisation and Farm Land Protection Ordinance promulgated</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/control-of-land-utilisation-and-farm-land-protection-ordinance-promulgated</link><description>The government has promulgated the "Control of Land Utilisation and Farm Land Protection Ordinance, 2026" introducing penalties of up to three years' imprisonment or Tk 1 million in fines or both for misuse of land, including agricultural land.
The Ordinance stipulates that cultivated land must no</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 02:53:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Over 48pc candidates are businesspersons</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/over-48pc-candidates-are-businesspersons</link><description>More than 48 per cent of the candidates contesting the upcoming national elections in February are businessmen, according to the candidates' affidavits analysed by Transparency International Bangladesh (TIB).
The figure is the lowest since the ninth parliamentary election.
It was 57.67 per cent i</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 03:08:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump says US 'armada' heading toward Iran</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-says-us-armada-heading-toward-iran</link><description>President Donald Trump said on Thursday that the United States has an "armada" heading toward Iran but hoped he would not have to use it, as he renewed warnings to Tehran against killing protesters or restarting its nuclear program.
US officials, speaking on condition of anonymity, say the aircraf</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 04:15:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US withdraws from World Health Organization</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-withdraws-from-world-health-organization</link><description>The United States officially left the World Health Organization on Thursday after a year of warnings that doing so would hurt public health in the US and globally, saying its decision reflected failures in the UN health agency's management of the Covid-19 pandemic.
President Donald Trump gave noti</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 04:30:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Teacher arrested after viral video shows alleged child abuse in Dhaka school</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/teacher-arrested-after-viral-video-shows-alleged-child-abuse-in-dhaka-school</link><description>Police have arrested Pabitra Kumar Barua, a teacher allegedly involved in the abuse of a child at a school in Dhaka’s Paltan.
He was arrested from Dhaka’s Mirpur area early on Friday morning, said Mohammad Harun Or Rashid, deputy commissioner of the Motijheel Division of the police, bd</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 05:20:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Feb 12 elections to set standard for future votes, CA tells US ambassador</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/feb-12-elections-to-set-standard-for-future-votes-ca-tells-us-ambassador</link><description>Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus has said the February 12 general election would set a benchmark for all future polls in Bangladesh.
He made the remarks when newly appointed US Ambassador to Bangladesh Brent Christensen paid his maiden courtesy call on the Chief Adviser at the State Guest Ho</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 05:35:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US seeks to be 'friends' with Jamaat-e-Islami: Washington Post</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/us-seeks-to-be-friends-with-jamaat-e-islami-washington-post</link><description>As the Jamaat-e-Islami readies for its strongest showing at the polls next month, US diplomats are quietly signalling a willingness to engage with the once-banned party, reports The Washington Post, citing audio recordings it says it obtained.
The party, historically outlawed under successive gove</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 06:07:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IPO lottery system returns to boost secondary market turnover</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/ipo-lottery-system-returns-to-boost-secondary-market-turnover</link><description>The main reason for restoring the lottery system in primary share allocation is to boost turnover in the secondary market against the backdrop of a persistent investor exodus.
The IPO lottery system was removed in April 2021 after it was repeatedly accused of depriving retail investors of IPO shar</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 06:22:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Train collides with crane arm in Spain's fourth rail accident in a week</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/train-collides-with-crane-arm-in-spains-fourth-rail-accident-in-a-week</link><description>A commuter train collided with a crane arm that swung into its path in southeastern Spain on Thursday, the transport minister said, in the country's fourth rail accident in less than a week.
Six people suffered minor injuries after the arm hit the passing train's windows, close to the port city of</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 06:37:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>