<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 17:18:30 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Khaleda’s health condition still fragile, doctors report no improvement</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/khaledas-health-condition-still-fragile-doctors-report-no-improvement</link><description>The health condition of BNP Chairperson Begum Khaleda Zia, now undergoing treatment at Evercare Hospital in the capital, has not shown any significant improvement, according to her medical board members and senior party leaders.
Doctors say the former prime minister is still suffering from pneumon</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 14:00:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BRAC Bank and Sheba Merchants partner to empower SMEs through financing and technology</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/brac-bank-and-sheba-merchants-partner-to-empower-smes-through-financing-and-technology</link><description>BRAC Bank has entered into a partnership with Sheba Merchants Limited to enable access to finance for SMEs associated with the Sheba Platform.
Under this collaboration, BRAC Bank will extend SME digital micro-loan facilities to eligible merchants registered on the platform, helping them access cap</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 14:15:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Meghna Bank celebrates achievements of chairperson, vice chairman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/meghna-bank-celebrates-achievements-of-chairperson-vice-chairman</link><description>Recently, Uzma Chowdhury, Chairperson of Meghna Bank PLC and Director, Finance of PRAN-RFL Group, has been awarded Bangladesh C-Suite Awards under the category of "Chief Finance Officer (CFO)/ Finance Director of the Year 2025".
This recognition reflects her exceptional leadership in financial gov</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 14:30:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka Bank launches Bangladesh’s first-ever youth-focused dual currency prepaid card 'Spark' in partnership with Mastercard</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/dhaka-bank-launches-bangladeshs-first-ever-youth-focused-dual-currency-prepaid-card-spark-in-partnership-with-mastercard</link><description>Dhaka Bank PLC.  in collaboration with Mastercard, has officially launched Bangladesh's first-everyouth-centric dual currency prepaid card, branded as “Spark”, at a grand launching ceremony held at a hotel at Gulshan on Monday, 24 November 2025.
The Spark Card of Dhaka Bank design</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 14:45:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP to stage ‘Victory Torch Roadshow’, grand rally on Dec 16</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-to-stage-victory-torch-roadshow-grand-rally-on-dec-16</link><description>BNP will organise a nationwide ‘Victory Torch Roadshow’ along with a ‘grand  rally’ on December 16 at Manik Mia Avenue in the capital to mark the Month of Victory.
BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir made the announcement at a press conference at the Part</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 15:00:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ireland opt to bat first sniffing series win in 2nd T20I</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/ireland-opt-to-bat-first-sniffing-series-win-in-2nd-t20i</link><description>Ireland won the toss and opted to bat first in the second T20I against Bangladesh at the Bir Sreshtho Flight Lieutenant Matiur Rahman Stadium on Saturday.
Ireland made a single change from the opening match, bringing in Ben Calitz in place of Curtis Campher.
Bangladesh came up with a reshuffle of</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 15:45:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pending India nod stalls Bhutan cargo at Burimari</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/pending-india-nod-stalls-bhutan-cargo-at-burimari</link><description>An initiative to send transshipment goods to Bhutan via Bangladesh’s road network on a trial basis has stalled at Burimari Land Port.
The container carrying the goods is stuck in Lalmonirhat as India did not grant permission, said Faruk Hossain, a member of the C&amp;amp;F Agents Association.
Port</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 16:00:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Takeaway from COP30</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/takeaway-from-cop30</link><description>The thirtieth United Nations  Climate Change Conference, (COP30)  held in Belem, Brazil from November 10 to 21, concluded with a compromise  agreement, meaning it fell short of expectations of the majority of participants. In a conference of a few major powers and many countries with</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 16:01:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Japanese embassy hosts Firoz Mahmud’s art exhibition</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/culture/japanese-embassy-hosts-firoz-mahmuds-art-exhibition</link><description>Firoz Mahmud’s art exhibition titled 'Multilayered Legacies' was inaugurated at the Embassy of Japan in Dhaka on Saturday.
Japanese Ambassador Saida Shinichi inaugurated the exhibition, where 35 artworks are on display.
'Multilayered Legacies' is a series of mixed-media works that engage wi</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 16:16:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh hold their nerve to beat Ireland, level T20I series</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/bangladesh-hold-their-nerve-to-beat-ireland-level-t20i-series</link><description>Bangladesh drew level in the T20I series with a composed four-wicket win over Ireland in Chattogram on Saturday night.
Bangladesh chased 171 with two balls to spare after a disciplined closing stand from Mohammad Saifuddin and Mahedi Hasan finished the job.
Ireland had posted 170 for six, a total</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 16:31:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sustainable political and social climate a primary requirement to attract investment: Jamaat Ameer at economic summit</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/sustainable-political-and-social-climate-a-primary-requirement-to-attract-investment-jamaat-ameer-at-economic-summit</link><description>Jamaat-e-Islami Ameer Dr Shafiqur Rahman on Saturday stated that a sustainable political and social atmosphere in Bangladesh is the primary requirement for both foreign and domestic investors.
Shafiqur made the remarks at the third session of the Bangladesh Economic Summit 2025, organised by Bangl</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 16:46:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladeshi shot dead by BSF near border in Chuadanga</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladeshi-man-shot-dead-by-bsf-near-border-in-chuadanga</link><description>A Bangladeshi man was shot dead by India’s Border Security Force (BSF) at the Gayeshpur border in Jibannagar upazila of Chuadanga district on Saturday.
The BSF took away his body after the shooting.
The dead man was identified as Shahidul Islam, 37, son of Noskor Ali from Gayeshpur village.</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 17:01:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>