<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 05:01:17 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Can next govt fulfil July dreams?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/can-next-govt-fulfil-july-dreams</link><description>Undeniably, the July uprising has radically changed the public's view on what future governments should be like. The Dr Yunus-led interim administration's role has been more than just arranging the 13th parliamentary election. In fact, its job has been to do the groundwork for the next elected gove</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 18:01:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Stop market manipulation, ensure fair competition</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/stop-market-manipulation-ensure-fair-competition</link><description>Bangladesh has been in the grip of persistently high inflation for years with consequent severe hardship for low- and middle-income families. Although the interim government managed to bring the inflation rate down to an average 8.9 per cent in 2025 from the double-digit levels in 2024, the prices</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 18:16:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Taskforce for skewed trade tax restructuring</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/taskforce-for-skewed-trade-tax-restructuring</link><description>An expert body has recommended radical restructuring of anomalous trade taxes for building a dynamic and trade-oriented economy capable of generating jobs and inclusive growth.
As of the last financial year, finished consumer goods enjoyed about 2.4 times higher tariff protection than intermediate</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 19:19:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Defunct on ground, alive on bourses: Why delisting is urgent</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/defunct-on-ground-alive-on-bourses-why-delisting-is-urgent</link><description>Meghna Pet Industries' existence has long been reduced to a name on paper. It has been out of business for more than 23 years, has failed to declare dividends for years, and has not held annual general meetings for more than a decade.
The company meets all the conditions for delisting. Still, its</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 01:54:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hassan O. Rashid to join EBL</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/hassan-o-rashid-to-join-ebl</link><description>Seasoned banker Hassan O. Rashid has resigned as Chief Executive Officer of Prime Bank PLC and plans to join Eastern Bank Limited (EBL) as its top executive, subject to regulatory clearance.
The move marks a return to EBL for Mr Rashid, who previously served the bank in senior leadership roles bef</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 02:09:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cloths “R” Us signs deal with Fitfamz, Guardian Life to boost employee healthcare</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/cloths-r-us-signs-deal-with-fitfamz-guardian-life-to-boost-employee-healthcare</link><description>Cloths “R” Us Ltd, a Dhaka-based sustainable apparel manufacturer, on Sunday signed a memorandum of understanding (MoU) with Fitfamz and Guardian Life Insurance Limited to provide comprehensive healthcare benefits for its employees.
Under the agreement, employees of Cloths “R&amp;rdq</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 02:24:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bogura green chillies capitalise on India supply gap</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/bogura-green-chillies-capitalise-on-india-supply-gap</link><description>Bogura's famously pungent green chilies are carving out a growing presence in international markets, capitalising on a supply gap created by India's withdrawal from key Middle Eastern export destinations.
Over the past three months, about 1,500 tonnes of green and dried chilies from the northern d</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 02:39:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Post-election optimism lifts undervalued stocks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/post-election-optimism-lifts-undervalued-stocks</link><description>Stocks saw a big jump on the first trading day after the 13th parliamentary election, as investor confidence improved and bargain hunters took positions in potentially lucrative shares amid renewed optimism.
The market opened higher, aided by price appreciation in select large-cap stocks, as oppor</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 02:54:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Farmlands become useless for some crops, fertility declines for others</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/farmlands-become-useless-for-some-crops-fertility-declines-for-others</link><description>Soil traders have been indiscriminately extracting topsoil from Chandpur's remote farmlands for the past several months, which, experts say, has been leaving those lands uncultivable for some crops and less fertile for others.
Illegal soil extraction continued during the winter in the district's F</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 03:09:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique assures Jamaat chief of protection for opposition activists, discusses post-poll amity with Nahid</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-assures-jamaat-chief-of-protection-for-opposition-activists-discusses-post-poll-amity-with-nahid</link><description>Bangladesh's prime minister-in-waiting Tarique Rahman assures the leader of Jamaat-e-Islami that he has instructed party members to protect minority communities and opposition activists amid concerns over post-election reprisals.
Rahman, the chair of the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP), visited</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 03:24:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Agent banking lending jumps to Tk 350b</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/agent-banking-lending-jumps-to-tk-350b</link><description>Lending through agent banking rose sharply to Tk 350.23 billion by the end of December 2025, underscoring the rapid expansion of this alternative delivery channel, particularly in rural Bangladesh. 
The latest data from Bangladesh Bank (BB) show strong quarterly growth in credit, deposits and</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 03:39:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Polls termed as 'great success'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/polls-termed-as-great-success</link><description>Interim government's council of advisers Sunday billed the national elections under their stewardship as a "great success" at its final meeting before their exit after a new government assumes office tomorrow.
The outgoing post-uprising interim cabinet formally adopted a vote of thanks for what me</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 04:42:42 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>