<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 12:47:08 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Interim govt achieves almost all its targets: Shafiqul Alam</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/interim-govt-achieves-almost-all-its-targets-shafiqul-alam</link><description>Refuting some people's claims that this interim government is "the weakest administration in Bangladesh's history", Chief Adviser's Press Secretary Shafiqul Alam today (Tuesday) said that in reality the government has achieved almost all of its targets in just 15 months.
". . . I say with confiden</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 10:05:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>E-passport booklets procurement gets CCGP nod</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/e-passport-booklets-procurement-gets-ccgp-nod</link><description>The Advisers Council Committee on Government Purchase (CCGP) on Tuesday recommended direct government-to-government procurement of e-passport booklets and related training under a project titled “Introduction of E-Passport and Automated Border Control Management in Bangladesh.”
The rec</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 10:20:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BB resets prices of commemorative gold, silver coins</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bb-resets-prices-of-commemorative-gold-silver-coins-1</link><description>Bangladesh Bank (BB) has reset the prices of commemorative gold and silver coins citing a price hike of the precious metals in local and international markets.
The prices of gold coins have been increased to Tk 1,85,000 each while the prices of silver coins have been hiked to Tk 14,000 each.</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 10:35:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DBL, Bright Ceramics host Annual Business Conference 2025</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/dbl-bright-ceramics-host-annual-business-conference-2025</link><description>DBL and Bright Ceramics successfully hosted their Annual Business Conference 2025 on November 14 &amp; 15, bringing together business partners from across the nation.
Centered on the inspiring theme “Echoes of Excellence,” the conference united dealers, distributors and partners from every</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 10:50:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Home Adviser signals zero tolerance on unrest as election in February</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/home-adviser-signals-zero-tolerance-on-unrest-as-election-in-february</link><description>Home Affairs Adviser Lt Gen (retd) Md Jahangir Alam Chowdhury on Tuesday said law-enforcement agencies are fully prepared to act against any attempt to destabilise the country, as the next national election is going to be held in the first half of February.
He made the remarks at a meeting with Ge</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 11:05:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Malaysian High commissioner visits CSE</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/malaysian-high-commissioner-visits-cse</link><description>Mohd Shuhada Othman, High Commissioner of Malaysia to Bangladesh recently visited CSE head office in Chattogram.
CSE Managing Director M. Shaifur Rahman Mazumdar, FCA, FCMA, briefed the High Commissioner in detail through a presentation about CSE’s contribution, current role and future devel</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 11:20:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC issues gazette granting party registration to NCP, BaSaD Marxist</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ec-issues-gazette-granting-party-registration-to-ncp-basad-marxist</link><description>With the 13th parliamentary election approaching, the Election Commission (EC) has granted party registration to the National Citizen Party (NCP) and Bangladesher Samajtantrik Dal Marxist.
EC Secretary Akhtar Ahmed told journalists at a briefing on Tuesday afternoon at EC headquarters that a forma</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 11:15:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>World Bank delegation meets Jamaat Ameer</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/world-bank-delegation-meets-jamaat-ameer</link><description>A World Bank delegation held a meeting with Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami Ameer Dr Shafiqur Rahman on Tuesday.
The meeting was held at the Jamaat chief’s office in Bashundhara, Dhaka.
The delegation was led by Jean-Denis Pesme, Country Director of the World Bank’s Dhaka Regional Office.</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 11:30:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Record number of first-time voters to vote, AL can’t participate: Prof Yunus</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/record-number-of-first-time-voters-to-vote-al-cant-participate-prof-yunus</link><description>Chief Adviser Prof Muhammad Yunus on Tuesday said a record number of young people would cast their first ballots in the upcoming national election, as they had been unable to vote in the three rigged general elections held under the previous autocratic regime.
He said the Awami League would not be</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 11:45:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Number of voters in Bangladesh stands at 127 million</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/number-of-voters-in-bangladesh-stands-at-127-million</link><description>Bangladesh is entering the election season with a voter roll nearing the 130-million mark, after the Election Commission (EC) confirmed a final count of 127.69 million eligible citizens for next February’s general election.

The figures -- detailed at a Tuesday briefing by EC Secretary Akht</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 12:00:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dengue claims 4 more lives, 920 hospitalised in 24 hours</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dengue-claims-4-more-lives-920-hospitalised-in-24-hours</link><description>Four more deaths were reported from dengue in 24 hours till Tuesday morning, raising the number of fatalities from the mosquito-borne disease in Bangladesh to 343 this year.
During the period, 920 more patients were hospitalised with viral fever, raising the total infected-case to 86, 924 this yea</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 12:15:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Four ‘human traffickers’ held in Teknaf raid</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/four-human-traffickers-held-in-teknaf-raid</link><description>Border Guard Bangladesh (BGB) has arrested four suspected human traffickers during a raid in Cox’s Bazar’s Teknaf.
Eight others, including two children were rescued, in the operation, Lt Col Ashiqur Rahman, commander of the Teknaf-2 BGB battalion, said on Tuesday.
The detainees were i</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 12:30:43 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>