<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 06:37:33 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Atlas expects profit by FY27 after 11 years of losses</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/atlas-expects-profit-by-fy27-after-11-years-of-losses</link><description>State-owned Atlas Bangladesh expects to break its cycle of losses after 11 years-by FY27-emboldened by what it claims are profitable partnerships and the launch of its own brand of electric two-wheelers.
Its Managing Director Md Ajibor Rahman said the company revised its business strategy after th</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 04:15:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka stocks snap out of two-day recovery streak</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/dhaka-stocks-snap-out-of-two-day-recovery-streak</link><description>The Dhaka bourse closed Wednesday's session with a marginal loss after two previous recovery sessions following a price correction experienced by market leaders such as Grameenphone and Square Pharmaceuticals.
On the day, the majority of blue-chip stocks closed in the red, while junk stocks domina</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 04:30:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Thailand, Cambodia keep fighting across contested border</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/thailand-cambodia-keep-fighting-across-contested-border</link><description>Fighting between Thailand and Cambodia entered its fourth day on Thursday as both sides waited for a promised telephone call from US President Donald Trump, who says he believes he can again end the conflict between the two Southeast Asian nations.
On Wednesday, clashes at more than a dozen locati</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 03:45:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Duty-evaded handsets’ sale to continue until March</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/duty-evaded-handsets-sale-to-continue-until-march</link><description>The government is sticking to its plan to activate the National Equipment Identity Register (NEIR) on December 16, while allowing the sale of duty-evaded mobile handsets in the market until March next year.
However, this latest development has failed to appease a section of phone traders who rely</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 04:00:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ctg ICDs defer export handling halt</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ctg-icds-defer-export-handling-halt</link><description>Nineteen privately operated inland container depots (ICDs) in Chattogram have postponed a planned suspension of export cargo- and empty-container handling that was due to begin on Thursday, easing immediate concerns over potential disruption to the country's export supply chain.
The ICDs play a cr</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 04:15:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Finance adviser focuses on rural enterprise-led poverty reduction</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/finance-adviser-focuses-on-rural-enterprise-led-poverty-reduction</link><description>Finance Adviser Dr Salehuddin Ahmed has called for sustainable poverty reduction through the development of rural entrepreneurship, stressing that creating jobs outside cities is essential to narrow the growing gap between urban and rural areas.
While acknowledging the need for projects to address</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 04:30:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ten journalists receive accolades for in-depth judicial reporting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ten-journalists-receive-accolades-for-in-depth-judicial-reporting</link><description>A total of 10 journalists from different media outlets have received "Media Award on Judicial Independence 2025" for their outstanding performance in-depth reporting on judicial independence and reforms.
They were conferred the award at a ceremony, jointly organised by National Institute of Mass C</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 04:45:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sumaiya Islam wins Franco-German Award for Human Rights`</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/sumaiya-islam-wins-franco-german-award-for-human-rights</link><description>Sumaiya Islam, executive director of Bangladesh Nari Sramik Kendra (BNSK), has been awarded the 2025 Franco-German Award for Human Rights and Rule of Law.
Ambassadors of France and Germany to Bangladesh, Jean-Marc Séré-Charlet and Dr. Rüdiger Lotz, presented the award to Sumaiya</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 05:00:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DUCSU hosts Victory Day theatre fest Dec 11-13</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ducsu-hosts-victory-day-theatre-fest-dec-11-13</link><description>Ahead of the Victory Day, the Dhaka University Central Students' Union (DUCSU) is hosting a special theatre festival on December 11-13.
Titled "From Victory to Victory, Theatre Festival 2025," the event will be held at the National Theatre Hall of Bangladesh Shilpakala Academy.
DUCSU Literary and</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 05:15:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>20th death anniv of Mostafijur Rahman observed</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/20th-death-anniv-of-mostafijur-rahman-observed</link><description>CHATTOGRAM, Dec 10: The 20th death anniversary of Alhaj Mostafijur Rahman, the founder of Mostafa Group, was observed in the port city on Wednesday.
To mark the day, a commemorative meeting was held at the head office of the Mostafa Group. Managing Director of the company Alhaj Jahir Uddin preside</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 05:30:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tejgaon College students block Farmgate over Sakib’s ‘murder’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tejgaon-college-students-block-farmgate-over-sakibs-murder</link><description>Students of Dhaka’s Tejgaon College have blocked the road in Farmgate over the alleged murder of Sakib, one of their classmates.
The protest began around 10:30 am, bringing traffic to a halt on nearby roads.
Kya Shan U Balpan, officer-in-charge of Tejgaon Police Station, is trying to convin</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 06:21:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two earthquakes shake Sylhet within five minutes</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/two-earthquakes-shake-sylhet-within-five-minutes</link><description>Two mild earthquakes were felt in Sylhet just five minutes apart in the early hours of Wednesday, according to the European-Mediterranean Seismological Centre (EMSC).
India’s National Centre for Seismology (NCS) reported that the first tremor struck at 2:50 am, registering a magnitude of 3.5</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 06:36:48 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>