<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 03:09:04 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Is Myanmar resistance in retreat?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/is-myanmar-resistance-in-retreat</link><description>Has the Myanmar Army now been gaining the upper hand over the rebels and regaining territory lost to the rebel forces so far? A BBC report says that with the support of China, the Myanmar army has intensified air strikes against the rebel held positions. Earlier, when the Myanmar government forces</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 17:35:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>South Asia can't afford another war</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/south-asia-cant-afford-another-war</link><description>The border between Pakistan and Afghanistan has always been more than a line on a map. It is a frontier where geopolitics, history, and mistrust converge - often violently. Today, as tensions flare once again along the Durand Line, the prospect of another conflict in this fragile region casts a lon</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 17:50:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka's preeminence and the paradox</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/dhakas-preeminence-and-the-paradox</link><description>Dhaka District's preeminence on account of the capital city it hosts is quite logical. But such a primacy is not axiomatic. In many countries commercial capitals outstrip their administrative capitals particularly on the strength of economic muscle. Even in Bangladesh, Chattogram had the potential</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 18:05:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>'Neglect’ in probe: Mayor issues notice to CCC CEO</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/mayor-issues-notice-to-chattogram-city-corporation-ceo-over-negligence-in-investigation</link><description>Mayor Sahadat Hossain has served a show-cause notice to Chattogram City Corporation (CCC) chief executive officer on the charge of “negligence in duty”.
The mayor alleged that CEO Sheikh Mohammed Tauhidul Islam had neglected the investigation into allegations of irregularities in tax a</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 18:20:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Worry overshadows Asycuda replacement move</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/worry-overshadows-asycuda-replacement-move</link><description>A government move to phase out from the tested customs digital-platform Asycuda to adopt an advanced system has raised more concerns than corroboration from stakeholders in foreign trade and national revenue.



Customs authority, economists and businesses foresee a possible setback in import</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 19:33:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Accession requires opening services sector</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/accession-requires-opening-services-sector</link><description>Bangladesh's coveted membership in the Regional Comprehensive Economic Partnership (RCEP), world's largest trade bloc, presupposes challenging sweeping liberalisation of trade in services as a predominant condition.
A study, backed by an UN agency, shows how to circumvent the challenge in a measur</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 01:22:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fault-lines found in design, construction, safety checkup</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fault-lines-found-in-design-construction-safety-checkup</link><description>Beating global experience of once in 20 years, mishaps occurred twice over a year in Dhaka metro rail that raised doubts about the construction and safety qualities of the popular mass transport.
Experts are raising questions over not only design or construction faults but also deploring a shockin</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 01:37:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CA to get today NCC suggestions on July Charter execution</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ca-to-get-today-ncc-suggestions-on-july-charter-execution</link><description>Long-awaited recommendations on modus operandi of implementation of the July National Charter-a reform blueprint born out of last year's historic people's uprising-will be submitted to the government today as the consensus panel wrapped up its dos Monday.
Implementation of the much-hyped charter o</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 01:52:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Al-Arafah Bank MD removed over irregularities</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/al-arafah-bank-md-removed-over-irregularities</link><description>The managing director of Al-Arafah Islami Bank PLC, Farman R Chowdhury, has been removed from his position over irregularities in the bank's agent-banking operations.
Confirming the development, Bangladesh Bank (BB) spokesperson Areif Hossain Khan said the bank's board had recommended Mr Chowdhury</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 02:07:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Economic governance needs to undergo major changes</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/economic-governance-needs-to-undergo-major-changes</link><description>Speakers at the Economic Reform Summit 2025 have called for deep structural changes in Bangladesh's economic governance, stressing deregulation, restoration of central bank independence, and a shift from bureaucratic dominance to private sector-led reform.
Addressing the event as chief guest on Mo</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 02:22:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh offered use of Karachi port, jute duty cut</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladesh-offered-use-of-karachi-port-jute-duty-cut</link><description>Pakistan has offered Bangladesh the use of its Karachi port for conducting foreign trade with countries such as China, Gulf, and Central Asian nations, officials said on Monday.
In response, Dhaka expressed interest in exploring the proposal by forming a sectoral working group, officials attending</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 02:37:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BD to import 1.42m tonnes of refined petroleum in H1</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bd-to-import-142m-tonnes-of-refined-petroleum-in-h1</link><description>The government will import up to 1.42 million tonnes (mt) of refined petroleum products between January and June next year from global suppliers via a competitive bidding process.
State-run Bangladesh Petroleum Corporation (BPC) has already received offers from the global petroleum product supplie</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 02:52:54 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>