<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 16:32:46 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Ekushey Book Fair postponed due to elections, opens Feb 20</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ekushey-book-fair-postponed-due-to-elections-opens-feb-20</link><description>The Amar Ekushey Book Fair has been postponed to Feb 20 due to the national elections and will continue through to Mar 15.
The decision was confirmed at a meeting held at the Bangla Academy on Wednesday, bdnews24.com reports.</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 13:55:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat Ameer Shafiqur Rahman leaves for London</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-ameer-shafiqur-rahman-leaves-for-london</link><description>Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami Ameer Dr Shafiqur Rahman left Dhaka for the United Kingdom on Wednesday to attend a series of scheduled meetings and programmes with a delegation of the British government.
He departed Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport in the morning on a Biman Bangladesh Airlines f</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 14:10:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>FIFA agrees 50pc rise in prize money for 2026 World Cup</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/fifa-agrees-50pc-rise-in-prize-money-for-2026-world-cup</link><description>Prize money for next year’s World Cup will be 50 percent higher than the previous edition with world governing body FIFA agreeing a record $727 million financial contribution to the tournament on Wednesday.
The biggest slice of FIFA’s funding package for the North American showpiece -</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 13:58:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>South Korean envoy pays farewell call on CA</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/south-korean-envoy-pays-farewell-call-on-ca</link><description>Park Young-sik, Ambassador of the Republic of Korea to Bangladesh, paid a farewell call on Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus at the State Guest House Jamuna on Wednesday, marking the completion of his diplomatic tenure in Bangladesh.
During the meeting, Ambassador Park expressed his condolenc</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 14:13:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Amir Khosru, Gias Quader, Mir Helal collect nomination papers in Chattogram</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/amir-khosru-gias-quader-mir-helal-collect-nomination-papers-in-chattogram</link><description>Senior BNP leader Amir Khosru Mahmud Chowdhury has collected his nomination paper for the Chattogram-10 constituency, as multiple contenders from the BNP and Jamaat-e-Islami move to enter the race across the port city.
On Wednesday, the documents were secured from the Chattogram Divisional Commiss</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 14:28:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jatiya Party to contest in all 300 seats amid ‘poll concerns’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jatiya-party-to-field-candidates-for-300-constituencies-despite-fears-of-engineered-elections</link><description>The Jatiya Party, led by GM Quader, has announced it will field candidates in all 300 constituencies for the parliamentary polls, despite concerns over “voting fairness”, Secretary General Shameem Haider Patwary has said.
On Wednesday, Shameem highlighted the “deteriorating law-a</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 14:43:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Google works to erode Nvidia’s software advantage with Meta’s help</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/google-works-to-erode-nvidias-software-advantage-with-metas-help</link><description>Alphabet’s Google is working on a new initiative to make its artificial intelligence chips better at running PyTorch, the world’s most widely used AI software framework, in a move aimed at weakening Nvidia’s longstanding dominance of the AI computing market, according to people fa</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 14:58:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Three ministries must unite for ‘One Health’ pledge: Adviser Farida</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/three-ministries-must-unite-for-one-health-pledge-adviser-farida</link><description>Effective implementation of the ‘One Health’ approach requires coordinated commitment at the highest level among the ministries of Health and Family Welfare, Environment, Forest and Climate Change, and Fisheries and Livestock, Fisheries and Livestock Adviser Farida Akhter said on Wednes</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 15:13:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Russian attack on Ukraine’s Zaporizhzhia injures 26, governor says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/russian-attack-on-ukraines-zaporizhzhia-injures-26-governor-says</link><description>Russian glide bomb attacks on apartment blocks in Ukraine’s Zaporizhzhia region wounded 26 people, including a child, on Wednesday, regional Governor Ivan Fedorov said, as thick black smoke could be seen billowing from charred buildings.
Fedorov wrote on Telegram that three strikes hit the r</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 15:28:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mainul Kabir joins SBAC Bank as MD &amp; CEO</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/mainul-kabir-joins-sbac-bank-as-md-ceo</link><description>SM Mainul Kabir has joined SBAC Bank PLC as Managing Director &amp; CEO on Wednesday.
Before joining SBAC Bank, Mainul Kabir served as Deputy Managing Director of United Commercial Bank PLC, according to a press release.
Mainul Kabir brings over 30 years of distinguished and active experience in the</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 15:43:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Southeast Bank holds Annual Risk Conference-2025</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/southeast-bank-holds-annual-risk-conference-2025</link><description>Southeast Bank PLC organised “Annual Risk Conference-2025” in a hybrid format on Saturday (December 13, 2025) at the Southeast Bank Training Institute, Dhaka.
The conference was chaired by Md. Khalid Mahmood Khan, Managing Director of Southeast Bank PLC, while ANM Moinul Kabir, Directo</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 15:58:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Police disclose special security measures for Christmas, New Year’s Eve</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/police-disclose-special-security-measures-for-christmas-new-years-eve</link><description>Police have taken special security measures ahead of the twin celebrations for Christmas and New Year’s Eve.
A meeting on security and law and order was held at the Hall of Pride of Police Headquarters on Wednesday, chaired by Inspector General of Police (IGP) Bangladesh Baharul Alam, ahead</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 16:13:41 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>