<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 06:59:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Asiatic Labs' half-year profit surpasses FY25 earnings</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/asiatic-labs-half-year-profit-surpasses-fy25-earnings</link><description>Asiatic Laboratories has posted an impressive 86 per cent year-on-year growth in profit to Tk 164 million in the second quarter of FY26, driven by higher sales amid a stable forex market.
With the latest quarterly earnings, its half-yearly profit-Tk 316 million-in July-December last year surpassed</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:20:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Starlink deal opens new revenue stream for Kay &amp; Que</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/starlink-deal-opens-new-revenue-stream-for-kay-que</link><description>Kay &amp; Que (Bangladesh) has become the sales agent for Starlink Satellite Internet Service in Bangladesh, a move expected to increase the company's revenue and income in the coming quarters.
The listed IT venture, belonging to the conglomerate Multimode Group owned by BNP Vice Chairman Abdul Awal M</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:35:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Explosion at illegal coal mine kills at least 18 in India’s Meghalaya</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/explosion-at-illegal-coal-mine-kills-at-least-18-workers-in-indias-meghalaya</link><description>An explosion ripped through an illegal coal mine in India’s northeastern state of Meghalaya on Thursday, killing at least 18 workers and injuring another, authorities said.
Police officer Vikash Kumar said rescue teams recovered 18 bodies from the site of the explosion in a remote area of th</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:50:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BB raises limit for digital services to Tk 2,000</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bb-raises-limit-for-digital-services-to-tk-2000</link><description>Bangladesh Bank has increased the monthly spending limit for mobile subscribers purchasing digital products and services through direct operator billing (DOB) from Tk 600 to Tk 2,000, aiming to expand access to digital services and boost the country's digital economy.
In a circular issued on Febru</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 04:50:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ROAD TRANSPORT SECTOR: Most laws, reforms, regulations remain largely unimplemented</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/road-transport-sector-most-laws-reforms-regulations-remain-largely-unimplemented</link><description>At least 10 laws, regulations and policy reforms were introduced in the road transport sector since 2009. But, most of these remained largely unimplemented over the past 16 years.
Sector analysts said political interference and shifting priorities either shelved or rendered most of the initiatives</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:05:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Adviser focuses on supportive policy environment for education, research</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/adviser-focuses-on-supportive-policy-environment-for-education-research</link><description>A two-day Robo Carnival, focusing on artificial intelligence (AI) and robotics, began at the Bangladesh University of Engineering and Technology (BUET) on Thursday, aiming to promote innovation, research culture, and skill development among young people.
The inaugural ceremony started at ECE build</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:20:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ctg Port Authority writes to ACC to probe assets of 15 staff members</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/chittagong-port-authority-writes-to-acc-to-probe-assets-of-15-protesting-staff-members</link><description>The Chittagong Port Authority has written to the Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) to conduct an investigation into the movable and immovable assets of 15 workers involved in protests against the leasing of the New Mooring Container Terminal (NCT) to foreign handlers.
At the same time, the port aut</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:35:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tk 1,268.80 cr project aims to shield haor and Barind livelihoods from climate shocks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tk-126880-cr-project-aims-to-shield-haor-and-barind-livelihoods-from-climate-shocks</link><description>As floodwaters repeatedly inundate homes in the haor basin and drought tightens its grip on the high Barind survival for millions in rural Bangladesh has become an annual test of endurance.
Climate change has turned once-predictable seasons into cycles of uncertainty—washing away crops in on</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:50:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh steps up road safety drive with a big driver training deal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-steps-up-road-safety-drive-with-a-big-driver-training-deal</link><description>Bangladesh has taken a major step towards safer roads with the signing of a crucial agreement to train 60,000 vehicle drivers nationwide, aiming to reduce road fatalities and build a skilled transport workforce.
 
An official deal was signed at the Road Transport and Highways Division betwee</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 06:05:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Only 7pc of inmates opt for postal voting before Feb 12 polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/only-7pc-of-inmates-opt-for-postal-voting-before-feb-12-polls</link><description>Only about seven per cent of inmates in the country’s prisons have shown interest in voting by postal ballot in the upcoming election.
According to data from the Prisons Department, 5,960 prisoners out of around 85,000 inmates housed in 72 prisons across the country will cast their votes by</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 06:20:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>In Hasina’s hometown, voters face an unfamiliar ballot</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/in-hasinas-hometown-voters-face-an-unfamiliar-ballot</link><description>For the first time in decades, the image that once defined the hometown of Bangladesh's ousted premier Sheikh Hasina during elections, her Awami League party's "boat" symbol, is absent.
In its place, posters of rivals like the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP), the Jamaat‑e‑Islami party and indep</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 06:35:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Japan to send election observer mission to Bangladesh for Feb-12 polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/japan-to-send-election-observer-mission-to-bangladesh-for-feb-12-polls</link><description>Japan has decided to deploy an Election Observer Mission to Bangladesh from February 9 to February 14 to support the fair implementation of the general election of Bangladesh scheduled for February 12.
 
The mission will be headed by Watanabe Masato, former Ambassador of Japan to Bangladesh.</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 06:50:53 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>