<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 14:53:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>LPG price cut by Tk 15 for 12kg cylinder</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/lpg-price-cut-by-tk-15-for-12kg-cylinder</link><description>The price of a 12kg cylinder of liquefied petroleum gas (LPG), widely used for household cooking, has been reduced by Tk 15.
The new pricing sets the 12kg cylinder at Tk1,341 in retail, down from the previous price of Tk 1,356.
The Bangladesh Energy Regulatory Commission (BERC) said the new price</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 12:16:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Withdrawal of 1,202 more politically motivated cases approved: Home Minister</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/withdrawal-of-1202-more-politically-motivated-cases-approved-home-minister</link><description>Home Minister Salahuddin Ahmed on Tuesday said the government has approved the withdrawal of 1,202 more politically motivated cases filed over the past 17 years against opposition leaders, party activists and others.
Earlier approval was given for withdrawal 1,006 politically motivated cases, he t</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 12:31:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NBR forms committee to prepare budget for 2026-27 fiscal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/nbr-forms-committee-to-prepare-budget-for-2026-27-fiscal</link><description>The National Board of Revenue (NBR) has formed a budget committee by assigning additional responsibilities to four senior officials to support the preparation and coordination of the national budget for the 2026–27 fiscal year.
According to an official order issued on February 23 by the NBR</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 12:46:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chattogram-1 MP Nurul Amin hurt in car crash</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/chattogram-1-mp-nurul-amin-hurt-in-car-crash</link><description>Nurul Amin, the member of parliament from Chattogram-1 (Mirsarai), has been injured in a road accident in Feni while returning from Cumilla.
The accident occurred around 3:00 pm on Tuesday in Feni Sadar Upazila on the Dhaka-Chattogram Highway.
Locals rescued him after the accident and took him to</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 13:01:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Schoolboy rescued within an hour after PM’s call</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/pm-tariques-intervention-leads-to-rescue-of-kidnapped-schoolboy-within-an-hour</link><description>A desperate father burst into the prime minister’s office (PMO) in tears after learning his schoolboy son had been kidnapped. Within minutes, Tarique Rahman picked up the phone and ordered police to act—and less than an hour later, officers stormed an unfinished building in Khilgaon to</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 12:20:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Power deals signed during AL regime threat to sovereignty: Minister</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/power-deals-signed-during-al-regime-threat-to-sovereignty-minister</link><description>Power, Energy, and Mineral Resources Minister Iqbal Hasan Mahmud has described electricity purchase agreements signed during the previous Awami League government with India, foreign entities, and private companies as a grave threat to the country’s independence and sovereignty.
The minister</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 12:35:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Australian PM Albanese briefly evacuated from residence after security threat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/australian-pm-albanese-briefly-evacuated-from-residence-after-security-threat</link><description>Australian Prime Minister Anthony Albanese was evacuated from his residence in Canberra late on Tuesday following a security threat, and returned a few hours later after nothing suspicious was found, ABC News reported.
Police said they had responded to an “alleged security incident”, w</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 12:50:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trust Bank and Grameenphone join hands to accelerate digital transformation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/trust-bank-and-grameenphone-join-hands-to-accelerate-digital-transformation</link><description>Trust Bank PLC and Grameenphone have agreed to collaborate on digital transformation initiatives aimed at strengthening technological infrastructure and enhancing value-added customer experiences.
According to a press release, this strategic partnership is expected to significantly improve the con</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 13:05:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Man to be grilled over ‘raping’ police officer</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/man-to-be-grilled-over-raping-police-officer</link><description>A Dhaka court has ordered a businessman to be questioned for five days in a case filed by a police officer on charges of rape and fraud.
Dhaka Metropolitan Magistrate Mahbub Alam issued the order on Tuesday, and Prosecution Police Sub-Inspector (SI) Tahmina Akhter gave information about the remand</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 13:20:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sarwar Alam reappointed president’s press secretary</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/sarwar-alam-reappointed-presidents-press-secretary</link><description>Retired information cadre officer Md Sarwar Alam has been reappointed as press secretary to President Md Shahabuddin, filling a post that had remained vacant for more than a year.
The public administration ministry issued an order on Tuesday appointing him on a one‑year contractual basis.
In an i</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 13:35:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Standard Islami Bank holds its 423rd board meeting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/standard-islami-bank-holds-its-423rd-board-meeting</link><description>423rd Board Meeting of Standard Islami Bank PLC was held on Tuesday at the bank’s board room at its head office in Dhaka, according to a press release.
Chairman of the Board of Directors Mohammed Abdul Aziz presided over the meeting. It was attended by Vice Chairman Gulzar Ahmed, Directors K</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 13:50:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>PM orders steps to reopen weak, closed factories</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/pm-orders-public-private-partnerships-to-relaunch-weak-closed-industries</link><description>Prime Minister Tarique Rahman has ordered ministries to take steps to reopen dwindling and closed industries in partnership with private entrepreneurs.
Atiqur Rahman Rumon, the prime minister’s assistant press secretary, confirmed the directive on Tuesday.
The move aligns with the BNP&amp;rsquo</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 14:05:32 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>