<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 08:32:31 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Elder son accused of killing mother and brother in Cumilla</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/elder-son-accused-of-killing-mother-and-brother-in-cumilla</link><description>A woman and her younger son were stabbed to death at Basantapur village in Adarsha Sadar upazila of Cumilla on Monday, allegedly by her elder son.
The deceased were identified as Rahela Begum, 65, wife of the late Azgar Ali, and her younger son Kamal Hossain, 35.
Rahela’s elder son, Billal</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 06:36:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DSE, CSE indices rise in first hour of trade</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/dse-cse-indices-rise-in-first-hour-of-trade</link><description>Bangladesh’s capital market opened on a positive note on Monday, with key indices of both the Dhaka and Chattogram stock exchanges edging up in the first hour of trading.
At the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE), the benchmark DSEX gained 35 points, while the Shariah index DSES advanced 13 points a</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 06:51:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>42 Indian Umrah pilgrims feared dead in Saudi tanker collision</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/42-indian-umrah-pilgrims-feared-dead-in-saudi-tanker-collision</link><description>At least 42 Indian Umrah pilgrims are feared dead after a bus carrying them from Makkah to Madinah collided with a diesel tanker on Monday, causing a massive fire, media reports said.
Initial reports indicate that many of the victims were women and children from Hyderabad. Unofficial sources sugge</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 07:06:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Iran's foreign minister says the nation is no longer enriching uranium</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/irans-foreign-minister-says-the-nation-is-no-longer-enriching-uranium-at-any-site-in-the-country</link><description>Iran’s foreign minister said Sunday that Tehran is no longer enriching uranium at any site in the country, trying to signal to the West that it remains open to potential negotiations over its atomic programme.
Answering a question from an Associated Press journalist visiting Iran, Foreign Mi</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 06:30:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pistol, crude bombs recovered from train compartment at Airport Railway Station</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/pistol-crude-bombs-recovered-from-train-compartment-at-airport-railway-station</link><description>Bangladesh Army in a drive recovered a homemade pistol and several crude bombs from a train compartment at Airport Railway Station in the capital on Monday morning.
During the drive, army members searched several compartments of Dinajpur-bound Ekota Express train and recovered those from a sack of</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 06:45:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CPA signs 30-year concession deal with APM Terminals for Laldia Container Terminal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/cpa-signs-30-year-concession-deal-with-apm-terminals-for-laldia-container-terminal</link><description>The Chittagong Port Authority (CPA) on Monday signed a concession agreement with the Denmark-based APM Terminals for development and operations for 30 years of the Laldia Container Terminal (LCT) under a Public-Private Partnership (PPP) framework.
 
Shipping Adviser Brigadier General (Retd)</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 07:00:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ICT-1 reading out verdict in Hasina’s case</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ict-1-reading-out-verdict-in-hasinas-case</link><description>The International Crimes Tribunal-1  (ICT-1) is reading out its verdict in a high-profile case against former Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina and two others for crimes against humanity committed during last year’s July-August uprising.
The three member tribunal led by Justice Md. Golam Mor</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 07:15:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hasina verdict being shown on big screen at DU’s TSC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hasina-verdict-being-shown-on-big-screen-at-dus-tsc</link><description>The proceedings of the verdict against deposed prime minister Sheikh Hasina in a crimes against humanity case are being broadcast on a large screen at Dhaka University's TSC (Teacher-Student Centre).
Around 12 pm on Monday, a visit to the area revealed an LED screen installed on the eastern side o</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 07:30:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>5 JUCSU leaders selected for university senate</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/5-jucsu-leaders-selected-for-university-senate</link><description>Jahangirnagar University Central Student Union (JUCSU) has nominated five representatives including Vice President (VP) and General Secretary (GS) to serve on the university’s Senate.
The decision was taken during JUCSU’s third executive meeting on Sunday night, based on the consents f</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 07:45:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Awami League using looted money for acts of sabotage: Rizvi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/awami-league-using-looted-money-for-acts-of-sabotage-rizvi</link><description>BNP Senior Joint Secretary General Ruhul Kabir Rizvi on Monday alleged that the fascist Awami League is using ‘money looted from various banks and mega projects’ to buy cocktails and carry out acts of sabotage.
“Those who committed crimes during the fascist era are now the ones s</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 08:00:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hasina convicted in crimes against humanity case</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hasina-convicted-in-crimes-against-humanity-case</link><description>A Bangladesh court convicted ousted Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina of crimes against humanity on Monday, concluding a months-long trial that found her guilty of ordering a deadly crackdown on a student-led uprising last year.</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 08:15:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Land office signboard, rail line torched in Ctg</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/land-office-signboard-rail-line-torched-in-ctg</link><description>A land office signboard, a section of a highway, and a rail line in Chattogram have been hit by arson attacks.
In the early hours of Monday, tree stumps and tyres were set on fire on the railway track and highway in the Hathazari upazila, reports bdnews24.com.
Around the same time, the signboard</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 08:30:52 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>