<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 14:26:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>HR experts urge govt to implement anti-torture commitments</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hr-experts-urge-govt-to-implement-anti-torture-commitments</link><description>Human rights experts, government officials and international partners have called for swift and substantive implementation of Bangladesh’s new obligations under the Optional Protocol to the Convention against Torture (OPCAT), arguing that ratification must now translate into real accountabili</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 10:52:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Women call for quick passage of tobacco law changes to protect health</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/women-call-for-quick-passage-of-tobacco-law-changes-to-protect-health</link><description>Women from different professions have called for the immediate passage of proposed amendments to the tobacco control law to better protect women’s health.
They made the demand on Tuesday at a discussion marking Begum Rokeya Day, jointly organised by the Bangladesh Women Journalists Forum and</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 11:07:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Interim govt urges halt to protests after election schedule announcement</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/interim-govt-urges-halt-to-protests-after-election-schedule-announcement</link><description>Bangladesh’s interim government has urged political groups, activists and the public to refrain from holding unauthorised protests and street gatherings once the timetable for the national election is announced, warning that illegal assemblies will be met with legal action.
The election sche</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 11:22:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Attack on Jamaat candidate’s motorcade leaves 10 people injured in Sirajganj</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/attack-on-jamaat-candidates-motorcade-leaves-10-people-injured-in-sirajganj</link><description>At least 10 activists of the Jamaat-e-Islami have been injured in an attack on the motorcade of the party’s leader Shahinur Alam, who has been nominated to contest in the parliamentary polls from the Sirajganj-1 constituency.
Kazipur Police chief Shah Enayetur Rahman confirmed the incident o</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 11:37:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>JIC ‘torture’: Will Army officers face trial?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jic-abduction-torture-will-army-officers-face-trial-as-tribunal-set-for-order-sunday</link><description>An order on whether to frame charges against deposed prime minister Sheikh Hasina and a group of former serving Army officers in the Joint Interrogation Cell (JIC) “abduction and torture” crimes against humanity case will be delivered on Dec 14.
The date was set on Tuesday by the three</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 11:52:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jet fuel price hiked by upto 4.36pc for December</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/jet-fuel-price-hiked-by-upto-436pc-for-december</link><description>The energy regulatory commission raised the price of jet A-1 fuel, known as aviation fuel, by 4.10 per cent to US$0.6875 per litre for international flights and by 4.36 per cent to Tk 104.61 per litre for domestic flights from the country’s airports for December compared to previous month&amp;rsq</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 12:07:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Midland Bank Family provided financial assistance to Sajida Foundation for Korail slum fire relief</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/midland-bank-family-provided-financial-assistance-to-sajida-foundation-for-korail-slum-fire-relief</link><description>Midland Bank Family provided financial assistance of Tk. 10.00 Lac to Sajida Foundation, a charitable organisation for Korail Slum Fire Relief.
The Bank provided Tk. 5.00 lac financial assistance from its Islami Banking Fund under its Corporate Social Responsibilities (CSR) activity, as part of th</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 12:22:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Riad elects president, Ishtiaq vice president of BAPLC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/riad-elects-president-ishtiaq-vice-president-of-baplc</link><description>Riad Mahmud, Managing Director, National Polymer Industries PLC, has recently been elected as the President of the Bangladesh Association of Publicly Listed Companies (BAPLC) for the term 2026-2027.
Engr. Syed Ishtiaq Ahmed, Managing Director, Saiham Cotton Mills Ltd elected as Vice President of t</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 12:37:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>445th board meeting of Al-Arafah Islami Bank held</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/445th-board-meeting-of-al-arafah-islami-bank-held</link><description>445th Board meeting of Al-Arafah Islami Bank was held on Tuesday (December 09, 2025) at the Bank’s Head Office.
Vice Chairman of the Board of Directors Md. Shahin Ul Islam presided over the meeting, according to a press release.
The overall business performance of the Bank was reviewed and</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 12:52:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>RHPW 2025 calls for stronger support, political solutions for the Rohingya</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rhpw-2025-calls-for-stronger-support-political-solutions-for-the-rohingya</link><description>Civil society leaders and humanitarian experts from across the Asia-Pacific have urged stronger global support for Rohingya refugees and renewed political efforts to ensure their safe, dignified, and voluntary repatriation to Myanmar.
The call came on Tuesday during an international seminar organi</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 13:07:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BRAC Bank offers complimentary business consultation to entrepreneurs at SME product fair</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/brac-bank-offers-complimentary-business-consultation-to-entrepreneurs-at-sme-product-fair</link><description>BRAC Bank has set up a dedicated SME Solution Clinic at the 12th National SME Product Fair 2025, offering complimentary one-on-one consultations for entrepreneurs about modern business management.
Each day of the fair from December 7 to December 14, 2025, the bank will focus on a specialised theme</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 13:22:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mercantile Bank organised AML &amp; CFT Training in Sylhet</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/mercantile-bank-organised-aml-cft-training-in-sylhet</link><description>Mercantile Bank PLC has organised a comprehensive training program on ‘Prevention of Money Laundering &amp; Combating Financing of Terrorism’ in Sylhet on Saturday (06.12.2025).
The training was aimed at strengthening awareness and capacity among banking and financial professionals from th</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 13:37:36 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>