<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 15:16:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Bank merger: BSEC urges central bank to protect interests of investors</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bank-merger-bsec-urges-central-bank-to-protect-interests-of-investors</link><description>The Bangladesh Securities and Exchange Commission (BSEC), the stock market regulator, has sent a letter to Bangladesh Bank (BB) regarding the planned merger of five commercial banks, urging the central bank to ensure the protection of the interests of general investors.
The letter was sent to the</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 13:30:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Air France suspends flights to Madagascar amid security concerns</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/africa/air-france-suspends-flights-to-madagascar-amid-security-concerns</link><description>Madagascar's presidency said on Sunday that an attempt to grab power by force was underway in the African nation as more soldiers joined a youth-led protest movement that has rocked the former French colony for more than two weeks.
Troops from the elite CAPSAT unit that helped President Andry Rajo</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 13:45:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Transport strike hits five districts, commuters in chaos</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/transport-strike-hits-five-districts-commuters-in-chaos</link><description>Commuters have faced severe disruption as an indefinite transport strike paralysed bus services from Mymensingh, Netrokona, Sherpur, Jamalpur, and parts of Kishoreganj.
The strike, called by bus workers protesting the arrest of a worker and the closure of 16 United Service buses, left passengers s</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 14:15:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DSE, CSE open week with significant losses</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/dse-cse-open-week-with-significant-losses</link><description>Dhaka and Chattogram stock markets opened the week with significant losses on Sunday as all major indices declined and most company shares fell.
At the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE), the benchmark DSEX index dropped 81 points to close at 5,202.
Other indices also fell, with the Shariah-based DSES lo</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 13:31:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>131st board meeting of Padma Bank held</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/131st-board-meeting-of-padma-bank-held</link><description>The Board meeting of Padma Bank PLC was held on Thursday (October 09).
The meeting was chaired by Padma Bank Chairman Md. Shawkat Ali Khan, Managing Director &amp; CEO of Sonali Bank, according to a press release.
The meeting was conducted by Padma Bank Chief Executive Officer Kazi Md. Talha (Current</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 13:46:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NRBC Bank holds financial awareness programme at Jagannath University</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/nrbc-bank-holds-financial-awareness-programme-at-jagannath-university</link><description>NRBC Bank PLC has launched a week-long financial awareness program titled “Festival of Youth” at Jagannath University to promote financial literacy, encourage entrepreneurship and guide students in pursuing higher education both at home and abroad.
According to a press release, the cam</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 14:31:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cashless Bangladesh: Islami Bank leads day-long rally, seminar and stalls in Faridpur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/cashless-bangladesh-islami-bank-leads-day-long-rally-seminar-and-stalls-in-faridpur</link><description>A day-long colorful roadshow, seminar and stall exhibition were held in Faridpur district on 12 October 2025, Sunday marking the “Cashless Bangladesh Initiative Expansion Campaign,” organized by Bangladesh Bank in collaboration with Islami Bank Bangladesh PLC.
According to a press rele</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 14:46:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bank Asia partners with Momen Real Estates to offer exclusive home loan service</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bank-asia-partners-with-momen-real-estates-to-offer-exclusive-home-loan-service</link><description>Bank Asia PLC has entered into a strategic partnership with Momen Real Estates Limited to offer exclusive privileges for its home loan customers, according to a press release.
Through this collaboration, Bank Asia will provide home financing facilities to clients of Momen Real Estates Limited on a</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 15:01:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC registration: Further verification required on info provided by 10 parties</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-registration-further-verification-required-on-info-provided-by-10-parties</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has decided to conduct a fresh field-level investigation of information submitted by ten new political parties, as it continues to hold off on decisions over their registration status.
According to an EC letter signed by senior assistant secretary Nazmul Kabir on Sunda</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 15:16:52 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>