<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 10:43:35 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Three killed in Sirajganj road crash</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/three-killed-in-sirajganj-road-crash567</link><description>Three people, including two children, have died after a three-wheeler- known locally as a “votvoti” - crashed into an autorickshaw in Tarash upazila of Sirajganj district.
Police said one of the victims was an 8-month-old girl, reports bdnews24.com.
The accident occurred around 9:30 a</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 07:35:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Man to die for killing wife over dowry</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/man-to-die-for-killing-wife-over-dowry456</link><description>A Dhaka court has sentenced a man to death for the murder of his wife over a demand for dowry in 2016.
Dhaka Women and Children Repression Prevention Tribunal Judge Munshi Md Moshiar Rahman delivered the verdict in the case on Thursday, reports bdnews24.com.
The death row convict, Sohel Rana, is</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 08:05:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh, ADB ink $100m deal to help CMSMEs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/bangladesh-adb-ink-100m-deal-to-help-cmsmes</link><description>The Asian Development Bank (ADB) and Bangladesh on Thursday signed a $100 million agreement to help cottage, micro, small, and medium-sized enterprises (CMSMEs) outside Dhaka and Chattogram metropolitan areas gain access to medium and long-term credit.
Economic Relations Division (ERD) Secretary,</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 08:20:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UK signs $468 million deal to supply India with missiles</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/uk-signs-468-million-deal-to-supply-india-with-missiles</link><description>Britain said on Thursday it had signed a 350 million pound ($468 million) contract to supply the Indian army with UK-manufactured lightweight missiles, as part of a deepening weapons and defence partnership between the two countries.
The announcement came as British Prime Minister Keir Starmer was</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 08:35:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat mourns death of Prof Dr Tofail Ahmed</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jamaat-mourns-death-of-prof-dr-tofail-ahmed</link><description>Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami expressed deep shock and sorrow at the death of the local government expert, researcher, and chief of the Local Government Reform Commission, Professor Dr Tofail Ahmed. 
In a condolence message, party Secretary General Prof Mia Golam Parwar said that Prof Dr Tofail</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 08:50:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EBL to provide automated 24/7 cash management services for bKash agents, distributors</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ebl-to-provide-automated-cash-management-services-for-bkash-agents-distributors-1</link><description>Eastern Bank PLC (EBL) has entered into a partnership agreement with bKash Limited, the country’s largest mobile financial service provider, to introduce 24/7 automated cash management services for bKash’s agents, distributors, and partners nationwide.
Through this partnership, bKash&amp;r</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 09:05:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Joy in Israel and Gaza after ceasefire announced</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/joy-in-israel-and-gaza-after-ceasefire-announced</link><description>Israelis and Palestinians rejoiced on Thursday after a ceasefire and hostage deal was announced under the first phase of U.S. President Donald Trump’s initiative to end the war in Gaza.
Egypt’s state-affiliated Qahera TV reported the ceasefire had officially come into effect after noon</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 09:35:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India's Modi, Britain's Starmer push for benefits from trade deal to add jobs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/indias-modi-britains-starmer-push-for-benefits-from-trade-deal-to-add-jobs</link><description>Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi and British counterpart Keir Starmer hailed the potential on Thursday of their months-old trade deal to transform commercial links, as London unveiled further Indian investment in Britain.
Starmer is in the financial capital of Mumbai on a two-day visit to India</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 09:50:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NBR sets up e-Return Help Desks in all tax zones</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/nbr-sets-up-e-return-help-desks-in-all-tax-zones</link><description>The National Board of Revenue (NBR) has set up e-Return Help Desks in all tax zones across the country to facilitate smooth and hassle-free submission of online income tax returns by the esteemed taxpayers.
Earlier on August 4, 2025, Finance Adviser Dr Salehuddin Ahmed formally inaugurated the e</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 10:05:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Russia gives cautious welcome to Gaza ceasefire</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/russia-gives-cautious-welcome-to-gaza-ceasefire</link><description>The Kremlin on Thursday welcomed a Gaza ceasefire agreement between Israel and Hamas but said the key would be to see how the deal was implemented.
Israel and Hamas agreed on Wednesday to the first phase of US President Donald Trump's plan for Gaza, a ceasefire and hostage release deal that could</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 10:20:58 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>