<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 14:15:38 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Bangladesh launches typhoid vaccination drive to combat drug-resistant threat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/bangladesh-launches-typhoid-vaccination-drive-to-combat-drug-resistant-threat</link><description>Bangladesh launched a nationwide vaccination campaign on Sunday to protect millions of children from typhoid, a deadly and increasingly drug-resistant disease that poses a growing public health threat.
The month-long campaign aims to immunise around 50 million children aged between nine months and</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 11:30:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Symbols outside official list never issued: CEC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cec-nasir-says-no-political-party-ever-received-symbol-outside-the-official-list</link><description>Chief Election Commissioner AMM Nasir Uddin reminded that the National Citizen Party could not be allocated the “Shapla” symbol because it was not included in the commission’s official list of approved symbols.
On Sunday, Nasir also said the commission has never given a symbol ou</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 11:45:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Uttara Bank organised ‘Annual Risk Management Conference-2025’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/uttara-bank-organised-annual-risk-management-conference-2025</link><description>The ‘Annual Risk Management Conference-2025’ of Uttara Bank PLC was held at Radisson Blu, Dhaka Water Garden recently.
Mr. Md. Abul Hashem, Managing Director and CEO of Uttara Bank PLC, was present as chief guest in the conference, according to a press release.
The Conference was pres</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 12:00:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Union Bank holds its 182nd meeting of Board of Directors</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/union-bank-holds-its-182nd-meeting-of-board-of-directors</link><description>The 182nd board meeting of the Board of the Directors of Union Bank PLC was held at the bank’s Head Office, Gulshan-1, Dhaka, on Sunday (October 12, 2025).
Chairman of the Board of the Directors of the bank Mr. Md. Fariduddin Ahmed presided over the meeting, according to a press release.
Ch</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 12:15:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sonali Bank signs an agreement with NCC Bank</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/sonali-bank-signs-an-agreement-with-ncc-bank</link><description>Sonali Bank PLC signed an agreement with National Credit and Commerce Bank PLC (NCC) to collect challan, utility bill, pension scheme installments and others charges-fees from NCC Bank’s Internet Banking customers through the Sonali Payment Gateway.
The signing ceremony was held at Sonali Ba</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 12:30:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Foreign operators to run three container terminals by December, says shipping secretary</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/foreign-operators-to-run-three-container-terminals-by-december-says-shipping-secretary</link><description>Foreign operators will manage three major container terminals in Bangladesh -- Chattogram’s New Mooring Container Terminal, Laldia Terminal, and Keraniganj’s Pangaon Inland Container Terminal -- by December, the Shipping Ministry Secretary Mohammad Yousuf has said.
He added that the La</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 12:45:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh Bank &amp; Prime Bank jointly hold Entrepreneur Development Training Program</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladesh-bank-prime-bank-jointly-hold-entrepreneur-development-training-program</link><description>Month-long Entrepreneur Development Training Program has been successfully concluded under the joint initiative of Bangladesh Bank and Prime Bank PLC.
The program was organised under the “Skills for Industry Competitiveness and Innovation Program (SICIP)”, financed by the Asian Develop</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 13:00:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Teachers call strike from Monday over police assault</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/teachers-call-strike-from-monday-over-police-assault</link><description>MPO teachers and staff have announced that they will begin their nationwide strike a day early, starting Monday, demanding increased house rent and other allowances.
Delawar Hossain Azizi, secretary of the MPO Education Nationalisation Alliance, announced the plan during a sit-in at the Shaheed Mi</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 13:15:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bank merger: BSEC urges central bank to protect interests of investors</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bank-merger-bsec-urges-central-bank-to-protect-interests-of-investors</link><description>The Bangladesh Securities and Exchange Commission (BSEC), the stock market regulator, has sent a letter to Bangladesh Bank (BB) regarding the planned merger of five commercial banks, urging the central bank to ensure the protection of the interests of general investors.
The letter was sent to the</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 13:30:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Air France suspends flights to Madagascar amid security concerns</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/africa/air-france-suspends-flights-to-madagascar-amid-security-concerns</link><description>Madagascar's presidency said on Sunday that an attempt to grab power by force was underway in the African nation as more soldiers joined a youth-led protest movement that has rocked the former French colony for more than two weeks.
Troops from the elite CAPSAT unit that helped President Andry Rajo</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 13:45:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Transport strike hits five districts, commuters in chaos</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/transport-strike-hits-five-districts-commuters-in-chaos</link><description>Commuters have faced severe disruption as an indefinite transport strike paralysed bus services from Mymensingh, Netrokona, Sherpur, Jamalpur, and parts of Kishoreganj.
The strike, called by bus workers protesting the arrest of a worker and the closure of 16 United Service buses, left passengers s</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 14:15:38 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>