<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 14:24:06 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Saki’s wife owns more than double his wealth</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ganosamhati-leader-zonayed-sakis-wife-owns-more-than-double-his-wealth</link><description>Zonayed Saki, chief coordinator of the Ganosamhati Andolon, has declared assets worth less than half of those owned by his wife, according to an affidavit filed with his nomination papers for Bangladesh’s upcoming 13th national parliamentary election.
Saki entered the race for parliamentary</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 12:16:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Exams scrapped for shipping agent licences</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/shipping-agent-licence-rules-revised-exam-requirement-dropped</link><description>The National Board of Revenue (NBR) has withdrawn the requirement for written and oral examinations for shipping agent licences linked to customs stations at sea ports and inland river ports across Bangladesh.
Under the new system, licences will be issued solely on the basis of submitted documents</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 12:01:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>45 land in jail over vandalism at BTRC building during NEIR protest</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/45-land-in-jail-over-vandalism-at-btrc-building-during-neir-protest</link><description>A Dhaka court has sent 45 people to jail over vandalism at the Bangladesh Telecommunication Regulatory Commission (BTRC) building during protests against the introduction of the National Equipment Identity Register (NEIR).
Dhaka Metropolitan Magistrate Israt Jahan passed the order on Friday after</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 12:16:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NEIR won’t immediately block illegal, clone handsets: Taiyeb</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/neir-wont-immediately-block-illegal-clone-handsets-taiyeb</link><description>Following the launch of the National Equipment Identity Register (NEIR), citizens should not panic as illegal or cloned handsets will not be blocked automatically during the first 90 days, Faiz Ahmad Taiyeb, Special Assistant to the Chief Adviser on Posts, Telecommunications, and ICT, said on Frida</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 12:31:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UK records hottest and sunniest year ever in 2025</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/uk-records-hottest-and-sunniest-year-ever-in-2025-says-weather-service</link><description>Britain experienced its hottest and sunniest year on record in 2025, surpassing the previous high set in 2022, the national weather service said on Friday, as persistent high-pressure systems and unusually warm seas drove up temperatures.
The Met Office said the average annual temperature was 10.0</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 12:46:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Biman gets Pakistan nod for Karachi–Dhaka flights</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/biman-gets-permission-from-pakistan-for-direct-flights-between-karachi-and-dhaka</link><description>The Pakistan government has granted Biman Bangladesh Airlines permission to operate direct flights between Dhaka and Karachi.
According to a Geo News report on Friday, the Civil Aviation Authority (CAA) of Pakistan issued the approval.
Bangladesh’s national flag carrier has initially been c</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 13:01:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Kamal Hossain hospitalised with pneumonia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/gono-forum-chief-kamal-hossain-hospitalised-with-pneumonia</link><description>Kamal Hossain, founder of the Gono Forum, has been admitted to Square Hospital in Dhaka in a critical condition.
Gono Forum General Secretary Mizanur Rahman on Friday said that doctors have diagnosed Kamal with pneumonia.
“[Kamal] is suffering from lung pneumonia. His condition is very seri</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 13:16:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hannan Masud owns five times more wealth than his father</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/hannan-masud-owns-five-times-more-wealth-than-his-father</link><description>NCP leader Abdul Hannan Masud owns five times more wealth than his father, an analysis of affidavits filed by the father-son duo has revealed.
Hannan, 26, is the senior joint chief convenor of the National Citizen Party (NCP).
Both him and his father, Amirul Islam Mohammad Abdul Malek, have filed</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 13:17:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Samsung Electronics says customers praised competitiveness of HBM4 chip</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/samsung-electronics-says-customers-praised-competitiveness-of-hbm4-chip</link><description>Samsung Electronics customers have praised the differentiated competitiveness of its next-generation high-bandwidth memory (HBM) chips, or HBM4, saying "Samsung is back", co-CEO and chip chief Jun Young-hyun said in a New Year address.
In October, Samsung said it was in "close discussion" to suppl</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 13:32:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Yemen's Saudi-backed govt launches operation against UAE-backed separatists</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/yemens-saudi-backed-government-launches-operation-against-uae-backed-separatists</link><description>Yemen's Saudi-backed government launched what it called a peaceful operation to take back military positions from the UAE-backed southern separatists on Friday, who in turn said seven Saudi airstrikes had taken place since the declaration.
The Saudi-backed governor of Yemen's Hadramout province an</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 13:47:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Leaders of 1990’s All-Party Student Alliance offer fateha at Khaleda Zia’s grave</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/leaders-of-1990s-all-party-student-alliance-offer-fateha-at-khaleda-zias-grave</link><description>The leaders of 1990's DUCSU and All-Party Student Alliance on Friday paid tributes to the grave of former prime minister and BNP chairperson Begum Khaleda Zia.
After paying tributes, the then vice-president (VP) of Dhaka University Central Students Union (DUCSU) and the convener of the All-Party S</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 14:02:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Inqilab Moncho sets 22-working-day deadline for trial in Hadi killing</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/inqilab-moncho-sets-22-working-day-deadline-for-trial-in-hadi-killing</link><description>Inqilab Moncho has announced plans to launch a movement to oust the government if the trial over the killing of Sharif Osman bin Hadi is not completed within 22 working days.


The organisation’s Member Secretary Abdullah Al Jaber made the announcement on Friday after</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 14:17:12 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>