<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 15:25:52 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Administrator, associate administrators assume responsibility at Union Bank</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/administrator-associate-administrators-assume-responsibility-at-union-bank</link><description>Mr. Mohammad Abul Hashem, Director of Bangladesh Bank, has joined as Administrator on 05 November 2025to supervise and manage the overall activities of Union Bank PLC.
In addition, Additional Directors of Bangladesh Bank Mr. Kazi Abdul Mannan, Mr. Md. Al-Mehedi Hasan and Joint Directors Mr. Md. Ta</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 13:52:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ONE Bank holds Agent Banking Conference 2025</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/one-bank-holds-agent-banking-conference-2025</link><description>ONE Bank successfully organized Agent Banking Conference 2025 and Training session for Agent Banking Outlet Proprietors &amp; their users on November 8, 2025, at the Bangladesh Military Museum, Dhaka.
According to a press release, the day-long event brought together outlet proprietors, their users, an</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 14:07:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Russia adds ex-PM Kasyanov, economist Guriev to ‘extremists and terrorists’ list</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/russia-adds-ex-pm-kasyanov-economist-guriev-to-extremists-and-terrorists-list</link><description>Russia’s financial watchdog has added former prime minister Mikhail Kasyanov and leading economist Sergei Guriev to its list of “extremists and terrorists” in its latest moves against prominent exiled critics of the Kremlin.
The watchdog, Rosfinmonitoring, added the two men to a</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 14:22:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Modhumoti Bank holds 44th meeting of risk management committee</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/modhumoti-bank-holds-44th-meeting-of-risk-management-committee</link><description>The 44th Meeting of the Risk Management Committee of the Board of Directors of Modhumoti Bank PLC was held on Sunday, according to a press release.
The meeting was presided over by Mr. Mostafa Kamal, Chairman of the Board’s Risk Management Committee of Modhumoti Bank PLC. Among the members o</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 13:25:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Islami Bank holds board meeting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/islami-bank-holds-board-meeting-112233</link><description>A meeting of the board of directors of Islami Bank Bangladesh PLC was held on Monday at Islami Bank Tower.
Professor Dr. M. Zubaidur Rahman, chairman of the bank, presided over the meeting, according to a press release.
Mohammad Khurshid Wahab, chairman of the executive committee, Md. Abdus Salam</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 13:40:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka Bank, UNCDF partner to promote digital financial literacy for migrant families under Shafal Programme</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/dhaka-bank-uncdf-partner-to-promote-digital-financial-literacy-for-migrant-families-under-shafal-programme</link><description>Dhaka Bank PLC, in partnership with the Shafal Programme; a joint initiative of the United Nations Capital Development Fund (UNCDF) and the Embassy of Switzerland in Bangladesh has launched the “Digital Financial Literacy (DFL) for Migrant Workers &amp; Families” initiative to strengthen di</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 13:55:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Britain’s BBC ‘determined to fight’ any Trump case, chair tells staff</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/britains-bbc-determined-to-fight-any-trump-case-chair-tells-staff</link><description>Britain’s BBC is “determined to fight” any legal action filed by US President Donald Trump, saying on Monday there was no basis for a defamation case over its editing of one of his speeches.
Trump said on Friday he would likely sue the BBC this week for as much as $5 billion afte</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 14:10:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Citizens Bank PLC holds Annual Risk Conference 2025</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/citizens-bank-plc-holds-annual-risk-conference-2025</link><description>Citizens Bank PLC organized Annual Risk Conference 2025 at its Head Office in Dhaka recently, according to a press release.
Mr. A.N.M. Moinul Kabir, Director, Dept. of Offsite Supervision, Bangladesh Bank inaugurated the conference as the chief guest and delivered his valuable guidelines regarding</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 14:25:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BRAC Bank starts comprehensive training to groom new SME entrepreneurs in Sirajganj</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/brac-bank-starts-comprehensive-training-to-groom-new-sme-entrepreneurs-in-sirajganj</link><description>BRAC Bank has formally launched the second batch of intensive training for promising SME business owners in Sirajganj under the Entrepreneurship Development Programme of the Finance Division of the Ministry of Finance and Bangladesh Bank.
BRAC Bank, with support from the Finance Division of the Mi</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 14:40:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jubo Dal leader shot dead in Pallabi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/jubo-dal-leader-shot-dead-in-pallabi</link><description>A Jatiyatabadi Jubo Dal leader has been shot dead in Dhaka’s Pallabi, police say.
On Monday at 7pm, three masked men wearing helmets entered a hardware shop near C Block, close to the old police station, and shot Golam Kibria at close range.
Local resident said Kibria was the member secreta</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 14:55:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh Election: EC to launch mobile app for postal balloting Tuesday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-election-ec-to-launch-mobile-app-for-postal-balloting-tuesday</link><description>The Election Commission is set to launch a mobile app ‘Postal Vote BD’ on Tuesday (November 18) for a particular section of voters including expatriates to register to vote through the postal balloting in the 13th parliamentary election.
The ‘Postal Vote BD’ mobile app will</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 15:10:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Russian missile strike kills three, wounds 10 in Kharkiv region, Ukraine says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/russian-missile-strike-kills-three-wounds-10-in-kharkiv-region-ukraine-says</link><description>A Russian missile strike on the eastern Ukrainian city of Balakliia killed three people, with three teenagers among the 10 wounded, Kharkiv regional officials said on Monday.
The overnight attack damaged multi-storey residence blocks and destroyed scores of cars in the city centre, Oleh Synehubov,</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 15:25:52 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>