<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 06:00:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Aminul Islam takes charge as ICT chief prosecutor</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/aminul-islam-takes-charge-as-ict-chief-prosecutor</link><description>The government has appointed Md Aminul Islam, a pro-BNP Supreme Court lawyer, as the new chief prosecutor of the International Crimes Tribunal (ICT) in Dhaka, replacing Muhammad Tajul Islam.
The Ministry of Law, Justice and Parliamentary Affairs issued a notification on Monday, confirming the appo</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 03:01:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Culex density rises in Dhaka, may peak in March</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/culex-density-rises-in-dhaka-may-peak-in-march</link><description>The high density of Culex mosquitoes in the capital and other parts of the country is unlikely to ease anytime soon, experts say, at least until the rains arrive and local government authorities become fully functional.
The surge in mosquitoes has made life uncomfortable both indoors and outdoors,</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 03:16:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nine hurt in Ctg gas blast</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nine-hurt-in-ctg-gas-blast</link><description>CHATTOGRAM, Feb 23: Nine persons, including a child, were injured in a gas explosion at Halima Manzil in the port-city's Halishahar area on Monday. The victims were identified as Shipon (30), Sumon (40), Shaon (17), Anas (07), Aimman (09), Shakwat (46), Ayesha (04), Pakhi (35), and Rani (40).
Accu</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 03:31:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DCCI flags extortion, opaque US trade deal as risks to economic recovery</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/dcci-flags-extortion-opaque-us-trade-deal-as-risks-to-economic-recovery</link><description>Rampant extortion, deteriorating law and order and an opaque trade agreement with the United States are threatening to suffocate Bangladesh's fragile economic recovery, the Dhaka Chamber of Commerce &amp; Industry (DCCI) has warned.
Speaking at a press conference on Monday titled "Expectations from th</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 03:46:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Karwan Bazar traders announce lower profit sales during Ramadan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/karwan-bazar-traders-announce-lower-profit-sales-during-ramadan</link><description>Traders at Karwan Bazar on Monday made an announcement to sell several essential items at lower profit margins during the holy month of Ramadan.
The announcement which aims to help stabilise prices of daily necessities such as lemons, edible oil, and sugar was made at a press conference organised</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 04:01:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Despite strong profits, Biman's total assets decline for third straight year</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/despite-strong-profits-bimans-total-assets-decline-for-third-straight-year</link><description>Despite repeated claims by Biman Bangladesh Airlines that it has remained profitable over the five consecutive years, the national carrier's total assets have continued to decline.
According to the airline's latest audited financial statements, total assets stood at Tk 168.72 billion at the end of</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 04:16:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Miscreants vandalise BNP office in Natore</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/miscreants-vandalise-bnp-office-in-natore</link><description>Miscreants vandalised a local BNP office in Naldianga upazila of Natore on Monday evening.
Rakib Hossain, a local Jubo Dal leader, said a group of assailants attacked the BNP office at Ward No. 9 in Chatarbhag Market of Brakhpur Union and caused extensive damage.
The incident occurred during Ifta</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 04:31:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fire guts valuables at Khulna shopping mall</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fire-guts-valuables-at-khulna-shopping-mall</link><description>A fire gutted the valuables of five shops at Baitun Nur Shopping Complex near New Market in Khulna city early Tuesday.
Witnesses said the fire started around 11:30 pm, and locals informedthe  Khulna Fire Service immediately.
Six fire units of Khulna Fire Service brought the blaze under contr</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 04:46:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Seven die as Delhi-bound air ambulance crashes in Jharkhand</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/seven-die-as-delhi-bound-air-ambulance-crashes-in-indias-jharkhand</link><description>All seven people, including two crew members, on board an air ambulance were killed after the aircraft crashed in the eastern Indian state of Jharkhand, local officials said Tuesday.
The air ambulance crashed on Monday night near Simaria in Chatra district, about 111 km north of Ranchi, the capita</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 05:07:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gold falls from three-week high on profit-booking, firm dollar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/global/gold-falls-from-three-week-high-on-profit-booking-firm-dollar</link><description>Gold prices fell on Tuesday as investors booked profits after bullion rose more than 2% in the previous session, while pressure from a stronger dollar also weighed on the yellow metal.
Spot gold fell 0.8% to $5,189.99 per ounce by 0125 GMT, snapping a four-session winning streak and dropping from</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 05:22:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Narayanganj’s daily battle with traffic and broken roads</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/narayanganjs-daily-battle-with-traffic-and-broken-roads</link><description>For thousands of residents in Narayanganj, a short journey across town has become an exhausting daily trial.
What was once a 10-minute commute now routinely stretches beyond an hour, as chronic traffic congestion, pothole-ridden roads and ongoing development works converge to choke the city’</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 05:37:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ctg gas blast toll rises to 2 as teen dies a day after mother</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ctg-gas-blast-toll-rises-to-2-as-teen-dies-a-day-after-mother</link><description>A teenage boy has died a day after his mother succumbed to burn injuries from a gas explosion at a flat in Chattogram’s Halishahar, raising the death toll in the incident to two.
The victim, 16-year-old Shawon, had suffered burns across 50 per cent of his body, including his respiratory tr</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 05:52:12 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>