<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 02:22:08 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>‘Party support, not lineage, drew me back to Bangladesh’, Tarique tells Time Magazine</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/party-support-not-lineage-drew-me-back-to-bangladesh-tarique-tells-time-magazine</link><description>BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman has said he is the right person to heal Bangladesh’s divisions, insisting his return is driven by party supporters rather than family lineage.
“It’s not because I’m the son of my father and mother,” he told the Time Magazine in his first ex</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 16:14:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chinese fossils show marine animals thriving half a billion years ago</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/chinese-fossils-show-marine-animals-thriving-half-a-billion-years-ago</link><description>Scientists have unearthed in southern China fossils of a multitude of marine creatures dating to more than a half billion years ago, showing a deep-water ecosystem thriving in the aftermath of the first mass extinction of the animal world.
The Cambrian Period fossils, about 512 million years old,</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 16:08:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC estimates Tk 31 billion cost for Feb-12 election, referendum</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-estimates-tk-31-billion-cost-for-feb-12-election-referendum</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has estimated the overall expenditures for the upcoming referendum and the 13th national parliamentary election at some Tk 31 billion.
The Commission on Wednesday approved the budget, estimating the total cost of Tk 31 billion to conduct the referendum and general elec</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 16:23:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Voting in Bangladesh to be held through 42,779 polling stations</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/voting-in-bangladesh-to-be-held-through-42779-polling-stations</link><description>The balloting will be held through 42,779 polling stations in the 300 constituencies throughout the country in the referendum and national election scheduled for February 12 next.
“The final number of polling stations is 42,779 and that of polling booths is 247,482 in the referendum and 13th</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 16:38:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Why Phillips Curve fails in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/why-phillips-curve-fails-in-bangladesh</link><description>In simple terms, the Phillips Curve proposes a trade-off: when an economy grows rapidly and jobs become plentiful, prices tend to rise faster; when unemployment is high, inflation tends to slow. In other words, a country may tolerate some inflation to achieve more employment or accept higher unempl</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 16:53:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>When laws fail to protect children</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/when-laws-fail-to-protect-children</link><description>That the corporal punishment of children is banned is nothing new. But the fact is there are few schools or madrasahs countrywide that are following this rule. The issue has once again come into focus and triggered public outrage after two recent incidents of violence against children surfaced on s</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 17:08:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tradable savings certificate on bond market</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/tradable-savings-certificate-on-bond-market</link><description>The liquidity crisis in banks stemming mainly from non-performing loans (NPLs) has long stoked the compulsion of exploring alternative sources of sustainable fund. Since foreign investment is hard to come by, the search for such alternative sources has become even more compelling. Now the Banglades</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 17:23:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Asif, Mahfuj occupy homes meant for ministers, two months on</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/asif-mahfuj-occupy-homes-meant-for-ministers-two-months-on</link><description>Nearly two months after resigning as interim ministers, Mahfuj Alam has said he will vacate his government-allotted residence in the Secretariat before the election, while Asif Mahmud Shojib Bhuyain has claimed that he left his allotted house about a month ago.
However, despite Asif’s claim,</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 18:47:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat leader dies after election event clash in Sherpur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jamaat-leader-dies-after-election-event-clash-in-sherpur</link><description>A local Jamaat-e-Islami leader has died after being injured in a clash during an election manifesto reading programme in Sherpur.
Rezaual Karim, secretary of Jamaat’s Sreebordi Upazila unit, was injured in a confrontation triggered by a dispute over seating at the event in Jhenaigati.
Moham</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 19:02:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Banks seek nod to disclose loan defaulters’ photos, lists</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/banks-seek-nod-to-disclose-loan-defaulters-photos-lists</link><description>Commercial banks have sought permission from Bangladesh Bank to publish photographs and lists of loan defaulters as part of efforts to recover defaulted loans.
The Association of Bankers, Bangladesh (ABB), representing commercial banks, sent a letter to Governor Ahsan H Mansur on Wednesday outlini</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 19:17:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Internet blackout forced ‘mighty’ govt to flee: Yunus</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/yunus-says-internet-shutdown-during-uprising-ignited-youth-anger-that-toppled-powerful-government</link><description>Chief Advisor Muhammad Yunus has said the consequences of the internet shutdown during the July Uprising unleashed youth frustration that toppled a “mighty” government.
Speaking at the inauguration of the four-day Digital Devices and Innovation Expo on Wednesday, the interim government</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 19:32:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No more credit squeeze with tightfisted monetary policy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/no-more-credit-squeeze-with-tightfisted-monetary-policy</link><description>Planning Adviser Prof Wahiduddin Mahmud has said it is time to make a review of the tight monetary policy stance, for the same has not worked as desired.



"There is no longer much need to control inflation by reducing credit flow through monetary policy by simply increasing interest rates. In</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 20:33:19 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>