<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 14:18:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Ctg rally protests ‘foreign control’ of port terminals</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/foreign-control-over-chattogram-port-terminals-part-of-long-term-conspiracy-says-rally</link><description>A rally in Chattogram has alleged that plans to hand over the city’s port terminals to foreign companies are part of “a long-term imperialist conspiracy” centred on Bangladesh’s hill regions.
The protest was held on Saturday afternoon at Agrabad intersection under the banne</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 11:33:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>RSF identifies 314 accident-prone upazilas across Bangladesh, 139 as highly risky</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rsf-identifies-314-accident-prone-upazilas-across-bangladesh-139-as-highly-risky</link><description>The Road Safety Foundation (RSF) has identified 314 accident-prone upazilas, each falling under its respective police station across Bangladesh, categorizing 139 as highly accident-prone areas and 175 as accident-prone zones.
Within them, 21 upazilas are considered extremely high-risk, according t</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 12:03:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>PR system demand part of plan to form a fragile government: Hafizuddin</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/pr-system-demand-part-of-plan-to-form-a-fragile-government-hafizuddin</link><description>BNP senior leader Hafizuddin Ahmed on Saturday said the demand for proportional representation (PR) in the next national election is aimed at creating a weak government in the country.
“Demanding proportional representation (PR) essentially means demanding a weak government--such unrealistic</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 12:18:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sirajganj beggar Saleha dies leaving behind 3 sacks of money</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/sirajganj-beggar-saleha-dies-leaving-behind-3-sacks-of-money</link><description>Saleha Begum, popularly known as “Saleha Pagli,” a beggar from Sirajganj, passed away on Friday night while undergoing treatment at Shaheed Ziaur Rahman Medical College Hospital in Bogura.
Saleha Begum, wife of the late Abdus Salam from Masumpur colony in Sirajganj, had been staying in</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 12:33:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Muntassir Mamoon removed from CU Bangabandhu Chair</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/chittagong-university-revokes-bangabandhu-chair-appointment-of-muntassir-mamoon</link><description>Chittagong University has cancelled the appointment of historian Prof Muntassir Mamoon to the prestigious Bangabandhu Chair.
The university sent a letter to Mamun on Oct 19, formally ending his appointment retroactive to Mar 15, 2023.
In the letter signed by Acting Registrar Professor Mohammed Sa</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 13:03:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sonali Bank holds day-long workshop for managers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/sonali-bank-holds-day-long-workshop-for-managers</link><description>Sonali Bank PLC arranged a day-long ‘Soft skills for branch managers’ on Saturday.
Sonali Bank PLC MD  CEO Md. Shawkat Ali Khan inaugurated the workshop at a function at the bank’s Staff College in the city’s Uttara, where College Principal and General Managers In-char</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 13:18:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘DBL is committed to excellence’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/dbl-is-committed-to-excellence</link><description>Country’s ceramic industry has been growing steadily against the backdrop of rapid urbanisation and modern lifestyle changes, among others. Amid such transformation, the DBL Group has emerged as a big name in the country’s ceramic industry. Mr. M. A. Jabbar, managing director of DBL Gro</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 13:33:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>National Bank’s ‘Managers Meet’ inspires 19 branch leaders of Cumilla Region</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/national-banks-managers-meet-inspires-19-branch-leaders-of-cumilla-region</link><description>National Bank PLC organized an engaging and outcome-driven “Managers Meet” with 19 branch managers from the Cumilla region on 23 October 2025, aimed at reviewing branch performance, sharing operational insights, and setting a renewed course for sustainable growth and service excellence.</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 13:48:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Salman Shah ‘murder’: Police want immigration alert</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/entertainment/salman-shah-murder-police-want-immigration-alert</link><description>Police have requested support from the immigration authorities to prevent suspects in actor Salman Shah’s alleged murder from leaving the country.
Masud Alam, deputy commissioner of Dhaka Metropolitan Police’s Ramna Division, said they are acting in line with court orders regarding the</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 14:18:09 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>