<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 15:23:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Russia, at war, faces double trouble</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/russia-at-war-faces-double-trouble-trump-ultimatum-and-a-hit-to-oil-sales-to-india</link><description>Russia, the world's second largest oil exporter, is weighing how to respond to US sanctions on top oil firms Rosneft and Lukoil and the prospect of lower sales to its biggest buyer, India.
President Vladimir Putin, who sent troops into Ukraine in 2022, has been in discussions with US President Don</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 13:18:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Japan's Mount Fuji sees snow for first time this winter, 21 days later than usual</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/japans-mount-fuji-sees-snow-for-first-time-this-winter-21-days-later-than-usual</link><description>The peak of Japan's Mount Fuji was capped with snow for the first time this winter on Thursday, reaching the milestone 21 days later than the average since records began in 1894, the meteorological agency said.
This year's snowfall came two weeks earlier than 2024, when snow settled on the 3,776-m</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 13:33:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Most Americans think Trump targets his enemies</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/majority-of-americans-think-trump-is-targeting-enemies-reuters-ipsos-poll-finds</link><description>More than half of Americans, including about three in 10 Republicans, believe President Donald Trump is using federal law enforcement to go after his enemies, according to a new Reuters/Ipsos poll that also found growing concern about US political divisions nine months into his second term in offic</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 12:57:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Flyadeal launches low-cost direct flights on Dhaka–Jeddah route</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/flyadeal-launches-low-cost-direct-flights-on-dhaka-jeddah-route</link><description>Saudi Arabia’s low-cost carrier Flyadeal has officially launched its operations in Bangladesh, introducing direct flights between Dhaka and Jeddah at affordable fares.
The airline’s inaugural flight departed from Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport on Wednesday (October 22) at noon,</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 13:12:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Bangladesh can turn climate challenges into sustainable growth’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/bangladesh-can-turn-climate-challenges-into-sustainable-growth</link><description>With the right partnerships and policies, Bangladesh can turn climate challenges into sustainable and inclusive growth, said Ambassador Christian Brix Møller of Denmark to Bangladesh.
Carbon markets can play a central role in this transformation,” he noted while addressing a dialogue</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 13:27:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>First ever mass media campaign on ‘speeding’ launched</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/first-ever-mass-media-campaign-on-speeding-launched</link><description>Dhaka North City Corporation (DNCC) and Vital Strategies jointly launched the first-ever mass media campaign today (Thursday) to inform the public, including drivers, about the Motor Vehicle Speed ​​Limit Guidelines 2024.
The campaign was officially launched at the conference room of DNCC this aft</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 13:57:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NIMD delegation meets BNP, talks about polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/nimd-delegation-meets-bnp-talks-about-polls</link><description>A visiting delegation from the Netherlands-based Institute for Multi-Party Democracy (NIMD) met BNP leaders on Thursday and discussed Bangladesh’s overall political situation and issues related to the national election.
The hour-long meeting, which began around 4 pm, was held at the BNP Chai</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 14:12:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh win first ODI series after 19 months</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/bangladesh-win-first-odi-series-after-19-months</link><description>Bangladesh put up a dominating performance to thrash West Indies by 179 runs in the third and final match today to take the series 2-1, ending a painful losing streak at their sacred venue-Sher-e-Bangla National Cricket Stadium.
Having won the game, Bangladesh clinched an ODI series after March, 2</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 14:42:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NRBC Bank holds Entrepreneur Development Training</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/nrbc-bank-holds-entrepreneur-development-training</link><description>NRBC Bank has organised an entrepreneurship development training aimed at promoting the growth of small and medium enterprises (SMEs).
The program was held on Thursday, October 23, 2025, in Feni, under the supervision of the Bangladesh Bank and with financial support from the Asian Development Ban</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 14:57:39 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>