<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 23:16:17 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Yamal among highest-paid players in 2025 in Forbes list topped by Ronaldo</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/yamal-among-highest-paid-players-in-2025-in-forbes-list-topped-by-ronaldo</link><description>Barcelona's 18-year-old winger Lamine Yamal has gate-crashed football's financial elite, landing among Forbes' top 10 highest-paid players in 2025, topped by Portugal forward Cristiano Ronaldo.
Ronaldo tops Forbes' latest list with a staggering $280 million in earnings this year, maintaining his s</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 16:21:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>More than one million World Cup tickets sold through Visa pre-sales</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/more-than-one-million-world-cup-tickets-sold-through-visa-pre-sales</link><description>More than one million tickets for the 2026 World Cup have been sold following the conclusion of the Visa V.N pre-sales phase, world football’s governing body FIFA said on Thursday.
Fans from 212 countries and territories purchased tickets during the pre-sales period, which opened in mid-Sept</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 16:51:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>RUCSU elections vote counting under way at girls’ hall</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/rucsu-elections-vote-counting-under-way-at-girls-hall</link><description>Vote counting has begun at Rajshahi University four and a half hours after balloting concluded for the student union, hall councils, and senate student elections.
On Thursday, the RUCSU Election Commission announced that counting started at the girls’ hall. Completing the entire process and</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 17:06:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Access to mental health service in times of catastrophe</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/access-to-mental-health-service-in-times-of-catastrophe</link><description>As the world marks World Mental Health Day 2025, the conversation has turned to an urgent question: who receives care when disaster strikes? This year's theme - "Access to Services: Mental Health in Catastrophes and Emergencies" - underscores a sobering truth. When earthquakes, floods, wars, or pan</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 17:22:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Opting for energy-efficient building glass</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/opting-for-energy-efficient-building-glass</link><description>Glass-fronted buildings have nowadays become the new norm in cities in Bangladesh. Almost all corporate headquarters, luxury hotels, hospitals, and shopping malls in all big cities, particularly Dhaka, have adopted this new architectural style, as it represents progress and sophistication. But thes</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 17:37:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Beyond observance of the World Standards Day</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/beyond-observance-of-the-world-standards-day</link><description>Observance of the World Standards Day or International Standards Day on October 14 in this country has become routine but its confinement to the official circle and some private agencies has little helped create the mass awareness and spread the message. The rhetoric speakers at the function exude</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 17:52:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Addressing NTBs to cement partnership with EU</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/addressing-ntbs-to-cement-partnership-with-eu</link><description>While Bangladesh has long focused on removing non-tariff barriers (NTBs) in other countries to facilitate its exports, it now finds itself facing similar demands from the European Union (EU) -- its largest trading partner. The EU has formally asked Dhaka to eliminate a number of trade- and investme</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 18:07:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tens of thousands light torches in north demanding fair share of Teesta water</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tens-of-thousands-light-torches-in-north-demanding-fair-share-of-teesta-water</link><description>Around one hundred thousand people across northern Bangladesh lit torches on Thursday evening, demanding a fair share of the Teesta River water and the swift implementation of the Teesta Master Plan to revive the river’s flow. 
The torch processions were held under the second phase of t</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 19:09:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Three reasons why IMF cuts Bangladesh's growth forecast</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/three-reasons-why-imf-cuts-bangladeshs-growth-forecast</link><description>The International Monetary Fund (IMF) has cited three major reasons for downward revision of Bangladesh's GDP-growth prospect for this fiscal year, including a pass-through ambience of uncertainty.
"I think there are three reasons, one of course is the policy mix has been tighter, the second tarif</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 19:24:02 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>