<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 05:59:16 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>BTRC issues revised guidelines for GSO satellite operators</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/btrc-issues-revised-guidelines-for-gso-satellite-operators</link><description>The Bangladesh Telecommunication Regulatory Commission (BTRC) has issued a revised set of "Regulatory and Licensing Guidelines for Geosynchronous Orbit (GSO) Satellite Operator", replacing the 2022 "Regulatory and Licensing Guidelines for Satellite Operator in Bangladesh" with a more specialised an</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 02:50:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>RMG exports to EU grow 5.97pc in 2025 amid rising competition</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/rmg-exports-to-eu-grow-597pc-in-2025-amid-rising-competition</link><description>Bangladesh's readymade garment (RMG) exports to the European Union (EU) recorded 5.97 per cent year-on-year growth in 2025, according to Eurostat data.
The country fetched 19.41 billion euros from garment shipments to the 27-nation bloc, up from 18.31 billion euros in 2024.
However, single-month</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 03:05:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladeshi Ahmed Fahmi shortlisted for Commonwealth Youth Awards 2026</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/youth-and-entrepreneurship/bangladeshi-ahmed-fahmi-shortlisted-for-commonwealth-youth-awards-2026</link><description>Bangladeshi youth leader Ahmed Fahmi has been shortlisted as a regional finalist for Asia for the 2026 Commonwealth Youth Awards for Excellence in Development Work. The recognition highlights his contributions to climate resilience and community-based development in Bangladesh.
Fahmi is among 20 f</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 03:20:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Is work-life balance a thing in Bangladesh?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/youth-and-entrepreneurship/is-work-life-balance-a-thing-in-bangladesh</link><description>In Bangladesh, in many households, work doesn't end when the work hours are over. The phone rings continuously, messages need to be answered and exhaustion turns into a daily routine. For the vast majority of professionals, this has become normal and hardly anyone questions it. Yet globally, the co</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 03:35:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Global learnings for Bangladesh's new government</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/youth-and-entrepreneurship/global-learnings-for-bangladeshs-new-government</link><description>To the newly elected party,
Your victory in February 2026 carries a mandate that extends far beyond partisan politics. The students who stood in the streets during July 2024 did not risk their lives for cosmetic change or a mere rotation of parties. They demanded the dismantling of a system that h</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 03:50:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Crowds gather at date market ahead of Ramadan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/crowds-gather-at-date-market-ahead-of-ramadan</link><description>A few days remain before the Islamic holy month of Ramadan. As that time edges closer, the hustle and bustle at markets selling dates – one of the staples of many Iftar tables – has reached a new level as buyers and sellers haggle over prices. On Saturday afternoon, crowds were seen at</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 04:05:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat-led 11-party alliance seeks fresh vote count in 30 constituencies</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-led-11-party-alliance-seeks-fresh-vote-count-in-30-constituencies</link><description>The Jamaat-e-Islami–led 11-party alliance has demanded a fresh vote count in 30 constituencies from the election, alleging widespread irregularities and biased conduct during polling and result tabulation.
Alliance leaders raised the allegations at a press conference on Saturday at Jamaat&amp;rs</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 04:20:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat surge wipes out Jatiya Party in former Rangpur bastion</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-surge-wipes-out-jatiya-party-in-former-rangpur-bastion</link><description>Jatiya Party has suffered a near wipe-out in its former stronghold Rangpur, while a Jamaat-e-Islami-led 11-party alliance has emerged as the dominant force in the division.
The alliance won 19 of the region’s 33 seats in the national election.
BNP secured 13 seats and an independent candida</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 04:35:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh invites Indian PM Modi to Tarique Rahman’s swearing-in</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-invites-indian-pm-modi-to-tarique-rahmans-swearing-in</link><description>Dhaka has invited Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi to attend the swearing-in ceremony of Bangladesh’s prime minister-in-waiting Tarique Rahman in what is being seen as the incoming government’s first calculated diplomatic overture.
Diplomatic sources in the region said on Saturday n</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 04:50:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>As BNP returns to power, Tarique Rahman faces defining task of healing a divided Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/as-bnp-returns-to-power-tarique-rahman-faces-defining-task-of-healing-a-divided-bangladesh</link><description>After a long road marked by street movements, repression and prison sentences, the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) is poised to form a government again -- nearly two decades after it last held power.
The mandate is sweeping. Expectations are sky-high. The obstacles ahead are mountainous.
Beyon</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 05:05:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BCB president Aminul skips India-Pakistan clash in Colombo</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bcb-president-aminul-skips-india-pakistan-clash-in-colombo</link><description>Bangladesh Cricket Board (BCB) President Aminul Islam has decided not to attend today’s high-voltage T20 World Cup match between India and Pakistan in Colombo, reportedly because the Bangladesh national team is not participating in the tournament.
According to BCB sources, Aminul retur</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 05:20:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh’s incoming govt takes office with economy at crossroads</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/bangladeshs-incoming-govt-takes-office-with-economy-at-crossroads</link><description>As Bangladesh prepares for the formation of a new government following the 13th national election, expectations are running high among depositors, investors and job seekers seeking relief from prolonged financial strain.
The BNP-led alliance is set to assume office amid mounting economic pre</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 05:35:04 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>