<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 15:26:58 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>People want to see Islamic governance this time: Charmonai</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/people-want-to-see-islamic-governance-this-time-charmonai</link><description>Islami Andolan Bangladesh Ameer Mufti Rezaul Karim, better known as Charmonai pir, on Tuesday said that the July uprising did not take place to allow extortionists or killers to assume power.
He made the remarks while addressing the divisional gathering of eight like-minded Islamic parties in Bari</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 12:15:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Primary teachers’ group warns of locking schools amid demands over pay, promotions</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/primary-teachers-group-warns-of-locking-schools-amid-demands-over-pay-promotions</link><description>As a section of government primary school teachers continue their work stoppage by boycotting annual exams over pay raises and grade complexities, while another group threatened to “lock” schools if their demands are not met.
On Tuesday, several assistant teachers under the banner of t</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 12:30:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP to shift investment focus from megaprojects to grassroots: Amir Khosru</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-to-shift-investment-focus-from-megaprojects-to-grassroots-amir-khosru</link><description>BNP Standing Committee member Amir Khosru Mahmud Chowdhury on Tuesday said their party would prioritise investment at the grassroots level instead of megaprojects if it returns to power, ensuring that development benefits reach all citizens.
“Many megaprojects have already been implemented.</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 12:45:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Why house rent guidelines not issued in Dhaka, other cities: HC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/why-house-rent-guidelines-not-issued-in-dhaka-other-cities-hc</link><description>The High Court on Tuesday issued a rule seeking explanation as to why guidelines for determining house rents in all city corporations including Dhaka have not been formulated.
A High Court bench headed by Justice Shikdar Mahmudur Razi issued the rule after primary hearing of a writ petition in thi</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 13:00:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh, Myanmar fishery sector leaders sign deal for market expansion</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladesh-myanmar-fishery-sector-leaders-sign-deal-for-market-expansion</link><description>Bangladesh and Myanmar fishery sector leaders teamed up to help boost trade growth and market expansion of the fisheries industries of the two countries.
In this connection, Bangladesh Frozen Foods Exporters Association (BFFEA) and Myanmar Fishery Products Processors and Exporters Association (MPE</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 13:15:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Army chief for developing army as a professional force</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/army-chief-for-developing-army-as-a-professional-force</link><description>Chief of Army Staff General Waker-Uz-Zaman has reiterated his deep determination to develop the Army as a trained, disciplined and professional force equipped with modern weapons.
He came up with this call while speaking at the ‘Presidential Parade’ marking the commissioning of the off</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 13:30:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC plans extended polling hours, extra voting booths in referendum, polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-plans-extended-polling-hours-extra-voting-booths-in-referendum-polls</link><description>With Bangladesh set to hold parliamentary elections alongside the referendum, the Election Commission (EC) is considering extending polling time by one hour and doubling the number of voting booths in each centre in an effort to ensure smooth voting and prevent delays in counting.
On Tuesday, Elec</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 13:45:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sri Lanka Cyclone: 3 Bangladesh nationals rescued</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/sri-lanka-cyclone-3-bangladesh-nationals-rescued</link><description>India has rescued and assisted over 150 people, including three Bangladesh nationals, through its combined operations, which are continuing in Sri Lanka following Cyclone Ditwah.
In coordination with the Sri Lankan Air Force, Chetak helicopters from INS Vikrant and MI-17 helicopters of the Indian</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 14:00:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique Rahman will return soon if Khaleda Zia’s condition remains unchanged: Fakhrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-rahman-will-return-soon-if-khaleda-zias-condition-remains-unchanged-fakhrul</link><description>BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir on Tuesday said that party's Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman will return to the country from London soon, if the health condition of chairperson and former Prime Minister Begum Khaleda Zia remains unchanged.
According to BNP media cell, Fakhrul said</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 14:15:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ukraine struck at least 8 Russian oil refineries last month, drone commander says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/ukraine-struck-at-least-8-russian-oil-refineries-last-month-drone-commander-says</link><description>Ukrainian forces carried out strikes on at least eight Russian oil refineries last month, among 88 targets damaged in long-range drone attacks aimed at weakening Russia’s war effort, a top drone commander said on Tuesday.
Kyiv has stepped up strikes on Russian oil facilities such as refineri</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 14:30:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bank of England sees greater financial risks from AI and lending</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/bank-of-england-sees-greater-financial-risks-from-ai-and-lending</link><description>The Bank of England said on Tuesday that threats to Britain’s financial system had risen this year due to stretched valuations of companies investing in artificial intelligence, risky lending and bets with borrowed money in government bond markets.
The comments in its half-yearly Financial S</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 14:45:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tanzid matches T20 record for catches in Ireland series-decider</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/cricket/tanzid-matches-t20-record-for-catches-in-ireland-series-decider</link><description>Tanzid Hasan has transformed a routine fielding session into a historic display, claiming five crucial catches in succession and cementing Bangladesh’s dominance in the series-decider against Ireland.
In the third T20I in Chattogram on Tuesday, the Tigers dismissed the tourists for 117, owin</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 15:00:57 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>