<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 16:56:36 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Tarique to deliver election address on BTV</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-to-deliver-election-address-on-btv</link><description>BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman will deliver an election address to the nation on Bangladesh Television (BTV) on February 9 ( Monday) ahead of the national election for February 12 next.
Following a letter sent to the Election Commission by BNP, Tarique Rahman has been allocated the time to air his sp</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 14:07:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt Purchase Committee approves fertiliser purchase deals</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-purchase-committee-approves-fertiliser-purchase-deals</link><description>The government on Tuesday approved separate proposals for procuring some 210 thousand metric tons of fertiliser from various sources to meet the country’s agricultural demand during the upcoming crop seasons.
The approvals came from the 5th meeting of the Advisers Council Committee on Govern</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 14:22:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>TIB failed to recognise work on reforms: Finance Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tib-failed-to-recognise-work-on-reforms-finance-adviser</link><description>Finance Adviser Dr Salehuddin Ahmed on Tuesday said Transparency International Bangladesh (TIB) has failed in many cases to properly recognise the government’s ongoing reform initiatives, arguing that not all reforms are immediately visible.
He made the remarks while speaking to reporters at</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 14:37:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>TIB failed to recognise work on reforms: Finance Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tib-failed-to-recognise-work-on-reforms-finance-adviser-1</link><description>Finance Adviser Dr Salehuddin Ahmed on Tuesday said Transparency International Bangladesh (TIB) has failed in many cases to properly recognise the government’s ongoing reform initiatives, arguing that not all reforms are immediately visible.
He made the remarks while speaking to reporters at</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 14:52:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Government sacks Biman MD Shafiqur, puts bureaucrat Humaira in charge</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/government-sacks-biman-md-shafiqur-puts-bureaucrat-humaira-in-charge</link><description>The government has fired Biman Bangladesh Airlines Managing Director and Chief Executive Officer Shafiqur Rahman after his arrest on charges of torturing a child domestic worker.
The Ministry of Civil Aviation and Tourism announced the decision in an office order on Tuesday.
Humaira Sultana, an a</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 15:07:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nurul Azim joins Shimanto Bank as MD &amp; CEO</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/nurul-azim-joins-shimanto-bank-as-md-ceo</link><description>Experienced banker Md. Nurul Azim has officially assumed office on Tuesday (03 February) as the Managing Director and Chief Executive Officer (MD &amp; CEO) of Shimanto Bank PLC. 
Prior to joining Shimanto Bank, he served as the Managing Director of Islamic Finance and Investment PLC, according t</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 15:22:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Purchase Committee approves power purchase proposals from three power plants</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/purchase-committee-approves-power-purchase-proposals-from-three-power-plants</link><description>The government on Tuesday approved power purchase proposals from three major combined cycle power plants at re-determined levelised tariffs, aiming to ensure grid stability while optimising electricity generation costs.
The approvals came from the 5th meeting of the Advisers Council Committee on G</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 15:37:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Draft education law aims to phase out coaching</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/draft-education-law-seeks-to-end-coaching-guidebooks-and-corporal-punishment-in-five-years</link><description>The interim government has come up with a draft education law that proposes a five-year plan to transform teaching and learning in Bangladesh, phasing out private tuitions, guidebooks, and corporal punishments from classrooms.
Teachers, however, may exercise reasonable disciplinary measures in the</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 15:45:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Old Dhaka Muslims observe Shab-e-Barat with traditional foods, charity and illuminated graveyards</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/old-dhaka-muslims-observe-shab-e-barat-with-traditional-foods-charity-and-illuminated-graveyards</link><description>Muslims across the country are observing the holy night of Shab-e-Barat with prayers, zikr and tasbeeh throughout the night, while graveyards have been decorated with lights as devotees seek forgiveness for the departed souls.
In villages and many urban areas, families traditionally prepare homema</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 16:00:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt warns importers over ‘floating warehouses’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/government-orders-cargo-clearance-from-lighter-vessels-within-three-days</link><description>The shipping ministry has ordered importers to clear cargo from lighter vessels within three days or face legal action.
The directive came from Shipping Advisor M Sakhawat Hussain at an inter-ministerial meeting on Tuesday at the ministry that addressed the ongoing crisis in cargo handling from mo</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 16:15:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Taiyeb urges new employees to devote to public services responsibly</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/taiyeb-urges-new-employees-to-devote-to-public-services-responsibly</link><description>Chief Adviser’s Special Assistant for Posts, Telecommunications and Information Technology Ministry Faiz Ahmad Taiyeb on Tuesday called upon the newly appointed office support staff to devote themselves to public service with utmost sincerity.
He made the call while speaking as the chief gue</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 16:30:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh shaken by second quake in a day</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-shaken-again-as-59-magnitude-quake-hits-near-myanmar-border</link><description>Bangladesh has experienced its second earthquake in a single day, this time originating near the Myanmar border.
According to GFZ Earthquake Explorer, the tremor struck at 9:34pm Bangladesh time with a magnitude of 5.9 on the Richter scale.
No immediate reports of casualties or damage have emerge</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 16:45:48 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>