<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 04:21:22 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>RU admission test likely to begin from Jan 16</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/ru-admission-test-likely-to-begin-from-jan-16</link><description>The admission test for the 2025-26 academic session at Rajshahi University (RU) is likely to begin on January 16, 2026, much earlier than previous years, university sources said.
The decision comes as the authorities want to adjust the test schedule ahead of the national election in February and t</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 01:36:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Over 62,500 BO accounts closed in nine months amid market volatility</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/over-62500-bo-accounts-closed-in-nine-months-amid-market-volatility</link><description>Amid persistent volatility in the equity market, as many as 62,552 beneficiary owners' (BO) accounts have been closed over the past nine months, reflecting investors' growing frustration and reduced participation.
According to data from Central Depository Bangladesh Ltd (CDBL), the number of activ</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 01:51:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rice prices keep rising despite record harvest, high imports</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/rice-prices-keep-rising-despite-record-harvest-high-imports</link><description>Rice prices continue to rise in Bangladesh despite record local production and high imports, increasing hardship for ordinary consumers.
In Dhaka's retail markets, coarse rice sells at Tk 58-62 per kg, medium quality at Tk 65-72, and fine rice at Tk 75-98, marking a Tk 2-3 increase over the past t</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 02:06:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt to form multistakeholder reform committee</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/govt-to-form-multistakeholder-reform-committee</link><description>The government has decided to form a multistakeholder reform committee aimed at enhancing the country's tax-to-GDP ratio. Economists, trade experts, business leaders, civil society members, and journalists are expected to be included as committee members.
The move comes after the dissolution of th</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 02:21:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>11 infected with anthrax in Gaibandha</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/11-infected-with-anthrax-in-gaibandha</link><description>GAIBANDHA, Oct 04: At least 11 people were infected with anthrax after slaughtering a sick cow in Sundarganj Upazila of Gaibandha.
Of them, five were admitted to Gaibandha District Hospital. The rest were receiving treatment locally.
Sundarganj Upazila Health and Family Planning Officer Dr. Dibak</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 02:36:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mobile payments attract women more than men: Study</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/mobile-payments-attract-women-more-than-men-study</link><description>Women in Bangladesh are more motivated than men to adopt mobile payment services, according to a new study published in Nature's Scientific Reports.
The research reveals that women's intention to use mobile financial platforms such as bKash, Nagad and Rocket is twice as strongly influenced by thei</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 02:51:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Commonwealth Youth Awards launches New Media Freedom category for media professionals</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/article/commonwealth-youth-awards-launches-new-media-freedom-category-for-media-professionals</link><description>The Commonwealth Youth Awards has expanded its recognition programme to include young media professionals for the first time. The new category, announced in Dhaka on October 04 will honour journalists, broadcasters and writers who use their platforms to advance community development and peace.
The</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 03:06:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How smart executives turn disasters into distinction</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/article/how-smart-executives-turn-disasters-into-distinction</link><description>The project collapsed. Deadlines shattered. Budgets exploded. Fingers pointed in your direction. Most professionals instinctively retreat, hoping the storm passes unnoticed. This response, though natural, represents a fundamental miscalculation about how careers actually advance. The way you handle</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 03:21:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>An unexplored opportunity for Bangladesh's universities</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/article/an-unexplored-opportunity-for-bangladeshs-universities</link><description>At the age of 42, Shajeeb Ahmed finally held his undergraduate degree. More than two decades had passed since he left formal education after HSC, forced to support his family through a series of modest jobs. When colleagues half his age received promotions he deserved, he understood the price of th</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 03:36:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jute-made home décor offers better option</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/analysis/jute-made-home-decor-offers-better-option</link><description>Often called the "golden fibre", jute has been the most important fibre in the whole world for decades. It's natural golden shine and strength, made it worthy of its name "golden fibre".
The story starts in the rural parts of Bengal. Farmers grow jute with great care. They sell it to what we call</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 04:06:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BANGLADESH: A rising investment destination on its path from LDC to DC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/analysis/bangladesh-a-rising-investment-destination-on-its-path-from-ldc-to-dc</link><description>Bangladesh stands at the threshold of transformation, recognized globally as a story of resilience and dynamic progress. Rising from the ashes of 1971, it has developed a vibrant and diversified economy, led by the world-renowned ready-made garment sector. As Bangladesh prepares to graduate from th</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 04:21:21 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>