<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 17:17:47 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>How a two-day insurance claim settlement secures future of Nazmun Nahar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/how-a-two-day-insurance-claim-settlement-secures-future-of-nazmun-nahar</link><description>In the BRAC Bank conference room, young Nabil sat with his face buried in his mother Nazmun Nahar's shoulder. Barely four, the child, currently recovering from a low-grade fever, occasionally looked up at his mother, seemingly unaware of the significance of the meeting.
Having lost her husband, Ar</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 15:13:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AL urges UN to halt election support</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/awami-league-calls-for-suspension-of-undp-assistance-in-parliamentary-election</link><description>The Awami League, which is banned from conducting political activities and cannot participate in the next general election, has appealed to the United Nations to refrain from supporting polls in Bangladesh.
On Saturday, the party sent a letter to Stefan Liller, representative of the United Nations</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 15:28:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bomb explodes outside NCP leader’s office</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crude-bomb-explodes-outside-ncp-leaders-office-in-shariatpur</link><description>A crude bomb has exploded outside the private office of a National Citizen Party (NCP) leader in Shariatpur, triggering panic in the locality.
The blast occurred around Monday night near the municipal Eidgah ground beside the office of Sabuj Talukder, the district NCP’s senior joint coordina</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 15:43:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC issues notifications over awarding registration to NCP, two other parties</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-issues-notifications-over-awarding-registration-to-ncp-two-other-parties</link><description>The Election Commission on Tuesday issued separate notifications over awarding registration to three political parties, including the National Citizen Party (NCP).
According to the notifications, the Commission decided to award registration to NCP with the electoral symbol of ‘Water Lily Bud</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 14:58:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCP to field candidates in all 300 seats: Nahid</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ncp-to-field-candidates-in-all-300-seats-nahid</link><description>The National Citizen Party (NCP) will contest the upcoming national election with the ‘Shapla Kali’ symbol and plans to field candidates in all 300 constituencies, said its convener Nahid Islam.
In a video message to the nation on Tuesday night, Nahid said the party expects to finalise</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 15:13:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No application for voter relocation to be accepted after Nov 10</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/no-application-for-voter-relocation-to-be-accepted-after-nov-10</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) will not accept any application for the relocation of voting addresses after November 10, ahead of the 13th parliamentary election slated for early February 2026.
The EC announced the deadline for voter transfer applications based on changes in residence in a circular</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 15:28:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EU urges inclusion of Airbus in Biman's fleet plan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/eu-urges-inclusion-of-airbus-in-bimans-fleet-plan</link><description>The European Union (EU) today urged Bangladesh to ensure transparency and fair competition in major procurement decisions, particularly regarding the inclusion of Airbus in Biman Bangladesh Airlines' fleet renewal plans, to maintain a level playing field for European companies.
"In this regard, I</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 15:58:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tthree motorcyclists killed in Bagerhat road accident</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tthree-motorcyclists-killed-in-bagerhat-road-accident</link><description>Three motorcyclists were killed in a bus and truck collision at Belai Bridge on the Khulna-Mongla highway in Rampal upazila of Bagerhat on Tuesday.
The deceased were identified as Jamir Ijaddar, 50, Mizan Bepari, 45 and Haripada Roy, 40, all residents of Rajnagar Union under Rampal upazila, report</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 16:28:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat for referendum in Nov, election in Feb</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-for-referendum-in-nov-election-in-feb</link><description>Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami on Tuesday called on the interim government to hold the referendum on the July Charter within November and to ensure parliamentary elections in February next year. 
The demand was made at a meeting of the party's Central Executive Council chaired by Ameer Dr. Shafiq</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 16:43:41 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>