<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 17:36:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Tornado destroys over 500 houses in Nilphamari, injures 30</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/tornado-destroys-over-500-houses-in-nilphamari-injures-30</link><description>A sudden tornado struck Garagram Union of Kishoreganj Upazila in Nilphamari on Sunday morning, injuring at least 30 people and damaging over 500 houses.
Most injuries were caused by falling tree branches and collapsing homes. Among the injured, Taiful, 30, Tasin, 25, Royal, 30, Gulchan, 40, and At</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 15:21:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>49th Special BCS admit card download starts Sunday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/49th-special-bcs-admit-cards-available-for-download-from-sunday</link><description>Job seekers can download the admit card for the 49th Special BCS written examination, which is scheduled for next Friday, starting from Sunday night.
More than 312,000 candidates applied to take the multiple-choice question (MCQ) test for this Special BCS, which aims to recruit 683 teachers for go</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 15:36:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Eminent academic Syed Manzoorul Islam put on life support</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/eminent-academic-syed-manzoorul-islam-put-on-life-support</link><description>Syed Manzoorul Islam, emeritus professor and eminent writer, has been placed on life support at Labaid Hospital in Dhaka.
He has been undergoing treatment at the hospital since Friday, after suffering a heart attack.
Quoting the doctor, Mazharul Islam, chief executive of publishing house Anyaprok</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 16:06:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DGHS urges early test for dengue fever</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/health-authorities-recommend-immediate-dengue-test-for-fever-to-prevent-complications</link><description>The Directorate General of Health Services has recommended that anyone who develops a fever immediately undergo an NS1 test for dengue to ensure timely detection.
The health directorate made the request in a public notice issued on Sunday.
In the 24 hours until Sunday morning, Bangladesh reported</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 15:44:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pereira sees red as toothless Wolves remain winless</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/pereira-sees-red-as-toothless-wolves-remain-winless</link><description>Wolverhampton Wanderers manager Vitor Pereira was sent off as his side remained the only club in England's top four divisions without a league win after a 1-1 home draw with Brighton &amp; Hove Albion in the Premier League on Sunday.
Pereira was shown a red card after 20 minutes when he lost his tempe</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 16:14:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fishermen allege Tk 5.0 million extortion attempt, loot of fish worth Tk 50 million in Feni project</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fishermen-allege-tk-50-million-extortion-attempt-loot-of-fish-worth-tk-50-million-in-feni-project</link><description>Fishermen in Feni’s Sonagazi upazila have alleged that miscreants looted fish worth Tk 50 million from a fisheries project after they refused to pay Tk 5.0 million in extortion money.
The incident took place at the Char Khondakar and Char Ramnarayan fisheries projects. On Sunday, affected fi</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 16:29:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Lalmonirhat at flood risk as Teesta flows above danger level</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/lalmonirhat-at-flood-risk-as-teesta-flows-above-danger-level</link><description>Relentless rainfall and upstream runoff have sent the waters of the Teesta River surging above the danger level, putting the low-lying areas on the left bank of the river, including Lalmonirhat, at risk of flooding.
Around 3pm on Sunday, the water flow recorded at Dalia Point of Teesta Barrage was</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 16:59:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique vows green, sustainable Bangladesh on World Habitat Day</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/tarique-vows-green-sustainable-bangladesh-on-world-habitat-day</link><description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman has pledged to build a greener and more sustainable Bangladesh, stressing the importance of protecting both the environment and planned urbanization.
In a post on his verified Facebook page marking World Habitat Day on Sunda, he said, “I pledge that BNP gov</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 17:14:36 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>