<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 07:26:35 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Special initiative taken to manage stray dogs on St. Martin's Island</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/special-initiative-taken-to-manage-stray-dogs-on-st-martins-island</link><description>The government has taken up a special initiative to manage the dog population on St. Martin's Island as part of a broader effort to protect the island's fragile environment and biodiversity, particularly its endangered marine turtles.
St. Martin's is the only coral island in Bangladesh, situated i</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 04:03:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Much-longed for bridge lies incomplete for years in Sylhet</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/much-longed-for-bridge-lies-incomplete-for-years-in-sylhet</link><description>Construction works for a bridge over the Chhora River - long demanded by students and workers in the Surma tea garden area in Madhabpur Upazila - remain incomplete for years.
The earthen access route at one side of the bridge - which enabled some people to use the structure in the absence of a con</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 04:18:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Adilur for strengthening SME Foundation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/adilur-for-strengthening-sme-foundation</link><description>Advisor for Industries, Housing and Public Works Adilur Rahman Khan has laid importance on strengthening the SME Foundation structurally to further energise the small and medium enterprise sector and accelerate its development for expanding domestic and international markets for different products.</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 04:33:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mobile phone traders demand reforms to NEIR</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/mobile-phone-traders-demand-reforms-to-neir</link><description>Mobile phone traders on Sunday staged a demonstration in the capital's Agargaon area demanding the reform of NEIR initiative.
The road in front of BTRC building was blocked as part of the protest - held under the banner of "Bangladesh Mobile Business Community" around 10 AM.
General Secretary of</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 04:48:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BD, Thailand willing to expand trade relations</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bd-thailand-willing-to-expand-trade-relations</link><description>Bangladesh and Thailand want to further expand their existing trade relations and make more effective use of maritime transport facilities between the two nations.
The views came when Thailand Ambassador to Bangladesh, Thitiporn Chirasawadi, made a courtesy call on Commerce Adviser Sk Bashir Uddin</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 05:03:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>38th AGM of Kohinoor Chemical held</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/38th-agm-of-kohinoor-chemical-held</link><description>The 38th Annual General Meeting (AGM) of Kohinoor Chemical Company (BD) Limited was held at 3:15 pm on Sunday on a digital platform.
Md Rezaul Karim, managing director of Kohinoor Chemical Company, was present at the meeting, says a media release.
Md Ebadul Karim, director, Prof Dr Anwar Hossain,</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 05:18:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt set to implement new project to digitise medical, nursing education</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/govt-set-to-implement-new-project-to-digitise-medical-nursing-education</link><description>The government has taken a project aimed at streamlining and strengthening the management of medical, population and nursing education services across the country.
The project “Integrated Improvement in the Management of Activities of the Directorate General of Medical Education (DGME), NIPO</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 05:33:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two Bangladeshi workers die in Maldives</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/two-bangladeshi-workers-die-in-maldives</link><description>Two Bangladeshi migrant workers have reportedly died from cardiac complications within a span of 12 hours in the Maldives.
The men, Ahmed Kamal, 48, and Selim Uddin, 64, were both from Moulvibazar district, reports bdnews24.com.
Md Jasim Uddin, welfare assistant at the Bangladesh High Commission,</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 05:48:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Thailand launches air strikes at Cambodia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/thailand-launches-air-strikes-at-cambodia</link><description>Thailand has launched air strikes along its disputed border with Cambodia, the Thai military said on Monday, after both countries accused the other of breaching a ceasefire agreement brokered by US President Donald Trump.
At least one Thai soldier has been killed, and four wounded in the fresh cla</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 06:03:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shakib Al Hasan cancels retirement</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/cricket/shakib-al-hasan-cancels-retirement</link><description>Bangladesh all-rounder Shakib Al Hasan has rowed back on his decision to retire from Tests and T20Is, saying he now intends to play in all three formats at home before drawing the curtain on his illustrious international career.
He made the remarks during an appearance on the Beard Before Wicket p</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 06:33:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Seven fishermen kidnapped, ransom demanded</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/seven-fishermen-kidnapped-ransom-demanded</link><description>Seven fishermen were abducted allegedly by a group of pirates from different areas of the Sundarbans on Sunday.
The abductors are now charging Tk 50, 000 as ransom for each fisherman.
The incident occurred on Sunday morning in the Malancha River of the Satkhira range, including Hanskhali, Chelaka</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 06:48:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC, Jamaat meet ahead of polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ec-jamaat-meet-ahead-of-polls</link><description>A delegation from Jamaat-e-Islami has sat down for talks with the Election Commission amid preparations to announce the schedule of the 13th parliamentary election and the planned national referendum, expected to take place simultaneously in early February next year.
The meeting began around 11:30</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 07:03:33 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>