<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 15:26:50 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Students call sit-in over DCU push</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/students-call-sunday-sit-in-at-shikkha-bhaban-over-dhaka-central-university-demands</link><description>Students from the seven colleges have announced a continuous sit-in outside Shikkha Bhaban on Abdul Gani Road this Sunday, demanding the issuance of the Dhaka Central University Ordinance.
The declaration came around 4:15pm on Wednesday during a briefing outside Dhaka College, delivered by Abdur R</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 12:37:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>MPPA framework to transform industrial renewable energy procurement: Experts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/mppa-framework-to-transform-industrial-renewable-energy-procurement-experts</link><description>Experts and sector insiders on Wednesday at a discussion said that the imminent Merchant Power Purchase Agreement (MPPA) framework would transform how industries in Bangladesh procure renewable energy.
The possible transition of the renewable energy sector would also help Bangladesh prepare for it</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 12:52:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shimanto Bank launches 'NARI Shanchoy Account' for women</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/shimanto-bank-launches-nari-shanchoy-account-for-women</link><description>Shimanto Bank PLC has launched the “NARI Shanchoy Account,” a specialized savings product offering exclusive benefits for women.
The product was inaugurated at the bank’s Corporate Head Office in presence of all female officials, according to a media release. 
The NARI</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 13:07:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khaleda led from the streets, not from palaces: Moyeen Khan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/khaleda-led-from-the-streets-not-from-palaces-moyeen-khan</link><description>BNP Standing Committee member Abdul Moyeen Khan has said that despite being a national leader, Khaleda Zia built her political legacy on the streets alongside millions of supporters, not from any position of comfort or privilege.
Speaking at a prayer gathering organised by the Jatiyatabadi Palli C</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 13:22:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shahjalal Islami Bank provides financial assistance to a blood cancer patient for his treatment</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/shahjalal-islami-bank-provides-financial-assistance-to-a-blood-cancer-patient-for-his-treatment</link><description>As part of Corporate Social Responsibility (CSR) Program, Shahjalal Islami Bank PLC provided financial assistance of Tk 5.00 (Five Lac) to Md. Shahin Mollah, a resident of Shuktail Village, Gopalganj district, on 02nd December 2025, for the treatment of his blood cancer.
The Deputy Managing Direct</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 13:37:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCP warns of resistance if corrupt EC officials are not removed: Nahid Islam</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ncp-warns-of-resistance-if-corrupt-ec-officials-are-not-removed-nahid-islam</link><description>National Citizen Party (NCP) Convener Nahid Islam on Wednesday warned that the party will “resist” if immediate action is not taken against corrupt officials still working inside the Election Commission (EC).
He issued the warning after a meeting with the Chief Election Commissioner at</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 13:08:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CA Yunus visits Khaleda Zia in Evercare Hospital</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ca-yunus-visits-khaleda-zia-in-evercare-hospital</link><description>Chief Advisor Muhammad Yunus has visited BNP Chairperson Khaleda Zia at Evercare Hospital.

His motorcade entered the hospital at 7:07pm on Wednesday. BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir received him, bdnews24.com reports. 
The chief advisor was then taken to the fourth-floor</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 13:23:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tenure of independent investigation commission on BDR carnage extended</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tenure-of-independent-investigation-commission-on-bdr-carnage-extended</link><description>The government has extended the tenure of the National Independent Investigation Commission formed to reinvestigate the BDR carnage till December 7.
Cabinet Division issued a notification in this regard on Wednesday.
The interim government formed the independent commission on December 24 last yea</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 13:38:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Supply shortfall results in sudden onion price-hike</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/supply-shortfall-results-in-sudden-onion-price-hike</link><description>The country produced 4.4 million tonnes of onion in the 2024-25 growing season, exceeding the estimated demand of 3.5 million tonnes. However, there is now a shortage of onions, and the price has increased.
The prices of locally produced onions have surged recently at both farm and retail levels.</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 13:53:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Probe report in July crimes against humanity case against Joy, others received</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/probe-report-in-july-crimes-against-humanity-case-against-joy-others-received</link><description>The prosecution of the International Crimes Tribunal (ICT) has received the probe report in a case filed over crimes against humanity committed during the July Mass Uprising against Sajeeb Wazed Joy and three others.
"We have received the probe report over July Mass Uprising crimes against humanit</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 14:08:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Standard Chartered and Channel i honour agricultural innovators at 10th Agrow Award</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/standard-chartered-and-channel-i-honour-agricultural-innovators-at-10th-agrow-award</link><description>Standard Chartered Bangladesh and Channel i celebrated the remarkable achievements and pioneering spirit of individuals and organisations shaping the future of the nation’s agriculture sector at the Standard Chartered–Channel i Agrow Award 2025, marking its landmark 10th season.
Hosted</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 14:23:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BRAC Bank leaders stress future-focused risk strategy at Annual Risk Conference 2025</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/brac-bank-leaders-stress-future-focused-risk-strategy-at-annual-risk-conference-2025</link><description>BRAC Bank’s senior leadership has underscored the need for stronger governance, strict compliance, and proactive preparedness to address the risks that may emerge in the coming years.
The call came during the bank’s Annual Risk Conference 2025, according to a media release. 
Vete</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 14:38:35 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>