<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 10:40:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>MANIKGANJ, SYLHET: Too many brick kilns put public health, environment in crisis</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/manikganj-sylhet-too-many-brick-kilns-put-public-health-environment-in-crisis</link><description>An excessive number of brick klins have been polluting the environment in a union in Manikganj, while pollution from unauthorised brick klins deteriorates public health and the environment across four districts in the Sylhet division.
Our correspondent from Manikganj writes, Singair Upazila's Bald</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 06:05:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gaza deaths in war's first 15 months higher than reported, study says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/gaza-deaths-in-wars-first-15-months-higher-than-reported-study-says</link><description>More than 75,000 Palestinians were killed in the first 15 months of Israel's military assault in Gaza, a figure far higher than the 49,000 deaths local health officials announced at the time, says a new study by The Lancet Global Health medical journal.
The peer-reviewed study, published on Wednes</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 06:20:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No security threat surrounding Feb 21 events, says DMP chief</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/no-security-threat-surrounding-feb-21-events-says-dmp-chief</link><description>Dhaka Metropolitan Police Commissioner Sheikh Md Sazzat Ali has said there is no security threat surrounding the observance of Language Martyrs’ Day and International Mother Language Day on Feb 21.
However, he said a multi-layered security arrangement has been put in place, with 15,000 polic</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 07:08:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Food stocks sufficient to keep Ramadan market stable, says commerce minister</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/food-stocks-sufficient-to-keep-ramadan-market-stable-says-commerce-minister</link><description>Commerce Minister Khandaker Abdul Muktadir has said the government has sufficient food stocks to keep prices of essential commodities stable during Ramadan.
Speaking to reporters at Sylhet Osmani International Airport on Friday, he said ensuring price stability was one of the key responsibilities</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 07:23:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Public sufferings in the name of movement won’t be tolerated : RAB</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/public-sufferings-in-the-name-of-movement-wont-be-tolerated-rab</link><description>No one will be allowed to hold the general public hostage or create public suffering in the name of movements or demands, said RAB Director General AKM Shahidur Rahman on Friday.
All necessary measures will be taken to ensure uninterrupted movement and daily life of ordinary people, he told report</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 09:04:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two suspected robbers lynched by mob in Gaibandha</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/two-suspected-robbers-lynched-by-mob-in-gaibandha</link><description>Two men have been beaten to death by locals on suspicion of robbery in Gaibandha’s Sadullapur Upazila.
The incident occurred at dawn on Friday in Khorddmojahidpur village, according to Sadullapur Police Station chief (OC) Abdul Alim.
Police said the men were part of a group that allegedly a</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 09:19:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CNG filling stations to remain closed from 3pm-9pm during Ramadan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cng-filling-stations-to-remain-closed-from-3pm-9pm-during-ramadan</link><description>The government has extended the daily downtime for CNG filling stations during Ramadan to ensure an adequate gas supply for power generation at Iftar.
In a notice issued on Friday, the Energy and Mineral Resources Division said CNG stations will remain closed from 3pm to 9pm each day from the firs</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 09:34:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trader dead, 3 injured as oil tanker crashes into Noakhali shop</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/trader-dead-3-injured-as-oil-tanker-crashes-into-noakhali-shop</link><description>A fertiliser trader has been killed and three others, including his two sons, injured after an oil tanker ran them over and crashed into a roadside shop in Noakhali's Kabirhat Upazila.
The accident occurred around 11am on Friday in the Transmitter area of Sundalpur union along the Sonapur–Ka</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 09:40:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Malaysian PM calls Tarique, congratulates him on landslide victory</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/malaysian-pm-calls-tarique-congratulates-him-on-landslide-victory</link><description>Prime Minister of Malaysia Anwar Ibrahim on Friday telephoned Prime Minister Tarique Rahman and congratulated him on assuming office following a landslide election victory.
“Malaysian Prime Minister Anwar Ibrahim called Tarique Rahman around 3pm and warmly congratulated him on becoming the P</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 09:55:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No more running after doctors, services to reach doorsteps: Health Minister</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/no-more-running-after-doctors-services-to-reach-doorsteps-health-minister</link><description>Health and Family Welfare Minister Sardar Md Sakhawat Hossain on Friday said people will no longer have to run after doctors as the government aims to ensure that doctors reach out to patients at their doorsteps.
“We will build the Health Ministry as a completely corruption- and syndicate-fr</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 10:10:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Budget to be allocated for people, not for individuals or groups: Amir Khasru</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/budget-to-be-allocated-for-people-not-for-individuals-or-groups-amir-khasru</link><description>Finance and Planning Minister Amir Khasru Mahmud Chowdhury today said future budgets would prioritize the welfare of the people rather than cater to specific individuals or groups.
He made the remarks during his first visit to his constituency in Chattogram after assuming office as Finance Ministe</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 10:25:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Is SpiceJet barred from flying over Bangladesh skies?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/is-spicejet-barred-from-flying-over-bangladesh-skies</link><description>The Civil Aviation Authority of Bangladesh (CAAB) has refuted reports in the Indian media that SpiceJet has been barred from entering the country’s airspace over unpaid dues.
Several Indian outlets, citing news agency PTI, reported that Bangladesh was not “allowing” the Indian ai</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 10:40:25 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>