<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 13:34:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Emerging markets including Bangladesh face USD 3.7 trillion annual ESG funding gap: Study</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/emerging-markets-including-bangladesh-face-usd-37-trillion-annual-esg-funding-gap-study</link><description>Emerging economies are grappling with an annual shortfall of USD 3.7 trillion in Environmental, Social, and Governance (ESG) finance required to meet the United Nations Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs) by 2030, according to a new report by Dun &amp; Bradstreet titled “ESG Funding in Emerging</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 11:39:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IMF delegation meets Jamaat representatives</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/imf-delegation-meets-jamaat-representatives</link><description>A delegation from the International Monetary Fund (IMF) on Wednesday held a meeting with representatives of Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami in the afternoon at the party’s central office.
Adviser to the IMF Mission Chief for Bangladesh, Chris Papageorgiou led the IMF delegation, reports BSS.
The</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 11:54:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Midland Bank organizes seminar at Jahangirnagar University jointly with Communic-IBA to promote Financial Literacy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/midland-bank-organizes-seminar-at-jahangirnagar-university-jointly-with-communic-iba-to-promote-financial-literacy</link><description>Midland Bank PLC, in collaboration with Communic-IBA of Jahangirnagar University, jointly organized a seminar on Financial Literacy on 10 November 2025 at the Senate Hall of Jahangirnagar University, Savar, Dhaka.
The seminar was chaired by Professor Dr. Ireen Akther, Director, IBA, Jahangirnagar</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 10:39:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>At least 42 migrants missing, presumed dead, after boat capsizes off Libya, IOM says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/at-least-42-migrants-missing-presumed-dead-after-boat-capsizes-off-libya-iom-says</link><description>At least 42 migrants are missing and presumed dead after a rubber boat capsized off the coast of Libya, the International Organization for Migration said on Wednesday.
Libyan authorities rescued seven survivors who had drifted at sea for six days after the vessel, carrying 49 people, sank near the</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 10:54:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Missing’ Bangladesh Bank official Naim Rahman found in Madaripur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/missing-bangladesh-bank-official-naim-rahman-found-in-madaripur</link><description>Bangladesh Bank Deputy Director Naim Rahman, who had been missing for two days, was rescued by police in Madaripur on Tuesday night (November 11).
Bangladesh Bank authorities confirmed today that he is currently safe.
Colleagues at the central bank extended their gratitude for the recovery of Nai</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 11:24:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Metro rail accident: Probe body seeks more time to complete investigation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/metro-rail-accident-probe-body-seeks-more-time-to-complete-investigation</link><description>The probe committee formed to investigate the metro rail accident in which a pedestrian was killed after a bearing pad fell from a pier of the elevated structure has sought more time to complete the investigation from multiple aspects. 
Informing this, Managing Director of Dhaka Mass Transit</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 11:39:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BB extends Tk 250b pre-financing scheme for CMSME sector</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bb-extends-tk-250b-pre-financing-scheme-for-cmsme-sector</link><description>Bangladesh Bank (BB) has extended the tenure of the Tk 250 billion (Tk 25,000 crore) pre-financing scheme designated for the Cottage, Micro, Small, and Medium Enterprises (CMSME) sector.
The central bank issued a circular on Wednesday announcing that the scheme, which originally had a three-year t</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 11:54:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Police vehicle fire in Ramna due to mechanical fault: DMP</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/police-vehicle-fire-in-ramna-due-to-mechanical-fault-dmp</link><description>A police single-cabin pickup caught fire in front of Ramna Police Station near Kakrail intersection on Wednesday due to a mechanical malfunction, according to Dhaka Metropolitan Police (DMP).
The vehicle broke down earlier in the day, and a mechanic was called to repair it. Despite several attempt</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 12:09:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh Election: Electoral dialogue with political parties to begin Thursday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-election-electoral-dialogue-with-political-parties-to-begin-thursday</link><description>The Election Commission is set to start its much-talked-about dialogue with political parties on Thursday morning, starting with discussions with six registered parties ahead of the 13th parliamentary election likely to be held in early February 2026.
The Commission has invited 12 registered polit</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 12:24:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>30pc of youths undecided about vote choice in upcoming national election: Survey</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/30pc-of-youths-undecided-about-vote-choice-in-upcoming-national-election-survey</link><description>Around 30 per cent of youths are undecided about who they will vote for in the upcoming 13th national election, while 20 per cent said they would cast their votes for the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP), a survey has revealed.
According to the survey, nearly 17 per cent of young people said the</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 12:39:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mostafa Quamrus Sobhan elected chairman of Rupali Insurance Company</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/mostafa-quamrus-sobhan-elected-chairman-of-rupali-insurance-company</link><description>Mostafa Quamrus Sobhan has been elected Chairman of Rupali Insurance Company Limited for the second consecutive term at its 217th Board Meeting at Rupali Bima Bhaban.
Sobhan is the only son of former BGMEA President Mostafa Golam Quddus, founder of Rupali Insurance Co. Ltd., Sonali Life Insurance</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 12:54:33 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>