<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 16:38:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Bangladesh Bank requires adequate operational, administrative independence: Finance adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/bangladesh-bank-requires-adequate-operational-administrative-independence-finance-adviser</link><description>Finance Adviser Dr Salehuddin Ahmed has said Bangladesh Bank requires adequate operational and administrative independence to perform its duties effectively.
The adviser also pointed out that such autonomy must be balanced with accountability within the sovereign framework of the state.
He came u</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 14:38:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>2 candidates hid British citizenship in affidavits: TIB</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/2-candidates-hid-british-citizenship-in-affidavits-tib</link><description>Transparency International Bangladesh (TIB) has said at least two candidates contesting the 13th parliamentary election concealed their dual citizenship in their submitted affidavits.
Both the candidates are British citizens but their affidavits made no mention of this, said Dr. Iftekharuzzaman, e</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 14:53:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Central bank adopts direct action strategy to expedite reforms: Governor</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/central-bank-adopts-direct-action-strategy-to-expedite-reforms-governor</link><description>Bangladesh Bank (BB) Governor Dr Ahsan H Mansur has said the central bank has adopted a direct action strategy by forming three specific task forces instead of a banking commission so that the country can expedite financial sector reforms.
Describing the financial sector reforms through the bankin</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 15:08:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh approves Japan trade deal for 7,379 products</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-approves-japan-trade-deal-for-7379-products</link><description>The Council of Advisers on Thursday approved a proposal to sign the Economic Partnership Agreement (EPA) with Japan, which will help Bangladesh enjoy immediate duty-free access to the Japanese market for 7,379 products.
In return, Japan will receive immediate duty-free access to 1,039 products fro</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 14:08:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nahid slates Tarique, ‘Slum dwellers want safety, not flats’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ncp-chief-nahid-criticises-bnps-family-card-promise-urges-voters-to-prioritise-justice</link><description>National Citizen Party (NCP) Convenor Nahid Islam has criticised BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman’s promise of family cards for urban poor, arguing that slum residents seek safety and dignity, not flats.
Speaking at a Jamaat-e-Islami election rally in Mirpur-10 on Thursday, Nahid said it is possi</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 14:23:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Saraswati Puja to be celebrated Friday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/saraswati-puja-to-be-celebrated-friday</link><description>Saraswati Puja, one of the main religious festivals of the Hindu community, will be celebrated in the country on Friday.
As Saraswati is considered as the Goddess of wisdom and knowledge, Hindu devotees, especially students, celebrate the Puja in different educational institutions and temples.
It</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 14:38:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US Army medical commander visits Bangladesh to expand cooperation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/us-army-medical-commander-visits-bangladesh-to-expand-cooperation</link><description>Maj Gen E Darrin Cox, commanding general of the 18th Theater Medical Command under the US Army Pacific, has visited Bangladesh to strengthen medical cooperation with the Bangladesh Army.
The Jan 18–22 visit aimed to strengthen medical partnerships with the Bangladesh Army Medical Forces, US</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 14:53:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No scope for ballot snatching this time: Home adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/no-scope-for-ballot-snatching-this-time-home-adviser</link><description>Home Affairs Adviser Lt Gen (retd) Jahangir Alam Chowdhury on Thursday said that there would be no possibility of ballot snatching at polling centres in the upcoming national election.
“The upcoming national election will be free, fair, impartial, peaceful and festive in Bangladesh’s h</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 15:08:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Reach polling centres before Fajr to safeguard votes: Tarique</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/reach-polling-centres-before-fajr-to-safeguard-votes-tarique</link><description>BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman on Thursday urged his party leaders, activists and voters to go to polling centres before Fajr prayers on the election-day to prevent any vote rigging.
“Many people say voters should stand in line after Fajr prayers on the election-day. I say this time you should</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 15:23:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ADP implementation is crucial for accelerating development: Faruk E Azam</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/adp-implementation-is-crucial-for-accelerating-development-faruk-e-azam</link><description>Adviser for the Ministry of Disaster Management and Relief Faruk E Azam, on Thursday said implementation of the Annual Development Programme (ADP) is one of the main tools for ensuring smooth in the country. 
“Delivery of expected public services and development benefits depends on its</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 15:38:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BGB deployed in Mirpur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/border-guards-deployed-in-mirpur-on-first-day-of-election-campaign</link><description>The Border Guard Bangladesh (BGB) has been deployed in Mirpur on the first day of the election campaign.
The BGB said in a message that the move aims to preserve law and order ahead of the parliamentary polls.
The BGB personnel have been deployed only in Mirpur.</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 15:53:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BKMEA chief urges for curbing deferred-payment exports</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bkmea-chief-urges-for-curbing-deferred-payment-exports</link><description>BKMEA President Mohammad Hatem has called on policymakers and the central bank to address what he described as worsening bottlenecks in export financing and payment recovery.
Deferred payment structures allow buyers to extract excessive advantages and contribute to large sums of export proceeds re</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 16:08:57 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>