<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 09:25:13 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>BNP, Jamaat block highway over Gazipur-6 seat issue</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-jamaat-block-highway-over-gazipur-6-seat-issue</link><description>Supporters of BNP and others on Wednesday morning blocked the busy Dhaka-Mymensingh highway for around one and a half hours in the Tongi College Gate area, demanding restoration of the Gazipur-6 parliamentary seat.
Hundreds of vehicles remained stuck on both sides of the busy route, causing suffer</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 05:51:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NBR orders transfer of ex-MPs' 31 duty-free cars for govt use</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nbr-orders-transfer-of-ex-mps-31-duty-free-cars-for-govt-use</link><description>The National Board of Revenue (NBR) has issued a special order for the transfer of 31 luxury cars for official use, as those were previously imported under duty-free privileges by members of the now-dissolved 12th National Parliament.
The vehicles will be handed over to the Directorate of Governme</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 06:06:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Swedish envoy in Dhaka on four-day rights mission</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/swedish-envoy-in-dhaka-on-four-day-rights-mission</link><description>Sweden’s Ambassador for Human Rights, Democracy and Rule of Law, Irina Schoulgin-Nyoni, is now on a four-day visit to Bangladesh, focusing on key human rights.
issues, including the rights and empowerment of women and girls, freedom of expression and media freedom, and the role of civil soci</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 06:21:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Police hunt for ‘Awami League activists’ in Dhaka hotels, arrest 44</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/police-hunt-for-awami-league-activists-in-dhaka-hotels-arrest-44</link><description>Police have beefed up security in Dhaka ahead of the banned Awami League’s announced programme on November 13. Law enforcers have conducted overnight raids in different hotels and shared accommodations as Awami League leaders and activists head to the capital for the protest.
On Tuesday, the</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 06:36:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EU delegation chief Miller meets BNP’s Fakhrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/eu-delegation-chief-miller-meets-bnps-fakhrul</link><description>Michael Miller, ambassador and head of the European Union Delegation to Bangladesh, held a courtesy meeting with BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir on Wednesday.
The meeting was held at the BNP chairperson’s office in Dhaka’s Gulshan at 11:00 am today, reports bdnews24.c</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 06:51:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Grameen Bank branch set on fire in Brahmanbaria</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/grameen-bank-branch-set-on-fire-in-brahmanbaria</link><description>Unidentified miscreants set fire to a Grameen Bank branch in Vijaynagar upazila of Brahmanbaria on Wednesday.
The incident occurred around 2:00 am at the bank’s Chandura branch in the upazila.
Bank Manager Md Kalim Uddin said the attackers poured petrol inside the office before setting it o</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 07:06:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Police vehicle burns in Dhaka’s Ramna, microbus catches fire in Uttara</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/police-vehicle-burns-in-dhakas-ramna-microbus-catches-fire-in-uttara</link><description>A police pickup van has caught on fire in front of the Ramna Police Station in Dhaka’s Kakrail while a fire was sparked on a microbus in the capital’s Uttara.
Both incidents occurred due to mechanical problems, according to the police and the Fire Service. No one was hurt in either inc</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 07:21:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jet Crash: Two more Milestone students return home after 114 days</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jet-crash-two-more-milestone-students-return-home-after-114-days</link><description>Two more students of Milestone School and College have returned home after 114 days of treatment for burn injuries sustained in the tragic Air Force plane crash in Uttara of Dhaka.
The returnees are Saiba Jahan Saima, 10, and Saira Jahan, 10, students of class IV, UNB reports.
On Wednesday mornin</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 07:25:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bus set ablaze in Kishoreganj</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bus-set-ablaze-in-kishoreganj</link><description>Unidentified miscreants set fire to a parked bus of Tisha Paribahan at Bajitpur Bus Stand in Kishoreganj district early Wednesday.
The incident occurred around 1:00 am at the bus stand on the Bajitpur-Dhaka highway, confirmed Bajitpur Upazila Nirbahi Officer Shahidul Islam Sohan.
He said the atta</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 07:40:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Petrol bombs thrown at Mohammadpur Preparatory School overnight</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/petrol-bombs-thrown-at-mohammadpur-preparatory-school-overnight</link><description>Assailants have reportedly conducted a petrol bomb attack on Preparatory School and College located on Iqbal Road in Dhaka’s Mohammadpur.
The incident occurred on Tuesday night, three days after an explosive device went off near the entrance of St Joseph School, not far from the institution,</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 07:55:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>469 killed in 469 road accidents in October</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/469-killed-in-469-road-accidents-in-october</link><description>A total of 469 people were killed and 1280 others injured in October in 469 road accidents, according to a BJKS (Bangladesh Jatri Kalyan Samiti) press release on Wednesday.
Meanwhile, 52 accidents on the railways resulted in 47 deaths and 30 injuries. Besides, 12 people died and 1 went missing in</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 08:10:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Chhatra League’ locks five buildings at DU</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/chhatra-league-locks-five-buildings-at-du</link><description>The banned organisation Bangladesh Chhatra League, the student wing of the Awami League, has allegedly locked five buildings at Dhaka University overnight as the party’s “lockdown” programme looms.
The gates to the Faculty of Fine Arts, Institute of Nutrition and Food Sciences, C</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 08:25:47 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>