<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 06:34:54 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>How earthquakes made people rethink living in high-rises</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/how-earthquakes-made-people-rethink-living-in-high-rises</link><description>"I live on the tenth floor at Wari with my two elderly parents and my wife. When the building started shaking, I felt helpless. I kept thinking that if something happened to them, I wouldn't even know how to get them down the stairs in time. Since that day, the thought of shifting keeps coming back</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 03:22:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The artistry of Nat’l Botanical Garden</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/the-artistry-of-natl-botanical-garden</link><description>You may be familiar with Mirpur's National Botanical Garden. But do you know why it's so well-liked? With about 56,000 species, a dedicated study herbarium, a variety of leisure amenities including lakes and cactus houses, and a sizable nursery, it is an extensive plant conservation centre. It prov</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 03:37:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Court orders arrest of bosses of Nestlé Bangladesh, MGI, over ‘substandard KitKat, sugar’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/court-orders-arrest-of-bosses-of-nestle-bangladesh-mgi-over-substandard-kitkat-sugar</link><description>A Dhaka court handling food fraud cases has issued arrest warrants against three individuals for producing, importing and marketing substandard food products.
Special Metropolitan Magistrate Nusrat Sahara Bithi issued the arrest warrants on Monday after two separate cases were filed against the th</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 03:52:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Complex licencing, reliance on imported devices, higher tariffs key challenges</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/complex-licencing-reliance-on-imported-devices-higher-tariffs-key-challenges</link><description>Bangladesh's health sector is grappling with multiple challenges, including complex licensing procedures, heavy reliance on imported medical devices, and slow progress in manufacturing API (Active Pharmaceutical Ingredient).
And addressing such issues has become crucial as the country approaches i</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 04:07:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New rules formulated to control noise pollution</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/new-rules-formulated-to-control-noise-pollution</link><description>The government has formulated the Noise Pollution (Control) Rules 2025, removing limitations of the previous rules, bringing clarity to some key regulatory issues, and expanding enforcement authority.
Previously, only magistrates were empowered to take actions against noise pollution, making it di</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 04:22:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Korail Slum fire doused nearly 16 hours of efforts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/korail-slum-fire-doused-nearly-16-hours-of-efforts</link><description>Firefighters finally extinguished the devastating fire that broke out at Karail Slum in the Tejgaon area of Dhaka after nearly 16 hours of efforts on Wednesday morning.
Shahjahan Sikder, duty assistant director (media cell) at the Fire Service and Civil Defence (FSCD) headquarters, said they were</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 04:37:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cuba accuses US of seeking violent overthrow of Venezuelan government</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/cuba-accuses-us-of-seeking-violent-overthrow-of-venezuelan-government</link><description>Cuba on Tuesday accused the US of seeking a violent overthrow of the Venezuelan government, calling the increased presence of US military forces in the region an "exaggerated and aggressive" threat.
The US overthrowing Venezuelan President Nicolas Maduro's government would be extremely dangerous a</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 04:52:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bolsonaro starts serving 27-year sentence for Brazil coup plot</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/brazils-former-president-bolsonaro-starts-serving-27-year-sentence-for-coup-plot</link><description>Brazil's Supreme Court on Tuesday ordered former far-right President Jair Bolsonaro to begin a 27-year prison sentence for a coup plot against his successor, a climax to years of political turmoil and legal battles over his contentious legacy in Brazilian democracy.
The top court formally conclude</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 05:07:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Alphabet races toward $4 trillion valuation as AI-fuelled gains accelerate</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/alphabet-races-toward-4-trillion-valuation-as-ai-fuelled-gains-accelerate</link><description>Alphabet closed in on a $4 trillion valuation on Monday, set to become only the fourth company to enter the exclusive club, as the Google parent rides an artificial intelligence-driven rally.
Shares of the company rose more than 5% to hit a record high of $315.9, giving it a market capitalisation</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 05:22:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Taiwan plans extra $40 billion in defence spending to counter China</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/taiwan-plans-extra-40-billion-in-defence-spending-to-counter-china</link><description>Taiwan will introduce a $40-billion supplementary defence budget to underscore its determination to defend itself in the face of a rising threat from China, President Lai Ching-te said on Wednesday.
China, which views democratically-governed Taiwan as its own territory, has ramped up military and</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 05:37:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US budget deficit hits $284b in October</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/us-budget-deficit-hits-284b-in-october</link><description>The US government posted a higher $284 billion deficit for October in a report delayed and impacted by the recent federal government shutdown and reflecting record tariff revenues offset by a shift of some November benefit payments into last month's data, the Treasury Department said on Tuesday.
T</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 05:52:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>One spouse is enough, Vatican tells world's Catholics</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/others/one-spouse-is-enough-vatican-tells-worlds-catholics</link><description>Happily ever after doesn't require any complicated maths, the Vatican said on Tuesday -- for Catholics, one spouse is enough.
In a new decree approved by Pope Leo, the Vatican's top doctrinal office told the world's 1.4 billion Catholics they should seek to marry one spouse for life and should not</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 06:07:18 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>