<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 10:22:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Osman Hadi’s Jhalakathi home 'burgled'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/osman-hadis-jhalakathi-home-burgled</link><description>A burglary has been reported at the village home of Osman Hadi, an election hopeful and convener of Inquilab Mancha, who was shot in Dhaka.
The incident took place late on Friday night at Hadi’s house in the Khasmahal area of Jhalakathi's Nalchhiti, according to his cousin Sirajul Islam, rep</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 07:37:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gun Attack on Hadi: DMP releases suspect’s photo, seeks public help</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/gun-attack-on-hadi-dmp-releases-suspects-photo-seeks-public-help</link><description>The Dhaka Metropolitan Police (DMP) on Saturday released a photograph of a suspect involved in the gun attack on Inquilab Moncho spokesperson Sharif Osman Hadi and urged people to share any information about the suspect.
A suspect has been identified preliminarily through analysis of CCTV footage</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 07:52:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Yunus meets BNP, Jamaat and NCP leaders after attack on Hadi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/yunus-meets-bnp-jamaat-and-ncp-leaders-after-attack-on-hadi</link><description>Chief Advisor Muhammad Yunus is holding talks with representatives of the BNP, Jamaat-e-Islami and National Citizen Party (NCP) in the wake of the shooting attack on Osman Hadi, an election hopeful and convener of Inquilab Mancha.
The meeting began around 11:15am on Saturday at the State Guest Hou</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 08:07:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gun attack on Hadi: BNP seeks CA’s action on violence</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/gun-attack-on-hadi-bnp-seeks-cas-action-on-violence</link><description>BNP on Saturday called on Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus to take immediate and effective steps to prevent a recurrence of violence and ensure quick justice following the gun attack on Dhaka-8 independent candidate Sharif Osman Hadi.
"We have urged the Ministry of Home Affairs to be more ac</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 08:22:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DMP chief hopeful of arresting key suspect in Hadi shooting 'soon'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dmp-chief-hopeful-of-arresting-key-suspect-in-hadi-shooting-soon</link><description>Dhaka Metropolitan Police Commissioner Sazzat Ali has expressed hope that the prime suspect in the attempted killing of Sharif Osman Hadi, convener of the Inquilab Mancha platform, will be brought to justice "soon".
Speaking to reporters after attending the annual general meeting of the Banglade</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 08:37:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt offers Tk 5m reward for information leading to arrest of Hadi shooting suspect</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-offers-tk-5m-reward-for-information-leading-to-arrest-of-hadi-shooting-suspect</link><description>Home Affairs Advisor Jahangir Alam Chowdhury has announced a reward of Tk 5.0 million for information leading to the arrest of the gunman who shot Inquilab Mancha Convener Sharif Osman Bin Hadi.
Jahangir announced on Saturday after an emergency law and order meeting at the Secretariat as police co</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 08:52:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC issues circular on JS polls nomination process</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-issues-circular-on-js-polls-nomination-process</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) today (Saturday) issued a circular outlining procedures related to the upcoming 13th Jatiya Sangsad (JS) elections. 
The directive covers collection and submission of nomination papers, deposit of security money, eligibility of proposers and seconders, party-nomin</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 09:07:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>$211.7m green project: IFAD approves $51.4m co-financing</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/2117m-green-project-ifad-approves-514m-co-financing</link><description>The Executive Board of the International Fund for Agricultural Development (IFAD), at its 146th session held on December 9–10, 2025, has approved US$51.4 million in financing for Bangladesh as part of a US$211.7 million development project, a spokesman said on Saturday.
The new investment ai</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 09:22:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Syngenta opens second Farmer School in Rajshahi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/syngenta-opens-second-farmer-school-in-rajshahi</link><description>Syngenta Bangladesh has inaugurated its second Farmer School at Nimpara Union, Charghat, Rajshahi on December 11, 2025, in collaboration with local government to help marginal farmers learn better farming methods and promote sustainable farming.
The inauguration ceremony was graced by Md. Rahatul</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 09:37:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Former BNP lawmaker Akhtaruzzaman joins Jamaat-e-Islami</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/former-bnp-lawmaker-akhtaruzzaman-joins-jamaat-e-islami</link><description>Freedom fighter and former BNP lawmaker Akhtaruzzaman has joined the Islamist party Jamaat-e-Islami.
The retired Army major completed the party’s associate membership process after meeting Jamaat chief Shafiqur Rahman at its office in the capital’s Moghbazar, reports bdnews24.com.
In</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 09:52:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladeshis among 18 crew members detained by Iran from foreign tanker seized in Gulf of Oman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladeshis-among-18-crew-members-detained-by-iran-from-foreign-tanker-seized-in-gulf-of-oman</link><description>Iranian authorities detained 18 crew members, including Bangladeshis, after seizing a foreign tanker in the Gulf of Oman on Friday that they said was carrying 6 million litres of smuggled fuel, Iranian media reported on Saturday, citing the Hormozgan province judiciary.
It said those detained unde</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 10:07:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt assures full security for Tarique Rahman ahead of homecoming</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-assures-full-security-for-tarique-rahman-ahead-of-homecoming</link><description>Home Adviser Lieutenant General (Retd) Md Jahangir Alam Chowdhury today (Saturday) assured that the government will take all necessary measures to ensure the security of Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman upon his return to the country.
"There is no apprehension rega</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 10:22:09 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>