<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 07:16:37 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Prof Yunus leaves for Rome to attend WFF</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/prof-yunus-leaves-for-rome-to-attend-wff</link><description>Chief Adviser Prof Muhammad Yunus left Dhaka for Rome, the capital city of Italy, on Sunday morning to join the 2025 World Food Forum (WFF) that began on October 10 and runs through October 17, hosted by the Food and Agriculture Organization at its headquarters.
A commercial flight of Biman Bangla</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 04:31:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Earthquake strikes Philippines again</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/earthquake-strikes-philippines-again</link><description>An earthquake with a magnitude of 6.0 jolted 10 km ENE of Aras-asan, Philippines at 14:32:58 GMT on Saturday, the US Geological Survey said.
The epicentre, with a depth of 59.3 km, was initially determined to be at 8.92 degrees north latitude and 126.40 degrees east longitude, reports Xinhua.
&amp;nb</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 04:46:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bus strike enters day two in Mymensingh division</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bus-strike-enters-day-two-in-mymensingh-division</link><description>Bus services between Mymensingh division and the rest of the country remained suspended for the second consecutive day on Sunday due to a bus workers’ strike in protest against the arrest of a transport worker, leaving passengers in trouble.
Commuters who had purchased tickets in advance wer</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 05:16:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>9,500 people still missing in Gaza: Civil Defense</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/9500-people-still-missing-in-gaza-civil-defense</link><description>The Gaza-based Civil Defense said Saturday that it has received reports of 9,500 missing persons since the outbreak of the Israel-Hamas conflict on Oct. 7, 2023.
In a statement, Mahmoud Basal, spokesperson for the Civil Defense, urged the International Committee of the Red Cross to coordinate with</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 05:31:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt plans rail link for all economic zones</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-plans-rail-link-for-all-economic-zones</link><description>The government has undertaken a major initiative to establish railway connectivity with all economic zones (EZs) across the country to make goods transportation faster, cheaper and more efficient.
“We are preparing an integrated plan for all economic zones in the country with focus on Mirsar</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 06:01:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Crimes against humanity’: Jamaat chief Shafiqur applauds initiative to bring army officers to justice</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/crimes-against-humanity-jamaat-chief-shafiqur-applauds-initiative-to-bring-army-officers-to-justice</link><description>Jamaat-e-Islami chief Shafiqur Rahman has welcomed the initiative to bring several Bangladesh Army officers accused of involvement in enforced disappearances and murders to justice.
In a Facebook post published at 7am on Sunday, Shafiqur said the army had “already made a clear announcement t</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 06:31:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dense fog disrupted ferry movement for three hours</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dense-fog-disrupted-ferry-movement-for-three-hours</link><description>The Ferry movement on the Paturia-Daulatdia river route on the Padma resumed from 7:20 am today (Sunday) after a 3.20-hour suspension for dense fog disruption, Bangladesh Inland Water Transport Corporation (BIWTC) Paturia Ghat sources said.
BIWTC Paturia Ghat Assistant General Manager (AGM) Abdus</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 06:46:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>MPO-listed teachers hold demonstration, call work stoppage from Tuesday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/mpo-listed-teachers-hold-demonstration-call-work-stoppage-from-tuesday</link><description>Teachers and employees of Monthly Pay Order (MPO) listed institutions are conducting a demonstration in front of the Jatiya Press Club in Dhaka, demanding their housing allowance be raised to 20 percent of their basic salary.
Several thousand teachers and employees attended the programme from 9am</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 07:16:37 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>