<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 17:19:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>PS Masud returns to promote river-based tourism: Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ps-masud-returns-to-promote-river-based-tourism-adviser</link><description>Shipping and Labour and Employment Adviser Brigadier General (Retd) Dr. M. Sakhawat Hussain on Friday said the historic paddle steamer PS Masud is set to become a unique blend of heritage and river-centric tourism in the country.
“This 100-year-old steamer of the Bangladesh Inland Water Tran</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 14:32:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UN must continue to evolve to fulfill collective aspiration for peace, multilateralism: CA</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/un-must-continue-to-evolve-to-fulfill-collective-aspiration-for-peace-multilateralism-ca</link><description>Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus has said the United Nations (UN) must continue to evolve and adapt to fulfill collective aspiration for peace and multilateralism.
"The United Nations must continue to evolve and adapt if it is to fulfill our collective aspiration for peace and multilateralis</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 14:47:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>22 Ctg garment factories shut in a year</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/rmg-sector-in-chattogram-hit-hard-as-22-factories-close-since-last-year</link><description>Chattogram has seen nearly 22 garment factories shut down over the past year following the shift in Bangladesh’s political landscape, leaving thousands of workers without jobs.
Factory owners say the sector is going through one of its toughest periods yet, and they see little sign of recover</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 15:02:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Three children drown in Kishoreganj</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/three-children-drown-in-kishoreganj</link><description>Three children drowned while playing near a beel (wetland) in Austagram upazila of Kishoreganj on Friday evening, casting a pall of grief over the area.
The incident occurred at Paschim Alinagar village under Deoghar Union.
The deceased were identified as Mishkat (5), son of Abul Kalam; Mahin (6)</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 15:17:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Putin envoy Kirill Dmitriev says he is in the US for a long-planned meeting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/putin-envoy-kirill-dmitriev-says-he-is-in-the-us-for-a-long-planned-meeting</link><description>Kirill Dmitriev, Russian President Vladimir Putin's special envoy for investment and economic cooperation, said on Friday he was in the United States for a long-planned meeting and that U.S.-Russia dialogue continued.
In a phone call with Reuters, Dmitriev declined to say who he was meeting.
"Thi</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 15:47:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Couple arrested allegedly with 22,000 Yaba pills on bus in Jamalpur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/couple-arrested-allegedly-with-22000-yaba-pills-on-bus-in-jamalpur</link><description>A couple allegedly carrying 22,000 Yaba pills on them have been arrested in Jamalpur Sadar Upazila.
Police made the arrest on Friday morning, said Jamalpur Additional Superintendent (ASP) Sohel Mahmud.
The detainees have been identified as Abdul Matin, 47, and his wife Shahida Begum, 35.
Speakin</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 16:02:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The future of HR in the corporate world</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/the-future-of-hr-in-the-corporate-world</link><description>Technology has brought an unprecedented transformation across every layer of the corporate world. From production systems and marketing to administrative work, automation now touches almost every function. Yet, the most fascinating shift is happening in Human Resource Management. Once regarded as t</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 16:32:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Looking at acts of wrongdoing</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/looking-at-acts-of-wrongdoing</link><description>Engaging in harmful activities, casually or carelessly, is being seen as a normal practice in the country. Over the years, attempting to curb or even minimise such acts has become difficult because a growing number of people do not find anything wrong with their actions that negatively affect other</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 16:47:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How to waste Tk 42.68 billion!</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/how-to-waste-tk-4268-billion</link><description>An old joke tells of an African minister who once visited his Asian friend's huge mansion and asked how he could afford it on a government salary. The Asian smiled and gestured to a half-finished bridge and a new highway outside his window. "10 per cent from each," he said. A year later, the visit</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 17:02:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fire at Mirpur Community Center Building</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fire-at-mirpur-community-center-building</link><description>A fire broke out on the sixth floor of a six-storey building that houses a garment factory at Bibah Bari Community Center on Kalshi Road in Mirpur 12 on Thursday night.
According to the Fire Service and Civil Defence, the fire was reported at 10:12 pm, and the first unit reached the scene at 10:27</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 17:17:24 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>