<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:55:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Advisers approve six ordinances, VAT relief on LP gas</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/advisers-approve-six-ordinances-vat-relief-on-lp-gas</link><description>The Council of Advisers in its meeting on Thursday approved six ordinances and three proposals and reviewed the performance of the interim government since its formation in August 2024.
Chief Adviser Prof Muhammad Yunus chaired the meeting.
Chief Adviser’s Press Secretary Shafiqul Alam brie</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 01:14:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP unveils election manifesto today</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-unveils-election-manifesto-today</link><description>The Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) will announce its election manifesto today (Friday), ahead of the 13th national parliamentary election. Party Chairman Tarique Rahman will formally unveil the manifesto.
BNP media cell member Shairul Kabir Khan confirmed it on Thursday. He said the manifesto</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 01:29:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Smart electricity meters lie idle</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/smart-electricity-meters-lie-idle</link><description>Around 0.4 million smart pre-payment meters imported under Dhaka Power Distribution Company's (DPDC) long-delayed smart-metering project are lying idle in warehouses, raising concerns about possible technical deterioration and inefficient use of public funds.
Nearly eight years after the project w</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 01:44:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Interim govt pushes thru 116 ordinances, 14 foreign deals</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/interim-govt-pushes-thru-116-ordinances-14-foreign-deals</link><description>The interim government has pushed through 116 ordinances and 14 bilateral agreements in its bid for stabilising governance and executing systemic reforms.
The figures were presented Thursday at a meeting of the council of advisers, according to the chief adviser's press secretary, Shafiqul Alam, n</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 01:59:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BB mops up dollars as remittances rise</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bb-mops-up-dollars-as-remittances-rise</link><description>The central bank purchased a further US$196.50 million through auction from 16 banks on the interbank spot market on Thursday, aiming to keep the exchange rate of the US dollar against the local currency stable.
The amount was bought under the Multiple Price Auction method, with the cut-off rate s</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 02:14:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh-US trade deal now on Feb 09</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladesh-us-trade-deal-now-on-feb-09</link><description>Bangladesh and the United States are poised to open a new chapter in bilateral trade relations as they are set to sign an agreement to this effect on February 09, officials said.
When the deal is penned, it will mark the culmination of months of negotiations aimed at easing Washington's reciprocal</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:05:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt to propose UN-led investigation into Hadi’s killing</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-to-propose-un-led-investigation-into-hadis-killing</link><description>The interim government is going to propose the Office of the United Nations High Commissioner for Human Rights (OHCHR) take charge of the inquiry into the killing of Sharif Osman bin Hadi, slain convenor of Inqilab Moncho.
The announcement comes amid ongoing demonstrations by the Inquilab Moncho a</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 02:44:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Editors' Council urges protection of journalists covering election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/editors-council-urges-protection-of-journalists-covering-election</link><description>The Editors' Council has urged the authorities and political parties to ensure the safety of journalists covering the upcoming elections.
In a statement issued on Thursday, the council said journalists face a range of risks while gathering and disseminating news during election periods, and that e</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 03:31:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>'New govt should prioritise primary healthcare, UHC'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/new-govt-should-prioritise-primary-healthcare-uhc</link><description>Public health experts have suggested the upcoming elected government prioritise primary healthcare services and universal health coverage (UHC) as the health-sector reform commission formed by the interim government dissatisfied them.
They made the suggestion at a policy dialogue titled "Priority</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 03:46:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Asiatic Labs' half-year profit surpasses FY25 earnings</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/asiatic-labs-half-year-profit-surpasses-fy25-earnings</link><description>Asiatic Laboratories has posted an impressive 86 per cent year-on-year growth in profit to Tk 164 million in the second quarter of FY26, driven by higher sales amid a stable forex market.
With the latest quarterly earnings, its half-yearly profit-Tk 316 million-in July-December last year surpassed</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:20:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Starlink deal opens new revenue stream for Kay &amp; Que</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/starlink-deal-opens-new-revenue-stream-for-kay-que</link><description>Kay &amp; Que (Bangladesh) has become the sales agent for Starlink Satellite Internet Service in Bangladesh, a move expected to increase the company's revenue and income in the coming quarters.
The listed IT venture, belonging to the conglomerate Multimode Group owned by BNP Vice Chairman Abdul Awal M</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:35:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Explosion at illegal coal mine kills at least 18 in India’s Meghalaya</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/explosion-at-illegal-coal-mine-kills-at-least-18-workers-in-indias-meghalaya</link><description>An explosion ripped through an illegal coal mine in India’s northeastern state of Meghalaya on Thursday, killing at least 18 workers and injuring another, authorities said.
Police officer Vikash Kumar said rescue teams recovered 18 bodies from the site of the explosion in a remote area of th</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:50:03 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>