<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 08:31:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>World's richest nations are pulling back from global development efforts: Study</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/worlds-richest-nations-are-pulling-back-from-global-development-efforts-study-shows</link><description>Two dozen of the world's richest nations, including the United States and Japan, are pulling back from their global development push, a study published on Thursday, opens new tab shows, with many slashing aid budgets and cash funnelled through multilateral lenders.
The Commitment to Development In</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 06:15:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bomb explodes outside ex-home minister’s Dhanmondi residence</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bomb-explodes-outside-ex-home-ministers-dhanmondi-residence</link><description>A crude bomb has exploded in front of former home minister Asaduzzaman Khan Kamal’s residence on Dhanmondi Road No. 5 in Dhaka.
Police confirmed the incident occurred shortly after 12:30 am on Thursday at the main gate of the house.
Sub-Inspector Md Shahjalal of Dhanmondi Police Station tol</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 06:30:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Indonesia evacuates stranded climbers after Semeru volcano erupts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/indonesia-evacuates-stranded-climbers-after-semeru-volcano-erupts</link><description>Indonesian authorities evacuated more than 900 people and were facilitating the safe return on Thursday of 170 climbers stranded after the eruption of its Semeru volcano, one of the country's tallest mountains.
The alert level was maintained at its highest after Semeru on Java island erupted 10 ti</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 06:45:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Youth ‘commits suicide’ in Dhaka’s Hazaribagh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/youth-commits-suicide-in-dhakas-hazaribagh</link><description>A 25-year-old youth was found dead after allegedly hanging himself from a ceiling fan at his residence in Hazaribagh of Dhaka on Thursday.
The deceased was identified as Md Nazmul, son of Abul Bashar of Barguna Sadar upazila. He had been living with his family at a rented house in the Vaucher area</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 07:00:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump to meet NYC mayor-elect Mamdani</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-to-meet-nyc-mayor-elect-mamdani</link><description>US President Donald Trump said he will meet New York City Mayor-elect Zohran Mamdani at the White House on Friday in what would be the first meeting of the Republican leader with the democratic socialist who won this month's mayoral election.
Mamdani and Trump have been critical of each other, wit</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 06:15:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh seeks urgent international actions for Rohingya repatriation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-seeks-urgent-international-actions-for-rohingya-repatriation</link><description>Bangladesh has called for urgent international action for the return of the Rohingyas, as it was no longer possible for Bangladesh to bear the burden of hosting 1.3 million Rohingyas.The UN General Assembly’s third committee has adopted by consensus the resolution on Rohingya Muslims calling</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 06:30:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP to ensure all future investments follow economic benchmarks, says Khosru</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bnp-to-ensure-all-future-investments-follow-economic-benchmarks-says-khosru</link><description>Every future investment will be made in strict adherence to economic standards to ensure that taxpayers’ money is used for public welfare, BNP Standing Committee Member Amir Khasru Mahmud Chowdhury said on Thursday.
Khosru said that investments must be carefully evaluated, speaking at an eve</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 06:45:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump approves 28-point plan for Russia-Ukraine peace</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-approves-28-point-plan-for-russia-ukraine-peace</link><description>US President Donald Trump has approved a 28-point plan for peace between Russia and Ukraine that US officials developed in consultation with Russian and Ukrainian officials, NBC News reported on Wednesday.
Trump's special envoy, Steve Witkoff, Vice President JD Vance, Secretary of State Marco Rubi</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 07:00:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Police recover a student's dead body in Gaibandha</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/police-recover-a-students-dead-body-in-gaibandha</link><description>Fulchhari Thana police recovered the hanging body of a college student from the family toilet at Kanchipara village of Kanchipara union in Fulchhari upazila of Gaibandha district on Wednesday.
The victim has been identified as Riyad Miah, 23, son of Rahmat Ali, of the village. He is also an interm</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 07:15:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Iran denies starting nuclear talks with US</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/iran-denies-starting-nuclear-talks-with-us</link><description>Iran's Foreign Ministry spokesman Esmaeil Baghaei on Wednesday rejected a recent claim by the US president that Tehran and Washington were holding nuclear talks.
He made the remarks in an address to reporters in Tehran, one day after US President Donald Trump said the United States was talking to</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 07:30:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Three executive magistrates dismissed during training</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/three-executive-magistrates-dismissed-during-training</link><description>The government has dismissed three assistant commissioners (executive magistrates) while they were undergoing foundation training.
A notification, signed by Ehsanul Haque, Senior Secretary to the Ministry of Public Administration, was issued in this regard on Wednesday, reports UNB.
Those dismiss</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 07:45:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Joy confident India will reject Bangladesh’s request to extradite Hasina</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/joy-confident-india-will-reject-bangladeshs-request-to-extradite-hasina</link><description>Sajeeb Wazed Joy, the son and former ICT advisor to ousted prime minister Sheikh Hasina, says India is not likely to accept the Bangladesh government’s request to extradite her to face a death sentence over crimes against humanity.
"India has always been a good friend, and in the crisis, Ind</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 08:00:42 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>