<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 15:21:04 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>China blames US for global panic over rare earths controls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/china-blames-us-for-global-panic-over-rare-earths-controls</link><description>China on Thursday accused the US of stoking panic over its rare earth controls and said Treasury Secretary Scott Bessent had made "grossly distorted" remarks about a top Chinese trade negotiator, rejecting a White House call to roll back the curbs.
The official newspaper of the governing Communist</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 13:32:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chinese company signs agreement to invest in BEPZA Economic Zone</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/chinese-company-signs-agreement-to-invest-in-bepza-economic-zone</link><description>October4128 (BD) Ltd., a Chinese-owned company, signed an agreement on Thursday with the Bangladesh Export Processing Zones Authority (BEPZA) to invest US$ 19.72 million in establishing a high-end garments manufacturing facility at the BEPZA Economic Zone (BEPZA EZ) in Mirsharai, Chattogram.
Membe</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 13:47:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>48 officials appointed to Islami Bank under Hasina's direct order</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/48-officials-appointed-to-islami-bank-under-hasinas-direct-order</link><description>Recruitments at Islami Bank Bangladesh PLC occurred under the direct order of former prime minister Sheikh Hasina, with 48 officials appointed through such directives, according to sources within the bank.
Once regarded as one of the strongest private banks in Bangladesh, Islami Bank has slipped i</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 14:17:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Number of Rohingyas leaving by boats tripled in first half of 2025: UNHCR</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/number-of-rohingyas-leaving-by-boats-tripled-in-first-half-of-2025-unhcr</link><description>The number of Rohingya refugees who left Bangladesh by boats in the first six months of the year tripled compared to last year, as conditions for children in Bangladesh’s Cox’s Bazar camps continue to deteriorate and funding cuts reduce essential services, said Save the Children.
About</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 13:33:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gaza ceasefire must be maintained, peace would benefit region: IMF’s Georgieva</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/imfs-georgieva-says-gaza-ceasefire-must-be-maintained-peace-would-benefit-region</link><description>International Monetary Fund Managing Director Kristalina Georgieva on Thursday urged all parties to continue moving in the direction of a sustained lasting peace following a ceasefire in Gaza, saying it would benefit the entire region.
Georgieva, speaking during the annual meetings of the IMF and</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 13:48:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IPDC hosts interactive Wellness Program to Promote Wellbeing</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ipdc-hosts-interactive-wellness-program-to-promote-wellbeing</link><description>IPDC Finance PLC recently concluded a four-day Wellness Program, held from 13 to 16 October 2025, aimed at reaffirming their commitment to the physical and mental wellbeing of its employees and customers.
The initiative reflected IPDC’s continued dedication to fostering a healthy, supportive</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 14:03:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>9.6pc growth of remittance inflow till Oct 15</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/96pc-growth-of-remittance-inflow-till-oct-15</link><description>Inflow of remittances witnessed a year-on-year growth of 9.6 percent reaching US$1435 million in the first 15 days of October, according to the latest data of Bangladesh Bank (BB) issued.
Last year, during the same period, the country’s remittance inflow was $1310 million.
During the July t</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 14:18:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Recommendations on Charter implementation to be submitted before Oct 31: Ali Riaz</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/recommendations-on-charter-implementation-to-be-submitted-before-oct-31-ali-riaz</link><description>Vice Chair of the National Consensus Commission (NCC) Prof Ali Riaz on Thursday said the Commission will place a clear, specific and comprehensive recommendation before the government for the implementation of the July National Charter 2025 within its extended tenure that ends on October 31 next.</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 14:33:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Premier Bank holds workshop on Integrity &amp; Ethics Practice in Banking</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/premier-bank-holds-workshop-on-integrity-ethics-practice-in-banking</link><description>The Premier Bank PLC organised an insightful workshop on Integrity &amp; Ethics Practice in Banking at its Learning &amp; Talent Development Center (LTDC), Head Office, on Saturday (October 11, 2025).
The program focused on promoting ethical standards, transparency, and good governance across all levels o</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 14:48:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>RUCSU election concludes peacefully; 69.83pc voter turnout recorded</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rucsu-election-concludes-peacefully-6983pc-voter-turnout-recorded</link><description>The long-awaited Rajshahi University Central Students’ Union (RUCSU) election, along with hall and senate representative polls, concluded peacefully on Thursday (October 16) without any report of irregularities or untoward incidents — marking the successful return of campus democracy af</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 15:18:14 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>