<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 14:21:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>No one should touch young voter's rights: Jamaat Ameer</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/no-one-should-touch-young-voters-rights-jamaat-ameer</link><description>Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islam Ameer Dr Shafiqur Rahman today said that the party will always be beside the young voters who participated in the July Mass Uprising with full support.
"No one should touch their votes. If anyone does, fire will burn. That slogan is over. Terrorists used to say, 'I w</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 11:31:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh expresses surprise as Hasina speaks at New Delhi event</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-expresses-surprise-as-hasina-speaks-at-new-delhi-event</link><description>The government and people of Bangladesh have expressed surprise and shock that fugitive Sheikh Hasina, convicted by the International Crimes Tribunal for crimes against humanity, was permitted to make a statement at a public event in New Delhi on January 23, the Ministry of Foreign Affairs said on</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 11:46:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Home ministry denies parole application for Jashore jail prisoner Saddam</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/home-ministry-denies-parole-application-for-jashore-jail-prisoner-saddam</link><description>The Ministry of Home Affairs has clarified that no application was submitted for the parole release of prisoner Jewel Hasan Saddam, who is currently detained in Jashore Central Jail following the death of his wife and child.
In a statement issued on the matter, the Home Ministry said neither Sadda</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 12:01:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pakistan announce T20 World Cup squad amid participation doubts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/cricket/pakistan-announce-t20-world-cup-squad-amid-participation-doubts</link><description>Pakistan on Sunday announced their squad for next month's Twenty20 World Cup, a day after their cricket board chief cast doubt over the team's participation in the global showpiece that begins on February 7.
Pakistan Cricket Board (PCB) Chairman Mohsin Naqvi, also the country's interior minister,</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 12:16:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Yunus hails SAFF women’s futsal triumph</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/yunus-congratulates-bangladesh-for-historic-saff-womens-futsal-triumph</link><description>Chief Advisor Muhammad Yunus has congratulated the Bangladesh women’s team for becoming SAFF Women’s Futsal Champions.
In a message on Sunday, he underscored the achievement as “a matter of pride for the country’s sporting arena”.
In the final of the inaugural SAFF t</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 12:31:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt to accept foreign loans only for critical projects: Planning Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-to-accept-foreign-loans-only-for-critical-projects-planning-adviser</link><description>Planning Adviser Dr Wahiduddin Mahmud on Sunday said the government is moving away from financing large-scale development projects through foreign loans and stressed the need for avoiding a ‘debt trap’.
“We do not want to take loans for big projects unnecessarily. Institutions li</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 12:04:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ECNEC approves 25 projects worth Tk 451.91 billion</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ecnec-approves-25-projects-worth-tk-45191-billion</link><description>The Executive Committee of the National Economic Council (ECNEC) today approved 25 development projects worth Tk 451.91 billion, including a 1,000-bed Bangladesh-China Friendship General Hospital in the northern region.
Of the total project cost, Tk 108.81 billion will come from government funds,</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 12:19:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Abbas vows to rid Dhaka-8 of drugs, extortion, crimes</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/abbas-vows-to-rid-dhaka-8-of-drugs-extortion-crimes</link><description>BNP senior leader and Dhaka-8 constituency candidate Mirza Abbas on Sunday vowed to make his area free from drugs, extortion and crime if elected through the national election billed for February 12.
“For the past 17 years, my area has been destroyed by drugs, terrorism and extortion. I prom</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 12:34:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>451st board meeting of Al-Arafah Islami Bank held</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/451st-board-meeting-of-al-arafah-islami-bank-held</link><description>The 451st Board meeting of Al-Arafah Islami Bank PLC was held on Sunday at the bank’s head office, according to a press release.
Chairman of the Board of Directors Khwaja Shahriar presided over the meeting. The overall business performance of the Bank was reviewed and several policy decision</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 12:49:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DBBL holds Managers’ Conference-2026</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/dbbl-holds-managers-conference-2026</link><description>The Managers’ Conference-2026 of Dutch-Bangla Bank was held on 24 &amp; 25 January 2026 in Dhaka to review the bank’s overall performance for the year 2025 and discuss the business plan and strategy for achieving targets for the year 2026, according to a press release.
The Conference was p</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 13:04:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Racket altering mobile IMEI numbers busted in Dhaka, 1 held</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/racket-altering-mobile-imei-numbers-busted-in-dhaka-1-held</link><description>The Detective Branch (DB) Cyber Division of Dhaka Metropolitan Police (DMP) has busted a major racket involved in illegally altering mobile phone IMEI numbers and arrested a man in this connection.
They also seized software, a laptop and other equipment during the drive, said DMP Deputy Commission</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 13:19:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Muggers loot Tk 24 lakh firing shots, exploding crude bombs in Gazipur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/muggers-loot-tk-24-lakh-firing-shots-exploding-crude-bombs-in-gazipur</link><description>Muggers looted Tk 24 lakh by firing gunshots and exploding crude bombs in Basan area of Gazipur on Sunday afternoon.
Witnesses said Saiful Islam, a staff of Dutch-Bangla Bank agent outlet, owned by Shafiqul Islam, was heading towards Chandona intersection around 4:00pm to deposit money at a bank,</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 13:34:11 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>