<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 16:29:28 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>National Bank launches Remittance Cash Payment Automation system</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/national-bank-launches-remittance-cash-payment-automation-system</link><description>National Bank PLC has inaugurated its revolutionary ‘Remittance Cash Payment Automation’ system, describing it as a bold leap forward in digital transformation, according to a press release.
The launch ceremony took place on November 25, at 4PM at the Bank’s Head Office, where th</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 13:34:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ACC files case against ex-minister Farhad, wife</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/acc-files-case-against-ex-minister-farhad-wife</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) has filed a case against former minister Farhad Hossain and his wife Syeda Monalisa Islam on charges of acquiring assets beyond known sources.
ACC director general Md Akter Hossain said that assistant director Khorshed Alam revealed the inconsistent of wealth t</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 13:49:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>MTB’s prominence in Mastercard Excellence Awards 2025</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/mtbs-prominence-in-mastercard-excellence-awards-2025</link><description>Mutual Trust Bank PLC (MTB) has been remarkably recognized at the Mastercard Excellence Awards 2025, securing four prestigious accolades— the highest number awarded to an individual bank this year, according to a press release.
The award giving ceremony was held on 22 November 2025 at the Ra</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 14:04:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chinese Ambassador sends bouquet to Khaleda, wishes her recovery</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/chinese-ambassador-sends-bouquet-to-khaleda-wishes-her-recovery</link><description>Chinese Ambassador to Bangladesh Yao Wen on Wednesday sent a bouquet and a letter wishing a speedy recovery to BNP Chairperson and former Prime Minister Khaleda Zia.
“The bouquet and message were delivered on Wednesday at around 6:40pm to the BNP Chairperson’s Gulshan office,” sa</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 14:19:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Modhumoti Bank holds 140th meeting of executive committee</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/modhumoti-bank-holds-140th-meeting-of-executive-committee</link><description>The 140th Meeting of the Executive Committee of Modhumoti Bank PLC was held on Wednesday, 26th November 2025 at Bank’s Head Office premises.
The meeting was presided by EC Chairman, Mr. Salahuddin Alamgir. Among others, Mr. Mohammad Ismail Hossain, Mr. Nemai Kumar Saha and Managing Director</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 14:34:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Postal voting sign-up open until Dec 18: EC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-to-keep-postal-voting-registration-open-for-all-bangladeshi-expatriates-until-dec-18</link><description>The Election Commission has decided to lift the regional restrictions and five-day timeframe imposed on postal voting registration, allowing Bangladeshi expatriates to enrol until Dec 18 to vote for the parliamentary elections.
Initially, the EC gave five days to Bangladeshi expatriates to registe</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 14:49:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamuna Bank conducts financial literacy program at Sreemangal school</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/jamuna-bank-conducts-financial-literacy-program-at-sreemangal-school</link><description>Jamuna Bank PLC recently organised a Financial Literacy Program for students at the auditorium of Sreemangal Govt. Girls High School in Moulvibazar, as part of the bank’s ongoing Financial Literacy initiatives, according to a press release.
Mr. Abdus Sobhan, Executive Vice President &amp; Head o</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 15:04:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IFIC Bank appoints Sheikh Akhter Uddin Ahmed as its DMD</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ific-bank-appoints-sheikh-akhter-uddin-ahmed-as-its-dmd</link><description>Mr. Sheikh Akhter Uddin Ahmed joined IFIC Bank PLC as Deputy Managing Director, effective 25 November 2025, according to a press release.
With a distinguished career spanning 27 years across both domestic and international banking, Mr. Ahmed brings a wealth of expertise and proven leadership to th</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 15:19:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ali Riaz doesn’t know woman spreading ‘fabricated allegations’ against him: CA press wing</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ali-riaz-doesnt-know-woman-spreading-fabricated-allegations-against-him-ca-press-wing</link><description>Chief Adviser’s Special Assistant Professor Ali Riaz on Wednesday clarified that he does not know the woman named Atandrranu Ripa, who is circulating “false, fabricated and baseless” allegations against him.
“Prof Riaz said that he does not know the woman circulating the al</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 15:34:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Community Bank signs business partnership with Tropical Homes</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/community-bank-signs-business-partnership-with-tropical-homes</link><description>Community Bank Bangladesh PLC. and Tropical Homes Limited have recently signed a Memorandum of Understanding (MoU) to strengthen mutual cooperation and offer enhanced loan facilities within the Real Estate sector.
According to a press release, the signing ceremony took place at the Bank’s He</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 15:49:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Al-Arafah Islami Bank signs agreement with Sunlife Insurance Company</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/al-arafah-islami-bank-signs-agreement-with-sunlife-insurance-company</link><description>Al-Arafah Islami Bank PLC, country’s one of the leading Shariah-based banks, has signed a Memorandum of Understanding with Sunlife Insurance Company Limited.
According to a press release, the agreement will enable seamless premium collection, enhanced data security, real-time reporting, and</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 16:04:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Guinea-Bissau army officers take control after disputed vote, RFI reports</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/guinea-bissau-army-officers-take-control-after-disputed-vote-rfi-reports</link><description>A group of senior army officers announced on Wednesday that they have seized control of Guinea-Bissau "until further notice," following the West African nation's disputed presidential election, French radio RFI reported.</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 16:19:09 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>