<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 15:38:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Indian Army chief threatens to ‘wipe Pakistan off Map’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/indian-army-chief-threatens-to-wipe-pakistan-off-map</link><description>India’s Army chief Gen Upendra Dwivedi has issued a sharp warning to Pakistan, accusing the country of fuelling terrorism and threatening its existence on the map unless it ends state-backed militancy.
Speaking at an Army post in Rajasthan’s Anupgarh on Friday, Gen Dwivedi said Indian</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 12:42:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Turag boat capsize: Child’s body recovered</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/childs-body-recovered-from-turag-river-after-boat-capsize-another-still-missing</link><description>Rescuers have recovered the body of a child after a boat capsized in the Turag River at Kaliakair in Gazipur, leaving another child still missing.
A diving team from Tongi Fire Station pulled out the body along with the sunken boat around 11am on Friday, said Md Alauddin, deputy assistant director</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 12:57:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Islami Bank regains control of its Facebook page</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/islami-bank-regains-control-of-its-facebook-page</link><description>The Islami Bank Bangladesh PLC regained control of its official Facebook page on Friday afternoon, nearly 10 hours after it was hacked.
Local news portals said the page was hacked around 5:42 am, and the authorities of the bank regained the control around 4:00 pm on Friday.
Nazrul Islam, head of</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 13:12:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>22-day hilsa fishing ban to begin Friday midnight</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/22-day-hilsa-fishing-ban-to-begin-friday-midnight</link><description>A 22-day ban on hilsa fishing will come into effect across the country’s rivers and marine waters from Friday midnight with a view to protecting the species during its peak breeding season.
Fisheries and Livestock Adviser Farida Akhter outlined the ban at a press conference on Monday at the</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 13:42:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India rejects claims of backing unrest in Khagrachhari</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/india-rejects-claims-of-backing-unrest-in-khagrachhari</link><description>India has rejected allegations that it instigated recent unrest in Bangladesh’s Khagrachhari district.
Speaking at a press conference in New Delhi on Friday, Indian foreign ministry spokesperson Randhir Jaiswal said the claims were ‘false and baseless’, according to bdnews24.com.</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 13:49:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Deep depression weakens into land depression over Bay</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/deep-depression-weakens-into-land-depression-over-bay</link><description>The land deep depression over coastal Odisha and adjoining area moved northnorthwestwards, weakened into a land depression over Odisha and adjoining Chhattisgarh at 3pm on Friday, according Bangladesh Meteorological Department (BMD).
It is likely to move in a north-northwestward direction further</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 14:04:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tributes for Ahmed Rafiq at Shaheed Minar on Saturday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tributes-for-ahmed-rafiq-at-shaheed-minar-on-saturday</link><description>Language Movement activist Ahmed Rafiq will be taken to the Central Shaheed Minar on Saturday, where people from all walks of life can pay their last respects.
The tribute ceremony, organised by the Ahmed Rafiq Foundation, will begin at 11am.
Afterwards, in line with his final wish, his remains w</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 14:19:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh demands immediate release of flotilla detainees</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-slates-israeli-interception-of-gaza-aid-flotilla-demands-release-of-all-activists</link><description>Bangladesh has condemned the interception of the Global Sumud Flotilla in international waters, which was carrying humanitarian aid for Gaza, by Israeli forces.
In a statement on Friday, the foreign ministry described the act as “a flagrant violation of international law and a brazen manifes</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 14:49:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCP clarifies position on pressing for ‘Shapla’ election symbol</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ncp-continues-pressing-for-shapla-as-election-symbol-disputes-ecs-decision</link><description>The National Citizen Party (NCP) has again demanded the “Shapla” as its electoral symbol, rejecting the Election Commission’s (EC) stance that the flower cannot be allocated due to its place in the national emblem.
In a statement on Friday, NCP Convenor Nahid Islam explained why</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 15:19:09 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>