<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 05:44:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Ctg election fever peaks before Feb 12</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ctg-election-fever-peaks-before-feb-12</link><description>Election fever has gripped Chattogram ahead of the 13th Jatiya Sangsad (JS) election slated for 12 February. Campaigning by candidates and discussions among voters are at their peak, with supporters of candidates in the city's 16 constituencies holding processions almost daily. Both candidates and</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 02:54:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nat’l telehealth helpline 16263 faces shutdown amid funding crisis</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/natl-telehealth-helpline-16263-faces-shutdown-amid-funding-crisis</link><description>Bangladesh's flagship public telehealth service, Shastho Batayan 16263, which has served as a critical healthcare lifeline for millions, is facing an uncertain future due to prolonged funding delays and administrative bottlenecks, triggering concern among health experts, service providers and polic</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 03:09:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP to pursue balanced regional dev for equitable wealth distribution</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-to-pursue-balanced-regional-dev-for-equitable-wealth-distribution</link><description>BNP chairman Tarique Rahman has outlined the BNP's vision for region-specific development for balanced national uplift, youth-focused culture and inclusive growth in his party's election manifesto.
Tarique Rahman unveiled his party's broad development vision, placing balanced regional growth, yout</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 03:24:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>H1 sales of saving tools return to positive territory at Tk 24.61b</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/h1-sales-of-saving-tools-return-to-positive-territory-at-tk-2461b</link><description>The net sales of state-run savings instruments returned to positive territory in the first half of the current fiscal year 2025-26 with savers showing growing interest in the secured investment tools.
According to the latest Bangladesh Bank (BB) data, net sales of the savings tools stood at Tk 24.</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 03:26:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Navigating fog is like driving blindfolded</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/analysis/navigating-fog-is-like-driving-blindfolded</link><description>GENERAL EXPERIENCE OF DRIVING IN FOG
From the cab, we do not see the tracks ahead. It just looks like a white wall, and we drive through that. Navigating fog is like driving blindfolded. We sound the whistle frequently, at least four times in a minute. Depending on fog density, we drive at reduced</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 03:41:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A Divided World</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/others/a-divided-world</link><description>In spite of all philosophical and technological advances, the world today is as divided as it was centuries ago. We look at some areas of this division.
We are an impatient nation. In a traffic jam on highways, it is very common to see drivers veer into the opposite lane and thus create a roadbloc</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 03:56:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Learning a lesson of cosmopolitanism in the capital</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/analysis/learning-a-lesson-of-cosmopolitanism-in-the-capital</link><description>Is Bangladesh a nation of forgers? When such denigration comes from none other than the head of the government, one who is a recipient of the highest award on offer in the world, people cannot but look askance. In fact, any generalised perception of any race, people or nation is faulty. But this ki</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 04:11:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fortune Shoes stock price manipulation: FID seeks list of ICB employees involved</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/fortune-shoes-stock-price-manipulation-fid-seeks-list-of-icb-employees-involved</link><description>The Financial Institutions Division (FID) has asked the Bangladesh Securities and Exchange Commission (BSEC) to provide a list of Investment Corporation of Bangladesh (ICB) employees allegedly involved in the manipulation of stock price of Fortune Shoes Ltd.
This move follows an investigation repo</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 04:26:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ctg port operations resume as strike suspended</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ctg-port-operations-resume-as-strike-suspended</link><description>CHATTOGRAM, Feb 06: After a six-day halt, the operational activities at the Chittagong Port resumed on Friday as the workers suspended their strike for two days.
As a result, the loading and unloading of goods and containers from ships at the jetties and the outer anchorage, as well as the transpo</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 04:42:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Poultry, fish, lemon, cucumber prices rise well ahead of Ramadan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/poultry-fish-lemon-cucumber-prices-rise-well-ahead-of-ramadan</link><description>Poultry, fish, lemon and cucumber prices witnessed a hike in the market last week, enhancing woes of the commoners.
Broiler chicken prices increased to Tk 180-190 a kg, marking Tk 10 a kg hike. Sonali (Pakistani) chicken prices also rose to Tk 320-350 per kg, from Tk 280-300 a week ago.
Egg price</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 04:57:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Illegal arms, drugs seized in city: Five held</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/illegal-arms-drugs-seized-in-city-five-held</link><description>A large cache of illegal arms, ammunition, narcotics and cash has been recovered in joint operations conducted by the army in the capital's North Badda and Dhalpur areas.
The Inter-Services Public Relations (ISPR) disclosed the information in a press release issued on Friday, saying that five peop</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 05:12:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ISU and Asia e University Malaysia sign MoU to expand higher study opportunities</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/isu-and-asia-e-university-malaysia-sign-mou-to-expand-higher-study-opportunities</link><description>International Standard University (ISU) and Asia e University (AeU) Malaysia have signed a Memorandum of Understanding (MoU) aimed at expanding higher study opportunities, strengthening academic collaboration, and promoting joint research initiatives.
The MoU signing ceremony and a discussion sess</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 05:27:54 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>