<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 04:42:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>'75pc' of Dhaka polling centres deemed 'high-risk'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/police-classify-three-quarters-of-dhaka-polling-centres-as-high-risk</link><description>With the parliamentary elections less than 10 days away, the Dhaka Metropolitan Police (DMP) has classified nearly three-quarters of the capital’s polling centres as “important”, reflecting concerns over potential “risks”, according to the home advisor.
The DMP overse</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 17:32:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tobacco costs more than twice the revenue: Official</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/tobacco-costs-bangladesh-more-than-twice-it-earns-health-official-says</link><description>Bangladesh earns about Tk 400 billion a year in revenue from the tobacco sector, but the wider costs linked to tobacco use amount to around Tk 870 billion annually, a senior health official has said.
The estimate suggests a net annual loss of at least Tk 470 billion, with the economic burden runni</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 17:47:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Petrobangla, BPC get new chiefs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/erfanul-haque-named-petrobangla-chairman-rezanur-rahman-to-lead-bpc</link><description>The government has reshuffled the leadership of two key state-owned energy corporations, appointing Md Erfanul Haque as chairman of Bangladesh Oil, Gas and Mineral Corporation (Petrobangla) and Md Rezanur Rahman as chairman of Bangladesh Petroleum Corporation (BPC).
The appointments were confirmed</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 18:42:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh, Japan sign defence equipment, technology transfer agreement</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladesh-japan-sign-defence-equipment-technology-transfer-agreement</link><description>Bangladesh and Japan signed a defence equipment and technology transfer agreement at Dhaka Cantonment under the supervision of the Armed Forces Division (AFD) on Tuesday.
Lieutenant General S M Kamrul Hassan, Principal Staff Officer of AFD, signed on behalf of Bangladesh, while Japan's Ambassador</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 01:55:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Saif al-Islam Gaddafi, son of late Libyan leader, has been killed, sources say</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/saif-al-islam-gaddafi-son-of-late-libyan-leader-has-been-killed-sources-say</link><description>The most prominent son of late Libyan leader Muammar Gaddafi, Saif al-Islam Gaddafi, has been killed, sources close to the family, his lawyer Khaled el-Zaydi and Libyan media said on Tuesday.
Details surrounding the circumstances of his death were not immediately clear.
While Saif al-Islam is wel</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 02:10:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Programmer arrested over alleged hack of Jamaat chief Shafiqur’s X account</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/programmer-arrested-over-alleged-hack-of-jamaat-chief-shafiqurs-x-account</link><description>Police have confirmed the detention of Sarowar Alam, an assistant programmer at Bangabhaban, following allegations that he "hacked" the X account of Jamaat-e-Islami chief Shafiqur Rahman.
On Tuesday night, a senior Dhaka Metropolitan Police official said that Sarowar was apprehended at Motijheel.</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 02:25:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AL leaders in India ‘plot’ political return as Bangladesh nears election: Guardian</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/awami-league-leaders-in-india-plot-political-return-as-bangladesh-nears-election-guardian</link><description>Exiled Awami League members have been plotting a political return from India as Bangladesh prepares for its first national election since Sheikh Hasina’s government was toppled by mass protests, The Guardian reports.
Writing on Tuesday, the UK-based newspaper said senior party leaders now li</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 02:40:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangabhaban programmer held over alleged hack of Jamaat chief's X account</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bangabhaban-programmer-held-over-alleged-hack-of-jamaat-chiefs-x-account</link><description>Police have confirmed the detention of Sarowar Alam, an assistant programmer at Bangabhaban, following allegations that he 'hacked' the X account of Jamaat-e-Islami chief Shafiqur Rahman.
On Tuesday night, a senior Dhaka Metropolitan Police official said that Sarowar was apprehended at Motijheel.</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 02:55:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sherpur-3 Jamaat MP candidate Nuruzzaman Badal dies</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/sherpur-3-jamaat-mp-candidate-nuruzzaman-badal-dies</link><description>Mohammad Nuruzzaman Badal, Jamaat-e-Islami’s MP candidate from Sherpur-3 constituency and the party's district secretary, passed away early Wednesday.
He breathed his last at around 1:30 am while undergoing treatment for kidney complications at Swadesh Hospital in Mymensingh, said Sherpur di</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 03:10:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC revises BNCC deployment decision following BNP's objection</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-revises-bncc-deployment-decision-following-bnps-objection</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has revised its earlier decision on deploying Bangladesh National Cadet Corps (BNCC) cadets during the upcoming 13th national parliamentary election and referendum, limiting their role only to maintaining discipline at postal ballot vote-counting centres following objec</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 03:25:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Spain, Greece’s teen social media ban plans draw fury from Elon Musk</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/spain-greeces-teen-social-media-ban-plans-draw-fury-from-elon-musk</link><description>Spain and Greece on Tuesday proposed bans on social media use by teenagers as attitudes hardened in Europe against technology some say is designed to be addictive and the measures announced by Spain's Prime Minister, Pedro Sánchez, drew fury from Elon Musk.
Spain wants to prohibit social me</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 04:12:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Badol, Jamaat’s candidate for the Sherpur-3 parliamentary race, dies of health complications</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/badol-jamaats-candidate-for-the-sherpur-3-parliamentary-race-dies-of-health-complications</link><description>Md Nuruzzaman Badol, Jamaat-e-Islami’s candidate for the Sherpur-3 (Sreebordi-Jhenaigati) parliamentary race in the 13th national election, has died at the age of 52.
Badol, the secretary of the district’s Jamaat unit, had been suffering from kidney disease for a long time. He died at</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 04:27:51 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>