<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 20:22:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Bangladesh put on cyclone alert</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/bangladesh-on-alert-as-bay-depression-brews-into-possible-cyclone-montha-sunday</link><description>A low-pressure system over the Bay of Bengal has intensified, with the Bangladesh Meteorological Department (BMD) warning it may develop into a cyclone by Sunday.
The system has remained over the same area while moving west-northwest on Saturday evening.
Meteorologist Md Omar Faruk told bdnews24.</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 16:24:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A tribute to Rakib Hasan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/reviews/a-tribute-to-rakib-hasan</link><description>In the mid ‘80s, Dhaka was a slow-paced city, almost like a large district town. 
Life revolved around one TV channel!
Radio programmes had avid listeners, tuning to BBC during any political upheaval was common along with the name Mark Tully.
BTV provided the late evening thrills thro</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 16:20:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Innovation or stagnation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/innovation-or-stagnation</link><description>This year’s Nobel Prize in Economics awarded to Joel Mokyr, Philippe Aghion, and Peter Howitt signifies recognition of substantial advancements in the field of innovation-driven economic growth. Their research is anchored in the concept of creative destruction, a theoretical framework first a</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 16:35:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A stride towards recognizing workers' rights</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/a-stride-towards-recognizing-workers-rights</link><description>To align Bangladesh's labour laws with international standards, enhance workers' rights, and strengthen workplace safety and protections, the interim government on Thursday approved the draft ordinance of the Labour Law. Among major changes, the draft law recognises domestic helps as worker, relaxe</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 17:05:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Consensus Commission says July Charter plan ready for submission ‘soon’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/consensus-commission-says-july-charter-plan-ready-for-submission-soon</link><description>The National Consensus Commission has said recommendations on the methods and process for implementing the July Charter will be submitted to the government “very soon”.
The announcement came in a media statement on Saturday after the commission held a review meeting with experts.
&amp;ldq</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 17:35:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>13.5 tonnes of bullet casings found in Natore warehouse</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/135-tonnes-of-bullet-casings-found-in-natore-warehouse</link><description>A businessman in Natore’s Baraigram Upazila has sparked concern among locals by storing around 13.5 tonnes of bullet shells in his warehouse.
Police, however, say he legally purchased the shells from Rajendrapur Cantonment in Gazipur for use in his factory.
Natore Superintendent of Police (</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 17:50:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ex-CIA officer alleges Musharraf handed Pakistan’s nukes to US</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/ex-cia-officer-alleges-musharraf-handed-pakistans-nukes-to-us</link><description>Former CIA officer John Kiriakou has accused the United States of effectively “purchasing” former general Pervez Musharraf by funnelling vast sums of aid into Pakistan, the Hindustan Times has claimed.
Kiriakou also claimed, in an interview with ANI cited by the Indian media, that Mush</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 18:05:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP to recruit religious teachers in primary schools</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bnp-to-recruit-religious-teachers-in-primary-schools</link><description>BNP Standing Committee member Salahuddin Ahmed on Saturday said BNP will create posts for religious teachers in the country’s primary schools if the party gets the chance to form the government.
“If Allah and people give us the responsibility to run the government, we will create posts</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 18:20:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka-dwellers enjoy double country's per-capita fortune</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/dhaka-dwellers-enjoy-double-countrys-per-capita-fortune</link><description>Dhaka district that hosts Bangladesh's centrepetal capital city alone accounts for nearly 46 per cent of the national GDP, estimated at US$462 billion in FY2024-25, while the Dhaka-dwellers enjoy nearly double the country's per-capita income.
Such over-concentration of the economy and fortune in a</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 18:35:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Meghna Bank holds Chattogram Town Hall Meeting 2025</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/meghna-bank-holds-chattogram-town-hall-meeting-2025-2026</link><description>Meghna Bank PLC organized the ‘Chattogram Town Hall Meeting 2025’ on Saturday at the Chittagong Boat Club, with the participation of officials from all branches and departments under the Chattogram region.
The event was graced by Uzma Chowdhury, chairperson of Meghna Bank, as the chief</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 19:36:23 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>