<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 06:58:20 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>AMTOB eager to work closely with new govt</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/amtob-eager-to-work-closely-with-new-govt</link><description>Leaders of the Association of Mobile Telecom Operators of Bangladesh (AMTOB) on Thursday expressed their willingness to work closely with the government on future initiatives aligned with national development goals.
They expressed the desire during a courtesy call on Posts, Telecommunications and</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 03:27:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BGMEA accords reception to its members elected to JS</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bgmea-accords-reception-to-its-members-elected-to-js</link><description>Bangladesh Garment Manufacturers and Exporters Association (BGMEA) on Thursday accorded a reception to its members who have been elected members of parliament in the 13th national election.
A total of 17 members from the readymade garment sector, including three ministers, three state ministers an</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 03:42:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Women bank savings, but barriers to credit persist</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/women-bank-savings-but-barriers-to-credit-persist</link><description>Women's participation in the formal banking system continues to expand, but a persistent gender gap in access to credit remains a key concern, according to the latest Bangladesh Bank (BB) data.
While women are steadily strengthening their presence on the deposit side, their share in lending remain</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 03:57:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ekushey Book Fair opens with incomplete stalls, low turnout</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ekushey-book-fair-opens-with-incomplete-stalls-low-turnout</link><description>The much-anticipated Amar Ekushey Boimela (Book Fair) began at Suhrawardy Udyan in the capital on Thursday in an unprepared state, with most stalls still under construction and a noticeably thin presence of visitors.
Traditionally held throughout February, commemorating the 1952 Language Movement,</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 04:12:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Women paid less than men for same work in BD: WB</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/women-paid-less-than-men-for-same-work-in-bd-wb</link><description>Women in Bangladesh continue to receive lower wages than their male counterparts for the same work, according to the World Bank's (WB) latest report titled 'Women, Business and the Law 2026'.
The report, released on Tuesday, says Bangladesh scored much lower than the global standards across three</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 04:27:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shafiqur urges law-enforcers to be pro-people</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/shafiqur-urges-law-enforcers-to-be-pro-people</link><description>Leader of the Opposition in parliament and Jamaat-e-Islami Ameer Dr Shafiqur Rahman has urged law enforcers to be people-oriented and proactive for the welfare of citizens and the progress of the country.
He made the comments as the chief guest while speaking at a views-exchange meeting between Ja</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 04:42:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Paramount Skydance wins Warner Bros, Netflix walks away and its shares jump</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/paramount-skydance-wins-warner-bros-netflix-walks-away-and-its-shares-jump</link><description>Paramount Skydance emerged as the winner in a months-long battle to acquire Warner Bros Discovery, after streaming giant Netflix on Thursday refused to raise its bid for the storied Hollywood studio.
"We've always been disciplined, and at the price required to match Paramount Skydance's latest o</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 04:57:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ivy, Bodi get HC bail in July Uprising cases</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ivy-bodi-get-hc-bail-in-july-uprising-cases</link><description>The High Court (HC) has granted ad-interim bail to Selina Hayat Ivy, former mayor of Narayanganj City Corporation (NCC), in five cases, including four over murder, filed in connection with the July Uprising.
The HC bench of Justice KM Zahid Sarwar and Justice Sheikh Abu Taher passed the order on T</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 05:12:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trade disruption feared as crime surges at Jashore's Nawapara port</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/trade-disruption-feared-as-crime-surges-at-jashores-nawapara-port</link><description>BENAPOLE, Feb 26: Organised criminal groups have been committing robberies and theft every day from cargo vessels anchored at the Nawapara river port in Jashore's Abhaynagar Upazila. The port now stands at the centre of an estimated Tk 250 billion economic activity, with the movement of more than 5</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 05:27:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BSEC seeks ACC probe into RACE over disputed tax reporting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/bsec-seeks-acc-probe-into-race-over-disputed-tax-reporting</link><description>The country's largest asset manager, RACE Management, has been found to have reported a fictitious tax charge of Tk 96.8 million in the FY24 financial statements of six funds under its management.
Following the discovery, the Bangladesh Securities and Exchange Commission (BSEC) referred the matter</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 05:42:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Stocks cross 5,600 mark on increased appetite for bank stocks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/stocks-cross-5600-mark-on-increased-appetite-for-bank-stocks</link><description>The benchmark index of the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) surpassed the 5,600-point threshold once again after six months as investors showed buying appetite in bank stocks amid improved post-election sentiment.
Market analysts cited the ongoing market recovery as being driven by broad-based investor</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 05:57:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pakistan bombs targets in Afghan cities, minister calls it 'open war'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/pakistan-bombs-targets-in-afghan-cities-minister-calls-it-open-war</link><description>Pakistan bombed Taliban government targets in Afghanistan's major cities overnight, officials from both countries said on Friday, with Pakistan's defence minister describing the conflict as "open war".
Security sources in Pakistan said the strikes involved air and ground strikes against Taliban po</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 06:12:01 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>