<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 11:23:44 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>TikTok seals deal for new US joint venture to avoid American ban</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/tiktok-seals-deal-for-new-us-joint-venture-to-avoid-american-ban</link><description>TikTok's Chinese owner, ByteDance, on Thursday said it has finalised a deal to establish a majority American-owned joint venture that will secure US data, to avoid a US ban on the short video app used by over 200 million Americans.
The deal is a milestone for the social media firm after years of b</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 07:19:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BR seeks extra Tk1.95b for land acquisition, two years more</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/br-seeks-extra-tk195b-for-land-acquisition-two-years-more</link><description>The Bangladesh Railway (BR) has sought an additional Tk1.95 billion for acquiring 3.347 acres of land for the Jamuna railway bridge construction projects, officials said on Tuesday.
The BR has proposed an increase of the land acquisition cost by 56.41 per cent to Tk 5.422 billion from the existing</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 07:34:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat chief calls for unity, restraint as election campaign enters second day</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-chief-calls-for-unity-restraint-as-election-campaign-enters-second-day</link><description>Jamaat-e-Islami chief Shafiqur Rahman has called on political parties and the government to remain united and refrain from any form of interference as the election campaign enters its second day.
Speaking to journalists at the domestic lounge of Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport in Dhaka on F</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 07:49:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Iran says ‘finger on trigger’ as Trump claims Tehran wants talks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/iran-says-finger-on-trigger-as-trump-claims-tehran-wants-talks</link><description>Iran's powerful Revolutionary Guard has warned the United States that its forces remain on high alert, even as President Donald Trump said Tehran appears willing to enter negotiations.
In a statement aired by state television on Thursday, Revolutionary Guard commander Gen Mohammad Pakpour said his</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 08:04:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US names new top envoy for Venezuela after Maduro capture</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-names-new-top-envoy-for-venezuela-after-maduro-capture</link><description>The United States has named a two-time US ambassador as its top envoy for Venezuela, according to the US embassy in Caracas website.
Laura Dogu, who previously served as ambassador to Honduras and Nicaragua, will serve as charge d'affaires to the Venezuela Affairs Unit based out of the embassy in</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 08:19:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Feb 12 election to set standard for future polls: CA</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/feb-12-election-to-set-standard-for-future-polls-ca</link><description>Chief Advisor Muhammad Yunus says the Feb 12 general elections will set a benchmark for all future polls in Bangladesh.
He made the remarks during a maiden courtesy call by newly appointed US Ambassador to Bangladesh Brent Christensen on the chief advisor at the State Guest House Jamuna in Dhaka,</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 08:34:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Indonesia finds bodies of 10 passengers on crashed surveillance plane</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/indonesia-finds-bodies-of-10-passengers-on-crashed-surveillance-plane</link><description>Indonesian rescuers on Friday had found the bodies of 10 passengers on a fishery surveillance plane that went missing in Indonesia's South Sulawesi province at the weekend, the country's search and rescue agency said.
The ATR 42-500 turboprop owned by aviation group Indonesia Air Transport (IAT) l</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 08:49:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Muchabbir killing: Another ‘shooter’ arrested</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/another-shooter-arrested-over-killing-of-swecchasebak-dal-leader-muchabbir</link><description>The Dhaka Metropolitan Police’s Detective Branch has arrested another alleged shooter accused of killing Swechhasebak Dal leader Azizur Rahman Muchabbir.
The suspect, identified as Rahim, was arrested in a raid in Narsingdi early on Friday, DB Additional Commissioner Md Shafiqul Islam said.</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 09:04:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gold prices hit new record high in Bangladesh within 12 hours of cut</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/gold-prices-hit-new-record-high-in-bangladesh-within-12-hours-of-cut</link><description>Gold prices in Bangladesh have surged again, just 12 hours after a brief reduction, setting a new all-time record in the domestic market.
The price of the highest-quality 22-carat gold has been increased by Tk 6,299 per bhori (11.664 grams), pushing the price to a record Tk 255,617 per bhori, acco</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 09:43:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Denmark, NATO seek to boost Arctic security amid Greenland crisis</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/denmark-nato-seek-to-boost-arctic-security-amid-greenland-crisis</link><description>Denmark's Prime Minister Mette Frederiksen said on Friday she had agreed with NATO chief Mark Rutte that the alliance needs to boost security in the Arctic following weeks of turmoil over US President Donald Trump's threat to annex Greenland.
The governments of Denmark and Greenland, a Danish auto</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 09:58:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India's JSW Steel posts quarterly profit rise on higher volume</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/indias-jsw-steel-posts-quarterly-profit-rise-on-higher-volume</link><description>India's JSW Steel (JSTL.NS) reported a jump in third-quarter profit on Friday, as higher sales volumes helped mitigate the impact of lower steel prices.
Its consolidated net profit rose nearly three-fold year-on-year to 21.39 billion rupees ($232.7 million) for the quarter ended December 31.
($1</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 10:13:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>500 foreign observers, journalists expected to oversee upcoming polls: EC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/500-foreign-observers-journalists-expected-to-oversee-upcoming-polls-ec</link><description>Election Commission (EC) Senior Secretary Akhter Ahmed has said nearly 500 foreign observers and journalists are expected to come to Bangladesh to observe the 13th National Parliament Election and the referendum scheduled for February 12.
“We expect nearly 500 foreign observers and journalis</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 10:28:42 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>