<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 12:40:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Vatican visit by King Charles to show closening Anglican-Catholic ties</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/vatican-visit-by-king-charles-to-show-closening-anglican-catholic-ties</link><description>Britain's King Charles and Queen Camilla will meet Pope Leo at the Vatican next week in a visit seen as a sign of closening ties between the Catholic Church and the Anglican Communion, five centuries after their turbulent separation.
The British royals will arrive on Oct 22 for the two-day state v</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 09:55:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UN says 560 tonnes of food entering Gaza daily since ceasefire but more needed</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/un-says-560-tonnes-of-food-entering-gaza-daily-since-ceasefire-but-more-needed</link><description>The UN World Food Programme said on Friday it has brought about 560 tonnes of food per day on average into Gaza since the Israel-Hamas ceasefire took effect, but that still fell short of the scale of need in the enclave.
With famine conditions present in parts of Gaza, UN Under-Secretary-General f</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 10:10:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Britain's Starmer calls for Israeli soccer fans to be allowed at Aston Villa match</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/britains-starmer-calls-for-israeli-soccer-fans-to-be-allowed-at-aston-villa-match</link><description>British Prime Minister Keir Starmer has said fans of Israeli side Maccabi Tel Aviv should not be barred from a soccer match in Birmingham next month, as tensions over antisemitism and protests against Israel's war in Gaza dog his government.
Aston Villa said travelling Maccabi fans - who were invo</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 10:25:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>What could a Ukraine peace look like?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/what-could-a-ukraine-peace-look-like</link><description>US President Donald Trump has said he will meet Russian President Vladimir Putin in Budapest soon to discuss a way to end the war in Ukraine.
So what might a peace deal look like?
WHO WOULD GET WHAT?
Russia controls more than 116,000 square km (44,800 square miles), or more than 19 per cent of U</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 10:55:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>July Charter signing start of ‘New Bangladesh’: Prof Yunus</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/july-charter-signing-start-of-new-bangladesh-prof-yunus</link><description>Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus on Friday described the signing moment of the July Memorial Charter-2025 as a ‘great day’ and sees it as the beginning of ‘New Bangladesh’.
“It’s a great day. It’s the beginning of New Bangladesh,” he said in hi</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 11:10:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Putin held meeting of top officials following call with Trump</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/putin-held-meeting-of-top-officials-following-call-with-trump</link><description>Russian President Vladimir Putin convened a meeting of Russia's powerful Security Council following a phone call with US President Donald Trump, Russian news agencies reported on Friday, citing Kremlin aide Yuri Ushakov.
According to Ushakov, Putin provided a detailed briefing to Security Council</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 11:25:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Suicide attack kills 7 Pakistani troops near Afghan border, security officials say</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/suicide-attack-kills-7-pakistani-troops-near-afghan-border-security-officials-say</link><description>Seven Pakistani soldiers were killed in a suicide attack near the Afghan border on Friday, Pakistani security officials said, amid a fragile ceasefire between Islamabad and Kabul that paused days of intense fighting between the former allies this month.
The South Asian neighbours engaged in fierce</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 11:40:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Historic July Charter signed</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/historic-july-charter-signed</link><description>The Historic July Charter was officially signed on Friday afternoon at the South Plaza of the Jatiya Sangsad Bhaban.
Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus and Vice President of the National Consensus Commission Professor Ali Riaz signed the charter, joined by several other political leaders.
Amo</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 11:55:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Zelensky to seek weapons from Trump in the shadow of a new Putin summit</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/zelensky-to-seek-weapons-from-trump-in-the-shadow-of-a-new-putin-summit</link><description>US President Donald Trump will discuss the possible supply of long-range Tomahawk missiles to Ukraine with President Volodymyr Zelensky on Friday but the surprise announcement of a new US-Russian summit cast doubt over the prospect.
Trump said on Thursday he may meet Russian President Vladimir Put</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 12:25:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two probe bodies formed over CEPZ building fire</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/two-probe-bodies-formed-over-cepz-building-fire</link><description>Two separate probe committees have been formed to investigate the devastating fire that broke out in a seven-storey building inside the Chattogram Export Processing Zone (CEPZ) area.
The fire, which started yesterday afternoon, was finally brought under control this morning after nearly 17 hours o</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 12:40:24 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>