<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 11:37:50 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Govt seeks public opinions on pay scale reform</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-seeks-public-opinions-on-pay-scale-reform</link><description>The government is soliciting opinions from the public and stakeholders to make revisions to the national pay scale that are widely acceptable.
A panel formed to review the existing structure has prepared four separate questionnaires to gather opinions online with the aim of making recommendations</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 09:38:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Devotees pack pavilions on Nabami as Durga Puja nears climax</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/devotees-pack-pavilions-on-nabami-as-durga-puja-nears-climax</link><description>As the Durga Puja festival enters its ninth day, a tinge of sorrow filled the air as devotees prepare to bid farewell to the goddess.
Undeterred by the rain on Wednesday, worshippers thronged temples and pavilions across the country to take part in the Sandhi Puja rituals marking Maha Nabami, the</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 08:23:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BGB chief visits Dhakeshwari, Ramna Kali temples</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bgb-chief-visits-dhakeshwari-ramna-kali-temples</link><description>Bangladesh Border Guard (BGB) Director General Major General Mohammad Ashrafuzzaman Siddiqui on Wednesday visited the Dhakeshwari National Temple and Ramna Kali Mondir in the capital to inspect the overall security arrangement taken at the temples for peaceful and festive celebrations of the Durga</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 08:38:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Which film did Shah Rukh Khan disown?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/entertainment/which-film-did-shah-rukh-khan-disown</link><description>In the early 1990s, Shah Rukh Khan was still a newcomer in Bollywood. He had shown promise with Deewana and Raju Ban Gaya Gentleman, but he wasn't yet the superstar who would one day be called the "King of Bollywood." Hungry for opportunities, he signed multiple films, hoping that at least some wou</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 08:53:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mother, daughter killed in Bogura road accident</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/mother-daughter-killed-in-bogura-road-accident</link><description>A woman and her daughter were killed when a pickup truck hit their scooty at Adamdighi upazila of Bogura district on Tuesday.
The deceased were identified as Nazira Akhter Mim, 27, a Quran teacher, and her two-year-old daughter, Nazifa Akhter, reports BSS.
Nazira's husband, Ramzan Ali Tota, an im</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 09:08:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BMW to recall over 145,000 US vehicles, citing starter motor defect</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bmw-to-recall-over-145000-us-vehicles-citing-starter-motor-defect</link><description>BMW is recalling over 145,000 vehicles in the U.S. as an overheated starter could increase the risk of a fire, the U.S. National Highway Traffic Safety Administration said on Wednesday.
 
The issue affects vehicles across 2020 340I, X7, and X5 models, the auto safety regulator said.</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 09:23:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>'Stop election-fixing before preaching about match-fixing': Tamim</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/cricket/stop-election-fixing-before-preaching-about-match-fixing-tamim</link><description>Clad in a mustard-coloured panjabi, former Bangladesh captain Tamim Iqbal walked up to the dais to address the media on the last day for candidates to withdraw from the upcoming Bangladesh Cricket Board (BCB) elections.
With a smile on his face, he said: “I thought I’d wear this panjab</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 09:53:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Asia draws $100 billion in capital as investors diversify beyond US, Goldman executive says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/global/asia-draws-100-billion-in-capital-as-investors-diversify-beyond-us-goldman-executive-says</link><description>Asia excluding China has attracted about $100 billion in capital inflows over the past nine months as global investors diversify beyond the US, said Kevin Sneader, Goldman Sachs' president for Asia-Pacific ex-Japan, on Wednesday.
“There is incremental flow in this part of the world,” S</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 10:08:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CHT unrest part of national and international conspiracies: Rizvi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/cht-unrest-part-of-national-and-international-conspiracies-rizvi</link><description>BNP Senior Joint Secretary General Ruhul Kabir Rizvi on Wednesday said the ongoing unrest in the Chattogram Hill Tracts (CHT) during the Durga Puja celebrations is part of a ‘national and international conspiracy’ aimed at destabilising Bangladesh.
“Some countries want to keep Ha</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 10:38:37 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>