<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 17:56:46 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Police recover and return 105 lost mobile phones to owners in Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/police-recover-and-return-105-lost-mobile-phones-to-owners-in-dhaka</link><description>Police have recovered 105 mobile phones lost at different times and returned them to their rightful owners in the capital.
The recovered phones were handed over by Paltan Model Police Station of the Dhaka Metropolitan Police (DMP).
DMP’s Deputy Commissioner (Media) Talebur Rahman said polic</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 15:30:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Candidates allocated symbols, campaign begins on Thursday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/candidates-allocated-symbols-campaign-begins-on-thursday</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has completed the allocation of symbols for 1,973 candidates contesting 298 constituencies across the country for the upcoming 13th national parliamentary election.
With the symbol allocation completed, candidates will be able to start their campaigns from Thursday, EC</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 15:46:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US looks forward to working with all Bangladeshi political parties: Ambassador</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/us-looks-forward-to-working-with-all-bangladeshi-political-parties-ambassador</link><description>Expressing optimism over the future of the two countries, US Ambassador to Bangladesh Brent T. Christensen on Wednesday said his country does not take any side and it is the 'sovereign decision' of the people of Bangladesh whom they want.
“We don't take any side," he said during his first in</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 16:01:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Eight UNOs transferred with EC consent</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/eight-unos-transferred-with-ec-consent</link><description>The government has transferred Upazila Nirbahi Officers (UNOs) of eight upazilas with the consent of the Election Commission.
The Ministry of Public Administration issued a notification in this regard on Tuesday.
As per the order, Israt Jahan, UNO of Patharghata in Barguna, has been transferred t</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 16:16:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fraternal clash between BNP activists in Mymensingh leaves 10 injured</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/fraternal-clash-between-bnp-activists-in-mymensingh-leaves-10-injured</link><description>At least 10 people were injured in a clash between the supporter groups of two BNP leaders in Mymensingh-10 (Gafargaon) constituency on Wednesday evening.
The clash occurred in front of Islamia School in Gafargaon after election symbols were allocated for the constituency. Supporters of Akhtaruzza</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 16:31:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique heads to Shah Paran's shrine to launch election campaign in Sylhet</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-heads-to-shah-parans-shrine-to-launch-election-campaign-in-sylhet</link><description>BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman has started for Sufi saint Hazrat Shah Paran's shrine after praying at Hazrat Shahjalal’s resting place in Sylhet in keeping with party tradition to officially begin his election campaign.
He departed from Sylhet’s Osmani International Airport by road shortl</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 16:01:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ACC to charge 21 over BCS appointments under freedom fighter quota</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/acc-to-prosecute-21-over-bcs-recruitments-under-freedom-fighter-quota-without-application</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) has decided to file six cases against 21 individuals over appointing six officers through the 29th Bangladesh Civil Service (BCS) exam under the freedom fighter quota.
ACC Director General Md Akhtar Hossain informed journalists about the decision to prosecute t</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 16:16:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ex-caretaker advisor Hafizuddin Khan dies</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/former-caretaker-government-advisor-hafizuddin-khan-dies-at-89</link><description>Former advisor to a caretaker government and civil servant M Hafizuddin Khan has died at the age of 89.
He died at his residence in Uttara’s Sector 1 on Wednesday at 7pm due to natural causes, according to his maternal cousin Liaquat Ali.
Hafizuddin served as secretary of the posts and tele</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 16:31:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique Rahman visits Shahjalal shrine, offers prayers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-rahman-visits-shahjalal-shrine-offers-prayers</link><description>BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman visited the shrine of Hazrat Shahjalal (RA) in Sylhet on Wednesday night.
He later performed Nafl prayers at 9:05pm, said BNP Media Cell member Sayrul Kabir Khan.
At 9:30pm, Tarique Rahman also visited the grave of late General (retired) M. A. G. Osmani, the first Comm</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 16:46:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gold price tops Tk 250,000 per bhori, sets new all-time high in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/gold-price-tops-tk-250000-per-bhori-sets-new-all-time-high-in-bangladesh</link><description>Gold prices in Bangladesh have surged past the Tk 250,000 mark per bhori on Wednesday, hitting an all-time high in the domestic market.
The Bangladesh Jewellers Association (BAJUS) raised the price of 22-carat gold by Tk 8,339 per bhori (11.664 grams), setting the new rate at Tk 252,467, the highe</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 17:01:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jatiya Party launches election campaign</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jatiya-party-launches-election-campaign-amid-worries-over-fairness-level-playing-field</link><description>The Jatiya Party is heading into the campaign in 196 constituencies, raising concerns that include possible “election engineering”.
Secretary General Shameem Haider Patwary said there is anxiety among candidates over potential obstacles to campaigning and the absence of a “level</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 17:16:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New US Ambassador to Bangladesh raises concern over China</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/new-us-ambassador-to-bangladesh-raises-concern-over-chinas-regional-influence</link><description>Newly appointed US Ambassador to Bangladesh Brent T Christensen on Wednesday said he is concerned about broader Chinese influence in South Asia, stressing that they have a host of options available to try to help their partner militaries meet their capability needs.
‘You know, as I sai</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 17:31:09 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>