<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 10:44:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Five new products to be included in TCB sales from Nov: Commerce Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/five-new-products-to-be-included-in-tcb-sales-from-nov-commerce-adviser</link><description>Trading Corporation of Bangladesh (TCB) is set to add five more products, including tea and salt, from November, said Commerce Adviser Sk. Bashir Uddin on Monday.
"The inclusion of five new products in TCB's ongoing sales programme will provide further relief to low-income families and contribute</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 09:37:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat pushing for PR to block elections: Hafizuddin</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-pushing-for-pr-to-block-elections-hafizuddin</link><description>BNP Standing Committee member Hafizuddin Ahmed on Monday said Jamaat-e-Islami is pushing for a proportional representation (PR) system to block elections as it has always feared the people’s verdict.
“A political party that opposed the Liberation War in 1971 and the Pakistan Movement i</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 08:29:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Why are so many young people having heart attacks?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/why-are-so-many-young-people-having-heart-attacks</link><description>It is a scene that has become unsettlingly common in Bangladesh. A young professional, barely in his late thirties, collapses at his office desk. A father in his early forties suddenly dies while on the treadmill. A woman in her thirties, juggling long hours at work and endless responsibilities at</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 08:44:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BBS, UNOPS sign MoU to strengthen statistical capacity in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bbs-unops-sign-mou-to-strengthen-statistical-capacity-in-bangladesh</link><description>The Bangladesh Bureau of Statistics (BBS), under the Statistics and Informatics Division (SID) of the Ministry of Planning, signed a Memorandum of Understanding (MoU) on Monday with the United Nations Office for Project Services (UNOPS) to strengthen statistical capacity, modernise data management,</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 08:59:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Special drive to protect mother hilsa from Oct 4-25: Farida</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/special-drive-to-protect-mother-hilsa-from-oct-4-25-farida</link><description>Fisheries and Livestock Adviser Farida Akhter today announced that netting of hilsa will be suspended nationwide from October 4 to 25 as part of a special drive to protect mother hilsa.
She made the announcement at a press conference held at the ministry's conference room at the Secretariat, BSS r</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 09:29:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Kremlin accuses Moldova of preventing hundreds of thousands of Moldovans in Russia from voting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/kremlin-accuses-moldova-of-preventing-hundreds-of-thousands-of-moldovans-in-russia-from-voting</link><description>The Kremlin on Monday accused the authorities in Moldova of preventing hundreds of thousands of Moldovans living in Russia from voting in an important parliamentary election by providing only two polling stations for voters in the country.
Moldova's pro-European Union ruling party won a resounding</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 09:44:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Climate change and pollution threaten Europe's resources, EU warns</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/climate-change-and-pollution-threaten-europes-resources-eu-warns</link><description>Climate change and environmental degradation pose a direct threat to the natural resources that Europe needs for its economic security, the EU's environmental agency said on Monday.
The European Environment Agency said biodiversity in Europe is declining due to unsustainable production and consump</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 09:59:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Six months in, Canada's Carney faces two-front trade war with little leverage</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/six-months-in-canadas-carney-faces-two-front-trade-war-with-little-leverage</link><description>After some six months as Canada's Prime Minister, former banker Mark Carney faces a tepid economy and mounting obstacles as he attempts to forge a new path for the country amid tariff disputes with its two largest trading partners.
Carney has not sealed a new economic relationship with the United</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 10:14:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jatiya Party leader Mamunur Rashid remanded for 6 days in anti-terrorism case</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jatiya-party-leader-mamunur-rashid-remanded-for-6-days-in-anti-terrorism-case</link><description>A Dhaka court has placed Kazi Md Mamunur Rashid, secretary general of the Raushon Ershad-led faction of the Jatiya Party, on six days’ remand in an anti-terrorism case.
Metropolitan Magistrate Sarah Farzana Haque issued the remand order on Monday in response to a petition from the investigat</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 10:44:09 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>