<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 14:28:18 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Al-Arafah Islami Bank donates Taka 8 lakh to Dhaka National Medical College</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/al-arafah-islami-bank-donates-taka-8-lakh-to-dhaka-national-medical-college</link><description>Leading Sharia-compliant Islamic Bank Al-Arafah Islami Bank has donated Taka 8 (eight) lakh to Dhaka National Medical College under its Corporate Social Responsibility (CSR) program.
The donation was made for the purchase of surgical medical equipment for the college's urology department and denta</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 11:24:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fascist AL distorted history of Liberation War for petty party gains: Tarique Rahman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/fascist-al-distorted-history-of-liberation-war-for-petty-party-gains-tarique-rahman</link><description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman on Monday said the fascist Awami League (AL) distorted the history of Bangladesh’s independence and Liberation War for their own petty party interests.
“A deposed and fugitive clique has distorted the history of independence and the Liberation War for</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 11:39:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ukraine peace talks stretch into second day at start of pivotal week for Europe</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/ukraine-peace-talks-stretch-into-second-day-at-start-of-pivotal-week-for-europe</link><description>Ukraine said on Sunday it was willing to drop its ambition to join the NATO alliance in exchange for Western security guarantees. But it was not immediately clear how far talks had progressed on that or other vital issues such as the future of Ukrainian territory, and how much the talks in Berlin c</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 11:54:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Anis Alamgir to be interrogated for five days in anti-terror case</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/anis-alamgir-to-be-interrogated-for-five-days-in-anti-terror-case</link><description>A Dhaka court has granted police five days to question senior journalist Anis Alamgir in custody in an anti-terror case.
Additional Chief Metropolitan Magistrate Jashita Islam issued the order on Monday following a hearing on the investigating officer’s request for a seven-day remand.
Prose</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 12:09:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gold gains 1 per cent on safe-haven demand, softer dollar ahead of US jobs data</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/gold-gains-1-per-cent-on-safe-haven-demand-softer-dollar-ahead-of-us-jobs-data</link><description>Gold climbed 1 per cent on Monday to hover near a seven-week high, supported by a weaker dollar, expectations of interest rate cuts and safe-haven buying due to geopolitical tensions, while silver gained but held below Friday’s record high.
Spot gold gained 0.9 per cent to $4,343.96 an ounce</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 12:24:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US Embassy warns citizens to avoid gatherings, crowds</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-embassy-warns-citizens-to-avoid-gatherings-crowds</link><description>The US Embassy in Dhaka has warned US citizens that peaceful gatherings could “turn into violence” ahead of the parliamentary election.
The embassy issued a security alert for the entire country on Monday.
The Election Commission has scheduled the general election and referendum for F</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 12:39:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rob Reiner and wife found dead at Los Angeles residence</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/rob-reiner-and-wife-found-dead-at-los-angeles-residence</link><description>Director and actor Rob Reiner and his wife Michele were found dead Sunday at a Los Angeles home owned by Reiner, according to a law enforcement official briefed on the investigation.
The official, who spoke to The Associated Press on condition of anonymity because they were not authorised to discu</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 12:54:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Canadian housing starts increase 9.4 per cent in November</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/canadian-housing-starts-increase-94-per-cent-in-november</link><description>Canadian housing starts rose 9.4 per cent in November from the previous month, data from the national housing agency showed on Monday.
The seasonally adjusted annualized rate of housing starts climbed to 254,058 units from a revised 232,245 units in October, the Canada Mortgage and Housing Corpora</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 13:09:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nation set to celebrate Victory Day on Tuesday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nation-set-to-celebrate-victory-day-on-tuesday</link><description>The nation is set to celebrate the Victory Day on Tuesday, as the country was liberated from the Pakistani occupation forces on that day 54 years back through a nine-month-long bloodstained War of Liberation.
On December 16 in 1971, Bangladesh was born as an independent country at the cost of supr</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 13:24:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Editors’ Council condemns case against Anis Alamgir</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/editors-council-condemns-case-against-anis-alamgir</link><description>The Editors’ Council on Monday strongly condemned the filing of a case under the Anti-Terrorism Act against journalist Anis Alamgir, alleging that he was summoned to the Detective Branch (DB) office without any specific allegation.
In a statement, Editors’ Council President Nurul Kabir</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 13:39:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Returning officers asked to finalise panels of polling officers by December 18</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/returning-officers-asked-to-finalise-panels-of-polling-officers-by-december-18</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has directed the returning officers (ROs) to finalise the panels of polling officers in line with the fixed guidelines by December 18 next for the upcoming national election and the referendum on the July Charter, scheduled to be held simultaneously on February 12, 2026</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 13:54:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chilean investors cheer election of Kast as president</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/chilean-investors-cheer-election-of-kast-as-president</link><description>The Chilean peso strengthened against the US dollar on Monday after right-wing hardliner Jose Antonio Kast was elected president in a commanding runoff win against leftist candidate Jeannette Jara.
While the market had largely priced in a Kast win, his margin of victory - some 16 percentage points</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 14:09:06 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>