<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 17:18:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nigeria seeks French help to combat insecurity, Macron says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/nigeria-seeks-french-help-to-combat-insecurity-macron-says</link><description>Nigerian President Bola Tinubu has sought more help from France to fight widespread violence in the north of the country, French President Emmanuel Macron said on Sunday, weeks after the United States threatened to intervene to protect Nigeria's Christians.
Nigeria, Africa's most populous country,</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 13:40:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Islami Bank launches stall at SME fair with various services for entrepreneurs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/islami-bank-launches-stall-at-sme-fair-with-various-services-for-entrepreneurs</link><description>Islami Bank Bangladesh PLC launched a stall at the 12th National SME Fair 2025, a seven-day event organized by the SME Foundation, according to a press release.
Md. Omar Faruk Khan, Managing Director of the bank, inaugurated the stall at the Bangladesh-China Friendship Conference Center on Sunday</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 13:55:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Soybean oil increases by Tk 6 per litre, palm oil rises by Tk 16</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/soybean-oil-increases-by-tk-6-per-litre-palm-oil-rises-by-tk-16</link><description>The Bangladesh Vegetable Oil Refiners and Vanaspati Manufacturers Association has announced an increase in the retail prices of edible oil, raising the rates of bottled soybean and palm oil with effect from Monday morning.
In a media release issued on Sunday evening, the association said a litre o</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 14:10:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No compromise with terrorism, extortion, drugs: Mirza Abbas</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/no-compromise-with-terrorism-extortion-drugs-mirza-abbas</link><description>BNP senior leader Mirza Abbas on Sunday warned that there will be ‘no compromise with terrorism, extortion or drugs’ if he is elected, vowing to free public spaces and tackle growing drug abuse in the capital.
“Drug use has marked a rise in recent years as playgrounds, recreation</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 14:25:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>10 BNP men injured in Gazipur-1 over nomination dispute</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/10-bnp-men-injured-in-gazipur-1-over-nomination-dispute</link><description>At least ten people were injured in clashes between two factions of the BNP in Gazipur on Sunday evening over the party’s nomination for the Gazipur-1 constituency.
Supporters of Dr. Barrister Ishraq Ahmed Siddiqui, who was denied the nomination, also saw their election office attacked and v</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 14:40:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Election schedule to be announced any day this week: EC Sanaullah</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/election-schedule-to-be-announced-any-day-this-week-ec-sanaullah</link><description>The schedule for the 13th Jatiya Sangsad (National Parliament) election and the referendum will be announced this week, said Election Commissioner (EC) Brig Gen (retd) Abul Fazal Md. Sanaullah.
“The schedule for the national election and the referendum will be announced very soon. As the Chi</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 14:55:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chhatra Shibir announces full panel for SUCSU election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/chhatra-shibir-announces-full-panel-for-sucsu-election</link><description>Bangladesh Islami Chhatra Shibir’s SUST unit has announced a 23-member full panel for the Shahjalal University of Science and Technology Central Students’ Union (SUCSU) and hall union elections.
Azizur Rahman Azad, central publicity secretary of Chhatra Shibir, announced the panel name</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 15:10:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rupali Haque Chowdhury elected FICCI president for 2026-27</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/rupali-haque-chowdhury-elected-ficci-president-for-2026-27</link><description>Rupali Haque Chowdhury, Managing Director of Berger Paints Bangladesh Limited, has been elected President of the Foreign Investors’ Chamber of Commerce and Industry (FICCI) for the tenure of 2026–2027.
The election was announced at FICCI’s 62nd Annual General Meeting (AGM) held o</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 15:25:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Interim govt failed to curb corruption: TIB</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tib-says-interim-administration-failed-to-take-stand-against-corruption</link><description>Transparency International Bangladesh chief Iftekharuzzaman has said the interim government failed to take a stand against corruption.
Iftekharuzzaman, executive director of the local chapter of Berlin-based Transparency International, a global anti-corruption organisation, presented topics that t</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 15:40:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Netanyahu says he will not quit politics if he receives a pardon</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/netanyahu-says-he-will-not-quit-politics-if-he-receives-a-pardon</link><description>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said on Sunday that he would not retire from politics if he receives a pardon from the country’s president in his years-long corruption trial.
Asked by a reporter if planned on retiring from political life if he receives a pardon, Netanyahu replied:</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 15:55:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gender differentials in workforce</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/gender-differentials-in-workforce</link><description>Gender differentials in workforce
 
When women have access to credit and generate profits, they are more likely than men to use their income to improve their families' wellbeing. Thus, improving women's access to these assets brings Bangladesh closer to reaping 
the first demog</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 16:10:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ESCAP and the next frontier of Asia-Pacific development</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/reviews/escap-and-the-next-frontier-of-asia-pacific-development</link><description>The United Nations Economic and Social Commission for Asia and the Pacific (ESCAP) is one of the five Regional Commissions under the jurisdiction of the UN Economic and Social Council. It was established in order to increase economic activity in Asia and the Far East, as well as to foster economic</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 16:25:47 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>