<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 03:17:30 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Many practitioners face regulatory limbo</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/many-practitioners-face-regulatory-limbo</link><description>Bangladesh's financial reporting and audit ecosystem is on the verge of serious disruption as the Financial Reporting Council (FRC) has yet to complete the enlistment and renewal process for auditors and audit firms, leaving many practitioners in regulatory limbo.
Despite clear provisions under th</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 00:32:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Korea eyes trade pact with Bangladesh amid investment hurdles</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/korea-eyes-trade-pact-with-bangladesh-amid-investment-hurdles</link><description>South Korea is pushing for the early conclusion of a Comprehensive Economic Partnership Agreement (CEPA) with Bangladesh, as both countries seek to elevate a five-decade-long relationship to a new level of trade and investment cooperation.
Speaking at a seminar on Korean investors' CSR activities</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 00:47:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat, allies announce nationwide protest over five-point demand</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-allies-announce-nationwide-protest-over-five-point-demand</link><description>The Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami, along with like-minded parties, announced on Sunday a nationwide protest programme to press five demands, including introducing a Proportional Representation (PR) system in the next national elections.
At a press conference held at the National Press Club in Dhaka,</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 01:02:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Call for venture capital boost to power startup growth</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/call-for-venture-capital-boost-to-power-startup-growth</link><description>Bangladesh's startup scene is brimming with ideas but starved of patient capital, industry leaders and financial experts said on Sunday.
They stressed that the country must now move beyond its dependence on high-interest bank loans and embrace venture capital to unlock the next wave of innovation</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 01:17:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Distribution of smart family card faces blow</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/distribution-of-smart-family-card-faces-blow</link><description>An official initiative to provide smart family cards to 10 million low-income families under the Trading Corporation of Bangladesh (TCB) is facing a setback due to non-completion of their database, official sources said.
As a result, the TCB has requested the Ministry of Commerce (MoC) to take nec</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 01:32:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Yields on T-bills fall as banks park idle funds</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/yields-on-t-bills-fall-as-banks-park-idle-funds</link><description>Yields on treasury bills (T-bills) declined further on Sunday as banks continued to channel their surplus liquidity into government securities, amid sluggish private-sector credit growth in the run-up to the national elections.
The cut-off yield, commonly known as the interest rate, on the 91-day</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 01:47:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BARVIDA seeks govt action against attacks, extortion at car showrooms</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/barvida-seeks-govt-action-against-attacks-extortion-at-car-showrooms</link><description>The Bangladesh Reconditioned Vehicles Importers and Dealers Association (BARVIDA) has warned the government that they would go for a tougher programme if a crackdown on extortionists and attackers who vandalised car showrooms was not initiated by October 30th.
President of BARVIDA Abdul Haque issu</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 02:02:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Media professional found dead in city</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/media-professional-found-dead-in-city</link><description>A female media professional was found dead at her residence in the Sobhanbagh area of the capital on Saturday evening.
The deceased was identified as Sornomoye Biswas, 28. She joined Dhaka Stream early this year as a trainee graphic designer.
Sher-e-Bangla Nagar Police Station Sub-Inspector (SI)</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 02:17:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BSRM posts record profit in FY25 on higher sales, lower input costs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/bsrm-posts-record-profit-in-fy25-on-higher-sales-lower-input-costs</link><description>Bangladesh Steel Re-Rolling Mills (BSRM) has secured a record profit in FY25 in a challenging business environment, driven by higher sales and lower input costs.
It earned a consolidated profit of Tk 6.14 billion in the year, a 42 per cent year-on-year increase from the year before, according to a</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 02:32:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Why fresh funds are so urgent</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/why-fresh-funds-are-so-urgent</link><description>The Investment Corporation of Bangladesh (ICB) is hopeful of returning to profit if it gets immediate liquidity support to overcome its liabilities.
The largest investment bank, which is highly dependent on the secondary market for revenue generation, has already shown signs of recovery, securing</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 02:47:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gono Forum signs July Charter</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/gono-forum-signs-july-charter</link><description>The Gono Forum, led by Kamal Hossain, signed Sunday the July National Charter two days after initially refusing to do so at a ceremony held in the Parliament complex due to disagreements over constitutional wording.
With this latest development, 25 political parties and alliances have now signed t</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 03:02:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ACC files case against ex-AL lawmaker Hasanat Abdullah</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/acc-files-case-against-ex-al-lawmaker-hasanat-abdullah</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) has filed a case against former Awami League (AL) lawmaker Abul Hasanat Abdullah, accusing him of accumulating Tk 1.22 billion in illegal assets and engaging in large-scale money laundering over a decade.
According to the case statement, filed by SM Rashedur Re</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 03:17:29 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>