<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 08:34:58 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Bangladesh added to US visa bond scheme requiring payments of up to $15,000</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-added-to-us-visa-bond-scheme-requiring-payments-of-up-to-15000</link><description>Bangladesh has been added to a list of countries whose citizens are required to post a visa bond of up to $15,000 in order to travel to the United States.
Under the policy, applicants from listed countries who are otherwise eligible for B1/B2 visitor visas may be asked to pay a refundable bond bef</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 05:30:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh records season's lowest temperature</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-records-seasons-lowest-temperature</link><description>Bangladesh recorded the lowest temperature of the current winter season on Wednesday.
The season’s lowest temperature of 6.7 degrees Celsius was recorded in Badalgachhi upazila of Naogaon district this morning.
The bone-chilling cold, intensified by icy northern winds, has slowed daily life</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 05:45:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Early results show neck-and-neck race for JnUCSU VP post</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/early-results-show-neck-and-neck-race-for-jnucsu-vp-post</link><description>Preliminary results from seven departments in the Jagannath University Central Students’ Union (JnUCSU) election indicate a closely contested race for the post of vice-president (VP).
Candidates from the Oikkoboddho Nirbhik Jobian panel, backed by Chhatra Dal and Chhatra Odhikar Parishad, ar</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 06:00:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump freezes over $10 billion in childcare, family assistance funds to 5 US states</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-freezes-over-10-billion-in-childcare-family-assistance-funds-to-5-us-states</link><description>US President Donald Trump's administration is freezing more than $10 billion in federal childcare and family assistance funds to California, Colorado, Illinois, Minnesota and New York, the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) said, citing what it called concerns about fraud and misuse.
Th</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 06:15:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NBR launches automated online VAT refund system</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nbr-launches-automated-online-vat-refund-system</link><description>The National Board of Revenue (NBR) on Wednesday launched an automated online Value Added Tax (VAT) refund system, allowing refunds to be transferred directly to taxpayers' bank accounts, a move considered as ending long-standing delays and harassment in the refund process.
NBR Chairman Md Abdur R</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 06:30:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt plans to expand advanced laparoscopic surgery to district level</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/govt-plans-to-expand-advanced-laparoscopic-surgery-to-district-level</link><description>Despite the advent of expensive robotic surgery, laparoscopic and minimally invasive procedures done without opening the abdomen are highly popular in urological treatment.
The government has undertaken a plan to deliver these advanced, affordable services to people’s doorsteps across the co</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 06:15:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh's PMI rises by 0.2 points in December</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/bangladeshs-pmi-rises-by-02-points-in-december</link><description>Bangladesh’s overall Purchasing Managers’ Index (PMI) rose slightly in December, indicating a faster pace of economic expansion, driven mainly by continued growth in agriculture, manufacturing and services, according to the latest PMI report.
PMI increased by 0.2 points in December fro</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 06:30:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nepal city under curfew following Mosque vandalism</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/southern-nepal-border-city-under-curfew-following-mosque-vandalism</link><description>A curfew was imposed on a key border city in southern Nepal after Hindu and Muslim groups began protesting against each other following the vandalism of a mosque over the weekend, officials said Tuesday.
The curfew orders issued by the Parsa District Administration said that no one will be allowed</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 06:45:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Asked Xi to play a mediating role on North Korea</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/asked-xi-to-play-a-mediating-role-on-north-korea</link><description>South Korean President Lee Jae Myung said on Wednesday that much progress had been made in restoring trust with Beijing, and that he had asked Chinese President Xi Jinping to play a role in mediating Seoul's efforts to engage North Korea.
Lee, who held talks with Xi this week, said the Chinese lea</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 07:00:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ongoing cold wave to persist for three to four more days: Met office</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/ongoing-cold-wave-to-persist-for-three-to-four-more-days-met-office</link><description>The current cold wave sweeping parts of the country will continue for three to four more days until January 11, according to the Bangladesh Meteorological Department.
According to the Met Office’s regular bulletin, a mild to moderate cold wave is sweeping over Rajshahi, Rangpur, Khulna and B</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 07:15:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh receives first US corn shipment since 2018</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladesh-receives-first-us-corn-shipment-since-2018</link><description>Bangladesh has received its first consignment of corn from the United States since 2018.
The process of unloading the shipment started at 11:20 am on Wednesday at a jetty on the Karnaphuli River in Chattogram, near the Chittagong Port Authority’s water transport licensing office.
An event m</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 07:30:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India’s top court denies bail to 2 Muslim activists after 5 years in jail without trial</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/indias-top-court-denies-bail-to-2-muslim-activists-after-5-years-in-jail-without-trial</link><description>India’s Supreme Court on Monday denied bail to two Muslim student activists who have spent years in detention without trial over a conspiracy case linked to one of the country’s deadliest outbreaks of religious violence.
Umar Khalid and Sharjeel Imam were arrested five years ago under</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 08:30:46 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>