<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 17:27:36 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Changes likely at top of police administration: Minister Salahuddin</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/changes-likely-at-top-of-police-administration-minister-salahuddin</link><description>Home Minister Salahuddin Ahmed on Sunday said changes are likely at the top level of the police administration.
“Some changes will come, but it will take some time,” he told reporters at the Secretariat after a courtesy meeting at the Prime Minister’s Office.
Speaking about the</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 13:49:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>First batch of BRAC Bank’s Branch Young Leaders graduates</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/first-batch-of-brac-banks-branch-young-leaders-graduates</link><description>BRAC Bank has marked a significant milestone in its talent development journey with the graduation of the first batch of Branch Young Leaders.
This pioneering initiative has been designed to build a strong pipeline of future-ready branch leaders to support the bank’s expanding distribution n</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 14:04:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Army reshuffle brings new DGFI chief</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-army-shake-up-sees-new-cgs-afd-pso-and-dgfi-chief-in-major-command-changes</link><description>A major shake-up at the top levels of the Bangladesh Army has brought new leadership to key posts including the chief of general staff (CGS), principal staff officer (PSO) of the Armed Forces Division (AFD), and the head of the Directorate General of Forces Intelligence (DGFI).
According to a sour</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 14:19:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India, China invites Bangladesh FM to pay official visits</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/india-china-invites-bangladesh-fm-to-pay-official-visits</link><description>India, China and Pakistan on Sunday invited Foreign Minister Dr Khalilur Rahman to pay official visits to the countries at mutually convenient times.
The envoys of China and India extended the invitations on behalf of their respective foreign ministers during separate meetings with the Foreign Min</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 14:34:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BCB bans women’s team selector Manjurul Islam over ‘sexually harassing’ Jahanara</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/cricket/bcb-bans-womens-team-selector-manjurul-islam-over-sexually-harassing-jahanara</link><description>The Bangladesh Cricket Board (BCB) has barred Manjurul Islam from all forms of cricketing activity under its jurisdiction following allegations of sexual harassment made by former women’s team captain Jahanara Alam.
The decision comes after the board reviewed recommendations from an independ</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 14:49:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>21 women among Jamaat’s 88-member new central council</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/21-women-among-jamaats-88-member-new-central-council</link><description>Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami has announced a new 88-member Central Working Council for the 2026–2028 term, including 21 women.
The party said the decision was taken at a virtual meeting of its Central Majlis-e-Shura on 20 February, presided over by its Ameer and Leader of the Opposition in par</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 15:04:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Liberation war foundation of Bangladesh’s freedom: Hafiz Uddin</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/liberation-war-foundation-of-bangladeshs-freedom-hafiz-uddin</link><description>Liberation War Affairs Minister Hafiz Uddin Ahmed Bir Bikram has said the great Liberation War is the fundamental basis of Bangladesh’s freedom.
“It would not be appropriate to equate any other movement or struggle with the Liberation War. We must always remember that the sole foundati</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 15:19:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>150 BNP men sued over blocking MP Rumeen at Shaheed Minar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/150-bnp-men-sued-over-blocking-mp-rumeen-at-shaheed-minar</link><description>A case has been filed against 150 people for allegedly obstructing newly elected MP Rumeen Farhana from paying tribute at the Shaheed Minar in Brahmanbaria and assaulting her supporters.
The majority of the accused are activists of the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) and its affiliate organisat</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 15:28:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Central bank buys $123m through auction</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/central-bank-buys-123m-through-auction</link><description>Bangladesh Bank (BB) on Sunday purchased US$123 million from eight commercial banks through multiple auction methods.
According to central bank data, it bought dollars at the rate of Tk 122.30.
Accordingly, total purchases stood at $1,448 million in February and $5,381.50 million in FY 2025-26 ti</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 15:43:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh Bank relaxes down payment policy for affected borrowers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/bangladesh-bank-relaxes-down-payment-policy-for-affected-borrowers</link><description>Bangladesh Bank (BB) has relaxed its down payment requirements to provide a strategic breather for struggling businesses, allowing affected borrower institutions to pay half of their required down payment initially to facilitate financial reorganization.
According to a directive issued on Sunday b</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 15:58:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Police parade ‘extortionist’, announce arrest via megaphone in Mohammadpur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/police-parade-extortionist-announce-arrest-via-megaphone-in-mohammadpur</link><description>Police have paraded an alleged extortionist through the streets of Mohammadpur after arresting him for demanding illegal tolls from several local businessmen.
The suspect, identified with a single name Faruk alias “Kala Faruk”, was apprehended on Sunday afternoon during a raid in Keran</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 16:13:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh Army undergoes a major reshuffle</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-army-undergoes-a-major-reshuffle</link><description>The Bangladesh Army saw a reshuffle in several key positions on Sunday.
General Officer Commanding (GOC) of the Army Training and Doctrine Command (ARTDOC), Lt Gen Md Mainur Rahman, has been appointed Chief of General Staff of Bangladesh Army, according to the Ministry of Defence.
GOC of the 24 I</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 16:28:36 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>