<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 14:20:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Around 6,000 students in Malaysia infected with influenza, prompting school closures</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/around-6000-students-in-malaysia-infected-with-influenza-prompting-school-closures</link><description>Around 6,000 students in Malaysia have been infected with influenza and some schools have been closed for the safety of children and staff, an education ministry official said.
“We already have extensive experience in dealing with infectious diseases from the COVID-19 pandemic,” direct</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 10:56:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DSE, CSE end lower despite early gains</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/dse-cse-end-lower-despite-early-gains</link><description>Bangladesh’s stock markets ended lower on Tuesday despite a positive start, as most companies saw a decline in share prices by the end of the trading session.
At the end of the day’s trading, the key index of the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE), DSEX, lost 30 points, UNB reports. 
Amo</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 11:11:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Five-Day furniture fair kicks off in Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/five-day-furniture-fair-kicks-off-in-dhaka</link><description>The five-day-long 20th National Furniture Fair 2025 begins on Tuesday in the capital at the Rajdarshan Hall of International Convention City Bashundhara (ICCB) in Kuril, Dhaka
The five-day event is being held across Gul Naksha (Hall—1), Pushpa guccha (Hall—2), and Rajdarshan (Hall&amp;mdas</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 11:41:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chief adviser mourns tragic deaths in Mirpur fire</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/chief-adviser-mourns-tragic-deaths-in-mirpur-fire</link><description>Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus on Tuesday expressed profound shock and sorrow at the tragic deaths of nine people in a devastating fire in a garment factory and chemical warehouse at Shialbari in the city's Mirpur area.
In a condolence message, the Chief Adviser prayed for the eternal peac</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 11:56:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Benapole Port police station without OC for 25 days</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/benapole-port-police-station-without-oc-for-25-days</link><description>Law and order in the country’s largest land port area has reportedly deteriorated as Benapole Port Police Station remains without an officer-in-charge (OC) for the past 25 days.
According to police sources, former OC Russel Mia was transferred on September 19, but no replacement has been app</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 12:11:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCP takes to FB over ‘Shapla’ logo demand</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/facebook-abuzz-with-ncp-leaders-demand-for-shapla-poll-symbol</link><description>The National Citizen Party leaders took to social media to press their demand for the “Shapla”, or water lily, symbol after the Election Commission set a deadline for the party to select a poll logo from its prescribed list.
On Tuesday, NCP Joint Secretary Zahirul Islam Musa posted on</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 12:41:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh Bank buys $2.12 billion from banks so far in FY’26</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/bangladesh-bank-buys-212-billion-to-keep-foreign-exchange-market-stable</link><description>Bangladesh Bank on Tuesday bought US$38 million from six banks as part of continuing efforts to keep the foreign exchange market stable.
After the latest purchase, a total of $2.12 billion was brought from different banks so far in the current fiscal year FY2025-26.
Arif Hossain Khan, Executive D</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 12:56:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP backs same-day polls, referendum plan: Fakhrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-agrees-to-proposal-for-election-referendum-on-same-day-says-fakhrul</link><description>The Bangladesh Nationalist Party has agreed to the National Consensus Commission’s proposal to hold the general election and a referendum on the same day, according to secretary general Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir.
He made the announcement around 3pm on Tuesday while addressing an extended m</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 13:11:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ACC Chief urges political parties not to nominate corrupt individuals in elections</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/acc-chief-urges-political-parties-not-to-nominate-corrupt-individuals-in-elections</link><description>Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) Chairman Dr. Mohammad Abdul Momen on Tuesday urged all political parties not to nominate corrupt individuals in the upcoming elections.
He made the call while addressing the opening ceremony of a day-long workshop organized for members of Reporters Against Corrupti</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 13:26:49 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>