<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 22:21:30 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Alphabet hits $4 trillion valuation as AI refocus lifts sentiment</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/alphabet-hits-4-trillion-valuation-as-ai-refocus-lifts-sentiment</link><description>Alphabet hit a $4 trillion market valuation on Monday, as the Google parent's sharpened artificial intelligence focus allayed doubts about its strategy and thrust it back to the forefront of the high-stakes race.
The tech giant on Wednesday surpassed Apple in market capitalisation for the first ti</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 16:45:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>41 regain candidacy, 24 rejected on third day of appeal hearings</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/41-regain-candidacy-24-rejected-on-third-day-of-appeal-hearings</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has approved 41 petitions on the third day of appeal hearings challenging returning officers’ decisions on nomination papers for the national election.
EC spokesperson Ruhul Amin Mollik said on Monday that 24 petitions were rejected during the hearings, while fou</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 17:00:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ACC files two cases against former CMP CT unit officer, wife and sisters over Tk 611.9 million illicit wealth</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/acc-files-two-cases-against-former-cmp-ct-unit-officer-wife-and-sisters-over-tk-6119-million-illicit-wealth</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) on Monday filed two separate cases against former Deputy Commissioner of Chattogram Metropolitan Police’s Counter Terrorism Unit, Md Hamidul Alam, his wife and three sisters over allegations of acquiring illicit wealth worth Tk61.19 crore.
ACC Director Ge</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 17:16:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>People want jobs plan, not promises, experts say</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/people-want-jobs-plan-not-promises-experts-say</link><description>Employment has emerged as the top concern for Bangladeshis, with citizens expecting political parties to offer clear, realistic and actionable plans rather than vague promises before the general election.
This message came from a roundtable jointly organised by Democracy International (DI) and The</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 17:31:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ICC sees no specific threat to Tigers in India</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/bangladesh-face-no-exceptional-threat-for-t20-wc-participation-in-india-says-icc-review</link><description>The Bangladesh team are not subject to any unusual or serious security risks while playing in India for the 2026 T20 World Cup, according to an ICC assessment shared with the Bangladesh Cricket Board (BCB).
The review identifies low to moderate risk levels at certain venues, which are part of rout</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 17:46:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC bars polls to all bodies, associations before Feb 12 elections done</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-bars-polls-to-all-bodies-associations-before-feb-12-elections-done</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has directed the authorities concerned not to allow elections of any organisation or association, including professional bodies, across the country before the 13th parliamentary election scheduled for February 12, 2026 - the same day as a key referendum. 
The Comm</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 18:01:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Health, education allocations face staggering cut</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/health-education-allocations-face-staggering-cut</link><description>Health and education sectors have taken the major brunt of a sizeable cut in the current development budget halfway through the fiscal year.   
The ongoing Annual Development Programme (ADP) outlay for the fiscal year 2025-26 has been cut by 13.04 per cent to Tk 2.0 trillion.
With</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 18:16:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Beyond open tendering</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/beyond-open-tendering</link><description>As Chairman of the Chittagong Port Authority, I welcome the decisive shift of the Nobel Laureate Dr Muhammad Yunus-led government towards port-centred maritime development as a foundation of Bangladesh's economic transformation. More than 92 per cent of our international trade passes through Chitta</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 18:17:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>When ideology, power, and sport collide</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/reviews/when-ideology-power-and-sport-collide</link><description>The T20 Men's ICC World Cup has transcended being a mere celebration of sporting success. In the Global South, particularly in South Asia, it has become one of the most ardent expressions in this age. It is in this context that the realms of sport and the construction of the post-colony become impo</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 18:32:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BD in troubled waters  of tomorrow</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/bd-in-troubled-waters-of-tomorrow</link><description>As is the usual practice every year, economists and experts on business trends locally and globally have been making their projections and predictions about how the country's as well as the world's economy will fare in the coming year (s). So far as Bangladesh's economy is concerned, much cannot be</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 18:47:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Protecting the deep-sea ecosystem of the Bay</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/protecting-the-deep-sea-ecosystem-of-the-bay</link><description>The deep sea is often imagined as distant, dark and detached from everyday life. In reality, it is one of the planet's most vital ecological frontiers -- and in the Bay of Bengal it is now under serious threat. Bangladesh's deep-sea ecosystem, once resilient and largely unexplored, is showing unmis</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 19:02:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Overcoming economic malaises</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/overcoming-economic-malaises</link><description>The Centre for Policy Dialogue (CPD), a local think tank, has pinpointed the weaknesses of the country's economy and also recommended various measures to overcome those. In fact, the very title of the paper, "State of the Bangladesh Economy in FY2025-26" amply clarifies the objectives of the briefi</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 19:17:12 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>