<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 10:23:17 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Terrifying moments on the tracks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/analysis/terrifying-moments-on-the-tracks</link><description>Trains move on, but some journeys remain unfinished in the mind. In candid conversations with The Financial Express, four veteran locomotive masters of Bangladesh Railway recall moments of fear, bravery, and responsibility on the rails that still haunt them
One night in 2015, I was driving the Dhu</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 06:38:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique meets journalists</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-meets-journalists</link><description>BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman has exchanged greetings with journalists at a party-organised event in Dhaka, marking his first public engagement since formally taking charge of the party.
The programme began at 11:00 am on Saturday at a hotel in Dhaka’s Banani.
Editors of national dailies, chi</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 06:53:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh requests US to ease business travel</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-requests-us-to-ease-business-travel</link><description>National Security Adviser Dr Khalilur Rahman has requested Allison Hooker, US Under Secretary of State for Political Affairs, to ease travel of Bangladeshi businessmen to the US in the context of the recent visa bond move, as he met her at the State Department in Washington, DC, on Friday.
Dr Khal</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 07:08:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh expresses interest in joining Gaza stabilisation force</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-expresses-interest-in-joining-gaza-stabilisation-force</link><description>Bangladesh has expressed interest in being part of an international stabilisation force proposed for deployment in Gaza during meetings between its national security adviser and senior US officials in Washington.
National Security Adviser Khalilur Rahman conveyed the position while meeting Allison</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 07:23:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fakhrul sees new opportunity to build liberal democratic Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/fakhrul-sees-new-opportunity-to-build-liberal-democratic-bangladesh</link><description>BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir on Saturday said a new scope has opened before the nation to build a liberal democratic Bangladesh.
“People are now hopeful as a scope has been created for building a liberal democratic Bangladesh,” he said.
Fakhrul made the remarks wh</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 07:38:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gas valve burst causes pressure drop, disrupting supply across Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/gas-valve-burst-causes-pressure-drop-disrupting-supply-across-dhaka</link><description>A sharp drop in gas pressure has disrupted supply across Dhaka after a key valve exploded on the distribution line.
Residents in areas including Dhanmondi, Mohammadpur, Shyamoli, New Market, Hazaribagh and Gabtoli are receiving little or no gas supply.
State-run distributor Titas Gas said the pro</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 07:53:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tasnim Jara gets back candidacy on appeal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tasnim-jara-gets-back-candidacy-on-appeal</link><description>Tasnim Jara, a former National Citizen Party (NCP) leader, regained her candidacy status on Saturday, the first day of the appeal hearing.
The Election Commission has upheld the candidacies of Tasnim Jara and Jamaat-e-Islami's AHM Hamidur Rahman Azad for the upcoming national election.
The decisi</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 08:08:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>International Conference on Mother Language and Awards 2026 held at Nalanda Open University</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/others/international-conference-on-mother-language-and-awards-2026-held-at-nalanda-open-university</link><description>A two-day international conference focusing on mother language, human rights, peace, and press freedom was held on January 4–5 at Nalanda Open University in Rajgir, Bihar. The event was jointly organized by Nalanda Open University and the SAARC Journalists Forum.
Titled International Confere</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 08:23:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>'We don't want to go back to pre-Aug 5 days': Tarique</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/we-dont-want-to-go-back-to-pre-aug-5-days-tarique</link><description>BNP leader Tarique Rahman has said there is “no reason” for the country to return to the political conditions that existed before the toppling of the Awami League regime on August 5, 2024.
“We don’t want to go back to pre-August 5 days. There’s no reason for us to do</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 08:38:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Titas begins repair work to restore gas supply</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/titas-begins-repair-work-to-restore-gas-supply</link><description>State-run distributor Titas Gas Transmission and Distribution PLC on Saturday began repair work on a damaged gas valve on Mirpur Road and a gas pipeline under the Turag River to restore normal gas supply in the city.
According to a Titas Gas press release issued today, a four-inch diameter valve i</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 08:53:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NASA cuts space station mission due to astronaut's health issue</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/nasa-cuts-space-station-mission-due-to-astronauts-health-issue</link><description>In a rare move, NASA is cutting a mission aboard the International Space Station short after an astronaut had a medical issue.
The space agency said Thursday the US-Japanese-Russian crew of four will return to Earth in the coming days, earlier than planned.
NASA cancelled its first spacewalk of t</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 09:08:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>China, Russia, Iran start 'BRICS Plus' naval exercises in South African waters</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/china-russia-iran-start-brics-plus-naval-exercises-in-south-african-waters</link><description>China, Russia and Iran began a week of joint naval exercises in South Africa's waters on Saturday in what the host country described as a BRICS Plus operation to "ensure the safety of shipping and maritime economic activities".
 
BRICS Plus is an expansion of a geopolitical bloc originally c</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 09:23:23 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>