<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 06:33:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Two killed in Netrokona road crash</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/two-killed-in-netrokona-road-crash46</link><description>Two people were killed and three others injured when a CNG-run auto-rickshaw crashed into a stationary truck on the Netrokona–Mymensingh highway on Thursday night.
The deceased were identified as Abdul Jalil, 45, of China Mor area of Mymensingh, and Shahid Mia, 42, of Asdaati village in Netr</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 03:07:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IDLC Finance secures Q3 profit growth on higher investment income</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/idlc-finance-secures-q3-profit-growth-on-higher-investment-income</link><description>IDLC Finance reported a 34.78 per cent year-on-year rise in profit to Tk 0.68 billion for the third quarter ending in September this year, driven by higher investment income.
The company is among the few non-bank financial institutions (NBFIs) that have managed to contain non-performing loans. H</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 03:22:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ESPN, ABC, other Disney networks go dark on YouTube TV after failed talks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/espn-abc-other-disney-networks-go-dark-on-youtube-tv-after-failed-talks</link><description>Google's YouTube TV said on Thursday Disney's networks, including ESPN and ABC, have gone dark on its platform after the two companies failed to reach a new licensing deal.
"Our contract with Disney has reached its renewal date, and we'll not agree to terms that disadvantage our members while bene</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 03:37:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EBL's business acumen achieves one of lowest NPL ratios</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/ebls-business-acumen-achieves-one-of-lowest-npl-ratios</link><description>Eastern Bank's non-performing loans stood at just 3.07 per cent at the end of September this year, far below the industry average of over 27 per cent as of June.
"Strong focus on asset quality has driven the bank to achieve low non-performing loans," the bank said in a statement on Thursday.
Th</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 03:52:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ACC to sue former Robi official for 'acquiring' illegal assets</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/acc-to-sue-former-robi-official-for-acquiring-illegal-assets</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) has decided to file a case against Md Rakibul Hasan, a former official of Robi Axiata Limited, on charges of acquiring illegal wealth and hiding information about his assets.
ACC Deputy Director Md. Akhtarul Islam on Thursday confirmed that charge-sheet has bee</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 04:07:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Financial autonomy in doubt as separate judiciary secretariat nears reality</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/financial-autonomy-in-doubt-as-separate-judiciary-secretariat-nears-reality</link><description>Although most disagreements over establishing a separate secretariat for the judiciary have been resolved, questions persist over whether it will actually enjoy financial independence.
The uncertainty arises from objections raised by the inter-ministerial committee on legal scrutiny of the Cabin</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 04:22:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DU student suspended for ‘religious defamation’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/du-student-suspended-for-religious-defamation</link><description>Dhaka University (DU) has suspended Abrar Faiyaz, a student of the Department of Computer Science and Engineering (CSE) of the 2021-2022 academic session, for six months over allegations of making remarks defaming religion.
Two other students, Mehtajur Rahman and Tasnia Islam, are also under inv</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 04:37:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US signs 10-year defence pact with India, Hegseth says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-signs-10-year-defence-pact-with-india-hegseth-says</link><description>The United States has signed a 10-year defence framework agreement with India, US Defense Secretary Pete Hegseth said on Friday.
The framework is considered a cornerstone for regional stability and deterrence, enhancing coordination, information sharing and technological cooperation between the tw</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 04:52:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Taiwan does not want China's 'one country, two systems', president says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/taiwan-does-not-want-chinas-one-country-two-systems-president-says</link><description>Taiwan does not want China's "one country, two systems" and must uphold its freedom and democracy, and resolve to defend itself, President Lai Ching-te said on Friday, rejecting Beijing's latest push to get the island to come under Chinese control.
China said this week it "absolutely will not" rul</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 05:22:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Missing man found dead in locked warehouse in Meherpur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/missing-man-found-dead-in-locked-warehouse-in-meherpur</link><description>Police on Thursday recovered the decomposed body of a man, who had gone missing for several days, from a locked warehouse in Gangni upazila of Meherpur district.
The deceased was identified as Biplob Hossain, 52, son of the late Anisur Rahman of Bogura Sadar upazila. He was a carpenter by professi</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 05:37:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Light rain, thundershowers likely in parts of Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/light-rain-thundershowers-likely-in-parts-of-bangladesh</link><description>The Bangladesh Meteorological Department (BMD) has forecast rain or thundershowers with lightning across all divisions, including Dhaka, over the next 24 hours starting 6:00 pm on Friday.
According to a BMD bulletin, “Light to moderate rain or thundershowers is likely at most places over Ran</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 05:52:29 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>