<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 15:25:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Kamal Hossain hospitalised with pneumonia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/gono-forum-chief-kamal-hossain-hospitalised-with-pneumonia</link><description>Kamal Hossain, founder of the Gono Forum, has been admitted to Square Hospital in Dhaka in a critical condition.
Gono Forum General Secretary Mizanur Rahman on Friday said that doctors have diagnosed Kamal with pneumonia.
“[Kamal] is suffering from lung pneumonia. His condition is very seri</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 13:16:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hannan Masud owns five times more wealth than his father</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/hannan-masud-owns-five-times-more-wealth-than-his-father</link><description>NCP leader Abdul Hannan Masud owns five times more wealth than his father, an analysis of affidavits filed by the father-son duo has revealed.
Hannan, 26, is the senior joint chief convenor of the National Citizen Party (NCP).
Both him and his father, Amirul Islam Mohammad Abdul Malek, have filed</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 13:17:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Samsung Electronics says customers praised competitiveness of HBM4 chip</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/samsung-electronics-says-customers-praised-competitiveness-of-hbm4-chip</link><description>Samsung Electronics customers have praised the differentiated competitiveness of its next-generation high-bandwidth memory (HBM) chips, or HBM4, saying "Samsung is back", co-CEO and chip chief Jun Young-hyun said in a New Year address.
In October, Samsung said it was in "close discussion" to suppl</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 13:32:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Yemen's Saudi-backed govt launches operation against UAE-backed separatists</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/yemens-saudi-backed-government-launches-operation-against-uae-backed-separatists</link><description>Yemen's Saudi-backed government launched what it called a peaceful operation to take back military positions from the UAE-backed southern separatists on Friday, who in turn said seven Saudi airstrikes had taken place since the declaration.
The Saudi-backed governor of Yemen's Hadramout province an</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 13:47:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Leaders of 1990’s All-Party Student Alliance offer fateha at Khaleda Zia’s grave</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/leaders-of-1990s-all-party-student-alliance-offer-fateha-at-khaleda-zias-grave</link><description>The leaders of 1990's DUCSU and All-Party Student Alliance on Friday paid tributes to the grave of former prime minister and BNP chairperson Begum Khaleda Zia.
After paying tributes, the then vice-president (VP) of Dhaka University Central Students Union (DUCSU) and the convener of the All-Party S</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 14:02:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Inqilab Moncho sets 22-working-day deadline for trial in Hadi killing</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/inqilab-moncho-sets-22-working-day-deadline-for-trial-in-hadi-killing</link><description>Inqilab Moncho has announced plans to launch a movement to oust the government if the trial over the killing of Sharif Osman bin Hadi is not completed within 22 working days.


The organisation’s Member Secretary Abdullah Al Jaber made the announcement on Friday after</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 14:17:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shoe trader found murdered at Savar home</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/shoe-trader-found-murdered-at-savar-home</link><description>A businessman was murdered by miscreants at his residence in Savar, police said on Friday.
The victim was identified as Delwar Hossain, a shoe trader by profession.
His body was recovered this evening from his house in Baradeshi Uttarpara area under Aminbazar Union of Savar.
According to</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 14:10:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Policewoman ‘takes own life’ in Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/policewoman-kills-herself-at-her-home-in-dhaka</link><description>A policewoman has hanged herself in apparent suicide in Dhaka’s Dakhshinkhan, police say citing her family.
The 28-year-old Rajia Sultana Mim, a Nayek at the Armed Police Battalion (APBn), was a native of Barishal’s Wazirpur.
Police said Rajia hanged herself from the grill on the balc</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 14:25:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Earthquake of magnitude 6.3 strikes southern Mexico</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/earthquake-of-magnitude-63-strikes-southern-mexico</link><description>A magnitude 6.3 earthquake struck the southern Mexican state of Guerrero on Friday, the German Research Center for Geosciences (GFZ) said.
The quake was at a depth of 10 km (6.21 miles), GFZ said.
There was no serious damage in Guerrero reported immediately, Mexico’s President Claudia Shein</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 14:40:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rumeen rues independent run</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/rumeen-farhana-shrugs-twist-of-fate-for-not-riding-bnp-wave</link><description>Rumeen Farhana, a recently expelled leader of the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP), has filed her nomination for the Brahmanbaria-2 constituency as an independent candidate, expressing a sense of irony about her political fate.
During the scrutiny of nomination papers at the Brahmanbaria deputy</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 14:55:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Zelenskiy names spy chief to head presidential administration in big shake-up</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/zelenskiy-names-spy-chief-to-head-presidential-administration-in-big-shake-up</link><description>President Volodymyr Zelenskiy named Ukraine’s defence spy chief as his top adviser on Friday, placing a popular military leader at the centre of decision-making as Kyiv seeks to strengthen its defences against Russia and its hand in U.S.-backed peace talks.
The appointment of Kyrylo Budanov,</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 15:10:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US imposes 1pc tax on cash and money order remittances</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/us-imposes-1pc-tax-on-cash-and-money-order-remittances</link><description>The United Stated has introduced a one per cent tax on money migrants send home to their families in other countries, including Bangladesh.
The new tax took effect from Thursday, the first day of the year.
The tax applies to remittances sent via cash, money order, or any other “cashier&amp;rsqu</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 15:25:23 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>