<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 12:53:56 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>'We must stop unnecessary land acquisition' : Land Adviser Ali Imam</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/we-must-stop-unnecessary-land-acquisition-land-adviser-ali-imam</link><description>Land Adviser Ali Imam Majumder on Tuesday called for responsible land acquisition in Bangladesh, warning that large tracts of land are often acquired without genuine need, putting public resources and local communities at risk.
Speaking at a seminar titled 'Strengthening Institutional Capacity and</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 10:02:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ex-ACC commissioner Jahurul questioned for 3 hours</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/acc-grills-ex-commissioner-jahurul-haque-over-bribery-abuse-of-power-allegations</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) has questioned its former commissioner Md Jahurul Haque for nearly three hours as part of an inquiry into allegations of bribery, abuse of power and forgery.
Jahurul arrived at the ACC headquarters in Segunbagicha around 10:30am on Wednesday, accompanied by his</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 10:17:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Lottery system returns to IPOs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh-restores-lottery-system-for-ipo-share-allocation-under-revised-rules</link><description>The lottery system for allocating shares to investors in initial public offerings has been reinstated in Bangladesh’s capital market.
Officials of the Bangladesh Securities and Exchange Commission (BSEC) say shares of companies coming to the market through IPOs will now be distributed throug</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 10:32:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>6 die in Rangpur over 3 days after ‘drinking bootleg alcohol’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/6-die-in-rangpur-over-3-days-after-drinking-bootleg-alcohol</link><description>Two more people have died of alcohol poisoning after drinking “bootleg alcohol” in Rangpur, leading to a tally of six deaths from alcohol over three days in the district. Two others have been hospitalised.
The bodies were recovered around midnight on Tuesday and sent to Rangpur Medical</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 10:47:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>World Bank raises Bangladesh growth forecast for FY26-27</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/world-bank-raises-bangladesh-growth-forecast-to-61-per-cent-for-fy26-27</link><description>Bangladesh’s medium-term economic outlook has improved, with growth expected to strengthen steadily over the next two fiscal years, according to the World Bank’s latest Global Economic Prospects report.
The report revised up its projections for Bangladesh, forecasting economic growth o</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 10:15:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Siberian doctors held over infant deaths</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/russia-detains-top-doctors-at-siberian-hospital-after-nine-babies-die</link><description>Authorities in Russia have detained the chief doctor and acting head of the intensive care unit at a Siberian maternity hospital after nine newborn babies died in just a few days earlier this month, investigators said on Wednesday.
The deaths have provoked widespread shock and anger in Russia, whe</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 10:30:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Iran warns neighbours it could strike US bases if Washington intervenes in protests</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/iran-warns-neighbours-it-could-strike-us-bases-if-washington-intervenes-in-protests</link><description>Tehran has warned neighbouring countries hosting US troops that it would retaliate against American bases if Washington carries out threats to intervene in protests in Iran, a senior Iranian official told Reuters on Wednesday.
Three diplomats said some personnel had been advised to leave the main</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 10:45:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ICAB to host SAFA International Conference 2026 in Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/icab-to-host-safa-international-conference-2026-in-dhaka</link><description>The Institute of Chartered Accountants of Bangladesh (ICAB) will host SAFA International Conference 2026 in Dhaka on Saturday.
The conference, titled “Next Generation Profession: Converging Ethical AI and Sustainability Reporting,” will bring together a large number of foreign and loca</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 11:00:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>SAARC Journalist Forum President Lama meets former Home Minister Thapa</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/saarc-journalist-forum-president-lama-meets-former-home-minister-thapa</link><description>President of the SAARC Journalist Forum (SJF) Raju Lama met former Nepal Home Minister Ram Bahadur Thapa “Badal” on Wednesday.
During the meeting, SJF President Lama congratulated Thapa on his election as a Vice President of the CPN UML. Thapa was elected as the Vice President of CPN U</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 11:15:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Operation Devil Hunt Phase-2: 67 arrested in 24 hours in Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/operation-devil-hunt-phase-2-67-arrested-in-24-hours-in-dhaka</link><description>Law enforcers have arrested 67 people from different parts of the capital as part of the ongoing Operation Devil Hunt Phase-2 in 24 hours till Wednesday morning.
Among the arrestees, 17 were arrested from Jatrabari, 28 from Mugda, eight each from Rupnagar and Hatirjheel areas and three each from S</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 11:30:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EBL invests Tk 7.4m for Coastal Greening and Climate Resilience on Bhasan Char</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ebl-invests-tk-74m-for-coastal-greening-and-climate-resilience-on-bhasan-char</link><description>Eastern Bank PLC. (EBL) has partnered with NouKollan Foundation Trading Company Ltd. (NKFTCL) to implement a large-scale afforestation and land restoration initiative on Bhasan Char Island.
As part of EBL’s Corporate Social Responsibility (CSR) commitment, the bank will invest BDT 7.4 millio</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 11:45:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Denmark and Greenland to face Vance in high-stakes White House meeting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/denmark-and-greenland-to-face-vance-in-high-stakes-white-house-meeting</link><description>The Danish and Greenlandic foreign ministers will meet with US Vice President JD Vance at the White House on Wednesday following weeks of threats by President Donald Trump to take control of Greenland, an autonomous territory of Denmark.
Trump has said the strategically located and mineral-rich is</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 12:00:48 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>