<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 06:34:34 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Algerian Revolution Day observed in city</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/algerian-revolution-day-observed-in-city</link><description>The Embassy of Algeria in Dhaka on Saturday commemorated the '71st Anniversary of the Start of the Glorious Liberation Revolution of November 1, 1954', marking a defining chapter in Algeria's struggle for independence and human dignity.
The grand event, held at Le Méridien Dhaka, brought to</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 02:55:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Suhrawardy Udyan: Cannabis peddling rampant despite police surveillance</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/suhrawardy-udyan-cannabis-peddling-rampant-despite-police-surveillance</link><description>For the past several months, Shahbagh police have been conducting regular drives to curb anti-social activities, including illicit cannabis peddling, in Suhrawardy Udyan, one of Dhaka's most prominent public places.
In the past month alone, police carried out five separate operations, arresting 28</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 03:10:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Guardian Life, BRAC Univ hold seminar on ins awareness for youth</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/guardian-life-brac-univ-hold-seminar-on-ins-awareness-for-youth</link><description>As part of the government of Bangladesh's nationwide initiative "Tarunnyer Utsab: Customer Service Week 2025," a special seminar titled "Conventional Insurance Plans for Youth" was held at BRAC University on Sunday to raise awareness about insurance and financial literacy among students.
The semin</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 03:25:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Greater awareness on cancer, affordable treatments stressed</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/greater-awareness-on-cancer-affordable-treatments-stressed</link><description>Developing affordable and accessible preventives and curatives to combat non-communicable diseases like caners and heart ailments came under focus when a Singaporean specialist met the Chief Adviser.
A spokesman for the CA Office said Professor Muhammad Yunus made a call for greater awareness on s</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 03:55:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>HC questions legality of setting timeframe for taking cognizance of offence</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hc-questions-legality-of-setting-timeframe-for-taking-cognizance-of-offence</link><description>The High Court (HC) has questioned the legality of the declaration of Section 18 of "The Child Marriage Restraint Act, 2017" that limits a two-year timeframe for taking cognisance of crimes committed against any child.
The High Court on Sunday issued a rule asking the respondents to explain as to</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 04:10:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Crucial bridge lies half-built in Manikganj for over a year</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/crucial-bridge-lies-half-built-in-manikganj-for-over-a-year</link><description>Construction work of a bridge over the Tarail embankment road, connecting Ghior and Harirampur upazilas in Manikganj, has remained suspended for more than a year.
Consequently, several thousand local residents are forced to cross the river using a temporary bamboo bridge every day, risking their l</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 04:25:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>COVID affected traders, unemployed youths to be imparted skill trainning</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/covid-affected-traders-unemployed-youths-to-be-imparted-skill-trainning</link><description>Government development organisation Palli Karma-Sahayak Foundation (PKSF) will finance an initiative taken by its RAISE to provide skills training to 400 COVID-19 affected traders and unemployed youths in Magura at the informal sector.
The orientation programme for the initiative was held on Sunda</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 04:40:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt extends factory licence renewal to five years</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/govt-extends-factory-licence-renewal-to-five-years</link><description>The government has approved a proposal to extend the renewal period for factory, shop, and establishment licences issued by the Department of Inspection for Factories and Establishments (DIFE) from one year to five years.
The change, introduced in the draft amendment to the labour law and recently</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 04:55:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Abdur Rahim Khan takes over as FBCCI administrator</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/abdur-rahim-khan-takes-over-as-fbcci-administrator</link><description>Additional Secretary of the Ministry of Commerce Md. Abdur Rahim Khan has officially taken charge as the Administrator of the country's apex trade body-- Federation of Bangladesh Chambers of Commerce and Industry (FBCCI).
To this effect, the FBCCI issued a press release on Sunday.
The term of for</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 05:10:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Youth urged to spread insurance’s positive impact</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/youth-urged-to-spread-insurances-positive-impact</link><description>Insurance Development and Regulatory Authority (IDRA) Chairman Dr M Aslam Alam has called on the younger generation to explore career opportunities in the insurance industry, highlighting its growing importance to Bangladesh's economy.
"The insurance sector in Bangladesh is expanding rapidly. If o</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 05:25:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rupali Bank slips into deep loss as non-performing loans surge</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/rupali-bank-slips-into-deep-loss-as-non-performing-loans-surge</link><description>Rupali Bank has reported hefty losses for the third quarter through September this year due to rising non-performing loans.
The lone listed state-run lender suffered a loss of Tk 1.68 billion in the quarter to September this year, as against a profit of Tk 31 million in the same quarter a year ago</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 05:40:57 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>