<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 03:24:50 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>BNP leader Shimul Biswas, 3 others injured in Paban road accident</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/bnp-leader-shimul-biswas-3-others-injured-in-paban-road-accident</link><description>Four people, including Shamsur Rahman Shimul Biswas, special assistant to BNP Chairperson and party-nominated candidate for Pabna-5 seat, were injured in a collision between a truck and a microbus in Atgharia upazila of Pabna on Tuesday evening.
The accident occurred around 6pm in Ekdanto area whi</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 17:30:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DU Faculty of Fine Arts admission results released with 11.25pc pass rate</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/du-faculty-of-fine-arts-admission-results-released-with-1125pc-pass-rate</link><description>For the 2025-2026 academic year, 602 students have passed the admission test for Dhaka University's Faculty of Fine Arts undergraduate programme from 5,352 test-takers.
The results released on Tuesday evening show a pass rate of 11.25 percent, bdnews24.com reports. 
Among those who passed, 1</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 17:45:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt on bank borrowing spree for bailout funds</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/govt-on-bank-borrowing-spree-for-bailout-funds</link><description>Government bank borrowing goes ballooning with the fundraising through special auction of bonds and bills to pay for five-in-one Sammilito Islami Bank and possible liquidation of nine hard-up nonbanks.
To meet the fresh financing challenges, amid less-than-expected level of revenue-mobilisation dr</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 18:00:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>PSC overhauls marks structure for 50th BCS preliminary exam</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/psc-overhauls-marks-structure-for-50th-bcs-preliminary-exam</link><description>The Public Service Commission (PSC) has revised the marks distribution for the BCS preliminary examination, releasing the updated syllabus and allocation for the 50th BCS with the changes incorporated.
On Tuesday, the commission published the syllabus and the full breakdown for the 200-mark exam o</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 18:15:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CA greets U-21 hockey team for winning challenger trophy of Junior Hockey World Cup</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/ca-greets-u-21-hockey-team-for-winning-challenger-trophy-of-junior-hockey-world-cup</link><description>Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus today congratulated Bangladesh Youth Hockey team for winning the Challenger Trophy of Junior Hockey World Cup.
In a congratulatory message, he said this achievement has made the nation proud, BSS reports. 
Through hard work, discipline, team solidarity</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 18:30:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Build 'new Bangladesh' with women at forefront</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/build-new-bangladesh-with-women-at-forefront</link><description>Place women at the centre of political and social transformation, the Chief Adviser urges, asserting that a "new Bangladesh must rise with the womenfolk leading the way". Speaking at the 2025 Begum Rokeya Day ceremony in Dhaka on Tuesday, Prof Muhammad Yunus notes that the country still falls short</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 01:27:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ILO defers action about Bangladesh amid political transition</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ilo-defers-action-about-bangladesh-amid-political-transition</link><description>Bangladesh gets a breathing space as the International Labour Organization (ILO) defers until March its decision about further action for nonobservance of three labour rights-related core conventions, sources say.
However, the UN labour agency presses for timely implementation in all priority area</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 01:42:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NBR to bring 4m entities under VAT net in two years</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nbr-to-bring-4m-entities-under-vat-net-in-two-years</link><description>The National Board of Revenue (NBR) has set an ambitious goal to bring four million businesses under VAT registration within the next two years.
This is part of its efforts to expand the VAT net and ensure greater compliance across the country.
NBR Chairman Md Abdur Rahman Khan says the current 6</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 01:57:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BB buys $202m at Tk 122.29 per dollarBB buys $202m at Tk 122.29 per dollar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bb-buys-202m-at-tk-12229-per-dollarbb-buys-202m-at-tk-12229-per-dollar</link><description>The central bank purchased over US$2.50 billion from banks in nearly last five months aiming to encourage both exporters and remitters through keeping the dollar-taka rate stable.
As part of the ongoing intervention, the Bangladesh Bank (BB) bought $202 million more through auction from 13 commerc</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 02:12:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Judiciary functions set to gain new momentum</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/judiciary-functions-set-to-gain-new-momentum</link><description>The judiciary of Bangladesh is set to enter a new phase of efficiency and institutional independence with the promulgation of the Supreme Court Secretariat Ordinance 2025, a long-awaited reform that grants full financial and administrative autonomy to the apex court.
The landmark Ordinance reshape</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 02:27:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No street protest after poll schedule announced</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/no-street-protest-after-poll-schedule-announced</link><description>Bangladesh's interim government urges political groups, activists and the public to desist from staging unauthorised protests and street gatherings once the timetable for national elections is announced, or else illegal assemblies will invite legal action.
Schedule is expected within days for the</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 02:42:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>5-yr bond yield rises</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/5-yr-bond-yield-rises</link><description>The yield on five-year treasury bonds edged up on Tuesday, signalling higher government borrowing from the banking system in the coming months to help finance the budget deficit, officials said.
The cut-off yield, commonly referred to as interest rate, on Bangladesh Government Treasury Bonds (BGTB</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 02:57:39 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>