<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 18:36:59 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Bangladeshis in Qatar instructed to avoid military zones</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladeshis-in-qatar-instructed-to-avoid-military-zones</link><description>The Bangladesh embassy in Qatar has issued an urgent security advisory for its expatriates, instructing them to stay away from military installations and remain indoors following a major military escalation involving Iran, Israel, and the United States.
The notice, issued Saturday, comes in the wa</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 15:11:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Iran defence minister, Guards commander 'killed' in Israeli strikes</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/iran-defence-minister-guards-commander-killed-in-israeli-strikes</link><description>Iran's Defence Minister Amir Nasirzadeh and Revolutionary Guards commander Mohammed Pakpour are believed to have been killed in Israeli attacks, two sources familiar with Israel's military operations and one regional source said.</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 15:26:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Political parties should work to change people's fortune: PM</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/political-parties-should-work-to-change-peoples-fortune-pm</link><description>Prime Minister Tarique Rahman today said political parties should take an oath to work together to change the destiny of the countrymen.
"The people of Bangladesh are now looking to all of us, especially to the political parties, with great hope and aspirations. Today, at this Iftar mahfil, let's</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 15:41:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Will extend full support to all reasonable govt steps: Jamaat Ameer</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/will-extend-full-support-to-all-reasonable-govt-steps-jamaat-ameer</link><description>Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami Ameer Dr Shafiqur Rahman on Saturday said his party will extend full support to all reasonable initiatives taken by the government by playing a constructive and responsible role in Parliament.
The Jamaat Ameer made the remarks while addressing an iftar mahfil at the Bang</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 15:56:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCP may lead Bangladesh one day, says home minister</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ncp-may-lead-bangladesh-one-day-says-home-minister</link><description>Home Minister Salahuddin Ahmed says the future of the National Citizen Party (NCP) is promising, suggesting that the youth-led organisation could one day ascend to state power.
Speaking at a discussion and Iftar party marking the party’s first anniversary at Dhanmondi’s Abahani Club gr</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 16:11:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Oil and gas majors and traders suspend shipments via Hormuz</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/oil-and-gas-majors-and-traders-suspend-shipments-via-hormuz</link><description>Some oil majors and top trading houses have suspended crude oil, fuel and liquefied natural gas (LNG) shipments via the Strait of Hormuz as the US and Israel attack Iran and Tehran retaliates, four trading sources said on Saturday.
"Our ships will stay put for several days," one top executive at a</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 16:26:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Israel strikes two schools in Iran, killing more than 50 people</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/israel-strikes-two-schools-in-iran-killing-more-than-50-people</link><description>An Israeli strike has hit an elementary girls’ school in Minab, a city in the Hormozgan province of southern Iran, killing at least 53 people, according to state media, as the immediate civilian cost from Israel and the United States’s huge bombardment of Iran comes into sharper focus.</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 16:41:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Russia slams Trump, Israel for ‘irresponsible attack’ on Iran</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/russia-slams-trump-israel-for-irresponsible-attack-on-iran</link><description>Russia on Saturday criticised US President Donald Trump and Israel for embarking on a dangerously irresponsible attack on Iran which Moscow said was plunging the entire Middle East into the abyss.
The United States and Israel launched strikes on Iran, targeting its leadership and plunging the Midd</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 16:56:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Supreme leader is alive as far as I'm aware: Iran's foreign minister</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/supreme-leader-is-alive-as-far-as-im-aware-irans-foreign-minister</link><description>Iranian Foreign Minister Abbas Araghchi said Iran’s Supreme Leader, Ayatollah Seyyed Ali Khamenei, is alive “as far as I know,” speaking in an interview with NBC following US and Israeli strikes, CNN reports. 
“Almost all officials are safe and sound and alive,”</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 17:11:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Footpaths to be cleared in an orderly way through dialogue after eid: Rabiul Alam</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/footpaths-to-be-cleared-in-an-orderly-way-through-dialogue-after-eid-rabiul-alam</link><description>Footpaths in the city will be freed from illegal occupation in a planned and orderly manner through dialogue with city authorities, traders and hawkers after Eid-ul-Fitr, said Road Transport and Bridges, Railways, and Shipping Minister Sheikh Rabiul Alam on Saturday.
He made the remarks while inau</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 17:26:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gold posts massive Tk 7,640 single-day hike in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/gold-posts-massive-tk-7640-single-day-hike-in-bangladesh</link><description>Gold prices in Bangladesh surged by Tk 7,640 per bhori in a single day as the Bangladesh Jewellers Association (BAJUS) revised rates twice on Saturday, setting the price of 22-carat gold at Tk 268,680 per bhori (11.664 grams).
BAJUS first announced a Tk 4,374 hike in the morning and later raised t</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 17:41:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka deeply concerned over safety of Bangladeshis in Middle East</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/dhaka-deeply-concerned-over-safety-of-bangladeshis-in-middle-east</link><description>Bangladesh on Saturday expressed deep concern over the welfare of its citizens in the Middle East in the wake of recent hostilities in the region including Iran.
Bangladesh has already initiated actions to ensure the safety and security of its premises in Tehran, its diplomats and other staff in t</description><pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 17:56:25 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>