<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 23:21:44 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Death toll in South Africa’s latest pub shooting rises to 10</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/africa/death-toll-in-south-africas-latest-pub-shooting-rises-to-10</link><description>The death toll in South Africa ’s latest mass shooting at a pub rose to 10 on Tuesday, while police said they had identified two potential suspects.
Three women and seven men were killed in Sunday’s early-morning assault in the township of Bekkersdal, 46 kilometers (28 miles) west of J</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 15:30:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Vietnam-Bangladesh direct flights likely from 2026</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/vietnam-bangladesh-direct-flights-likely-from-2026</link><description>Vietnamese Ambassador to Bangladesh Nguyen Manh Cuong has said the aviation authorities in Bangladesh and Vietnam are now in the final stage of considering the new Air Services Agreement which will facilitate the establishment of official direct flight connecting Hanoi and Dhaka in 2026.
Once the</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 15:45:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fight over sandbar control claims 5 lives</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/robber-groups-clash-for-control-supremacy-over-sandbar-killing-five-members</link><description>A gunbattle between two “robber gangs” in Noakhali’s Hatia for occupying land and establishing control in a sandbar has left five dead and 10 others injured.
The shootout took place at Jaglar Char on Tuesday morning between two robber gangs, said Abu Taib Md Arif Hossain, an addi</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 16:00:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BGMEA recommends factory closures in Tongi, Gazipur on Tarique’s return day</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bgmea-recommends-factory-closures-in-tongi-gazipur-on-tariques-return-day</link><description>he Bangladesh Garment Manufacturers and Exporters Association (BGMEA), an organisation of traders in the sector, has suggested declaring a holiday for ready-made garment factories in Dhaka’s Tongi and Gazipur on Dec 25, the day BNP leader Tarique Rahman is set to return to the country.
In a</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 16:35:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientific awareness still limited in Bangladesh: Dr Firdausi Qadri</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/scientific-awareness-still-limited-in-bangladesh-dr-firdausi-qadri</link><description>Eminent scientist Dr Firdausi Qadri, renowned for her contributions to vaccine innovation, testing and deployment as well as infectious disease research in Bangladesh with ICDDR, B, has said that awareness about science in the country remains limited, although gradual progress is taking place.
She</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 16:50:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cambodia backs Bangladesh's ASEAN dialogue partner bid</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cambodia-backs-bangladeshs-asean-dialogue-partner-bid</link><description>Cambodia has reaffirmed its support for Bangladesh's bid to become an ASEAN Sectoral Dialogue Partner, underlining the importance of sustained engagement with ASEAN during the first-ever Foreign Office Consultations between the two countries.
The assurance was conveyed at the inaugural Foreign Off</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 17:05:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Krishak Dal leader killed in Sylhet road crash</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/krishak-dal-leader-killed-in-sylhet-road-crash</link><description>Iron Mia, 50, convener of the Bishwanath Upazila unit of Bangladesh Jatiotabadi Krishak Dal, was killed in a road accident at Nazirbazar in Dakshin Surma, Sylhet.
The accident occurred at around 6:30 pm on Tuesday.
Irun Mia was a resident of Naogaon village in Bishwanath upazila, reports UNB.
Ac</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 17:52:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt releases electoral song produced for Dhaka division</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-releases-electoral-song-produced-for-dhaka-division</link><description>Ahead of the upcoming parliamentary election and referendum, the Ministry of Cultural Affairs has produced eight songs for the country's eight divisions.
The song produced for the Dhaka division was released today, said the Chief Adviser's Press Wing on Tuesday night, reports BSS.
The song has be</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 18:07:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>When politics &amp; journalism become dangerous</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/when-politics-journalism-become-dangerous</link><description>The country has plunged into another upheaval again– suspected by many as an ominous sign of conspiratorial machinations. The countrywide unified protests did not begin with attacks on newspaper offices or assaults on journalists. It began with the shooting and killing of the young political</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 18:24:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ADP implementation in a shambles</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/adp-implementation-in-a-shambles</link><description>For years, poor implementation of Bangladesh's Annual Development Programme (ADP) has remained a recurring concern, despite ever-expanding budgets and ambitious targets. The Ministry of Planning has candidly acknowledged that flawed project design and absence of competent project directors lie at t</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 18:39:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A fresh shot in the Karnaphuli Tunnel's arm!</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/a-fresh-shot-in-the-karnaphuli-tunnels-arm</link><description>The 3.32 km Karnaphuli Tunnel, South Asia's first underwater river tunnel connecting the port city of Chattogram with Anwara upazila, aimed at increasing connectivity and boost trade, has turned out to be a white elephant. The reason is that the forecasts about the project's earning from the toll t</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 18:54:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Higher taxing of billionaires likely to narrow inequality</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/higher-taxing-of-billionaires-likely-to-narrow-inequality</link><description>Ramping up the tax incidence on high-net-worth individuals (HNWI) is under government strategy to narrow widening income inequality in Bangladesh as the Gini index is getting imbalanced.



Medium and Long-term Revenue Strategy (MLTRS) for the financial year 2025-26 to FY2034-35, published by t</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 19:09:49 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>