<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 12:38:16 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Jamaat fully prepared with candidates in all 300 seats: Mia Parwar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-fully-prepared-with-candidates-in-all-300-seats-mia-parwar</link><description>Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami has completed selecting candidates for contesting in all 300 constituencies in the upcoming national elections, announced the party’s secretary general and former MP Mia Golam Parwar on Friday.
“Every Jamaat worker must now go on the ground and work with full</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 10:18:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Saudi Arabia launches new licensing system for Hajis’ accommodation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/saudi-arabia-launches-new-licensing-system-for-hajis-accommodation</link><description>The Ministry of Hajj and Umrah of Saudi Arabia has announced a new licensing system for pilgrim accommodations in Makkah and Medina for the 2026 Hajj season.
Licences will now be issued through the temporary hostel licensing service, developed in collaboration with the Ministry of Tourism and the</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 10:48:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat protests Israeli attack on Gaza flotilla</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jamaat-rallies-in-dhaka-to-protest-israeli-attack-on-gaza-aid-flotilla</link><description>Jamaat-e-Islami has staged a protest march in Dhaka to condemn the Israeli attack on a flotilla carrying aid to Gaza.
The demonstration began with a brief gathering on Friday at the north gate of Baitul Mukarram National Mosque after Jummah prayers and ended near Shantinagar. The march was organis</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 11:03:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No legal barrier to implementing the July Charter: Attorney General</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/no-legal-barrier-to-implementing-the-july-charter-attorney-general</link><description>Attorney General Md Asaduzzaman on Friday said there is no legal barrier to implementing the July Charter and that it can proceed in line with the recommendations of the National Consensus Commission.
He made the remarks while talking to journalists following a view-exchange meeting with local med</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 11:33:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>YouTube to pay $24.5 million to settle Trump account suspension suit</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/youtube-to-pay-245-million-to-settle-trump-account-suspension-suit</link><description>Alphabet-owned YouTube has agreed to pay $24.5 million to settle a lawsuit that U.S. President Donald Trump brought against the company over the suspension of his account following the January 2021 U.S. Capitol riots, a court filing showed on Monday.
The deal makes Google the last of the three big</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 11:23:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prof Yunus at UNGA: Press Secretary outlines 6 key achievements</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/prof-yunus-at-unga-press-secretary-outlines-6-key-achievements</link><description>Chief Adviser’s Press Secretary Shafiqul Alam on Friday listed six major achievements during Chief Adviser Prof Muhammad Yunus’ recent UNGA tour, including his government’s democratic commitment and vision for a collaborative future.
Prof Yunus led Bangladesh’s high-level d</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 11:38:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Elon Musk becomes world’s first half-trillionaire</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/elon-musk-becomes-worlds-first-half-trillionaire</link><description>Elon Musk on Wednesday became the first person to surpass $500 billion in net worth, powered by a rebound in Tesla's share price this year and swelling valuations of his other tech ventures.
The milestone comes just under a year after Musk's net worth crossed $400 billion and underscores his lead</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 11:53:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Israel intercepts last Gaza flotilla boat, begins deportations</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/israel-intercepts-last-gaza-flotilla-boat-begins-deportations</link><description>The Israeli military intercepted the last boat in an aid flotilla attempting to reach blockaded Gaza on Friday, a day after stopping most of the vessels and detaining some 450 activists including Swedish campaigner Greta Thunberg.
The organisers of the Global Sumud Flotilla said the Marinette was</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 12:23:16 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>