<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 14:48:47 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Bangladesh to seek delay in LDC graduation, says Commerce Minister</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladesh-to-seek-delay-in-ldc-graduation-says-commerce-minister</link><description>The newly elected BNP government will take necessary steps to defer Bangladesh’s graduation from the Least Developed Country (LDC) status, Commerce Minister Khandaker Abdul Muktadir said on Wednesday.
“We will take all required measures to defer the LDC graduation. Work on the matter h</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 13:39:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>PM’s address to nation rescheduled for 9:45 pm</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/pms-address-to-nation-rescheduled-for-945-pm</link><description>Prime Minister Tarique Rahman's maiden address to the nation has been rescheduled for 9.45pm on Wednesday, according to a press release issued by the Information and Broadcasting ministry this evening.
Bangladesh Television (BTV) will telecast the speech live while all television channels have bee</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 12:10:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt won’t allow a patronage economy to continue: Finance Minister</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/govt-wont-allow-a-patronage-economy-to-continue-finance-minister</link><description>Finance and Planning Minister Amir Khasru Mahmud Chowdhury on Wednesday underscored the need for the democratisation of the country’s economy so that its benefits reach all the people.
“We can’t allow a patronage economy to continue,” the minister told newsmen at his Bangla</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 12:25:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Women entrepreneurs share their journeys ahead of SME fair</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/women-entrepreneurs-share-their-journeys-ahead-of-sme-fair</link><description>Women entrepreneurs have underscored the importance of resilience, institutional backing, and family support in overcoming barriers and sustaining their businesses, as they shared their journeys ahead of an upcoming SME fair organised by MIDAS.
They were speaking at a one-day CMSME Market Readines</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 12:40:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Arrest warrant issued against UK MP Tulip</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-court-issues-arrest-warrant-for-uk-mp-tulip-over-gulshan-flat-scam</link><description>A Dhaka court has issued an arrest warrant against British Labour MP Tulip Siddiq in a corruption case over a flat in Gulshan.
Metropolitan Senior Special Judge Md Sabbir Faiz passed the order on Wednesday after taking cognisance of the charge sheet filed by the Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC).</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 12:55:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chicken, chickpeas, fruit prices jump in Dhaka before Ramadan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/chicken-chickpeas-fruit-prices-jump-in-dhaka-before-ramadan</link><description>The prices of chicken, chickpeas and fruits have surged in Dhaka’s kitchen markets ahead of Ramadan, driven by rising demand and tighter supplies, adding fresh strain on household budgets.
A visit to several markets in the capital on Wednesday found that the prices of chickpeas, lentils, pou</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 13:10:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Media leaders urge unity, action over attacks on Prothom Alo and Daily Star</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/media-leaders-urge-unity-action-over-attacks-on-prothom-alo-and-daily-star</link><description>Condemning the recent attacks on media outlets, senior journalists, newspaper owners and other stakeholders on Wednesday underscored the need for strengthening unity among them to face any challenges in the coming days.
They also urged the government to take necessary steps against the people dire</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 13:25:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ishraque wages ‘war’ against price-gouging before Ramadan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ishraque-wages-war-against-price-gouging-before-ramadan</link><description>State Minister for Liberation War Affairs Ishraque Hossain has pledged strict action against market syndicates and those hoarding goods to spike prices during Ramadan.
He announced on Wednesday on his verified Facebook page his zero-tolerance policy against those creating artificial crises and inc</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 13:40:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two bodies found dead on Cox’s Bazar beach</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/two-bodies-found-dead-on-coxs-bazar-beach</link><description>Police recovered the bodies of a young man and a young woman from a beach along the Marine Drive road in Teknaf upazila of Cox’s Bazar on Wednesday.
One of the bodies was found near Uttar Lombrori and another near Mitapani Chhara boat terminal areas.
Locals spotted the bodies and informed p</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 13:55:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Police deliver credible, acceptable election with utmost sincerity: DMP Commissioner</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/police-deliver-credible-acceptable-election-with-utmost-sincerity-dmp-commissioner</link><description>Sheikh Md Sazzat Ali, Commissioner of the Dhaka Metropolitan Police (DMP), on Wednesday said the police have delivered a free, fair and widely acceptable election with the highest level of sincerity and dedication.
He made the remarks while addressing DMP members as the chair at the monthly crime</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 14:10:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>By-elections to Bogura-6, Sherpur-3 soon after Eid: EC Masud</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/by-elections-to-bogura-6-sherpur-3-soon-after-eid-ec-masud</link><description>The Election Commission will hold by-elections to two parliamentary seats – Bogura-6 and Sherpur-3— soon after Ramadan.
“We don’t want any election in (the month of) Ramandan. We’ll arrange by-elections to the vacant parliamentary seats soon after the Eid-ul Fitr,&amp;rdq</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 14:25:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prime Bank, Hyatt Place Dhaka Uttara sign deal to offer exclusive deal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/prime-bank-hyatt-place-dhaka-uttara-sign-deal-to-offer-exclusive-deal</link><description>Prime Bank PLC has signed a strategic partnership agreement with Hyatt Place Dhaka Uttara to offer an exclusive deal including Buy One Get One (B1G1) offer.  In this regard a signing ceremony was recently held at Hyatt Place Dhaka Uttara, according to a press release.
Under this agreement, fr</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 14:40:09 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>