<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 12:34:52 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>All vessels approaching Gaza together after regrouping in middle of sea: Shahidul Alam</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/all-vessels-approaching-gaza-together-after-regrouping-in-middle-of-sea-shahidul-alam</link><description>Bangladeshi photographer Shahidul Alam has said the vessel Conscience, a participant of Gaza-bound vessels under the global initiative Freedom Flotilla Coalition (FFC) and Thousands Madleens to Gaza (TMTG), is now approaching together to Gaza together with other boats in the initiative.
In a Faceb</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 11:23:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP won’t bow to any party's will: Salahuddin</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-wont-bend-to-any-political-partys-will-says-salahuddin</link><description>BNP leader Salahuddin Ahmed has insisted the party will not yield to pressure from any political party.
Speaking at an event on Saturday, marking the 36th founding anniversary of the National Democratic Party (NDP), an organisation within the BNP-led alliance “Jatiyatabadi Samamona Jote&amp;rdqu</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 10:34:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rizvi slams India for depicting Dr Yunus as ‘Asur’ during Durga Puja</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/rizvi-slams-india-for-depicting-dr-yunus-as-asur-during-durga-puja</link><description>BNP Senior Joint Secretary General Ruhul Kabir Rizvi on Saturday criticised India for displaying ‘poor taste’ by making an idol of the demon ‘Asur’ with the face of Chief Adviser Dr Muhammad Yunus during Durga Puja celebrations.
“We have seen that in India, an idol of</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 11:04:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ramadan may begin on Feb 19: UAE astronomers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/uae-astronomers-predict-ramadan-will-begin-on-feb-19-across-middle-east</link><description>Astronomers have predicted that Ramadan will begin on Feb 19, a Thursday, in the UAE and other Middle Eastern countries.
Ibrahim Al Jarwan, chairman of the Emirates Astronomy Society, said, according to preliminary calculations, the new moon for Ramadan will occur at 4:01pm on Feb 17 in UAE time,</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 11:34:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>French PM plans new tax on people earning over 250,000 euros a year, Les Echos says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/french-pm-plans-new-tax-on-people-earning-over-250000-euros-a-year-les-echos-says</link><description>French Prime Minister Sebastien Lecornu plans a tax targeting individuals with annual incomes of over 250,000 euros to try to win the Socialist opposition’s backing for his government’s 2026 state budget, financial daily Les Echos said on Saturday.
Les Echos reported that Lecornu plans</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 11:49:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Another candidate pulls out of ‘farcical’ BCB polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/another-candidate-pulls-out-of-farcical-bcb-polls</link><description>Another candidate, Councillor of the Rajshahi Divisional Sports Association Hasibul Alam, has withdrawn candidacy for the Bangladesh Cricket Board (BCB) election, citing fears of rigging.
He was running for a director’s post from Rajshahi. On Saturday, he arrived at the BCB office and declar</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 12:19:52 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>