<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 12:35:57 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Disagreements are natural in politics, Adviser Rizwana says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/disagreements-are-natural-in-politics-adviser-rizwana-says</link><description>Environment Adviser Syeda Rizwana Hasan on Sunday said differences of opinion between political parties are natural and should be viewed as an essential part of the democratic process.
"If one political party disagrees with another on a certain issue, that's not far off as earlier many major parti</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 09:41:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AL cannot participate in next polls: EC Anwarul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/al-cannot-participate-in-next-polls-ec-anwarul</link><description>Election Commissioner Md. Anwarul Islam Sarker today (Sunday) said Awami League will not be able to participate in the next elections.
“Legally, the activities of Awami League are suspended. Therefore, they will not be able to participate in the next election,” he told reporters after</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 09:56:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fakhrul pledges to nationalise MPO-listed institutions if BNP returns to power</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/fakhrul-pledges-to-nationalise-mpo-listed-institutions-if-bnp-returns-to-power</link><description>BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir on Sunday assured that their party will give priority to the nationalisation of MPO-listed educational institutions if it returns to power in the next election.
The BNP leader gave the assurance during a meeting with leaders of the Jatiyakaran Ando</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 10:26:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP permitted to buy two bulletproof vehicles ahead of election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bnp-permitted-to-buy-two-bulletproof-vehicles-ahead-of-election</link><description>The BNP has received government approval to purchase two bulletproof vehicles ahead of the 13th National Parliamentary Election.
The Ministry of Home Affairs approved the purchase to ensure the security of BNP Chairperson Khaleda Zia and acting Chairman Tarique Rahman during the party’s elec</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 10:41:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ACC sues ex-MP Abul Hasanat for Tk 1.22b graft, laundering</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/acc-sues-ex-mp-abul-hasanat-for-tk-122b-graft-laundering</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) has filed a case against former Awami League lawmaker Abul Hasanat Abdullah, accusing him of amassing Tk 1.22 billion in illegal assets and engaging in large-scale money laundering over more than a decade.
According to the case statement filed by SM Rashedur Re</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 10:56:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>RUCSU building being renovated for newly elected leaders</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rucsu-building-being-renovated-for-newly-elected-leaders</link><description>After 35 years, the long-awaited Rajshahi University Central Students’ Union (RUCSU) election concluded yesterday, with Islami Chhatra Shibir-backed candidates achieving a landslide victory.
Of the 23 central positions, Shibir’s panel won 20, including vice-president (VP) and assistant</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 11:26:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Police halt teachers’ ‘Hunger March’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/mpo-teachers-forced-to-abandon-hunger-march-to-ministry-for-police-blockade</link><description>MPO-registered teachers and staff campaigning for a 20 percent basic salary increase, higher house rent allowances, and the nationalisation of all private educational institutions have been prevented from carrying out a “Hunger March” by law-enforcing agencies.
On Sunday, as the march</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 11:41:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>After army coup, Madagascar’s Gen Z demand a voice in shaping what comes next</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/africa/after-army-coup-madagascars-gen-z-demand-a-voice-in-shaping-what-comes-next</link><description>When an elite army colonel joined Madagascar’s Gen Z protests earlier this month, forcing the president to flee the country, youth-movement leader Olivia Rafetison was happy to have the protection of men with guns, after weeks of state repression.
“He said: ‘we’re for the p</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 12:11:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DSEX falls close to 5,000-point level amid persistent losses</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/dsex-falls-close-to-5000-point-level-amid-persistent-losses</link><description>The key index of the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) has fallen close to the 5,000-point level amid persistent losses, raising concerns among investors that the DSEX could slip below the threshold if the downturn continues.
On Sunday, the first trading day of the week, indices at both the DSE and the C</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 12:26:43 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>