<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 07:21:16 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Acute crisis of non-urea fertilisers hits winter vegetable farming</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/acute-crisis-of-non-urea-fertilisers-hits-winter-vegetable-farming</link><description>Several thousand farmers in five upazilas of Lalmonirhat district have become very much frustrated as they are facing acute crisis of various non-urea fertilisers in the current seasons.
The farmers are now very much busy cultivating different winter vegetables.
Many of them cultivated early-vari</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 03:15:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Global and local challenges weigh heavily on RMG export</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/global-and-local-challenges-weigh-heavily-on-rmg-export</link><description>The export performance of the readymade garment (RMG) sector, the country's largest foreign currency earner, has been severely affected by multiple factors, including new US tariffs, a sluggish global economy, and local challenges in securing complex, small-sized orders, industry insiders say.
The</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 03:30:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BTRC to hold public hearing on telecom services on Nov 25</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/btrc-to-hold-public-hearing-on-telecom-services-on-nov-25</link><description>The Bangladesh Telecommunication Regulatory Commission (BTRC) on November 25 will hold a public hearing to receive opinions, complaints, questions and recommendations from consumers, service providers, professionals and other stakeholders regarding the performance of telecommunication services and</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 03:45:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ACC to sue 5 recruiting agencies over Tk 3.14b embezzlement</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/acc-to-sue-5-recruiting-agencies-over-tk-314b-embezzlement</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) has decided to file cases against five more recruiting agencies and 26 individuals on charges of embezzling and laundering Tk 3.14 billion in the name of sending workers to Malaysia.
Md Akhter Hossain, Director General (Prevention) of the ACC, told reporters on</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 04:00:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Former Sramik Dal leader shot dead in Ctg</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/former-sramik-dal-leader-shot-dead-in-ctg</link><description>A local leader of Bangladesh latiotabadi Sramik Dal was shot dead by unidentified assailants in Rangunia Upazila on Thursday night.
The deceased was identified as Abdul Mannan, 40, son of Md. Nazer Sawdagar of Ward No. 3. He served as the vice-president of the Sarafbhata Union unit of Sramik Dal,</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 03:46:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Teen drowns in Turag River while fleeing after 'setting bus on fire' in Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/teen-drowns-in-turag-river-while-fleeing-after-setting-bus-on-fire-in-dhaka</link><description>A teenager drowned in the Turag River on Thursday night while fleeing an angry crowd after allegedly setting an empty bus on fire at Mirpur.
The deceased was identified as Sayyaf, 18. Another youth, Rudro Mohammad Nahian Amir Sani, 18, was detained at the scene, while a third suspect managed to es</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 04:01:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ronaldo shown first red card for Portugal in 22 years</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/football/ronaldo-shown-first-red-card-for-portugal-in-22-years</link><description>Portugal's long-time talisman Cristiano Ronaldo was asked to walk off after he was shown a red card for elbowing Ireland defender Dara O'Shea in the second half of the FIFA World Cup 2026 qualifier on Thursday night.
As a result of this, the 40-year-old is now in some serious danger of being banne</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 04:16:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pickup van torched in Dhaka’s Ashulia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/pickup-van-torched-in-dhakas-ashulia</link><description>A pickup van parked on the side of the road in Dhaka’s Ashulia has been set on fire.
The incident occurred in front of Modular Garments in Ashulia’s Sarkar Market area around 5:00 am on Friday, according to Abu Sayem Masum, senior station officer of the Zirabo Modern Fire Service.
No</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 04:31:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US approves potential $330m military sale to Taiwan, first under Trump</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-approves-potential-330-million-military-sale-to-taiwan-first-under-trump</link><description>The US approved the possible sale to Taiwan of fighter jet spare and repair parts for $330 million, the Pentagon said late on Thursday, marking the first such potential transaction since President Donald Trump took office in January.
"The proposed sale will improve the recipient's capability to me</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 04:46:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DU chemistry professor accused of sexually harassing male students</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/du-chemistry-professor-accused-of-sexually-harassing-male-students</link><description>Students of Dhaka University’s Chemistry Department have accused Professor Md Ershad Halim of sexually harassing several male students.
The allegations were raised at a press conference held on Thursday night at the Dhaka University Journalists’ Association (DUJA) office, where student</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 05:01:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BBC apologises to Trump over speech edit but rejects defamation claim</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/bbc-apologises-to-trump-over-speech-edit-but-rejects-defamation-claim</link><description>The British Broadcasting Corporation sent a personal apology to US President Donald Trump on Thursday but said there was no legal basis for him to sue the public broadcaster over a documentary his lawyers called defamatory.
The documentary, which aired on the BBC's "Panorama" news programme just b</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 06:12:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Türkiye bans 102 footballers over betting scandal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/football/turkiye-bans-102-footballers-over-betting-scandal</link><description>Türkiye's football authorities have handed temporary bans to 102 professional players as part of a widening investigation into illegal betting activities.
The Professional Football Disciplinary Board of the Turkish Football Federation (TFF) on Thursday suspended 25 players from the Super Lig</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 06:27:34 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>