<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 07:51:40 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Despite strong profits, Biman's total assets decline for third straight year</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/despite-strong-profits-bimans-total-assets-decline-for-third-straight-year</link><description>Despite repeated claims by Biman Bangladesh Airlines that it has remained profitable over the five consecutive years, the national carrier's total assets have continued to decline.
According to the airline's latest audited financial statements, total assets stood at Tk 168.72 billion at the end of</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 04:16:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Miscreants vandalise BNP office in Natore</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/miscreants-vandalise-bnp-office-in-natore</link><description>Miscreants vandalised a local BNP office in Naldianga upazila of Natore on Monday evening.
Rakib Hossain, a local Jubo Dal leader, said a group of assailants attacked the BNP office at Ward No. 9 in Chatarbhag Market of Brakhpur Union and caused extensive damage.
The incident occurred during Ifta</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 04:31:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fire guts valuables at Khulna shopping mall</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fire-guts-valuables-at-khulna-shopping-mall</link><description>A fire gutted the valuables of five shops at Baitun Nur Shopping Complex near New Market in Khulna city early Tuesday.
Witnesses said the fire started around 11:30 pm, and locals informedthe  Khulna Fire Service immediately.
Six fire units of Khulna Fire Service brought the blaze under contr</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 04:46:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Seven die as Delhi-bound air ambulance crashes in Jharkhand</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/seven-die-as-delhi-bound-air-ambulance-crashes-in-indias-jharkhand</link><description>All seven people, including two crew members, on board an air ambulance were killed after the aircraft crashed in the eastern Indian state of Jharkhand, local officials said Tuesday.
The air ambulance crashed on Monday night near Simaria in Chatra district, about 111 km north of Ranchi, the capita</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 05:07:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gold falls from three-week high on profit-booking, firm dollar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/global/gold-falls-from-three-week-high-on-profit-booking-firm-dollar</link><description>Gold prices fell on Tuesday as investors booked profits after bullion rose more than 2% in the previous session, while pressure from a stronger dollar also weighed on the yellow metal.
Spot gold fell 0.8% to $5,189.99 per ounce by 0125 GMT, snapping a four-session winning streak and dropping from</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 05:22:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Narayanganj’s daily battle with traffic and broken roads</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/narayanganjs-daily-battle-with-traffic-and-broken-roads</link><description>For thousands of residents in Narayanganj, a short journey across town has become an exhausting daily trial.
What was once a 10-minute commute now routinely stretches beyond an hour, as chronic traffic congestion, pothole-ridden roads and ongoing development works converge to choke the city’</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 05:37:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ctg gas blast toll rises to 2 as teen dies a day after mother</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ctg-gas-blast-toll-rises-to-2-as-teen-dies-a-day-after-mother</link><description>A teenage boy has died a day after his mother succumbed to burn injuries from a gas explosion at a flat in Chattogram’s Halishahar, raising the death toll in the incident to two.
The victim, 16-year-old Shawon, had suffered burns across 50 per cent of his body, including his respiratory tr</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 05:52:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mexico deploys 2,000 soldiers after cartel leader's death</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/mexico-sends-2000-soldiers-to-jalisco-after-cartel-leaders-death</link><description>Mexican authorities on Monday deployed an additional 2,000 military troops to the western state of Jalisco following violence in the wake of the capture and death of Mexico's most-wanted cartel leader Nemesio Oseguera, known as "El Mencho."
At least 62 people were killed in the early Sunday raid a</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 05:53:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NBR introduces email OTP system for overseas taxpayers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/nbr-introduces-email-otp-system-for-overseas-taxpayers</link><description>The National Board of Revenue (NBR) has introduced a special email verification system allowing Bangladeshi expatriates to file their income tax returns online without relying on mobile-based OTP authentication.
The tax authority announced the measure in a statement on Tuesday, saying the initiati</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 06:08:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Four of a family injured in Cumilla gas cylinder blast</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/four-of-a-family-injured-in-cumilla-gas-cylinder-blast</link><description>Four members of a family, including a woman and a child, have suffered burn injuries after an explosion triggered by a suspected gas cylinder leak in Cumilla’s Daudkandi.
The incident occurred around 6:00 am on Tuesday on the ground floor of a three-storey building in West Maijpara of Ladakh</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 06:23:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>PM to confer 'Ekushey Padak 2026' Thursday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/pm-to-confer-ekushey-padak-2026-thursday</link><description>Prime Minister Tarique Rahman is expected to distribute the 'Ekushey Padak 2026' at a ceremony on Thursday. 
The award distribution ceremony will be held at the Osmani Memorial Auditorium in the capital at 11:00 a.m. on February 26, a handout stated. 
The government has already announce</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 06:38:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chinese envoy invites PM to visit China</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/chinese-envoy-invites-pm-to-visit-china</link><description>Chinese Ambassador to Bangladesh Yao Wen has invited Prime Minister Tarique Rahman to visit China and conveyed warm congratulations and greetings from Chinese President Xi Jinping and Premier Li Qiang.
The Chinese envoy extended the invitation when he paid a call on the premier at his Cabinet Divi</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 06:53:03 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>