<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 20:28:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Obaidul Quader returns home in Kolkata after hospital treatment</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/obaidul-quader-returns-home-in-kolkata-after-hospital-treatment</link><description>Awami League General Secretary Obaidul Quader has returned to his residence in Kolkata after receiving two days of treatment at a local hospital.
Quader, who has been in India since the fall of the Sheikh Hasina government, was admitted to a hospital in Kolkata’s New Town after complaining o</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 16:48:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gold prices in Bangladesh jump nearly Tk 3,000 per bhori in 24 hours</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/gold-prices-in-bangladesh-jump-nearly-tk-3000-per-bhori-in-24-hours</link><description>Gold prices in Bangladesh rose sharply again within 24 hours as the Bangladesh Jewellers Association (BAJUS) on Monday increased the price by Tk 2,916 per bhori, following a hike a day earlier.
In a notification issued in the night, BAJUS fixed the price of 22-carat gold at Tk 227,856 per bhori (1</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 17:03:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DMP transfers one joint commissioner, 13 deputy commissioners</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dmp-transfers-one-joint-commissioner-13-deputy-commissioners</link><description>The Dhaka Metropolitan Police (DMP) has transferred one Joint Commissioner and 13 Deputy Commissioner (DC).
An office order signed by DMP Commissioner Sheikh Md Sajjat Ali was issued in this regard on Monday.
According to the order, Joint Commissioner (Current Charge) ASM Shamsur Rahman has been</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 17:18:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jubo Dal leader shot dead near home in Raozan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jubo-dal-leader-shot-dead-near-home-in-raozan</link><description>A Jubo Dal leader has been shot and killed near his home in Chattogram’s Raozan.
Police said the murder took place around 8:30pm on Monday in Raozan’s Purbo Guzra union.
The victim has been identified as Jane Alam Sikder, 48, a member of the Upazila chapter of Jatiyatabadi Jubo Dal. H</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 17:33:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Move on to get 10 SoEs, MNCs listed</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/move-on-to-get-10-soes-mncs-listed</link><description>A move advances to rope in 10 more entities having public shares to the stock market long starved of good stocks and facing frequent volatilities, officials say.
 Of the ten blue-chip companies, some are solely owned by government while some are multinationals wherein government has small sta</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 17:48:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A unique mix of public-private sector  economic dev introduced by ex-PM</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/a-unique-mix-of-public-private-sector-economic-dev-introduced-by-ex-pm</link><description>Begum Khaleda Zia blended public-and private-sector development in a way uniquely suited to Bangladesh, prioritising business growth while ensuring social responsibility, a commemorative meeting recalls. 
The International Chamber of Commerce (ICC) Bangladesh organised the 'Memorial and Dua M</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 18:03:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Stocks, bonds and oil steady as investors downplay Venezuela upheaval</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/stocks-bonds-and-oil-steady-as-investors-downplay-venezuela-upheaval</link><description>Stocks edged up, bonds steadied and oil prices held firm on Monday as investors reacted calmly to potential market ramifications of the US capture of Venezuelan President Nicolas Maduro.
A STOXX benchmark of Europe's biggest companies rose 0.3 per cent while MSCI's broadest index of Asia-Pacific s</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 18:18:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Return of irregular migrants from European Union</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/return-of-irregular-migrants-from-european-union</link><description>Alberto Horst. Head of European Migration and Diversity and Senior Policy Analyst have drawn attention to an important dimension. He recalled that the European Commission pledged to deliver a "new common approach on the return of irregular migrants" within the first 100 days of its new mandate. It</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 19:28:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>From promise to practice: Building a fair agricultural economy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/reviews/from-promise-to-practice-building-a-fair-agricultural-economy</link><description>For decades, those who feed our nation have stood at the wrong end of the market. Cost of inputs rise relentlessly, yet when harvest season arrives, prices collapse under the weight of middlemen and fragile market systems. The result is familiar: farmers sink into debt while consumers face volatili</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 19:43:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Venezuelan dilemma</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/the-venezuelan-dilemma</link><description>The sitting president of Venezuela has been, what the US said, 'captured' along with his wife, son and other officials as a fugitive evading law. Venezuela is a oil-and-mineral-rich country of the South American continent lying along the coast of North Atlantic Ocean and bordering the Caribbean Sea</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 19:58:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Year 2026: Socio-political stability main expectation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/year-2026-socio-political-stability-main-expectation</link><description>The turning of the year rarely arrives quietly. In Bangladesh, as in much of the world, the dawn of 2026 comes weighted with both memory and expectation -- memory of a turbulent transition and expectation of a long-delayed recovery. If 2025 was a year of endurance, 2026 must become a year of delive</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 20:13:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Let the NBR's impressive work be carried over</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/let-the-nbrs-impressive-work-be-carried-over</link><description>That Bangladesh's tax-to-GDP ratio is one of the lowest in the world is widely known. In the Asia-Pacific region this ratio is as high as 19.50 on an average and the average for the developing countries is 17-18 per cent. Bangladesh cuts a sorry figure with this proportion as low as 7.0-9.0 per cen</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 20:28:45 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>