<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 17:18:26 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>BDR Mutiny: Probe body says Hasina had ‘green signal’ for entire incident</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bdr-mutiny-probe-body-says-hasina-had-green-signal-for-entire-incident</link><description>The Commission, formed to reinvestigate the 2009 BDR massacre, the brutal massacre committed in the name of BDR mutiny submitted its report to Chief Adviser Prof Muhammad Yunus on Sunday, noting that then PM Sheikh Hasina had a ‘green signal’ for the entire incident to take place while</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 13:41:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Islami Bank holds Shari’ah Supervisory Council meeting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/islami-bank-holds-shariah-supervisory-council-meeting-1</link><description>A meeting of the Shari’ah Supervisory Council of Islami Bank Bangladesh PLC was held on Sunday at Islami Bank Tower, according to a press release.
Mufti Sayeed Ahmed, Chairman of the Council presided over the meeting. Md. Omar Faruk Khan, Managing Director of the bank, Prof. Dr. Abu Bakr Raf</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 13:56:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Metro rail operation halted as two individuals climb onto station rooftop</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/metro-rail-operation-halted-as-two-individuals-climb-onto-station-rooftop</link><description>Metro rail services were suspended temporarily on Saturday night after two individuals climbed onto the roof of the Bangladesh Secretariat Station, authorities said.
In a statement, the Dhaka Mass Transit Company Limited (DMTCL) informed passengers that train movement had been halted as a precauti</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 14:11:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Swiss voters reject proposed tax on super rich</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/swiss-voters-reject-proposed-tax-on-super-rich</link><description>Switzerland on Sunday overwhelmingly rejected a proposed 50 per cent tax on inherited fortunes of 50 million Swiss francs ($62 million) or more, with 78 per cent of votes against the plan, an outcome that even exceeded the two‑thirds opposition indicated in polls.
Bankers have watched the vote clo</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 14:26:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Community Bank signs deal to join Bangladesh Bank’s SMEDP-2 Refinance Facility</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/community-bank-signs-deal-to-join-bangladesh-banks-smedp-2-refinance-facility</link><description>Community Bank Bangladesh PLC has signed a ‘Participatory Agreement’ with Bangladesh Bank to join the Refinance Agreement under the Small and Medium Enterprise Development Project–2 (SMEDP-2), aimed at strengthening SME financing and expanding access to credit for small and medium</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 14:41:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bank Asia establishes solar-powered irrigation project for farmers in Rangpur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bank-asia-establishes-solar-powered-irrigation-project-for-farmers-in-rangpur</link><description>As part of corporate social responsibility, Bank Asia has established a modern two-tier solar-powered irrigation project in Pirgacha, Rangpur, aimed at supporting marginal farmers by ensuring an adequate water supply for agriculture.
According to a press release, the initiative has been implemente</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 14:56:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>60-hour training mandatory for driving license: BRTA chairman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/60-hour-training-mandatory-for-driving-license-brta-chairman</link><description>Bangladesh Road Transport Authority (BRTA) Chairman Abu Momtaz Saad Uddin Ahmed today said no one will be issued a driving license without completing mandatory 60 hours of training.
“From now on, 60 hours of mandatory training must be completed to obtain a driving license, as the government</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 15:11:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh Bank extends Tk 80b Sukuk term for five years</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh-bank-extends-tk-80b-sukuk-term-for-five-years</link><description>The term for the first Bangladesh Government Investment Sukuk, valued at Tk 80 billion (Tk 8,000 crore), which was issued against the “Safe Water Supply Across the Country” project, has been extended by an additional five years.
Bangladesh Bank in a press release on Sunday informed thi</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 15:26:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>'Ties with Pakistan kept poor intentionally by past regime'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ties-with-pakistan-kept-poor-intentionally-by-past-regime</link><description>Foreign Adviser Touhid Hossain on Sunday said, Bangladesh’s relations with Pakistan had been intentionally kept poor for many years.
“Certain decisions caused relations with Pakistan to deteriorate compared to before” he said while addressing a meeting organised by the DCAB in th</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 15:41:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Differing geo-political dimensions in North Africa</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/differing-geo-political-dimensions-in-north-africa</link><description>Analysts have been monitoring carefully how North African countries are grappling with what to do next while war between Iran and Israel rages on with some more affected by the clashes than others. 
In an interesting analysis Alissa Pavia has drawn attention to how Israel-Iran War has squeezed Egy</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 15:56:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chasing wild goose of siphoned money</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/chasing-wild-goose-of-siphoned-money</link><description>Industrial stagnation and shrinking private investment have resulted in 1.4 million people's loss of jobs, who are now out on the streets, said former FBCCI president A.K. Azad, also, Managing Director of the Ha-Meem Group, while speaking at a discussion event styled, "Bangladesh Economic Conferenc</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 16:11:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Danger of population growth beyond limits</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/danger-of-population-growth-beyond-limits</link><description>At a time when election, referendum and lease of seaports hog newspaper headlines, some highly important issues receive scant attention. One such issue is population growth in a country that is already gasping for breath under the weight of an outsize people. According to a survey, "Multiple Indica</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 16:26:29 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>