<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 15:28:41 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Jatiya Party’s vote share was systematically suppressed, Shameem Patwary alleges</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jatiya-partys-vote-share-was-systematically-suppressed-shameem-patwary-alleges</link><description>Jatiya Party Secretary General Shameem Haider Patwary has alleged that the party was premeditatedly defeated in the parliamentary elections.
Speaking at a media briefing held on Sunday at the Dhaka Reporters’ Unity auditorium, he claimed the party’s vote share was systematically suppre</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 14:16:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Domestic worker held over ‘killing’ elderly couple</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/domestic-worker-held-over-killing-elderly-couple</link><description>A domestic worker accused of drugging an elderly couple and looting their flat in Uttara has been arrested.
The suspect, who took up work under the fake name “Marufa”, was identified as 40-year-old Bilkis Begum, according to police.
Police said she had taken the job at the house just</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 12:49:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>MTB Neo launches country's first AI-powered Personal Financial Management (PFM) feature</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/mtb-neo-launches-countrys-first-ai-powered-personal-financial-management-pfm-feature</link><description>Mutual Trust Bank PLC (MTB) continues to lead Bangladesh’s digital banking transformation with the launch of the country's first AI-powered Personal Financial Management (PFM) feature, integrated into its flagship mobile banking platform, MTB Neo.
This pioneering solution empowers users with</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 13:04:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pakistan’s Ishaq Dar holds phone talks with Bangladesh FM</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/pakistans-ishaq-dar-holds-phone-talks-with-bangladesh-fm</link><description>Seeking stronger cooperation, Deputy Prime Minister and Foreign Minister of Pakistan Mohammad Ishaq Dar on Sunday held a telephone conversation with Foreign Minister Dr Khalilur Rehman, felicitating him on his recent appointment.
Both leaders expressed a desire to further strengthen bilateral ties</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 13:19:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BSFF signs MoU with Thailand’s TFM on development of aquaculture sector</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bsff-signs-mou-with-thailands-tfm-on-development-of-aquaculture-sector</link><description>Bangladesh Shrimp and Fish Foundation (BSFF) and Thai Union Feedmill Public Company Limited (TFM) teamed up to strengthen long-term collaboration to facilitate the sustainable development of the aquaculture sector in Bangladesh, especially in the coastal region.
In this connection, BSFF chairman S</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 13:34:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Changes likely at top of police administration: Minister Salahuddin</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/changes-likely-at-top-of-police-administration-minister-salahuddin</link><description>Home Minister Salahuddin Ahmed on Sunday said changes are likely at the top level of the police administration.
“Some changes will come, but it will take some time,” he told reporters at the Secretariat after a courtesy meeting at the Prime Minister’s Office.
Speaking about the</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 13:49:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>First batch of BRAC Bank’s Branch Young Leaders graduates</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/first-batch-of-brac-banks-branch-young-leaders-graduates</link><description>BRAC Bank has marked a significant milestone in its talent development journey with the graduation of the first batch of Branch Young Leaders.
This pioneering initiative has been designed to build a strong pipeline of future-ready branch leaders to support the bank’s expanding distribution n</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 14:04:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Army reshuffle brings new DGFI chief</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-army-shake-up-sees-new-cgs-afd-pso-and-dgfi-chief-in-major-command-changes</link><description>A major shake-up at the top levels of the Bangladesh Army has brought new leadership to key posts including the chief of general staff (CGS), principal staff officer (PSO) of the Armed Forces Division (AFD), and the head of the Directorate General of Forces Intelligence (DGFI).
According to a sour</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 14:19:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India, China invites Bangladesh FM to pay official visits</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/india-china-invites-bangladesh-fm-to-pay-official-visits</link><description>India, China and Pakistan on Sunday invited Foreign Minister Dr Khalilur Rahman to pay official visits to the countries at mutually convenient times.
The envoys of China and India extended the invitations on behalf of their respective foreign ministers during separate meetings with the Foreign Min</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 14:34:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BCB bans women’s team selector Manjurul Islam over ‘sexually harassing’ Jahanara</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/cricket/bcb-bans-womens-team-selector-manjurul-islam-over-sexually-harassing-jahanara</link><description>The Bangladesh Cricket Board (BCB) has barred Manjurul Islam from all forms of cricketing activity under its jurisdiction following allegations of sexual harassment made by former women’s team captain Jahanara Alam.
The decision comes after the board reviewed recommendations from an independ</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 14:49:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>21 women among Jamaat’s 88-member new central council</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/21-women-among-jamaats-88-member-new-central-council</link><description>Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami has announced a new 88-member Central Working Council for the 2026–2028 term, including 21 women.
The party said the decision was taken at a virtual meeting of its Central Majlis-e-Shura on 20 February, presided over by its Ameer and Leader of the Opposition in par</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 15:04:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Liberation war foundation of Bangladesh’s freedom: Hafiz Uddin</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/liberation-war-foundation-of-bangladeshs-freedom-hafiz-uddin</link><description>Liberation War Affairs Minister Hafiz Uddin Ahmed Bir Bikram has said the great Liberation War is the fundamental basis of Bangladesh’s freedom.
“It would not be appropriate to equate any other movement or struggle with the Liberation War. We must always remember that the sole foundati</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 15:19:47 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>