<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 11:25:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Court orders arrest of journalist Anis Alamgir in graft case</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/court-orders-arrest-of-journalist-anis-alamgir-in-graft-case</link><description>A court has ordered that journalist Anis Alamgir be placed under arrest in a case filed by the Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) over allegations of acquiring assets beyond known sources of income.
The order was issued on Wednesday by Dhaka Metropolitan Senior Special Judge Md Sabbir Fayez followin</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 08:35:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US Ambassador Christensen meets CEC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/us-ambassador-christensen-meets-cec</link><description>US Ambassador to Bangladesh Brent Christensen has held a meeting with Chief Election Commissioner AMM Nasir Uddin in Dhaka amid preparations for the upcoming 13th parliamentary elections.
The meeting began around 11:45am on Wednesday at the Nirbachan Bhaban in Agargaon.
This was Christensen&amp;rsquo</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 08:50:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BUBT Economics Department Hosts Insightful Session on "Research Methodology: Economic  Advancement in Real Life" During Research Week of the University</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/bubt-economics-department-hosts-insightful-session-on-research-methodology-economic-advancement-in-real-life-during-research-week-of-the-university</link><description>The Department of Economics at Bangladesh University of Business and Technology (BUBT) organized a keynote session titled "Research Methodology: Advancement in Real Life" as part of its Research Week festivities. The event featured esteemed academics who shared critical insights on contemporary res</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 09:05:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rebuilding human capital biggest challenge for next govt: Wahiduddin</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rebuilding-human-capital-biggest-challenge-for-next-govt-wahiduddin</link><description>Planning Adviser Dr Wahiduddin Mahmud on Wednesday said the foremost challenge for the next government will be rebuilding human capital and strengthening governance, alongside preserving fragile macroeconomic stability following years of structural decline and a series of economic shocks.
“F</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 09:52:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka court sentences ‘Cross-eyed Robin’ to death over 2015 Jurain murder</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dhaka-court-sentences-cross-eyed-robin-to-death-over-2015-jurain-murder</link><description>A Dhaka court has sentenced Robin, alias “Cross-eyed Robin”, to death for the shooting and killing of a young man named Sohel in Jurain’s Rishipara around 11 years ago.
The verdict was delivered on Wednesday by Dhaka Additional Metropolitan Sessions Judge Md Khorshed Alam, bdnews</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 10:07:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hajj arrangements underway smoothly according to roadmap: Adviser Khalid</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hajj-arrangements-underway-smoothly-according-to-roadmap-adviser-khalid</link><description>Religious Affairs Adviser Dr A F M Khalid Hossain on Wednesday said all preparations for Hajj are progressing according to the roadmap.
The Ministry of Religious Affairs is working relentlessly to complete cent percent accommodation contracts within the stipulated timeframe, he said during a meeti</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 09:39:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US ready to work with any elected government in Bangladesh: Christensen</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/us-ready-to-work-with-any-elected-government-in-bangladesh-christensen</link><description>The United States will take no side in Bangladesh’s election and is prepared to work with whichever government is chosen by voters, according to US Ambassador Brent Christensen.
Speaking to reporters after meeting Bangladesh’s Chief Election Commissioner AMM Nasir Uddin in Dhaka on Wed</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 09:54:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Adani boosts power supply to Bangladesh despite souring diplomatic ties</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/indias-adani-boosts-electricity-supply-to-bangladesh-despite-souring-diplomatic-ties</link><description>India's Adani Power is boosting electricity exports to Bangladesh, data from both governments showed, despite worsening bilateral relations and a Bangladesh government-appointed panel calling the supply overpriced.
Exports to Bangladesh from Adani's Godda coal-fired power plant in India's eastern</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 10:09:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Daffodil International University celebrates its 13th Convocation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/daffodil-international-university-celebrates-its-13th-convocation</link><description>Daffodil International University (DIU) held its 13th Convocation today, Wednesday (28 January 2026), at Daffodil Smart City, with the participation of 4,020 graduating students from undergraduate and postgraduate programs.
Among them, 3,391 students completed undergraduate degrees and 629 complet</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 10:24:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EBL launches Trade Hub at Chattogram EPZ</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ebl-launches-trade-hub-at-chattogram-epz</link><description>Eastern Bank PLC (EBL) has officially launched a dedicated Trade Hub at the Chattogram Export Processing Zone (CEPZ) to provide specialised trade-related banking services for customers operating within the CEPZ area.
The EBL CEPZ Trade Hub has been specifically designed to expedite import and expo</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 10:39:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>510 tonnes of rice imported from India reach Benapole</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/510-tonnes-of-rice-imported-from-india-reach-benapole</link><description>A total of 510 tonnes of parboiled rice have been imported from India through the Benapole Land Port in Jashore after a gap of three months, with the import cost standing at Tk 50 per kg.
The consignments arrived at the port in 14 trucks on Tuesday and entered Transshipment Yard No. 31, said Benap</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 10:54:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US will work with whoever wins Bangladesh polls: Christensen</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/us-ready-to-work-with-any-elected-government-in-bangladesh-says-ambassador-christensen</link><description>The United States will take no side in Bangladesh’s election and is prepared to work with whichever government is chosen by voters, according to US Ambassador Brent Christensen.
Speaking to reporters after meeting Bangladesh’s Chief Election Commissioner AMM Nasir Uddin in Dhaka on Wed</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 11:09:55 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>