<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 07:20:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Hurricane Melissa kills 25 in Haiti</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/hurricane-melissa-kills-25-in-haiti</link><description>Hurricane Melissa barrelled through the northern Caribbean on Wednesday after thrashing Cuba's second-biggest city, isolating hundreds of rural communities, unleashing devastation in Jamaica and drenching Haiti, where at least 25 were killed.
Melissa struck Jamaica on Tuesday as the strongest-ever</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 05:21:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Motorcyclist killed in Dinajpur road crash</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/motorcyclist-killed-in-dinajpur-road-crash465676876</link><description>A motorcyclist was killed in a head-on collision with a tractor at Barsha Gopalpur area on the Birganj–Pirganj road in Birganj upazila of Dinajpur on Wednesday night.
The deceased was identified as Mojaharul Islam (47), son of Md Azizur Rahman of Mashkhuria village in Pirganj upazila of Thak</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 04:17:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Protests erupt after police raid in Brazil leaves 119 dead</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/protests-erupt-after-police-raid-in-brazil-leaves-119-dead</link><description>A massive police raid on a drug gang embedded in low-income neighbourhoods of Rio de Janeiro that left at least 119 people dead drew protests for excessive force on Wednesday and calls for the Rio’s governor to resign.
Dozens of favelas residents gathered in front of the state’s govern</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 04:32:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Woman killed in Gaibandha road accident</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/woman-killed-in-gaibandha-road-accident</link><description>An old woman was crushed under the wheels of a tractor at Chak Gobindapur area in Faridpur union of Sadullapur upazila in Gaibandha district on Wednesday.
The victim has been identified as Kapashi Beoya, 80, the wife of late Pacha Shekh of the area, reports BSS.
Local sources said a soil-loaded t</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 04:47:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US cuts China tariffs to 47pc after Trump-Xi meeting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/global/us-cuts-china-tariffs-to-47pc-after-trump-xi-meeting</link><description>US President Donald Trump said on Thursday he had agreed to reduce tariffs on China to 47 per cent in exchange for Beijing resuming US soybean purchases, keeping rare earths exports flowing and cracking down on the illicit trade of fentanyl.
His remarks after face-to-face talks with Chinese Presid</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 05:32:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rain, thundershowers likely over Rangpur, Rajshahi, Mymensingh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rain-thundershowers-likely-over-rangpur-rajshahi-mymensingh42</link><description>Bangladesh Meteorological Department (BMD) forecast rain or thundershowers at many places over Rangpur, Rajshahi and Mymensingh divisions in the next 24 hours beginning from 9:00 am today.
“Light to moderate rain or thundershowers is likely to occur at most places over Rangpur, Rajshahi and</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 05:47:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IUB's Ive Sithi Chambugong to represent Bangladesh at Int'l Gold Event in Nigeria</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/iubs-ive-sithi-chambugong-to-represent-bangladesh-at-intl-gold-event-in-nigeria</link><description>Ive Sithi Chambugong, an undergraduate student of Biochemistry and Biotechnology at Independent University, Bangladesh (IUB), will represent Bangladesh at the International Gold Event (IGE) and Forum 2025 in Lagos, Nigeria, from November 16-22, 2025. She is a DEA Gold Award Holder and the first ele</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 06:02:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh braces for surge in elderly population</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-braces-for-surge-in-elderly-population</link><description>Bangladesh is facing a rapidly aging population, with a new study projecting the 60+ age group will grow from 13 percent in 2020 to over 30 percent by 2050.
These findings were released at an event in Dhaka Tuesday as part of launching Bangladesh's first-ever Country Diagnostic Study (CDS) on Long</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 06:17:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique calls for childcare plan to empower women</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-calls-for-childcare-plan-to-empower-women</link><description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman has called for building Bangladesh in a way where every working mother and every female student has the freedom to thrive, instead of being forced to leave work or education due to a lack of adequate childcare.
In a post on his verified Facebook page on Thursday,</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 06:32:20 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>