<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 07:26:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>NBR cuts customs duty on date imports ahead of Ramadan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nbr-cuts-customs-duty-on-date-imports-ahead-of-ramadan</link><description>The government has reduced customs duty on the import of dates by 40 percent ahead of the holy month of Ramadan, aiming to ensure adequate supply and keep prices within the purchasing capacity of general consumers.
In a press release issued on Wednesday, the National Board of Revenue (NBR) said th</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 03:45:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>VAT exemption on Metro Rail extended till June 2026</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/vat-exemption-on-metro-rail-extended-till-june-2026</link><description>The government has extended the Value Added Tax (VAT) exemption on Metro Rail services until June 30, 2026, aiming to promote the use of the country's modern, environmentally friendly mass transit system.
According to a press release issued today by the National Board of Revenue (NBR), the decisio</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 04:00:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Yields on long-term treasury bonds rise further</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/yields-on-long-term-treasury-bonds-rise-further</link><description>Yields on long-term treasury bonds increased further on Tuesday, as banks were reluctant to invest surplus funds in the government securities ahead of the year-end closing and upcoming national polls.
The cut-off yield, generally known as the interest rate, on the 15-year Bangladesh Government T</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 04:15:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ferry movement on Paturia-Daulatdia route suspended</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ferry-movement-on-paturia-daulatdia-route-suspended</link><description>Ferry movement on the Paturia-Daulatdia river route was suspended early this morning due to dense fog, disrupting communication with the southern districts of the country.
Bangladesh Inland Water Transport Corporation (BIWTC) Paturia Ghat Assistant General Manager (AGM) Abdus Salam said ferry oper</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 04:30:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tripartite partnerships to build AI infrastructure, LLM for older citizens</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/tripartite-partnerships-to-build-ai-infrastructure-llm-for-older-citizens</link><description>The Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) has stepped up preparations for the upcoming parliamentary election and is shaping its election manifesto with a sharper focus on digital transformation and artificial intelligence.
In a recent interview with The Financial Express, the party's IT Affairs Secr</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 04:45:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Healthy foods you can add to your diet this winter</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/healthy-foods-you-can-add-to-your-diet-this-winter</link><description>As winter settles in Bangladesh, the mesmerising sight of local winter vegetables and colourful seasonal fruits, and the joy of enjoying 'pitha' with friends and family on a chilly day, bring us much joy.
From early-morning bazaar trips to drinking date palm juice and warm evening tea, winter chan</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 05:00:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Severe cold cripples daily life in Chuadanga</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/severe-cold-cripples-daily-life-in-chuadanga</link><description>Residents of the southwestern district of Chuadanga are grappling with reducing temperatures as dense fog and chilling winds disrupt daily life.
Despite clear skies in the morning, the intensity of the cold persists, causing severe suffering, particularly, homeless and vulnerable people.
The loca</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 05:15:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Morning tradition that refuses to fade Dhaka's enduring newspaper culture</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/morning-tradition-that-refuses-to-fade-dhakas-enduring-newspaper-culture</link><description>"People don't actually read newspapers. They step into them every morning like a hot bath." Marshall McLuhan's words drift easily into the first light over Dhaka. They capture a feeling many once knew well, when the newspaper was not just information but a way to settle into the day. That feeling h</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 05:30:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NBR cuts customs duty on date imports ahead of Ramadan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/nbr-cuts-customs-duty-on-date-imports-ahead-of-ramadan-1</link><description>The government has reduced customs duty on the import of dates by 40 percent ahead of the holy month of Ramadan, aiming to ensure adequate supply and keep prices within the purchasing capacity of general consumers.
In a press release issued on Wednesday, the National Board of Revenue (NBR) said th</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 05:45:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>World Bank helps Bangladesh create economic opportunities for low-income youth</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/world-bank-helps-bangladesh-create-economic-opportunities-for-low-income-youth</link><description>The World Bank approved $150.75 million to help Bangladesh scale up support to create employment, opportunities and better income for low-income youth and microentrepreneurs, with a focus on women and those living in climate-vulnerable areas.
The additional financing to the Recovery and Advancemen</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 06:00:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Zubayer Rahman Chowdhury appointed new chief justice</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/zubayer-rahman-chowdhury-appointed-new-chief-justice</link><description>Justice Zubayer Rahman Chowdhury of the Appellate Division has been appointed as the chief justice, succeeding Justice Syed Refaat Ahmed at the apex of the country’s judiciary.
Justice Refaat had assumed the top judicial post during the political upheaval of 2024 following the student-led ma</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 06:15:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trade through Benapole port to remain off on Thursday, Friday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/trade-through-benapole-port-to-remain-off-on-thursday-friday</link><description>Import and export trade through the country’s largest land port Benapole will remain suspended on Thursday and Friday on the occasion of Christmas and the weekend, officials said Wednesday.
Benapole Port Director Shamim Hossain said that no goods will be imported or exported during the perio</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 06:30:48 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>