<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 10:27:11 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>A third of Americans support US strike on Venezuela, Reuters poll finds</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/a-third-of-americans-support-us-strike-on-venezuela-reuters-poll-finds</link><description>One in three Americans approves of the US military strike on Venezuela that toppled the country's president and 72% worry the US will become too involved in the South American country, according to a Reuters/Ipsos poll that concluded on Monday.
The two-day poll showed 65% of Republicans back the m</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 05:12:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Over a dozen media workers detained in Venezuela</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/over-a-dozen-media-workers-detained-in-venezuela-says-national-press-association</link><description>More than a dozen media workers were detained on Monday while covering events in the Venezuelan capital Caracas, including a march in support of ousted President Nicolas Maduro and the swearing-in of the country's new legislature, the South American nation's press association said.
All 14 of those</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 05:27:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CIA concludes regime loyalists best suited to lead Venezuela after Maduro</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/cia-concludes-regime-loyalists-best-suited-to-lead-venezuela-after-maduro</link><description>A classified CIA assessment presented to US President Donald Trump concluded senior Maduro loyalists, including Vice President Delcy Rodriguez, were best positioned to maintain stability if the Venezuelan leader lost power, two sources briefed on the matter said on Monday.
The sources, speaking on</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 05:42:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>1.53m voters opt for postal ballots</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/153m-voters-opt-for-postal-ballots</link><description>A total of 15,33,682 voters have registered through the "Postal Vote BD" app to cast their votes by postal ballot in the upcoming 13th Jatiya Sangsad Election and the Referendum.
According to the Election Commission (EC), the registration process through the app concluded at midnight on Monday, wh</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 06:28:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trader assaulted during student union election at Jagannath University</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/trader-assaulted-during-student-union-election-at-jagannath-university</link><description>A trader has been assaulted at the main gate of Dhaka's Jagannath University during voting in the university’s first-ever central students’ union election.
The incident occurred around 9:45 am on Tuesday, when Nazrul Islam was attacked by several students amid allegations of “ele</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 06:43:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cold wave tightens grip as Rajshahi records season's lowest 7°C</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/cold-wave-tightens-grip-as-rajshahi-records-seasons-lowest-7c</link><description>A biting cold wave swept across large parts of Bangladesh on Tuesday, pushing temperatures down to the season's lowest and disrupting daily life in at least 10 districts.
According to the Bangladesh Meteorological Department (BMD), the country's lowest temperature was recorded at 7.0°C in Rajs</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 07:28:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>JnUCSU polls: Police intervene after VP candidate's wife 'harassed' while campaigning</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/jnucsu-polls-police-intervene-after-vp-candidates-wife-harassed-while-campaigning</link><description>Police have taken the wife of a vice-president (VP) candidate in the Jagannath University Central Students’ Union (JnUCSU) election into custody following a dispute outside the campus gate.
The woman, Mahima Akter, is the wife of Islami Chhatra Shibir-backed candidate Riazul Islam. The incid</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 07:43:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Traders behind LPG price manipulation: Energy adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/traders-behind-lpg-price-manipulation-energy-adviser</link><description>Power, Energy and Mineral Resources Adviser Muhammad Fouzul Kabir Khan on Tuesday said the abnormal rise in Liquefied Petroleum Gas (LPG) prices was created by retail and wholesale traders.
“Some traders created an artificial crisis in the market by taking advantage of the Bangladesh Energy</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 08:29:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Media trying to defame July Uprising leaders ahead of polls, says NCP's Nahid</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/media-trying-to-defame-july-uprising-leaders-ahead-of-polls-says-ncps-nahid</link><description>National Citizen Party (NCP) Convenor Nahid Islam has alleged that some media outlets are attempting to defame leaders and activists of the July Uprising ahead of the upcoming elections.
“The incident involving July activist Tahrima Jannat Surovi, who was recently released on bail, is a cont</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 08:44:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt approves direct procurement of EPI vaccines for FY26</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-approves-direct-procurement-of-epi-vaccines-for-fy26</link><description>The government on Tuesday approved in principle a proposal to procure vaccines under the Expanded Programme on Immunisation (EPI) for the current fiscal year (FY26) through the Direct Procurement Method (DPM).
The approval was given at this year's first meeting of the Advisers Council Committee on</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 09:15:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh's response to Mustafizur’s IPL exclusion ‘robust and appropriate’, says advisor</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/bangladeshs-response-to-mustafizurs-ipl-exclusion-robust-and-appropriate-says-advisor</link><description>Finance Advisor Salehuddin Ahmed has described Bangladesh's response to the removal of cricketer Mustafizur Rahman from the Indian Premier League (IPL) as “robust” and “appropriate”. However, he downplayed the likelihood of any lasting impact on relations with India.
Sale</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 09:30:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rizvi urges ensuring dignity, protection for drivers, laborers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/rizvi-urges-ensuring-dignity-protection-for-drivers-laborers</link><description>BNP Senior Joint Secretary General Ruhul Kabir Rizvi today (Tuesday) urged to enact effective and welfare-oriented laws to ensure dignity, security and respect for laborers and motor vehicle drivers across the country.
"Working-class people earn their livelihood through hard labor but are often su</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 09:45:45 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>