<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 02:02:51 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Chief prosecutor, CPB's Prince clash over ‘mob’ label for July Uprising</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/chief-prosecutor-tajul-cautions-over-mob-label-for-july-uprising-cpbs-ruhin-prince-calls-remarks-a-threat</link><description>Chief Prosecutor Mohammad Tajul Islam has warned against using the word “mob” to describe the July Uprising, saying it risks questioning the legitimacy of the movement.
Speaking at a policy dialogue on “Judicial Independence and Rule of Law” organised by the Centre for Gove</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 17:23:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP alleges ‘voter transfer’ to Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bnp-asks-ec-for-data-on-transferred-voters-raises-postal-ballot-concerns</link><description>BNP has alleged that “a political party” is bringing in voters from outside areas to Dhaka in an attempt to secure victories for its candidates.
In a meeting with Chief Election Commissioner AMM Nasir Uddin at the Election Commission headquarters in Agargaon on Sunday, the party demand</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 17:38:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>35 Bangladeshi workers sent back from Russia within six months of migration</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/35-bangladeshi-workers-sent-back-from-russia-within-six-months-of-migration</link><description>Within six months of migration, 35 Bangladeshi workers have been sent back from Russia.
A media statement issued by BRAC, citing the workers, said they were sacked without any valid reason.
The workers alleged that 120 people who migrated from Bangladesh in July were dismissed. They alleged that</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 17:53:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCP weighs election boycott over ‘one-sided’ EC decisions: Asif Mahmud</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ncp-reconsiders-election-participation-over-one-sided-ec-decisions-asif-mahmud</link><description>National Citizen Party (NCP) reconsiders whether it should participate in the upcoming national election, citing what it described as one-sided decisions by the Election Commission (EC), party spokesperson Asif Mahmud Shojib Bhuiyan said on Sunday.
Speaking at an emergency press conference at the</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 18:08:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DU female students hold symbolic barbecue, demand women-friendly campus</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/du-female-students-hold-symbolic-barbecue-demand-women-friendly-campus</link><description>A group of Dhaka University female students have staged a symbolic protest titled “Burn the Administration Barbecue” and submitted a memorandum, demanding a safe, equal-rights-based and discrimination-free campus for women.
Dhaka University Central Students’ Union executive membe</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 19:45:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prof Yunus calls for unity for successful election, country’s future</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/prof-yunus-calls-for-unity-for-successful-election-countrys-future</link><description>Chief Adviser Prof Muhammad Yunus on Sunday urged all concerned to unite and work for the success of the upcoming election and the country, irrespective of victory or defeat in the election, scheduled for February 12.
“We must hold a fair election under any circumstances. Please inform us of</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 20:00:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Power generation halted at Barapukuria plant after boiler tube bursts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/power-generation-halted-at-barapukuria-plant-after-boiler-tube-bursts</link><description>Power generation at Unit-1 of the Barapukuria Thermal Power Plant in Dinajpur was suspended on Sunday after a boiler tube burst, bringing electricity production at the plant to a complete halt.
As a result, all three units of the plant, with a combined capacity of 525 megawatts (MW), are now out o</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 20:15:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Weighing downside risks, upside benefits of BKB-RAKUB merger</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/weighing-downside-risks-upside-benefits-of-bkb-rakub-merger</link><description>A government move for the merger of Rajshahi Krishi Unnayan Bank (RAKUB) with Bangladesh Krishi Bank (BKB) stokes fear it could weaken region-specific farm financing and create new operational challenges instead problem solving.
The banking regulator, on the other hand, has listed upside gains of</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 20:30:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The politics of Ziaur Rahman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/the-politics-of-ziaur-rahman</link><description>An abyss of uncertainty was prevailing in the political arena of Bangladesh towards the end of March 1971. When the failure of the political leadership to provide direction became acute, when the people were dazed and dumbfounded by the barbarous brutality of the Pakistani military forces, the youn</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 20:45:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>When freaks and minnows rule the roost</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/when-freaks-and-minnows-rule-the-roost</link><description>What a historic moment of mental bankruptcy the world has just witnessed! The beaming faces of Venezuelan opposition leader Maria Corina Machado and US President Donald Trump have flashed on TV screens and pages of newspapers all across the globe as this year's Nobel Peace Prize winner Machado hand</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 21:00:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Return of Sundarbans bandits?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/return-of-sundarbans-bandits</link><description>On November 2018, the government of the day declared the Sundarbans free of bandits who used to rule the forest and would force forest-dependent people including local fishers, wood-cutters (bawalis), honey collectors (moualis) and crab-catchers to pay protection money to continue with their trade.</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 21:15:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>It is time to ingrain farm-to-table concept</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/it-is-time-to-ingrain-farm-to-table-concept</link><description>Dhaka's kitchen markets are now a visual feast, overflowing with vibrant greens and colourful produce of a winter harvest. To the casual observer, the sheer volume of supply would suggest a season of relief for the city's beleaguered consumers. However, the reality on the ground is starkly differen</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 21:30:49 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>