<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 07:53:20 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>The heritage of Dhaka's oldest mosque, Binat Bibi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/the-heritage-of-dhakas-oldest-mosque-binat-bibi</link><description>Narinda, an area in old Dhaka, is known for traffic jams, crowds, and pollution. Got its name from Narayoner dia, meaning the island of Narayan, now known as Narinda, is popular for its Jhunur morog polao. However, there is another fact that residents of Narinda should feel proud of. It is the Bina</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 04:45:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Janata Bank officer found dead at rehab centre</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/janata-bank-officer-found-dead-at-rehab-centre</link><description>A senior bank official has died at a drug rehabilitation centre in Bogura, with his family alleging he was beaten to death.
The incident occurred on Tuesday night at “Mayer Ashroy Drug Addiction Rehabilitation Centre” in Sabgram of Sadar Upazila, according to Additional Superintendent</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 05:00:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Direct Dhaka-Malé-Dhaka flights of Maldivian Airlines resume Mar 12</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/direct-dhaka-male-dhaka-flights-of-maldivian-airlines-resume-mar-12</link><description>Direct Dhaka- Malé-Dhaka flights of Maldivian Airlines will resume on March 12 this year, reinforcing air connectivity between the two friendly South Asian countries, according to a press release issued on Tuesday.
Maldivian Airlines has already signed an agreement with its Bangladeshi Gene</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 05:15:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP govt reconstitutes powerful ECNEC body</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bnp-govt-reconstitutes-powerful-ecnec-body</link><description>In a move to consolidate economic governance, the newly elected BNP-led government on Tuesday reconstituted the Executive Committee of the National Economic Council (ECNEC), restoring the apex body responsible for approving major public investment projects.
The reorganisation places Prime Minister</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 05:30:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NFAs surpass 34m with deposits exceeding Tk 72.6b</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/nfas-surpass-34m-with-deposits-exceeding-tk-726b</link><description>Bangladesh's financial inclusion drive gathered further momentum in the December 2025 quarter, with no-frill accounts (NFAs) surpassing 34 million and deposits climbing above Tk 72.60 billion, according to the latest data from Bangladesh Bank (BB).
The number of NFAs -- low-cost accounts that can</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 05:45:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DU students protest, as 'police beat journalists'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/du-students-protest-as-police-beat-journalists</link><description>Two journalists and several students of Dhaka University (DU) were ‘beaten’ during an anti-narcotics drive of police at Suhrawardy Udyan in the capital on Monday evening.
The injured are Tofayel Ahmed of Banglanews- 24.com, and Kawsar Ahmed Ripon of Ajker Patrika. The incident sparked</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 06:00:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Apex rolls out ‘Style-e No.1’ Eid campaign with star reunion</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/apex-rolls-out-style-e-no1-eid-campaign-with-star-reunion</link><description>Apex Footwear Limited has launched its largest campaign of the year ahead of Eid, aiming to position itself as the country’s No. 1 stylish destination for families.
Titled ‘Style-e No.1’, the campaign reflects the company’s vision to become the ultimate stylish destination</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 06:15:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ali Hossain Fakir takes charge as IGP</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ali-hossain-fakir-takes-charge-as-igp</link><description>Ali Hossain Fakir took over as the Inspector General of Police (IGP) on Wednesday.
He took over the responsibility at Police Headquarters, succeeding his predecessor.
Ali Hossain Fakir is a senior career police officer with decades of experience in policing and administration, reports UNB.
The g</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 06:30:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh, Malaysia keen to enhance religious cooperation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-malaysia-keen-to-enhance-religious-cooperation</link><description>Bangladesh and Malaysia have agreed to strengthen cooperation in the field of religious affairs. 
Religious Affairs Minister Kazi Shah Mofazzal Hossain Kaikobad and Malaysian Religious Affairs Minister Dr Zulkifli Hasan agreed on this issue in a virtual meeting held on Tuesday, a handout said</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 06:45:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jubo League leader Samrat jailed for 20 years in graft case</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jubo-league-leader-samrat-jailed-for-20-years-in-graft-case</link><description>A Dhaka court has sentenced Jubo League leader Ismail Hossain Chowdhury Samrat to 20 years in prison in a case over illegal wealth accumulation and money laundering.
Judge Md Zakaria Hossain of Dhaka Special Judge’s Court-6 delivered the verdict on Wednesday.
According to court officials, S</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 07:00:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chattogram blast from ‘gas leak’: Death toll rises to 5</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/chattogram-blast-from-gas-leak-death-toll-rises-to-5</link><description>The death toll following a blast apparently from a gas leak at Halishahar in Chattogram has risen to five with the death of another victim on Wednesday morning.
Shawakhat Hossain,49, who sustained 100 per cent burns, breathed his last at 10:40 am, said Assistant Professor Dr Shawon Bin Rahman, a r</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 07:15:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BB officers’ welfare council threatens agitation over transfer of 3 members</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bb-officers-welfare-council-threatens-agitation-over-transfer-of-3-members</link><description>The Bangladesh Bank Officers' Welfare Council (BBOWC) has warned of launching a protest demanding the resignation of its governor, Dr Ahsan H Mansur, if he does not withdraw the transfer of its three members.
A day after issuing a show-cause notice for arranging a press conference without permissi</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 07:30:40 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>