<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 14:28:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Next govt will have final call on Gaza deployment: Foreign adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/next-govt-will-have-final-call-on-gaza-deployment-foreign-adviser</link><description>The interim government has not taken any decision on deploying forces to Gaza and will leave any final call to the next elected government, the country’s foreign affairs adviser has said, underlining Dhaka’s cautious approach amid international discussions on a possible stabilisati</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 11:43:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Some personnel advised to leave US military base in Qatar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/some-personnel-advised-to-leave-us-military-base-in-qatar-diplomats-say</link><description>Some personnel have been advised to leave the US military's Al Udeid Air Base in Qatar by Wednesday evening, three diplomats told Reuters, amid warnings from Washington that it could intervene to protect protesters in Iran.
The US embassy in Doha had no immediate comment and Qatar's ministry of fo</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 11:58:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trader fined Tk 50,000 for hoarding LPG cylinders in Sylhet</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/trader-fined-tk-50000-for-hoarding-lpg-cylinders-in-sylhet</link><description>The National Consumer Rights Protection Directorate (NCRPD) on Wednesday imposed a fine of Tk 50,000 on a trader for illegally stockpiling a large number of LPG gas cylinders at a house in Shibganj area of Sylhet city.
Based on a tip-off, a drive was conducted at a residence and a truck loading 13</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 12:13:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ADP spending sinks to 17 per cent in 6 months</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh-adp-2025-26-sees-only-175-per-cent-implementation-in-first-half-lowest-in-two-decades</link><description>Bangladesh’s Annual Development Programme (ADP) has recorded its lowest mid-year implementation rate in two decades, with only 17.54 per cent of allocations spent in the first six months of the 2025-26 fiscal year.
According to the Implementation Monitoring and Evaluation Division (IMED), Tk</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 12:28:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Win for ‘Yes’ to ensure discrimination-free Bangladesh for youths: Ali Riaz</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/win-for-yes-to-ensure-discrimination-free-bangladesh-for-youths-ali-riaz</link><description>Special Assistant to the Chief Adviser Professor Ali Riaz on Wednesday said voting ‘Yes’ in the referendum would pave the way for building a new, discrimination-free Bangladesh for the young generation.
“To rebuild the country anew, people must vote ‘Yes’ in the refer</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 12:43:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Iran’s currency crash hits Iraq's pilgrimage industry</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/irans-currency-crash-hits-iraqs-pilgrimage-industry</link><description>In Najaf’s market, Ahmed Salam once ran two shops selling prayer beads and accessories to Iranian pilgrims in the Iraqi holy Shi’ite Muslim city, a prime destination for millions of visitors.
Today, Salam stands behind the counter of his remaining store, after selling the other to pay</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 12:58:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Southeast Bank signs MoU with Banani Bidyaniketan School and College</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/southeast-bank-signs-mou-with-banani-bidyaniketan-school-and-college</link><description>Southeast Bank PLC recently signed a Memorandum of Understanding (MOU) with Banani Bidyaniketan School and College at the bank’s Head Office, in Dhaka for providing Total Education Management Solution “SoutheastEduFin” - an advanced Education Management System (EMS) to streamline</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 13:13:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>2025 among world’s three hottest years on record, WMO says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/2025-among-worlds-three-hottest-years-on-record-wmo-says</link><description>Last year was among the planet’s three warmest on record, the World Meteorological Organization said on Wednesday, as EU scientists also confirmed average temperatures have now exceeded 1.5 degrees Celsius of global warming for the longest since records began.
The WMO, which consolidates eig</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 13:28:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US expected to unveil post-war Gaza leadership, sources say</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-expected-to-unveil-post-war-gaza-leadership-sources-say</link><description>US President Donald Trump is expected on Wednesday to push ahead with his phased plan for Gaza's future by announcing the administration that will run the war-ravaged Palestinian territory, four Palestinian sources said.
Israel and Hamas in October signed off on Trump's 20-point plan which says th</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 13:43:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shimanto Bank inks MoU with Neelima Resort and Tours</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/shimanto-bank-inks-mou-with-neelima-resort-and-tours</link><description>Shimanto Bank has recently signed a Memorandum of Understanding (MoU) with Neelima Resort and Tours at the bank’s Head Office, according to a press release.
As part of this agreement, all Debit and Credit Card holders, along with employees of Shimanto Bank, will be entitled to enjoy exclusiv</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 13:58:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Stay vigilant against banned organisations, DMP Commissioner asks officers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/stay-vigilant-against-banned-organisations-dmp-commissioner-asks-officers</link><description>Dhaka Metropolitan Police (DMP) Commissioner Sazzat Ali asked all officers to strictly follow the code of conduct and remain vigilant against any activities by banned organisations that could disrupt the electoral environment.
“Violations of the electoral code of conduct could jeopardise the</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 14:13:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Islami Bank holds board meeting on Wednesday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/islami-bank-holds-board-meeting-on-wednesday</link><description>A meeting of the board of directors of Islami Bank Bangladesh PLC was held on Wednesday at Islami Bank Tower, according to a press release.
Professor Dr. M. Zubaidur Rahman, chairman of the bank, presided over the meeting. Mohammad Khurshid Wahab, chairman of the executive committee, Md. Abdus Sal</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 14:28:27 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>