<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 18:31:18 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>5 madrasha students stabbed by ‘fellow student’ in Gazipur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/5-madrasha-students-stabbed-by-fellow-student-in-gazipur</link><description>Five students of a madrasha were stabbed allegedly by a fellow student in Sreepur upazila of Gazipur on Thursday.
The injured were identified as Rifat, Nadim, Muhin, Rifat, and Rashidul, students of Gararan Khaliliya Bahumukhi Fazil Madrasa.
The victims said their final examinations were underway</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 15:37:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>4,042 candidates clear 46th BCS written exam</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/4042-candidates-clear-46th-bcs-written-exam</link><description>The Public Service Commission (PSC) has released the results of the 46th Bangladesh Civil Service (BCS) written examination, with 4,042 candidates making the cut.
The results were published at 9pm on Thursday, PSC spokesperson SM Matiur Rahman confirmed.
Candidates can check their outcome at www.</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 15:44:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Back-to-back fires hit Karwan Bazar and Moghbazar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/back-to-back-fires-hit-karwan-bazar-and-moghbazar</link><description>Two separate fires broke out at a shanty adjacent to the Karwan Bazar railway gate in Tejgaon and at an eight-storey building in Moghbazar on Thursday night.
Duty officer at the Fire Service and Civil Defence control room Rakibul Hasan said they received the first call at 8:50pm from Karwan Bazar</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 15:59:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Putin says US-Ukraine text could form basis for future peace deal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/putin-says-us-ukraine-text-could-form-basis-for-future-peace-deal</link><description>Russian President Vladimir Putin said on Thursday that outline draft peace proposals discussed by the United States and Ukraine could become the basis of future agreements to end the conflict in Ukraine, but that if not Russia would fight on.
US President Donald Trump has long said he wants to end</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 16:14:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>46pc of Bangladeshis use feature phones: official</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/46-per-cent-of-bangladeshis-use-feature-phones-miss-government-benefits-official</link><description>Information and Communication Technology Division Secretary Shish Haider Chowdhury has said 46 percent of Bangladesh’s population still use feature or button phones, leaving them “deprived” of the benefits of various government initiatives due to their lack of internet connectivit</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 16:29:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rented barge allegedly cut up in BNP leader’s dockyard</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rented-barge-allegedly-cut-up-in-bnp-leaders-dockyard</link><description>A barge has been allegedly cut up at a dockyard by a man posing as its owner.
The barge’s original owner, Rakesh Sharma, lodged the case at Sonargaon Police Station on Monday, alleging that the vessel was dismantled without his permission.
He named seven suspects, including: Md Zafar, 42, S</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 16:44:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Panna pulls out of Hasina’s defence</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/lawyer-zi-khan-panna-withdraws-from-hasinas-defence-over-lack-of-confidence-in-ict</link><description>Senior lawyer ZI Khan Panna has said he will not act as state-appointed lawyer for Sheikh Hasina in two cases involving enforced disappearances and torture at the TFI and JIC during the Awami League government.
Freedom fighter Panna, a Supreme Court lawyer, was initially appointed on Nov 23 by a t</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 16:59:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Onion, ginger imports to stop in three years: agri secretary</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/onion-ginger-imports-to-stop-in-three-years-agri-secretary</link><description>The Secretary of Agriculture, Dr. Mohammad Emdadullah Mian, announced that the agricultural sector managed to save Tk 4,000 crore over the past year by curbing corruption and waste in development projects.
He further declared that Bangladesh aims to achieve self-sufficiency in onion and ginger pro</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 17:00:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>President Parade (Winter)-2025 held at BAF Academy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/president-parade-winter-2025-held-at-baf-academy</link><description>The President Parade (Winter)-2025, marking the commissioning of No 87 BAFA (Bangladesh Air Force Academy) Course, Direct Entry-2025B and SPSSC-2025B of Bangladesh Air Force, was held at BAF Academy in Jashore on Thursday.
Chief of Air Staff Air Chief Marshal Hasan Mahmood Khan attended the ceremo</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 17:15:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Six tycoons shortlisted for siphoned-off asset recovery rapidly</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/six-tycoons-shortlisted-for-siphoned-off-asset-recovery-rapidly</link><description>The Bangladesh Bank has shortlisted six tycoons and decided to speed up probe and disposal of cases against them over the laundered money siphoned off to several countries.
Investigators name the suspect conglomerates like NASSA, Beximco, Saifuzzaman, Sikder Group, S. Alam and Orion.
On Wednesday</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 17:30:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Next frontier of Bangladesh's export diversification</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/next-frontier-of-bangladeshs-export-diversification</link><description>There are always points in the economic development of countries where the roadmap for the future becomes distinctly visible once the driving engine, which for so long propelled success to dizzying heights, is no longer commensurate with ambitions born out of success. Bangladesh has finally reached</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 17:45:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A journalist's journey through history and the craft</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/reviews/a-journalists-journey-through-history-and-the-craft</link><description>Journalism is not only a profession; it demands passion, devotion and commitment. It also comes with the responsibility to serve readers, viewers and listeners with unbiased information and perspectives they need to make important decisions in everyday life.
Aspiring journalists may wonder how the</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 18:00:49 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>