<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 05:22:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Dollar reserves steady for guided exchange</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/dollar-reserves-steady-for-guided-exchange</link><description>Regulatory foreign-exchange-market intervention pays off as Bangladesh's reserves stay steady for guided exchange and dollar buy from banks as a stabilising measure, sources say.
The country's foreign-exchange reserves show a rebound following the Bangladesh Bank's market intervention to keep taka</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 01:30:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khaleda Zia's health gets more stable, says Dr Zahid</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/khaleda-zias-health-gets-more-stable-says-dr-zahid</link><description>BNP Chairperson Khaleda Zia's health saw a bit more improvement on Friday from the utmost stability attained in the past one month, according to his personal physician.
BNP Standing Committee Member Dr. AZM Zahid Hossain shared the update to the reporters in front of Evercare Hospital.
Zahid Hoss</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 01:45:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fiscal space shrinks as subsidy burden rises</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/fiscal-space-shrinks-as-subsidy-burden-rises</link><description>Bangladesh's fiscal landscape is facing a significant strain as the government's expenditures on subsidies and incentives surged over the last several fiscal years.
This sharp spike is largely attributed to a massive backlog of arrears in the power sector and the rising costs of agricultural input</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 02:00:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UN calls for calm, urges all to refrain from violence</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/un-calls-for-calm-urges-all-to-refrain-from-violence-1</link><description>The United Nations Human Rights Office urges all to remain calm and to restrain from violence.
In the wake of the death of July protester, Sharif Osman Hadi and the violence that followed Jeremy Laurence, UN Human Rights Office spokesperson, on Friday said, "We are deeply troubled by the killing o</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 02:15:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>TIB condemns killing of Hadi, attacks on media houses</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tib-condemns-killing-of-hadi-attacks-on-media-houses</link><description>Transparency International Bangladesh (TIB) condemned the targeted killing of Inquilab Moncho spokesperson Osman Hadi and unprecedented destructive attacks on media freedom and dissent on Friday.
TIB requested that the government take responsibility and act effectively.
It expressed deep concern</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 02:30:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Worsening pollution fuels air purifier mkt</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/worsening-pollution-fuels-air-purifier-mkt</link><description>Amid the deteriorating air quality in Bangladesh, especially in the capital, businesses are identifying a growing opportunity in the sale of air purifiers.
Consumer adoption of this appliance is currently at a nascent stage, but it is likely to accelerate as public health awareness rises, say busi</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 02:45:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Stocks tumble amid growing political concerns</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/stocks-tumble-amid-growing-political-concerns</link><description>Stocks took a sharp downturn this week, reversing the gains made in the previous week, as jittery investors, unsettled by growing political unrest, rushed to dump their holdings across major sectors.
Analysts pointed to the escalating political concerns, particularly after the Election Commission</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 03:00:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Seven more market intermediaries get extra time to adjust negative equity</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/seven-more-market-intermediaries-get-extra-time-to-adjust-negative-equity</link><description>The Bangladesh Securities and Exchange Commission (BSEC) has given additional time to seven more market intermediaries to ensure compliance with provisioning requirements for unrealised losses and adjustments to negative equity.
The extension will take effect after December 31, when the current de</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 03:15:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NDF president Anisul's house set on fire in Chattogram</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ndf-president-anisuls-house-set-on-fire-in-chattogram</link><description>Miscreants set fire to the house of Barrister Anisul Islam Mahmud, president of the National Democratic Front (NDF), in Hathazari upazila of Chattogram district on Friday night.
Witnesses said some unidentified people swooped on the residence of Anisul around 11:40 pm and carried out vandalism.
L</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 04:33:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How ADR reshaping labour dispute redressal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/analysis/how-adr-reshaping-labour-dispute-redressal</link><description>In this dynamic era of industrialisation, the relationship between workers and employers is not merely a legal or administrative matter -- it is one of the key pillars of a nation's economic stability, productivity, and social harmony. The better the working environment, the greater the satisfactio</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 04:48:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IUB's ICEBTM 2025: A bold academic push against Bangladesh's jobless crisis</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/analysis/iubs-icebtm-2025-a-bold-academic-push-against-bangladeshs-jobless-crisis</link><description>One key reason behind China's rapid economic growth is its success in aligning the needs of industry with the skills produced by universities. China deliberately promoted close cooperation between academia and industry, creating mechanisms that move scientific research quickly into commercial use.</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 05:03:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>When civilisation ceases to exist</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/analysis/when-civilisation-ceases-to-exist</link><description>Evolution of civilisation is a long process. From its tentative beginning, a civilisation also ascends its summit at certain point and then the decline of the process also begins. Like human species or any other living being a civilisation sees many ups and downs and ultimately meets its end. Sever</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 05:18:38 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>