<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 09:24:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Paramount Skydance to cut 1,000 jobs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/paramount-skydance-to-cut-1000-jobs</link><description>Paramount Skydance will begin a major round of layoffs with about 1,000 job cuts on Wednesday, a source familiar with the matter said on Monday.
The job cuts, which follow the $8.4 billion merger between Skydance Media and Paramount Global, would impact roughly 5.0 per cent of Paramount's employee</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 07:01:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rain likely over Khulna, Barishal, Chattogram</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rain-likely-over-khulna-barishal-chattogram</link><description>The Bangladesh Meteorological Department (BMD) forecast rain or thundershowers at a few places over Khulna, Barishal and Chattogram divisions for the next 24 hours, beginning at 9:00 am today.
"Rain or thundershowers is likely to occur at a few places over Khulna, Barishal and Chattogram divisions</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 07:16:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chattogram Port disposes of long-stored hazardous goods in two-day operation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/chattogram-port-disposes-of-long-stored-hazardous-goods-in-two-day-operation</link><description>In a move to ensure port safety and environmental protection, a total of 19 containers of Dangerous Goods (DG) that had been lying unattended for years at Chattogram Port were safely destroyed over the weekend under strict supervision and environmental compliance.
The destruction process, conducte</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 07:46:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CA receives recommendations from Consensus Commission</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ca-receives-recommendations-from-consensus-commission</link><description>The National Consensus Commission has handed over its recommendations on the implementation of the July National Charter to Muhammad Yunus, chief advisor to the interim government.
The incident occurred after 1 pm on Tuesday at the chief advisor’s official residence, the State Guest House Ja</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 07:17:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CRAB holds 105th board meeting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/crab-holds-105th-board-meeting</link><description>The Credit Rating Agency of Bangladesh Ltd. (CRAB) held its 105th Board Meeting on October 27, 2025, at Square Center, Mohakhali.
The meeting was chaired by CRAB Chairman Noor A. Alam Chowdhury, according to a press release.
Among those present were board directors Tapan Chowdhury, Asif Saad Bin</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 07:32:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BUET admission applications open from Nov 16; exams start from Jan 10</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/buet-admission-applications-open-from-nov-16-exams-start-from-jan-10</link><description>Applications for the admission tests at the Bangladesh University of Engineering and Technology (BUET) will begin on November 16, with exams scheduled to start on January 10.
The Bangladesh University of Engineering and Technology on Monday published the admission circular for the 2025–26 ac</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 08:02:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ULAB hosted it’s 8th Convocation Ceremony</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/ulab-hosted-its-8th-convocation-ceremony</link><description>The University of Liberal Arts Bangladesh (ULAB) held its 8th Convocation on Tuesday at the Bangladesh-China Friendship Conference Centre, delving into the theme "Informed Minds, Inspire Paths”. The Chancellor’s Representative, Ms. Syeda Rizwana Hasan, Advisor for the Ministry of Enviro</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 08:32:06 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>