<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 15:40:17 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Dhaka University admission tests start Nov 28 for 2025-26 session</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/dhaka-university-admission-tests-start-nov-28-for-2025-26-session</link><description>Dhaka University has announced the schedule for admission application and exams for the 2025–2026 Academic Session, setting Nov 28 for the start of the tests.
According to a notice on Monday, applications for admission will begin on Oct 29 and continue until 11:59 pm on Nov 16.
The notice,</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 11:56:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Garment workers stages demo to press home 9-point demand</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/garment-workers-stages-demo-to-press-home-9-point-demand</link><description>The workers of a garment factory in Konabari area of Gazipur staged demonstrations in front of the factory to press-home their nine-point demand including payment of their salary within 7-10 days of a month.
Quoting witnesses, Morshed Zaman, inspector of Gazipur Industrial Police (Konabari zone) s</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 12:11:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pubali Bank donates two buses to BUET</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/pubali-bank-donates-two-buses-to-buet</link><description>As a part of Corporate Social Responsibility (CSR), the Board of Directors of Pubali Bank PLC donated two buses to Bangladesh University of Engineering and Technology (BUET), according to a press release.
Mohammad Ali, Managing Director and CEO of Pubali Bank PLC, handed over the key to Professor</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 12:26:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fishing ban hits poor fishermen hard, study finds</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fishing-ban-hits-poor-fishermen-hard-study-finds</link><description>As much as 56 per cent of small-scale fishers remain excluded from government aid during the annual fishing ban, pushing 70 per cent to take informal and exploitative loans, said a new study on Monday.
The situation often forces marginalised communities to fish illegally for survival, the study ad</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 12:41:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Al-Arafah Islami Bank signs agreement with ACI Godrej Agrovet</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/al-arafah-islami-bank-signs-agreement-with-aci-godrej-agrovet</link><description>A Memorandum of Understanding (MoU) has been signed between Al Arafah Islami Bank, the country’s leading Sharia-compliant bank, and ACI Godrej Agrovet Private Limited. Under the agreement, ACI Godrej will collect sales prices from its distributors through the bank’s branches, sub-branch</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 13:11:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCC Bank launches its 1st Annual Sustainability Report 2024</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ncc-bank-launches-its-1st-annual-sustainability-report-2024</link><description>NCC Bank officially launched its 1st Annual Sustainability Report 2024 during an “Awareness Building Program on Sustainable Finance” organized by the bank, according to a press release.
The report, prepared by prioritizing Environmental, Social, and Governance (ESG) issues, is expected</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 13:26:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BRAC Bank inaugurates new branch in Nikunja</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/brac-bank-inaugurates-new-branch-in-nikunja</link><description>BRAC Bank has inaugurated a new branch at Nikunja, Dhaka, to provide the best-in-class services and a delightful banking experience to its valued customers.
BRAC Bank’s Managing Director &amp; CEO Tareq Refat Ullah Khan formally inaugurated the branch at Asian Tower in Joar Sahara Commercial Are</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 13:41:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>2,000 police, 12 RAB units, 6 BGB platoons for RUCSU polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rucsu-polls-6-platoons-of-bgb-12-platoons-of-rab-2000-police-persecuted-to-guard-campus</link><description>The Rajshahi University Central Students’ Union (RUCSU), Senate student representative and hall union elections will be conducted under tight security.
At a coordination meeting on Monday afternoon, Rajshahi Metropolitan Police Commissioner Mohammad Abu Sufian said for the polls, 2,000 polic</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 14:11:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US is ready for deal with Iran when Tehran is, Trump says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-is-ready-for-deal-with-iran-when-tehran-is-trump-says</link><description>The United States is prepared to make a deal with Iran when Tehran is ready, US President Donald Trump said in a speech to the Israeli parliament on Monday.
Tehran and Washington held five rounds of nuclear talks, prior to a 12-day war between Iran and Israel in June, which Washington joined by st</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 14:41:17 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>