<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 17:17:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Election uncertainty may endanger democratic transition: Tarique</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/election-uncertainty-may-endanger-democratic-transition-tarique</link><description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman on Sunday voiced concern over the growing public doubt about whether the upcoming national election will be held as scheduled, saying that such uncertainty could put the country’s democratic transition at risk.
“During the rule of the fallen, defeated</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 14:14:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Building confidence to boost Japanese investment in Bangladesh: JBCCI president</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/building-confidence-to-boost-japanese-investment-in-bangladesh-jbcci-president</link><description>Japan-Bangladesh Chamber of Commerce and Industry (JBCCI) President Tareq Rafi Bhuiyan (Jun) has said Japanese investment in Bangladesh has grown nearly threefold over the past decade, but there is significant room to grow, compared to the broader landscape of Japanese investments in Asia.
“</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 14:29:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Transparency, consistency can unlock greater Japanese investment in Bangladesh’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/transparency-consistency-can-unlock-greater-japanese-investment-in-bangladesh</link><description>Kazuiki Kataoka, Country Representative of the Japan External Trade Organization (JETRO), Bangladesh, has said Bangladesh is gaining strong attention from Japanese investors.
“Every week, JETRO receives enquiries from companies across Japan seeking to understand Bangladesh’s economy an</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 14:59:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC restores JAGPA’s registration</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ec-restores-jagpas-registration</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has restored the registration of the Jatiya Ganotantrik Party (JAGPA), along with its electoral symbol, 'Hukka' following a directive from the court.
This information was revealed on Sunday through a circular signed by Akhtar Ahmed, the Senior Secretary of the EC Secre</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 15:14:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Bangladesh-Japan ties evolving from aid to strategic investment partnership’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/bangladesh-japan-ties-evolving-from-aid-to-strategic-investment-partnership</link><description>Secretary General of the Japan-Bangladesh Chamber of Commerce and Industry (JBCCI) Maria Howlader, FCA, has said Japan has been one of Bangladesh’s most trusted and time-tested partners for over five decades.
“Since the establishment of diplomatic relations in 1972, Japan—mainly</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 15:29:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Amar Ekushey Book Fair 2026 likely after polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/amar-ekushey-book-fair-2026-likely-after-polls</link><description>A meeting between the Director General of Bangla Academy Professor Mohammad Azam and a delegation from the Bangladesh Publishers and Booksellers Association was held today to discuss the possible schedule for the Amar Ekushey Book Fair 2026.
The meeting took place at 6:30 pm today, where the assoc</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 15:44:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two bodies recovered from building in North Badda</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/two-bodies-recovered-from-building-in-north-badda</link><description>Police recovered the bodies of a youth and a woman from a building in the city’s North Badda area on Sunday.
The deceased were identified as Saiful Islam, 28, a security guard of the building, and Sakila, 24, who worked there as a cleaner, said Officer-in-Charge of Badda Police Station Habib</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 15:59:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>25 injured as villagers clash in Faridpur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/25-injured-as-villagers-clash-in-faridpur</link><description>At least 25 people have been injured in a violent clash between two village groups in Faridpur’s Bhanga Upazila over a long-standing land dispute.
The confrontation began around 4pm on Sunday in Gopinathpur village, with both sides wearing helmets and wielding makeshift shields, bamboo stick</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 16:14:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Brahmanbaria Gunfight: Death toll rises to two</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/brahmanbaria-gunfight-death-toll-rises-to-two</link><description>The death toll from a gunfight over local dominance in Nabinagar upazila of Brahmanbaria has risen to two.
Hotel employee Yasin, son of Shafiqul Islam of Alamnagar village in Barikandi union, died from his injuries while undergoing treatment at Dhaka Medical College Hospital on Sunday afternoon, p</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 16:29:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No tourists on Day 2 in Saint Martin’s Island</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/no-tourists-on-day-2-in-saint-martins-island</link><description>For the second day of the tourist season, not a single visitor have travelled to Saint Martin’s Island, leaving local traders disheartened after being granted permission to operate for three months.
Although overnight stays are not allowed in November, small traders -- particularly restauran</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 16:59:44 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>