<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 15:22:37 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Ireland offers support for police reform in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ireland-offers-support-for-police-reform-in-bangladesh</link><description>Ireland has expressed its willingness to share experience and expertise in police reform to support Bangladesh’s ongoing efforts to strengthen accountable and rights-based governance following the July 2024 uprising.
Non-resident Ambassador of Ireland to Bangladesh, Kevin Kelly, and Baroness</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 11:52:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC orders all voter transfer requests to be resolved by Nov 17</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-orders-all-voter-transfer-requests-to-be-resolved-by-nov-17</link><description>Ahead of the next parliamentary election, the Election Commission has instructed that all voter transfer applications must be resolved by November 17.
On Wednesday, Senior Assistant Secretary Nasir Uddin Chowdhury issued the directive to field officers.
According to the notice, applications for v</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 12:07:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP candidate Ershad Ullah, another shot in Chattogram</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-candidate-ershad-ullah-another-shot-in-chattogram</link><description>Two people, including BNP candidate of Chattogram-8 constituency Ershad Ullah, were shot in an attack by armed miscreants during electioneering in Bayezid area of Chattagram port city on Wednesday.
The other injured person was identified as Sarwar Babla, UNB reports. 
Officer-in-charge of Ba</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 12:37:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Female entrepreneurs urge EC for nomination of women in 150 seats</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/female-entrepreneurs-urge-ec-for-nomination-of-women-in-150-seats</link><description>A delegation of women entrepreneurs on Wednesday urged the Election Commission (EC) to ensure that female candidates are nominated in at least 150 parliamentary seats and facilitate women voters in exercising their franchise in the national election.
The delegation, led by President of Women Entre</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 12:52:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Salahuddin steps down from national team coaching set-up</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/cricket/salahuddin-steps-down-from-national-team-coaching-set-up</link><description>Bangladesh national men's cricket team's senior assistant coach Mohammed Salahuddin has submitted his resignation to the Bangladesh Cricket Board (BCB) CEO.
He will leave his position at the end of the upcoming Test and T20I series against Ireland.
Chairman of BCB’s Cricket Operations Commi</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 13:22:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Administrators appointed to 5 banks ahead of major merger</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/administrators-appointed-to-5-banks-ahead-of-major-merger</link><description>Bangladesh Bank (BB) has appointed temporary administrators to each of the five struggling Shariah-based banks as part of its plan to merge them into a single entity under the Bank Resolution Ordinance. 
Bangladesh Bank (BB) Governor Ahsan H Mansur today (Wednesday) confirmed it at a press co</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 13:37:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP leader found dead in Cox’s Bazar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/bnp-leader-found-dead-in-coxs-bazar</link><description>A BNP leader was found dead under a bridge in Teknaf upazila of Cox’s Bazar district on Wednesday.
The deceased was identified as Yunus Shikdar, convener of Arafat Rahman Koko Krira Sangsad Teknaf upazila unit and a member of No One ward of Sabrang union.
Himel Roy, office-in-charge of Tekn</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 13:52:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pubali Bank PLC signs agreement with VISA Worldwide Pte Limited</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/pubali-bank-plc-signs-agreement-with-visa-worldwide-pte-limited</link><description>Recently, Pubali Bank PLC and Visa Worldwide Pte. Limited signed an agreement to launch promotion, marketing, and various incentive programs for Visa card and POS acquiring business by Pubali Bank PLC.
Managing Director &amp; Chief Executive Office of Pubali Bank PLC. Mohammad Ali; Country Manager of</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 14:22:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Justice Muhammad Khurshid Alam Sarkar removed from High Court</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/justice-muhammad-khurshid-alam-sarkar-removed-from-high-court</link><description>Justice Muhammad Khurshid Alam Sarkar of the High Court Division has been removed from his position as a judge.
A gazette issued by the Law and Justice Division and signed by Secretary Liaquet Ali Molla stated that, based on an investigation by the Supreme Judicial Council, Justice Khurshid Alam S</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 14:37:57 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>