<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 05:21:52 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>BNP to focus on vibrant capital market, if voted to power: Khosru</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-to-focus-on-vibrant-capital-market-if-voted-to-power-khosru</link><description>BNP standing committee member Amir Khosru Mahmud Chowdhury said on Saturday the party would put its focus on how to make the reeling capital market vibrant to lessen pressure on the banks if it is voted to power.
The former commerce minister shared the party's priority pledges ahead of the upcomin</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 02:15:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Energy issues weigh heavy on private sector</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/energy-issues-weigh-heavy-on-private-sector</link><description>The private sector is facing a deepening crisis as persistent gas shortages and repeated energy price hikes have slashed output up to a half in key industries, sparking concerns over economic growth, employment, and competitiveness of Bangladesh's manufacturing base, economists and industrialists w</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 02:30:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt may approve third revision of MRT-6 project tomorrow</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-may-approve-third-revision-of-mrt-6-project-tomorrow</link><description>With massive cost escalations in areas such as consultancy and electro-mechanical systems, the government may revise the MRT-6 project for the third time tomorrow (Monday), extending the timeline by three years, officials said on Saturday.
Despite the proposed removal of four station plazas -- a k</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 02:45:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ICB seeks CIB list waiver for its officials becoming defaulter cos' directors</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/icb-seeks-cib-list-waiver-for-its-officials-becoming-defaulter-cos-directors</link><description>The Investment Corporation of Bangladesh (ICB) has urged the authorities concerned to take necessary steps so that its officials are not enlisted as defaulters by the central bank's Credit Information Bureau (CIB), when they are nominated as directors of any loan defaulter company.
The state-run e</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 03:00:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Election schedule likely in second week of Dec</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/election-schedule-likely-in-second-week-of-dec</link><description>The schedule for the next parliamentary elections and referendum is likely to be announced in the second week of December, Chief Election Commissioner (CEC) AMM Nasir Uddin said on Saturday.
"Hopefully, we are expecting it (schedule announcement) to take place in the second week of December," he s</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 03:15:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NPLs jump to 34pc as stricter rules expose hidden defaults</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/npls-jump-to-34pc-as-stricter-rules-expose-hidden-defaults</link><description>Non-performing loans (NPLs) in Bangladesh's agriculture sector have surged to substantial levels, with nearly 34 per cent of outstanding farm credit now classified as defaulted, according to the latest Bangladesh Bank (BB) data.
The sharp rise has heightened concerns over the financial stability o</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 03:30:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Experts warn of extreme earthquake risk</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/experts-warn-of-extreme-earthquake-risk</link><description>Bangladesh faces an alarming level of earthquake risk due to its location atop three active tectonic fault lines, earthquake specialists warned on Saturday.
They cautioned that without immediate, coordinated action, the country could face a large-scale humanitarian disaster.
Their concerns were r</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 03:20:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ICB hides losses by valuing securities at cost with regulatory approval</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/icb-hides-losses-by-valuing-securities-at-cost-with-regulatory-approval</link><description>The state-run Investment Corporation of Bangladesh (ICB) avoids showing actual losses by valuing its investments in securities at cost rather than at current market value.
The Bangladesh Bank has issued a 'no objection' to reporting investments at cost price in the financial statements of ICB, the</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 03:35:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Beximco Pharma a company of general investors run by professionals: CFO Ali Nawaz</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/beximco-pharma-a-company-of-general-investors-run-by-professionals-cfo-ali-nawaz</link><description>Beximco Pharma, one of Bangladesh's leading drugmakers, has long been run by professionals with no board interference in its daily operations. The company is largely owned by general investors, who hold 86 per cent of its shares, while sponsors hold the remaining 14 per cent, said its Chief Financi</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 03:50:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sonadia Island under severe existential threat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/sonadia-island-under-severe-existential-threat</link><description>Sonadia Island, a natural reserve island in Maheshkhali upazila, 15 kilometres north-west of Cox's Bazar district, is under severe existential threat.
In the name of development of tourism, hotels and resorts are being built by cutting down the tamarisk trees in the mangrove forest and destroying</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 04:05:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gopalganj farmers to get half a billion from jute sale in two upazilas</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/gopalganj-farmers-to-get-half-a-billion-from-jute-sale-in-two-upazilas</link><description>Jute farmers in Gopalganj's Muksudpur and Kashiani upazilas will get half a billion taka this year by selling jute sticks.
The Department of Agricultural Extension, (DAE), Gopalganj, targeted 68,960 tonnes of jute stick production from the jute cultivated on 17,240 hectares in two upazilas this ye</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 04:20:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hallmark MD Tanvir dies in custody</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hallmark-md-tanvir-dies-in-custody</link><description>Hallmark Group’s managing director Md Tanvir Mahmud has died while serving his prison sentence for a long-standing loan fraud case.
Prison authorities reported that he passed away at Dhaka Medical College Hospital on Saturday night around 10:30 pm, reports bdnews24.com.
Assistant Inspector</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 04:35:29 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>