<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 15:39:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Food aid in Somalia could halt within weeks due to funding shortages, WFP warns</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/africa/food-aid-in-somalia-could-halt-within-weeks-due-to-funding-shortages-wfp-warns</link><description>The UN World Food Programme said on Friday its life-saving food and nutrition assistance in Somalia could grind to a halt by April unless new funding is secured, putting millions of people at risk of worsening hunger.
An estimated 4.4 million people face crisis-level food insecurity, with nearly o</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 11:59:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Eight feared dead after a bus with Chinese tourists sinks into Russia's Lake Baikal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/eight-feared-dead-after-a-bus-with-chinese-tourists-sinks-into-russias-lake-baikal</link><description>Seven Chinese tourists and a bus driver are feared dead after a tourist bus driving across a frozen stretch of Lake Baikal in Russia's Siberia plunged into the water when the ice broke beneath it, local governor, Igor Kobzev, said on Friday via his channel in Telegram.
One tourist managed to escap</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 12:14:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ex-Biman MD sent to jail in housemaid assault case</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ex-biman-md-sent-to-jail-in-housemaid-assault-case</link><description>A Dhaka court on Friday sent former Managing Director of Biman Bangladesh Airlines, Dr Md Shafiqur Rahman, to jail in a case filed over the alleged assault of his 11-year-old housemaid.
Dhaka Metropolitan Magistrate Alberuni Mir passed the order in the afternoon. Another accused, housemaid Sufia B</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 12:29:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>TIB slates transport minister for toll remarks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tib-rebukes-minister-over-claim-consensual-roadside-collections-are-not-extortion</link><description>Transparency International Bangladesh (TIB) has criticised the transport minister’s description of roadside collections as “compromise-based transactions”, calling it an “attempt to legitimise a serious criminal offence”.
In a statement issued on Friday, the local cha</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 12:44:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Family card’ rollout before Eid: relief minister</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/family-card-scheme-will-launch-before-eid-ul-fitr-says-minister-dulu</link><description>The government will introduce the “family card” programme before Eid ul-Fitr, according to Disaster Management and Relief Minister Asadul Habib Dulu.
The distribution will begin as a pilot project in eight Upazilas, prioritising the poorest households, he said on Friday afternoon in La</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 12:59:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Delhi seeks ‘stronger’ ties with Dhaka: Jaiswal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/india-looks-to-strengthen-multifaceted-relations-with-bangladesh-says-jaiswal</link><description>India has voiced its expectation of strengthening its “multifaceted” relationship with Bangladesh.
At a weekly briefing on Friday, Ministry of External Affairs spokesperson Randhir Jaiswal said Prime Minister Narendra Modi congratulated Bangladesh Prime Minister Tarique Rahman soon aft</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 13:14:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Finance minister pledges ‘revolutionary’ shift in economy, stock market</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/finance-minister-pledges-revolutionary-shift-in-economy-stock-market</link><description>Finance and Planning Minister Amir Khosru Mahmud Chowdhury on Friday pledged sweeping changes to the country’s economy and capital markets, vowing that a 'revolutionary transformation' is on the way.
Talking to reporters at Shah Amanat International Airport as he arrived in Chattogram after</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 13:29:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Police search royal mansion as investigation into king’s brother goes on</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/police-search-royal-mansion-as-investigation-into-kings-brother-goes-on</link><description>British police were searching the former mansion of King Charles’ younger brother Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor on Friday after a photograph of the royal emerging from a police station was splashed on newspapers around the world.
Mountbatten-Windsor was arrested on Thursday, his 66th birthday,</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 13:44:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Canal excavation to begin in 15 days: Farhad</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/state-minister-farhad-says-canal-excavation-will-start-within-15-days</link><description>The government will begin its canal excavation programme within the next 15 days, State Minister for Water Resources Farhad Hossain Azad has said.
Speaking after a meeting with local residents of Boda Upazila in Panchagarh on Friday afternoon, he said swift action would be taken to restore the cou</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 14:09:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Spain's top court rejects father's bid to halt daughter's euthanasia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/spains-top-court-rejects-fathers-bid-to-halt-daughters-euthanasia</link><description>Spain's Constitutional Court has rejected an appeal by the father of a 25‑year‑old paraplegic woman who opposes her access to euthanasia, the court said in a statement on Friday.
In 2021, Spain became the fourth European Union country to legalise euthanasia and assisted suicide for people with inc</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 14:24:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BSEC chairman urges richer reporting as verified information protects capital market</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/bsec-chairman-urges-richer-reporting-as-verified-information-protects-capital-market</link><description>The Bangladesh Securities and Exchange Commission (BSEC) has insisted that the capital market must remain free of “garbage,” with any misleading or unverified information removed immediately.
BSEC Chairman Khondoker Rashed Maqsood said journalists are actively helping in this process b</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 14:39:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Meghmallar Bosu hospitalised after ‘overdose’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/students-union-leader-meghmallar-hospitalised-after-overdosing</link><description>Meghmallar Bosu, president of a faction of the Dhaka University unit of the Bangladesh Students’ Union, has been admitted to hospital after “taking a large dose of medicine”.
He was admitted to Dhaka’s Shaheed Suhrawardy Medical College Hospital on Friday afternoon, the org</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 14:54:12 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>