<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 08:32:46 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Changing global poverty landscape and rising risks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/reviews/changing-global-poverty-landscape-and-rising-risks</link><description>The world today stands at a pivotal moment in its long struggle against poverty. For decades, policymakers celebrated remarkable progress in eradicating poverty. The share of people living in extreme poverty fell from nearly 38 per cent in 1990 to below 10 per cent by the end of the 2010s. Much of</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 05:31:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A life that refused to bow</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/reviews/a-life-that-refused-to-bow</link><description>With the demise of Khaleda Zia (1945-2025), Bangladesh is not only bidding farewell to a former prime minister but also to an era. It is an era that encapsulates not only the political struggles but the moral fabric of this republic. It is an era born of resistance, an era in which its dreams of de</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 05:46:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chuadanga records season's lowest temperature at 8.2°C</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/chuadanga-records-seasons-lowest-temperature-at-82c</link><description>Chuadanga has recorded this winter's lowest temperature as the mercury plunged to 8.2 degrees Celsius amid dense fog. At the same time, chilly winds have been blowing, causing severe cold across the district.
The temperature was recorded at 6:00 am on Wednesday, according to Altaf Hossain, an obse</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 05:45:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nation mourns as it prepares to bid farewell to Khaleda Zia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nation-mourns-as-it-prepares-to-bid-farewell-to-khaleda-zia</link><description>Bangladesh is in mourning following the death of Khaleda Zia, the country’s first female prime minister.
A three-day state mourning period began on Wednesday, with the national flag flown at half-mast at all government, autonomous and private institutions, educational establishments, and Ban</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 06:00:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Braving cold and fog, mourners gather to bid farewell to Khaleda Zia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/braving-cold-and-fog-mourners-gather-to-bid-farewell-to-khaleda-zia</link><description>Braving biting winter cold and dense fog, thousands of mourners converged on Manik Mia Avenue on Wednesday to offer final prayers for former prime minister Begum Khaleda Zia, turning the capital into a sea of grief, remembrance and quiet reverence.
People from different parts of the country began</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 06:15:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khaleda Zia's body reaches Manik Mia Avenue, janaza at 2pm</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/khaleda-zias-body-reaches-manik-mia-avenue-janaza-at-2pm</link><description>The body of BNP Chairperson and three-time former Prime Minister Begum Khaleda Zia, widely regarded as an uncompromising leader for democracy in Bangladesh, reached Manik Mia Avenue around 11:50 am on Wednesday for her namaz-e-janaza, scheduled to be held at 2:00 pm.
A motorcade carrying her body</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 06:30:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Zohran Mamdani is set to be sworn in as mayor as NYC rings in the New Year</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/zohran-mamdani-is-set-to-be-sworn-in-as-mayor-as-nyc-rings-in-the-new-year</link><description>Zohran Mamdani will become mayor of New York City as the clock ticks over into 2026 — but the celebrations are set to last through New Year's Day.
 
The Democrat's team is planning two separate swearing-in ceremonies Thursday — a small, private one with his family in an old subwa</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 06:45:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nepalese FM in Dhaka to attend Khaleda’s funeral</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nepalese-fm-in-dhaka-to-attend-khaledas-funeral</link><description>Nepalese Foreign Affairs Minister Bala Nanda Sharma arrived in Dhaka on Tuesday night to attend the state funeral of former Prime Minister and Chairperson of the Bangladesh Nationalist Party Begum Khaleda Zia and pay last respects on behalf of the government and the people of Nepal.
Secretar</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 07:00:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bhutan FM arrives to attend Khaleda’s funeral</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bhutan-fm-arrives-to-attend-khaledas-funeral</link><description>Bhutan’e Foreign Affairs and External Trade Minister Lyonpo D. N. Dhungyel arrived in Dhaka this morning to attend the state funeral of former prime minister and BNP chairperson Begum Khaleda Zia on behalf of his government.
He was received at Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport (HSIA) &amp;n</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 07:15:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jaishankar in Dhaka to pay last respect to ex-PM Khaleda</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jaishankar-in-dhaka-to-pay-last-respect-to-ex-pm-khaleda</link><description>External Affairs Minister Dr S Jaishankar arrived in Dhaka on Wednesday to represent the government and people of India at the funeral of three-time former Prime Minister and Chairperson of the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) Khaleda Zia.
As Delhi believes Khaleda Zia’s vision and legacy</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 07:30:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pakistan’s Speaker arrives to attend Khaleda Zia’s funeral</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/pakistans-speaker-arrives-to-attend-khaleda-zias-funeral</link><description>Speaker of Pakistan’s National Assembly Sardar Ayaz Sadiq arrived in Dhaka on Wednesday morning to attend the funeral of former prime minister and BNP chairperson Begum Khaleda Zia today, representing the Government of Pakistan.
He was received at Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport (HSIA</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 07:45:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tk 5,000 fine for selling cigarettes near schools, hospitals</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tk-5000-fine-for-selling-cigarettes-near-schools-hospitals</link><description>The government has promulgated the Smoking and Tobacco Products Usage (Control) (Amendment) Ordinance, 2025, with a provision of maximum fine of Tk 5,000 for selling cigarettes or tobacco products in areas near educational institutions, hospitals and other sensitive areas.
The ordinance was promul</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 08:00:45 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>