<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 10:17:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Bangladesh, EU agree to conclude PCA negotiation earliest</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/bangladesh-eu-agree-to-conclude-pca-negotiation-earliest</link><description>Bangladesh and the European Union (EU) have agreed to continue working intensively with the objective of concluding the Comprehensive Partnership and Cooperation Agreement (PCA) negotiations at the earliest possible time. 
The consensus was made during the third round of negotiations on the P</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 06:33:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fisherman killed by lightning strike in Kishoreganj</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fisherman-killed-by-lightning-strike-in-kishoreganj</link><description>A fisherman was killed and two others were injured in a lightning strike at Chikni haor of Borgaon village under Tarail upazila of the district this morning.
The deceased was identified as Bajlu Mia, 48, son of late Ramzan Ali of Borgaon village under Jawar union of the upazila.
Lightning, follow</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 06:48:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nation bids farewell to eminent academic Syed Manzoorul Islam</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nation-bids-farewell-to-eminent-academic-syed-manzoorul-islam</link><description>Emeritus Professor Syed Manzoorul Islam has been laid to rest after people from all walks of life gathered to honour and bid farewell to one of the country's most respected literary and academic figures.
From 11am to 1pm on Monday, his body was kept at the Central Shaheed Minar, where mourners --</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 07:18:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump administration lays off dozens of CDC officials, NYT reportsTrump administration lays off dozens of CDC officials, NYT reports</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/trump-administration-lays-off-dozens-of-cdc-officials-nyt-reportstrump-administration-lays-off-dozens-of-cdc-officials-nyt-reports</link><description>The Trump administration has laid off dozens of employees at the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention in its latest round of cuts, including "disease detectives”, high-ranking scientists and the entire Washington office, the New York Times reported on Saturday.
The White House and the</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 07:33:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Israel rejects release of most popular Palestinian leader from prison</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/israel-rejects-release-of-most-popular-palestinian-leader-from-prison</link><description>The most popular and potentially unifying Palestinian leader — Marwan Barghouti — is not among the prisoners Israel intends to free in exchange for hostages held by Hamas under the new Gaza ceasefire deal.
Israel has also rejected freeing other high-profile prisoners whose release Hama</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 07:48:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Unbearable and ordinary life keeps going: Krasznahorkai, the Nobel winner</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/others/unbearable-and-ordinary-life-keeps-going-krasznahorkai-the-nobel-winner</link><description>Life, he seems to say, is both unbearable and ordinary, and that is the secret reason people keep going.
This year, the Nobel Prize in Literature went to László Krasznahorkai — a writer whose sentences refuse to stop and whose worlds never quite make sense. For many, his novels</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 08:18:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CA to leave for Rome on Sunday to join WFF event</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ca-to-leave-for-rome-on-sunday-to-join-wff-event</link><description>Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus will leave for Rome on Sunday to join a flagship event of the World Food Forum (WFF).
A flight of Biman Bangladesh Airlines, carrying the chief adviser and his entourage, will depart from Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport (HSIA) here around 11.30 am, Chi</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 08:33:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prisoner dies at DMCH</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/prisoner-dies-at-dmch</link><description>An inmate of Dhaka Central Jail died at Dhaka Medical College Hospital (DMCH) on Saturday.
The deceased was identified as Miaz Uddin, 60, son of Binod Ali, reports UNB.
Inspector Md Faruk, in charge of DMCH police camp, said Miaz Uddin fell sick at the jail on Friday night and he was taken to the</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 08:48:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nobel Prize in Physics marks 100 years of Quantum wonders</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/nobel-prize-in-physics-marks-100-years-of-quantum-wonders</link><description>It's been a hundred years since scientists opened the mysterious box of quantum theory. The questions have only grown stranger. This year, the Nobel Prize in Physics goes to three researchers—John Clark, Michelle Deere, and John Martinez—for their groundbreaking work on quantum tunnelli</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 09:03:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Security beefed up at Ctg airport, port amid fears of cyber attack</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/security-beefed-up-at-ctg-airport-port-amid-fears-of-cyber-attack</link><description>Authorities have strengthened security in and around Shah Amanat International Airport and the seaport amid fears of possible cyberattacks.
To prevent any untoward incidents, the airport and police authorities have taken joint precautionary measures including setting up a four-tier security cordon</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 09:18:59 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>