<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 09:55:16 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>EC transfers 112 officials to upazila level</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-transfers-112-officials-to-upazila-level</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has transferred 112 officials from its secretariat and subordinate offices to various upazila and thana-level postings across the country.
An official order in this regard was issued today, signed by Assistant Secretary Mohammad Shahidur Rahman.
According to the order</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 06:24:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt approves withdraw of 1,202 more politically motivated cases</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-approves-withdraw-of-1202-more-politically-motivated-cases</link><description>Home Minister Salahuddin Ahmed has said the government has approved the withdrawal of 1,202 more politically motivated cases filed against opposition party leaders and activists during the 17-year rule of the fascist Awami League (AL).
The decision came after a thorough review process to assess al</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 06:39:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mexican cartel clashes fuel worries in lead up to FIFA World Cup</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/mexican-cartel-clashes-fuel-worries-in-lead-up-to-fifa-world-cup</link><description>Maria Dolores Aguirre's family corner store has lived off tourism that has flowed into her charming cobblestoned town of Tapalpa, tucked away in the mountains of Jalisco state.
That was until gunshots erupted and helicopters flew overhead as the Mexican army killed the country's most powerful drug</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 06:54:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Foreign investors keen on Nagad, Jamaat MP tells BB governor</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/foreign-investors-keen-on-nagad-jamaat-mp-tells-bb-governor</link><description>Barrister Mir Ahmad Bin Quasem Arman, a newly elected lawmaker from Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami, held discussions with the central bank governor on bringing global investors to the mobile financial service provider Nagad.
Barrister Arman arrived at the Bangladesh Bank (BB) headquarters at around 11</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 07:09:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Government to form commission to probe 2009 BDR mutiny: Salahuddin</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/government-to-form-commission-to-probe-2009-bdr-mutiny-salahuddin</link><description>Home Minister Salahuddin Ahmed has said the government will constitute a commission to reinvestigate the 2009 BDR carnage inside Pilkhana in the capital.
“We will constitute another enquiry commission to investigate the BDR carnage as per our decision to ensure justice,” he said.
The</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 07:24:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nepali video falsely circulated against BNP: BanglaFact</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nepali-video-falsely-circulated-against-bnp-banglafact</link><description>BanglaFact, the fact-checking and media research wing of the Press Institute of Bangladesh (PIB), has identified a misleading campaign on social media using a video from Nepal to target the BNP.
According to BanglaFact, the video being circulated with claims that a BNP leader beat an elderly man i</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 07:39:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Court orders seizure of Sheikh Rehana’s husband Shafiq’s tax records</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/court-orders-seizure-of-sheikh-rehanas-husband-shafiqs-tax-records</link><description>A Dhaka court has ordered the seizure of income tax records of Shafiq Siddiqi, husband of Sheikh Rehana, in connection with an investigation into alleged illicit wealth amounting to nearly Tk 87.5 million.
Dhaka Metropolitan Senior Special Judge Sabbir Faiz passed the order on Tuesday after a peti</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 07:54:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two fishermen shot by ‘pirates’ in Bay of Bengal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/two-fishermen-shot-by-pirates-in-bay-of-bengal</link><description>Two fishermen have been injured in an alleged pirate attack while fishing in the Bay of Bengal near the Sundarbans.
The incident occurred around 4am on Saturday near Narikelbaria, Golam Mostofa Chowdhury, president of the Barguna District Fishermen Trawler Owners’ Association, said.
He adde</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 07:56:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gas explosion in Chattogram claims third life</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/gas-explosion-in-chattogram-claims-third-life</link><description>Another victim has died following a gas explosion in the port city of Chattogram, raising the death toll to three, officials said.
Md Samir Ahmed Suman, 40, died at about 11:55 am on Tuesday while receiving treatment in the Intensive Care Unit (ICU) of the National Institute of Burn and Plastic Su</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 08:11:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>'BNP's position is very clear': Moyeen Khan weighs in on Awami League's return</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnps-position-is-very-clear-moyeen-khan-weighs-in-on-awami-leagues-return</link><description>BNP Standing Committee member Abdul Moyeen Khan has said his party believes in multi-party democracy and does not support “one-party rule” amid questions over the possible return of the Awami League to active politics.
He made the remarks on Tuesday morning after placing wreaths at the</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 08:26:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bogura-6, Sherpur-3 by-polls likely on April 9</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bogura-6-sherpur-3-by-polls-likely-on-april-9</link><description>By-elections to two parliamentary constituencies – Bogura-6 and Sherpur-3 -- are likely to be held on April 09 next.
The Election Commission is considering April 9 as the tentative date to hold by-elections in the two constituencies, an EC official said on Tuesday.
He said the schedule for</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 08:41:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>President to pay tribute to BDR martyrs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/president-to-pay-tribute-to-bdr-martyrs</link><description>President Mohammed Shahabuddin will pay tribute to martyred BDR (Now BGB) members at Banani military graveyard on Wednesday.
The President will place a wreath at 10:00 am, marking the National Martyred Army Day, said a notification issued by the Protocol Wing of the President’s Office on Mon</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 08:56:26 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>