<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 08:31:38 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Japan's new PM preparing large economic stimulus to tackle inflation, sources say</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/japans-new-pm-preparing-large-economic-stimulus-to-tackle-inflation-sources-say</link><description>Japan's new Prime Minister Sanae Takaichi is preparing an economic stimulus package that is likely to exceed last year's $92 billion to help households tackle inflation, government sources familiar with the plan said on Wednesday.
The package of more than 13.9 trillion yen ($92.19 billion) marks T</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 06:03:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>70pc banks yet to embrace AI in cybersecurity, BIBM survey finds</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/70pc-banks-yet-to-embrace-ai-in-cybersecurity-bibm-survey-finds</link><description>A recent survey by the Bangladesh Institute of Bank Management (BIBM) has revealed that the majority of banks in the country remain far from adopting artificial intelligence (AI) for automating incident response in cybersecurity operations.
According to the survey, about 70 per cent of banks have</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 06:33:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Yunus set for talks with NCP, Jamaat today</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/yunus-set-for-talks-with-ncp-jamaat-today</link><description>Chief Advisor Muhammad Yunus is scheduled to meet with leaders of the National Citizen Party (NCP) and Jamaat-e-Islami as part of the ongoing political dialogue ahead of the upcoming 13th national election.
The head of the interim government will hold talks with an NCP delegation at 5:15pm on Wedn</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 06:29:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ACCGP approves 1 lakh tonnes of rice import worth Tk 446.22 crore</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/accgp-approves-1-lakh-tonnes-of-rice-import-worth-tk-44622-crore</link><description>The Advisers Council Committee on Government Purchase (ACCGP) on Wednesday gave approval for the import of a total of 100,000 metric tonnes of rice, including parboiled and Atap varieties, worth about Tk 446.22 crore, alongside several key infrastructure and power sector proposals at its meeting.</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 06:44:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Seven Pacific Jeans factories to reopen Thursday after weeklong closure</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/seven-pacific-jeans-factories-to-reopen-thursday-after-weeklong-closure</link><description>Seven factories of Pacific Jeans Group, one of the country's leading garment exporters, are set to reopen tomorrow (Thursday) following a week-long closure due to “attacks on factories and poor working conditions.”
The information was confirmed in a company notice signed by Managing Di</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 08:14:51 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>