<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 23:18:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Sarjis, ex-student leader trade barbs in Manikganj</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/heated-words-fly-in-manikganj-between-sarjis-and-former-students-against-discrimination-leader</link><description>A heated exchange has erupted between NCP Chief Organiser (North) Sarjis Alam and a former leader of the Students Against Discrimination Movement in Manikganj.
The altercation took place towards the end of the NCP’s coordination meeting held at the City Dream Hotel and Convention Hall, accor</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 17:04:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Can Donald Trump serve a third term as US president?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/can-donald-trump-serve-a-third-term-as-us-president</link><description>President Donald Trump on Monday declined to dismiss speculation that he would seek a third term and said he hadn't considered whether he would go to court to contest the US Constitution's two-term limit for presidents.
Here is a look at the legal barriers Trump faces.
WHAT DOES THE CONSTITUTION</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 17:19:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Japan plans to recruit 100,000 workers in phases</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/japanese-delegation-briefs-yunus-on-recruitment-plan-of-100000-worker-over-five-years</link><description>A high-level Japanese delegation has presented the progress in recruiting 100,000 skilled Bangladeshi workers to Chief Advisor Muhammad Yunus.
The 23-member delegation from the National Business Support Combined Cooperatives (NBCC) met Yunus at the State Guest House Jamuna on Sunday afternoon, the</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 16:35:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Putin says 'everything going to plan' with North Korea</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/putin-says-everything-going-to-plan-with-north-korea</link><description>Russian President Vladimir Putin asked North Korean Foreign Minister Choe Son Hui during talks in the Kremlin on Monday to tell his country's leader Kim Jong Un that everything was "going to plan" in bilateral relations.
Putin and Kim sealed a strategic partnership treaty last year, which included</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 16:50:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UP member publicly shaves five youths’ heads at Patuakhali village arbitration</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/up-member-publicly-shaves-five-youths-heads-at-patuakhali-village-arbitration</link><description>A Union Parishad member in Patuakhali’s Rangabali Upazila has been accused of forcibly shaving the heads of five youths in public as a form of punishment during a village arbitration following a skirmish.
Rangabali Upazila administrator (UNO) Rajib Das Purkaystha said a three-member inquiry</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 17:05:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Short-run vs long-run inflation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/short-run-vs-long-run-inflation</link><description>Whenever we go grocery shopping, prices, particularly food prices feel much more than the single-digit inflation figure suggests. Economic statistics can often obscure lived experience, and our daily reality often tells a different story, the one of steadily eroding purchasing power over years and</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 17:20:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Is Myanmar resistance in retreat?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/is-myanmar-resistance-in-retreat</link><description>Has the Myanmar Army now been gaining the upper hand over the rebels and regaining territory lost to the rebel forces so far? A BBC report says that with the support of China, the Myanmar army has intensified air strikes against the rebel held positions. Earlier, when the Myanmar government forces</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 17:35:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>South Asia can't afford another war</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/south-asia-cant-afford-another-war</link><description>The border between Pakistan and Afghanistan has always been more than a line on a map. It is a frontier where geopolitics, history, and mistrust converge - often violently. Today, as tensions flare once again along the Durand Line, the prospect of another conflict in this fragile region casts a lon</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 17:50:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka's preeminence and the paradox</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/dhakas-preeminence-and-the-paradox</link><description>Dhaka District's preeminence on account of the capital city it hosts is quite logical. But such a primacy is not axiomatic. In many countries commercial capitals outstrip their administrative capitals particularly on the strength of economic muscle. Even in Bangladesh, Chattogram had the potential</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 18:05:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>'Neglect’ in probe: Mayor issues notice to CCC CEO</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/mayor-issues-notice-to-chattogram-city-corporation-ceo-over-negligence-in-investigation</link><description>Mayor Sahadat Hossain has served a show-cause notice to Chattogram City Corporation (CCC) chief executive officer on the charge of “negligence in duty”.
The mayor alleged that CEO Sheikh Mohammed Tauhidul Islam had neglected the investigation into allegations of irregularities in tax a</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 18:20:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Worry overshadows Asycuda replacement move</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/worry-overshadows-asycuda-replacement-move</link><description>A government move to phase out from the tested customs digital-platform Asycuda to adopt an advanced system has raised more concerns than corroboration from stakeholders in foreign trade and national revenue.



Customs authority, economists and businesses foresee a possible setback in import</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 19:33:25 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>