<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 22:25:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Bangladesh to showcase global textile leadership at Heimtextil 2026</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladesh-to-showcase-global-textile-leadership-at-heimtextil-2026</link><description>Bangladesh is set to reinforce its position as a global powerhouse in the textile sector by participating in Heimtextil 2026, the world’s largest trade fair for home and contract textiles.
Scheduled to take place from January 13–16, 2026, in Frankfurt, Germany, the event serves as a cr</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 16:27:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UK condemns Iran leadership for 'brutal killing' of protesters</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/uk-condemns-iran-leadership-for-brutal-killing-of-protesters</link><description>British foreign minister Yvette Cooper on Tuesday condemned the Iranian leadership for what she described as the “horrendous and brutal killing” of protesters, saying Britain had summoned the Iranian ambassador to underline the gravity of the situation.
“The United Kingdom condem</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 16:42:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gas supply cut off in Uttara, nearby areas after valve rupture: Titas</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/gas-supply-cut-off-in-uttara-nearby-areas-after-valve-rupture-titas</link><description>A valve on an industrial customer’s service line near the Uttara–Tongi Bridge ruptured on Tuesday, triggering a high-pressure gas leak and forcing an immediate shutdown of supply through Uttara’s main pipeline, according to a statement from Titas Gas Transmission and Distribution</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 16:57:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CU administration accused of bias in granting hall parliament leader preferred subject</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/cu-administration-accused-of-bias-in-granting-hall-parliament-leader-preferred-subject</link><description>Allegations of bias have been made against the Chittagong University administration in the transfer of a first-year student of the Institute of Fine Arts in the 2024-25 session.
Some students allege that Sumaiya Karim, who ranked 91st in the admission test, was allowed to transfer to the Applied A</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 17:12:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump urges Iranians to keep protesting, says 'help is on its way'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-urges-iranians-to-keep-protesting-says-help-is-on-its-way</link><description>US President Donald Trump urged Iranians on Tuesday to keep protesting and said help was on the way, without giving details, as Iran's clerical establishment pressed its crackdown against the biggest demonstrations in years.
"Iranian Patriots, KEEP PROTESTING - TAKE OVER YOUR INSTITUTIONS!!!... HE</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 17:27:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh suspends visa on arrival for all countries until Feb 15</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-suspends-visa-on-arrival-for-all-countries-until-feb-15</link><description>The government of Bangladesh has suspended the “Visa on Arrival” facility for all eligible countries, including Bhutan, with effect from January 15 to February 15, 2026.
The Ministry of Foreign Affairs and External Trade informed the general public that the Embassy of the People’</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 17:42:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Reviving the capital market in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/reviving-the-capital-market-in-bangladesh</link><description>Bangladesh recorded nominal economic growth under the previous regime. The headline performance, however, concealed deep-rooted structural weaknesses from entrenched corruption, weak fiscal discipline, and severe governance failures. These deficiencies strained the economy, leading to a sharp build</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 17:57:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UN rights chief offers support to combat election misinformation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/un-rights-chief-offers-support-to-combat-election-misinformation</link><description>UN High Commissioner for Human Rights Volker Türk has offered the support of his office to counter the surge of misinformation targeting the February 12 elections as Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus sought support of the organization to address the issue. 
“There has been a f</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 18:12:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Agro-processing calls for strategic push</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/agro-processing-calls-for-strategic-push</link><description>Despite the popular perception that Bangladesh as an agro-based country has immense potential for exporting agro-processed foods, the reality is hardly encouraging. The country has yet to make any significant headway in harnessing its advantages in this promising field. While agriculture continues</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 18:27:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Treating road safety as an emergency</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/treating-road-safety-as-an-emergency</link><description>Bangladesh ranks among the worst nations in the world in terms of road safety. A World Economic Forum (WEF) opinion survey ranked Bangladesh's roads among the worst in Asia and 113th globally considering their poor infrastructures. In South Asia, Sri Lanka, India and Pakistan ranked significantly b</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 18:42:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Process ongoing for LNG deal with truant firm Socar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/process-ongoing-for-lng-deal-with-truant-firm-socar</link><description>Preparation is on stream to award a liquefied natural gas (LNG)-supply contract to a truant foreign firm that had previously left Bangladesh without completing a contracted drilling job, sources say, stoking fresh concerns.
Energy-industry insiders say the move towards deal-making with Socar, an A</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 18:57:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP in favor of 'Yes' vote in referendum: Nazrul Islam Khan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-in-favor-of-yes-vote-in-referendum-nazrul-islam-khan</link><description>BNP standing committee member and election conducting committee chairman Nazrul Islam Khan today said that the party will vote "Yes" in the upcoming referendum, as it supports the reform initiatives.
"We have decided that we will vote 'Yes' in the referendum. We are in favour of reforms," he told</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 19:12:40 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>