<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 22:31:05 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>US, Russia to reestablish military-to-military talks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-russia-to-reestablish-military-to-military-talks</link><description>The US military said that Washington and Moscow on Thursday agreed to reestablish high level military-to-military dialogue, following talks in Abu Dhabi, a move which could signal a move towards normalising some ties between the United States and Russia.
The United States halted military-to-milita</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 15:55:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Yunus pushes ‘problem-solving’ training overhaul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/yunus-calls-for-problem-solving-oriented-government-training</link><description>Chief Adviser Muhammad Yunus has emphasised shifting government training away from rigid routines towards problem solving approaches.
A report on institutional evaluation of training centres was presented to Yunus at the State Guest House Jamuna on Thursday.
Yunus said, “There should be no</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 16:10:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Terrorism, corruption to be eliminated through ballot revolution: Mamunul Haque</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/terrorism-corruption-to-be-eliminated-through-ballot-revolution-mamunul-haque</link><description>Bangladesh Khelafat Majlis Ameer Maulana Mamunul Haque on Thursday said terrorism and corruption would be eliminated from Bangladesh’s politics through a “ballot revolution” in the February 12 elections. 
He made the remarks while addressing an election rally at the Azim Uddin Hi</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 16:25:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Impunity begins at home!</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/impunity-begins-at-home</link><description>Why khunti, a metal cooking spatula, has become a preferred instrument of cruelty in the houses of a section of senior government officials needs serious psychological and social analysis. The latest example of the brutal torture of a teenage poor domestic worker allegedly by the wife of a now-sack</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 16:00:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Right time for promoting light engineering industry</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/right-time-for-promoting-light-engineering-industry</link><description>The three-day Bangladesh Light Engineering Expo 2026, only the second of its kind, has brought to the fore the sombre fact of the gap between the country's capacity development in this sector and the potential it holds. Even the second such exposition corroborates this unmistakeable fact. But here</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 16:15:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Challenges beyond the interim period</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/challenges-beyond-the-interim-period</link><description>The statement by Finance Adviser Dr Salehuddin Ahmed that the interim government is leaving the country's economy in a stable position does not entirely sound like rhetoric, especially when viewed against the backdrop of the looming collapse from which the economy has managed to recover over the pa</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 16:30:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Learning in proximity to life</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/learning-in-proximity-to-life</link><description>The primary objective of education is making individuals cultured while culture refers to a composite of values that include a commitment to human welfare, a normative sense of the good, and spirit of collective. Welfare must be ensured for all; however, priority should be given to those whose labo</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 16:45:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Explaining the rise and fall of empires</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/reviews/explaining-the-rise-and-fall-of-empires</link><description>Despite humans seldom learning from history although it invariably repeats itself, the rise and fall of empires and civilisations as well as their causes and consequences have always attracted the attention of historians and laymen alike. Treading on this same path, the Swedish scholar cum historia</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 17:00:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh’s path to compensate torture victims opens after UN approves withdrawal of ‘objection’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladeshs-path-to-compensate-torture-victims-opens-after-un-approves-withdrawal-of-objection</link><description>The United Nations has formally accepted Bangladesh’s proposal to withdraw its reservation under the Convention against Torture, clearing the way for victims of torture and enforced disappearance -- including the families of victims who died -- to claim compensation and redress.
The Chief Ad</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 17:15:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BB officers' council demands full autonomy and legal reforms</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bb-officers-council-demands-full-autonomy-and-legal-reforms</link><description>The Bangladesh Bank Officers' Welfare Council has issued a seven-point demand to the authorities, calling for comprehensive legal reforms to establish the full autonomy of the central bank.
The demands were formally presented during a press conference held at the central bank’s headquarters</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 17:30:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP and Jamaat election camps vandalized in Gazipur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-and-jamaat-election-camps-vandalized-in-gazipur</link><description>Two local election camps of BNP and Jamaat-e-Islami were vandalized in Kapasia, Gazipur, following tensions over a political rally on Thursday night.
According to local residents, the incident took place near Saldaoi Bazar while a Jamaat election rally was ongoing, UNB reports. 
A scuffle br</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 18:30:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Strikers give two-day break for urgent export-import delivery</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/strikers-give-two-day-break-for-urgent-export-import-delivery</link><description>Protesters at Chattogram seaport gave a two-day break in their strike for urgent export-import delivery following government intervention on Thursday, after disruption of Bangladesh's external trade for six days.



Labour leaders at Chattogram Port announced the Friday-Saturday suspension of t</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 19:33:23 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>