<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 03:53:59 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>ACC prosecutes ex-MP Iqbal, son over 'illicit wealth'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/acc-prosecutes-former-mp-iqbal-and-son-for-allegedly-acquiring-illicit-wealth</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission has brought charges of acquiring illicit wealth against former Awami League MP and Premier Bank chairman HBM Iqbal.
The agency has also filed a separate case on the same charge against his son and another former Premier Bank chair -- Imran Iqbal.
On Sunday, ACC spok</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 19:30:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rice imports hit record highs despite satisfactory stock</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/rice-imports-hit-record-highs-despite-satisfactory-stock</link><description>Rice imports into Bangladesh spiked by nearly a record 5,400 per cent in the first two months of this fiscal year as traders rushed to cash in on duty waivers coupled with price fall in India.



Economists alert to risk of farmers being deprived of fair price as government procurement has be</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 19:45:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cross-border payment system in BIMSTEC vision amid global monetary volatility</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/cross-border-payment-system-in-bimstec-vision-amid-global-monetary-volatility</link><description>Spadework gets started to establish cross-border digital payment system for sub-regional bloc BIMSTEC to deepen economic integration and promote financial inclusion across South and Southeast Asia.
Sources say the Bay of Bengal Initiative for Multi-Sectoral Technical and Economic Cooperation (BIMS</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 01:11:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Data protection entities to face strict accountability</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/data-protection-entities-to-face-strict-accountability</link><description>The government has taken a tougher stance on safeguarding citizens' personal information through the newly approved Personal Data Protection Ordinance 2025.
The ordinance aims to establish a strict accountability framework for both public and private institutions handling personal data.
Announcin</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 01:26:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Films on Hasina family swallow half of ICT project budget</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/films-on-hasina-family-swallow-half-of-ict-project-budget</link><description>A government project that set out to train young Bangladeshis to build mobile apps and video games has ended up spending nearly half its budget making animated films about ousted Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina and her family.
The flagship "Mobile Game and Application Skill Development Project", laun</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 02:11:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Six die after reportedly consuming toxic liquor in Chuadanga</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/six-die-after-reportedly-consuming-toxic-liquor-in-chuadanga</link><description>Six people have died and another remains in critical condition after reportedly consuming toxic liquor in the Dingedah area of Chuadanga Sadar Upazila between Thursday and Sunday.
The deceased were identified as Kheder Ali, 40, a van driver from Nafarkanti village; Mohammad Selim, 40, a fish trade</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 02:26:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Midnight clash between DU, Dhaka College students leaves several injured</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/midnight-clash-between-du-dhaka-college-students-leaves-several-injured</link><description>A clash broke out between students of Dhaka University (DU) and Dhaka College around midnight, leaving several people, including journalists, injured.
The incident occurred around 1:00 am on Sunday (October 12), when students from both sides engaged in chase and counter-chase and threw brick chips</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 03:12:04 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>