<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 06:37:39 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Workplace deaths soar in 2025, as safety situation worsens</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/workplace-deaths-soar-in-2025-as-safety-situation-worsens</link><description>Workplace safety situation worsened sharply in 2025, with at least 1,190 workers died and 222 were injured in job-related accidents across the country, according to a new report released on Tuesday.
The death toll marked a significant rise from 2024, when 905 workers died and 218 were injured. The</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 03:01:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DEMISE OF KHALEDA: BGMEA, BKMEA, BTMA urge factory closure today</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/demise-of-khaleda-bgmea-bkmea-btma-urge-factory-closure-today</link><description>The country's leading textile and apparel trade bodies -- BGMEA, BKMEA and BTMA -- have requested their members to keep all factories closed today (Wednesday), expressing solidarity with the state mourning declared by the government following the death of BNP Chairperson and former Prime Minister B</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 03:16:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Munafa Islamic Digital Bank can win back affected clients</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/munafa-islamic-digital-bank-can-win-back-affected-clients</link><description>The proposed Munafa Islamic Digital Bank aims to introduce specially designed products targeting Shariah-compliant clients who have been badly affected by the recent shock in the country's unconventional banking ecosystem.
AKIJ Resource, a business entity originating from one of the country's olde</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 03:31:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prolonged cold spell hits low-wage earners hard</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/prolonged-cold-spell-hits-low-wage-earners-hard</link><description>A prolonged cold spell, with dense fog, winds, and low temperatures have been disrupting normal life and severely affecting thousands of low-wage earners in Rajshahi, Rangpur and Chandpur districts.
Our correspondent from Rajshahi reports, according to Rajshahi Meteorological Office, the city reco</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 03:46:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Political profile of Begum Khaleda Zia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/political-profile-of-begum-khaleda-zia</link><description>Begum Khaleda Zia, an icon of democratic tolerance in Bangladesh who served thrice as the Prime Minister (1991-96, 1996, 2001-06), and chairperson of Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) for over four decades, is no more. She was born on  August 15 1945 at Jalpaiguri of undivided Bengal, where h</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 04:01:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka-Delhi relations: from crisis to cooperation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/dhaka-delhi-relations-from-crisis-to-cooperation</link><description>Dhaka-Delhi relations, long characterised by periodic flare-ups and uneasy cooperation, have entered a sudden and potentially dangerous downturn. In recent weeks, violent protests in Bangladesh, the suspension of visa services, and threats directed at Bangladeshi diplomats in New Delhi have shaken</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 04:16:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Here are the roads under traffic restriction for Khaleda’s Janaza</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/here-are-the-roads-under-traffic-restriction-for-khaledas-janaza</link><description>Traffic will remain restricted on several roads in the capital on Wednesday due to the movement of the convoy carrying the body of former Prime Minister and BNP Chairperson Begum Khaleda Zia.
The funeral prayer (Namaj-e-Janaja) of Begum Khaleda Zia is scheduled to be held at the South Plaza of the</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 04:31:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique recites Quran, prays for his mother</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-recites-quran-prays-for-his-mother</link><description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman recited from the Holy Quran at his Gulshan residence and prayed for his mother, former Prime Minister Begum Khaleda Zia, shortly after her body arrived there on Wednesday morning.
Sitting alone next to his mother's coffin inside the residence, Tarique Rahman appe</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 04:46:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trade, professional bodies condole Khaleda Zia's death</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/trade-professional-bodies-condole-khaleda-zias-death</link><description>Different trade bodies, professional organisations and right groups of the country have expressed condolences at the death of BNP chairperson and former Prime Minister Begum Khaleda Zia.
In separate messages, they also expressed on Tuesday their sympathy to her family, including her son and BNP ac</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 05:01:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A tribute to Khaleda Zia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/a-tribute-to-khaleda-zia</link><description>The death of Begum Khaleda Zia yesterday, December 30, is an irreparable loss to the nation at a moment when it is at a critical juncture. In fact, this is no eulogy to her memory to say that Khaleda Zia was the first elected female prime minister of the country or that she was elected prime minist</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 05:16:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Changing global poverty landscape and rising risks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/reviews/changing-global-poverty-landscape-and-rising-risks</link><description>The world today stands at a pivotal moment in its long struggle against poverty. For decades, policymakers celebrated remarkable progress in eradicating poverty. The share of people living in extreme poverty fell from nearly 38 per cent in 1990 to below 10 per cent by the end of the 2010s. Much of</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 05:31:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A life that refused to bow</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/reviews/a-life-that-refused-to-bow</link><description>With the demise of Khaleda Zia (1945-2025), Bangladesh is not only bidding farewell to a former prime minister but also to an era. It is an era that encapsulates not only the political struggles but the moral fabric of this republic. It is an era born of resistance, an era in which its dreams of de</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 05:46:14 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>