<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 16:24:28 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Touhid plays down backlash over foreign diplomats meeting AL leader Saber</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/touhid-plays-down-backlash-over-foreign-diplomats-meeting-al-leader-saber</link><description>Foreign Advisor Touhid Hossain has said ambassadors are free to visit “anyone’s home”, adding that the government has nothing to say or do about it.
The remarks came after reports that three European Union envoys recently held a meeting at the residence of former minister and Awa</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 13:25:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Uttara Bank holds anti money laundering conference</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/uttara-bank-holds-anti-money-laundering-conference</link><description>The “Anti Money Laundering Conference-2025” of Uttara Bank PLC was held at Radisson Blu, Dhaka Water Garden recently, according to a press release.
Mr. Md. Abul Hashem, Managing Director &amp; CEO of Uttara Bank PLC, was present as chief guest at the conference. The conference was presided</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 13:55:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Modhumoti Bank donates Tk 300,000 to Amader Pathshala under CSR program</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/modhumoti-bank-donates-tk-300000-to-amader-pathshala-under-csr-program</link><description>Modhumoti Bank PLC donated Tk 300,000 recently to “Amader Pathshala” under the Bank’s CSR program for conducting social welfare programs and educational programs for underprivileged children, according to a press release.
Mr. Shahnawaj Chowdhury, Managing Director (Current Charge</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 14:10:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Remittance inflow witnesses 14.6pc growth till Oct 7</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/remittance-inflow-witnesses-146pc-growth-till-oct-7</link><description>Inflow of remittances witnessed 14.6 percent (pc) growth, reaching US$8,278 million during the period from July 1 to October 7, 2025 which was $7,225 million during the same period of the previous fiscal year.
According to the latest data of Bangladesh Bank (BB) issued, expatriates sent remittance</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 14:25:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>HSBC named the best in four categories in Bangladesh by Euromoney</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/hsbc-named-the-best-in-four-categories-in-bangladesh-by-euromoney</link><description>The Hongkong and Shanghai Banking Corporation Limited (HSBC) Bangladesh has been voted as the ‘Best Cash Management Bank’ in Bangladesh for the 16th time and ‘Best Cash Management Bank for Client Service’ in Bangladesh for the 8th time in a row, according to a press release.</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 14:40:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>City Bank publishes its inaugural ESG report</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/city-bank-publishes-its-inaugural-esg-report</link><description>City Bank PLC has published its inaugural Environmental, Social and Governance (ESG) Report, “Bank on Solidity, Banking on Sustainability”, marking a key milestone in its sustainability journey. Building on previous Sustainability Reports, this comprehensive ESG Report aligns with globa</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 15:10:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BRAC Bank, VisionSpring join MBM Group in celebrating World Sight Day</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/brac-bank-visionspring-join-mbm-group-in-celebrating-world-sight-day</link><description>BRAC Bank, VisionSpring, and MBM Group jointly celebrated World Sight Day 2025 at Cutting Edge Industries Limited, a concern of MBM Group, according to a press release.
The event was organised by MBM Group to mark the occasion with BRAC Bank, which facilitated the eye screening of their factory wo</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 15:25:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>12 officers relocated to B’baria over traffic issues</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/adviser-fouzul-orders-12-dhaka-officers-to-serve-in-bbaria-to-tackle-traffic-issues</link><description>Road Transport Adviser Fouzul Kabir Khan has ordered 12 ministry officials, including senior engineers, to leave their Dhaka offices and work from a temporary base in Brahmanbaria to improve conditions on the Dhaka–Sylhet Highway.
After inspecting the damaged section of the highway on Wednes</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 15:40:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Afghan Taliban foreign minister heads for first visit to India to foster ties abroad</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/afghan-taliban-foreign-minister-heads-for-first-visit-to-india-to-foster-ties-abroad</link><description>Afghanistan’s Taliban foreign minister left for New Delhi on Wednesday, his ministry said, in what would be the first visit to India by a Taliban leader since the group seized power in 2021.
The trip highlights Taliban efforts to expand engagement with regional powers in a quest for economic</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 15:55:34 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>