<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 20:37:06 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Inflation that defies reason</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/inflation-that-defies-reason</link><description>After showing a downward trend for a month or two, inflation rose again in September, renewing concerns among consumers who have been severely affected by high prices over the past three years. Taming this persistent inflation has been one of the top priorities of the interim government. In pursuit</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 15:50:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The saga of plurilateral trade deals</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/the-saga-of-plurilateral-trade-deals</link><description>Over the last couple of years, several members of the World Trade Organisation (WTO) have been negotiating issues still not covered by the multilateral trade negotiations under the WTO framework, thereby bypassing the multilateral approach. The result of the move is a rise in talks on plurilateral</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 16:05:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Will this Gaza ceasefire hold?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/will-this-gaza-ceasefire-hold</link><description>The guns have fallen silent in Gaza, at least for the time being. After two ruinous years of Israel's bombing, starvation and deprivation in Gaza, the first phase of a US-brokered ceasefire between Israel and Hamas has come into force. As the Israeli Defence Forces (IDF) withdraw to predetermined l</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 16:20:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DU treasurer upholds vital role of Islamic banking in global economy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/du-treasurer-upholds-vital-role-of-islamic-banking-in-global-economy</link><description>Dhaka University Treasurer Professor M. Jahangir Alam Chowdhury on Saturday said Islamic banking and finance continue to play an increasingly vital role in the global economy — not merely for being interest-free, but also for their ethical and socially responsible principles.
He made the rem</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 16:35:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ties with India must be based on equality: Fakhrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bnp-seeks-friendship-with-india-on-equal-footing-says-mirza-fakhrul</link><description>BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir has said the party seeks friendly relations with India, but only on the principle of equality.
Speaking on Saturday afternoon at a memorial event in Gazipur’s Kapasia, he said India must refrain from “interfering” in Bangladesh's</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 17:05:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gunfire erupts at Chattogram concert after ‘Joy Bangla’ chant</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/gunfire-erupts-at-chattogram-concert-after-joy-bangla-chant</link><description>A concert in the port city of Chattogram turned violent on Saturday night after chants of “Joy Bangla” reportedly sparked clashes and gunfire, local media said.
One person, 23-year-old Md Sharif, was shot and seriously wounded. He was taken to Chittagong Medical College Hospital (CMCH)</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 18:36:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Four killed, 12 wounded as gunfire erupts after high-school football game in Mississippi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/four-killed-12-wounded-as-gunfire-erupts-after-high-school-football-game-in-mississippi</link><description>Four people were killed and 12 others injured -- four critically -- in a mass shooting in the US state of Mississippi, according to a BBC report.
The shooting took place around midnight on the main street in Leland, a small town about 120 miles (190km) north-east of Jackson, the state capital, Lel</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 18:51:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt moves to waive VAT on  exporters' local procurement</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/govt-moves-to-waive-vat-on-exporters-local-procurement</link><description>A government move gets going to waive value-added tax (VAT) on local procurements by exporters to enhance the global competitiveness of Bangladesh's export sector, particularly in preparation for the privilege rescinded post-LDC era.
In a recent directive, the National Board of Revenue (NBR) clari</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 19:06:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jatiya Party alleges police attack at rally, calls it an ‘ominous sign’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jatiya-party-alleges-police-attack-at-rally-calls-it-an-ominous-sign</link><description>The Jatiya Party has alleged that police attacked its workers’ rally outside the party’s central office in Dhaka’s Kakrail, describing the incident as an “ominous sign” for national politics.
The rally was disrupted around 3:30pm on Saturday after clashes ensued betwe</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 19:21:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Warrants for 100 Army officers a ‘rumour’: press secy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/arrest-warrants-against-100-more-army-officers-baseless-rumour-says-press-secretary</link><description>Chief Advisor’s Press Secretary Shafiqul Alam has dismissed social media claims that arrest warrants were being issued against more than 100 Army officers, calling these “completely fabricated and baseless”.
In a Facebook post on Saturday, he said false rumours were being spread</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 19:36:54 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>