<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 07:22:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Lalmonirhat border transit route for drug smuggling</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/lalmonirhat-border-transit-route-for-drug-smuggling</link><description>Various types of illicit drugs are being smuggled into Bangladesh from the neighbouring country, India, through different border points in Lalmonirhat district.
Trade of these narcotic substances has emerged as a grave concern among the inhabitants and guardians in five upazilas of the frontier no</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 03:59:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Suicide bombers kill 3 at Pakistan paramilitary HQ</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/suicide-bombers-kill-3-at-pakistan-paramilitary-hq</link><description>Three suicide bombers targeted the headquarters of a Pakistani paramilitary force on Monday, killing three personnel and wounding at least five, authorities said.
The attackers opened fire as they forced themselves into the headquarters of the frontier constabulary in Peshawar city before blowing</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 04:14:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ACC to probe graft charges against Quader's 'foster son' Hiru</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/acc-to-probe-graft-charges-against-quaders-foster-son-hiru</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) has decided to investigate corruption allegations against Md Asaduzzaman Hiru, so-called foster son of Awami League General Secretary Obaidul Quader.
Hiru is accused of having earned a huge amount of illegal wealth through smuggling, hundi (illegal money transf</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 04:29:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gas tariff raised by 82pc for fertiliser factories from Dec 1</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/gas-tariff-raised-by-82pc-for-fertiliser-factories-from-dec-1</link><description>Gas price for fertiliser factories has been hiked by 82.81 per cent to Tk 29.25 per cubic meter from the previous rate of Tk 16 per cubic meter with effect from December 1.
Bangladesh Energy Regulatory Commission (BERC) Chairman Jalal Ahmed announced the enhanced tariff at a press briefing at its</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 04:44:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Coverage of defence purchases by Sena Insurance opposed by public, private peers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/coverage-of-defence-purchases-by-sena-insurance-opposed-by-public-private-peers</link><description>Stakeholders have strongly opposed a plea by Sena Kalyan Sangstha (SKS) to allow its concern, Sena Insurance, to underwrite insurance risks relating to defence purchases, terming the move a violation of the Insurance Corporation Act.
They said the Act entitles only the state-run Sadharan Bima Corp</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 04:59:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Unitholders reject conversion, seek redemption upon maturity</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/unitholders-reject-conversion-seek-redemption-upon-maturity</link><description>Another closed-end mutual fund - Vanguard AML BD Finance Mutual Fund One - is going to be liquidated next month after a majority of its unitholders voted against its conversion into an open-ended fund upon maturity.
The fund's trustee - Bangladesh General Insurance Company (BGIC) - at a recent mee</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 05:14:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ICAB, CIPFA step up partnership to advance public finance</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/icab-cipfa-step-up-partnership-to-advance-public-finance</link><description>The Institute of Chartered Accountants of Bangladesh (ICAB) and the UK-based Chartered Institute of Public Finance and Accountancy (CIPFA) have renewed their commitment to advancing high-quality public sector financial management by re-signing a Memorandum of Understanding (MoU).
The MoU was signe</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 05:29:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Digital payments surge in 2024, MFS usage remains uneven: BB</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/digital-payments-surge-in-2024-mfs-usage-remains-uneven-bb</link><description>Bangladesh's payment ecosystem saw strong growth and structural transformation throughout 2024, driven by rising digital adoption, major technological upgrades, and strengthened regulatory oversight, according to the latest Bangladesh Bank (BB) Payment Systems report.
Covering January-December 202</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 05:44:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ceramic Expo 2025 set for global showcase</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ceramic-expo-2025-set-for-global-showcase</link><description>The fourth edition of Ceramic Expo Bangladesh 2025 will begin on Thursday at the International Convention City Bashundhara (ICCB) in the city, bringing together some of the world's leading ceramic manufacturers, technologists and buyers.
Organised by the Bangladesh Ceramic Manufacturers and Export</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 05:59:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Country to fully implement payment interoperability by 2027: BB governor</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/country-to-fully-implement-payment-interoperability-by-2027-bb-governor</link><description>Bangladesh Bank (BB) Governor Dr Ahsan H Mansur has said the country is expected to fully implement interoperability across its payment ecosystem by July 2027.
To reach this milestone and move toward a cashless or less-cash society, the central bank has signed a digital agreement with the Gates Fo</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 06:14:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Man crushed under train in Gazipur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/man-crushed-under-train-in-gazipur</link><description>An unidentified man was killed after being hit by a train in Kaliakair of Gazipur district on Monday.
The deceased, aged about 60 years, was wearing a lungi and a t-shirt, reports UNB.
The train hit the man on the Dhaka-Rajshahi railway route in the Bajhizoltoli area of Kaliakair, said Joydebpur</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 06:29:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Woman killed being hit by pickup van in Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/woman-killed-being-hit-by-pickup-van-in-dhaka</link><description>An unidentified woman was killed after being hit by a speeding pickup van in front of Forazi Hospital at the Rampura area in Dhaka on Sunday night.
Hasan, a pedestrian, said that when the woman, aged about 65, was crossing the road, the pickup van knocked her down around 10:45 pm, reports UNB.
So</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 06:44:25 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>