<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 12:51:31 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>China says Philippines distorted facts about incident near disputed atoll</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/china-says-philippines-distorted-facts-about-incident-near-disputed-atoll</link><description>China's defence ministry accused the Philippines on Wednesday of distorting the facts about an incident involving the Chinese coastguard and Filipino fishermen near a South China Sea shoal.
Manila's coastguard said over the weekend that three Filipino fishermen were injured and two fishing vessels</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 10:20:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>TikTok monitored Grindr activity through third-party tracker, privacy group alleges</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/tiktok-monitored-grindr-activity-through-third-party-tracker-privacy-group-alleges</link><description>A privacy advocacy group, noyb, filed complaints to Austria’s data protection authority on Wednesday against TikTok, Grindr (GRND.N), opens new tab and AppsFlyer, alleging these companies breached regional privacy laws, risking exposure of sensitive data.
Vienna-based organization None of Yo</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 10:35:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt to prepare area-based wildlife inventory</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-to-prepare-area-based-wildlife-inventory</link><description>The government has decided to prepare a countrywide area-based wildlife inventory so that locals can be made aware of these wild animals. 
The decision was taken at the 41st meeting of the Wildlife Advisory Board held recently, with Environment, Forest and Climate Change Adviser Syeda Rizwana</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 10:50:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bringing back laundered funds may take 4–5 years: BB governor</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bringing-back-laundered-funds-may-take-4-5-years-bb-governor</link><description>Bangladesh Bank Governor Dr. Ahsan H. Mansur said on Wednesday that recovering laundered money from abroad is a lengthy process and it may four to five years.
Dr. Mansur made the remarks while talking to reporters after a meeting with Finance Adviser Dr. Salehuddin Ahmed at the Secretariat.
When</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 11:05:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh must avoid return to fascism: Moyeen Khan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bangladesh-must-avoid-return-to-fascism-moyeen-khan</link><description>BNP senior leader Dr Abdul Moyeen Khan on Wednesday said Bangladesh cannot afford to return to a fascist path again in the future.
“We don’t want Bangladesh to be known again in the world as a fascist state. We want to build a humane Bangladesh,” he said.
The BNP leader made the</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 10:21:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ADN Telecom wins Gold Award at 12th ICSB National Award for Corporate Governance Excellence in 2024</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/adn-telecom-wins-gold-award-at-12th-icsb-national-award-for-corporate-governance-excellence-in-2024</link><description>ADN Telecom Limited has been honored with the prestigious Gold Award at the 12th ICSB National Award for Corporate Governance Excellence, 2024, in the Information and Communication Technology category.
The award ceremony, held on December 15, 2025, in the Pan Pacific Sonargaon Dhaka, recognized th</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 10:36:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hero Alom gets interim bail</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hero-alom-granted-1-month-interim-bail-in-domestic-violence-case</link><description>Content creator Ashraful Alam, popularly known as Hero Alom, has been granted one month’s interim bail in a case filed by his former wife accusing him of “attempted murder and assault”.
Alom appeared in the court of Dhaka Additional Chief Metropolitan Magistrate Awlad Hossain Muh</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 10:51:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Police block ‘March to Indian High Commission’ in North Badda</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/police-block-march-to-indian-high-commission-in-north-badda</link><description>Police have blocked a protest march towards the Indian High Commission in Dhaka by a group called the July Oikya.
On Wednesday afternoon, police intercepted the procession, which started from the Rampura Bridge, in front of Hossain Market in North Badda, bdnews24.com reports.
Badda Zone Assistant</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 11:06:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EU to send 175-200 observers during February-12 election: EC Secretary</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/eu-to-send-175-200-observers-during-february-12-election-ec-secretary</link><description>The European Union (EU) will send some 175-200 observers to watch the upcoming parliamentary election and the referendum on the July National Charter, scheduled to be held on February 12, 2026, said EC Senior Secretary Akhtar Ahmed on Wednesday.
“The EU has confirmed that it will deploy an o</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 11:21:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Doctors in England start five-day walkout during flu surge</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/doctors-in-england-start-five-day-walkout-during-flu-surge</link><description>Doctors in England began a five-day strike on Wednesday over pay and working conditions during a surge in flu cases and with no end in sight to an increasingly bitter dispute with the government.
The walkout is the latest in a series of strikes this year by "resident" or junior hospital doctors, w</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 11:36:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EU Parliament approves phase out of Russian gas imports</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/eu-parliament-approves-phase-out-of-russian-gas-imports</link><description>The European Parliament on Wednesday approved the bloc's plan to phase out Russian gas imports by late 2027, clearing the penultimate legal hurdle before the ban can pass into law.
The Russian gas ban still requires formal approval at a meeting of EU countries' ministers, expected early next year.</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 11:51:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC urges equal media coverage for all candidates</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-urges-equal-media-coverage-for-all-candidates</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has called for equal opportunities for all candidates in election coverage on Bangladesh Television and private TV channels.
Creating a congenial environment is crucial for free, fair, and credible elections, said an EC statement signed by Md Ruhul Amin Mollick, direct</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 12:06:58 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>