<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 08:30:34 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Explosions heard in Dhaka’s New Market, Dhanmondi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/explosions-heard-in-dhakas-new-market-dhanmondi</link><description>Police have reported hearing explosions in Dhaka’s New Market and Dhanmondi.
These incidents happened amid a spate of arson attacks and crude bomb explosions surrounding the verdict in the crimes against humanity case against Sheikh Hasina.
After 10:00 pm on Monday, at least four crude bomb</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 04:47:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Schoolboy killed in Dhaka road crash</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/schoolboy-killed-in-dhaka-road-crash</link><description>A class IX student was killed after being hit by a CNG-run auto-rickshaw in the Kadamtoli area of Dhaka on Monday.
The deceased was identified as Mohammad Rafi, 16, son of Ramjan Mia of the Jurain area in the capital.
Inspector Md Faruk, in charge of Dhaka Medical College and Hospital police camp</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 05:02:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Japan warns citizens in China about safety</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/japan-warns-citizens-in-china-about-safety</link><description>Japan has warned its citizens in China to step up safety precautions and avoid crowded places amid a deepening dispute between Asia's two largest economies over Japanese Prime Minister Sanae Takaichi's comments on Taiwan.
The advisory issued by Japan's embassy in China came as a senior Japanese fo</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 05:17:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Urgent RDPP approval sought, as project tenure ends in Dec</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/urgent-rdpp-approval-sought-as-project-tenure-ends-in-dec</link><description>The revision of the first metro rail project's Development Project Proposal (DPP) has become urgent, with officials rushing to secure approval from the Executive Committee of the National Economic Council (ECNEC) before the interim government's tenure ends.
Officials said a significant portion of</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 05:32:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DU professor suspended over sexual harassment</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/du-professor-suspended-over-sexual-harassment</link><description>Dr Ershad Halim, a professor of Dhaka University's Chemistry Department, has been suspended from all academic and administrative duties over allegations of sexual harassment made by several of his male students. A probe committee has also been formed to investigate the matter.
A press release issu</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 05:47:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nabanna vibes fill RU</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/nabanna-vibes-fill-ru</link><description>A crisp winter morning at Rajshahi University's (RU) Agriculture Faculty turned into a vibrant celebration of tradition as the warm aroma of freshly made pitha filled the air.
With the theme "Him-him shiter batas", the Agronomy and Agricultural Extension Association hosted the lively "Nabanna and</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 06:02:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bogura sees a boom in poultry industry</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/bogura-sees-a-boom-in-poultry-industry</link><description>BOGURA, Nov 17: Bogura - the district best known for its agricultural machineries- has now seen a boom in the local poultry industry, stemming from the vigorous growth of its other traditional businesses.
The northern district has now emerged as a thriving poultry hub, where thousands of farms, ha</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 06:17:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hamas rejects UN Gaza resolution</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/hamas-rejects-un-gaza-resolution</link><description>Hamas rejected the United Nations Security Council passing a US-drafted resolution endorsing US President Donald Trump's Gaza plan, saying it fails to meet Palestinians' rights and demands and seeks to impose an international trusteeship on the enclave that Palestinians and resistance factions oppo</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 06:32:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Grameen Bank branch torched in Magura</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/grameen-bank-branch-torched-in-magura</link><description>A branch of Grameen Bank in Magura’s Mohammadpur Upazila has reportedly been hit by an arson attack.
Unidentified attackers allegedly poured petrol through a window and set fire to the bank, located next to the Aminur Rahman Degree College, around 3:30 am on Tuesday, according to Sohana Sult</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 06:47:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Diamond World owner sued for 'laundering' Tk 6.78 billion</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/diamond-world-owner-sued-for-laundering-tk-678-billion</link><description>The Criminal Investigation Department (CID) has filed a case against Diamond World owner Dilip Kumar Agarwala on allegations of laundering Tk 6.78 billion through the smuggling of gold and diamonds.
According to a CID statement, the money laundering case was lodged at Gulshan Police Station on Mon</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 07:02:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>198 murders reported in Dhaka in 10 months: DMP</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/198-murders-reported-in-dhaka-in-10-months-dmp</link><description>A total of 198 murders have taken place in Dhaka over the past 10 months, according to the Dhaka Metropolitan Police (DMP).
The information was shared by DMP Deputy Commissioner Muhammad Talebur Rahman while speaking to reporters on Tuesday.
He said an average of around 20 murders occurred each m</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 07:47:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka University deputy registrar arrested on terror charges</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dhaka-university-deputy-registrar-arrested-on-terror-charges</link><description>Dhaka University Deputy Registrar Muhammad Lovelu Mollah has been arrested in connection with a case filed under the Anti-Terrorism Act.
Shahbagh Police Station chief Mohammad Khalid Monsur said on Tuesday that Lovelu was placed under arrest in the case, alleging that he funded marches by the Bang</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 08:02:55 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>