<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 21:20:46 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Fun to dream, harder to do the math</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/fun-to-dream-harder-to-do-the-math</link><description>It is often suggested—sometimes wistfully, sometimes with great confidence—that if Bangladesh simply adopts a specific policy (or a specific set of policies), it can “become the next Singapore.” This is an uplifting thought, but simple arithmetic delivers a gentle reality ch</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 16:16:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>What powered Hadi, his July comrades?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/what-powered-hadi-his-july-comrades</link><description>Sharif Osman Hadi's martyrdom and the outpouring of grief and sympathy that his assassination aroused among the public has been, in a word, historic. The masterminds behind his killing might have thought that they had succeeded in removing him from public memory forever. But their killing mission b</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 15:32:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Preventing mob justice imperative for ensuring rule of law</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/preventing-mob-justice-imperative-for-ensuring-rule-of-law</link><description>Mob justice has emerged as one of the gravest threats to Bangladesh's fragile transition, provoking deep anxiety among citizens across political, social and professional divides. Despite repeated assurances from the interim government, vigilante violence continues unabated, exposing a dangerous ero</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 15:47:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Urgency of constructing technical institutions</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/urgency-of-constructing-technical-institutions</link><description>At a time when technical and vocational education is not an option but a sine qua non, two projects given the go-ahead in 2014 and 2020 to develop required infrastructure for students to learn such specialised knowledge and skills could be an answer to youth unemployment. Under one such programme,</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 16:02:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Inqilab Moncho demands justice for Hadi before any election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/inqilab-moncho-demands-justice-for-hadi-before-any-election</link><description>Inqilab Moncho on Monday demanded that justice for the killing of its founder Osman Hadi be ensured before the 13th parliamentary election and any proposed referendum, warning that no election would be acceptable without holding Hadi's killerss accountable.
Speaking at an emergency press conferenc</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 16:17:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Those opposed to election also stoking violence, instability: Amir Khosru</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/those-opposed-to-election-also-stoking-violence-instability-amir-khosru</link><description>BNP Standing Committee member Amir Khosru Mahmud Chowdhury on Monday said those who do not want elections are behind the recent incidents of violence, attacks and instability in the country.
“The concentration of power in the hands of the government is not good for any state; the power of th</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 16:32:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gold prices hit fresh record in Bangladesh within 24 hours</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/gold-prices-hit-fresh-record-in-bangladesh-within-24-hours</link><description>Gold prices in Bangladesh have surged again within 24 hours, setting a new all-time high as the Bangladesh Jewellers Association (BAJUS) on Monday raised the price of 22-carat gold by Tk 3,966 per bhori.
With the latest adjustment, the price of 22-carat gold has been fixed at Tk 222,083 per bhori</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 16:47:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Election to be held on time, Yunus tells US Special Envoy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/election-to-be-held-on-time-yunus-tells-us-special-envoy</link><description>Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus on Monday reiterated his commitment to holding the general election on February 12 next.
"The nation is eagerly waiting to exercise their voting rights which were stolen by the autocratic regime," he said.
Prof Yunus made the remarks during a telephone conve</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 17:02:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>3 more vessels to join Shipping Corporation's fleet in six months: Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/3-more-vessels-to-join-shipping-corporations-fleet-in-six-months-shipping-adviser</link><description>Shipping Adviser Brigadier General (Retd) Dr. M Sakhawat Hossain on Monday said that Bangladesh Shipping Corporation’s (BSC) fleet will be expanded with the addition of three new ships within the next six months.
The ships will be acquired using government funding and BSC’s own resourc</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 17:17:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DUCSU VP turns down govt gunman offer</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/ducsu-vice-president-rejects-government-gunman-offer-demands-security-for-all</link><description>Dhaka University Central Students’ Union (DUCSU) Vice-President Abu Shadik Kayem has rejected state protection, saying personal security arrangements are unjustifiable when public safety remains fragile for the wider population.
In the wake of recent violence in the country, the interim gove</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 17:49:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ACC moves to prosecute Ron, 30 others for ‘embezzlement’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/acc-moves-to-prosecute-ron-and-30-others-over-tk-813-billion-embezzlement</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) has approved a case against 31 individuals, including former National Bank director Ron Haque Sikder, on charges of misappropriating Tk 8.13 billion by creating "paper" or counterfeit institutions.
The list of accused also includes Maksuda Haque, the widow of l</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 18:04:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh, Japan close to landmark EPA signing</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh-japan-close-to-landmark-epa-signing</link><description>Bangladesh is poised to sign its first-ever Economic Partnership Agreement (EPA) with Japan by the end of January 2026, as the two countries finalised the draft text proposing immediate duty-free access for a wide range of products, including readymade garments, from the very first day.



Co</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 18:19:29 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>