<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 14:26:49 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>BASIC Bank’s Managers Conference-2026 held</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/basic-banks-managers-conference-2026-held</link><description>BASIC Bank PLC, 100 per cent state-owned commercial bank, held the Managers Conference—2026 on Saturday at Mukti Auditorium, Biddut Bhaban in the Capital, according to a press release.
Helal Ahmed Chowdhury, Chairman of the bank's Board of Directors, inaugurated the conference as Chief Guest</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 13:13:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>TIB slams draft media ordinances as ‘mockery’ of free press</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tib-slams-draft-media-ordinances-as-mockery-of-free-press</link><description>Transparency International Bangladesh (TIB) on Saturday described the draft National Media Commission and Broadcasting Commission Ordinances as a ‘parting mockery’ of public expectations for free media development.
The TIB said the demand for a unified, independent and effective media</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 11:45:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>St Martin’s falls silent as tourists depart</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/st-martins-falls-silent-as-tourists-depart</link><description>As the last tourist vessel pulled away from the jetty on Jan 31, the coral island of St Martin’s slipped into an unfamiliar quiet, its beaches emptied not by weather, but by a government order aimed at giving the battered ecosystem a chance to breathe.
The early closure of the tourism season</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 12:00:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mirza Abbas says ‘no mouthful election promises’, vows welfare-driven drives</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/mirza-abbas-says-no-mouthful-election-promises-vows-welfare-driven-drives</link><description>Standing Committee Member of BNP and the party’s candidate for the Dhaka-8 constituency Mirza Abbas has said that if elected in the upcoming election, he would prioritize the welfare of the country’s citizens alongside fulfilling his responsibilities as a lawmaker.
“If elected, I</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 12:15:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Three jailed for cheating by proxy in Bridge Division recruitment exam</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/three-jailed-for-cheating-by-proxy-in-bridge-division-recruitment-exam</link><description>Three candidates were jailed and fined for cheating using proxies in a recruitment exam under the Bridge Division held on Saturday.
The exam took place at BAF Shaheen College, Jahangir Gate, Dhaka Cantonment, for the posts of computer operator, accountant, office assistant cum computer typist, and</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 12:30:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BRAC Bank hosts entrepreneur conference to promote its pioneering SME Digital Loan ‘Shafollo’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/brac-bank-hosts-entrepreneur-conference-to-promote-its-pioneering-sme-digital-loan-shafollo</link><description>BRAC Bank recently organised an entrepreneur conference of its SME Digital Loan ‘Shafollo’ in Gazipur to showcase the country’s first SME digital loan programme.
The engagement, that brought together more than 200 small and medium business owners, reinforces the bank’s comm</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 12:45:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Md. Siddiqur Rahman takes charge as Acting Managing Director of Standard Bank</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/md-siddiqur-rahman-takes-charge-as-acting-managing-director-of-standard-bank</link><description>Md. Siddiqur Rahman, the Deputy Managing Director &amp; Chief Operating Officer of the bank, has taken charge as Acting Managing Director of Standard Bank PLC, according to a press release.
Mr. Rahman joined the Shari`ah-based Standard Bank as DMD in August 2023and has played a pivotal role in strengt</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 13:00:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Karmasangsthan Bank holds business review meeting in Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/karmasangsthan-bank-holds-business-review-meeting-in-dhaka</link><description>Karmasangsthan Bank held a Business Review Meeting-2026 on Saturday at the conference hall of the Department of Youth Development in Motijheel, Dhaka.
The meeting was attended by regional managers, branch managers, and field officers from the Dhaka, Dhaka North, and Narayanganj regions under the D</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 13:15:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Election violence in January kills 4, injures 509 across Bangladesh: MSF</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/election-violence-in-january-kills-4-injures-509-across-bangladesh-msf</link><description>At least four people have been killed and 509 others injured in 64 incidents of election-related violence across Bangladesh in January, according to rights group Manabadhikar Shongskriti Foundation (MSF).
The figures come amid reports of clashes between activists of the BNP and Jamaat-e-Islami in</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 13:30:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Explosion occurs at Iran's southern port of Bandar Abbas</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/explosion-occurs-at-irans-southern-port-of-bandar-abbas-iranian-media-reports</link><description>An explosion occurred at Iran's southern port of Bandar Abbas on Saturday, Iranian media reported, without giving a cause for the blast.
The semi-official Tasnim news agency said that social media reports alleging that a Revolutionary Guard navy commander was targeted in the explosion were "comple</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 13:45:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Islami Bank holds employee conference for 3 zones, 5 corporate branches in Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/islami-bank-holds-employee-conference-for-3-zones-5-corporate-branches-in-dhaka</link><description>Islami Bank Bangladesh PLC is the largest bank in the country and the employees should make efforts to further increase public confidence in this institution. Clients are the lifeblood of the bank, so ensuring their satisfaction is the main goal of the bank. All problems of customers must be resolv</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 14:00:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pakistan says 67 militants killed after coordinated attacks in Balochistan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/pakistan-says-67-militants-killed-after-coordinated-attacks-in-balochistan</link><description>At least 67 militants were killed on Saturday as they battled Pakistan's security forces in multiple cities across the southwestern province of Balochistan, four security officials told Reuters.
Some 10 police and security personnel and 11 civilians were also killed during the orchestrated militan</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 14:15:43 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>