<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 12:40:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Govt approves import of 50,000 mts rice from India, wheat from US</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/govt-approves-import-of-50000-mts-rice-from-india-wheat-from-us</link><description>The government on Tuesday approved a proposal to import 50,000 metric tonnes of non-Basmati parboiled rice from India under the international open tender system for the fiscal year 2025–26.
The Advisers Council Committee on Government Purchase (ACCGP) in its meeting approved the proposal, re</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 10:12:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Clarke, Devoret and Martinis win 2025 Nobel Prize in Physics</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/clarke-devoret-and-martinis-win-2025-nobel-prize-in-physics</link><description>U.S.-based scientists John Clarke, Michel Devoret and John Martinis won the 2025 Nobel Prize in Physics for "experiments that revealed quantum physics in action", the award-giving body said on Tuesday.
"This year's Nobel Prize in Physics has provided opportunities for developing the next generatio</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 10:27:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh, UN stress sustained collaboration, innovation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-un-stress-sustained-collaboration-innovation</link><description>Bangladesh and the United Nations (UN) on Tuesday emphasised the importance of sustained collaboration, innovation, and inclusive growth as Bangladesh prepares for its upcoming national elections in February and enters a new chapter in its development journey.
UN Resident Coordinator Gwyn Lewis pa</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 10:09:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt exceeds IMF-set limit on external borrowing: Dr Salehuddin</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/govt-exceeds-imf-set-limit-on-external-borrowing-dr-salehuddin</link><description>Finance Adviser Dr Salehuddin Ahmed said on Tuesday that the government has already crossed the external borrowing limit set by the International Monetary Fund (IMF).
But, he said, development partners’ concerns over debt sustainability are understandable and rooted in ensuring prudent finan</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 10:24:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CCGP rejects Payra Port connecting road variation proposal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ccgp-rejects-payra-port-connecting-road-variation-proposal</link><description>The Advisers Council Committee on Government Purchase (CCGP) on Tuesday turned down a proposal from the Ministry of Shipping regarding a variation order for the construction of the 6.35 km (4+2 lane) connecting road under the Payra Port development project.
The proposal concerned the “Constr</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 10:39:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Over 400,000 children in Manikganj to receive free typhoid vaccines</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/over-400000-children-in-manikganj-to-receive-free-typhoid-vaccines</link><description>A daylong consultation workshop on typhoid vaccination was held in Manikganj with the participation of journalists, under the project `Awareness Campaign for the Development of Children, Adolescents, and Women’ and with financial support from UNICEF Bangladesh.
The workshop took place on Tue</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 10:54:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ACC sues 2 Benapole customs officials; Tk 2.76 lakh seized</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/acc-sues-2-benapole-customs-officials-tk-276-lakh-seized</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) has filed a case against two officials of Benapole Customs House after their detention with Tk 2.76 lakh in bribe during a drive on Monday.
Deputy Director and investigation officer Al Amjn filed the case on Tuesday against Benapole Customs House revenue office</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 11:09:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dengue: Two more die ; 715 hospitalised</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/dengue-two-more-die-715-hospitalised</link><description>Two more deaths from dengue were reported in the 24 hours till Tuesday morning as Bangladesh continues to grapple with a surge in infections.
With the latest fatalities, the total number of deaths from the mosquito-borne disease in Bangladesh has risen to 217 this year, according to the Directorat</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 11:54:05 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>