<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 04:44:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Bangladesh's RCEP bid enters formal evaluation stage</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladeshs-rcep-bid-enters-formal-evaluation-stage</link><description>Bangladesh's pursuit of membership in the world's largest trade bloc -- the Regional Comprehensive Economic Partnership (RCEP) -- has officially entered a structured evaluation process, marking a key step in the country's bid to join the Asia-Pacific trade grouping.
A planned visit by a Bangladesh</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 01:01:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DMTCL planning to extend completion timeline until 2035</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dmtcl-planning-to-extend-completion-timeline-until-2035</link><description>The Dhaka Mass Transit Company Limited (DMTCL) is planning a fresh timeline for developing five additional metro rail corridors in the megacity, following a lapse of over a year, as the current target of completing all Mass Rapid Transit (MRT) lines by 2030 was never considered "realistic".
Offici</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 01:16:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh witnesses sharp rise in US buyer audits amid shift from China</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladesh-witnesses-sharp-rise-in-us-buyer-audits-amid-shift-from-china</link><description>Bangladesh has emerged as one of the strongest performers among Asian sourcing destinations, recording a 61 per cent year-on-year rise in inspection and audit queries from US buyers in the third quarter of 2025.
The surge reflects American companies' continued shift away from China amid trade tens</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 01:31:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>MFS transactions rebound in Aug</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/mfs-transactions-rebound-in-aug</link><description>After several months of slowdown, overall mobile financial service (MFS) transactions in Bangladesh rebounded in August 2025, according to the latest data from the Bangladesh Bank (BB).
However, remittance inflows through MFS channels registered a slight decline during the period.
Total MFS trans</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 01:46:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NBR publishes English version of new Income Tax Act</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nbr-publishes-english-version-of-new-income-tax-act</link><description>The National Board of Revenue (NBR) has published the official English version of the Income Tax Act, 2023, responding to demands from foreign investors seeking greater clarity in the application of tax laws.
Foreign investors had expressed concerns over potential misinterpretation and legal compl</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 02:01:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Genuine banking reform elusive without accountability: Experts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/genuine-banking-reform-elusive-without-accountability-experts</link><description>Genuine reform in Bangladesh's banking sector will remain elusive unless those responsible for looting banks under political protection during the past Awami League regime are held accountable, experts said at a seminar in Dhaka on Saturday.
They cautioned that recapitalising the collapsing instit</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 02:16:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Deep-discounted MFs face mandatory liquidation or conversion under draft rules</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/deep-discounted-mfs-face-mandatory-liquidation-or-conversion-under-draft-rules</link><description>The securities regulator has proposed liquidating closed-end mutual funds or converting them into open-ended funds before maturity if their units trade at more than a 25 per cent discount to net asset value (NAV) on the bourses.
The provision has been newly added to the draft amendment to the mutu</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 02:31:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BD calls for unified negotiation strategy ahead of COP30 summit</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bd-calls-for-unified-negotiation-strategy-ahead-of-cop30-summit</link><description>With the COP30 climate summit set to take place in Belém, Brazil, next month, Bangladesh has called for urgent preparation and a stronger, unified negotiation strategy to secure fair global commitments on climate finance, renewable energy, and Loss and Damage support.
Speakers at the openin</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 02:46:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>MPO teachers hold black flag march over three-point demand</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/mpo-teachers-hold-black-flag-march-over-three-point-demand</link><description>Teachers and employees from non-government educational institutions, listed under the Monthly Pay Order (MPO) scheme, held a black flag march and protest rally on Saturday in support of their three-point demand.
The black flag march began at 12:00 pm from the Central Shaheed Minar. It proceeded th</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 03:01:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Growers reluctant to release potatoes from cold storages</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/growers-reluctant-to-release-potatoes-from-cold-storages</link><description>Potato farmers are running away, skipping repeated calls from cold storage owners in the district to take back their stockpiled potatoes as prices of their produced crop are still in a downtrend.
Cold storage operators said growers have been expressing reluctance to release their potatoes as marke</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 03:16:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>10th grader stuns Gaibandha residents with car-shaped vessel</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/10th-grader-stuns-gaibandha-residents-with-car-shaped-vessel</link><description>A tenth grader applied engineering enthusiast in Gaibandha has fascinated locals and visitors by making a car-shaped vessel, which the admirers say when driven in the Brahmaputra River, appears as nothing short of a scene from a movie.
Rahad Mia -- a student of Science in Gunbhari High School in t</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 03:31:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ctg port users give 7-day ultimatum to cut tariffs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ctg-port-users-give-7-day-ultimatum-to-cut-tariffs</link><description>The business community, port users, exporters, importers and all others involved with the Chittagong Port operations have threatened to shut down the prime seaport, if the increased port tariffs are not withdrawn within a week.
The business leaders at a protest programme on Saturday gave the inter</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 03:46:21 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>