<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 10:25:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nepalese FM in Dhaka to attend Khaleda’s funeral</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nepalese-fm-in-dhaka-to-attend-khaledas-funeral</link><description>Nepalese Foreign Affairs Minister Bala Nanda Sharma arrived in Dhaka on Tuesday night to attend the state funeral of former Prime Minister and Chairperson of the Bangladesh Nationalist Party Begum Khaleda Zia and pay last respects on behalf of the government and the people of Nepal.
Secretar</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 07:00:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bhutan FM arrives to attend Khaleda’s funeral</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bhutan-fm-arrives-to-attend-khaledas-funeral</link><description>Bhutan’e Foreign Affairs and External Trade Minister Lyonpo D. N. Dhungyel arrived in Dhaka this morning to attend the state funeral of former prime minister and BNP chairperson Begum Khaleda Zia on behalf of his government.
He was received at Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport (HSIA) &amp;n</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 07:15:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jaishankar in Dhaka to pay last respect to ex-PM Khaleda</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jaishankar-in-dhaka-to-pay-last-respect-to-ex-pm-khaleda</link><description>External Affairs Minister Dr S Jaishankar arrived in Dhaka on Wednesday to represent the government and people of India at the funeral of three-time former Prime Minister and Chairperson of the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) Khaleda Zia.
As Delhi believes Khaleda Zia’s vision and legacy</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 07:30:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pakistan’s Speaker arrives to attend Khaleda Zia’s funeral</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/pakistans-speaker-arrives-to-attend-khaleda-zias-funeral</link><description>Speaker of Pakistan’s National Assembly Sardar Ayaz Sadiq arrived in Dhaka on Wednesday morning to attend the funeral of former prime minister and BNP chairperson Begum Khaleda Zia today, representing the Government of Pakistan.
He was received at Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport (HSIA</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 07:45:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tk 5,000 fine for selling cigarettes near schools, hospitals</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tk-5000-fine-for-selling-cigarettes-near-schools-hospitals</link><description>The government has promulgated the Smoking and Tobacco Products Usage (Control) (Amendment) Ordinance, 2025, with a provision of maximum fine of Tk 5,000 for selling cigarettes or tobacco products in areas near educational institutions, hospitals and other sensitive areas.
The ordinance was promul</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 08:00:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UAE to pull remaining forces from Yemen in crisis with Saudi Arabia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/uae-to-pull-remaining-forces-from-yemen-in-crisis-with-saudi-arabia</link><description>The United Arab Emirates said on Tuesday it was pulling its remaining forces out of Yemen after Saudi Arabia backed a call for UAE forces to leave within 24 hours, deepening a crisis between the two Gulf powers and oil producers.
Hours earlier, Saudi-led coalition forces had attacked the southern</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 07:45:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Md Nazmul Huda Sarkar promoted to DMD at Midland Bank</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/md-nazmul-huda-sarkar-promoted-to-dmd-at-midland-bank</link><description>Midland Bank PLC has promoted Md Nazmul Huda Sarkar to the position of Deputy Managing Director (DMD), effective from January 1, 2026, according to a media statement Wednesday.
Prior to this promotion, Md Nazmul Huda Sarkar served as Senior Executive Vice President (SEVP) and Chief Technology Offi</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 08:00:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tamijuddin Textile Mills holds AGM, approves 22pc dividend</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/tamijuddin-textile-mills-holds-agm-approves-22pc-dividend</link><description>The 42nd Annual General Meeting (AGM) of Tamijuddin Textile Mills PLC was held on Tuesday (December 30), 2025, at Gulshan Club in Gulshan 2, Dhaka.
The meeting was chaired by Chowdhury Mohammad Hanif Shoeb, chairman of the company. Other directors, along with the company secretary and the chief fi</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 08:15:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Managing Director of Notundhora Group receives Global NRB Awards 2025</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/managing-director-of-notundhora-group-receives-global-nrb-awards-2025</link><description>Managing Director of Notundhora Group, Dr. Md. Shadi-Uz-Zaman received "Global NRB Awards 2025" in the field of "Visionary Leadership in Real Estate &amp; Community Development" from the Honourable Governor of Bangladesh Bank, Dr. Ahsan H. Mansur in the NRB Global Convention, Dhaka 2025 at the  Gr</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 08:45:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India FM Jaishankar meets BNP leader Tarique to convey condolences over Khaleda's death</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/india-fm-jaishankar-meets-bnp-leader-tarique-to-convey-condolences-over-khaledas-death</link><description>India’s External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar has met Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) Acting Chairperson Tarique Rahman in Dhaka to convey India’s condolences following the death of his mother, former prime minister Khaleda Zia.
According to a statement posted on the BNP’s of</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 09:00:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khaleda Zia’s janaza held with tears of lakhs of mourners</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/khaleda-zias-janaza-held-with-tears-of-lakhs-of-mourners</link><description>Hundreds of thousands of people on Wednesday offered prayers at Manik Mia Avenue as the namaz-e-janaza of BNP Chairperson and three-time former Prime Minister Begum Khaleda Zia was held, bidding her a final farewell amid waves of grief.
Mufti Abdul Malek, Khatib of the national mosque Baitul</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 10:00:53 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>