<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 03:42:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>6 Bangladeshi peacekeepers killed in Sudan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/assault-on-un-base-in-abyei-claims-six-bangladeshi-lives-injures-eight-others</link><description>Six Bangladeshi peacekeepers have been killed and eight others injured in an attack on a United Nations base in Abyei, Sudan, the Inter-Services Public Relations (ISPR) has confirmed.
The assault occurred amid ongoing clashes in the region, the military’s media wing said in a statement issue</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 18:41:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Salah returns for Liverpool amid uncertainty over Merseyside future</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/salah-returns-for-liverpool-amid-uncertainty-over-merseyside-future</link><description>Liverpool forward Mohamed Salah made his return for the Merseyside club to loud applause and a standing ovation at Anfield during Saturday's Premier League clash with Brighton &amp; Hove Albion.
The Egyptian, whose future at the club has been in doubt since his scathing criticism a week earlier, was n</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 18:56:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hadi remains in critical condition with injury to brain stem, hospital says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hadi-remains-in-critical-condition-with-injury-to-brain-stem-ventilator-support-continues</link><description>Inquilab Mancha spokesperson Sharif Osman Hadi, who was shot in the capital’s Bijoynagar area on Friday, remains in critical condition while undergoing treatment at Evercare Hospital in Dhaka, hospital authorities said on Saturday.
Doctors said the bullet caused severe damage to Hadi’s</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 19:11:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>RMG export to US beats BD’s competitors</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/rmg-export-to-us-beats-bds-competitors</link><description>Bangladesh's apparel export to the United States, its single-largest market, circumvents tariff tempests and records a double-digit growth of18.64 per cent, the highest among major competitors, in the first nine months of 2025.
According to US official count, the exports grew both in terms of va</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 19:26:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CA meets Hadi family, vows justice, full med support</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ca-meets-hadi-family-vows-justice-full-med-support</link><description>Bangladesh's major political parties pledge to stay united against a "coordinated bid" to jeopardize the July uprising and jointly protest the shooting of an activist and prospective independent election candidate, Sharif Osman Hadi.
Leaders from the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP), Jamaat-e-Is</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 02:30:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hadi still in critical condition: Doctor</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hadi-still-in-critical-condition-doctor</link><description>Doctors said on Saturday the condition of Inqilab Mancha spokesperson Sharif Osman Hadi remained critical due to the severe brain injury he suffered in the shooting by assailants in the city on Friday.
Director (media services) at Evercare Hospital Bangladesh Dr Arif Mahmud said that the condition</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 02:00:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt mulls converting Bhola island gas to LNG</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-mulls-converting-bhola-island-gas-to-lng</link><description>The government mulls converting around 30 million cubic feet per day (mmcfd) of unutilised natural gas of gas-rich Bhola island to LNG and carrying it to gas-starved industries in the mainland for consumption, said sources.
The volume of converted LNG to be processed from Bhola gas will be only 2.</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 02:15:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NPL surge triggers systemic banking shock</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/npl-surge-triggers-systemic-banking-shock</link><description>Bangladesh is facing a growing "systemic shock" from non-performing loans (NPLs), with bad debts reaching record highs in 2024-25 and laying bare deep vulnerabilities in the country's banking sector.
The sharp deterioration in asset quality has constrained banks' ability to lend and raised fresh c</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 02:30:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>26th AGM of IPL held</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/26th-agm-of-ipl-held</link><description>The 26th Annual General Meeting (AGM) of the International Publications Ltd (IPL), the owning company of The Financial Express, was held on Saturday at the board room of the Apex Footwear Ltd in Gulshan with IPL Chairman Mr Mahbubur Rahman presiding. — FE photo
The 26th Annual General Meetin</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 02:45:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tk 5.0m bounty announced for shooting suspect</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tk-50m-bounty-announced-for-shooting-suspect</link><description>The interim government has announced a reward of Tk 5.0 million for information leading to the arrest of Faisal Karim Masud, the prime suspect in the shooting of Inquilab Mancha spokesperson and Dhaka-8 independent election hopeful Sharif Osman Hadi.
The attack, carried out in broad daylight in th</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 03:00:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Project aid to be trimmed by Tk 140b in FY26 RADP</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/project-aid-to-be-trimmed-by-tk-140b-in-fy26-radp</link><description>The government is likely to significantly reduce the project aid portion in the upcoming Revised Annual Development Programme (RADP) for the current fiscal year (FY) 2025-26, as many agencies have failed to implement projects on time, officials said on Saturday.
The allocation from foreign project</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 03:15:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IFAD approves $51.4m co-financing</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/ifad-approves-514m-co-financing</link><description>The Executive Board of the International Fund for Agricultural Development (IFAD), at its 146th session held on December 9-10, approved US$51.4 million in financing as IFAD's contribution to a $211.7 million project in Bangladesh, a spokesman said on Saturday.
The new investment aims to enhance cl</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 03:30:44 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>