<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 14:34:22 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>BFUJ, DUJ demand immediate 10th Wage Board announcement</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bfuj-duj-demand-immediate-10th-wage-board-announcement</link><description>Bangladesh Federal Union of Journalists (BFUJ) and Dhaka Union of Journalists (DUJ) on Wednesday demanded immediate announcement of the 10th Wage Board award for media professionals along with an interim dearness allowance.
BFUJ President Obaidur Rahman Shaheen, its Secretary General Kader Gani Ch</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 11:28:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Citizens Bank PLC inaugurates Kawran Bazar Sub Branch</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/citizens-bank-plc-inaugurates-kawran-bazar-sub-branch</link><description>Citizens Bank PLC has recently opened Kawran Bazar Sub Branch at Kazi Nazrul Islam Avenue, Dhaka.
Mr. Masuduzzaman, Chairman, Executive Committee of the Board of Directors of Citizens Bank PLC. formally inaugurated the Sub Branch as Chief Guest and delivered his valuable speech in presence of Inde</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 11:43:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Govt to renew passports for 69,000 Rohingyas under Saudi pressure’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-to-renew-passports-for-69000-rohingyas-under-saudi-pressure-touhid</link><description>Bangladesh has agreed to renew passports for 69,000 Rohingya refugees currently living in Saudi Arabia, following sustained pressure from Riyadh, said foreign adviser Touhid Hossain on Wednesday, insisting that the move does not confer citizenship.
Talking to the reporters, the interim government&amp;</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 11:58:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No security situation warrants diplomats’ families to go back home: Touhid Hossain</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/no-security-situation-warrants-diplomats-families-to-go-back-home-touhid-hossain</link><description>Foreign Affairs Adviser Md Touhid Hossain on Wednesday said there is no situation in the country that would compel foreign diplomats to send their family members back home, stressing that he sees no justification for the reported non-family posting of Indian diplomats.
“I don’t find an</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 12:13:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fire at Uttara Sector 11 kitchen market doused</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fire-engulfs-uttara-sector-11-kitchen-market</link><description>The fire that broke out at a kitchen market in the capital’s Uttara Sector 11 on Wednesday evening has been brought under control.
The blaze started at around 5:38 pm and was brought under control at around 6:08 pm, Fire Service Control Room Duty Officer Rakibul Hasan confirmed to the media.</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 12:28:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Indian parliament pays tributes to Bangladesh’s former PM Khaleda Zia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/indian-parliament-pays-tributes-to-bangladeshs-former-pm-khaleda-zia</link><description>The Rajya Sabha on Wednesday paid tribute to Bangladesh's former prime minister Khaleda Zia, besides erstwhile members of the upper house of the Indian parliament, L Ganesan and Suresh Kalmadi, who also passed away recently.
Soon after the house met for the day and before the laying of papers, Raj</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 12:43:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EU team meets Chattogram Jamaat leaders</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/eu-team-meets-chattogram-jamaat-leaders</link><description>Visiting European Union (EU) Election Observation Mission on Wednesday held meeting with Bangladesh Jamaat Islami Chattogram city unit leaders and extensively shared mutual views on upcoming election related issues.
Jamaat leaders at the meeting expressed their deep concern over nomination of bank</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 12:58:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UNDP, BSEC join forces to scale sustainable finance</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/undp-bsec-join-forces-to-scale-sustainable-finance</link><description>The United Nations Development Programme (UNDP) and the Bangladesh Securities and Exchange Commission (BSEC) signed a Memorandum of Understanding (MoU) on Wednesday.
The MoU was signed at the BSEC Bhaban, Dhaka, Bangladesh, marking a significant step toward mobilizing long-term domestic and intern</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 13:13:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Amnesty calls for human rights guarantees during election period in open letter to Yunus</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/amnesty-calls-for-human-rights-guarantees-during-election-period-in-open-letter-to-yunus</link><description>Bangladesh’s interim government must restore public trust by guaranteeing full respect for human rights and the rule of law in the fortnight ahead of next month’s national elections, Amnesty International’s Secretary General, Agnes Callamard, said in an open letter to Chief A</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 13:28:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP-Jamaat clash leaves 30 injured in Sherpur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bnp-jamaat-clash-leaves-30-injured-in-sherpur</link><description>At least 30 people were injured in a clash between supporters of Jamaat-e-Islami and the BNP in Jhenaigati upazila of Sherpur on Wednesday afternoon.
At least six motorcycles and over a hundred of chairs were vandalised  and set on fire during the clash that began at 3 pm.
The clash broke ou</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 13:43:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh unmoved by who thinks what about its decision on drone making: Foreign Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/doesnt-matter-who-thinks-what-about-bangladesh-decision-on-drone-making-foreign-adviser</link><description>Foreign Affairs Adviser Md Touhid Hossain on Wednesday defended the government’s decision to set up a UAV (drone) manufacturing and assembly plant in Bangladesh with support from China, stressing that it matters little what others may think about the move.
“If Bangladesh plans to estab</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 13:58:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat leader’s house set on fire in Bogura</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jamaat-leaders-house-set-on-fire-in-bogura</link><description>Miscreants set the house of a local Jamaat leader on fire at Burujbazar of Gabtoli upazila in Bogura district early Wednesday.
Shahadat Hossain, superintendent of Bogura Police, said a group of miscreants set the house of Alamgir Hossain Alam, secretary of Nepaltoli union unit Jamaat-e-Islami, on</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 14:13:20 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>