<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 10:26:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>DMTCL plans safety audit, to seek international support for metro rail operations</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/dmtcl-plans-safety-audit-to-seek-international-support-for-metro-rail-operations</link><description>The Dhaka Metro Rail Company is now planning to conduct a safety audit and carry out the operation and maintenance of the metro rail through renowned international companies, following several accidents and the identification of various problems across its systems.
Due to a lack of capacity and sk</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 07:21:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BTMA president urges policy reform, govt support for textile growth</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/btma-president-urges-policy-reform-govt-support-for-textile-growth</link><description>Showkat Aziz Russell, president of the Bangladesh Textile Mills Association (BTMA), has expressed concern over the challenges and fluctuating growth of the country's textile sector.
Speaking on Monday at a roundtable organised by The Financial Express, he said, “We are not seeing significant</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 07:36:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Interim govt seeks 'united political guidance' on July Charter referendum</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/interim-govt-seeks-united-political-guidance-on-july-charter-referendum</link><description>Bangladesh’s interim government has sought guidance from political parties over the implementation process for the July Charter and holding a referendum on it, asking them to resolve their differences and come to a united agreement.
An emergency meeting of the Advisory Council on Monday deci</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 07:51:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Upcoming election to determine Bangladesh’s future direction: CEC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/upcoming-election-to-determine-bangladeshs-future-direction-cec</link><description>Chief Election Commissioner AMM Nasir Uddin on Monday said the country's transition from the current critical time depends on the next parliamentary election.
"Bangladesh now stands at a very critical moment. Which direction we will move towards as a nation and as a country and how we will walk al</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 08:06:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BCMEA president stresses good governance to boost ceramic sector</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bcmea-president-stresses-good-governance-to-boost-ceramic-sector</link><description>Moynul Islam, president of the Bangladesh Ceramic Manufacturers and Exporters Association (BCMEA), has underscored the need for good governance to ensure sustainable growth of the country’s ceramic industry.
“Without improving governance, nothing will improve. When I look at reform opp</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 08:21:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Another shipment of over 60, 000 tonnes of US wheat arrives at Ctg port</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/another-shipment-of-over-60-000-tonnes-of-us-wheat-arrives-at-ctg-port</link><description>Another consignment of over 60,000 tonnes of wheat from the United States (US) has arrived at Chittagong Port.
MV SPAR ARIES, carrying 60,802 tonnes of wheat, docked at the outer anchorage of the country's premier seaport on Monday, said a statement of the Ministry of Food.
The shipment came unde</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 08:36:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh drops music, physical education teacher posts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-drops-music-physical-education-teacher-posts</link><description>The Ministry of Primary and Mass Education has decided to scrap the newly created posts for music teachers in government primary schools, following criticism from several religious organisations.
At the same time, the ministry has also cancelled the new position of physical education teacher, repo</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 09:06:12 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>