<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 09:41:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>No scope for NCP to get ‘shapla’ symbol: EC Secretary</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/no-scope-for-ncp-to-get-shapla-symbol-ec-secretary</link><description>Election Commission (EC) Senior Secretary Akhtar Ahmed has said that the National Citizen Party (NCP) will not be allotted the ‘Shapla’ (water lily) symbol. The party has been asked to select an alternative symbol and inform the commission by October 19.
“If the NCP fails to choo</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 08:09:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Process to receive bail bonds online begins Wednesday: Asif Nazrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/process-to-receive-bail-bonds-online-begins-wednesday-asif-nazrul</link><description>Law, Justice and Parliamentary Affairs Adviser Dr Asif Nazrul on Tuesday said the process of receiving bail bonds online will begin on a trial basis tomorrow (Wednesday), enabling bail documents to reach prisons directly with a single click.
“After a person secures bail, there are reportedly</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 08:24:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IOM launches Mobile Cinema Caravan ‘CinemArena’ in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/iom-launches-mobile-cinema-caravan-cinemarena-in-bangladesh</link><description>The International Organisation for Migration (IOM) has launched the renowned mobile cinema caravan 'CinemArena' in Bangladesh for the first time in Asia, aiming to raise awareness and foster dialogue on safe migration and human mobility.
With support from the Italian Ministry of Foreign Affairs an</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 08:54:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Administration hopes good voter turnout in CUCSU polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/administration-hopes-good-voter-turnout-in-cucsu-polls</link><description>Students are nearly ready to choose their representatives in the Chittagong University Central Students’ Union (CUCSU) and hall and hostel union elections.
Campaigning for the polls ended at midnight on Monday. The Chittagong University (CU) students will elect their representatives after 35</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 09:09:31 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>