<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 06:31:58 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>DSE grants FIX certification to nine more brokerage firms</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/dse-grants-fix-certification-to-nine-more-brokerage-firms</link><description>The Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) has awarded FIX (financial information exchange) certification to nine more brokerage firms as part of its initiative to introduce in-house order management systems (OMS) through API connectivity in all brokerage houses.
Mohammad Asadur Rahman, acting managing direct</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 04:30:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>POSTAL VOTING: Over 75,000 NRBs register since Nov 18</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/postal-voting-over-75000-nrbs-register-since-nov-18</link><description>Over 75,000 non-resident Bangladeshi (NRB) voters registered for postal voting, through a hybrid platform developed by the Election Commission (EC), ahead of the upcoming national election.
According to the latest data on the Out-of-Country Voting (OCV) portal, a total of 75,377 NRBs completed reg</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 04:45:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DWASA set to implement Tk 220m pilot project</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dwasa-set-to-implement-tk-220m-pilot-project</link><description>The Local Government Division (LGD) is moving to introduce a smart metering system in the water supply network, following similar modernisation efforts undertaken in the gas and power sectors.
The Dhaka Water Supply and Sewerage Authority (DWASA) is supposed to implement a Tk 220 million pilot pro</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 05:00:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US halts all visa issuance to Afghan citizens</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-halts-all-visa-issuance-to-afghan-citizens</link><description>The United States has paused Afghan visas, Secretary of State Marco Rubio said on Friday, two days after a man from Afghanistan shot and killed one National Guard soldier and critically injured another near the White House.
"President (Donald) Trump's State Department has paused visa issuance for</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 04:16:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Death toll from Hong Kong’s fire rises to 128</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/death-toll-from-hong-kongs-fire-rises-to-128</link><description>Hong Kong on Saturday mourned the 128 people known to have died in a massive fire at a high-rise apartment complex, a toll that is likely to rise, with 200 others still unaccounted for days after the disaster.
Authorities have arrested 11 people in connection with the city's worst blaze in nearly</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 04:31:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Section 144 imposed in Faridpur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/section-144-imposed-in-faridpur</link><description>The local administration has imposed Section 144 in Alfadanga upazila of Faridpur district to avoid possible chaos as two factions of BNP announced programmes at the same venue and time. 
Russel Iqbal, Alfadanga Upazila Nirbahi Officer (UNO) and executive magistrate, issued the order at 11:00</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 04:46:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Maritime ports advised to hoist signal No 2</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/maritime-ports-advised-to-hoist-signal-no-2216565</link><description>Maritime ports of Chattogram, Cox's Bazar, Mongla, and Payra have been advised to keep hoisted distant warning signal No 2 as the cyclonic storm ‘Ditwah’ over coastal Sri Lanka and adjoining southwest Bay of Bengal moved north-northwestwards over the same area.
It was centered at 06 am</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 05:01:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka to get state-of-the-art special needs school</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dhaka-to-get-state-of-the-art-special-needs-school</link><description>The government is set to establish a modern and fully equipped school for children with special needs in Dhaka, aiming to ease the acute shortage of quality education and therapy services for children with neurodevelopmental disorders (NDD) and other disabilities in the capital.
The new institutio</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 05:16:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Adani seeks up to $5 billion investment in Google data centre to join AI boom</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/indias-adani-seeks-up-to-5-billion-investment-in-google-data-centre-to-join-ai-boom</link><description>India's Adani Group plans to invest up to $5 billion in Alphabet-owned Google's India AI data centre project, an executive said on Friday, as it seeks to cash in on booming demand for data capacity in the world's most populous nation.
In October, Google said it would invest $15 billion over five y</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 05:31:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sammilito Islami bank to be launched next week: BB Governor</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/sammilito-islami-bank-to-be-launched-next-week-bb-governor</link><description>Bangladesh Bank (BB) governor Dr Ahsan H Mansur said the much-talked-about proposed Sammilito Islami Bank will be launched next week.
Speaking as the chief guest at the 4th Bangladesh Economic Conference on Saturday, the central bank governor said they have almost completed all the formalities to</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 05:46:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US FDA memo links 10 child deaths to COVID vaccines, New York Times reports</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/us-fda-memo-links-10-child-deaths-to-covid-vaccines-new-york-times-reports</link><description>The US Food and Drug Administration said in an internal memo that at least 10 children had likely died "because of" COVID-19 vaccinations, citing myocarditis, or heart inflammation, as a possible cause, the New York Times reported on Friday.
The Department of Health and Human Services, which inclu</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 06:01:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>11 Bangladeshis arrested in Singapore anti-drug raid</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/11-bangladeshis-arrested-in-singapore-anti-drug-raid</link><description>Singapore’s Central Narcotics Bureau (CNB) has arrested 11 Bangladeshis and one Myanmar national in a coordinated anti-drug operation in a Woodlands dormitory.
The raid was conducted from late Thursday night until early Friday morning amid heavy rain, with support from multiple government bo</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 06:16:18 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>