<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 06:35:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Political stability vital to sustain economic momentum: DCCI</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/political-stability-vital-to-sustain-economic-momentum-dcci</link><description>Dhaka Chamber of Commerce &amp; Industry (DCCI) has called for prudent, timely and effective economic measures to safeguard Bangladesh's economic momentum in 2026, amid political tension ahead of the 13th national election scheduled to be held on 12 February.
In this context, DCCI urges the interim go</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 01:55:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Auditors sound alarm as support lags and warnings go unheeded</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/auditors-sound-alarm-as-support-lags-and-warnings-go-unheeded</link><description>Auditors make observations on businesses' financial reports, but no regulatory actions follow critical opinions on data mismatches or other anomalies. The accumulation of non-performing loans is just one outcome of that regulatory failure, say auditors.
This is the backdrop to repeated attempts by</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 02:10:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Lack of food irradiation facilities fuels onion price swings</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/lack-of-food-irradiation-facilities-fuels-onion-price-swings</link><description>Every winter, Bangladesh produces a surplus of onions, causing prices to fall sharply to around Tk 60 per kilogramme, forcing farmers to sell below cost while large quantities rot in storage. Months later, shortages reappear, middlemen become active, imports are allowed, and prices surge again, hit</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 02:25:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BRTC's CNG bus-purchase project limping</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/brtcs-cng-bus-purchase-project-limping</link><description>The Bangladesh Road Transport Corporation (BRTC) has spent only Tk 27.5 million in more than two and a half years -- just 0.24 per cent of the total Tk 11.33 billion project -- to procure 340 CNG-powered single-decker air-conditioned buses.
Amid delays in bid evaluation, foreign lender approvals,</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 03:56:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Video messages of Hadi murder prime suspect under scrutiny: DMP chief</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/video-messages-of-hadi-murder-prime-suspect-under-scrutiny-dmp-chief</link><description>Dhaka Metropolitan Police (DMP) Commissioner Sheikh Md Sazzat Ali said that police were scrutinising two video messages reportedly released by Faisal Karim Masud, the prime suspect in the murder of Inquilab Moncho spokesperson Sharif Osman Hadi.
"No comments. We (police) are closely examining the</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 04:11:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt committed to ensuring justice for Hadi's murder, says Foreign Affairs Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-committed-to-ensuring-justice-for-hadis-murder-says-foreign-affairs-adviser</link><description>Foreign Affairs Adviser Md Touhid Hossain has said that the government is committed to bringing those involved in the murder of Hadi to justice.
He said work is continuing to complete the trial as quickly as possible.
"We cannot rush the judicial process. We are trying to bring back everyone invo</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 04:26:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IPO rulebook overhauled as BSEC hopes to attract ‘good companies’ in 2026</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/ipo-rulebook-overhauled-as-bsec-hopes-to-attract-good-companies-in-2026</link><description>The Bangladesh Securities and Exchange Commission (BSEC) has announced the publication of the new Initial Public Offering (IPO) rules in a gazette, voicing optimism that the reform will pave the way for quality companies to enter the capital market this year.
According to the regulator, the Bangla</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 04:41:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Reasons Bangladesh's mid-career women vanish from the workforce</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/youth-and-entrepreneurship/reasons-bangladeshs-mid-career-women-vanish-from-the-workforce</link><description>Anika stepped away from her specialist role in technology sector in Dhaka for two years to care for her newborn. It was a deliberate choice, or so she believed. Within months of returning, she discovered that the IT industry had moved on without her. Recruiters questioned her technical currency. Sa</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 04:56:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka's youths helping children dream bigger</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/youth-and-entrepreneurship/dhakas-youths-helping-children-dream-bigger</link><description>On a quiet winter morning in Dhaka, the sun struggles through the fog as children's laughter fills a schoolyard. Small hands press soil around young saplings. Inside a bright classroom, children turn book pages with wide eyes, discovering stories far beyond their textbooks.
In a city known for tra</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 05:11:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Why others should follow him</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/youth-and-entrepreneurship/why-others-should-follow-him</link><description>In a world where most people measure success in salaries and promotions, Munjer Alam chose a different path. Once the director of Finance at a prestigious multinational company, he turned away from the glow of corporate life to build something humbler, greener, and truer. An agricultural haven was</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 05:26:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India-Bangladesh ties will strengthen after normalcy restores post elections, Jaishankar says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/india-bangladesh-ties-will-strengthen-after-normalcy-restores-post-elections-jaishankar-says</link><description>India expects neighbourly relations in the region to grow stronger once the situation in Bangladesh normalises through elections, Indian External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar has said.
He expressed the hope while responding to a question about his recent visit to Bangladesh at an event in Chennai</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 05:41:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UN to meet Monday over US action in Venezuela</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/un-to-meet-monday-over-us-action-in-venezuela</link><description>The United Nations Security Council is due to meet on Monday after the US attacked Venezuela and deposed its long-serving autocratic President Nicolas Maduro, a move that UN Secretary-General Antonio Guterres views as setting "a dangerous precedent."
Colombia, backed by Russia and China, requested</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 05:56:48 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>