<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 02:06:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Taiyeb questions mobile traders’ opposition to NEIR after attack on BTRC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/taiyeb-questions-mobile-traders-opposition-to-neir-after-attack-on-btrc</link><description>Faiz Ahmad Taiyeb, special assistant to the chief advisor on information technology, has clarified the government’s firm stance on the implementation of the National Equipment Identity Register (NEIR).
He made the remarks on Sunday while visiting the Bangladesh Telecommunication Regulatory C</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 16:45:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Venezuela's interim government backs Maduro after his US capture</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/venezuelas-interim-government-says-it-remains-united-behind-maduro-after-his-us-capture</link><description>A top Venezuelan official declared on Sunday that the country's government would stay unified behind President Nicolas Maduro, whose capture by the US has sparked deep uncertainty about what is next for the oil-rich South American nation.
Maduro is in a New York detention centre awaiting a Monday</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 17:00:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gold prices rise for first time this year in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/gold-prices-rise-for-first-time-this-year-in-bangladesh</link><description>After three consecutive cuts, gold prices in Bangladesh have increased for the first time in 2026, as the Bangladesh Jewellers Association (BAJUS) announced a fresh hike on Sunday.
In a notification issued at night, BAJUS said the price of 22-carat gold has been raised by Tk 2,216 per bhori (11.66</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 17:15:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>LPG crisis artificial, stern action to be taken: Ministry</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/lpg-crisis-artificial-stern-action-to-be-taken-ministry</link><description>After three consecutive cuts, gold prices in Bangladesh have increased for the first time in 2026, as the Bangladesh Jewellers Association (BAJUS) announced a fresh hike on Sunday.
In a notification issued at night, BAJUS said the price of 22-carat gold has been raised by Tk 2,216 per bhori (11.66</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 17:30:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tigress trapped in poachers’ snare in Sundarbans rescued</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tigress-trapped-in-poachers-snare-in-sundarbans-rescued</link><description>A tigress trapped in a snare set by deer poachers in the Sundarbans was rescued by the Forest Department on Sunday afternoon near Boiragi Bari along Sarkir canal in Mongla upazila of Bagerhat district.
The tigress was tranquilised and safely freed from the trap around 3pm, said Divisional Forest O</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 17:47:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Deadline for NBR bifurcation missed, Jan action in wintry chill</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/deadline-for-nbr-bifurcation-missed-jan-action-in-wintry-chill</link><description>December deadline is missed and bid for completing all must-dos for bifurcating the revenue board within January has yet to get into right gear although revenue-sector overhaul is among major uprising-mandated reforms.  
Officials say the final stages of splitting the National Board of R</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 18:02:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Top business leaders meet Tarique Rahman, discuss economy, jobs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/top-business-leaders-meet-tarique-rahman-discuss-economy-jobs</link><description>Top business leaders and industrial entrepreneurs of the country held a meeting with BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman on Sunday night, discussing the current economic situation, investment challenges and rising unemployment.
The meeting was held at the BNP Chairperson’s political office in</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 18:17:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique assures business-friendly decisions for  economic rebound</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/tarique-assures-business-friendly-decisions-for-economic-rebound</link><description>Acting Chairman of BNP Tarique Rahman has assured business leaders that he would implement business-friendly policies if elected to form the government in the next general election.
He made this assurance during a meeting with prominent business leaders and entrepreneurs on Sunday evening at his G</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 18:32:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump is a threat to global order</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/trump-is-a-threat-to-global-order</link><description>As president Donald Trump spoke to the press at Mar A Lago, with his secretary of state, secretary of war and joint chief of staff behind him, a stunned world including his own country came to know that American armed forces had attacked Venezuela in the dead of night, abducted the president of tha</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 18:50:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>LPG cylinder-price hike and BERC inaction</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/lpg-cylinder-price-hike-and-berc-inaction</link><description>The Bangladesh Energy Regulatory Commission (BERC) has fixed the price of a 12-kg LPG (liquid petroleum gas) cylinder at Tk1,253 but its retail price has now crossed the Tk 2,000 mark. However, according to a report carried in a leading contemporary, the unilateral price hike is not uniform. The pr</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 19:05:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Return of gold as safest asset</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/return-of-gold-as-safest-asset</link><description>Precious metals including gold and silver have turned pricier recently. This was the trend last year when central banks around the world added hundreds of tons of gold to their reserves, according to the World Gold Council trade association. Similarly, price of silver has also seen a significant ri</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 19:20:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Poor management of traffic system</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/poor-management-of-traffic-system</link><description>The interim government has apparently failed to bring about any perceptible change in the atrocious traffic congestion and road safety.  On the contrary, the city's traffic situation appears to have worsened as Dhaka has literally become a city of road blockades. Since the government assumed o</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 19:35:33 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>