<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 16:31:22 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Two-year-old child trapped in abandoned deep well in Rajshahi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/two-year-old-child-trapped-in-abandoned-deep-well-in-rajshahi</link><description>A two-year-old boy became trapped inside an abandoned deep well in Koelhat village of Pachander Union in Tanor upazila of Rajshahi on Wednesday afternoon.
Sajid, son of Rakib, fell into the 35-feet-deep pipe while playing near his home in Koelhat Purbapara village. Locals initially tried to rescue</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 14:30:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Doubts over acceptable polls persist: Debapriya</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cpds-debapriya-says-concerns-about-credible-election-remain-despite-assurances</link><description>Debapriya Bhattacharya, fellow at the Centre for Policy Dialogue (CPD), has expressed concerns over the country’s capacity to hold a “credible and acceptable election”.
He spoke after a regional consultation organised by the Citizen Platform for SDG Implementation, Bangladesh, on</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 14:45:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>22 held smuggling 1,500 cement bags to Myanmar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/navy-detains-22-people-attempting-to-smuggle-1500-cement-bags-to-myanmar</link><description>The Bangladesh Navy has detained 22 people and seized two engine-powered boats carrying 1,500 bags of cement while attempting to smuggle them to Myanmar through the Bay of Bengal near St Martin’s Island in Teknaf, Cox’s Bazar.
During a routine night patrol on Tuesday, the Navy intercep</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 13:45:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt firm on NEIR activation from December 16</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-firm-on-neir-activation-from-december-16</link><description>The government is moving ahead with its plan to activate the National Equipment Identity Register (NEIR) from 16 December, while allowing the sale of duty-evaded mobile handsets already in the market until March next year.
However, the concession has failed to satisfy a section of phone traders wh</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 14:00:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Canada reaffirms support for human rights in Bangladesh, honours HR defenders</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/canada-reaffirms-support-for-human-rights-in-bangladesh-honours-hr-defenders</link><description>The High Commission of Canada in Bangladesh on Wednesday recognised Kalpona Akter and Rani Yan Yan as the inaugural laureates of the Canadian High Commission in Bangladesh Human Rights Defenders award for their meaningful contributions to the promotion and protection of human rights in Bangladesh.</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 14:15:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fahmida Khatun appointed as member of UN chief’s independent expert panel on MVI</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fahmida-khatun-appointed-as-member-of-un-chiefs-independent-expert-panel-on-mvi</link><description>United Nations Secretary-General António Guterres has appointed local think tank Centre for Policy Dialogue’s (CPD) Executive Director Dr Fahmida Khatun as a member of the Independent Expert Advisory Panel on the Multidimensional Vulnerability Index (MVI).
The 15-member global panel,</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 14:30:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NBR withdraws excise duty on air tickets for Hajj flights</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nbr-withdraws-excise-duty-on-air-tickets-for-hajj-flights</link><description>The National Board of Revenue (NBR) has waived excise duty on air tickets for Bangladeshi pilgrims travelling to Saudi Arabia for Hajj in 2026.
The move is aimed at reducing overall pilgrimage expenses and making the holy journey more accessible for ordinary worshippers.
According to an official</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 14:45:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Primary headteachers a step closer to 10th-grade pay</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-advances-process-to-upgrade-primary-headteachers-to-10th-grade-pay</link><description>The administrative process to upgrade the salaries of headteachers in government primary schools from 11th grade to 10th grade has moved forward.
On Wednesday, the recommendation of the Secretary Committee on Administrative Development was sent from the Cabinet Division to the Ministry of Primary</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 15:00:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Islami Bank holds board meeting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/islami-bank-hods-board-meeting</link><description>A meeting of the board of directors of Islami Bank Bangladesh PLC was held on Wednesday (December 10, 2025) at the Islami Bank Tower.
Professor Dr. M. Zubaidur Rahman, chairman of the bank, presided over the meeting, according to a press release.
Mohammad Khurshid Wahab, chairman of the executive</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 15:15:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sadiqur Rahman promoted to additional managing director at Meghna Bank</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/sadiqur-rahman-promoted-to-additional-managing-director-at-meghna-bank</link><description>Meghna Bank PLC has promoted Md. Sadiqur Rahman to the position of Additional Managing Director, according to a press release.
Before this elevation, he served as Deputy Managing Director and also held the role of Managing Director &amp; CEO (Current Charge).
The press statement says, “Mr. Rahm</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 15:30:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ICT orders notice in newspapers to summon Sajeeb Wazed Joy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ict-orders-notice-in-newspapers-to-summon-sajeeb-wazed-joy</link><description>The International Crimes Tribunal (ICT) on Wednesday ordered the publication of a notice in two national dailies to summon Sajeeb Wazed Joy, son of former Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina, in a case related to crimes against humanity during the July-August uprising in 2024.
A two-member judicial panel</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 15:45:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khaleda Zia responds to treatment, doctors optimistic about her progress</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/khaleda-zia-responds-to-treatment-doctors-optimistic-about-her-progress</link><description>BNP Chairperson Begum Khaleda Zia is responding to treatment at Evercare Hospital in the capital as she did in the past, according to her personal physician and BNP leader Dr AZM Zahid Hossain.
Addressing the media outside the hospital on Wednesday night, the BNP standing committee member said the</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 16:00:48 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>