<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 12:44:52 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>No scope of referendum before elections: BNP’s Fakhrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/no-scope-of-referendum-before-elections-says-bnps-mirza-fakhrul</link><description>There is no scope for holding a referendum before the general elections, says BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir.
He shared the party’s stance at a discussion on Friday as eight like-minded political parties, including Jamaat-e-Islami, are protesting to demand a referendum on</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 09:30:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CID notice in newspapers declares Hasina, 260 other fugitives</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cid-notice-in-newspapers-declares-hasina-260-other-fugitives</link><description>The Criminal Investigation Department (CID) on Friday published in two newspapers a notice declaring former Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina and 260 others as fugitives in a sedition case related to the ‘Joy Bangla Brigade’ platform.
According to the notice, published in English and Bengal</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 10:00:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nat’l polls will be held before Feb 15 regardless of referendum decision: Shafiqul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/natl-polls-will-be-held-before-feb-15-regardless-of-referendum-decision-shafiqul</link><description>Chief Adviser's Press Secretary Shafiqul Alam on Saturday said that the national election will be held before February 15, regardless of the decision taken regarding the proposed referendum. "The Chief Adviser will make the final decision on the referendum issue. Whatever the decision may be,</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 10:15:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Protests over Tanzania’s election results continue for third day</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/protests-over-tanzanias-election-results-continue-for-third-day</link><description>Demonstrations over Tanzania’s disputed election results entered a third day Friday, with hundreds of protesters clashing with police in the commercial capital, Dar es Salaam, prompting the deployment of the military and an internet shutdown.
The unrest began Wednesday after the Chama Cha Ma</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 10:45:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>British Council awards ‘Connections Through Culture’ grants to seven artistic collaborations between Bangladesh, UK</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/others/british-council-awards-connections-through-culture-grants-to-seven-artistic-collaborations-between-bangladesh-uk</link><description>The British Council has recently announced the recipients of its Connections Through Culture (CTC) Grant Programme 2025, which supports collaborations between artists and cultural practitioners in the United Kingdom and internationally.
Selected through an international open call, 127 grants have</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 11:00:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BRAC Healthcare now at Badda</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/brac-healthcare-now-at-badda</link><description>BRAC Healthcare Limited, a concern of BRAC Enterprises, has inaugurated its fourth centre in Gulshan Badda Link Road.
The centre, located at TA-97, Middle Badda, Gulshan, Dhaka, was officially opened by Tamara Hasan Abed, Managing Director of BRAC Enterprises, on Thursday (October 30, 2025), accor</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 11:15:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cooperatives can help build an equal and self-reliant Bangladesh: Prof Yunus</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cooperatives-can-help-build-an-equal-and-self-reliant-bangladesh-prof-yunus</link><description>Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus has called for strengthening the cooperative movement to build an inclusive, equitable and self-reliant Bangladesh.
He made the call marking the ‘54th National Co-operative Day’ to be observed on November 1.
In a message issued on Friday, Pr</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 11:47:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>27 police officers hurt in Ctg police lines accident</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/27-police-officers-injured-as-bus-overturns-in-chattogram-police-lines</link><description>At least 27 female police personnel have been injured after a bus overturned inside the Dampara Police Lines in Chattogram.
The accident occurred on Friday afternoon while the vehicle was descending a slope within the compound, police said.
Of the injured, 12 were taken to Chittagong Medical Coll</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 12:17:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>