<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 12:54:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Gold prices hit new record high in Bangladesh within 12 hours of cut</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/gold-prices-hit-new-record-high-in-bangladesh-within-12-hours-of-cut</link><description>Gold prices in Bangladesh have surged again, just 12 hours after a brief reduction, setting a new all-time record in the domestic market.
The price of the highest-quality 22-carat gold has been increased by Tk 6,299 per bhori (11.664 grams), pushing the price to a record Tk 255,617 per bhori, acco</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 09:43:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Denmark, NATO seek to boost Arctic security amid Greenland crisis</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/denmark-nato-seek-to-boost-arctic-security-amid-greenland-crisis</link><description>Denmark's Prime Minister Mette Frederiksen said on Friday she had agreed with NATO chief Mark Rutte that the alliance needs to boost security in the Arctic following weeks of turmoil over US President Donald Trump's threat to annex Greenland.
The governments of Denmark and Greenland, a Danish auto</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 09:58:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India's JSW Steel posts quarterly profit rise on higher volume</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/indias-jsw-steel-posts-quarterly-profit-rise-on-higher-volume</link><description>India's JSW Steel (JSTL.NS) reported a jump in third-quarter profit on Friday, as higher sales volumes helped mitigate the impact of lower steel prices.
Its consolidated net profit rose nearly three-fold year-on-year to 21.39 billion rupees ($232.7 million) for the quarter ended December 31.
($1</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 10:13:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>500 foreign observers, journalists expected to oversee upcoming polls: EC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/500-foreign-observers-journalists-expected-to-oversee-upcoming-polls-ec</link><description>Election Commission (EC) Senior Secretary Akhter Ahmed has said nearly 500 foreign observers and journalists are expected to come to Bangladesh to observe the 13th National Parliament Election and the referendum scheduled for February 12.
“We expect nearly 500 foreign observers and journalis</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 10:28:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>North Bangladesh has been deprived since independence: Jamaat chief</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/north-bangladesh-has-been-deprived-since-independence-jamaat-chief</link><description>Jamaat-e-Islami chief Shafiqur Rahman has said North Bangladesh, despite playing a vital role in bolstering the country’s food supply, has been deliberately deprived since the country’s independence.
“Since the creation of Bangladesh, North Bangladesh has not been poor —</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 10:45:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Few women in the race as Bangladesh goes to polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/few-women-in-the-race-as-bangladesh-goes-to-polls</link><description>Despite decades of pledges to ensure women’s political empowerment, the upcoming national election paints a starkly different picture, with female representation on the ballot remaining alarmingly low.
More than 30 registered political parties, including Jamaat-e-Islami, have fielded no fema</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 11:00:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Russia, Ukraine and US set to hold security talks in Abu Dhabi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/russia-ukraine-and-us-set-to-hold-security-talks-in-abu-dhabi</link><description>Russia said it will hold security talks with the US and Ukraine in Abu Dhabi on Friday, but warned after a late-night meeting between President Vladimir Putin and three US envoys that a durable peace would not be possible unless territorial issues were resolved.
Kremlin aide Yuri Ushakov told repo</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 11:15:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dinajpur to have city corporation if Jamaat wins: Shafiqur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dinajpur-to-be-upgraded-to-city-corporation-if-jamaat-comes-to-power-shafiqur</link><description>Jamaat-e-Islami chief Shafiqur Rahman has given assurances that Dinajpur will be converted into a city corporation if his party gets the opportunity to form a government.
He said, “For a larger district, city corporations have become district headquarters in many places. Do you have a city c</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 11:30:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Joint forces arrest 278 across Bangladesh in weeklong drive: ISPR</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/joint-forces-arrest-278-across-bangladesh-in-weeklong-drive-ispr</link><description>-Members of the joint forces, led by the Bangladesh Army, arrested 278 suspected criminals in a nationwide drive between Jan 16 and Jan 22, said the Inter-Services Public Relations (ISPR) on Friday.
The operations were conducted in different parts of the country, including the capital, by units un</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 11:45:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Heathrow's new scanners end dreaded rummage for liquids and laptops</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/heathrows-new-scanners-end-dreaded-rummage-for-liquids-and-laptops</link><description>Passengers will no longer be forced to dig around in their hand luggage to extract shampoos, water bottles and laptops when travelling through security at Heathrow, Europe's busiest airport, thanks to new specialist scanners.
Heathrow said on Friday that all security lanes across its four terminal</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 12:00:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AL ban strips Feb 12 vote of democratic legitimacy, Hasina</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/awami-league-ban-strips-feb-12-vote-of-democratic-legitimacy-hasina-tells-theprint</link><description>Sheikh Hasina has launched a stinging political broadside against the interim government, accusing Chief Advisor Muhammad Yunus of replacing constitutional rule with what she calls “authoritarianism dressed up as transition” by sidelining her party Awami League ahead of the Feb 12 gener</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 12:15:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh, Costa Rica eye stronger ties</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-costa-rica-eye-stronger-ties</link><description>Costa Rica has expressed its support for Bangladesh’s upcoming candidacy as a non-permanent member of the UN Security Council, as the two countries seek to strengthen relations across all potential areas.
Mushfiqul Fazal Ansarey, Ambassador of Bangladesh to Mexico with concurrent accreditati</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 12:30:47 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>