<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 16:32:58 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Chairman of Russian Federation congratulates Tarique</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/chairman-of-russian-federation-congratulates-tarique</link><description>The Chairman of the Government of the Russian Federation Mikhail Mishustin has congratulated Tarique Rahman upon his appointment to the post of the Prime Minister of the People’s Republic of Bangladesh.
The head of the Russian government expressed confidence that constructive joint efforts a</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 12:00:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>FA won’t take action against Man Utd owner Ratcliffe over immigration remarks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/fa-wont-take-action-against-man-utd-owner-ratcliffe-over-immigration-remarks</link><description>Manchester United owner Jim Ratcliffe will face no disciplinary action for saying Britain had been “colonised” by immigrants, the Football Association said on Saturday.
British billionaire Ratcliffe last week apologised for his choice of language but said it was important to raise the</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 12:01:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Banana trunks found inside guide wall construction in Madaripur!</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/banana-trunks-found-inside-guide-wall-construction-in-madaripur</link><description>A road construction project meant to improve connectivity in Madaripur has drawn sharp criticism after residents uncovered banana trunks placed inside the foundation of a guide wall.
The incident occurred at the Charkakair intersection in the Shiruail Union under a project by the Local Government</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 12:16:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Narsingdi retired teacher's tendons severed in land feud, mob torches attackers' home</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/narsingdi-retired-teachers-tendons-severed-in-land-feud-mob-torches-attackers-home</link><description>A retired schoolteacher has been critically injured after his leg tendons were allegedly severed in an attack over a land dispute in Narsingdi’s Shibpur Upazila. Angry residents, incited by rumours of his death, later vandalised and set fire to the accused neighbour’s house.
The incide</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 12:31:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique Rahman exchanges greetings with PMO officials</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-rahman-exchanges-greetings-with-pmo-officials</link><description>Prime Minister Tarique Rahman on Saturday exchanged greetings with the officials and employees of Prime Minister’s Office (PMO) at Tejgaon.
PM’s Additional Press Secretary Atiqur Rahman Rumon said, the Prime Minister exchanged greetings with the officials and employees and inquired abo</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 12:46:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ensuring media freedom my responsibility: Swapon</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/information-minister-swapon-pledges-to-guarantee-independent-media</link><description>Calling a free press essential for democracy, Information and Broadcasting Minister Zahir Uddin Swapon says he sees himself as a “guardian of the media”, responsible for ensuring journalists can work independently and without intimidation.
He made the remarks at a discussion marking th</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 13:01:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mongla Port to undergo radical changes in 6 months: Shipping Minister</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/mongla-port-to-undergo-radical-changes-in-6-months-shipping-minister</link><description>Shipping Minister Shaikh Rabiul Alam on Saturday said radical changes will be brought to the management of Mongla Port within the next 180 days.
He made the remarks while talking to reporters after visiting the port in the afternoon.
The minister said, considering the port’s importance to t</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 13:17:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Buildings must be constructed in accordance with law: Housing Minister</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/buildings-must-be-constructed-in-accordance-with-law-housing-minister</link><description>Housing and Public Works Minister Zakaria Taher Sumon on Friday said that no more high-rise buildings would be allowed to be constructed in violation of the law.
He expressed his firm stance during an exchange of views with officials of the ministry at the Cumilla Circuit House in the afternoon.</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 13:32:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Swiss Ambassador pays homage to language martyrs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/swiss-ambassador-pays-homage-to-language-martyrs</link><description>Swiss Ambassador to Bangladesh Reto Renggli on Saturday visited the Central Shaheed Minar, the language monument in Dhaka, to pay homage to the martyrs of the Bengali Language Movement on the occasion of International Mother Language Day.
“Coming from a country with four languages, we know h</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 13:47:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Knife attack on Jatrabari policeman during search</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/4-men-flee-after-stabbing-jatrabari-policeman-during-search-crude-bombs-found-in-bag</link><description>A routine police search in Dhaka’s Jatrabari has turned violent when a group of youths stabbed a constable and fled, leaving behind a bag containing crude bombs at the checkpoint.
The incident occurred around 2pm on Saturday at a police search post near the Kutubkhali Pocket Gate.
The injur</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 14:02:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New parliament may go into session by March 12: Salahuddin</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/new-parliament-may-go-into-session-by-march-12-salahuddin</link><description>The 13th National Parliament is likely to go into its maiden session on March 12 next month or one or two days earlier, said Home Minister and BNP Standing Committee member Salahuddin Ahmed.
“The first session of the National Parliament will begin on March 12 next month or one or two days ea</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 15:56:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Investing in children’s talents ensures bright future for nation: Minister Amin Ur Rashid</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/investing-in-childrens-talents-ensures-bright-future-for-nation-minister-amin-ur-rashid</link><description>Fisheries and Livestock Minister Mohammad Amin Ur Rashid has said that today’s children are the future of the nation and proper development of their talents will help build a worthy generation.
“If we can develop them properly, the country will have a capable and enlightened generation</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 16:11:59 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>