<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 06:54:06 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>BTMA suspends factory shutdown programme</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/btma-suspends-factory-shutdown-programme</link><description>The Bangladesh Textile Mills Association (BTMA) has suspended its programme to shut down factories following government assurances to resolve the ongoing crisis in the spinning sector.
In a statement issued on Thursday, the primary textile millers' trade body announced the withdrawal of its earlie</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 03:57:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BARC, PKSF to work together for inclusive agricultural growth</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/barc-pksf-to-work-together-for-inclusive-agricultural-growth</link><description>Palli Karma-Sahayak Foundation (PKSF) and the Bangladesh Agricultural Research Council (BARC) will work jointly to strengthen links between agricultural research and extension to achieve inclusive growth.
Although agriculture is a key pillar of food security and employment, it contributes only abo</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 04:12:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>3 RMG factories get LEED certification</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/3-rmg-factories-get-leed-certification</link><description>Three more local garment factories have received LEED (Leadership in Energy and Environmental Design) certification from the US Green Building Council (USGBC), with one achieving the highest score globally, taking Bangladesh's total to 273 LEED-certified factories.
HAMS Garments Ltd, located in Sr</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 04:27:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CIU launches Confucius Chinese Language Site</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ciu-launches-confucius-chinese-language-site</link><description>CHITTOGRAM, Jan 29:Chittagong Independent University (CIU) launched Confucius Chinese Language Site at the campus today Thursday.
North South University Vice Chancellor Prof. Dr. Abdul Hannan Chowdhury inaugurated the Confucius Chinese Language Site as chief guest. He officially announced the inau</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 04:30:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt to split CAAB into regulator, operator</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-to-split-caab-into-regulator-operator</link><description>The government has decided in principle to separate the Civil Aviation Authority of Bangladesh (CAAB) into two entities - regulatory and operational - to remove conflicts of interest and strengthen aviation safety, security and service standards.
According to a press release - issued by the Minist</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 04:45:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>RUET holds int'l conf'ce on ECTE on January 29-31</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ruet-holds-intl-confce-on-ecte-on-january-29-31</link><description>RAJSHAHI, Jan 29: The 5th International Conference on Electrical, Computer and Telecommunication Engineering (ICECTE 2026) started at the Rajshahi University of Engineering and Technology (RUET) auditorium on Thursday. The Faculty of Electrical and Computer Engineering (ECE) is organising the confe</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 05:00:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DUCSU protests killing of Sherpur Jamaat leader</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ducsu-protests-killing-of-sherpur-jamaat-leader</link><description>The Dhaka University Central Students' Union (DUCSU) staged a protest march at Dhaka University on Wednesday night, condemning the killing of a Jamaat-e-Islami leader in Sherpur and demanding justice for the ongoing election-related violence across the country.
The protest was organised in respons</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 05:15:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Expansion, diversification drive Olympic Industries' record Q2 profit</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/expansion-diversification-drive-olympic-industries-record-q2-profit</link><description>Olympic Industries secured the highest quarterly profit of Tk 625 million in the second quarter of FY26, driven by higher sales amid capacity expansion and product portfolio diversification.
The branded biscuit manufacturer sustained its growth momentum, supported by newly introduced chocolate and</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 05:30:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UK lawmaker Blackman questions Bangladesh election credibility</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/uk-lawmaker-blackman-questions-bangladesh-election-credibility</link><description>Robert John Blackman CBE MP, a senior British parliamentarian and member of parliament for Harrow East, has expressed concern over recent political developments in Bangladesh, warning that democratic stability and the rule of law could be at risk if elections are not inclusive and credible.
Blackm</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 05:45:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Square Pharma's Q2 profit rises on higher sales, subsidiary income</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/square-pharmas-q2-profit-rises-on-higher-sales-subsidiary-income</link><description>Square Pharmaceuticals posted double-digit year-on-year profit growth to Tk 7.27 billion in the second quarter of FY26, fueled by higher sales and substantial income from subsidiaries.
The 10 per cent year-on-year growth in earnings in the October-December quarter of FY26 pushed up the EPS of the</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 06:00:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Policy shift boosts Submarine Cables' Q2 profit</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/policy-shift-boosts-submarine-cables-q2-profit</link><description>Bangladesh Submarine Cables recorded a remarkable 80 per cent rise in profit to Tk 780.85 million in the second quarter of FY26, as revenue surged by more than 30 per cent compared with the same quarter a year earlier.
According to the company, the strong earnings growth was driven by a policy shi</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 06:15:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh elected Vice Chair of UN Peacebuilding Commission for 2026</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-elected-vice-chair-of-un-peacebuilding-commission-for-2026</link><description>Bangladesh has been elected as the Vice-Chair of the UN Peacebuilding Commission (PBC) for the year 2026.
The election of the five-member bureau of the PBC was held at the UN Headquarters in New York on Thursday, reports UNB. 
The members of the Commission during its first meeting of the 20t</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 06:30:46 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>