<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 21:20:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>JSD alleges attack en route to election rally</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/attack-vandalism-on-jsd-members-en-route-to-election-rally</link><description>Jatiya Samajtantrik Dal (JSD) activists have alleged attacks while travelling to an election rally in Ramgati Upazila, Lakshmipur.
These attacks took place in several places, including Ramdayal, Azadnagar, and Ramgati Bazar in the Upazila on Monday.
Party leaders claim 15 people were injured, inc</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 17:00:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladeshi sailor rescued from MT Kairos off Bulgarian coast</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladeshi-sailor-rescued-from-drone-hit-mt-kairos-off-bulgarian-coast</link><description>Bangladeshi sailor Mahfuzul Islam Plabon and three others have been rescued by the Bulgarian Coast Guard from the MT Kairos, a ship damaged in a Ukrainian drone attack.
The vessel, drifting uncontrollably off the Bulgarian coast, had its crew rescued on Monday at about 1:30pm Bangladesh time.
The</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 17:15:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tower Hamlets faces governance warning</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/tower-hamlets-council-under-lutfur-rahman-warned-over-governance-issues</link><description>Tower Hamlets Council has been flagged for persistent governance weaknesses, including delays in appointing a permanent chief finance officer, social housing management issues, and long-standing problems with contracts and internal investigations.
An external audit by EY outlined 10 issues at the</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 17:30:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Powerful 7.6-magnitude earthquake strikes Japan's northeast region</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/powerful-76-magnitude-earthquake-strikes-japans-northeast-region</link><description>A powerful 7.6-magnitude earthquake shook northeastern Japan late on Monday, prompting tsunami warnings and orders for about 90,000 residents to evacuate.
The Japan Meteorological Agency said a tsunami as high as 3 metres (10 feet) could hit Japan's northeastern coast after the earthquake struck o</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 17:45:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US sends back 31 Bangladeshis in handcuffs and shackles</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/us-sends-back-31-bangladeshis-in-handcuffs-and-shackles</link><description>The United States has once again sent back Bangladeshis, 31 of them this time, with their hands cuffed and shackled.
A special US military flight brought them to Shahjalal International Airport at 7pm on Monday.
BRAC provided transportation and emergency assistance to the returned migrants.
The</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 18:00:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DU students stage symbolic protest against razakars</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/du-students-stage-symbolic-protest-against-razakars</link><description>In the month of victory, students at Dhaka University (DU) staged a symbolic protest against 1971 razakars (collaborators) by trampling Pakistan’s flag.
A group of students displayed the symbolic flags at the entrances of the university’s TSC and three residential halls, bearing the me</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 18:15:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Recasting multiagency JIT under UK model underway</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/recasting-multiagency-jit-under-uk-model-underway</link><description>Remodeling the stolen asset recovery (SAR) initiative through creating an entity under a legal framework is under active consideration to give the drive a nudge.



Under the latest move Bangladesh Bank (BB) considers replicating UK's National Crime Agency (NCA) model which has written several</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 18:30:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Finding cure to jobless growth</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/finding-cure-to-jobless-growth</link><description>Bangladesh has entered a phase of development marked by jobless growth. Is it a short-term phenomenon that will somehow disappear or a systematic outcome of following the wrong development thesis? According to a recent report, while Bangladesh's productive sector experienced an impressive average a</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 18:45:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Payment Initiation Services: the future of payments in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/reviews/payment-initiation-services-the-future-of-payments-in-bangladesh</link><description>The global financial system is undergoing a major transformation due to emerging technology. FinTech 4.0 or the FinTech revolution are popular terms used to describe this transformation. The era of dominant digital finance has begun with the advent of FinTech 4.0. Open banking is the term for the p</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 19:00:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Guardians take charge at school exam</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/guardians-take-charge-at-school-exam</link><description>Guardians, not teachers, with the help of the head master conducted annual examinations at a government primary school in Rajshahi metropolitan city as the latter got involved in a movement to press home demand for pay-scale upgradation. Meanwhile, secondary school teachers under the banner of "Ban</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 19:50:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Urgent action needed to stop food contamination</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/urgent-action-needed-to-stop-food-contamination</link><description>The warning signs are unmistakable, and the consequences are no longer abstract. The growing presence of harmful chemicals in the Bangladeshi food chain now poses a direct threat to every family in the country -- a slow-moving public health emergency unfolding in plain sight. Rising levels of toxic</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 20:05:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Streamlining the ICT project</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/streamlining-the-ict-project</link><description>A select project titled "Digital Service Transformation for Access and Resilience (D-Star) has been returned by the Planning Commission (PC) for revision on account of what the PC considers excessive costs. Submitted to the PC by the Information and Communications Technology (ICT) Division for appr</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 20:20:58 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>