<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 08:35:58 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>No attack would foil upcoming election: EC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/no-attack-would-foil-upcoming-election-ec</link><description>No vicious attempts, including clandestine attack, would foil the upcoming 13th national election, Election Commissioner Brig. Gen. Abul Fazal Md. Sanaullah (Retd.) said on Sunday.
"The message from the Election Commission (EC) is very clear, there are no concerns regarding the election. The elect</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 06:45:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Excessive dependency on road network must be shifted to rail, waterways: Advisor</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/excessive-dependency-on-road-network-must-be-shifted-to-rail-waterways-advisor</link><description>The first-ever drafted integrated comprehensive transport master plan has found Dhaka city-centric congested development of road, rail, waterways, air passenger and freight services - although 42 natural multi-modal hubs exist in the country.
A baseline assessment on the master plan also shows tha</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 07:00:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Faisal only named suspect in Hadi shooting case</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/faisal-only-named-suspect-in-hadi-shooting-case</link><description>Faisal Karim Masud is the only suspect named in a case over the shooting of Inqilab Moncho Convenor Sharif Osman bin Hadi filed on Sunday night, according to bdnews24.com.
Deputy Commissioner Harun Or Rashid of the police’s Motijheel Division said on Monday morning that Inqilab Moncho Member</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 05:45:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Killing of six BD peacekeepers draws widespread condemnation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/killing-of-six-bd-peacekeepers-draws-widespread-condemnation</link><description>UN Secretary-General António Guterres joined Bangladesh on Sunday in mourning the tragic death of six members of the Bangladesh Army who were serving in a United Nations peacekeeping mission in Sudan.
The six Bangladeshi peacekeepers were killed, and eight others were injured in a drone att</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 06:00:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Airport runway expansion creates navigational hazards</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/airport-runway-expansion-creates-navigational-hazards</link><description>The expansion work of Cox's Bazar Airport has created serious environmental and navigational hazards, as the support infrastructure for the extended runway is being constructed by piling at the mouth of the Maheshkhali Channel, where the Bakkhali River meets the sea.
Experts warn that the developm</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 06:15:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Air ambulance lands in Dhaka to take bullet-hit Hadi to Singapore</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/air-ambulance-lands-in-dhaka-to-take-bullet-hit-hadi-to-singapore</link><description>An air ambulance, equipped with all emergency facilities for a critical patient, has landed at Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport to take bullet-hit Dhaka-8 aspiring independent candidate Sharif Osman Hadi to Singapore for advanced treatment.
The ambulance landed at 11:22 am, the airport autho</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 06:30:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Farmers busy preparing Boro seedbeds in Sylhet</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/farmers-busy-preparing-boro-seedbeds-in-sylhet</link><description>Farmers across four districts in Sylhet division are racing against time to prepare seedbeds as the window for Boro rice cultivation rapidly closes.
With the target for Boro farming this season set at 497,683 hectares, officials and farmers are working hard to meet the deadline.
The target for Bo</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 06:45:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Clothing trader shot dead in Khulna</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/clothing-trader-shot-dead-in-khulna</link><description>A clothing trader has been shot dead in Rupsha upazila of Khulna.
The killing took place around 10:30 pm on Sunday near the eastern end of the Rupsha Bridge in front of the Jabusa Autogas Filling Station, according to police.
The victim was identified as 30-year-old Sagar Sheikh, a resident of th</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 07:00:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Three more held over gun attack of Osman Hadi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/three-more-held-over-gun-attack-of-osman-hadi</link><description>Members of the Rapid Action Battalion (RAB) have arrested three more people in connection with the gun attack on Sharif Osman Hadi, an independent candidate for the Dhaka-8 constituency.
The arrestees are suspected shooter Faisal’s wife Begum Samia, his brother-in-law Shipu, and Begum Maria.</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 07:15:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Metro services to be suspended for 40 minutes on Tuesday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/metro-services-to-be-suspended-for-40-minutes-on-tuesday</link><description>Metro rail services will be suspended for 40 minutes on Tuesday to ensure the safety of paratroopers during Victory Day celebrations.
Dhaka Mass Transit Company Limited (DMTCL) announced on Monday that the suspension will be from 11:50 am to 12:30 pm.
A para jump is scheduled at Tejgaon Puratan A</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 07:30:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BGB says it's 'unclear' whether Hadi attackers crossed into India</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bgb-says-its-unclear-whether-hadi-attackers-crossed-into-india</link><description>The Border Guard Bangladesh (BGB) says it is not yet clear whether those involved in the shooting of Inqilab Moncho Convenor Sharif Osman Hadi in Dhaka had escaped to neighbouring India through the Mymensingh border.
Speaking to reporters at the Khagdohar BGB camp in Mymensingh on Monday, Col Sark</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 07:45:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Complaint filed against journo Anis, actress Shaon, model Maria</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/complaint-filed-against-journo-anis-actress-shaon-model-maria</link><description>Journalist Anis Alamgir, actress Meher Afroz Shaon, model Maria Kispotta and three others have been named in a complaint filed at Uttara West Police Station, accusing them of conspiring to destabilise the state and inciting a banned organisation.
The complaint was filed on Sunday night by Aryan Ah</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 08:00:48 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>