<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 08:28:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Over 30 mln people in Sudan in need of humanitarian assistance: UN agencies</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/over-30-mln-people-in-sudan-in-need-of-humanitarian-assistance-un-agencies</link><description>Sudan is facing one of the world's most severe emergencies, with more than 30 million people in need of humanitarian assistance, including over 9.6 million internally displaced people and nearly 15 million children, four UN agencies said Thursday.
In a joint press release, the International Organi</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 05:38:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>WEEKLY KITCHEN MARKET: Edible oil, veggies get costlier; commoners' woes mount</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/weekly-kitchen-market-edible-oil-veggies-get-costlier-commoners-woes-mount</link><description>Prices of edible oil and vegetables went up again last week, adding to sufferings of the common consumers.
Vegetable prices continued to rise. Brinjal now sells for Tk120-200 per kg, bitter gourd for Tk 100-110, pointed gourd for Tk 100-110, okra for Tk 100-110, long yard beans for Tk 110-120, tea</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 05:53:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>INDUSTRIAL, FACTORY FIRES: 152 incidents claim 131 lives, injure 578 from 2018 to June 2025</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/industrial-factory-fires-152-incidents-claim-131-lives-injure-578-from-2018-to-june-2025</link><description>A total of 152 fire incidents happened in industries and factories from 2018 to June 2025 that claimed 131 lives and injured 578, revealed a latest research study of labour safety rights groups.
From 2022 to June 2025 a total of 13 incidents of chemical explosions took place at ready-made garments</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 06:08:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka condemns so-called “Israeli sovereignty” over West Bank</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dhaka-condemns-so-called-israeli-sovereignty-over-west-bank</link><description>Bangladesh has strongly condemned the recent approval by the Israeli Knesset of draft laws aimed at imposing so-called “Israeli sovereignty” over the occupied territories in the West Bank of the State of Palestine.  “Bangladesh reaffirms that Israel has no sovereignty ov</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 07:11:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Student group BGCS renames itself as ‘Jatiya Chhatra Shakti’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/student-group-bgcs-renames-itself-as-jatiya-chhatra-shakti</link><description>Eight months after its formation, the Bangladesh Ganatantrik Chhatra Sangsad (BGCS) has renamed itself "Jatiya Chhatra Shakti", unveiling a new motto as part of its reorganisation strategy.
The organisation announced the change at a meeting held on Thursday at the Abu Sayed Convention Hall near th</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 07:41:07 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>