<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 16:33:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Trump calls for $1.5t military budget in 2027, up from $901b in 2026</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-calls-for-15t-military-budget-in-2027-up-from-901b-in-2026</link><description>President Donald Trump said on Wednesday the 2027 U.S. military budget should be $1.5 trillion, significantly higher than the $901 billion approved by Congress for 2026, boosting defense stocks, but sparking skepticism among budget experts.
Any such increase in the military budget would require co</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 14:00:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fire at Gazipur jhut warehouse</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/gazipur-factory-fire-spreads-to-nearby-warehouses-six-units-deployed</link><description>A fire has erupted at a “jhut” or waste fabric warehouse in Gazipur city, prompting a large response from the Fire Service to bring the blaze under control.
The incident occurred around 4:15pm on Thursday in Kathaltala of Dewaliabari in the city, said Saiful Islam, warehouse inspector</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 14:15:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Coast Guard arrests leader of gang abducting tourists in Sundarban</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/coast-guard-arrests-leader-of-gang-abducting-tourists-in-sundarban</link><description>The Bangladesh Coast Guard has arrested Masum Mridha, the alleged ringleader of a tourist abduction gang in the Sundarbans. It also recovered firearms, sharp weapons and ammunition during the operation.
Masum, 23, was detained on Wednesday in Dhanakhali, Terokhada upazila, Khulna, following intell</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 14:30:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Remittance funds to be credited in a day</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh-bank-orders-remittances-credited-within-one-working-day</link><description>Bangladesh Bank has directed banks to credit remittances sent by expatriates to customers’ accounts within one working day.
Any remittance received after banking hours must be credited on the following working day, according to instructions issued on Thursday.
Banks have been given until Ma</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 14:45:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique to visit Cox’s Bazar, Ctg Jan 18</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-rahman-to-travel-to-coxs-bazar-chattogram-on-jan-18</link><description>Tarique Rahman is set to visit Chattogram for the first time in nearly two decades.
The BNP acting chief will attend a prayer gathering for his mother Khaleda Zia at the premises of Jamiyatul Falah National Mosque on the afternoon of Jan 18, said Chattogram city BNP member secretary Nazimur Rahman</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 15:00:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump backs bill allowing 500pc tariffs on India, China over Russian oil</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/trump-backs-bill-allowing-500pc-tariffs-on-india-china-over-russian-oil</link><description>US President Donald Trump has backed a bipartisan bill that would allow Washington to impose tariffs of at least 500 percent on India and China over their imports of Russian oil, as part of efforts to pressure Moscow over the war in Ukraine.
The proposed legislation, titled the Sanctioning of Russ</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 14:55:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Teen soccer player who died in Swiss bar fire laid to rest</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/teen-soccer-player-who-died-in-swiss-bar-fire-laid-to-rest</link><description>Teammates of a 16-year-old soccer player Arthur Brodard were among the mourners on Thursday as Switzerland held funerals for some of the victims of the New Year bar fire in Crans-Montana that killed 40 people, most of them teenagers.
Brodard is one of seven victims from Lutry Football Club, the cl</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 15:10:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>469 appeals filed against RO’s decisions on nominations</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/469-appeals-filed-against-ros-decisions-on-nominations</link><description>A total of 469 aspirants have filed appeal petitions with the Election Commission till Thursday, a day before the expiry of deadline, challenging returning officers’ decisions on the rejection and acceptance of nomination papers for the February 12 national election.
Among them, 174 petition</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 15:25:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Referendum aims to block the road back to Fascism: Prof. Ali Riaz</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/referendum-aims-to-block-the-road-back-to-fascism-prof-ali-riaz</link><description>Special assistant to the Chief Adviser Professor Ali Riaz said on Thursday that the upcoming referendum, set to be held on the same day as the 13th parliamentary election, is designed to ensure that future leaders of the country cannot become fascist.
Speaking at a workshop titled “Upcoming</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 15:40:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Modhumoti Bank inaugurates its Keraniganj agent point</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/modhumoti-bank-inaugurates-its-keraniganj-agent-point</link><description>Modhumoti Bank PLC has been continuously expanding its banking footprint through branches, sub-branches, and agent banking points, with a vision to extend its services further and gradually bring underserved communities under the umbrella of financial inclusion.
As part of this ongoing initiative,</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 15:55:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NRBC Bank Chairman Md. Ali Hossain Prodhania receives ‘Excellence in Corporate Governance Award’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/nrbc-bank-chairman-md-ali-hossain-prodhania-receives-excellence-in-corporate-governance-award</link><description>Md. Ali Hossain Prodhania, Chairman of the Board of Directors of NRBC Bank PLC, has been honoured with the ‘Excellence in Corporate Governance Award’ in recognition of his outstanding leadership in promoting excellence, transparency and accountability in corporate governance and for exp</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 16:10:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Meghna Bank signs Participation Agreement with BB for Startup Refinance Scheme</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/meghna-bank-signs-participation-agreement-with-bb-for-startup-refinance-scheme</link><description>Recently, with a view to fostering an innovation-led entrepreneurial ecosystem, Meghna Bank PLC has signed a Participation Agreement with Bangladesh Bank under the Startup Refinance Scheme.
The signing ceremony was graced by Ms. Nurun Nahar, Deputy Governor of Bangladesh Bank, as the chief guest,</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 16:25:46 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>