<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 23:37:05 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Gold price hits Tk 200 thousand per Bhori for the first time</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/gold-price-in-bangladesh-surpasses-tk-200-thousand-per-bhori-for-the-first-time</link><description>Gold prices in Bangladesh have reached an unprecedented high, crossing the Tk 200,000 mark per bhori (11.664 grams) for the first time, driven by continuous price surges in September and early October.
On Monday night, the Bangladesh Jewellers Association (BAJUS) announced an increase of Tk 3,150</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 15:43:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Banks told to sign deals to recover laundered funds</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh-bank-orders-banks-to-partner-with-global-firms-to-recover-laundered-money</link><description>Bangladesh Bank has instructed all scheduled banks to enter agreements with a group of 12 international law and asset recovery firms in a coordinated effort to bring back money illicitly transferred abroad.
The directive came from Governor Ahsan H Mansur during a meeting with senior bank executive</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 15:58:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ICC convicts first Darfur militia leader for war crimes</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/icc-convicts-first-darfur-militia-leader-for-war-crimes</link><description>The International Criminal Court on Monday convicted the first Janjaweed militia leader put on trial for atrocities committed in Sudan's Darfur region more than 20 years ago.
The court found Ali Muhammad Ali Abd-Al-Rahman guilty of 27 counts of crimes against humanity and war crimes, including rap</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 16:28:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Satkhira man attacked by mob for insulting Quran, held over blasphemy case</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/satkhira-man-attacked-by-mob-for-insulting-quran-held-over-blasphemy-case</link><description>A young man, Sohag, 25, was publicly beaten in Debhata upazila after posting statements on Facebook insulting the holy Quran.
Later, he was arrested, and a blasphemy case was filed against him by Debhata police.
The incident took place on Monday after noon prayers at Sohag’s home near</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 16:43:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Journalists urge EC to show ‘strong stand’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/journalists-call-on-election-commission-to-take-strong-stand-before-polls</link><description>Journalists have urged the Election Commission to take a firm stance in ensuring a free, fair and inclusive parliamentary polls, stressing equal opportunity for all candidates and effective action against misinformation on social media and cyber platforms.
They also called for effective steps to g</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 16:58:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pakistan looks to unlock Saudi investment in visit following defence pact</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/pakistan-looks-to-unlock-saudi-investment-in-visit-following-defence-pact</link><description>A Saudi business delegation is due in Pakistan this week to kick off what Islamabad hopes is a program of investment following a mutual defence agreement, though major investments may be dependent on reforms, officials and experts said.
Pakistani sources anticipate initial investment plans of abou</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 17:13:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>To defer or to leap, that is the question</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/to-defer-or-to-leap-that-is-the-question</link><description>In 2026, Bangladesh is expected to graduate from the United Nations (UN)’s list of Least Developed Countries (LDCs). Some view this as a triumph, while others see it as a threat. The truth lies in between: graduation is neither a silver medal of development, nor a sentence of economic hardshi</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 17:28:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bureaucrats’ tax privileges come under NPC review</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bureaucrats-tax-privileges-come-under-npc-review</link><description>The National Pay Commission (NPC), now working on a new pay scale for government servants, is going to undertake a review of tax privileges enjoyed by the latter to minimize long-persistent disparity with private employees.



It is a long-debated issue which seems still sidelined in the inte</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 17:43:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Curbing anthrax outbreak</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/curbing-anthrax-outbreak</link><description>Anthrax has been in the news in Bangladesh for nearly a month. There are reports of anthrax infection in Pirgachha upazila of the northern district of Rangpur. Though ruminating, hooved and grazing animals like cow, goat, lamb, etc., are usually infected by anthrax, humans can also contract the dis</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 17:58:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh's animation dream: From margins to mainstream</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/bangladeshs-animation-dream-from-margins-to-mainstream</link><description>Bangladesh's animators have been busy. For more than a decade they have produced sleek, colourful sequences for global entertainment giants -- from television commercials to mobile games -- often without anyone knowing the work was done in Dhaka rather than Delhi or Manila. The talent is there; the</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 18:13:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Execution of Blue Network Programme</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/execution-of-blue-network-programme</link><description>At a time when Dhaka City's liveability is increasingly becoming suspect, the interim government has come up with an ambitious mega project called the Blue Network Programme under which the urban water infrastructure in and around the megalopolis will be restored. All water channels such as rivers,</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 18:28:38 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>