<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 05:22:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Long-term planning, management major hurdles, says BERC chairman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/long-term-planning-management-major-hurdles-says-berc-chairman</link><description>Bangladesh Energy Regulatory Commission (BERC) Chairman Jalal Ahmed says Bangladesh holds significant potential to expand renewable energy generation, particularly in the coastal region, but faces challenges in management and long-term planning.
Addressing these issues, he said, was the key to ens</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 02:37:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DSE to elect two shareholder directors on December 15</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/dse-to-elect-two-shareholder-directors-on-december-15</link><description>The Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) will hold an election for the posts of two shareholder-directors on December 15, as the three-year tenure of the existing board members will expire this year in line with the demutualisation scheme.
This year, Md. Shakil Rizvi, managing director of Shakil Rizvi Stock</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 02:52:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IFIC Bank’s ex-MD fined Tk 50m for misleading bond promotion</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/ific-banks-ex-md-fined-tk-50m-for-misleading-bond-promotion</link><description>The Bangladesh Securities and Exchange Commission (BSEC) has slapped ex-managing director of IFIC Bank with a fine of Tk 50 million for deceptive promotion of a zero-coupon bond.
According to a press release issued after the commission's meeting on Tuesday, the penalty was handed down for breach o</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 03:07:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Proposed changes to DAP threaten Dhaka's livability, opine experts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/proposed-changes-to-dap-threaten-dhakas-livability-opine-experts</link><description>A group of professionals, including planners and environmental activists, on Tuesday demanded immediate cancellation of the proposed amendments to Dhaka's Detailed Area Plan (DAP), saying that the changes will further worsen the city's livability issues, which are already in peril.
The government</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 03:22:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ACC seeks court approval for DNA tests of UNO, family</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/acc-seeks-court-approval-for-dna-tests-of-uno-family</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) has sought court approval to conduct DNA tests of Nachol Upazila Nirbahi Officer (UNO) Kamal Hossain, his biological parents, and his uncle and aunt to verify allegations that he fraudulently used the identity of a freedom fighter's (FF) child to secure his gove</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 03:37:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>403 BCL members get DU show-cause</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/403-bcl-members-get-du-show-cause</link><description>The Dhaka University (DU) on Tuesday issued show-cause notices to 403 student leaders and activists of the banned Bangladesh Chhatra League (BCL) for their involvement in illegal and violent incidents that took place at the campus and nearby areas during the July Uprising.
According to an official</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 03:52:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ACC to file case against Nizam Hazari's wife for Tk 453m illegal wealth</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/acc-to-file-case-against-nizam-hazaris-wife-for-tk-453m-illegal-wealth</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) has decided to file a case against Nurjahan Begum, wife of former Awami League (AL) lawmaker from Feni-2 constituency Nizam Uddin Hazari, on charges of possessing illegal wealth worth Tk 453.4 million and carrying out suspicious transactions of Tk 433.1 million.</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 04:07:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Manikganj District Public Library wrestling with multiple problems</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/manikganj-district-public-library-wrestling-with-multiple-problems</link><description>The Manikganj District Public Library is grappling with numerous challenges, including infrastructure decay, manpower shortage, and a poor location; all of which are seriously hampering its operation.
Despite housing more than 38,000 books, the library continues to suffer from a serious lack of re</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 04:22:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Vegetable farming on floating farm beds lucrative for Gopalganj farmers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/vegetable-farming-on-floating-farm-beds-lucrative-for-gopalganj-farmers</link><description>Vegetable cultivation on floating farm beds has been a source of additional and lucrative income for farmers in Gopalganj and this year about 1,650 of them are expecting high prices from the crops produced using this farming technique.
Officials at the Department of Agricultural Extension, Gopalga</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 04:52:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt raises BKB's capital base to Tk 15.5b to bolster its balance sheet</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/govt-raises-bkbs-capital-base-to-tk-155b-to-bolster-its-balance-sheet</link><description>The government has increased the paid-up capital of the state-owned Bangladesh Krishi Bank (BKB) to Tk 15.5 billion to strengthen the bank's balance sheet.
The increase was materialised through conversion of the previously reserved recapitalization worth Tk 6.50-billion into permanent paid-up capi</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 05:07:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mac Allister heads Liverpool to Champions League win over Real</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/mac-allister-heads-liverpool-to-champions-league-win-over-real-madrid</link><description>Liverpool's Alexis Mac Allister headed a second-half winner as the hosts earned a hard-fought 1-0 victory over Real Madrid in a battle between European giants on Tuesday, handing the LaLiga leaders their first defeat in the Champions League this season.
Arne Slot's men climbed to sixth in the tabl</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 05:22:03 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>