<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 08:31:16 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Over half of Bangladesh’s climate fund marred by corruption: TIB</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/over-half-of-bangladeshs-climate-fund-marred-by-corruption-tib</link><description>Transparency International Bangladesh (TIB) has found that more than half of the allocations from the country’s national climate fund have been affected by corruption, exposing serious governance failures in the management of climate finance.
According to a TIB study released on Tuesday, 54</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 05:46:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Egyptian envoy meets Mirza Fakhrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/egyptian-envoy-meets-mirza-fakhrul</link><description>Egyptian Ambassador to Bangladesh Omar Mohie Eldin Ahmed Fahmy met BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir in Dhaka on Tuesday and discussed various issues related to the upcoming national election and bilateral relations between the two countries.
The hour-long meeting began around 11:0</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 06:16:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>48,000 police members complete election training</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/48000-police-members-complete-election-training</link><description>Out of 150,000 police personnel designated for duty in the upcoming national parliamentary election due in February, 48,000 have completed their election training.
Ahead of the polls, multiple security forces involved in maintaining law and order, including the Army, police, Border Guard Banglades</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 06:31:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh seeks greater Filipino investment, ASEAN partnership</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-seeks-greater-filipino-investment-asean-partnership</link><description>Bangladesh has underscored the prospects for increased Filipino investment in its emerging sectors and reiterated its aspiration to become a Sectoral Dialogue Partner of the Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN).
Bangladesh and the Philippines held the third round of Foreign Policy Consul</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 07:46:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Maritime ports of Chattogram, Cox’s Bazar advised to hoist local cautionary signal No 3</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/maritime-ports-of-chattogram-coxs-bazar-advised-to-hoist-local-cautionary-signal-no-3</link><description>The maritime ports of Chattogram and Cox’s Bazar have been advised to hoist local cautionary signal No. 3 as the low-pressure area over the east-central Bay and adjoining Myanmar coast persists.
It is likely to move north-northwestwards along the Myanmar-Bangladesh coasts, said a special bul</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 08:16:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Seven killed in avalanche in Nepal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/seven-killed-in-avalanche-in-nepal</link><description>Seven people died in an avalanche in central Nepal on Monday while attempting to climb a mountain, police said.
A team of 15 people, with five foreign climbers and 10 Nepali mountain guides, was hit by the avalanche at the base camp of Yalung Ri Peak in Dolakha district, reports Xinhua.
"Seven bo</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 08:31:12 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>