<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 16:28:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Political party reform more important than state reform: Experts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/political-party-reform-more-important-than-state-reform-experts</link><description>Reforming political parties is more important than reforming the state itself if transparency, accountability and good governance are to be ensured in Bangladesh, according to experts.
They said this at a policy dialogue organised by the Centre for Governance Studies (CGS) on Saturday, UNB reports</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 12:45:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat to form inclusive government if voted to power: Dr Shafiqur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-to-form-inclusive-government-if-voted-to-power-dr-shafiqur</link><description>Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami Ameer Dr Shafiqur Rahman today (Saturday) said his party would form an inclusive government involving all sections of people if it comes to power.
"If we get the opportunity to govern, Insha'Allah we will form a government taking everyone along. United efforts are needed</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 13:00:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP feud sparks attacks on 11 homes in Shariatpur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-feud-sparks-attacks-on-11-homes-in-shariatpur</link><description>At least 11 houses have been vandalised, three set on fire, and more than 500 crude bombs exploded during attacks in Shariatpur Sadar, allegedly triggered by a dispute over joining the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP).
The incident took place around 11:00 pm on Friday in Chargayghar village of S</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 13:15:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No legal bar for govt officials to campaign for ‘Yes’ vote: Ali Riaz</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/no-legal-bar-for-govt-officials-to-campaign-for-yes-vote-ali-riaz</link><description>Professor Ali Riaz, Special Assistant to the Chief Adviser and Chief Coordinator of the referendum campaign, on Saturday said there is no legal bar for government officials from taking part in the campaign in favor of “Yes” vote in the referendum.
He said those who laid down their live</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 13:30:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US envoys in Israel to discuss future of Gaza, sources tell Reuters</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-envoys-in-israel-to-discuss-future-of-gaza-sources-tell-reuters</link><description>US envoys Steve Witkoff and Jared Kushner were in Israel on Saturday to meet with Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu, mainly to discuss Gaza, two people briefed on the matter said, as local authorities reported further violence in the enclave.
The US on Thursday announced plans for a &amp;ldquo</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 13:45:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Keraniganj BNP leader dies after shooting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/keraniganj-bnp-leader-dies-after-shooting</link><description>A union-level BNP leader, who was shot by miscreants on Thursday night in Keraniganj, has died after two days of hospitalisation.
Hasan Mollah, general secretary of Hazratpur Union BNP, died on Saturday around 4:00 pm while receiving treatment at Holy Family Hospital, police said.</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 14:00:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>After two decades, Ctg’s Polo Ground awaits Tarique’s return</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/after-two-decades-ctgs-polo-ground-awaits-tariques-return</link><description>After nearly 21 years, the historic Polo Ground in the port city of Chattogram is once again set to witness a defining political moment as BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman prepares to address a major election rally on Sunday.
The port city is buzzing with excitement as BNP leaders, activists and suppor</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 14:15:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tasnim Jara promises ‘no service, no bill’ gas policy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tasnim-jara-promises-no-service-no-bill-gas-policy</link><description>Tasnim Jara, an independent candidate of Dhaka-9 seat, on Saturday unveiled her election manifesto, pledging to stop billing residents for undelivered gas and ensure local issues are tracked through a transparent digital dashboard.
In a post on her verified Facebook page, the former National Citiz</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 14:30:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>PCB calls Bangladesh’s removal from T20 World Cup ‘an injustice’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/cricket/pcb-calls-bangladeshs-removal-from-t20-world-cup-an-injustice</link><description>Pakistan’s involvement in the T20 World Cup hangs in the balance after board Chairman Mohsin Naqvi indicated that a final decision would be made only following consultation with the government, ESPNcricinfo reports.
His remarks came in the immediate aftermath of the ICC’s formal remova</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 14:45:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ICC confirms it removes Bangladesh from T20 World Cup</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/cricket/icc-confirms-it-removes-bangladesh-from-t20-world-cup</link><description>The International Cricket Council (ICC) confirmed that Bangladesh have been removed from next month’s T20 World Cup after refusing to play their scheduled matches in India over security concerns, with Scotland called up as their replacement.
In a formal statement, the ICC said that, based on</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 15:00:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IGP orders police to be patient, neutral during election duties</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/igp-orders-police-to-be-patient-neutral-during-election-duties</link><description>Inspector General of Police (IGP) Baharul Alam on Saturday directed all police members to perform their duties with utmost vigilance, patience and neutrality during the upcoming 13th National Parliamentary Election.
He also instructed police personnel to ensure the use of body-worn cameras while o</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 15:15:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh, India reaffirm depth of ties; stress people-centred cooperation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-india-reaffirm-depth-of-ties-stress-people-centred-cooperation</link><description>Bangladesh and India used the occasion of the 77th anniversary of India’s Republic Day to publicly reaffirm the depth of their bilateral relationship, highlighting shared history, expanding energy and connectivity links, and the importance of addressing challenges through sustained dialogue.</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 15:30:44 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>