<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 03:42:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Bangladesh has no plan to import beef: Adviser Farida</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladesh-has-no-plan-to-import-beef-adviser-farida</link><description>Bangladesh has no plan to import beef, as it could hurt domestic farmers and pose potential health risks, said Fisheries and Livestock Adviser Farida Akhter on Tuesday.
“Beef import requires careful consideration. It is not like soap or shampoo that can be brought in at will. The government</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 16:59:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Limits of monetary policy independence</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/limits-of-monetary-policy-independence</link><description>The issue of central bank independence has two elements. First— governance, how is the central bank governed? Are its leadership appointments merit-based? Are its internal decisions insulated from day-to-day political interference? The prevailing wisdom around the world is that management sys</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 17:14:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>War on sovereignty of Venezuela not narcotics</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/war-on-sovereignty-of-venezuela-not-narcotics</link><description>The U.S. military operation resulting in the capture of Venezuelan President Nicolás Maduro and his wife represents a defining moment in the Trump administration's fight against alleged drug trafficking. The administration swiftly framed the action as a lawful criminal enforcement against na</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 17:29:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Completing NBR reform</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/completing-nbr-reform</link><description>Splitting the National Board of Revenue (NBR) between its policymaking and  revenue management  functions has been one of the major reform agendas of the post-July 2024 interim government. The aim was to render the tax regulator more efficient, transparent and accountable. Though the inte</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 17:44:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EU Ambassador meets Tarique Rahman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/eu-ambassador-meets-tarique-rahman</link><description>European Union (EU) Ambassador to Bangladesh Michael Miller today (Tuesday) held a courtesy meeting with BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman. 
The meeting took place at the BNP Chairperson's office in Gulshan at 6:30pm, according to BNP Media Cell member Shayrul Kabir Khan, BSS reports.</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 17:59:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Corruption corrodes  ICT-powered  knowledge economy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/corruption-corrodes-ict-powered-knowledge-economy</link><description>sector steeped in misdealing sending billions of fast bucks into pockets of a small group of politically and commercially favoured firms.
Such unholy practice happened in the fastest-growing knowledge economy as licensing decisions taken during the Awami League government between 2009 and 2024 fav</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 18:14:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ex-industries Minister Kamal Ahmed admitted to DMCH due to illness</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ex-industries-minister-kamal-ahmed-admitted-to-dmch-due-to-illness</link><description>Former industries minister Kamal Ahmed Majumdar (75) was admitted to Dhaka Medical College Hospital (DMCH) on Tuesday after falling ill at Keraniganj Central Jail.
He was brought to DMCH’s emergency department around 7:30 pm and admitted to Ward 220 of the Surgery Department for treatment, U</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 18:45:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Over 300 SAD leaders join BNP in Sherpur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/over-300-sad-leaders-join-bnp-in-sherpur</link><description>More than 300 leaders of the Students Against Discrimination (SAD) joined the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) in Sherpur on Tuesday.
The student leaders completed the formalities in the afternoon at the district BNP office in Raghunath Bazar under the leadership of the district SAD chief coordi</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 19:00:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EU, BNP discussed upcoming election, post-polls development: Nazrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/eu-bnp-discussed-upcoming-election-post-polls-development-nazrul</link><description>BNP standing committee member Nazrul Islam Khan said the European Union (EU) delegation held discussions with the party on the upcoming 13th national parliamentary election and the country's development outlook after the polls.
A delegation of the EU held the meeting with BNP Acting Chairman Tariq</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 19:15:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cheap capital, costly scrutiny: Why state-run energy firms shun listing</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/cheap-capital-costly-scrutiny-why-state-run-energy-firms-shun-listing</link><description>State-run fuel and energy companies could reduce their dependence on government and foreign funds as well as bank loans by listing on the stock market, but political and bureaucratic resistance persists -- largely to avoid heightened scrutiny of corrupt practices.
Government and foreign funds are</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 02:30:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh-sized territory lies undersea unexplored</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladesh-sized-territory-lies-undersea-unexplored</link><description>Bangladesh's vast deep-sea ecosystem holding potential caches of resources faces mounting pressure from overfishing, aggressive industrial practices and plastic pollution, shows a multinational survey.
With the new findings presented to the country's chief executive Tuesday, a conclusion was drawn</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 02:45:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cautious half-yearly monetary policy likely to keep policy rate unchanged</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/cautious-half-yearly-monetary-policy-likely-to-keep-policy-rate-unchanged</link><description>Elevated policy interest rate is likely to stay unchanged in the upcoming monetary policy stance (MPS) for the second half (H2) of this fiscal year as inflation rebounds after some remission.
Despite an outcry from the business circles over higher lending-rate regime amid persisting economic slowd</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 03:00:47 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>