<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 09:21:16 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Metro rail to extend operating hours from Sunday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/metro-rail-to-extend-operating-hours-from-sunday</link><description>Dhaka’s metro rail is set to extend its daily operation by one hour from Sunday, according to the Dhaka Mass Transit Company Limited (DMTCL), multiple local media reprots. 
Under the new timetable, trains will start running 30 minutes earlier in the morning and continue operating 30 min</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 05:57:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>HSC, equivalent exam results to be published on Thursday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hsc-equivalent-exam-results-to-be-published-on-thursday</link><description>The results of the HSC and equivalent examinations-2025 will be published tomorrow at 10 am.
The announcement was made in a notification on Monday signed by Dr. Khandoker Ehsanul Kabi, President of the Bangladesh Inter-Education Board Coordination Committee and Chairman of the Board of Intermediat</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 06:12:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mirpur fire: 16 bodies to be released from DMCH after identification</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/mirpur-fire-16-bodies-to-be-released-from-dmch-after-identification</link><description>The bodies of 16 people who died in a devastating fire at a chemical warehouse and garment factory in Mirpur, Dhaka on Tuesday will be handed over to their families soon after proper identification, officials said on Wednesday.
Brig Gen Md Asaduzzaman, director of Dhaka Medical College Hospi</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 06:27:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>July National Charter sent to political parties</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/july-national-charter-sent-to-political-parties</link><description>The much-awaited July National Charter-2025 has been sent to political parties across the country, the National Consensus Commission said.
At the same time, the charter was officially published, it said last night.
The 40-page document outlines the political history of Bangladesh, covering the Br</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 06:42:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Air pollution kills 19,000 children in BD in a year</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/air-pollution-kills-19000-children-in-bd-in-a-year</link><description>Air pollution has turned into a silent killer for children in Bangladesh, a new international study has found.
The research by Zero Carbon Analytics (ZCA) says air pollution is now the second biggest cause of death among children under five in the world, after malnutrition, with Bangladesh among t</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 07:12:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>22 fishermen jailed in Faridpur for defying ban fishing</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/22-fishermen-jailed-in-faridpur-for-defying-ban-fishing</link><description>A mobile court conducted by Faridpur’s Sadarpur Upazila administration sentenced 22 fishermen to 15 days in jail for catching mother hilsa defying the ongoing ban on Wednesday.
Sadarpur Upazila Nirbahi Officer (UNO) and Executive Magistrate Zakia Sultana said the operation was carried out fr</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 07:27:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CEC defends use of locally sourced ink in CUCSU polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/cec-defends-use-of-locally-sourced-ink-in-cucsu-polls</link><description>Chittagong University Central Students’ Union (CUCSU) Chief Election Commissioner Monir Uddin has said locally available ink -- instead of imported election ink -- is being used to mark voters’ fingers, but assured that this would not cause any issues in verifying voter identity.
After</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 07:42:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>MPO teachers’ strike enters 4th day</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/mpo-teachers-strike-enters-4th-day</link><description>Teachers and employees under the MPO scheme have continued their sit-in programme for a fourth consecutive day at the Central Shaheed Minar, demanding 20 per cent of their basic salary as housing allowance.
The interim government was given until 12:00 pm on Wednesday to respond to the demand, but</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 08:12:47 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>