<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 04:26:31 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>DESCO back in profit in Q1 on increased distribution margin</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/desco-back-in-profit-in-q1-on-increased-distribution-margin</link><description>Dhaka Electric Supply Company (DESCO) secured a profit of Tk 583 million in the first quarter through September this year, marking a strong turnaround from a loss of Tk 322 million in the same quarter last year.
Higher distribution revenue and foreign exchange gains due to favorable exchange rates</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 01:15:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ICB's losses double in July-Sept</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/icbs-losses-double-in-july-sept</link><description>The state-owned Investment Corporation of Bangladesh (ICB) reported a loss of Tk 1.54 billion for the first quarter of FY26, more than double the loss incurred in the same period last year.
The poor financial results came as no surprise to investors, as last month the investment bank declared a re</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 01:30:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>German envoy pledges to promote bilateral trade</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/german-envoy-pledges-to-promote-bilateral-trade</link><description>German Ambassador Dr Rüdiger Lotz expresses the optimism that Bangladesh will soon rejoin the ranks of vibrant democracies as it prepares for what he calls "the biggest democratic elections in the world" in 2026, when over 127 million citizens are expected to vote.
"At a time when democracy f</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 01:45:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>All 54 registered parties deserve equal treatment</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/all-54-registered-parties-deserve-equal-treatment</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) on Thursday began its long-awaited dialogue with registered political parties, pledging to play a completely neutral role in the forthcoming 13th national election and seeking the cooperation of all political actors to ensure a credible vote.
Chief Election Commissione</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 02:00:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BADAS spends Tk 1.14b to give free healthcare to diabetic patients in FY 25</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/badas-spends-tk-114b-to-give-free-healthcare-to-diabetic-patients-in-fy-25</link><description>In the fiscal year (FY) 2024-25, the Diabetic Association of Bangladesh (BADAS) spent around Tk1.14 billion to provide free insulin, medicines, and healthcare to diabetic patients across the country.
Currently, more than 6.5 million of the country's 13.8 million diabetic patients, nearly half, are</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 02:15:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EDITOR'S COUNCIL: Nurul Kabir, Dewan Hanif Mahmud made president, GS</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/editors-council-nurul-kabir-dewan-hanif-mahmud-made-president-gs</link><description>Nurul Kabir, Editor of the New Age, and Dewan Hanif Mahmud, Editor and Publisher of the daily Banik Barta, have been elected president and general secretary (GS), respectively, of the Editors' Council for a two-year term.
The election took place at the AGM at The Daily Star Centre in the capital o</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 02:30:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt decides to exempt excise duty on 2026 Hajj air tickets</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-decides-to-exempt-excise-duty-on-2026-hajj-air-tickets</link><description>The advisory council of the interim government on Thursday approved a proposal to exempt excise duty on air tickets for Bangladeshi pilgrims travelling to Saudi Arabia to perform Hajj in 2026, in a bid to reduce the overall cost of the pilgrimage.
According to official sources, the Ministry of Rel</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 02:45:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Snakebites claim five lives in Chandpur in nine months</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/snakebites-claim-five-lives-in-chandpur-in-nine-months</link><description>At least five people including, two housewives, have died receiving snakebites in Chandpur in the past nine months and as many as 555 people were also injured being bitten by venomous snakes in the district during the period.
Snakebite has taken life of a young housewife in Matlab Dakhshin upazila</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 03:00:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Acute crisis of non-urea fertilisers hits winter vegetable farming</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/acute-crisis-of-non-urea-fertilisers-hits-winter-vegetable-farming</link><description>Several thousand farmers in five upazilas of Lalmonirhat district have become very much frustrated as they are facing acute crisis of various non-urea fertilisers in the current seasons.
The farmers are now very much busy cultivating different winter vegetables.
Many of them cultivated early-vari</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 03:15:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Global and local challenges weigh heavily on RMG export</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/global-and-local-challenges-weigh-heavily-on-rmg-export</link><description>The export performance of the readymade garment (RMG) sector, the country's largest foreign currency earner, has been severely affected by multiple factors, including new US tariffs, a sluggish global economy, and local challenges in securing complex, small-sized orders, industry insiders say.
The</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 03:30:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BTRC to hold public hearing on telecom services on Nov 25</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/btrc-to-hold-public-hearing-on-telecom-services-on-nov-25</link><description>The Bangladesh Telecommunication Regulatory Commission (BTRC) on November 25 will hold a public hearing to receive opinions, complaints, questions and recommendations from consumers, service providers, professionals and other stakeholders regarding the performance of telecommunication services and</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 03:45:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ACC to sue 5 recruiting agencies over Tk 3.14b embezzlement</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/acc-to-sue-5-recruiting-agencies-over-tk-314b-embezzlement</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) has decided to file cases against five more recruiting agencies and 26 individuals on charges of embezzling and laundering Tk 3.14 billion in the name of sending workers to Malaysia.
Md Akhter Hossain, Director General (Prevention) of the ACC, told reporters on</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 04:00:57 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>