<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 13:34:13 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Sterling struggles for direction on first trading day of 2026</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/sterling-struggles-for-direction-on-first-trading-day-of-2026</link><description>The British pound was little changed against both the dollar and euro on Friday, with little news to drive the currency either way as 2026 gets off to a slow start.
Sterling was last trading at $1.3447 versus the dollar , down slightly from a three-month high of $1.3533 it hit last week. Against t</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 11:01:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>London's FTSE 100 starts New Year with 10,000 mark on global investor optimism</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/londons-ftse-100-starts-new-year-with-10000-mark-on-global-investor-optimism</link><description>The UK's FTSE 100 flew past the 10,000 points mark for the first time on Friday, riding a wave of upbeat investor sentiment across global markets on the first trading session of 2026.
The blue-chip FTSE 100 (.FTSE) rose 0.5 per cent by 1023 GMT, after marking its strongest yearly performance in 16</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 11:16:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UK factories pick up a bit of speed but outlook worries remain</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/uk-factories-pick-up-a-bit-of-speed-but-outlook-worries-remain</link><description>Britain's factory sector grew at its fastest pace in 15 months in December, though by less than previously thought, while confidence dipped despite some relief over finance minister Rachel Reeves' budget, a survey showed on Friday.
The S&amp;amp;P Global Purchasing Managers' Index for manufacturing rose t</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 11:31:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>European factory activity ends 2025 in deeper contraction but Asia shines on improved demand</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/european-factory-activity-ends-2025-in-deeper-contraction-but-asia-shines-on-improved-demand</link><description>Euro zone manufacturing activity shrank further in December but Asia's factory powerhouses closed 2025 on a firmer footing backed by a rebound in export orders and growing demand for artificial intelligence, private surveys showed.
Factory activity in the common currency bloc slid into deeper cont</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 11:46:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nagorik Oikko chief Manna's Bogura-2 nomination papers rejected</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/nagorik-oikko-chief-mannas-bogura-2-nomination-papers-rejected</link><description>Election officials have rejected the nomination papers of Nagorik Oikko President Mahmudur Rahman Manna, a prospective candidate for the Bogura-2 (Shibganj) constituency in the upcoming national polls.
Returning Officer Toufiqur Rahman declared the nomination invalid on Friday, citing discrepancie</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 12:01:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Saki’s wife owns more than double his wealth</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ganosamhati-leader-zonayed-sakis-wife-owns-more-than-double-his-wealth</link><description>Zonayed Saki, chief coordinator of the Ganosamhati Andolon, has declared assets worth less than half of those owned by his wife, according to an affidavit filed with his nomination papers for Bangladesh’s upcoming 13th national parliamentary election.
Saki entered the race for parliamentary</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 12:16:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Exams scrapped for shipping agent licences</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/shipping-agent-licence-rules-revised-exam-requirement-dropped</link><description>The National Board of Revenue (NBR) has withdrawn the requirement for written and oral examinations for shipping agent licences linked to customs stations at sea ports and inland river ports across Bangladesh.
Under the new system, licences will be issued solely on the basis of submitted documents</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 12:01:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>45 land in jail over vandalism at BTRC building during NEIR protest</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/45-land-in-jail-over-vandalism-at-btrc-building-during-neir-protest</link><description>A Dhaka court has sent 45 people to jail over vandalism at the Bangladesh Telecommunication Regulatory Commission (BTRC) building during protests against the introduction of the National Equipment Identity Register (NEIR).
Dhaka Metropolitan Magistrate Israt Jahan passed the order on Friday after</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 12:16:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NEIR won’t immediately block illegal, clone handsets: Taiyeb</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/neir-wont-immediately-block-illegal-clone-handsets-taiyeb</link><description>Following the launch of the National Equipment Identity Register (NEIR), citizens should not panic as illegal or cloned handsets will not be blocked automatically during the first 90 days, Faiz Ahmad Taiyeb, Special Assistant to the Chief Adviser on Posts, Telecommunications, and ICT, said on Frida</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 12:31:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UK records hottest and sunniest year ever in 2025</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/uk-records-hottest-and-sunniest-year-ever-in-2025-says-weather-service</link><description>Britain experienced its hottest and sunniest year on record in 2025, surpassing the previous high set in 2022, the national weather service said on Friday, as persistent high-pressure systems and unusually warm seas drove up temperatures.
The Met Office said the average annual temperature was 10.0</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 12:46:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Biman gets Pakistan nod for Karachi–Dhaka flights</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/biman-gets-permission-from-pakistan-for-direct-flights-between-karachi-and-dhaka</link><description>The Pakistan government has granted Biman Bangladesh Airlines permission to operate direct flights between Dhaka and Karachi.
According to a Geo News report on Friday, the Civil Aviation Authority (CAA) of Pakistan issued the approval.
Bangladesh’s national flag carrier has initially been c</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 13:01:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Kamal Hossain hospitalised with pneumonia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/gono-forum-chief-kamal-hossain-hospitalised-with-pneumonia</link><description>Kamal Hossain, founder of the Gono Forum, has been admitted to Square Hospital in Dhaka in a critical condition.
Gono Forum General Secretary Mizanur Rahman on Friday said that doctors have diagnosed Kamal with pneumonia.
“[Kamal] is suffering from lung pneumonia. His condition is very seri</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 13:16:59 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>