<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 11:21:08 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Bangladesh summons high commissioner again</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-summons-high-commissioner-again</link><description>Bangladesh has summoned India’s high commissioner in Dhaka on Tuesday over a series of protests and acts of vandalism targeting Bangladeshi missions in India.
The latest summons underscores mounting strain in bilateral ties during Bangladesh’s fragile political transition.
Since the i</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 08:19:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Airport authorities impose 24-hour visitor ban for Tarique’s homecoming</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/airport-authorities-impose-24-hour-visitor-ban-for-tariques-homecoming</link><description>Authorities have banned visitors at Shahjalal International Airport for 24 hours to manage crowds ahead of BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman’s return to the country.
According to a statement on Tuesday, authorities said the restriction will be in place from 6pm on Dec 24 to 6pm on Dec 25.</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 07:31:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ECNEC okays Tk 354.65 billion project to modernise Eastern Refinery</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ecnec-okays-tk-35465-billion-project-to-modernise-eastern-refinery</link><description>The Executive Committee of the National Economic Council (ECNEC) on Tuesday approved a Tk 354.65 billion project to modernise and expand Eastern Refinery Limited (ERL), aiming to strengthen Bangladesh's energy security, produce cleaner fuel and cut dependence on imported refined petroleum products.</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 07:46:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Protests at Bangladesh High Commission in Delhi over Dipu Das's lynching</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/protests-at-bangladesh-high-commission-in-delhi-over-dipu-dass-lynching</link><description>A major protest has erupted outside the Bangladesh High Commission in New Delhi in the wake of the brutal killing of a Hindu man, Dipu Chandra Das, in Mymensingh last week.
The demonstrations are being led by Vishwa Hindu Parishad (VHP) and Bajrang Dal to denounce alleged atrocities against Hindus</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 08:34:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ICT orders trial of Hasina, Kamal and 15 Army officers over alleged disappearances, torture at TFI</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ict-orders-trial-of-hasina-kamal-and-15-army-officers-over-alleged-disappearances-torture-at-tfi</link><description>The International Crimes Tribunal has ordered the start of trial proceedings against deposed prime minister Sheikh Hasina, former home minister Asaduzzaman Khan Kamal and 15 Army officers over allegations of enforced disappearances and torture during the previous Awami League government.
The order</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 08:49:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Protesters clash with police outside Bangladesh High Commission in Delhi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/protesters-clash-with-police-outside-bangladesh-high-commission-in-delhi</link><description>Tensions have flared again outside the Bangladesh High Commission in Delhi amid ongoing diplomatic strain between the two countries.
Indian media reported that activists of the Vishwa Hindu Parishad (VHP) and Bajrang Dal attempted to break through police barricades on Tuesday to approach the High</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 09:51:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Drone operation banned in and around airports</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/drone-operation-banned-in-and-around-airports</link><description>Drone operations have been banned in and around all airports, including Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport, due to national security risks and safe air navigation.
The Civil Aviation Authority of Bangladesh (CAAB) issued a letter in this regard informing all the authorities concerned, said a P</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 09:38:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NDF announces 119 candidates ahead of elections</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ndf-announces-119-candidates-ahead-of-elections</link><description>The 20-party alliance led by Anwar Hossain Manju’s Jatiya Party-JP and Anisul Islam Mahmud’s National Democratic Front-NDF has announced candidates for 119 constituencies in the upcoming 13th parliamentary election.
The NDF revealed its candidates at a press conference held at Hotel Sh</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 09:53:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Police fully prepared to ensure fair, festive, peaceful elections: IGP</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/police-fully-prepared-to-ensure-fair-festive-peaceful-elections-igp</link><description>Inspector General of Police (IGP) Baharul Alam on Tuesday said that Bangladesh Police is fully capable of ensuring a fair, peaceful, and festive environment in the upcoming referendum and the 13th national election slated for February 12.
“We’re completely ready for holding the forthco</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 10:08:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UN expert alarmed by violent attacks on Daily Star, Prothom Alo</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/un-expert-alarmed-by-violent-attacks-on-daily-star-prothom-alo</link><description>Mob attacks on leading media outlets and cultural centres in Bangladesh are deeply alarming and must be investigated promptly and effectively by the government and the perpetrators brought to justice without delay, a UN expert said on Tuesday.
The interim government has ‘largely followed the</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 10:23:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Deed of Agreement signed between Trust Bank &amp; Heguang Electronic Distribution Co. Ltd. (OPPO Bangladesh)</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/deed-of-agreement-signed-between-trust-bank-heguang-electronic-distribution-co-ltd-oppo-bangladesh</link><description>A Deed of Agreement has been signed between Trust Bank PLC and Heguang Electronic Distribution Co. Ltd. (OPPO Bangladesh).
The signing ceremony was attended by Mr. Md. Kamal Hossain Sarkar, Deputy Managing Director and Head of the Islamic Banking Division of Trust Bank PLC, along with other senior</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 10:38:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hindu groups protest outside Bangladesh Deputy High Commission in Kolkata</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hindu-groups-protest-outside-bangladesh-deputy-high-commission-in-kolkata</link><description>Hindu nationalist organisations staged another demonstration outside Bangladesh's Deputy High Commission in Kolkata on Tuesday, but police intercepted them before reaching the mission premises.
The Bangiya Hindu Jagaran Mancha organised a protest march starting from Sealdah Railway Station. When h</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 10:53:11 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>