<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 19:21:18 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Election Commission restores candidacy for 18 aspirants</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/election-commission-restores-candidacy-for-18-aspirants</link><description>On the seventh day of appeals over nomination rejections for the parliamentary polls, the Election Commission approved 18 more pleas, overturning the returning officers’ previous decisions.
With the latest restorations on Friday, as many as 353 candidates have regained their eligibility.
Co</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 17:00:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>QR-based payment systems in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/qr-based-payment-systems-in-bangladesh</link><description>The financial sector has undergone a profound transformation over the past few decades, mainly driven by rapid technological advancements. The most notable developments are the transition from traditional cash-based transactions to cashless or electronic payment systems. A cashless transaction refe</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 16:40:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Easing pre-Hajj medical tests</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/easing-pre-hajj-medical-tests</link><description>As the Hajj season approaches, registered pilgrims from Bangladesh are making preparations for pilgrimage. The government is providing information and taking necessary steps to facilitate the journey. This year, about 76,760 will perform Hajj in Makkah, Kingdom of Saudi Arabia (KSA), during the las</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 16:55:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Why does revenue stay low despite reforms?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/why-does-revenue-stay-low-despite-reforms</link><description>Most people who file income tax returns in Bangladesh do so with a sense of anxiety rather than confidence. They worry about audits, paperwork and arbitrary decisions even as they try to follow the rules. That unease is not irrational because for decades the country's tax system has combined weak e</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 17:10:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Holding auditors of failed Sharia-based banks accountable</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/holding-auditors-of-failed-sharia-based-banks-accountable</link><description>The Bangladesh Bank (BB) has reportedly dissolved the boards of five failed Sharia-based banks in the process of merger, appointed new administrators after removing their MDs and has been requested by the Financial Institutions Division to take legal actions against their owners, board members and</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 17:25:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>State must campaign for ‘Yes’ in referendum: Adviser Nurjahan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/campaigning-for-yes-in-referendum-is-a-state-obligation-adviser-nurjahan</link><description>Health and Family Welfare Adviser Nurjahan Begum on Friday said that campaigning in favor of a ‘Yes’ vote in the upcoming referendum is a collective obligation for the state.
She made the remarks while answering journalists’ questions after a discussion with district- and divisio</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 17:40:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tutor ‘confesses’ to killing student, mother in Keraniganj over ‘NGO loan row’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tutor-confesses-to-killing-student-mother-in-keraniganj-over-ngo-loan-row</link><description>A private tutor arrested in connection with the killing of a woman and her teenage daughter in Keraniganj has “confessed” to her role in the murders, which investigators say stemmed from a dispute over a loan.
The confession was recorded on Friday when Dhaka Senior Judicial Magistrate</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 17:55:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Memorial for ‘resolute’ Khaleda draws calls for unity</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/civic-memorial-remembers-resolute-khaleda-zia-urges-unity-amid-national-strain</link><description>Representatives from across the social and political spectrum have urged the nation to remain united during this period of transition, invoking the late BNP chairperson Khaleda Zia’s “resolute” spirit and her enduring message of peace over vengeance.
The call for solidarity reson</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 18:10:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Japan, Philippines sign new security pacts as regional tensions rise</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/japan-philippines-sign-new-security-pacts-as-regional-tensions-rise</link><description>The Philippines and Japan signed two defence pacts on Thursday, including a deal allowing their forces to exchange supplies and services, with both countries seeking to strengthen security cooperation in response to rising regional tensions.
The Acquisition and Cross-Servicing Agreement, designed</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 18:25:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique supports interim govt's US tariff deal, wants deeper trade ties</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-supports-interim-govts-us-tariff-deal-wants-deeper-trade-ties</link><description>Bangladesh Nationalist party (BNP) Chairman Tarique Rahman seeks to develop wider trade cooperation between Bangladesh and the United States to strengthen the bilateral ties.

The BNP leader has also lent support to the interim government- negotiated tariff agreement with the US Trump administrat</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 18:40:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ICC envoy to visit Dhaka over WC venue row</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/icc-envoy-to-visit-dhaka-as-bangladesh-holds-firm-on-world-cup-venue-stance</link><description>An International Cricket Council (ICC) representative will arrive in Dhaka on Saturday to discuss Bangladesh’s venue concerns for the T20 World Cup, marking a fresh attempt to break the deadlock over where the Tigers will play their games.
Initially, a two-member ICC delegation was expected</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 18:55:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Revenue control pushes Chittagong Port’s profit to 5-year high</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/revenue-control-pushes-chittagong-ports-profit-to-5-year-high</link><description>Chittagong Port has recorded a net profit of Tk 31.43 billion in 2025, the highest in the past five years.
Non-VAT and tax revenues contributed Tk 18.05 billion to the government treasury, also a five-year high.
Port Administration Director Md Omar Faruk said, “Since 2021, revenue has g</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 19:10:50 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>