<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 16:26:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Dhaka Bank signs participation agreement with Bangladesh Bank under FICGS</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/dhaka-bank-signs-participation-agreement-with-bangladesh-bank-under-ficgs</link><description>Dhaka Bank PLC has signed a participation agreement with Bangladesh Bank under the Financial Inclusion Credit Guarantee Scheme (FICGS).
The agreement aims to extend credit facilities to Tk 10/50/100 account holders, marginal and landless farmers, low-income professionals, school banking account ho</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 13:41:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ACC readies 5 cases against Salman F. Rahman over Janata Bank</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/acc-readies-5-cases-against-salman-f-rahman-over-janata-bank</link><description>Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) on Monday approved five separate cases against former Prime Minister’s Private Industry and Investment Adviser and Beximco Group Chairman Salman F Rahman, his brother, and top officials of Janata Bank over allegations of laundering nearly Tk 20 billion through</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 13:56:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>12 women among 237 candidates get BNP nomination</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/12-women-among-237-candidates-get-bnp-nomination</link><description>BNP on Monday nominated 12 women among its 237 candidates for the upcoming national parliamentary election.
BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir announced the names at a press conference held at the party Chairperson’s office in Gulshan.
BNP Chairperson Khaleda Zia has been nom</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 14:26:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Turkish parliamentary delegation calls on chief adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/turkish-parliamentary-delegation-calls-on-chief-adviser</link><description>Bangladesh and Türkiye have expressed keenness to further strengthen the bilateral cooperation in trade, investment, and humanitarian initiatives, particularly for Rohingyas, as a five-member Turkish parliamentary delegation paid a call on Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus on Monday.
The</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 14:56:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP leaves 63 seats open for allies</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-leaves-63-seats-open-for-allies</link><description>The Bangladesh Nationalist Party has withheld 63 parliamentary seats to accommodate allies, signalling a broader seat-sharing drive ahead of the general election due in February.
Unveiling an initial slate of 237 candidates who will run under the party’s “sheaf of paddy” symbol,</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 15:11:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Assailants attack tanker off Somalia in suspected pirate strike</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/assailants-attack-tanker-off-somalia-in-suspected-pirate-strike</link><description>Armed assailants attacked a commercial tanker off the coast of Mogadishu on Monday, firing at the vessel after attempting to board the ship in the first suspected Somali piracy incident of its kind since 2024, maritime sources said.
If confirmed, this would be the first Somali piracy attack agains</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 15:26:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique Rahman to contest from Bogura-6</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-rahman-to-contest-from-bogura-6</link><description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman will contest from Bogura-6 constituency in the upcoming 13th national parliamentary election.
BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir made the announcement at a press conference at the BNP Chairperson's office in Gulshan on Monday.
Fakhrul said that BN</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 15:56:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>November rain smashes onion fields</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/november-rain-smashes-onion-fields</link><description>Onion prices shot up to Tk 100-120 a kg, marking above 30 per cent hike in last two days.
November Rain in places amid the ongoing depression in the Bay had smashed newer crops in Pabna, Rajshahi and Faridpur regions.
Onion farmers in the region are now sourcing edible onion to grow seed onion (m</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 16:11:54 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>