<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 06:50:49 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Cox's Bazar Airport gets international status</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/coxs-bazar-airport-gets-international-status</link><description>The government has officially declared the Cox's Bazar Airport an international airport through a gazette notification issued by the Ministry of Civil Aviation and Tourism (MoCAT).
According to the notification issued on Sunday night, the declaration was made under Sub-rule (1) of Rule 16 of the C</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 03:53:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fishing ban deals impoverished fishermen a devastating blow</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/fishing-ban-deals-impoverished-fishermen-a-devastating-blow</link><description>A staggering 56 percent of the small-scale fishermen remain excluded from the government aid during the ban on fishing forcing 70 percent of them to take informal and exploitative loans, said a new study on Monday.
The situation often compels members of the marginalised community to fish illegally</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 04:08:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IMF chief vows to press G20 to prioritise global debt challenges</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/imf-chief-vows-to-press-g20-to-prioritise-global-debt-challenges</link><description>International Monetary Fund Managing Director Kristalina Georgieva on Monday said the IMF will continue to push the Group of 20 major economies to focus on persistent debt issues burdening developing economies.
Georgieva, speaking at the annual meetings of the IMF and World Bank in Washington, sai</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 04:38:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>FAO DG assures support for Bangladesh’s deep-sea fishing, fruit exports</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/fao-dg-assures-support-for-bangladeshs-deep-sea-fishing-fruit-exports</link><description>FAO Director-General Dr Qu Dongyu has assured continued support to Bangladesh in developing its deep-sea fishing industry and enhancing agricultural exports, particularly in fruits.
The commitment came during a bilateral meeting between Dr Qu and Bangladesh Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus o</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 05:08:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>14 die in Venezuela mine collapse</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/14-die-in-venezuela-mine-collapse</link><description>At least 14 people were killed after a gold mine collapsed in El Callao municipality in southern Venezuela following heavy rains in the area, emergency officials said on Monday.
The National Risk System teams said recovery efforts were underway, with the bodies found in three separate shafts, repo</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 05:23:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Stocks open higher with DSEX gaining 38 points</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/stocks-open-higher-with-dsex-gaining-38-points</link><description>Trading at the country’s stock exchanges began on a positive note on Tuesday, with key indices posting early gains in the first hour of the session.
At the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE), the benchmark index DSEX rose by 38 points within the first hour of trading. 
Other indices also moved</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 05:38:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fish trader injured in gun attack in Cumilla</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fish-trader-injured-in-gun-attack-in-cumilla</link><description>A 48-year-old fish trader sustained bullet injuries in a robbery attempt at the Gouripur Fisheries Project in Daudkandi upazila of Cumilla early Tuesday.
The injured, Amir Hossain, is the son of Abdul Awal of the upazila, reports UNB.
Quoting the victim’s brother Badsha Mia, inspector Md Fa</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 05:53:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dredger procurement project: BIWTA cuts components after tenure ends</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/dredger-procurement-project-biwta-cuts-components-after-tenure-ends</link><description>After the end of the project's tenure, the Bangladesh Inland Water Transport Authority (BIWTA) has decided to cut the procurement of some dredgers, a key component of the scheme, as execution drags on for seven years, insiders said on Saturday.
Since the project expired in June last, the state-run</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 06:08:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Students block Science Lab intersection for half hour</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/students-block-science-lab-intersection-for-half-hour</link><description>Students from Dhaka College and Begum Badrunnesa Government Women’s College blocked Dhaka’s Science Laboratory intersection for a half hour to demand the institutions maintain their autonomy and to protest attacks on demonstrators.
They marched to the intersection from their campuses a</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 06:23:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BTRC sets Oct 30 deadline to cap SIM ownership at 10 per NID</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/btrc-sets-oct-30-deadline-to-cap-sim-ownership-at-10-per-nid</link><description>The Bangladesh Telecommunication Regulatory Commission (BTRC) has set October 30 as the final date for mobile users to deactivate or transfer ownership of SIM (Subscriber Identity Module) cards that exceed the maximum limit of ten registered under a single National Identity Card (NID).
In a notice</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 06:38:08 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>