<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 20:26:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Bangladesh facing a state of instability, warns Fakhrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bangladesh-facing-a-state-of-instability-warns-fakhrul</link><description>BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir on Tuesday bemoaned that Bangladesh is currently experiencing a state of instability.
“At this moment, we truly needed people like Barrister Moudud Ahmed. Because, we are living in a state of instability. Barrister Moudud was undoubtedly one</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:00:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BMET's services digitalised through 'Overseas Employment Platform': Asif Nazrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bmets-services-digitalised-through-overseas-employment-platform-asif-nazrul</link><description>Expatriates' Welfare and Overseas Employment Dr Asif Nazrul has said all the services of Bureau of Manpower Employment and Training (BMET) have been digitalised through the launch of "Overseas Employment Platform".
"With the launch of the "Overseas Employment Platform" on April 1, 2025, all t</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 15:15:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Three export-oriented trade bodies demand revision of Labour Ordinance</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/three-export-oriented-trade-bodies-demand-revision-of-labour-ordinance</link><description>Three major export-oriented organisations - Bangladesh Garment Manufacturers and Exporters Association (BGMEA), Bangladesh Knitwear Manufacturers and Exporters Association (BKMEA) and Bangladesh Textile Mills Association (BTMA) — have demanded the withdrawal of the amended Labour Ordinance, s</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 15:30:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Basic sanitation is a daily battle for women in Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/basic-sanitation-is-a-daily-battle-for-women-in-dhaka</link><description>Shreya stands outside a small, dimly lit toilet block on a university campus in Dhaka, waiting. The door does not lock properly. The floor is still wet from the last user. She has already limited her water intake for the day. She carefully calculates how to avoid using a washroom she knows will be</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 15:45:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Grim warning at COP30: Record high CO2 emission</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/grim-warning-at-cop30-record-high-co2-emission</link><description>As delegates began to gather in Belém, deep in the heart of the Brazilian Amazon, for the COP30 climate summit, reports published in the Global Carbon Budget landed like a thunderclap-reminding the world that rhetoric has far outpaced action. The report, released last week, warns that global</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:00:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Implementing mandatory customs bond automation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/implementing-mandatory-customs-bond-automation</link><description>The customs bond facility allows export-oriented industries to import raw materials and intermediate goods duty-free. The condition is that the raw materials and intermediate goods thus imported have to be stored in bonded warehouses and not diverted to the domestic market and that the goods made f</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:15:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Morsalin strike ends Bangladesh’s 22-year wait for win over India</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/football/morsalin-strike-ends-bangladeshs-22-year-wait-for-win-over-india</link><description>Bangladesh have edged India 1-0 in a tense AFC Asian Cup qualifier to claim a victory over their neighbours after 22 years, thanks to a deft first-half strike by Sheikh Morsalin.
In the 12th minute, midfielder Rakib whipped the ball into the box, where Morsalin burst through and toe-poked it past</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:30:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DCs gave no advice on political speeches at Waz-Mahfils: CAO</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dcs-gave-no-advice-on-political-speeches-at-waz-mahfils-cao</link><description>The Chief Advisor’s Office (CAO) has dismissed media reports claiming deputy commissioners advised action on political speeches at Waz-Mahfils during a meeting in Dhaka.
On Tuesday, CA Press Wing Facts posted on Facebook that two deputy commissioners and one divisional commissioner spoke at</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:45:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gold prices fall again in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/gold-prices-fall-again-in-bangladesh</link><description>Gold prices in the domestic market have been reduced once more, with the Bangladesh Jewellers Association (BAJUS) cutting the price of 22-carat gold by Tk 1,364 per bhori.
The new price for 22-carat gold has been set at Tk 206,908 per bhori, effective from Wednesday, UNB reports. 
BAJUS anno</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:00:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique hails Bangladesh’s win, sees fresh optimism</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-hails-bangladeshs-win-sees-fresh-optimism</link><description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman on Tuesday said Bangladesh’s long-awaited football victory over India has rekindled a renewed sense of hope and unity across the nation.
In a post on his verified Facebook page, he wrote, “After 22 years, Bangladesh's victory against India today (Tues</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 18:02:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Advisor Bidhan says teachers leading protests responsible for police using sound grenades</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/advisor-bidhan-says-teachers-leading-protests-responsible-for-police-using-sound-grenades</link><description>Primary and Mass Education Advisor Bidhan Ranjan Roy Poddar has expressed sorrow over the death of assistant teacher Fatema Akter, who fell ill after police fired sound grenades during a teachers’ protest.
On Tuesday, he pledged support for her family but insisted that responsibility for the</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 20:11:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Amended law allows 20-worker TU, ample working facilities</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/amended-law-allows-20-worker-tu-ample-working-facilities</link><description>A remade law permits minimum 20-worker trade union with redefined labour and workplace categories and employer obligations across multiple sectors in the status-upgrading Bangladesh.



The interim government amends the labour law revising several provisions, like lowering trade union-registr</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 20:26:55 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>