<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 21:17:22 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>In need of reforms beyond trade policy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/in-need-of-reforms-beyond-trade-policy</link><description>The theme of the World Bank's latest South Asia Economic Update is timely and relevant to the prevailing global realities and economic challenges facing South Asian countries. In particular, the challenge of job creation is of utmost priority and key to maintaining economic and social stability in</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 16:52:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Lives lost for lack of antivenom injection</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/lives-lost-for-lack-of-antivenom-injection</link><description>Every year, there are reports galore on people in rural areas losing their lives from snakebites. Lack of anti-venom leaves the victims and their families devastated and helpless, as they can do nothing but wait for their inevitable death.
Blessed with vast wetlands, fertile plains and a tropical</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 17:22:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The World Teachers' Day and educational imbroglio</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/the-world-teachers-day-and-educational-imbroglio</link><description>The observance of the World Teachers' Day on October 5 was mostly a muted affair in this country. There is nothing to be surprised at the event passing so quietly. In a country where teachers, particularly those of the primary and secondary schools, are systematically neglected, why should such a d</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 17:37:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Growth without inclusion and saga of inequality</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/growth-without-inclusion-and-saga-of-inequality</link><description>Despite reforms, policy innovations, and impressive macroeconomic performance in recent decades, inequality continues to undercut the promise of inclusive growth. This paradox -- growth without equitable distribution -- has long been observed in developing nations, but it is particularly striking i</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 17:52:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh fall short in thrilling 3-4 defeat to Hong Kong in Asian Cup Qualifiers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/bangladesh-fall-short-in-thrilling-3-4-defeat-to-hong-kong-in-asian-cup-qualifiers</link><description>Bangladesh suffered a heartbreaking 3-4 defeat to Hong Kong in an action-packed, seven-goal thriller in the third round of the Asian Cup Qualifiers.
The match, held at the National Stadium on Thursday, saw Bangladesh take an early lead, only for their dreams to be crushed after a tense second half</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 18:07:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cox's Bazar’s first plastic recycling plant inaugurated</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/coxs-bazars-first-plastic-recycling-plant-inaugurated</link><description>Aiming to transform single-use plastic waste into valuable resources, the first municipal plastic recycling plant in Cox’s Bazar has officially begun operations. 
The facility, located in Mithaichori of Ramu upazila, was inaugurated by Mohammad Navid Shafiullah, additional secretary at</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 18:37:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hasina, Asaduzzaman ordered our killing: Asif Mahmud</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hasina-asaduzzaman-ordered-killing-of-anti-discrimination-coordinators-asif-mahmud-testifies</link><description>Asif Mahmud Shojib Bhuyain, one of the key coordinators of the Anti-discrimination Student Movement, has testified before the International Crimes Tribunal that “orders were issued to kill” the coordinators if they refused to call off the protests.
Now an advisor to the interim governm</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 18:52:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Lower interest to single digits, help economy grow</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/lower-interest-to-single-digits-help-economy-grow</link><description>Business leaders on Thursday urged the central bank to reinstate single-digit lending rates.
They deplored that ramped-up interest, currently hovering above 14 per cent, was harming business growth, investment and global competitiveness.
The strong plea for rate cut was made during a meeting with</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 19:37:55 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>