<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 09:50:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Thousands of Sri Lankan schools face teacher shortages</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/thousands-of-sri-lankan-schools-face-teacher-shortages</link><description>More than 3,000 Sri Lankan schools are operating with fewer than 10 teachers each, data released Thursday by the country's Department of Census and Statistics shows.
According to the data, 3,126 schools, including one national school, function with fewer than 10 teachers. An additional 4,263 schoo</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 06:02:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Asif Nazrul lauds Pakistan for boycotting match against India</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/asif-nazrul-lauds-pakistan-for-boycotting-match-against-india</link><description>Youth and Sports Adviser Dr Asif Nazrul has expressed gratitude to Pakistan for its decision to boycott the India match in protest against Bangladesh's exclusion from the T20 World Cup. 
Asif Nazrul, also the adviser of the Ministries of Law, Justice and Parliamentary Affairs and Expatriates'</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 06:17:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nigerien forces kill 47 terrorists</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/africa/nigerien-forces-kill-47-terrorists</link><description>Niger's Defence and Security Forces (FDS) said on Wednesday that they had "neutralised" 47 terrorists and arrested 21 others between Jan. 26 and Feb. 1 through targeted airstrikes and sustained ground operations nationwide.
According to a weekly information bulletin broadcast on national televisio</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 06:32:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Advisor Sakhawat faces protests at Ctg port</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/advisor-sakhawat-faces-protests-at-ctg-port</link><description>Shipping Advisor M Sakhawat Hussain has faced protests from workers and employees during a visit to Chittagong Port amid an ongoing strike.
Around 11:00 am on Thursday, he came under fire from protesting workers and employees outside Gate No. 4 of the port, reports bdnews24.com.
Earlier in the mo</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 06:47:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ex-MP Saiful sentenced to death in Ashulia corpse burning case</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ex-mp-saiful-sentenced-to-death-in-ashulia-corpse-burning-case</link><description>The International Crimes Tribunal has sentenced six people, including former Dhaka MP Md Saiful Islam, to death in a crimes against humanity case over the shooting of six people and the burning of their bodies in Savar's Ashulia during the July Uprising.
A three-member bench of International Crime</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 08:48:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mukhter Hossain appointed chairman of Uttara Finance &amp; Investments</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/mukhter-hossain-appointed-chairman-of-uttara-finance-investments</link><description>Mr. Md. Mukhter Hossain was appointed as an Independent Director and Chairman of the Board of Directors of Uttara Finance &amp; Investments Limited (UFIL) by Bangladesh Bank on January 27, 2026.
Mr. Hossain possesses a proven record as a strategic leader and decision-maker with deep knowledge across c</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 07:17:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>387 July warriors upgraded to 'A', 474 to 'B' category</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/387-july-warriors-upgraded-to-a-474-to-b-category</link><description>A total of 387 July warriors have been upgraded to the ‘A’ category from their previous ‘B’ and ‘C’ categories, while 474 warriors have been promoted from ‘C’ to ‘B’.
The Ministry of Liberation War Affairs issued a notification revising t</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 07:32:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bitcoin drops below $76000</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bitcoin-drops-below-76000</link><description>Bitcoin was on the cusp of breaking below the key $70,000 level on Thursday as a slide in the world's largest cryptocurrency showed no signs of stopping.
Bitcoin tumbled more than 3.0 per cent in the Asian session to $70,052.38, its lowest level since November 2024.
Ether, the world's second-larg</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 07:47:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US drone makers seek Asia sales</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/us-drone-makers-seek-asia-sales</link><description>Several US drone firms made their debuts at the Singapore Airshow this week, seeking to expand their business beyond the Pentagon to countries in Asia that are increasingly concerned about the threat posed by China's military build-up.
The lethal success of drones on both sides of Russia’s w</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 08:02:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Logistics policy gaps threaten trade competitiveness</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/logistics-policy-gaps-threaten-trade-competitiveness</link><description>As Bangladesh pushes to strengthen its trade and supply chains, long-standing weaknesses in how goods move across the country are coming under sharper scrutiny.
From crowded ports to fragmented decision-making, logistics is increasingly seen as a quiet constraint on economic growth - just as the c</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 08:17:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mustafizur Rahman signs direct deal with Lahore Qalandars in PSL</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/mustafizur-rahman-signs-direct-deal-with-lahore-qalandars-in-psl</link><description>Bangladesh left-arm fast bowler Mustafizur Rahman has been signed by Lahore Qalandars on a direct contract to feature in the Pakistan Super League, reports bdnews24.com.
The PSL franchise confirmed on social media that Mustafizur will once again represent his former side, securing his services for</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 09:03:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC to use wireless network to collect results from 108 remote centres</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ec-to-use-wireless-network-to-collect-results-from-108-remote-centres</link><description>The Election Commission has decided to use the modern network or wireless communication system of law-enforcing agencies to collect election results from 108 remote polling stations accessible by helicopter sorties in the three hill districts -- Rangamati, Khagrachhari and Bandarban.
In this regar</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 09:18:11 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>