<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 07:24:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Shasha Denims plans container handling to offset business slowdown</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/shasha-denims-plans-container-handling-to-offset-business-slowdown</link><description>Shasha Denims plans to diversify its business into inland container handling to sustain income amid uncertainty in denim manufacturing.
"The denim business is becoming challenging due to the unavailability of gas and other factors. That's why we have planned early to open other windows of earnin</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 01:07:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Savings certificate yields lowered twice, further cuts in Jan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/savings-certificate-yields-lowered-twice-further-cuts-in-jan</link><description>A retired banker's daughter increasingly struggles to manage the daily expenses of her parents, who are almost bed-ridden, and a downturn in receipts from investment in savings certificates worries her.
Sadia Chowdhury, daughter of former private banker Humayun Chowdhury, whose parents live in t</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 01:22:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt moves to eliminate child labour by 2030: Labour secy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-moves-to-eliminate-child-labour-by-2030-labour-secy</link><description>The government has initiated steps to formulate a national action plan to eliminate child labour from the country by 2030, said Dr Md Sanwar Jahan Bhuiyan, secretary at the Ministry of Labour and Employment, on Thursday.
"Eradication of child labour requires coordinated interventions -- particul</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 01:37:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Disappeared person's dependants can use victim's property</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/disappeared-persons-dependants-can-use-victims-property</link><description>Dependants of a victim of enforced disappearances now can use the victim's property sans any permission under provision of a draft law that remedies existing painful wait of many.
The Advisory Council of the interim government in its meeting Thursday approved the draft of two ordinances-one rela</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 01:52:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NBR launches digital truck tracking system at Benapole land port</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/nbr-launches-digital-truck-tracking-system-at-benapole-land-port</link><description>The National Board of Revenue (NBR) has introduced a new "Truck Movement" sub-module under the ASYCUDA World system to digitally track the entry of cargo-laden trucks from India and the exit of empty vehicles.
The initiative aims to strengthen monitoring, transparency and revenue protection, acc</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 02:07:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>July Revolution sought constitutional renewal, not repeal: Chief Justice</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/july-revolution-sought-constitutional-renewal-not-repeal-chief-justice</link><description>Chief Justice (CJ) Dr Syed Refaat Ahmed on Thursday said the July Revolution did not aim to overturn the Constitution, but rather to renew and strengthen the nation's engagement with it.
He made the remarks while responding to a farewell felicitation accorded to him by Attorney General Md Asaduz</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 02:22:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US launches review of advanced Nvidia AI chip sales to China, sources say</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/us-launches-review-of-advanced-nvidia-ai-chip-sales-to-china-sources-say</link><description>US President Donald Trump's administration has launched a review that could result in the first shipments to China of Nvidia's second-most powerful AI chips, five sources said, making good on his pledge to allow the controversial sales.
Trump this month said he would allow sales of Nvidia's H200 c</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 05:30:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Inqilab Mancha urges people to avoid violence</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/inqilab-mancha-urges-people-to-avoid-violence</link><description>Inqilab Moncho on Friday urged people to refrain from any form of violence over the death of its spokesperson Sharif Osman Bin Hadi who died at a Singapore hospital on Thursday a week after a gun attack on him.
In a Facebook post, the socio-cultural platform—formed in the wake of the July Re</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 05:35:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Australia plans gun buyback after Bondi massacre, as surfers honour victims</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/australia-plans-gun-buyback-after-bondi-massacre-as-surfers-honour-victims</link><description>Australia will launch a national gun buyback scheme following the mass shooting in Sydney, Prime Minister Anthony Albanese said on Friday, as hundreds of surfers and swimmers paddled out at Bondi Beach to honour victims.
The buyback would be similar to gun reforms introduced soon after the massacr</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 05:50:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCP’s Hannan Masud files GD over ‘death threats’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ncps-hannan-masud-files-gd-over-death-threats</link><description>Abdul Hannan Masud, the senior joint chief convenor of the National Citizen Party (NCP) and the party’s candidate for the upcoming Noakhali-6 parliamentary election, has allegedly received death threats.
Masud’s uncle Shamsul Tibriz, the chief convenor of the NCP’s Hatiya Upazila</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 06:05:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>As global scrutiny grows, Chinese firms look to call Singapore home</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/as-global-scrutiny-grows-chinese-firms-look-to-call-singapore-home</link><description>A growing number of Chinese companies are looking to domicile in Singapore, betting a move to the trade-focused city-state would reduce risks their operations get disrupted by Sino-US geopolitical tensions.
The trend, billed as "Singapore washing" by some analysts, started gaining traction near th</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 06:20:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Police chief inspects Daily Star, Prothom Alo buildings after arson attack</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/police-chief-inspects-daily-star-prothom-alo-buildings-after-arson-attack</link><description>Inspector General of Police (IGP) Baharul Alam has gone to inspect the damage to the buildings housing the Dhaka head offices of major newspapers Prothom Alo and The Daily Star.
He arrived for the inspection of the two buildings at 9am on Friday.
Abdullah Al Imran, additional deputy commissioner</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 06:35:40 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>