<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 15:25:56 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Skills for the perfect 'comeback': Insights from Mamdani's guidebook</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/others/skills-for-the-perfect-comeback-insights-from-mamdanis-guidebook</link><description>Swinging around a tree in the signature open-arm lean of Bollywood star Shah Rukh Khan, Zohran Mamdani asks, "Hey! Have you ever voted before?" Just a year ago, most New Yorkers were unfamiliar with him. Today, he's the city's first South Asian Muslim mayor and its youngest in generations. 
Early</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 12:15:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>5 more die of dengue; 1,139 hospitalised in 24 hours</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/5-more-die-of-dengue-1139-hospitalised-in-24-hours</link><description>The dengue situation in Bangladesh continues to worsen, with five more deaths and 1,139 new hospitalisations recorded across the country in the 24 hours till Wednesday morning.
According to the Directorate General of Health Services (DGHS), the latest figures bring this year’s total death to</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 12:30:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Proud to stand with Bangladesh as true partner: UK Minister</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/proud-to-stand-with-bangladesh-as-true-partner-uk-minister</link><description>UK Minister for International Development Jenny Chapman has said that the United Kingdom is proud to stand with Bangladesh as a genuine partner.
From supporting the Rohingya refugees being hosted by Bangladeshi communities, to tackling the climate crisis and irregular migration, she said their wor</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 12:45:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chief adviser to address the nation on Thursday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/chief-adviser-to-address-the-nation-on-thursday</link><description>Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus will address the nation on Thursday afternoon.
Bangladesh Television, BTV News and BTV World will broadcast his speech live, said Chief Adviser's Press Wing on Wednesday evening.</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 13:00:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt to revise film grant policy to boost quality: Mahfuj Alam</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-to-revise-film-grant-policy-to-boost-quality-mahfuj-alam</link><description>The government will amend its grant policy for short and full-length film production to enhance the quality of films produced with state support, Information and Broadcasting Adviser Md. Mahfuj Alam said on Wednesday.
He made the remarks at a view-sharing meeting on the proposed amendments to the</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 13:15:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DoE shuts illegal brick kilns, fines TK 1.8 million in Savar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/doe-shuts-illegal-brick-kilns-fines-tk-18-million-in-savar</link><description>The Department of Environment (DoE) today conducted a special enforcement drive in Savar Upazila to curb air pollution and implement the degraded airshed declaration, shutting down several illegal brick kilns and realizing fines amounting to TK 1.8 million (18 lakh).
The operation was carried out</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 13:30:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>7 activists of ‘banned BCL’ held from ex-minister Noufel’s residence in Chattogram</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/7-activists-of-banned-bcl-held-from-ex-minister-noufels-residence-in-chattogram</link><description>Police in a drive arrested seven suspected leaders and activists of the banned Bangladesh Chhatra League (BCL) from the residence of former Education Minister Mohibul Hasan Chowdhury Noufel in Sholoshohor in Chattogram port city on Wednesday.
Tipped off, a team of police conducted a drive at the r</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 13:45:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shahjalal Islami Bank signs MoU with National Pension Authority</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/shahjalal-islami-bank-signs-mou-with-national-pension-authority</link><description>A Memorandum of Understanding (MoU) been signed between the National Pension Authority and Shahjalal Islami Bank PLC on Wednesday at the conference room of the Finance Division at Bangladesh Secretariat for the purpose of smoothly implementing the registration, collection of subscription and API ac</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 14:00:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pubali Bank donates Tk 1.5 million to SUST for research, innovation conference</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/pubali-bank-donates-tk-15-million-to-sust-for-research-innovation-conference</link><description>Pubali Bank PLC has recently provided a financial contribution of Tk 1.5 million at the 13th Annual Research and Innovations Conference held at Shahjalal University of Science and Technology (SUST), according to a press release.
The conference was chaired by Vice Chancellor of Shahjalal University</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 14:15:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique warns against political volatility, urges election participation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-warns-against-political-volatility-urges-election-participation</link><description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman on Wednesday urged political parties not to make the country’s situation volatile by imposing various conditions, but instead to face people in next year’s national election, rather than issuing threats to the ‘fragile’ interim government.</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 14:30:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Midland Bank holds seminar at Jahangirnagar University to promote financial literacy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/midland-bank-holds-seminar-at-jahangirnagar-university-to-promote-financial-literacy</link><description>Midland Bank PLC, in collaboration with Communic-IBA of Jahangirnagar University, jointly organised a seminar on Financial Literacy on Wednesday at the Senate Hall of Jahangirnagar University, Savar, Dhaka, according to a press release.
The seminar was chaired by Professor Dr. Ireen Akther, Direct</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 14:45:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>RAB recovers petrol bombs, cocktails from Dhaka’s Mohammadpur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rab-recovers-petrol-bombs-cocktails-from-dhakas-mohammadpur</link><description>Members of the Rapid Action Battalion (RAB) recovered six petrol bombs and four crude bombs (cocktails) from the Rayerbazar Intellectuals’ Graveyard area under Mohammadpur Police Station on Wednesday evening.
The explosives were found abandoned during a special drive conducted by the Crime P</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 15:00:46 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>