<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 06:45:33 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Dhaka-Ctg highway’s 10-lane expansion shelved; focus shifts to railway</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/dhaka-ctg-highways-10-lane-expansion-shelved-focus-shifts-to-railway</link><description>The government has decided to abandon its plan to expand the Dhaka–Chattogram Highway into a 10-lane road, shifting focus instead to upgrading the country’s railway network.
The decision comes in response to growing land constraints and the need for a sustainable transport system, said</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 04:17:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>TCB seeks Tk 14.11b from govt to offset its losses against subsidised commodity sale</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/tcb-seeks-tk-1411b-from-govt-to-offset-its-losses-against-subsidised-commodity-sale</link><description>Trading Corporation of Bangladesh (TCB) has sought over Tk 14.11 billion as subsidy from the government to help offset its financial losses on account of selling essential commodities at subsidised rates, sources said.
The state-run agency in a letter recently requested the commerce ministry to ta</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 04:32:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump promises new tariffs on China</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/global/trump-promises-new-tariffs-on-china</link><description>US President Donald Trump revived the trade war against Beijing on Friday, ending an uneasy truce between the two largest economies with promises to sharply hike tariffs in a reprisal against China, curbing its critical mineral exports.
The president unveiled additional levies of 100 per cent on C</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 03:48:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>China hits back on US port fees with retaliatory levies</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/global/china-hits-back-on-us-port-fees-with-retaliatory-levies</link><description>China will slap port fees on US-owned, operated, built, or flagged vessels on Tuesday as a countermeasure to US port fees on China-linked ships starting the same day, China's transport ministry said on Friday.
Later in the day, US President Donald Trump said he was raising tariffs on Chinese expor</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 04:03:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>MIT refuses to accept White House terms for preferential funding</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/mit-refuses-to-accept-white-house-terms-for-preferential-funding</link><description>Massachusetts Institute of Technology President Sally Kornbluth on Friday said she "cannot support" a memo that the White House sent to nine elite US universities last week detailing policies they should follow to get preferential consideration for federal funding.
In an open letter to US Educatio</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 04:18:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Heavy rain, floods in Mexico leave 30 dead</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/heavy-rain-floods-in-mexico-leave-30-dead</link><description>Heavy rainfall in Mexico has left at least 27 people dead and more missing, authorities said on Friday, as downpours triggered several landslides, cut off power in some municipalities and caused rivers to burst their banks.
Civil protection authorities in Hidalgo state reported 16 deaths and said</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 04:33:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Shapla’ off limits to political parties, says EC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/shapla-off-limits-to-political-parties-says-ec</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has made it clear once again that the “Shapla”, or water lily, symbol cannot be allotted as a party emblem under any circumstances.
The commission said the decision was made in full accordance with the Constitution, election laws, and the rules governing th</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 04:48:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Heavy to very heavy rainfall likely in parts of Bangladesh: BMD</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/heavy-to-very-heavy-rainfall-likely-in-parts-of-bangladesh-bmd</link><description>Bangladesh Meteorological Department (BMD) has forecast moderately heavy to heavy rainfall in Mymensingh, Dhaka, Khulna, Barishal, Chattogram and Sylhet divisions in 24 hours commencing 9am on Saturday.
“Light to moderate rain or thunder showers accompanied by temporary gusty wind is likely</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 05:18:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump, 79, has "cardiac age" of 65-year-old, doctor says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/trump-79-has-cardiac-age-of-65-year-old-doctor-says</link><description>Donald Trump was found to be in "exceptional health" in a medical evaluation, the US president's doctor said in a memo released by the White House on Friday, with his "cardiac age" 14 years younger than in "chronological age".
Trump, 79, was the oldest person to assume the US presidency when he re</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 05:33:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gazans trek to ruined homes as Israeli forces pull back under ceasefire</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/gazans-trek-to-ruined-homes-as-israeli-forces-pull-back-under-ceasefire</link><description>Thousands of displaced Palestinians trekked over the wastelands of Gaza to return to the ruins of their abandoned homes on Friday, after a ceasefire took effect and Israeli troops began pulling back under the first phase of an agreement to end the war.
A huge column of people filed on foot north a</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 05:48:19 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>