<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 11:36:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Middle East does not need Iran-US war, diplomatic adviser to UAE president says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/middle-east-does-not-need-iran-us-war-diplomatic-adviser-to-uae-president-says</link><description>The Middle East does not need another confrontation between the US and Iran, and Tehran needs to reach a nuclear deal with Washington, the diplomatic adviser to the president of regional power United Arab Emirates said at a World Governments Summit panel in Dubai.
Iran and the United States will r</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 08:42:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Transport worker stabbed, robbed of Tk 90,000 at Dhaka’s Shyampur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/transport-worker-stabbed-robbed-of-tk-90000-at-dhakas-shyampur</link><description>Muggers snatched Tk 90,000 stabbing a transport worker near Sheikh Kamal School on Khondkar road at Shympur in Dhaka on Tuesday.
The victim is Golam Kibria, 45, a staff member of Borak Transport’s Bangsal branch.
Witnesses said when he was returning home by rickshaw three people stopped him</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 08:57:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump's tariff cut spells relief in India despite scant details</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/trumps-tariff-cut-spells-relief-in-india-despite-scant-details</link><description>US President Donald Trump's move to slash tariffs on Indian imports sparked a relief rally across the Asian country's markets on Tuesday, lifting sentiment among exporters and policymakers even as details of the agreement remained scant.
Trump announced a trade deal with India on Monday to cut tar</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 09:12:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh to face danger if voters fail to make right choice: Fakhrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bangladesh-to-face-danger-if-voters-fail-to-make-right-choice-fakhrul</link><description>BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir on Tuesday said the nation will face grave danger if voters fail to make the right decision in the election.
 “This election is extremely important. Citizens must make the right decision at the right time, vote for good leaders and a cap</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 09:27:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat may next claim ‘Ghulam Azam declared independence’: Rizvi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-may-next-claim-ghulam-azam-declared-independence-rizvi</link><description>BNP Senior Joint Secretary General Ruhul Kabir Rizvi on Tuesday strongly criticised Jamaat-e-Islami, saying that if the party continues to distort history, it may one day claim that Ghulam Azam proclaimed Bangladesh’s independence.
“When the Pakistani forces carried out atrocities agai</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 09:42:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Foreign diplomats joining guided tour of July Mass Uprising Memorial Museum</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/foreign-diplomats-joining-guided-tour-of-july-mass-uprising-memorial-museum</link><description>Diplomats stationed in Dhaka are joining a guided tour of July Mass Uprising Memorial Museum from 3pm to 5pm on Tuesday.
The Ministry of Foreign Affairs on January 29 wrote to all diplomatic missions, UN agencies and offices of international organisations in Dhaka, inviting Ambassadors, High Commi</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 09:57:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Apex Footwear Ltd. successfully concludes Apex Golf Tournament 2026 at Army Golf Club</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/apex-footwear-ltd-successfully-concludes-apex-golf-tournament-2026-at-army-golf-club</link><description>Apex Footwear Limited successfully concluded the much awaited Apex Golf Tournament 2026 at the prestigious Army Golf Club, Dhaka, marking yet another milestone in the company’s commitment to promoting sportsmanship and community engagement. 
Held from January 14 to January 17, 2026, the</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 10:12:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Iranian police say 139 foreigners arrested over unrest in Yazd province</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/iranian-police-say-139-foreigners-arrested-over-unrest-in-yazd-province</link><description>Iranian police said 139 foreign nationals have so far been arrested in the central province of Yazd for their participation in recent protests, the semi-official Tasnim news agency reported on Tuesday, without specifying their nationalities.
Yazd, a predominantly desert province with a relatively</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 10:27:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Spain to ban social media access for children under 16</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/spain-to-ban-social-media-access-for-children-under-16</link><description>Spain will ban access to social media for minors under 16 and platforms will be required to implement age verification systems, Prime Minister Pedro Sanchez said on Tuesday at the World Government Summit in Dubai.
"Our children are exposed to a space they were never meant to navigate alone... We w</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 10:42:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP’s Tarique Rahman heads to Barishal, Faridpur on Wednesday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnps-tarique-rahman-heads-to-barishal-faridpur-on-wednesday</link><description>BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman is headed to Barishal and Faridpur on Wednesday as part of his campaign ahead of the Feb 12 general election.
Mahadi Amin, spokesman for the party's central election management committee, made the announcement at a press briefing at the BNP’s office in Gulshan on</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 10:57:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rizwana Hasan urges action for horn-free streets in Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/rizwana-hasan-urges-action-for-horn-free-streets-in-dhaka</link><description>Bangladesh could have horn-free roads in the future if noise laws are properly enforced, said Syeda Rizwana Hasan, Adviser to the Ministries of Environment, Forest and Climate Change, Information and Broadcasting, and Water Resources.
She made the remark at a public program in Mazar Chattar, Dhaka</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 11:12:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gold Price Shock: Tk 16,330 surge hits Bangladesh overnight</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/gold-price-shock-tk-16330-surge-hits-bangladesh-overnight</link><description>Gold prices in Bangladesh soared again on Tuesday, climbing a total of Tk 16,330 per bhori through two separate hikes announced by the Bangladesh Jewellers Association (BAJUS), pushing the price back above Tk 260,000 per bhori.
In a morning notification, BAJUS said it had raised the price of 22-ca</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 11:27:38 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>