<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 04:40:28 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>BNP leader hacked to death in Bagerhat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bnp-leader-hacked-to-death-in-bagerhat</link><description>A BNP leader has been killed in Bagerhat town after assailants arrived on motorcycles and hacked him while he was sitting at a tea stall, police say.
The incident occurred around 6:30 pm on Friday at the three-road intersection in Uttar Harikhali, Bagerhat Sadar Model Police Station chief Md Mahmu</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 02:39:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Woman hacked to death over chicken in Mymensingh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/woman-hacked-to-death-over-chicken-in-mymensingh</link><description>A woman was hacked to death by a neighbour in Ishwarganj upazila of Mymensingh on Friday evening following a dispute over a chicken.
The deceased was identified as Rowshan Ara Begum, 50, of Khairati village under Ishwarganj union, reports UNB.
According to the police and locals, there had been a</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 02:54:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US university sold dead bodies for ‘Israeli military training’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-university-sold-dead-bodies-for-israeli-military-training</link><description>The University of Southern California (USC) has received at least $860,000 from the United States Navy since late 2017 in exchange for 89 cadavers, many of which were used to train the Israeli Defence Forces (IDF) in trauma surgery, according to a report by Annenberg Media.
The arrangement began w</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 03:09:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump orders Israel to stop bombing Gaza</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-orders-israel-to-stop-bombing-gaza</link><description>US President Donald Trump on Friday ordered Israel to stop bombing the Gaza Strip after Hamas said it had accepted some elements of his plan to end the nearly two-year war and return all the remaining hostages taken in the Oct. 7, 2023, attack. 
Hamas said it was willing to release the hostag</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 03:24:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Xi, Shahabuddin exchange congratulations on 50th anniversary of ties</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/xi-shahabuddin-exchange-congratulations-on-50th-anniversary-of-ties</link><description>Chinese President Xi Jinping and Bangladeshi President Mohammed Shahabuddin on Saturday exchanged congratulatory messages on the 50th anniversary of diplomatic ties between the two countries.</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 03:21:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Lawsuit seeks to stop Trump's $100,000 fee for H-1B visas</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/lawsuit-seeks-to-stop-trumps-100000-fee-for-h-1b-visas</link><description>In what appears to be the first major challenge to the new $100,000 fee required for H-1B visa applications, a coalition of health care providers, religious groups, university professors and others filed a federal lawsuit Friday to stop the plan, saying it has “thrown employers, workers and f</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 03:36:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Entire world supports Bangladesh’s democratic transition: Mirza Fakhrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/entire-world-supports-bangladeshs-democratic-transition-mirza-fakhrul</link><description>BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir on Friday night said the whole world is supporting Bangladesh’s process of democratic transition through the next national election.“The entire world supports our democratic transition. Especially the democratic world is fully behind it,</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 04:06:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khagrachhari blockade withdrawn after days of unrest</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/khagrachhari-blockade-withdrawn-after-days-of-unrest</link><description>The Jumma Chhatra-Janata has called off a blockade that had been enforced for four days in Khagrachhari following unrest triggered by the alleged rape of a Marma teenager.
The decision was announced on Saturday in a statement issued by the group’s media cell.
According to the statement, the</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 04:21:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>George Clooney says Trump should create incentives, not tariffs, for movie industry</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/george-clooney-says-trump-should-create-incentives-not-tariffs-for-movie-industry</link><description>Movie star George Clooney said on Friday that US President Donald Trump's threat to impose a 100 per cent tariff on all films produced overseas was the wrong solution for a real issue.
Clooney spoke before the annual Albies awards ceremony in London, a program that he and his wife Amal created to</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 04:36:17 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>