<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 15:24:41 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Afghanistan earthquake kills 21, historic sites damaged</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/afghanistan-earthquake-kills-21-historic-sites-damaged</link><description>Survivors of a powerful earthquake in northern Afghanistan spent Monday night outdoors in freezing temperatures as rescue operations continued and historical sites suffered damage.
The 6.3-magnitude quake struck just before 1 a.m. Monday near Khulm in Samangan province, killing 21 and injuring ove</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 13:05:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Charles Coste, world’s oldest Olympian, dies at 101</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/charles-coste-worlds-oldest-olympian-dies-at-101</link><description>Charles Coste, the world’s oldest living Olympian and 1948 Olympic cycling gold medalist, has died at 101, the French presidency announced Tuesday.
Coste won the team pursuit gold at the London Games and gained renewed attention last year as one of the final bearers of the Olympic flame for</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 12:28:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>3 killed in collision between two buses in Habiganj</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/3-killed-in-collision-between-two-buses-in-habiganj</link><description>At least three people were killed and 32 others injured when two passenger buses of Ena Paribahan and Royal Coach collided head-on on the Dhaka–Sylhet Highway in Habiganj on Tuesday afternoon.
The deceased were identified as Raju Mia, 45, son of Mukit Mia of Barachar village under Nabiganj u</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 12:43:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>48.9pc growth of remittance inflow till Nov 3</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/489pc-growth-of-remittance-inflow-till-nov-3</link><description>Inflow of remittances witnessed a year-on-year growth of 48.9 percent reaching US$350 million in the first three days of November, according to the latest data of Bangladesh Bank (BB) issued.
Last year, during the same period, the country’s remittance inflow was $221 million.
During the Jul</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 12:58:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tunisia repatriates 10,000 migrants in 2025, vows not to become a transit zone</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/tunisia-repatriates-10000-migrants-in-2025-vows-not-to-become-a-transit-zone</link><description>Tunisia has repatriated about 10,000 irregular migrants so far this year, most of them from sub-Saharan African countries, Foreign Minister Mohamed Ali Nafti said on Tuesday, as the North African country faces pressure from the European Union to stem crossings across the Mediterranean.
Nafti told</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 13:13:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IFIC Bank's former MD fined Tk 50 million over misleading bond advertisements</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/ific-banks-former-md-fined-tk-50-million-over-misleading-bond-advertisements</link><description>The Bangladesh Securities and Exchange Commission (BSEC) has decided to impose a substantial fine of Taka 50 million on the former Managing Director of IFIC Bank PLC, Shah Alam Sarwar, for violations of securities laws and regulations.
The decision was finalized during the 980th Commission Meeting</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 13:28:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Charan Centre decries axe on music, PE teachers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/charan-cultural-centre-demands-withdrawal-of-decision-to-scrap-music-physical-education-posts</link><description>Charan Cultural Centre has demanded that the government withdraw its decision to abolish the posts of music and physical education teachers in government primary schools.
In a statement issued on Tuesday, the organisation’s President Nikhil Das and General Secretary Zakir Hossain urged the a</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 13:43:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>This might be my last election: Fakhrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/this-might-be-my-last-election-fakhrul</link><description>Senior BNP leader Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir posted an emotional message on Facebook, reflecting on a political career filled with trials, dedication, and sacrifice.
“This election may be my last!” wrote the 77-year-old BNP secretary general on Tuesday, expressing gratitude to party l</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 13:58:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IMF-WB proposes unified DMO in Dhaka to strengthen public debt governance</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/imf-wb-proposes-unified-dmo-in-dhaka-to-strengthen-public-debt-governance</link><description>A joint International Monetary Fund (IMF) and World Bank technical assistance mission has recommended the establishment of a unified Debt Management Office (DMO) in Bangladesh to strengthen the country’s public debt management framework and reduce fiscal and operational risks.
The proposal w</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 14:13:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh Bank set to issue 7th investment sukuk bond worth Tk 25b</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh-bank-set-to-issue-7th-investment-sukuk-bond-worth-tk-25b</link><description>The Bangladesh Bank is preparing to issue the 7th ‘Bangladesh Government Investment Sukuk’ (Islamic bond) valued at Tk 25 billion (Tk 2,500 crore).
The Sukuk is aimed at funding the Important Rural Infrastructure Development Project for Noakhali, Feni, and Lakshmipur (IRIDPNFL) distric</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 14:43:06 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>