<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 15:38:04 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Repatriation only viable solution to Rohingya crisis: CA</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/repatriation-only-viable-solution-to-rohingya-crisis-ca</link><description>Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus has said that the repatriation of more than one million Rohingya refugees to their homeland in Myanmar’s Rakhine State remains the only viable and sustainable solution to the crisis.
 
He urged the UN refugee agency to continue its active engageme</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 11:57:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BTMA withdraws factory shutdown after government assurance</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/btma-withdraws-factory-shutdown-after-government-assurance</link><description>Bangladesh Textile Mills Association (BTMA) has suspended its planned factory shutdown after receiving government assurances to resolve the ongoing crisis related to yarn imports under the bonded warehouse facility.
In a statement issued on Thursday, the primary textile millers’ trade body a</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 12:12:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP to waive farm loans up to Tk 10,000 if elected: Tarique</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-to-waive-farm-loans-up-to-tk-10000-if-elected-tarique</link><description>BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman on Thursday pledged to waive agricultural loans of up to Tk 10,000, including interest, and will introduce farmer cards if his party is voted into power, framing the move as part of a broader effort to ease pressure on rural livelihoods.
The BNP chief came up with the p</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 12:27:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shimanto Bank inks MoU with Farazy Hospital</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/shimanto-bank-inks-mou-with-farazy-hospital</link><description>Shimanto Bank has recently signed a Memorandum of Understanding (MoU) with Farazy Hospital at the Bank’s Head Office.
Under this agreement, all Debit and Credit Card holders, as well as employees of Shimanto Bank, will be entitled to enjoy special discount when availing healthcare services f</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 12:42:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Yes’ or ‘No’ vote campaign by govt staff punishable: EC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/yes-or-no-vote-campaign-by-govt-staff-punishable-ec</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has warned against any government staff campaigning for either a “Yes” or “No” vote in the referendum.
The EC sent a directive to all returning officers on Thursday, saying taking sides would constitute a “punishable offence” under t</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 12:57:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Toddler endures another day in court as mother’s bail deferred</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/toddler-endures-another-day-in-court-as-mothers-bail-deferred</link><description>A one-and-a-half-year-old child has spent yet another day at a Dhaka court compound, waiting for the release of his mother Topsha Biswas, whose bail plea in hearing a police assault case is deferred to Sunday.
The toddler, Pranay Biswas from Dhamrai, has been staying at court as his mother remains</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 13:12:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Russia ready to evacuate staff from Iran's Bushehr nuclear plant</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/russia-is-ready-to-evacuate-its-staff-from-irans-bushehr-nuclear-plant-if-necessary-tass-reports</link><description>Russia is ready to evacuate its staff from Iran's Bushehr nuclear power plant if necessary, Alexei Likhachev, the head of Russia's state nuclear corporation, was cited as saying on Thursday by the state news agency TASS.
President Vladimir Putin said last year that hundreds of Russians were workin</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 13:27:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Southeast Bank completes centralisation, automation of documentation and limit loading functions</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/southeast-bank-completes-centralisation-automation-of-documentation-and-limit-loading-functions</link><description>The Credit Administration Division (CAD) of Southeast Bank PLC (SEBPLC) hosted an event on Wednesday to mark the successful completion of its full centralisation and automation of documentation and limit loading functions.
According to a press release, this strategic engagement significantly impro</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 13:42:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>'Political commitment, inclusive planning, coordinated action needed for Bhola's development'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/political-commitment-inclusive-planning-coordinated-action-needed-for-bholas-development</link><description>Sustainable development in Bhola requires political commitment, inclusive planning, and coordinated action among stakeholders, speakers at a National Dialogue on Thursday said.
The dialogue, “Our Vision for Fair Elections and Bhola’s Development,” was organised by Coast</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 13:57:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US ambassador warns of China's growing manufacturing dominance</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-ambassador-warns-of-chinas-growing-manufacturing-dominance</link><description>The top US envoy to China called Thursday for fair and reciprocal trade between the world's two largest economies and expressed concern about projections that China's dominance of global manufacturing will grow even further in the years to come.
US Ambassador David Perdue told business and governm</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 14:12:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mohammed Younus elected as chairman of Shahjalal Islami Bank</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/mohammed-younus-elected-as-chairman-of-shahjalal-islami-bank</link><description>Mr. Mohammed Younus has been unanimously elected as Chairman of the Board of Directors of Shahjalal Islami Bank PLC during its 404th Board meeting held on Wednesday.
In the same meeting, Mr. Mohiuddin Ahmed was re-elected and Mr. Fakir Akhtaruzzaman was elected as Vice-Chairmen, respectively, of t</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 14:27:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Three more local garment factories receive LEED certification</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/three-more-local-garment-factories-receive-leed-certification</link><description>Three more local garment factories have received LEED certification from the US Green Building Council (USGBC), with one achieving the highest score globally, taking the total number to 273.
HAMS Garments Ltd-- located in Sreepur of Gazipur has achieved Leadership in Energy and Environmental Desig</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 14:42:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>