<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 13:22:40 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Govt to block sites for gambling ads without notice from Sunday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-to-block-sites-for-gambling-ads-without-notice-from-sunday</link><description>The government has announced that any newspaper or its online version, website, news portal or electronic media outlet promoting gambling, betting or pornography will be blocked without prior notice from tomorrow.
Authorities cited a rise in such content across online platforms, calling it a punis</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 10:01:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Five flights diverted after fire at Dhaka airport’s cargo village</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/five-flights-diverted-after-fire-at-dhaka-airports-cargo-village</link><description>Five flights were diverted from Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport in Dhaka on Saturday afternoon following a major fire at the airport’s cargo village.
According to airport sources, the diversions began after 3pm on Saturday (October 18), soon after the fire broke out in the cargo villa</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 10:16:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>July Charter implementation failure to push Bangladesh backward: Attorney General</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/july-charter-implementation-failure-to-push-bangladesh-backward-attorney-general</link><description>Attorney General Md Asaduzzaman on Saturday said failure to implement the July Charter would set the country backward, describing it as a landmark political agreement that ensures transparency, structure, and clarity unlike any previous accord.
“The July Charter is a political settlement &amp;md</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 10:46:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>SAJIDA Foundation holds 32nd Annual General Meeting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/sajida-foundation-holds-32nd-annual-general-meeting</link><description>SAJIDA Foundation held its 32nd Annual General Meeting at a hotel in Dhaka on Saturday (October 18).
The meeting was presided over by Mr. Farooq Sobhan, Chairperson of the Governing Body, according to a media release. 
Other distinguished governing body and general body members of SAJIDA Fou</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 11:01:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>National Bank strengthens regional focus with “Managers Meet” in Khulna</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/national-bank-strengthens-regional-focus-with-managers-meet-in-khulna</link><description>National Bank PLC convened its “Managers Meet” in Khulna on October 16, 2025, uniting 23 branch managers from the region to evaluate performance, share insights, and chart the course for the bank’s continued growth and innovation.
The session was graced by Adil Chowdhury, Managin</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 11:31:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bank Asia wins prestigious WSBI SDG Award 2025 in Washington, D.C.</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bank-asia-wins-prestigious-wsbi-sdg-award-2025-in-washington-dc</link><description>Bank Asia PLC has been honored with the WSBI SDG Award 2025 in recognition of its outstanding contribution to advancing the United Nations Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs).
The bank received accolades across five key categories — Inclusive Banking and Social Impact, Economic Growth and E</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 11:46:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka University again restricts vehicle entry during weekends and holidays</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dhaka-university-again-restricts-vehicle-entry-during-weekends-and-holidays</link><description>Dhaka University authorities have decided to restrict vehicle entry to the campus from 3pm to 10pm on weekends and public holidays to ensure the safety of students.
In a statement issued on Saturday, the university’s Proctor’s Office announced that vehicle movement control within the c</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 12:01:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BRAC Bank partners with TK Group for enhanced digital cash management solutions</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/brac-bank-partners-with-tk-group-for-enhanced-digital-cash-management-solutions</link><description>BRAC Bank and TK Group have entered into a Transaction Banking Agreement to implement an advanced dealer collection solution through Virtual Accounts, marking a significant step forward in digitising corporate cash management in Bangladesh.
Under this partnership, BRAC Bank will provide an automat</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 12:16:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Moyeen Khan stresses engaging educated youths in development activities</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/moyeen-khan-stresses-engaging-educated-youths-in-development-activities</link><description>BNP senior leader Dr Abdul Moyeen Khan on Saturday stressed the need for turning the educated youth into a productive workforce, saying that no development plan can succeed without involving people in the country’s progress.
“Practical steps must be taken to prepare the educated popula</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 12:31:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Global film industry shrugs off renewed Trump movie tariff threat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/entertainment/global-film-industry-shrugs-off-renewed-trump-movie-tariff-threat</link><description>"Star Wars: Starfighter" is filming in Britain, soundstages in Hungary are packed and post-production houses in Australia are humming, as the global film industry keeps rolling despite US President Donald Trump's renewed threats to impose tariffs on movies made outside of the United States.
Trump</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 12:46:56 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>