<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 22:26:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>BNP 'practiced' polling booth capture in attacking NCP's Dhaka-18 candidate: Hasnat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bnp-practiced-polling-booth-capture-in-attacking-ncps-dhaka-18-candidate-hasnat</link><description>National Citizen Party (NCP) Chief Organiser (South Region) and Comilla-4 candidate Hasnat Abdullah on Monday alleged that the BNP started a “practice match” of capturing polling booths by carrying out attacks on NCP election campaigns and its candidate in Dhaka-18.
“Today, the k</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 17:14:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Bomb’ attack at Ctg BNP candidate’s rally</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crude-bombs-hurled-at-bnp-candidate-ershad-ullahs-election-rally-in-chattogram</link><description>Crude bombs have allegedly been hurled at an election rally of BNP candidate Ershad Ullah in the Chattogram-8 constituency, with a party leader blaming the Jamaat-e-Islami for the attack.
Five people threw improvised explosives in quick succession at the rally in Boalkhali Upazila on Monday evenin</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 17:29:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Israel retrieves last hostage body from Gaza in boost for Trump plan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/israel-retrieves-last-hostage-body-from-gaza-in-boost-for-trump-plan</link><description>Israel has retrieved the remains of the last remaining hostage held in Gaza, the military said on Monday, fulfilling a key condition of the initial phase of US President Donald Trump's plan to end the Gaza war.
The remains of police officer Ran Gvili have been identified and will be returned for b</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 17:44:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US envoy Christensen lauds Chittagong Port reforms, pledges support for modernisation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/us-envoy-christensen-lauds-chittagong-port-reforms-pledges-support-for-modernisation</link><description>US Ambassador Brent Christensen has praised reforms at Chittagong Port and pledged cooperation to modernise the facility.
Christensen led a delegation to the port on Monday, where its Chairman Rear Admiral Sayed Mohammad Moniruzzaman outlined progress made under the interim government since the Ju</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 17:59:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UAE bars use of its airspace for military action against Iran</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/uae-bars-use-of-its-airspace-for-military-action-against-iran</link><description>The United Arab Emirates will not let its airspace, territory or territorial waters be used for any hostile military actions against Iran, the UAE foreign ministry said on Monday, reaffirming its commitment to neutrality and regional stability.
Uncertainty over the possibility of military action i</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 19:15:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Move on to make Sanchayapatras tradable on bond market</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/move-on-to-make-sanchayapatras-tradable-on-bond-market</link><description>Savings certificates (Sanchayapatras) are being made tradable on bond market, among other measures, to systematically force or encourage corporates through applying push and pull factors to meet their long-term financing needs from outside banks.



This switch from banks to capital market for</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 19:30:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Newly elected JnUCSU VP alleges UGC being 'run by syndicate'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/newly-elected-jnucsu-vp-alleges-ugc-being-run-by-syndicate</link><description>Vice President of the Jagannath University Central Students’ Union (JnUCSU), Md. Riazul Islam has alleged that Jagannath University (JnU) is facing discrimination at the University Grants Commission (UGC) due to the absence of any JnU faculty members there, claiming that a “syndicate&amp;rd</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 19:45:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gold price skyrockets to Tk 262,440 per bhori overnight in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/gold-price-skyrockets-to-tk-262440-per-bhori-overnight-in-bangladesh</link><description>Gold prices in Bangladesh have climbed again within 24 hours, with the Bangladesh Jewellers Association (BAJUS) announcing a fresh hike on Monday that has pushed prices to a new all-time high.
In a notification issued late night, BAJUS said the price of 22-carat gold has been increased by Tk</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 20:00:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trust, not technology, will define future of accounting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/trust-not-technology-will-define-future-of-accounting</link><description>In an era of rapid technological change, rising sustainability demands, and persistent weaknesses in corporate governance, public trust in financial reporting has become more critical than before while transparency, ethics, and continuous professional upskilling are the main three pillars on which</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 20:15:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A society off its rocker</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/a-society-off-its-rocker</link><description>Reports of gruesome murder over political rivalries, turf wars among armed groups, or even family conflicts grab headlines from time to time. To ordinary people, the very report of killing one person by another is something shocking. But nowadays, it appears, even accidental killers, let alone the</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 20:30:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Strengthening economic cooperation with Australia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/strengthening-economic-cooperation-with-australia</link><description>Bangladesh and Australia like to describe each other as "old friends", and the phrase is not just diplomatic rhetoric. Australia was among the first countries to recognise Bangladesh after its independence in 1971. More than half a century later, that early political goodwill has matured into a rel</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 20:45:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Negotiable Instruments Act 2025</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/negotiable-instruments-act-2025</link><description>Only days before did the Ministry of Law (MoL) reject the draft of the Artha Rin Adalat Ain (Money Loan Court Act), suggesting amendment to the existing laws instead of getting ready a whole new Act. Now the council of advisers of the interim government has approved a similar but stringent law, the</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 21:00:51 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>