<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 16:24:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>BFUJ announces 1 Nov protest, demands ‘No Wage Board, No Media’ Policy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bfuj-announces-1-nov-protest-demands-no-wage-board-no-media-policy</link><description>The Bangladesh Federal Union of Journalists (BFUJ) has announced a nationwide protest on 1 November to press home a 21-point demand, including implementation of its ‘No Wage Board, No Media’ policy and formation of the 10th Wage Board.
The decisions came from the BFUJ Executive Committ</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 13:39:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Kushtia Civil Surgeon’s Office sealed over recruitment exam leak claims</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/kushtia-civil-surgeons-office-sealed-over-recruitment-exam-leak-claims</link><description>Several agitated jobseekers have locked the gate of the Civil Surgeon’s Office in Kushtia, accusing authorities of corruption and leaking question papers in the recruitment test for 115 health assistant posts.
The candidates gathered outside the office around 12:30pm on Saturday, a day after</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 14:09:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Women’s football match halted after crowd violence in Jhenaidah</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/womens-football-match-halted-after-crowd-violence-in-jhenaidah</link><description>Three people, including a woman footballer, were injured after some spectators entered the field and attacked during a friendly women’s football match in Maheshpur upazila of Jhenaidah on Friday afternoon.
The match was held at Mandartala playground, organized by Mandartala Jubo Sangha.
Dha</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 14:24:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Clash during eviction drive in Bhola leaves 15 workers injured</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/clash-during-eviction-drive-in-bhola-leaves-15-workers-injured</link><description>A violent confrontation and arson have broken out during an eviction drive targeting illegal structures at New Market in Bhola city, leaving 15 municipal sanitation workers injured.
During the clash on Saturday afternoon, three of the town council’s garbage and transport vehicles were set on</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 14:54:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>5 arrested for rape of housewife in Cumilla</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/5-arrested-for-rape-of-housewife-in-cumilla</link><description>In a shocking incident in Chouddagram, Cumilla, a husband allegedly detained his wife for three days and forced her to be raped by other men.
The victim filed a case with the local police, who have arrested five suspects in connection with the crime.
The arrested are identified as, the husband Ra</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 15:24:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Australian women cricketers ‘harassed’ in Indore during World Cup</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/australian-women-cricketers-harassed-in-indore-during-world-cup</link><description>Two players from Australia’s women’s cricket team were allegedly stalked and sexually harassed during their stay in India for the ICC Women’s World Cup.
According to the Indian Express, the players were walking in from their hotel in Indore to a café on Thursday morning wh</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 15:54:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump says he's willing to reduce tariffs on Brazil in right circumstances</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/trump-says-hes-willing-to-reduce-tariffs-on-brazil-in-right-circumstances</link><description>US President Donald Trump said on Friday he would consider reducing tariffs on Brazil, under the right circumstances.
Trump was speaking on Air Force One heading to Malaysia for a regional summit.
Trump increased tariffs on US imports of most Brazilian goods to 50 percent from 10 percent in early</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 16:09:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh put on cyclone alert</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/bangladesh-on-alert-as-bay-depression-brews-into-possible-cyclone-montha-sunday</link><description>A low-pressure system over the Bay of Bengal has intensified, with the Bangladesh Meteorological Department (BMD) warning it may develop into a cyclone by Sunday.
The system has remained over the same area while moving west-northwest on Saturday evening.
Meteorologist Md Omar Faruk told bdnews24.</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 16:24:41 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>