<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 14:27:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Chhatra Dal boycotts CU Victory Day event over pro-VC’s presence</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/chhatra-dal-boycotts-cu-victory-day-event-over-pro-vcs-presence</link><description>The Chittagong University unit of Jatiotabadi Chhatra Dal has boycotted the Victory Day programme, protesting the presence of pro-Vice-Chancellor Mohammed Shamim Uddin Khan.
The announcement of the boycott came during a discussion organised at the university’s Jarul Tola on Tuesday morning.</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 11:06:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nabanna Festival 2025 held at BRAC University</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/nabanna-festival-2025-held-at-brac-university</link><description>The BRAC University Marketing Association (BUMA) on Monday organised Nabanna Festival 2025 at BRAC University to introduce the next generation to Bengal’s history, traditions and culture.
The festival began at 9:00am on the university campus and concluded in the afternoon with cultural perfo</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 11:21:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Thailand works to repatriate thousands stranded at Cambodia border crossing</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/thailand-works-to-repatriate-thousands-stranded-at-cambodia-border-crossing</link><description>Thailand is working out how to repatriate up to 6,000 citizens unable to return home through a major border crossing in Cambodia closed as fighting along the contested border extended into a second week, authorities said on Tuesday.
The militaries of the Southeast Asian neighbours are clashing at</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 11:36:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shadik Kayem pledges to 'establish justice' on Victory Day</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/ducsu-vp-shadik-kayem-promises-to-establish-justice-on-victory-day</link><description>Dhaka University Central Students’ Union (DUCSU) Vice-President Abu Shadik Kayem has said the "pledge" for this Victory Day is to establish "justice” by holding those who have attempted to make the state "ineffective" since 1971 to account.
Paying tribute to the heroic martyrs at the N</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 11:52:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Faisal's associate to be quizzed for 7 days</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/faisals-associate-to-be-quizzed-for-7-days</link><description>Police have been granted seven days to grill an alleged associate of Faisal Karim Masud, the key suspect in the attempted murder of Inqilab Moncho leader Sharif Osman bin Hadi.
Dhaka Metropolitan Magistrate Hasibuzzaman issued the order on Tuesday in response to the police's 10-day remand petition</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 12:07:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Freedom fighter’s grave torched on Victory Day</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/freedom-fighters-grave-torched-in-shariatpur-on-victory-day</link><description>The grave of a freedom fighter has been set on fire in Shariatpur Sadar Upazila on the morning of Victory Day.
The family of freedom fighter Abdul Mannan Khan said that someone had set fire to the grave in Char Niamatpur village of Angaria Union and fled the scene on Tuesday morning.
Villagers sa</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 12:22:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Praising Ghulam Azam undermines freedom fighters: Abbas</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/where-do-freedom-fighters-stand-if-ghulam-azam-is-hailed-as-nations-best-son-mirza-abbas-asks</link><description>Senior BNP leader Mirza Abbas has questioned the labelling of some Jamaat-e-Islami leaders, convicted of war crimes, as the nation’s best sons.
He wondered where the freedom fighters stand if the likes of Ghulam Azam are hailed in that way.
After paying tribute to the martyrs of Bangladesh&amp;</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 12:37:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Subodh returns in a new graffiti by elusive artist HOBEKI?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/subodh-returns-in-a-new-graffiti-by-elusive-artist-hobeki</link><description>A new graffiti from the Subodh series has surfaced on the Agargaon Air Force wall, marking the latest intervention by the anonymous street artist HOBEKI?.
The reappearance has drawn attention not only for its timing but also for its location, which holds particular significance in the history of t</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 12:38:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Muhammad Yunus urges protection of Bangladesh’s youth</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/muhammad-yunus-urges-protection-of-bangladeshs-youth</link><description>Chief Advisor Muhammad Yunus has described the recent attack on Sharif Osman bin Hadi, convenor of the Inqilab Moncho, as not merely an assault on an individual but an attack on Bangladesh’s very existence.
Yunus addressed the nation at 6pm on Tuesday, during a Victory Day address, calling f</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 12:53:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat Islam opposed India, not 1971 war: Amir Hamza</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jamaat-islam-opposed-india-not-1971-war-amir-hamza</link><description>Mufti Amir Hamza, Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami–nominated candidate for the Kushtia-3 constituency, on Tuesday claimed that his party was not opposed to the Liberation War of 1971 but was instead against India, saying the real truth had long been suppressed.
“The role of Bangladesh Jamaat</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 13:08:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Army pays tribute to Liberation War martyrs with 31-gun salute</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/army-pays-tribute-to-liberation-war-martyrs-with-31-gun-salute</link><description>The Bangladesh Army marked Victory Day 2025 with a ceremonial 31-gun salute at sunrise to honour the nation’s martyrs who sacrificed their lives in the Liberation War.
At the Old Airport area in Tejgaon, an artillery regiment of the Bangladesh Army fired 31 rounds from six guns to pay tribut</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 13:23:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP finalises preparations for Tarique’s return after 18 years abroad</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bnp-completes-preparations-for-tariques-return-after-18-years-in-exile</link><description>BNP has completed preparations for the residence and offices of its Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman ahead of his return to Bangladesh after nearly 18 years in exile in London.
Party leaders said Tarique, the eldest son of BNP founder Ziaur Rahman and Chairperson Khaleda Zia, will move into house nu</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 13:38:57 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>