<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 17:24:35 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Italian police probe 13 fashion firms over labour abuse</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/italian-police-seek-governance-documents-from-13-fashion-firms-in-labour-abuse-probe</link><description>Italian police on Wednesday visited the headquarters of 13 high-end fashion firms, asking them to hand over documents on governance and supply-chain controls as part of an investigation into alleged worker abuse at fashion subcontractors, judicial documents showed.
The brands that received documen</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 14:45:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Forthcoming national election will be free, fair: Salahuddin Ahmed</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/forthcoming-national-election-will-be-free-fair-salahuddin-ahmed</link><description>BNP Standing Committee member Salahuddin Ahmed today (Thursday) said the upcoming national election will be a decisive one for the country’s history. 
“After 17 long years of democratic movement, struggle and sacrifice, the people will finally be able to exercise their right of vo</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 15:00:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Economists double down on December Fed cut despite policymaker divide</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/global/economists-double-down-on-december-fed-cut-despite-policymaker-divide</link><description>The US Federal Reserve will reduce its key interest rate by a quarter-percentage point at the December 9-10 policy meeting to support a cooling labour market, according to a majority of over 100 economists surveyed by Reuters.
That strong consensus broadly mirrored a November poll and the near-85</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 15:15:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Qatar air ambulance for Khaleda Zia delayed, Zubaida flying in</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/qatar-air-ambulance-for-khaleda-zia-delayed-zubaida-flying-in</link><description>The special air ambulance provided by the Emir of Qatar to transport BNP Chairperson Khaleda Zia to London is expected to be delayed after a “technical issue”, raising the possibility that her departure could slip past 10 am on Friday.
Zubaida Rahman, wife of Khaleda’s son Tariqu</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 15:30:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC clears two new political parties for registration, including Aam Jonotar Dal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ec-clears-two-new-political-parties-for-registration-including-aam-jonotar-dal</link><description>The Election Commission has decided to register two new parties, including the Aam Jonotar Dal, whose general secretary had made headlines in early November by staging a hunger strike demanding his party’s registration.
The second party selected for registration is Jonotar Dal, bdnews24.com</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 15:45:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tea worker killed in BSF firing in Moulvibazar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tea-worker-killed-in-bsf-firing-in-moulvibazar</link><description>The Indian Border Security Force has reportedly killed a Bangladeshi tea worker in Moulvibazar’s Kulaura Upazila.
Kulaura Police Station chief Omar Faruq Mondol confirmed the incident occurred along the border in Muraichhara on Thursday afternoon.
The victim has been identified as Sukhiram</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 15:17:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Experts press for transparent security reform in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/experts-press-for-transparent-security-reform-in-bangladesh</link><description>Speakers at a dialogue in Dhaka have highlighted the importance of ensuring sustained, inclusive and accountable approaches to security sector reform in Bangladesh.
They reaffirmed that effective police reform, democratic oversight, constructive media engagement and the integration of gender and h</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 15:32:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UK universities limit recruitment from Bangladesh, Pakistan, FT reports</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/uk-universities-limit-recruitment-from-bangladesh-pakistan-ft-reports</link><description>At least nine UK universities are restricting or suspending recruitment of students from Bangladesh and Pakistan, the Financial Times reported.
The moves follow tighter UK Home Office rules on student visa refusals, the newspaper said.
Universities including Wolverhampton, Sunderland, Coventry, L</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 15:47:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh’s export receipts decline in November</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladeshs-export-receipts-decline-in-november</link><description>Bangladesh’s export earnings have fallen for four consecutive months, though the cumulative total for the first five months of the fiscal year remains marginally above last year.
The Export Promotion Bureau (EPB) reported on Thursday that the country earned $3.89 billion from exports in Nove</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 16:02:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Berlin deploys fighter jets to Poland after Russian drone incursions</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/berlin-deploys-fighter-jets-to-poland-after-russian-drone-incursions</link><description>Germany has deployed five Eurofighter jets and some 150 military personnel to the Polish town of Malbork to help secure the country's airspace, the German air force said on Thursday, in response to Russian drone incursions in September.
Polish F-16 fighter jets, Dutch F-35s, Italian AWACS surveill</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 16:17:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AI, automation &amp; the future of work in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/ai-automation-the-future-of-work-in-bangladesh</link><description>There come tipping points in the economic life of a nation when small changes will just not be enough anymorea period when the very fabric of working, learning, and adding value is being turned upside down by new technologies that promise revolution rather than evolution. Bangladesh stands at one o</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 16:32:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Healthy soil for a healthy nation: why soil health matters</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/analysis/healthy-soil-for-a-healthy-nation-why-soil-health-matters</link><description>Soil alone contributes significantly to sustaining resilient food, water and energy security. Bangladesh's fertile and sacred soil bears the legacy of historical triumph, cultural pride and agricultural revolution. However, we are careless and cruel to our soil, ignoring its health and dignity. Our</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 16:47:16 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>