<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 06:30:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Flood situation improves in Lalmonirhat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/flood-situation-improves-in-lalmonirhat</link><description>LALMONIRHAT, Oct 07: Flood situation in Lalmonirhat's five upazilas has significantly improved in the last 24 hours to Tuesday as water receded in the Teesta and Dharla river basin areas and also due to no rainfall, or onrush of upstream waters in the greater Rangpur region.
Sources at the Teesta</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 04:12:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ecuador president's motorcade attacked by crowd throwing rocks, five detained</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/ecuador-presidents-motorcade-attacked-by-crowd-throwing-rocks-five-detained</link><description>Ecuadorean President Daniel Noboa escaped injury after his car was attacked by a crowd throwing rocks on Tuesday, in what a top minister said was an assassination attempt that had left signs of bullet damage on the vehicle.
Environment and Energy Minister Ines Manzano, who filed a formal report of</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 04:27:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>All stranded Everest hikers evacuated from remote Tibetan valley</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/all-stranded-everest-hikers-evacuated-from-remote-tibetan-valley</link><description>Rescuers guided all of the remaining trekkers near the east face of Everest in Tibet to safety on Tuesday, including hundreds of local guides and yak herders, authorities said, ending one of the largest search-and-rescue operations in the region.
Hundreds of hikers were stranded in deep snow over</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 04:42:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shahidul Alam kidnapped by Israeli forces</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/shahidul-alam-kidnapped-by-israeli-forces</link><description>Shahidul Alam, a Bangladeshi photographer, writer and managing director of Drik, has been kidnapped by Israeli forces from the Freedom Flotilla Coalition heading to Gaza.
He announced this in a video message on his verified Facebook page on Wednesday (October 8). according to local news reports.&amp;n</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 04:57:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Starmer rules out easing UK visa rules for India</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/starmer-rules-out-easing-uk-visa-rules-for-india</link><description>Keir Starmer has said the UK will not relax visa rules for India, speaking before he arrived in the country to tout the benefits of a recent trade agreement, according to a BBC reprot Wednesday.
The prime minister is leading a delegation of more than 100 entrepreneurs, cultural leaders and univers</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 05:00:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>15 die as landslide in Himachal Pradesh hits bus</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/landslide-in-indias-himachal-pradesh-hits-a-bus-killing-at-least-15-people</link><description>At least 15 people were killed late Tuesday after debris from a massive landslide hit a bus in India’s northern state of Himachal Pradesh, local authorities said.
The bus was traveling on a hilly stretch near Bilaspur district when a landslide struck following days of torrential rains. There</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 05:30:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh Bank warns public over unlicensed ‘Shohoz Cash’ platform</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-bank-warns-public-over-unlicensed-shohoz-cash-platform</link><description>Bangladesh’s central bank has warned the public against dealing with a company called "Shohoz Cash Ltd", saying it has not issued any mobile financial services (MFS) licence to the firm.
In a statement on Tuesday, the central bank said Shohoz Cash was not authorised to provide mobile banking</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 06:15:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Death toll climbs to 15 after landslide hits bus in India's Himachal Pradesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/death-toll-climbs-to-15-after-landslide-hits-bus-in-indias-himachal-pradesh</link><description>The death toll from a landslide that struck a private bus in India's mountainous state of Himachal Pradesh has risen to 15, with one child still missing, officials and police said on Wednesday.
Two children were injured in the incident, which took place on Tuesday evening, National Disaster Respon</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 06:30:02 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>