<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 13:32:33 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Trust Bank inaugurates new branch at Jolshiri Abashon Area</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/trust-bank-inaugurates-new-branch-at-jolshiri-abashon-area</link><description>Trust Bank PLC has officially inaugurated its new branch “Jolshiri Branch” at the Jolshiri Abashon Area in Rupganj, Narayanganj.
The Chairman of Trust Bank PLC and Chief of Army Staff, General Waker-uz-Zaman, SBP, OSP, SGP, psc, graced the occasion as the Chief Guest and inaugurated th</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 10:47:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Citing Biblical story, Taiwan president says Israel a model for island's defence</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/citing-biblical-story-taiwan-president-says-israel-a-model-for-islands-defence</link><description>Israel is a model for Taiwan to learn from in strengthening its defences, President Lai Ching-te said in remarks released on Tuesday, citing the Biblical story of David versus Goliath on the need to stand up to authoritarianism.
Taiwan has been a strong backer of Israel since the 2023 Hamas-led at</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 11:02:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Iyer recovering well from spleen injury, says India's Suryakumar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/iyer-recovering-well-from-spleen-injury-says-indias-suryakumar</link><description>India batsman Shreyas Iyer is in stable condition and recovering well from a spleen injury, Twenty20 captain Suryakumar Yadav said on Tuesday.
Iyer suffered a lacerated spleen during India's victory over Australia in the third one-day international on Saturday when he fell awkwardly in taking a ca</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 11:17:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bayern target Cup win at Cologne to extend perfect start</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/football/bayern-target-cup-win-at-cologne-to-extend-perfect-start</link><description>Bayern Munich are doing a lot of things right to carve out a 13-match winning run across all competitions this season, and will need to carry that momentum into Wednesday's German Cup second round at Cologne, coach Vincent Kompany said on Tuesday.
Bayern made it 13 wins from 13 matches across all</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 11:32:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Registration for class XI begins November 2</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/registration-for-class-xi-begins-november-2</link><description>Registration of students for admission into class XI through online for the 2025-2026 academic year will begin on November 2 and will continue until 5 pm on November 16.
The decision was taken in a meeting of Bangladesh Inter-Education Board Coordination Committee.
A letter in this regard was sen</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 11:47:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Immediate formation of 10th wage board demanded</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/immediate-formation-of-10th-wage-board-demanded</link><description>Leaders of Bangladesh Sangbadpathro Karmachari Federation (BSKF) and Bangladesh Federal Union of Newspaper Press Workers (BFUNPW) have demanded formation of the 10th wage board immediately for journalists, newspaper employees and workers.
The leaders of the two organisations made the call today wh</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 12:02:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Madagascar's military-led government names mostly civilian cabinet</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/africa/madagascars-military-led-government-names-mostly-civilian-cabinet</link><description>Madagascar's military-led government, which seized power this month, appointed a cabinet on Tuesday of mostly civilian ministers, including some prominent critics of ousted president Andry Rajoelina.
The appointments mark a key moment in Madagascar's political turmoil as the military consolidates</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 12:17:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ADB urges inclusive long-term elder care framework in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/adb-urges-inclusive-long-term-elder-care-framework-in-bangladesh</link><description>With Bangladesh’s population ageing rapidly, policymakers, development partners, and civil society representatives have come together to chart a roadmap for a sustainable long-term care (LTC) system for older persons.
The initiative was highlighted at a high-level seminar in Dhaka on Tuesday</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 12:32:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>OpenAI to offer ChatGPT Go free for a year in India</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/openai-to-offer-chatgpt-go-free-for-a-year-in-india</link><description>OpenAI will offer its ChatGPT Go subscription free to users in India for one year starting November 4, the Microsoft- (MSFT.O) backed startup said on Tuesday, as it seeks to boost adoption in its second-largest market.
The plan, which was first launched in India in August, is OpenAI's most afforda</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 12:47:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Swechchasebak Dal leader killed over kabadi dispute</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/swechchasebak-dal-leader-killed-over-kabadi-dispute</link><description>A union-level leader of Swechchasebak Dal, the voluntary wing of BNP, has been killed in an attack allegedly by his rivals over a kabadi game in Kalia upazila of Narail district.
The deceased was identified as Masud Sheikh, 46, member secretary of Babra-Hachla Union unit of the party and son of la</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 13:17:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shareholders applaud 175pc cash dividend at Walton Hi-Tech’s 19th AGM</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/shareholders-applaud-175pc-cash-dividend-at-walton-hi-techs-19th-agm</link><description>With the presence of large number of institutional and general shareholders, the 19th Annual General Meeting (AGM) of Walton Hi-Tech Industries PLC (WHILPLC), country's superbrand and tech giant listed in capital market, was successfully held on Tuesday (28 October, 2024) at Kurmitola Golf Club in</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 13:32:33 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>