<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 22:21:06 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>100 rooms of a colony burned to ashes in Gazipur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/100-rooms-of-a-colony-burned-to-ashes-in-gazipur</link><description>At least 100 rooms of a tin shed colony were destroyed in a massive fire that broke out in the Jorun area of Konabari in Gazipur.
The fire started at 5 pm on Wednesday in a room of the colony and quickly spread to the surrounding rooms. Initially, locals tried to extinguish the fire, but as it int</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 15:42:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India resumes business visas for Bangladeshis, Pranay Verma says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/india-resumes-business-visas-for-bangladeshis-pranay-verma-says</link><description>India has again started issuing business visas for Bangladeshi nationals, the Indian high commissioner in Dhaka has said.
Applications are being handled on a fast-track basis in emergencies, Pranay Kumar Verma said while speaking at an event titled “Pharma Connect” in Dhaka’s Bar</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 15:57:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>South Korean ferry with 267 on board runs aground, rescue underway</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/south-korean-ferry-with-267-on-board-runs-aground-rescue-underway</link><description>A South Korean passenger ferry carrying 267 passengers and crew ran aground on Wednesday off the southwestern tip of the Korean peninsula, triggering a rescue operation and stirring memories of a major ferry disaster in 2014.
President Lee Jae Myung, who is currently travelling in the Middle East,</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 16:12:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Returning officers should be Commission officials, not district administration: Moyeen Khan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/returning-officers-should-be-commission-officials-not-district-administration-moyeen-khan</link><description>BNP Standing Committee Member Dr Abdul Moyeen Khan today said the Election Commission (EC) should appoint its own officials as returning officers for the upcoming 13th National Parliament Election instead of relying on the district administration.
"If returning officers and assistant returning off</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 16:27:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat, allies to hold rallies in 7 divisional cities; demanding referendum before election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-allies-to-hold-rallies-in-7-divisional-cities-demanding-referendum-before-election</link><description>Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami, along with seven other political parties, on Wednesday, has reaffirmed its demand for a referendum before national elections and announced a series of rallies in divisional cities across the country.
The parties said they will organize rallies from November 30 to Decemb</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 16:43:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gold prices make big jump after two rounds of cuts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/gold-prices-make-big-jump-after-two-rounds-of-cuts</link><description>After two consecutive reductions, gold prices in the domestic market have surged again, with the Bangladesh Jewellers Association (BAJUS) raising the rate by Tk 2,612 per bhori for 22-carat gold.
The new price has been set at Tk 209,520 per bhori, effective from Thursday, UNB reports. 
BAJUS</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 16:58:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pallabi Jubo Dal leader murder: Two top suspects including alleged mastermind ‘Patha Sohel’ arrested</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/pallabi-jubo-dal-leader-murder-two-top-suspects-including-alleged-mastermind-patha-sohel-arrested</link><description>The Rapid Action Battalion (RAB-4) has arrested two top suspects in the murder of Golam Kibria (50), member secretary of the Jubo Dal’s Pallabi unit.
The arrestees are the alleged mastermind and planner of the killing, Md Monir Hossain alias Sohel alias Pata Sohel (30), and Md Sujon alias Bu</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 17:13:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka Central University draft ordinance being revised as first intake set for classes on Sunday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/dhaka-central-university-draft-ordinance-being-revised-as-first-intake-set-for-classes-on-sunday</link><description>Education authorities are reassessing and refining the draft ordinance for the proposed Dhaka Central University, which is to be formed with seven government colleges in the capital after their affiliation with Dhaka University was cancelled.
On Wednesday, officials said the draft is being revised</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 17:28:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Crude bomb explosions wound policeman in Pallabi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/crude-bomb-explosions-wound-policeman-in-pallabi</link><description>A policeman has been injured in crude bomb explosions in Pallabi.
Police said the blasts occurred around 8:30pm near a Trust Bank booth between Pallabi Police Station and the Army Camp, bdnews24.com reports.
ASI Nurul Islam was wounded and treated at a local hospital, according to Mohammad Maksud</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 17:45:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Foreign operators, personnel getting 10-year tax holiday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/foreign-operators-personnel-getting-10-year-tax-holiday</link><description>Two foreign operating companies investing in Bangladesh's Laldia and Pangaon container terminals to handle seaborne cargoes are receiving 10-year tax holiday, the revenue authority unveils government decision on just-signed deals.



Also, foreign technical personnel working in these terminals</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 18:00:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>What's holding back growth of cashless transactions?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/whats-holding-back-growth-of-cashless-transactions</link><description>Digital financial transactions have increased by leaps and bounds over the past decade in Bangladesh, primarily driven by the impressive growth in the number of Mobile Financial Service (MFS) users. Estimates suggest that there are now more than 90 million active MFS users in the country, collectiv</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 18:15:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Import of rice alone can't stabilise market</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/import-of-rice-alone-cant-stabilise-market</link><description>Bangladesh's drive to build a substantial stock of rice to meet any contingency appears, on the face of it, to be quite logical. When the market is jittery despite a highly satisfactory boro--- the number one grain--- harvest, the government allowed 242 private traders to import rice. Now that Asia</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 18:30:44 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>