<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 14:15:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>National Bank strengthens regional focus with “Managers Meet” in Khulna</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/national-bank-strengthens-regional-focus-with-managers-meet-in-khulna</link><description>National Bank PLC convened its “Managers Meet” in Khulna on October 16, 2025, uniting 23 branch managers from the region to evaluate performance, share insights, and chart the course for the bank’s continued growth and innovation.
The session was graced by Adil Chowdhury, Managin</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 11:31:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bank Asia wins prestigious WSBI SDG Award 2025 in Washington, D.C.</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bank-asia-wins-prestigious-wsbi-sdg-award-2025-in-washington-dc</link><description>Bank Asia PLC has been honored with the WSBI SDG Award 2025 in recognition of its outstanding contribution to advancing the United Nations Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs).
The bank received accolades across five key categories — Inclusive Banking and Social Impact, Economic Growth and E</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 11:46:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka University again restricts vehicle entry during weekends and holidays</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dhaka-university-again-restricts-vehicle-entry-during-weekends-and-holidays</link><description>Dhaka University authorities have decided to restrict vehicle entry to the campus from 3pm to 10pm on weekends and public holidays to ensure the safety of students.
In a statement issued on Saturday, the university’s Proctor’s Office announced that vehicle movement control within the c</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 12:01:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BRAC Bank partners with TK Group for enhanced digital cash management solutions</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/brac-bank-partners-with-tk-group-for-enhanced-digital-cash-management-solutions</link><description>BRAC Bank and TK Group have entered into a Transaction Banking Agreement to implement an advanced dealer collection solution through Virtual Accounts, marking a significant step forward in digitising corporate cash management in Bangladesh.
Under this partnership, BRAC Bank will provide an automat</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 12:16:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Moyeen Khan stresses engaging educated youths in development activities</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/moyeen-khan-stresses-engaging-educated-youths-in-development-activities</link><description>BNP senior leader Dr Abdul Moyeen Khan on Saturday stressed the need for turning the educated youth into a productive workforce, saying that no development plan can succeed without involving people in the country’s progress.
“Practical steps must be taken to prepare the educated popula</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 12:31:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Global film industry shrugs off renewed Trump movie tariff threat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/entertainment/global-film-industry-shrugs-off-renewed-trump-movie-tariff-threat</link><description>"Star Wars: Starfighter" is filming in Britain, soundstages in Hungary are packed and post-production houses in Australia are humming, as the global film industry keeps rolling despite US President Donald Trump's renewed threats to impose tariffs on movies made outside of the United States.
Trump</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 12:46:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fire rages for hours at Dhaka airport’s cargo village</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fire-rages-for-hours-at-dhaka-airports-cargo-village</link><description>A major fire has been burning for more three and a half hours at the cargo village of Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport in Dhaka, officials say.
The blaze began around 2:30pm on Saturday. Firefighters arrived soon after being alerted. As the flames spread, more units joined the operation.
By</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 12:47:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Election schedule to be unveiled in early December: CEC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/election-schedule-to-be-unveiled-in-early-december-cec</link><description>The schedule for the 13th national parliamentary election will be announced in the first week of December, Chief Election Commissioner (CEC) AMM Nasir Uddin said on Saturday.
"The Election Commission is committed to ensuring a free, fair and impartial election, overcoming all kinds of challenges,"</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 13:02:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka seeks China’s support in clean energy push</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/dhaka-seeks-chinas-support-in-clean-energy-push</link><description>Speakers at a workshop on Saturday called on China to enhance its sustainable investments and technological support to accelerate Bangladesh’s economic growth.
They urged the Asian economic powerhouse to expand financial and technical assistance in areas such as clean air initiatives, improv</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 13:32:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique Rahman calls on BNP to focus on serving people</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-rahman-calls-on-bnp-to-focus-on-serving-people</link><description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman on Saturday urged his party leaders and activists to dedicate themselves to serving the people, saying it should be the guiding principle of the party’s future politics.
“Let us transform ourselves today. Let every BNP leader and activist take a firm</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 13:47:31 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>