<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 12:48:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Trump says US will intervene if Iran violently suppresses peaceful protests</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-says-us-will-intervene-if-iran-violently-suppresses-peaceful-protests</link><description>US President Donald Trump on Friday said that if Iran shoots and violently kills peaceful protesters, the United States of America will come to their rescue.
"We are locked and loaded and ready to go," he said in a Truth Social post.
This follows the deaths of several people as Iran's biggest pro</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 10:00:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Renowned rhymester Sukumar Barua dies at 87</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/sukumar-barua-whose-rhymes-shaped-the-childhoods-of-generations-dies-at-87</link><description>Celebrated rhymester Sukumar Barua has died under hospital care at the age of 87.
He passed away at 6:55am on Friday at a private hospital in Gahira of Chattogram’s Raozan Upazila.
His son, Arup Ratan Barua, said Sukumar had been suffering from age-related illnesses for some time.
“T</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 10:15:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Condolence book opened at Bangladesh Embassy in Tokyo for Khaleda Zia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/condolence-book-opened-at-bangladesh-embassy-in-tokyo-for-khaleda-zia</link><description>The Embassy of Bangladesh in Tokyo on Friday opened a condolence book to pay tribute to former Prime Minister and Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) Chairperson Begum Khaleda Zia following her demise.
Representatives of various foreign diplomatic missions based in Japan visited the embassy and sig</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 10:30:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two sisters found dead under fallen tree in Gaibandha</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/two-sisters-found-dead-under-fallen-tree-in-gaibandha</link><description>The bodies of two young sisters who had earlier been reported missing have been found under a recently felled tree in Gaibandha Sadar Upazila.
The children’s bodies were discovered on Thursday evening in Khamar Raghunathpur village of Ballamjhar Union, according to bdnews24.com.
Police id</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 10:45:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pakistan court sentences journalists to life over links to protests after Imran Khan’s arrest</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/pakistan-court-sentences-journalists-to-life-over-links-to-protests-after-imran-khans-arrest</link><description>A Pakistani anti-terrorism court sentenced eight journalists and social media commentators on Friday to life imprisonment in absentia after convicting them of terrorism-related offences linked to online activity in support of jailed former prime minister Imran Khan.
The convictions stem from cases</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 11:00:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>GM Quader’s income falls, but cash holdings increase</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jatiya-party-leader-gm-quaders-income-falls-but-cash-holdings-increase</link><description>Jatiya Party Chairman GM Quader’s income over the past two years has declined but his cash holdings and overall assets appear to have increased based on the prospective candidate for the Rangpur-3 constituency’s latest wealth declaration.
A comparison of affidavits submitted ahead of t</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 11:15:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sterling struggles for direction on first trading day of 2026</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/sterling-struggles-for-direction-on-first-trading-day-of-2026</link><description>The British pound was little changed against both the dollar and euro on Friday, with little news to drive the currency either way as 2026 gets off to a slow start.
Sterling was last trading at $1.3447 versus the dollar , down slightly from a three-month high of $1.3533 it hit last week. Against t</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 11:01:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>London's FTSE 100 starts New Year with 10,000 mark on global investor optimism</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/londons-ftse-100-starts-new-year-with-10000-mark-on-global-investor-optimism</link><description>The UK's FTSE 100 flew past the 10,000 points mark for the first time on Friday, riding a wave of upbeat investor sentiment across global markets on the first trading session of 2026.
The blue-chip FTSE 100 (.FTSE) rose 0.5 per cent by 1023 GMT, after marking its strongest yearly performance in 16</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 11:16:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UK factories pick up a bit of speed but outlook worries remain</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/uk-factories-pick-up-a-bit-of-speed-but-outlook-worries-remain</link><description>Britain's factory sector grew at its fastest pace in 15 months in December, though by less than previously thought, while confidence dipped despite some relief over finance minister Rachel Reeves' budget, a survey showed on Friday.
The S&amp;amp;P Global Purchasing Managers' Index for manufacturing rose t</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 11:31:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>European factory activity ends 2025 in deeper contraction but Asia shines on improved demand</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/european-factory-activity-ends-2025-in-deeper-contraction-but-asia-shines-on-improved-demand</link><description>Euro zone manufacturing activity shrank further in December but Asia's factory powerhouses closed 2025 on a firmer footing backed by a rebound in export orders and growing demand for artificial intelligence, private surveys showed.
Factory activity in the common currency bloc slid into deeper cont</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 11:46:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nagorik Oikko chief Manna's Bogura-2 nomination papers rejected</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/nagorik-oikko-chief-mannas-bogura-2-nomination-papers-rejected</link><description>Election officials have rejected the nomination papers of Nagorik Oikko President Mahmudur Rahman Manna, a prospective candidate for the Bogura-2 (Shibganj) constituency in the upcoming national polls.
Returning Officer Toufiqur Rahman declared the nomination invalid on Friday, citing discrepancie</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 12:01:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Saki’s wife owns more than double his wealth</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ganosamhati-leader-zonayed-sakis-wife-owns-more-than-double-his-wealth</link><description>Zonayed Saki, chief coordinator of the Ganosamhati Andolon, has declared assets worth less than half of those owned by his wife, according to an affidavit filed with his nomination papers for Bangladesh’s upcoming 13th national parliamentary election.
Saki entered the race for parliamentary</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 12:16:34 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>