<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 23:24:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Rajshahi Warriors clinch BPL title</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/cricket/rajshahi-warriors-clinch-bpl-title</link><description>Rajshahi Warriors clinched the Bangladesh Premier League (BPL) title, beating Chattogram Royals by 63 runs, in the final match of the tournament on Friday.
The final was played at Sher-e-Bangla National Cricket Stadium in Mirpur, with Chattogram opting to field first after winning the toss in the</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 16:00:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique hears voters’ pleas at first Dhaka rally</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-rahman-hears-voters-concerns-at-first-dhaka-rally-promises-solutions</link><description>BNP Chairperson Tarique Rahman has listened directly to voters’ problems and expectations after calling residents onto the stage at the first election rally in his Dhaka constituency, pledging to address their concerns if elected.
He attended the public meeting on Friday in Bhashantek of Dha</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 16:30:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EU to suspend €93bn retaliatory trade package against US for 6 months</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/eu-to-suspend-eur93bn-retaliatory-trade-package-against-us-for-6-months</link><description>The European Commission said on Friday it would propose suspending for another six months an EU package of retaliatory trade measures against the US worth 93 billion euros ($109.19 billion) that would otherwise kick in on Feb 7.
The package, prepared in the first half of last year when the Europea</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 16:45:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>People will vote to reject corrupt candidates: Hasnat Abdullah</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/people-will-vote-to-reject-corrupt-candidates-hasnat-abdullah</link><description>Hasnat Abdullah, the 10-party alliance candidate for Cumilla-4 (Debidwar) and chief organiser (south) of the National Citizen Party (NCP), on Friday said the people would reject corrupt candidates through the ballot.
Speaking at several street rallies during door-to-door campaigning on the second</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 17:00:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Global fertility divide</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/global-fertility-divide</link><description>The world is entering a period of demographic divide that few policymakers are prepared to confront openly. Over the past seven decades, global fertility rates have fallen by more than half. Today, more than half of all countries—including every advanced economy, and a growing number of middl</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 16:30:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Importance of training for banks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/reviews/importance-of-training-for-banks</link><description>Every year, National Training Day in Bangladesh is observed on January 23. This year, Bangladesh observed the 30th anniversary to emphasise the importance of training for human resource development, skill enhancement, and economic growth. Over the years, Bangladesh Institute of Bank Management (BIB</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 16:45:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Can election ensure a smooth political transition?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/can-election-ensure-a-smooth-political-transition</link><description>With the national election set to take place within three weeks, political parties have started their campaigns. The campaign will intensify as election will be closer. Unlike the previous three elections, which were marked by manipulation and irregularities, the February 12 election is expected to</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 17:00:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dollar dependence vs economic power politics</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/dollar-dependence-vs-economic-power-politics</link><description>The global economy is entering another uncertain chapter as many long-held assumptions about trade and growth lose their footing. Bangladesh is arriving at this moment after years of relying on a familiar economic formula centred around remittances and garment exports. Those two pillars kept foreig</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 17:15:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt employees' pay hike and economic challenges</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/govt-employees-pay-hike-and-economic-challenges</link><description>The Ninth National Pay Commission report, as submitted on Wednesday (January 21), is learnt to have recommended a sweeping hike in the basic salaries of government servants. Evidently, implementation of this new pay structure is going to cost the state exchequer a humongous sum of additional Tk 1.0</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 17:30:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fakhrul warns Jamaat-e-Islami poses ‘threat’ to Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fakhrul-warns-jamaat-e-islami-poses-threat-to-bangladesh</link><description>BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir has described Jamaat-e-Islami, a force that opposed the 1971 Liberation War, as a threat to the nation's safety.
He believes that the country cannot be secure in the hands of those who originally did not want the birth of Bangladesh.
Speaking at a</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 17:45:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat alleges election code violations in eight districts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jamaat-alleges-election-code-violations-in-eight-districts</link><description>Jamaat-e-Islami has alleged that the electoral code of conduct has been violated in eight districts during election campaigning.
The party said the incidents occurred between Thursday, when campaigning officially began, and Friday afternoon.
At a press conference on Friday evening, party spokespe</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 18:00:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BB seeks authority to override law, waive banks' CRR penalties</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bb-seeks-authority-to-override-law-waive-banks-crr-penalties</link><description>Bangladesh Bank moves to bolster its regulatory authority to waive, remit, or reduce penalties for banks' Cash Reserve Ratio (CRR) shortfalls in special circumstances as the central bank oversees the largest bank-consolidation effort in nation's history.



To this end, sources say, the central</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 19:26:23 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>