<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 03:12:34 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Some 4,000 expats register on first day to vote in next election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/some-4000-expats-register-on-first-day-to-vote-in-next-election</link><description>Over 4,000 expatriate Bangladeshis registered on Thursday, the first day of the “Postal Vote BD” app launched by the Election Commission in a bid to allow more Bangladeshis residing abroad to participate in the upcoming national election.
As of 7:30 pm on Thursday, a total of 4,026 vot</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 15:45:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Unpacking emotional costs of remittance narrative</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/unpacking-emotional-costs-of-remittance-narrative</link><description>Labour migration has become one of Bangladesh's most celebrated development narratives. Over the decades, millions of Bangladeshis have travelled to the Gulf, Southeast Asia, Europe, and beyond, sending home remittances that sustain households and stabilise the national economy. These flows of mone</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 16:00:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Police, RAB launch crackdown to make Raozan ‘terror-free’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/police-rab-launch-crackdown-to-make-raozan-terror-free</link><description>Eight light guns (LG), along with local weapons and ammunition have been recovered in a special joint drive conducted by police and RAB members in Chattogram’s Raozan.
No arrests have been reported until now.
The drive, conducted on the early hours of Thursday across different locations in</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 16:15:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Should government still be in business?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/should-government-still-be-in-business</link><description>At a recent roundtable on business climate organised by The Financial Express, the vice chairman of the Export Promotion Bureau has posed a pertinent question: should the government be doing business at all? The question is as old as the state-owned enterprises themselves and is more relevant today</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 16:30:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hunger and food insecurity stare in the face of world</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/hunger-and-food-insecurity-stare-in-the-face-of-world</link><description>Reports on hunger and food insecurity are unnerving. The 2025 state of food security and nutrition in the world (SOFI) report finds that 673 million people constituting 8.3 per cent of the global population faced acute hunger in 2024. The SOFI is an annual publication by five important United Natio</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 16:45:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Labour ordinance goes past tripartite agreement</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/labour-ordinance-goes-past-tripartite-agreement</link><description>The interim government's amendment of the labour law, despite objections raised by business groups during the draft stage, has triggered fresh protests demanding its withdrawal. Opponents argue that some key provisions deviate from the understandings reached earlier in tripartite meetings involving</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 17:00:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tofail Ahmed‘s wife passes away</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tofail-ahmeds-wife-passes-away</link><description>Anwara Begum, wife of veteran Awami League politician, Advisory Council member, and former Commerce Minister Tofail Ahmed, has passed away.
She died on Thursday at 6:21 pm while undergoing treatment due to age-related complications at Square Hospital in Dhaka.
Tofail Ahmed’s personal assist</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 19:02:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Caretaker govt revives, with prospective effect</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/caretaker-govt-revives-with-prospective-effect</link><description>Election-time neutral caretaker government revives, with prospective effect, in a reversal of a previous Supreme Court verdict contentiously rescinding the system under the then divisive political circumstances.



The resurrected system of neutral government of 90-day tenure stays in animate</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 19:17:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh begins gap analysis to fit in RCEP trade standards</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladesh-begins-gap-analysis-to-fit-in-rcep-trade-standards</link><description>Bangladesh begins a critical gap analysis of its economic strengths for aligning its trade policies with protocols of the Regional Comprehensive Economic Partnership (RCEP) for joining the world's largest trade bloc.
The comprehensive analysis aims to assess where Bangladesh currently stands in co</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 02:15:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>First finance secretary Matiul Islam dies</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/first-finance-secretary-matiul-islam-dies</link><description>M Matiul Islam, the country's first finance secretary and a pioneering figure in the financial and banking sector, passed away early Thursday at the age of 95.
His namaz-e-janaza will be held at Azad Mosque in Gulshan after Jumma prayers today (Friday), his family said.
Born on January 24, 1930 i</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 02:30:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Risk-Based Supervision: BB asks banks to get ready ahead of January roll-out</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/risk-based-supervision-bb-asks-banks-to-get-ready-ahead-of-january-roll-out</link><description>The Bangladesh Bank (BB) plans to implement risk-based supervision (RBS) from January 2026 and has asked the country's commercial banks to take necessary measures in this regard.
As part of the shift from the decades-old compliance-based inspections, the central bankers concerned held a meeting wi</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 02:45:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Slow ADP spending drags development progress</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/slow-adp-spending-drags-development-progress</link><description>Development activities remain in disarray as government ministries and agencies struggle to recover from last year's disruptions caused by the July uprising, officials said on Thursday.
The sluggish execution of development projects has persisted into the first four months of the current fiscal ye</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 03:00:49 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>