<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 07:21:46 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Bus owners mull co-based services amid decision to halt BRT project</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bus-owners-mull-co-based-services-amid-decision-to-halt-brt-project</link><description>Taking advantage of the government's decision to discontinue the BRT project on Gazipur-Airport route, bus owners want to operate company-managed bus services using the dedicated bus corridor.
The National Bus Owners Association of Bangladesh (NBOAB) in a letter to the Chairman of Bangladesh Bus R</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 04:15:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ACC summons docs on EBL chairman Showkat, family</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/acc-summons-docs-on-ebl-chairman-showkat-family</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) has summoned detailed information from Eastern Bank PLC Chairman Md Showkat Ali Chowdhury and his family on their financial transactions, national identity documents, tax records, and other relevant papers as part of its investigation into allegations of irregul</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 04:30:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>RAB arrests two more 'top criminals' over Jubo Dal leader's murder</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rab-arrests-two-more-top-criminals-over-jubo-dal-leaders-murder</link><description>The Rapid Action Battalion (RAB) arrested two more "top criminals" in the capital in connection with the murder of Golam Kibria, the member secretary of the Jubo Dal's Pallabi Thana unit.
RAB-4 official Major Abrar Faisal Sadi said the arrestees are top criminals and alleged masterminds of the mur</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 04:45:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ACC launches probe into Tk 3.32b loss to state for purchasing Rose Garden</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/acc-launches-probe-into-tk-332b-loss-to-state-for-purchasing-rose-garden</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) has launched an investigation into the allegations that the state incurred a loss of Tk 3.32 billion in the name of purchasing the historic Rose Garden, known as the 'birthplace' of the Awami League (AL).
Anyone found involved in irregularities during the inqui</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 05:00:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh can't progress without women’s safety online and offline: Tarique Rahman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bangladesh-cant-progress-without-womens-safety-online-and-offline-tarique-rahman</link><description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman on Thursday said Bangladesh cannot move forward unless women feel safe both online and offline, calling for urgent national action to protect and empower women in the digital age.
“Women must feel safe. Both online and offline, at home and in public, in the</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 05:15:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump signs bill approving Epstein files release</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-signs-bill-approving-epstein-files-release</link><description>US President Donald Trump signed legislation on Wednesday ordering the Justice Department to release documents from its long-running investigation into sex offender Jeffrey Epstein — files eagerly sought by both his political opponents and members of his own base who have pressed for greater</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 05:30:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cambodia releases rare captive-bred storks in conservation breakthrough</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/cambodia-releases-rare-captive-bred-storks-in-conservation-breakthrough</link><description>Conservationists in Cambodia have for the first time released two captive-bred Greater Adjutant Stork chicks into the wild as part of an ongoing programme to revive a species under threat from poaching and habitat loss.
The nine-month-old storks - a male and a female - were fitted with GPS tracker</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 05:45:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Caretaker government key to fair elections: Amir Khosru</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/caretaker-government-key-to-fair-elections-amir-khosru</link><description>BNP Standing Committee Member Amir Khosru Mahmud Chowdhury on Thursday said that only a caretaker government can ensure a free and fair national election, welcoming the restoration of the system as a positive development.
Speaking to reporters after an event at Dhaka University on Thursday morning</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 06:00:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>World's richest nations are pulling back from global development efforts: Study</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/worlds-richest-nations-are-pulling-back-from-global-development-efforts-study-shows</link><description>Two dozen of the world's richest nations, including the United States and Japan, are pulling back from their global development push, a study published on Thursday, opens new tab shows, with many slashing aid budgets and cash funnelled through multilateral lenders.
The Commitment to Development In</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 06:15:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bomb explodes outside ex-home minister’s Dhanmondi residence</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bomb-explodes-outside-ex-home-ministers-dhanmondi-residence</link><description>A crude bomb has exploded in front of former home minister Asaduzzaman Khan Kamal’s residence on Dhanmondi Road No. 5 in Dhaka.
Police confirmed the incident occurred shortly after 12:30 am on Thursday at the main gate of the house.
Sub-Inspector Md Shahjalal of Dhanmondi Police Station tol</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 06:30:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Indonesia evacuates stranded climbers after Semeru volcano erupts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/indonesia-evacuates-stranded-climbers-after-semeru-volcano-erupts</link><description>Indonesian authorities evacuated more than 900 people and were facilitating the safe return on Thursday of 170 climbers stranded after the eruption of its Semeru volcano, one of the country's tallest mountains.
The alert level was maintained at its highest after Semeru on Java island erupted 10 ti</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 06:45:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Youth ‘commits suicide’ in Dhaka’s Hazaribagh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/youth-commits-suicide-in-dhakas-hazaribagh</link><description>A 25-year-old youth was found dead after allegedly hanging himself from a ceiling fan at his residence in Hazaribagh of Dhaka on Thursday.
The deceased was identified as Md Nazmul, son of Abul Bashar of Barguna Sadar upazila. He had been living with his family at a rented house in the Vaucher area</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 07:00:25 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>