<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 12:49:33 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Deer poacher held with 32 kgs of deer venison, trap in Bagerhat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/deer-poacher-held-with-32-kgs-of-deer-venison-trap-in-bagerhat</link><description>Members of Coast Guard in a drive arrested a deer poacher along with two deer heads, 32 kgs of venison, eight deer legs and 2000 metres of deer-hunting traps from a house at Kanainagar in Mongla upazila of Bagerhat district early Wednesday.
The arrestee was identified as Akter Biswas, 40, a member</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 10:14:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka expects answer from Delhi on Hasina’s extradition: Foreign Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dhaka-expects-answer-from-delhi-on-hasinas-extradition-foreign-adviser</link><description>Foreign Affairs Adviser Md Touhid Hossain on Wednesday said Bangladesh expects an answer from India on its latest request for extradition of convicted former Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina.
“I do not expect that they will answer within a week of Dhaka’s request but we expect we will get</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 10:29:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India protests China’s detention of citizen at Shanghai airport</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/india-protests-chinas-detention-of-citizen-at-shanghai-airport</link><description>India on Tuesday protested to China over what it described as the “arbitrary detention” of an Indian citizen at Shanghai airport, after Chinese authorities reportedly refused to recognize her passport.
The woman, Pem Wang Thongdok from the northeastern state of Arunachal Pradesh, was s</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 10:44:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two more Baul artistes injured in attack in Thakurgaon</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/two-more-baul-artistes-injured-in-attack-in-thakurgaon</link><description>At least two Baul artistes were injured in an attack ahead of a protest against the repression of Bauls and the arrest of Baul artiste Abul Sarkar.
The incident took place on Wednesday afternoon on the premises of the Thakurgaon court, said Thakurgaon Sadar Police chief Sarwar Alam Khan.
Sarwar s</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 10:59:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Police block teachers’ march towards Jamuna</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/police-block-teachers-march-towards-jamuna-demanding-mpo-inclusion</link><description>Police have blocked a teachers’ march towards the State Guest House Jamuna, the official residence of the chief advisor, demanding the inclusion of all recognised non-MPO educational institutions under the government’s monthly payment scheme.
The teachers, who have been holding a sit-i</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 11:14:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Onion imports withheld to protect farmers: Agriculture Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/onion-imports-withheld-to-protect-farmers-agriculture-adviser</link><description>Agriculture Adviser Lieutenant General (retd.) Md Jahangir Alam Chowdhury on Wednesday said the government has not allowed onion imports in order to protect local farmers.
“There is no onion crisis. Prices rose to Tk 120–130 earlier, but they have now come down to around Tk 95–10</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 10:46:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EBL sets new industry benchmark with 100 Structured Finance Deals</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ebl-sets-new-industry-benchmark-with-100-structured-finance-deals</link><description>Eastern Bank PLC (EBL) has reached a major milestone as its Structured Finance Unit successfully closed its 100th deal in September 2025.
Total arranged deals surpassed BDT 260 billion, including USD 887 million in foreign currency financing, according to a press release.
Speaking on the occasion</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 11:01:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Seize tax records of Benazir’s wife, daughter and Harun: Court</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/court-orders-seizure-of-tax-records-of-benazirs-wife-daughter-and-harun</link><description>A court has ordered the seizure of the income tax records of former police chief Benazir Ahmed’s wife, Zeeshan Mirza, and daughter, Tahsin Raisa Binte Benazir.
The court has also ordered the seizure of the tax documents of former chief of detective police Mohammad Harunor Rashid.
Dhaka Metr</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 11:16:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Man changes pleas to guilty over Liverpool soccer parade incident</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/football/man-changes-pleas-to-guilty-over-liverpool-soccer-parade-incident</link><description>A British man on Wednesday pleaded guilty to criminal charges over the incident in which a car ploughed into a crowd of Liverpool soccer fans during May's Premier League title victory parade.
Paul Doyle, 53, sobbed in the dock at Liverpool Crown Court as he changed his pleas to guilty, having plea</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 11:31:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Paris court: Hearing on request for Shein's suspension in France postponed to Dec 5</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/paris-court-hearing-on-request-for-sheins-suspension-in-france-postponed-to-dec-5</link><description>The hearing on the French government's request that Chinese online platform Shein be suspended in France for three months over sales of childlike sex dolls and banned weapons, has been postponed to December 5, a Paris court said on Wednesday.
Shein has already disabled its marketplace - where thir</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 11:46:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Russia says its proposals on New START arms treaty are intended to prevent negative global scenarios</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/russia-says-its-proposals-on-new-start-arms-treaty-are-intended-to-prevent-negative-global-scenarios</link><description>Russian Deputy Foreign Minister Sergei Ryabkov said on Wednesday that Moscow's proposals regarding the New START nuclear arms control treaty are designed to prevent negative global scenarios.
Earlier, President Putin offered to voluntarily uphold the limits capping the size of the world's two larg</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 12:01:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>British globe trekker faces changed world on final leg of 27-year journey</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/british-globe-trekker-faces-changed-world-on-final-leg-of-27-year-journey</link><description>Karl Bushby, a British ex-paratrooper who set out in 1998 to walk around the world, is on the final stretch of his 27-year-long trek home, and trying to cope with social media pressure in a world that has changed profoundly.
Walking in pouring rain in northwest Hungary, Bushby, 56, who started out</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 12:16:10 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>