<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 15:26:06 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Italy-based Bangladeshis send over $1.3b remittances yearly</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/italy-based-bangladeshis-send-over-13b-remittances-yearly</link><description>Bangladesh Ambassador to Italy Rakibul Haque on Friday said more than 200,000 Bangladeshi expatriates living in Italy send over USD 1.3 billion in remittances annually, making a significant contribution to Bangladesh’s economy while strengthening bilateral friendship and socio-cultural ties.</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 13:17:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Republicans risk moderates, US House majority, with no healthcare extension</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/republicans-risk-moderates-us-house-majority-with-no-healthcare-extension</link><description>Republican worries about losing their majority in the US House of Representatives next year erupted this week, when four moderates joined Democrats in a last-ditch effort to prevent a spike in healthcare costs for 24 million Americans beginning in less than two weeks.
The four - Representatives Ro</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 13:32:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two Bangladeshis killed at Sylhet border in ‘Indian Khasi firing’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/two-bangladeshis-killed-at-sylhet-border-in-indian-khasi-firing</link><description>Two Bangladeshi men were killed by gunfire allegedly from Indian Khasi people at the Sylhet border in Companiganj Upazila on Friday afternoon.
The shooting took place at the Damdama border area of Uttar Ronikhai Union, Companiganj Police chief Shafiqul Islam said.
The victims were identified only</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 13:47:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tight security at metro stations</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/heightened-security-imposed-at-dhaka-metro-stations-amid-nationwide-tensions</link><description>Strict security measures have been imposed at metro rail stations across Dhaka following incidents of attacks, vandalism and arson at different establishments amid anger and protests triggered by the death of Sharif Osman bin Hadi, convenor of Inqilab Moncho.
On Friday, Dhaka Mass Transit Company</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 14:02:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hadi's janaza at South Plaza of Sangsad Bhaban at 2 pm on Saturday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hadis-janaza-at-south-plaza-of-sangsad-bhaban-at-2-pm-on-saturday</link><description>The namaj-e-janaza of Shaheed Sharif Osman Hadi will be held at 2 pm on Saturday at the South Plaza of the Jatiya Sangsad (JS) Bhaban in the city.
The Chief Adviser's Press Wing confirmed the matter this evening and requested the people interested to attend the namaz-e-janaza of Shaheed Osman Hadi</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 13:18:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Lebanon-Israel truce committee talks widen</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/lebanon-israel-truce-committee-talks-widen-as-hezbollah-disarmament-deadline-nears</link><description>The committee overseeing the Hezbollah-Israel truce in Lebanon focused on Friday on how to return displaced people to their homes, addressing civilian issues to help prevent renewed war if a year-end deadline to disarm Hezbollah is not met.
The 15th meeting of the committee reflected a long-standi</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 13:33:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Election 2026: 450,000 Bangladeshi expats registered to vote</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/election-2026-450000-bangladeshi-expats-registered-to-vote</link><description>More than 450,000 expatriate Bangladeshi voters from different countries across the world registered through a mobile app, ‘Postal Vote Bd’, in the last one month to vote in the upcoming national election and the referendum, scheduled to be held simultaneously on February 12, 2026.
The</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 13:48:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP pays homage to Osman Hadi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-pays-homage-to-osman-hadi</link><description>BNP on Friday paid tributes to Inquilab Moncho spokesperson Sharif Osman Hadi as his body arrived at Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport from Singapore on Friday evening.
On behalf of the party, BNP Standing Committee member Salahuddin Ahmed and Acting Chairman’s adviser Dr Mahdi Amin pai</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 14:03:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fire breaks out at Udichi office in Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fire-breaks-out-at-udichi-office-in-dhaka</link><description>A fire has broken out following an attack at the Udichi Shilpigosthi office near the National Press Club in Dhaka.
Firefighters rushed to the scene to control the blaze around 7:30pm on Friday evening.
Jamshed Anwar Topon, general secretary of one faction of Udichi, told bdnews24.com: “The</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 14:18:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hadi to be buried beside Kazi Nazrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/osman-hadi-to-be-buried-beside-national-poet-kazi-nazrul-islam</link><description>Inqilab Moncho Convenor Sharif Osman bin Hadi will be buried beside the grave of national poet Kazi Nazrul Islam next to the Dhaka University Central Mosque, confirmed the platform in a Facebook Post.
Hadi’s family wished to have him buried at the place, the Inqilab Moncho said in the post o</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 14:33:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chhayanaut ‘will not waver’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/chhayanaut-says-it-will-not-waver-in-its-course</link><description>Chhayanaut will remain steadfast in its journey, the Bengali cultural organisation has said following the arson attack and widespread vandalism on its premises on Friday.
Around 6:30pm on Saturday, the statement signed by the organisation’s President Sarwar Ali and General Secretary Laisa Ah</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 14:48:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh issues travel pass for Tarique Rahman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bangladesh-issues-travel-pass-for-tarique-rahman</link><description>The Bangladesh high commission in London has issued a travel pass for Tarique Rahman in response to the BNP leader’s application for the document, an official said.
A foreign ministry official, who spoke on condition of anonymity, said Friday the mission took just a day to issue the travel d</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 15:03:46 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>