<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 08:29:54 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Brahmanbaria rail tracks set on fire</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/brahmanbaria-rail-tracks-set-on-fire</link><description>Unidentified miscreants set fire to a section of railway tracks in Brahmanbaria early Thursday, disrupting train movement.
The incident occurred around 1:45 am at the Dublar area in Basudeb Union of Brahmanbaria Sadar upazila. Train services on the route were halted for a short period following th</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 05:15:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>OpenAI fights order to turn over millions of ChatGPT conversations</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/openai-fights-order-to-turn-over-millions-of-chatgpt-conversations</link><description>OpenAI asked a federal judge in New York on Wednesday to reverse an order that required it to turn over 20 million anonymised ChatGPT chat logs amid a copyright infringement lawsuit by the New York Times and other news outlets, saying it would expose users' private conversations.
The artificial in</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 05:30:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Petrol bomb thrown at July martyrs’ monument in Barguna</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/petrol-bomb-thrown-at-july-martyrs-monument-in-barguna</link><description>Assailants have reportedly conducted a petrol bomb attack on the July martyrs’ monument in Barguna on Wednesday night.
The incident occurred after midnight near the northeast corner of the Circuit House field, according to police sources.
A video of the attack has since gone viral on social</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 05:45:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fire erupts at Khulna sub-registrar office</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fire-erupts-at-khulna-sub-registrar-office</link><description>A fire broke out at the Khulna Sadar sub-registrar office early Thursday, reportedly caused by a petrol bomb attack.
The incident occurred around 3:00 am, police said.
According to sources, several chairs and tables were burned in the blaze. A unit from the Tutpara Fire Station rushed to the spot</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 06:00:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Verdict on Hasina’s crimes against humanity case on Nov 17</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/verdict-on-hasinas-crimes-against-humanity-case-on-nov-17</link><description>The International Crimes Tribunal will decide whether or not ousted prime minister Sheikh Hasina, who is a “fugitive”, will be punished in a case over crimes against humanity for trying to suppress the July Uprising on November 17.
A three-member International Crimes Tribunal bench led</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 06:15:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Want to act as real referee in election: CEC Nasir</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/want-to-act-as-real-referee-in-election-cec-nasir</link><description>Chief Election Commissioner AMM Nasir Uddin on Thursday said the Election Commission wants to act as a true referee in the upcoming national election, emphasising the need for cooperation from all political parties.
"You (political parties) will play in the elections. You are the players. We reall</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 06:30:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>We live in the timeless world of Humayun Ahmed</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/entertainment/we-live-in-the-timeless-world-of-humayun-ahmed-1</link><description>Some names remain unchanged even when time passes. One such name is Humayun Ahmed. His words, his stories, and his characters are still alive. People read him, watch him, and talk about him even more than when he was alive.
Humayun Ahmed began his writing career in the 1970s. His first novel, Nond</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 06:45:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Security beefed up at tribunal, across Dhaka ahead of Hasina verdict date</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/security-beefed-up-at-tribunal-across-dhaka-ahead-of-hasina-verdict-date</link><description>Authorities have beefed up security at the International Crimes Tribunal (ICT) ahead of the announcement of the verdict date in a crimes against humanity case against ousted prime minister Sheikh Hasina.
A three-member bench of the ICT led by Justice Md Golam Mortuza Mozumder will set the date on</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 07:00:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US ends penny-making run after more than 230 years</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/others/us-ends-penny-making-run-after-more-than-230-years</link><description>The US is set to make its final penny.
The Philadelphia Mint will strike its last batch of one-cent coins on Wednesday, after more than 230 years of production.
The coins will remain in circulation, but the phase-out has already prompted businesses to start adjusting prices, as they say pennies a</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 07:15:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>JU’s first-year admission tests to begin on Dec 21</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/jus-first-year-admission-tests-to-begin-on-dec-21</link><description>Jahangirnagar University (JU) will begin its admission tests for first-year students of the 2025-26 academic session (55th batch) on December 21, said JU's acting registrar ABM Azizur Rahman on Wednesday.
Regarding the schedule for individual units, Azizur Rahman said, "No decision has been taken</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 07:30:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hope for exemplary maximum punishment for Hasina, says Chief Prosecutor Tajul Islam</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hope-for-exemplary-maximum-punishment-for-hasina-says-chief-prosecutor-tajul-islam</link><description>Chief Prosecutor Tajul Islam says he expects the International Crimes Tribunal to give the maximum punishment to ousted prime minister Sheikh Hasina and her former home minister Asaduzzaman Khan Kamal in a case of crimes against humanity for trying to suppress the July Uprising.
A three-member Int</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 07:45:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New French envoy meets Fakhrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/new-french-envoy-meets-fakhrul</link><description>Newly appointed French Ambassador to Bangladesh Jean-Marc Sere-Charlet met BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir on Thursday and discussed Bangladesh's current political situation and the upcoming national election.
The hour-long meeting began around 12pm at the BNP Chairperson's offic</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 08:00:48 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>