<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 10:26:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>CPA signs 30-year concession deal with APM Terminals for Laldia Container Terminal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/cpa-signs-30-year-concession-deal-with-apm-terminals-for-laldia-container-terminal</link><description>The Chittagong Port Authority (CPA) on Monday signed a concession agreement with the Denmark-based APM Terminals for development and operations for 30 years of the Laldia Container Terminal (LCT) under a Public-Private Partnership (PPP) framework.
 
Shipping Adviser Brigadier General (Retd)</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 07:00:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ICT-1 reading out verdict in Hasina’s case</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ict-1-reading-out-verdict-in-hasinas-case</link><description>The International Crimes Tribunal-1  (ICT-1) is reading out its verdict in a high-profile case against former Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina and two others for crimes against humanity committed during last year’s July-August uprising.
The three member tribunal led by Justice Md. Golam Mor</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 07:15:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hasina verdict being shown on big screen at DU’s TSC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hasina-verdict-being-shown-on-big-screen-at-dus-tsc</link><description>The proceedings of the verdict against deposed prime minister Sheikh Hasina in a crimes against humanity case are being broadcast on a large screen at Dhaka University's TSC (Teacher-Student Centre).
Around 12 pm on Monday, a visit to the area revealed an LED screen installed on the eastern side o</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 07:30:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>5 JUCSU leaders selected for university senate</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/5-jucsu-leaders-selected-for-university-senate</link><description>Jahangirnagar University Central Student Union (JUCSU) has nominated five representatives including Vice President (VP) and General Secretary (GS) to serve on the university’s Senate.
The decision was taken during JUCSU’s third executive meeting on Sunday night, based on the consents f</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 07:45:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Awami League using looted money for acts of sabotage: Rizvi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/awami-league-using-looted-money-for-acts-of-sabotage-rizvi</link><description>BNP Senior Joint Secretary General Ruhul Kabir Rizvi on Monday alleged that the fascist Awami League is using ‘money looted from various banks and mega projects’ to buy cocktails and carry out acts of sabotage.
“Those who committed crimes during the fascist era are now the ones s</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 08:00:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hasina found guilty of crimes against humanity</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hasina-found-guilty-of-crimes-against-humanity</link><description>Bangladesh's ousted Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina was found guilty of crimes against humanity by the International Crimes Tribunal-1 (ICT-1) on Monday and will be sentenced shortly.
Hasina, who is living in exile in India, was tried in absentia. The tribunal, after a months-long trial, concluded th</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 08:21:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Land office signboard, rail line torched in Ctg</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/land-office-signboard-rail-line-torched-in-ctg</link><description>A land office signboard, a section of a highway, and a rail line in Chattogram have been hit by arson attacks.
In the early hours of Monday, tree stumps and tyres were set on fire on the railway track and highway in the Hathazari upazila, reports bdnews24.com.
Around the same time, the signboard</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 08:30:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>It’s an election to save the country, work with honesty: Prof Yunus urges DCs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/its-an-election-to-save-the-country-work-with-honesty-prof-yunus-urges-dcs</link><description>Chief Adviser Prof Muhammad Yunus on Monday instructed the Deputy Commissioners (DCs) to carry out their responsibilities with full honesty, impartiality and integrity in the upcoming election and referendum, stressing that the election must be both festive and peaceful.
“This election (sche</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 08:36:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ICT verdict to uphold fair trial with international standards, hopes Fakhrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ict-verdict-to-uphold-fair-trial-with-international-standards-hopes-fakhrul</link><description>BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir on Monday expressed hope that the verdict in the case against former Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina will ensure a fair trial in line with international standards.
Mirza Fakhrul made a post on his verified Facebook page in the morning saying, "In Dhak</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 08:51:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Army disperses protesters attempting fresh vandalism at Dhanmondi 32</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/army-disperses-protesters-attempting-fresh-vandalism-at-dhanmondi-32</link><description>The Army and police have blocked a group of people attempting to demolish the ruins of Bangabandhu Sheikh Mujibur Rahman’s residence at Dhanmondi 32.
Around 12 pm on Monday, two excavators were brought to the area by an organisation named “Red July”.
Police and later the Army di</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 09:06:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hasina to be hanged for crimes against humanity</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hasina-to-be-hanged-for-crimes-against-humanity</link><description>The International Crimes Tribunal has sentenced ousted Bangladeshi prime minister Sheikh Hasina to death for crimes against humanity for her attempts to suppress the July Uprising.
Hasina, who ruled the country for a decade and a half with an iron fist, has fled to India since she was ousted from</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 09:21:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ex-IGP Mamun gets five-year jail term for crimes against humanity</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ex-igp-mamun-gets-five-year-jail-term-for-crimes-against-humanity</link><description>The International Crimes Tribunal-1 on Monday sentenced former Inspector General of Police Chowdhury Abdullah Al Mamun to five years in prison in a case filed over crimes against humanity.
The three-member tribunal, headed by Justice Golam Mortuza Majumder, pronounced the verdict in a packed court</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 09:36:16 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>