<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 12:57:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Hajj arrangements underway smoothly according to roadmap: Adviser Khalid</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hajj-arrangements-underway-smoothly-according-to-roadmap-adviser-khalid</link><description>Religious Affairs Adviser Dr A F M Khalid Hossain on Wednesday said all preparations for Hajj are progressing according to the roadmap.
The Ministry of Religious Affairs is working relentlessly to complete cent percent accommodation contracts within the stipulated timeframe, he said during a meeti</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 09:39:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US ready to work with any elected government in Bangladesh: Christensen</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/us-ready-to-work-with-any-elected-government-in-bangladesh-christensen</link><description>The United States will take no side in Bangladesh’s election and is prepared to work with whichever government is chosen by voters, according to US Ambassador Brent Christensen.
Speaking to reporters after meeting Bangladesh’s Chief Election Commissioner AMM Nasir Uddin in Dhaka on Wed</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 09:54:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Adani boosts power supply to Bangladesh despite souring diplomatic ties</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/indias-adani-boosts-electricity-supply-to-bangladesh-despite-souring-diplomatic-ties</link><description>India's Adani Power is boosting electricity exports to Bangladesh, data from both governments showed, despite worsening bilateral relations and a Bangladesh government-appointed panel calling the supply overpriced.
Exports to Bangladesh from Adani's Godda coal-fired power plant in India's eastern</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 10:09:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Daffodil International University celebrates its 13th Convocation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/daffodil-international-university-celebrates-its-13th-convocation</link><description>Daffodil International University (DIU) held its 13th Convocation today, Wednesday (28 January 2026), at Daffodil Smart City, with the participation of 4,020 graduating students from undergraduate and postgraduate programs.
Among them, 3,391 students completed undergraduate degrees and 629 complet</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 10:24:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EBL launches Trade Hub at Chattogram EPZ</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ebl-launches-trade-hub-at-chattogram-epz</link><description>Eastern Bank PLC (EBL) has officially launched a dedicated Trade Hub at the Chattogram Export Processing Zone (CEPZ) to provide specialised trade-related banking services for customers operating within the CEPZ area.
The EBL CEPZ Trade Hub has been specifically designed to expedite import and expo</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 10:39:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>510 tonnes of rice imported from India reach Benapole</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/510-tonnes-of-rice-imported-from-india-reach-benapole</link><description>A total of 510 tonnes of parboiled rice have been imported from India through the Benapole Land Port in Jashore after a gap of three months, with the import cost standing at Tk 50 per kg.
The consignments arrived at the port in 14 trucks on Tuesday and entered Transshipment Yard No. 31, said Benap</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 10:54:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hong Kong scientists launch AI model to better predict extreme weather</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/hong-kong-scientists-launch-ai-model-to-better-predict-extreme-weather</link><description>A team of Hong Kong scientists has developed an artificial intelligence weather-forecasting system to predict thunderstorms and heavy downpours up to four hours ahead, compared with the range of 20 minutes to two hours now.
The system will help governments and emergency services respond more effec</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 10:56:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Embezzlement’: Case against S Alam, PK Halder goes to trial</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/case-over-tk-240mn-embezzlement-against-s-alam-pk-halder-and-11-others-goes-to-trial</link><description>A Dhaka court has indicted 13 people, including S Alam Group Chairman Mohammad Saiful Alam and former managing director of Reliance Finance Limited (now Aviva Finance Limited) Prashanta Kumar (PK) Halder, in a case over the alleged embezzlement of Tk 240 million.
Dhaka Special Judge’s Court-</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 11:11:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India reports two Nipah virus infections as Thai, Malaysia step up screening</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/india-reports-two-nipah-virus-infections-as-thai-malaysia-step-up-screening</link><description>India is monitoring Nipah virus infections, with two reported from its eastern state of West Bengal since December, the health ministry said, as some Southeast Asia nations step up scrutiny of air travellers.
Tuesday's confirmation came a day after Thailand said it had tightened airport screening</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 11:26:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt plans Broadcast Commission; violators face jail, Tk 5 million fine</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-plans-broadcast-commission-violators-face-jail-tk-5-million-fine</link><description>The government is set to establish a new Broadcast Commission to streamline the operations of various broadcasting entities, set standards and curb irregularities.
The Ministry of Information and Broadcasting has prepared the draft Broadcast Commission Ordinance-2026, which proposes strict penalti</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 11:41:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Naogaon gears up for Tarique’s first rally in nearly two decades</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/naogaon-gears-up-for-tariques-first-rally-in-nearly-two-decades</link><description>Preparations are in full swing at the A-Team ground in Naogaon district town ahead of BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman’s visit on Thursday, marking his first public rally in the district in nearly 20 years as part of the party’s election campaign.
Party leaders and activists expressed optim</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 11:56:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Indices extend gains despite lower turnover at Bangladesh bourses</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/indices-extend-gains-despite-lower-turnover-at-bangladesh-bourses</link><description>Stock indices at both the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) and the Chittagong Stock Exchange (CSE) extended their gains on Wednesday, marking the second consecutive day of rise in the country’s capital market, despite a decline in overall turnover.
At the DSE, the benchmark index DSEX advanced by</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 12:11:03 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>