<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 10:43:38 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>387 July warriors upgraded to 'A', 474 to 'B' category</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/387-july-warriors-upgraded-to-a-474-to-b-category</link><description>A total of 387 July warriors have been upgraded to the ‘A’ category from their previous ‘B’ and ‘C’ categories, while 474 warriors have been promoted from ‘C’ to ‘B’.
The Ministry of Liberation War Affairs issued a notification revising t</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 07:32:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bitcoin drops below $76000</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bitcoin-drops-below-76000</link><description>Bitcoin was on the cusp of breaking below the key $70,000 level on Thursday as a slide in the world's largest cryptocurrency showed no signs of stopping.
Bitcoin tumbled more than 3.0 per cent in the Asian session to $70,052.38, its lowest level since November 2024.
Ether, the world's second-larg</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 07:47:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US drone makers seek Asia sales</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/us-drone-makers-seek-asia-sales</link><description>Several US drone firms made their debuts at the Singapore Airshow this week, seeking to expand their business beyond the Pentagon to countries in Asia that are increasingly concerned about the threat posed by China's military build-up.
The lethal success of drones on both sides of Russia’s w</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 08:02:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Logistics policy gaps threaten trade competitiveness</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/logistics-policy-gaps-threaten-trade-competitiveness</link><description>As Bangladesh pushes to strengthen its trade and supply chains, long-standing weaknesses in how goods move across the country are coming under sharper scrutiny.
From crowded ports to fragmented decision-making, logistics is increasingly seen as a quiet constraint on economic growth - just as the c</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 08:17:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mustafizur Rahman signs direct deal with Lahore Qalandars in PSL</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/mustafizur-rahman-signs-direct-deal-with-lahore-qalandars-in-psl</link><description>Bangladesh left-arm fast bowler Mustafizur Rahman has been signed by Lahore Qalandars on a direct contract to feature in the Pakistan Super League, reports bdnews24.com.
The PSL franchise confirmed on social media that Mustafizur will once again represent his former side, securing his services for</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 09:03:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC to use wireless network to collect results from 108 remote centres</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ec-to-use-wireless-network-to-collect-results-from-108-remote-centres</link><description>The Election Commission has decided to use the modern network or wireless communication system of law-enforcing agencies to collect election results from 108 remote polling stations accessible by helicopter sorties in the three hill districts -- Rangamati, Khagrachhari and Bandarban.
In this regar</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 09:18:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EBL to continue partnership with SOS Children’s Villages</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ebl-to-continue-partnership-with-sos-childrens-villages</link><description>Building on the success of its 2025 collaboration, Eastern Bank Limited PLC (EBL) has expressed its intent to continue supporting SOS Children’s Villages Bangladesh in 2026, focusing on youth skill development and clean water access for vulnerable communities.
The renewed partnership will st</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 09:04:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Four bodies recovered from Mirpur Bihari camp</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/four-bodies-recovered-from-mirpur-bihari-camp</link><description>Police have recovered the bodies of four members of the same family from Mirpur 11’s Wapda Bihari Camp in Dhaka’s Pallabi Thana.
AKM Alamgir Jahan, chief of Pallabi Police Station, said police went to a home and recovered the bodies after they were reported around 11am.
The bodies w</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 09:19:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AB Party candidate’s election office vandalised in Feni</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ab-party-candidates-election-office-vandalised-in-feni</link><description>Miscreants vandalised the election office of AB Party chairman Mujibur Rahman Manjur, the Eagle-symbol candidate of the 11-party alliance, at Izzatpur in Feni Sadar late Wednesday night.
Local sources said the office, located on Daiyabibi Bazar Road at Izzatpur, was inaugurated by party leaders an</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 09:34:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Former Biman MD, wife seek bail over ‘abusing’ domestic child worker, hearing on Sunday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/former-biman-md-wife-seek-bail-over-abusing-domestic-child-worker-hearing-on-sunday</link><description>Former Biman Bangladesh Airlines managing director and chief executive officer Shafiqur Rahman and his wife Bithi have sought bail in a case over the abuse of a child domestic worker.
Lawyer Zakir Hossain filed the bail petition on their behalf on Thursday at the court of Dhaka Chief Metropolitan</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 09:49:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nasser Hussain backs Bangladesh and Pakistan stance on T20 World Cup</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/nasser-hussain-backs-bangladesh-and-pakistan-stance-on-t20-world-cup</link><description>Former England captain Nasser Hussain has thrown his weight behind Bangladesh and Pakistan in the ongoing T20 World Cup crisis, asserting that it is high time to halt the intrusion of politics into the sport.
Speaking on the Sky Cricket Podcast with fellow commentator Mike Atherton, Hussain praise</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 10:04:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat Ameer vows to ensure security, rights of all, women safety</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-ameer-vows-to-ensure-security-rights-of-all-women-safety</link><description>Jamaat Ameer Dr Shafiqur Rahman on Thursday pledged to ensure the security and rights of people of all religions and communities, while promising strict measures to protect women from harassment and threats.
Speaking at an election rally organised by the Naogaon district Jamaat at Atim ground in N</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 10:19:36 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>