<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 16:33:14 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Young and old in Barishal join contract broiler farming</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/young-and-old-in-barishal-join-contract-broiler-farming</link><description>Many broiler chicken farmers sustained losses while buying feed on credit from dealers, and have now become contract farmers of poultry companies. Many young and elderly people who could not manage jobs, and who lacked capital to start a business, have also become contract farmers.
Farmers said co</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 13:46:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Applications for private MPO teachers open on Saturday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ntrca-invites-applications-for-67000-mpo-teachers-from-saturday</link><description>The Non-Government Teachers’ Registration and Certification Authority (NTRCA) has announced a major recruitment drive to appoint 67,208 teachers and lecturers to MPO-listed private educational institutions across Bangladesh.
Applications will open on Saturday and remain available until midni</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 14:01:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Uttara Bank introduces TakaPay Debit Card</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/uttara-bank-introduces-takapay-debit-card</link><description>Mr. Md. Abul Hashem, Managing Director and CEO of Uttara Bank PLC. has inaugurated the “TakaPay Debit Card” of the bank on Monday.
According to a press release, this card can be used to withdraw cash at all ATMs and make payment through POS machines within the country. Additional Manag</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 14:16:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Vote counting begins after JnU’s first polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/vote-counting-under-way-after-jagannath-universitys-first-student-council-election</link><description>After two decades of transformation, Jagannath University students have cast their ballots for the first-ever election of the central student council (JnUCSU).
Following a peaceful voting process, counting of votes began at 6:30pm at the Department of Geography and Environment on Tuesday.
Polling</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 14:31:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Over 15.33 lakh register for postal voting: Shafiqul Alam</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/over-1533-lakh-register-for-postal-voting-shafiqul-alam</link><description>Chief Adviser’s Press Secretary Shafiqul Alam on Tuesday said that a total of 15,33,682 voters have registered for casting their votes through postal ballots as registration for postal vote ended on Monday.
“A total of 15,33,682 voters have registered for casting their votes through po</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 14:46:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh Bank moves to liquidate nine NBFIs amid financial sector reforms</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh-bank-moves-to-liquidate-nine-nbfis-amid-financial-sector-reforms</link><description>Bangladesh Bank is set to initiate the liquidation of nine non-bank financial institutions (NBFIs) following the consolidation of five troubled Shariah banks into a single entity, marking a major step in the central bank’s efforts to reform the country’s financial sector.
Governor Ahsa</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 14:30:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Biman delays suspension of Dhaka–Sylhet–Manchester route to March</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/biman-delays-suspension-of-dhaka-sylhet-manchester-route-to-march</link><description>Biman Bangladesh Airlines has deferred by a month its decision to suspend flights on the Dhaka–Sylhet–Manchester route, now setting the suspension date for March instead of February.
In a statement issued on Tuesday, the airline said the decision was revised following a review by its b</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 14:45:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Terminal driveway closed at Ctg airport</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/vehicles-visitors-barred-from-shah-amanat-international-airport-terminal-over-security-concerns</link><description>Vehicles and visitors have been barred from entering the terminal driveway of Chattogram’s Shah Amanat International Airport, citing security concerns ahead of the general election.
The decision was taken at the airport security committee’s monthly coordination meeting on Tuesday, acco</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 15:00:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tofazzal death: 28 face charges for beating over ‘theft’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/tofazzal-death-28-face-charges-for-beating-over-theft</link><description>A chargesheet accusing 28 people, including former Bangladesh Chhatra League leader, has been filed 15 months after mentally-ill Toffazzal Hossain was beaten to death on suspicion of theft at Fazlul Huq Muslim Hall of Dhaka University.
Additional Superintendent Hannanul Islam of the Police Bureau</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 15:15:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>122 more appeals against EC decisions</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/122-more-appeals-against-ec-decisions</link><description>On the second day of appeals over nominations for the parliamentary polls, the Election Commission (EC) has received 122 applications challenging returning officers’ decisions.
Senior Assistant Secretary of the EC’s legal division Mainul Islam said confirmed the development on Tuesday.</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 15:30:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Vote discrepancy halts counting at JnU</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/vote-discrepancy-halts-counting-at-jnu</link><description>Jagannath University’s Central Student Union (JnUCSU) election has run into trouble during vote counting following a peaceful polling process.
A discrepancy in a single vote has suspended the counting for over two hours as the authorities work to verify results.
“We have encountered a</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 15:45:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>G7 finance ministers to meet in Washington to discuss rare earths, three sources say</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/g7-finance-ministers-to-meet-in-washington-to-discuss-rare-earths-three-sources-say</link><description>Finance ministers from the Group of Seven nations will meet in Washington on January 12 to discuss rare earths supplies, three sources familiar with the matter said on Tuesday.
One of the sources added that price floors for rare earths would be a point of discussion, among other critical mineral t</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 16:00:49 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>