<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 15:28:36 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>BGMEA felicitates Tarique Rahman on BNP’s landslide victory</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bgmea-felicitates-tarique-rahman-on-bnps-landslide-victory</link><description>The Bangladesh Garment Manufacturers and Exporters Association (BGMEA) on Saturday extended heartfelt congratulations to BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman on the party’s historic landslide victory in the 13th National Parliamentary Election.
In a congratulatory message, BGMEA President Mahmud Hasa</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 12:09:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique pledges justice, seeks unity to build ‘safe, humane Bangladesh’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-pledges-justice-seeks-unity-to-build-safe-humane-bangladesh</link><description>Stating that justice will be the guiding principle of his future government in ensuring the rule of law, BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman on Saturday sought cooperation from all political parties and forces in building a ‘safe and humane Bangladesh’.
Addressing a post-election press confere</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 12:24:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AI film school trains next generation of Hollywood moviemakers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/entertainment/ai-film-school-trains-next-generation-of-hollywood-moviemakers</link><description>Laid-off and sidelined by last year’s production slowdown, Hollywood visual‑effects veteran Michael Eng discovered a gap in his resume while perusing job listings in Los Angeles– experience in machine learning.
Eng turned to Curious Refuge, an online school teaching filmmaking powered</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 12:39:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>What’s next for Jamaat alliance?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/after-polls-jamaat-e-islami-alliance-debates-future-role</link><description>With the general election done and dusted, attention is shifting from the ballot box to the shape of opposition politics and, in particular, to the future of the Jamaat-e-Islami-led electoral alliance.
Within political circles, discussions are under way over whether the 11-party bloc assembled ahe</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 12:54:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>RAJUK dismisses social media post alleging Gulshan Niketan land grab</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rajuk-dismisses-social-media-post-alleging-gulshan-niketan-land-grab</link><description>RAJUK has said false information is being spread on social media about a piece of land in Dhaka’s Gulshan Niketan.
In a press note issued on Tuesday, RAJUK (Rajdhani Unnayan Kartripakkha) insisted the land is fully acquired and owned by it.
It said work has recently begun to build a public</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 13:09:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique Rahman to visit Jamaat Ameer, NCP chief Sunday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-rahman-to-visit-jamaat-ameer-ncp-chief-sunday</link><description>BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman is scheduled to visit the residences of Jamaat-e-Islami Ameer Shafiqur Rahman and National Citizen Party (NCP) Convener Nahid Islam on Sunday evening, signalling a gesture of political goodwill.
A BNP leader close to Tarique Rahman, who requested anonymity, told UNB tha</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 13:24:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DUCSU, Jatiya Chhatra Shakti condemn post-election violence across country</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/ducsu-jatiya-chhatra-shakti-condemn-post-election-violence-across-country</link><description>The Dhaka University Central Students’ Union (DUCSU) and Jatiya Chhatra Shakti have condemned widespread post-election violence across the country following the 13th National Parliamentary Election.
 
At a press conference held in front of the DUCSU building at 5:30 pm on Saturday, DUC</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 13:39:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Newly elected MPs to be sworn in on Tuesday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/newly-elected-mps-to-be-sworn-in-on-tuesday</link><description>The oath-taking ceremony of the newly elected members of parliament will take place on Tuesday.
Parliament Secretariat Secretary Kaniz Moul confirmed the date on Saturday.
Another official said the new government may take oath the same day.</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 13:54:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh Hindu Buddhist Christian Oikkya Parishad congratulates BNP-led alliance on election victory</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-hindu-buddhist-christian-oikkya-parishad-congratulates-bnp-led-alliance-on-election-victory</link><description>The Bangladesh Hindu Buddhist Christian Oikkya Parishad on Saturday congratulated the BNP-led alliance on its landslide victory in the 13th national elections.
In a statement, the organisation said the polls were held in a largely peaceful manner, with only a few isolated incidents reported.
It e</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 14:09:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat pulls election post minutes after upload</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jamaat-retracts-facebook-post-welcoming-election-results-minutes-after-publishing</link><description>The Jamaat-e-Islami has removed a Facebook post acknowledging the BNP’s absolute majority in the election just minutes after publishing it.
Jamaat made the post to its official Facebook page at 6:24pm on Saturday.
Within just a few minutes, it was shared more than a hundred times, drawing a</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 14:24:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BIMSTEC chief congratulates Tarique on victory</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bimstec-chief-congratulates-tarique-on-victory</link><description>The Secretary General of BIMSTEC Indra Mani Pandey on Saturday congratulated Chairman of Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) Tarique Rahman on his party’s historic victory in the 13th national parliamentary elections.
In a congratulatory message, the Secretary General extended warm greetings</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 14:39:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat seeks vote recount in 30 seats</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-seeks-vote-recount-in-30-seats</link><description>Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami has sought a recount of votes in at least 30 constituencies in the 13th parliamentary election, alleging widespread rigging, fraud and irregularities.
Speaking at a press conference at the party’s central office in Moghbazar in the capital, Assistant Secretary Gene</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 14:54:27 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>