<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 16:24:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>MTB Foundation distributes livelihood assets grants marking the bank’s anniversary</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/mtb-foundation-distributes-livelihood-assets-grants-marking-the-banks-anniversary</link><description>MTB Foundation, as part of its project titled ‘Creating Alternative Livelihood for Vulnerable Fishing Communities through Income Generating Activities (IGAs)’ distributed livelihood assets grants to a large number of Households (HHs) of the vulnerable fishing communities at Lalpur Union</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 13:54:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Islami Bank holds board meeting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/islami-bank-holds-board-meeting-11111</link><description>A meeting of the board of directors of Islami Bank Bangladesh PLC was held on Monday at the Islami Bank Tower.
Professor Dr. M. Zubaidur Rahman, chairman of the bank, presided over the meeting.Mohammad KhurshidWahab, chairman of the executive committee, Md. Abdus Salam, FCA, FCS, chairman of the a</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 14:09:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump’s latest China tariff brinkmanship clouds IMF, World Bank meetings</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/trumps-latest-china-tariff-brinkmanship-clouds-imf-world-bank-meetings</link><description>Finance chiefs gathering in Washington this week were ready to discuss the global economy’s surprising resilience in the face of Donald Trump’s tariff assaults - until U.S.-China trade war rhetoric reignited with the U.S. president threatening 100% duties on Chinese imports and whipsawi</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 14:24:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Lakshmipur man reclaims land after 43 years of legal battle</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/lakshmipur-man-reclaims-land-after-legal-battle-of-43-years</link><description>A man in Lakshmipur’s Raipur Upazila has reclaimed possession of nearly 1.4 hectares of land after a legal battle that lasted more than four decades.
On Monday, a court delegation handed over the disputed land to Bahar Patwary and his family with traditional drumming, in line with court inst</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 14:39:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Madagascar’s president has left the country after Gen Z protests</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/africa/madagascars-president-has-left-the-country-after-gen-z-protests</link><description>Madagascar’s president has fled the African nation, the head of the opposition and other officials said on Monday, the second time that young protesters have toppled a government in weeks of worldwide Gen Z unrest.
Siteny Randrianasoloniaiko, leader of the opposition in parliament, told Reut</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 15:09:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Faria Yasmin named first Bangladeshi and female MD of Bata Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/faria-yasmin-named-first-bangladeshi-and-female-md-of-bata-bangladesh</link><description>Bata Shoe Company (Bangladesh) Limited has named Faria Yasmin as its new managing director, according to a statement issued on Monday evening.
Faria Yasmin will be the first female managing director in the history of the company. Besides, she is also the first Bangladeshi to be named to lead the B</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 15:39:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>MPO-registered teachers set deadline for govt action on rent, festival allowances</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/mpo-registered-teachers-set-deadline-for-govt-action-on-rent-festival-allowances</link><description>MPO-registered teachers and staff participating in a continuous sit-in over a 20 percent house rent allowance in salaries have set a deadline for the government to meet their demands by 12pm Tuesday.
The protesters announced a “March to Secretariat” if demands remain unmet by then.
On</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 16:09:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Yunus says February election will institutionalise people’s power</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/yunus-says-february-election-will-institutionalise-peoples-power</link><description>Chief Advisor Muhammad Yunus has said the interim government’s commitment to justice and people’s power will be institutionalised through the parliamentary polls, slated for February.
In his keynote address at the World Food Forum (WFF) flagship event in Rome on Monday, he said the you</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 16:24:53 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>