<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 16:30:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Govt to procure 50,000mt non-Basmati parboiled rice, 10,000mt lentil</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/govt-to-procure-50000mt-non-basmati-parboiled-rice-10000mt-lentil</link><description>The government is set to procure significant quantities of rice and lentil as part of its food stock replenishment and market stabilisation measures.
The Advisers Council Committee on Government Purchase, in a meeting, approved separate proposals on Tuesday for procuring some 50,000 metric tonnes</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 13:30:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EU clears state aid for Poland’s first nuclear plant, PM Tusk says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/eu-clears-state-aid-for-polands-first-nuclear-plant-pm-tusk-says</link><description>The European Commission has agreed to allow Poland to provide state aid for the construction of the country’s first nuclear power plant, Polish Prime Minister Donald Tusk said on Tuesday.
The European Commission confirmed in a statement that it had approved the state aid.
Poland, seeking to</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 13:45:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fire rips through seven-storey building in Jakarta, killing 22 people</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/fire-rips-through-seven-storey-building-in-jakarta-killing-22-people</link><description>A fire swept through a seven-storey office block in Indonesia’s capital Jakarta on Tuesday, killing 22 people, police said.
The fire has now been extinguished and the recovered bodies have been sent to a hospital for identification, Susatyo Purnomo Condro, the head of Central Jakarta police,</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 14:00:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>85pc of workforce remains unrecognised in informal sector: Adviser Farida</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/85pc-of-workforce-remains-unrecognised-in-informal-sector-adviser-farida</link><description>Fisheries and Livestock Adviser Farida Akhter on Tuesday said that nearly 85 percent of Bangladesh’s workforce is employed in the informal sector, yet most remain unrecognised and excluded from social protection.
Speaking at the Informal &amp; Marginalised Formal Women Workers Convention 2025, o</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 14:15:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>56 migratory birds freed from poachers in Sylhet</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/56-migratory-birds-freed-from-poachers-in-sylhet</link><description>Fifty-six migratory birds, identified as Bali ducks, were released into the wild in Chondipul area of Sylhet after being rescued by the Forest Department from illegal traders, officials said Tuesday.
The birds, initially kept in sacks for sale, were freed at the banks of the Surma River in the pre</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 14:30:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt to procure 1 cargo LNG</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/govt-to-procure-1-cargo-lng</link><description>The government is moving ahead with the purchase of one spot cargo of LNG from the UK to meet the growing demand for energy in the country.
The Advisers Council Committee on Government Purchase in its 49th meeting in this year approved the proposal today. Finance Adviser Dr Salehuddin Ahmed presid</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 14:45:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BRAC University hosts seminar on implementing OPCAT in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/brac-university-hosts-seminar-on-implementing-opcat-in-bangladesh</link><description>BRAC University, the Embassy of Switzerland in Bangladesh and the Mission in Bangladesh of the United Nations High Commissioner for Human Rights (OHCHR) jointly organised a seminar on the “Operationalisation of the Optional Protocol to the Convention against Torture (OPCAT) in Bangladesh&amp;rdqu</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 15:00:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>12 scrapped solar projects revived as costs fall</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/12-scrapped-solar-projects-revived-as-costs-fall</link><description>The government has secured the opportunity to buy electricity at lower rates from 12 previously cancelled solar power projects after retendering brought down prices.
On Tuesday, Power Advisor Fouzul Kabir Khan said the government’s purchase advisory committee approved the revised tariffs for</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 15:00:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh Bank launches ‘E-Desk’ system</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-bank-launches-e-desk-system</link><description>In a major stride toward modernising its internal operations, Bangladesh Bank (BB) has officially launched the E-Desk System, marking a new chapter in the central bank's digitisation journey.
The system was inaugurated on Tuesday by Bangladesh Bank Governor Dr Ahsan H. Mansur, signalling the bank'</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 15:15:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Deal signed to purchase Eurofighter Typhoon from Italy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/deal-signed-to-purchase-eurofighter-typhoon-from-italy</link><description>Bangladesh Air Force (BAF) and Leonardo S.p.A., an Italian multinational company specialising in aerospace, defence and security, on Tuesday signed a Letter of Intent (LOI) at the Bangladesh Air Force (BAF) Headquarters in Dhaka.
“Through this LOI, Leonardo S.p.A will supply Eurofighter Typh</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 15:30:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Finance adviser explains rise in millionaire bank accounts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/finance-adviser-attributes-rise-in-millionaire-bank-accounts-to-hidden-money</link><description>Finance Adviser Salehuddin Ahmed has said the Bangladesh Bank’s report showing a rise in millionaire bank accounts is due to “money hidden at home for a long time” now being deposited.
He made these comments after a meeting of the Advisery Council Committee on Government Procurem</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 15:45:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NRBC Bank arranged a workshop on IFRS-9</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/nrbc-bank-arranged-a-workshop-on-ifrs-9</link><description>NRBC Bank arranged a workshop on International Financial Reporting Standards (IFRS-9) on Tuesday at their Human Resource and Training Development Centre (HRTDC), according to a press release.
Dr. Md Touhidul Alam Khan, Managing Director &amp; CEO, was the chief guest at the workshop. Raditha Alahakoon</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 16:00:50 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>