<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 14:18:33 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>DOGE 'doesn't exist' with eight months left on its charter</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/doge-doesnt-exist-with-eight-months-left-on-its-charter</link><description>US President Donald Trump's Department of Government Efficiency has disbanded with eight months left to its mandate, ending an initiative launched with fanfare as a symbol of Trump's pledge to slash the government's size but which critics say delivered few measurable savings.
"That doesn't exist,"</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 12:15:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh sends fresh letter to India seeking Hasina’s return</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-sends-fresh-letter-to-india-seeking-hasinas-return</link><description>The interim government has sent another letter to India seeking the return of Sheikh Hasina, who was sentenced to death for crimes against humanity during the July Uprising.
On Sunday, Foreign Advisor Touhid Hossain said the letter was dispatched on Friday.
On Monday, the International Crimes Tri</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 12:30:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCP voices concern over lack of level playing field</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ncp-voices-concern-over-lack-of-level-playing-field</link><description>National Citizens’ Party (NCP) Convener Nahid Islam on Sunday expressed deep concern over what he described as the absence of a proper level playing field ahead of the upcoming national election.
Speaking at a press conference organised by the party in Shahbagh, Nahid said the NCP expects a</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 11:15:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>South Africa says G20 summit outcome renews commitment to multilateralism</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/south-africa-says-g20-summit-outcome-renews-commitment-to-multilateralism</link><description>South Africa's President Cyril Ramaphosa said on Sunday that the Leaders' Declaration from this weekend's Group of 20 summit reflected a "renewed commitment to multilateral cooperation".
Ramaphosa, host of the Johannesburg summit, pushed through the declaration addressing global challenges like th</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 11:30:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh Earthquake: Fire Service issues 8 safety guidelines</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-earthquake-fire-service-issues-8-safety-guidelines</link><description>Several earthquakes, including one measuring 5.7 on the Richter scale, have been felt in different parts of Bangladesh, including the capital Dhaka, over the last two days.
This has spread panic among people in Dhaka city and the surrounding districts, UNB reports. 
Fire Service and Civil De</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 11:45:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Postal voting: 15,000 sign up in 4 days</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/over-15000-bangladeshi-expatriates-register-for-postal-voting-in-four-days</link><description>More than 15,000 Bangladeshi expatriates in East Asia, South America and Africa have registered in the first phase to cast their votes via post in the next parliamentary elections.
The Election Commission has given the expatriates in the regions, who have not yet registered on the Postal Vote BD a</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 12:00:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Court grants bail to Indian citizen Sakhina Begum accused of ‘illegal entry’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/court-grants-bail-to-indian-citizen-sakhina-begum-accused-of-illegal-entry</link><description>A Dhaka court has granted bail to Indian national Sakhina Begum in a case filed over alleged illegal entry.
The order came on Sunday from Additional Chief Metropolitan Magistrate Zakir Hossain.
Defence lawyer Rahmatullah Siddique sought bail, arguing that the charges are bailable and that Sakhina</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 12:15:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ASI found dead at CMP Chawkbazar barrack bathroom</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/asi-found-dead-at-cmp-chawkbazar-barrack-bathroom</link><description>The body of an Assistant Sub-Inspector (ASI) was recovered from the bathroom of a barrack under Chawkbazar police station in Chattogram on Sunday.
Chawk Bazar Zone Assistant Commissioner (AC) Tarikul Islam said colleagues recovered the hanging of Ohidur Rahman with a towel around his neck inside t</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 12:30:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Vietnam floods: Death toll rises to 90</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/vietnam-floods-death-toll-rises-to-90</link><description>At least 90 people have now died in floods and landslides in central Vietnam triggered by heavy rains earlier this week, state media reported Sunday, citing the country’s disaster prevention agency.
The deluges wreaked widespread destruction across a region already battered weeks ago by floo</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 12:45:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Antibiotic misuse poses bigger threat than recent quake: Adviser Farida</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/antibiotic-misuse-poses-bigger-threat-than-recent-quake-adviser-farida</link><description>Adviser Farida Akhter on Sunday warned that Bangladesh is facing a ‘severe, silent threat’ as the uncontrolled use of antibiotics continues to spread across hospitals, farms, fisheries and agricultural fields.
“While the recent 5.7-magnitude earthquake caused public anxiety, a mu</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 13:00:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Germany's Merz doubts Trump's Ukraine plan deadline can be met</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/germanys-merz-doubts-trumps-ukraine-plan-deadline-can-be-met</link><description>German Chancellor Friedrich Merz said on Sunday that he is not convinced that a solution agreeable to Ukraine based on the United States' 28-point plan will be found by the deadline set by President Donald Trump.
"Today is Sunday. President Trump's plan is to reach an agreement on Thursday. We are</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 13:15:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BGMEA for immediate inspection of factories</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bgmea-for-immediate-inspection-of-factories</link><description>The Bangladesh Garment Manufacturers and Exporters Association (BGMEA) advised its members to immediately inspect their factory buildings for any structural flaws following Friday's earthquake, warning of possible aftershocks and urging factories to strengthen safety systems.
In a notification iss</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 13:30:44 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>