<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 11:24:51 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Hotel Sarina celebrates Valentine’s Day with Curated Dining and Stay Experiences for Couples</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/hotel-sarina-celebrates-valentines-day-with-curated-dining-and-stay-experiences-for-couples</link><description>This Valentine’s Day, Hotel Sarina Dhaka is spreading love from every corner by presenting a range of thoughtfully curated dining and stay experiences designed exclusively for couples. With diverse cuisines, romantic ambiances, and multiple experiences under one roof, the hotel aims to make V</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 07:46:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Awami League open to talks with Tarique, says Joy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/awami-league-open-to-talks-with-tarique-says-joy</link><description>As Tarique Rahman prepares to lead a BNP government with a two-thirds majority, Sajeeb Wazed Joy says the Awami League would be willing to engage with him despite branding the Feb 12 election a “complete sham”.
In an interview with British broadcaster ITV, the son of deposed prime mi</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 08:01:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Basanta Utsab blooms with hope for 'open cultural windows'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/basanta-utsab-blooms-with-hope-for-open-cultural-windows</link><description>The Basanta Utsab has drawn a packed crowd to the lobby of the Liberation War Museum in Dhaka's Agargaon, with barely any room to move as spring revellers turn out in large numbers.
Most attendees have come dressed in shades of yellow, some with friends, others with parents and family members, whi</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 08:16:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>What perks do Bangladesh MPs enjoy?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/what-perks-do-bangladesh-mps-enjoy</link><description>As the process of forming the 13th Jatiya Sangsad gets underway following the national election, public attention has once again turned to the state privileges enjoyed by members of parliament (MPs).
The Election Commission (EC) has published the two gazette notifications of the 297 newly elected</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 08:31:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ali Riaz calls for implementing reforms following referendum verdict</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/prof-ali-riaz-calls-for-implementing-reforms-following-referendum-verdict</link><description>Chief Adviser’s Special Assistant Professor Ali Riaz on Sunday urged political parties to implement the reforms in line with the referendum verdict, noting that the overwhelming ‘Yes’ vote reflects a clear public mandate for change.
“The citizens of Bangladesh gave, in a cl</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 09:34:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CA congratulates Nahid Islam on NCP’s electoral success</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ca-congratulates-nahid-islam-on-ncps-electoral-success</link><description>Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus has congratulated National Citizen Party (NCP) Convener Nahid Islam on his party’s success in the 13th national parliamentary elections.
“The courage, determination and confidence with which the NCP participated in the 13th national parliament ele</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 09:06:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chakravorty tipped to be next high commissioner to Bangladesh: Report</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/chakravorty-tipped-to-be-next-high-commissioner-to-bangladesh-report</link><description>Senior Indian diplomat Sandeep Chakravorty, currently the country's ambassador to Indonesia, is expected to be appointed as the next high commissioner to Bangladesh, Indian media report.
The move comes as New Delhi seeks to recalibrate ties with Dhaka following a period of strained bilateral relat</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 09:21:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>28 candidates lose deposit money in Gaibandha</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/28-candidates-lose-deposit-money-in-gaibandha</link><description>The deposit money of 28 candidates who participated in the recent Parliamentary Election has been forfeited because they did not receive the required number of votes.
District election officer Mohammad Shahidul Islam said if a candidate gets less than one-eighth of the total valid votes cast, his</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 09:36:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>We recognise overall election outcome: Jamaat Ameer</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/we-recognise-overall-election-outcome-jamaat-ameer</link><description>Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami Ameer Dr Shafiqur Rahman on Saturday said the party recognises the overall outcome of the 13th parliamentary election and respects the rule of law, pledging to serve as a vigilant, principled and peaceful opposition.
In a statement posted on his verified Facebook account</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 09:51:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CA talks with Tarique Rahman, Shafiqur Rahman, Nahid Islam over phone</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ca-talks-with-tarique-rahman-shafiqur-rahman-nahid-islam-over-phone</link><description>Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus has congratulated and expressed thanks and gratitude to BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman, Jamaat Ameer Dr Shafiqur Rahman and NCP Convener Nahid Islam for their important contributions in helping make the election festive and peaceful through their responsible role</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 10:06:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>President will administer oath to ministers, says cabinet secretary</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/president-will-administer-oath-to-ministers-says-cabinet-secretary</link><description>The president will administer the oath to members of the new cabinet, Cabinet Secretary Sheikh Abdur Rashid has said, as discussions continue over who will swear in newly elected MPs.
Speaking at his office in the Secretariat on Saturday, he explained that in the absence of a speaker or deputy spe</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 10:21:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Man dies after post-poll violence in Bagerhat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/supporter-of-independent-candidate-dies-after-post-election-clash-in-bagerhat</link><description>A supporter of an independent candidate has died after being injured in a clash between rival political activists following the Feb 12 election in Bagerhat’s Kachua Upazila.
Osman Sardar, 29, died around 11:30am on Saturday while undergoing treatment at Khulna Medical College Hospital, accor</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 10:36:44 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>