<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 05:18:13 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>BIDA wavers over permitting tobacco sector investment</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bida-wavers-over-permitting-tobacco-sector-investment</link><description>A proposed export-oriented joint venture in tobacco sector has put Bangladesh Investment Development Authority (BIDA) in wavering over investment permission because of restrictions from the top court and health ministry.
Officials say the issue came to the spotlight after a proposal was placed to</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 03:16:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Drone sightings disrupt Munich airport, halt flights and impact thousands</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/drone-sightings-disrupt-munich-airport-halt-flights-and-impact-thousands</link><description>Germany's Munich airport said early on Friday that drone sightings on Thursday evening had forced air traffic control to suspend operations, leading to the cancellation of 17 flights and disrupting travel for nearly 3,000 passengers.
Another 15 arriving flights were diverted to Stuttgart, Nurember</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 03:31:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Venezuela accuses US of flying combat planes near its coast</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/venezuela-accuses-us-of-flying-combat-planes-near-its-coast</link><description>Venezuela's Defence Minister General Vladimir Padrino said on Thursday that five combat planes had been detected near the country's coast, in what he characterised as a threat by the United States.
"They are imperialist combat planes that have dared to come close to the Venezuelan coast," Padrino</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 03:18:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>More evidence suggests Saturn's moon Enceladus could support life</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/more-evidence-suggests-saturns-moon-enceladus-could-support-life</link><description>A fresh look at data collected by NASA's Cassini spacecraft has uncovered more evidence that Saturn's moon Enceladus may be able to support life, with additional complex organic molecules identified from the geyser-like jets of ice grains that spew into space from this small icy world's subsurface</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 03:33:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prof Yunus mourns language movement hero Ahmad Rafiq's death</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/prof-yunus-mourns-language-movement-hero-ahmad-rafiqs-death</link><description>Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus has expressed profound sorrow over the death of Ekushey Padak-winning language movement veteran and eminent intellectual Ahmad Rafiq.
In a condolence message, the chief adviser said Ahmad Rafiq was a distinguished witness and a powerful voice of the Language</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 03:48:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Israeli military stops nearly all boats in aid flotilla, sparking global protests</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/israeli-military-stops-nearly-all-boats-in-aid-flotilla-sparking-global-protests</link><description>Israel faced international condemnation and protests on Thursday after its military intercepted almost all of about 40 boats in a flotilla carrying aid to Gaza and took captive more than 450 foreign activists, including Swedish campaigner Greta Thunberg.
Cameras broadcasting live feeds from the bo</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 04:33:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Google says hackers are sending extortion emails to corporate executives</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/google-says-hackers-are-sending-extortion-emails-to-corporate-executives</link><description>Alphabet's Google said hackers are sending extortion emails to an unspecified number of executives from various companies, claiming to have stolen sensitive data from their Oracle business applications.
In a statement, Google said a group claiming affiliation with the ransomware gang cl0p claimed</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 04:48:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Islami Bank’s official Facebook page hacked</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/islami-banks-official-facebook-page-hacked</link><description>The official Facebook page of Islami Bank Bangladesh was hacked early Friday, with attackers posting a threatening message and altering the page’s profile and cover photos.
A hacking group identifying itself as 'Team MS 47OX' claimed responsibility in a post at 5:42 am, warning that it was m</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 05:03:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Downsizing credit rating industry seen as crucial for financial sector growth</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/downsizing-credit-rating-industry-seen-as-crucial-for-financial-sector-growth</link><description>Asset-quality reviews conducted by foreign firms this year have uncovered hidden bad debts and under-reported non-performing loans (NPLs) in domestic banks and other financial institutions, exposing the futility of the local credit rating industry.
Experts say the industry is overcrowded, creating</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 05:18:13 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>