<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 08:28:43 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Wrong-way van driver dies after collision with truck</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/wrong-way-van-driver-dies-after-collision-with-truck</link><description>A van driver was killed after being hit by a truck while crossing the road in the wrong direction on the Hatikumrul-Dhaka-Pabna road in Ullapara upazila of Sirajganj on Friday.
The deceased was identified as Ranzu Ahmed, 35, son of Yasin Ali from Chariashika Dakshin Para village in the same upazil</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 06:50:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rejoinder (2025-10-31)</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/rejoinder-2025-10-31</link><description>United Commercial Bank (UCB) has ruled out any discussion regarding a possible merger, saying that no such initiative is under consideration by either Bangladesh Bank (BB) or the bank itself.
The country's first-generation private commercial bank (PCB) also reaffirmed that there is no merger issue</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 07:20:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump-Putin summit cancelled after Moscow sent memo to Washington</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-putin-summit-cancelled-after-moscow-sent-memo-to-washington</link><description>The United States cancelled a planned Budapest summit between President Donald Trump and Russian President Vladimir Putin following Russia's firm stance on hardline demands regarding Ukraine, reports Reuters, citing the Financial Times on Friday.
The decision came after a tense call between the</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 06:28:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Delays, dollar depreciation push up EC4J project cost to Tk 12.64 billion</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/delays-dollar-depreciation-push-up-ec4j-project-cost-to-tk-1264-billion</link><description>The cost of the Export Competitiveness for Jobs (EC4J) project, designed to boost Bangladesh's export diversification and employment generation, has ballooned by nearly Tk 1.59 billion due to prolonged delays in implementation and rising foreign exchange costs.
According to official documents subm</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 06:43:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Eight shops gutted in Kurigram fire</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/eight-shops-gutted-in-kurigram-fire</link><description>Eight business establishments were gutted in a fire at Kachakata Bazaar in Nageshwari Upazila of Kurigram early Friday.
On information, a unit of the Nageshwari Fire Service rushed to the scene and brought the blaze under control within an hour, said Saiful Islam, team leader of the fire service.</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 06:58:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India urges Bangladesh to extradite Zakir Naik during his planned visit in Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/india-urges-bangladesh-to-extradite-zakir-naik-during-his-planned-visit-in-dhaka</link><description>India has expressed hope that Bangladesh will hand over Islamic preacher Dr. Zakir Naik if he visits Dhaka in November to participate in a charity event.
At a press briefing on October 30, Indian Ministry of External Affairs spokesperson Randhir Jaiswal said, "Zakir Naik is a fugitive. He is wante</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 07:13:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two dead as autorickshaw crashes into parked truck in Netrokona</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/two-dead-as-autorickshaw-crashes-into-parked-truck-in-netrokona</link><description>Two people have been killed and three others injured after an autorickshaw rammed into a sand-laden truck in Netrokona's Purbadhala Upazila.
The accident occurred around 11pm on Thursday on the Netrakona-Mymensingh regional highway in Narandia, according to Sub-Inspector Md Sabuj Mia from Shyamgan</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 07:28:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Saint Martin reopens for tourists on Saturday with strict eco-friendly rules</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/saint-martin-reopens-for-tourists-on-saturday-with-strict-eco-friendly-rules</link><description>Saint Martin’s Island will reopen to tourists on Saturday after a nine-month closure, with a strict daily cap of 2,000 visitors to help preserve its fragile ecosystem and biodiversity.
To this end, the government has issued 12 directives to ensure responsible and eco-friendly tourism, report</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 07:43:43 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>