<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 07:45:51 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>US to cut tariffs on India to 18pc</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/us-to-cut-tariffs-on-india-to-18pc</link><description>US President Donald Trump on Monday announced a trade deal with India that slashes US tariffs on Indian goods to 18 percent from 50 percent in exchange for India halting Russian oil purchases and lowering trade barriers.
Trump announced the deal on social media following a call with Indian Prime M</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 03:25:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Performance audit for COVID-19 Vaccine Recovery Project launched</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/performance-audit-for-covid-19-vaccine-recovery-project-launched</link><description>The government has initiated a comprehensive performance audit for the "Responsive COVID-19 Vaccine for Recovery Project" under the Asia Pacific Access Facility (APVAX).
This audit, scheduled for the 2025-2026 fiscal year, will assess the efficiency and compliance of vaccine-related recovery opera</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 03:40:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt sets subsidised prices for meat, milk, eggs during Ramadan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-sets-subsidised-prices-for-meat-milk-eggs-during-ramadan</link><description>Like every year, the government will sell key animal protein items at subsidised prices during the upcoming Ramadan to help ease pressure on consumers, officials said on Sunday.
Under the programme, beef will be sold at Tk 650 per kg, milk at Tk 80 per litre, eggs at Tk 96 per dozen (Tk 8.0 per pi</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 03:55:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jhenaidah heritage sites set to disappear for neglect</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/jhenaidah-heritage-sites-set-to-disappear-for-neglect</link><description>Jhenaidah's history is not merely a reflection of the past; it is the very identity of the region. However, the district's centuries-old historical and heritage structures-silent witnesses to the passage of time-are now facing severe neglect.
Due to lack of maintenance, unplanned use, and the abse</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 04:10:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Medicines worth Tk 24m expire in Sunamganj hospital: Official investigation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/medicines-worth-tk-24m-expire-in-sunamganj-hospital-official-investigation</link><description>An official investigation committee established recently that fifteen types of essential medicines worth Tk 24 million were expired at the Sunamganj 250 bed District Sadar Hospital in 2024.
Deputy Commissioner (DC) &amp; District Magistrate Dr. Mohammad Ilias Mia placed the investigation committee rep</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 04:25:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Apparel leaders push for cash incentive changes to aid spinners</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/apparel-leaders-push-for-cash-incentive-changes-to-aid-spinners</link><description>Leaders of the apparel and textile sector have urged the government to overhaul the existing cash incentive structure to enhance the competitiveness of local spinning mills.
Without targeted support, the primary textile sector could continue to lose ground amid rising costs and weak global demand,</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 04:40:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BRIC to invest $5.32m in agro-processing plant at Jamalpur EZ</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bric-to-invest-532m-in-agro-processing-plant-at-jamalpur-ez</link><description>Business Research International Corporation (BRIC), a local company, is set to invest $5.32 million in an agro-processing plant at the Jamalpur Economic Zone (EZ) to establish an agro-processing industry.
To this end, BRIC inked a land lease agreement with the Bangladesh Economic Zones Authority (</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 04:55:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mild earthquake jolts parts of country</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/mild-earthquake-jolts-parts-of-country983</link><description>A mild earthquake measuring 4.1 on the Richter scale was felt in Southwestern part of the country in the early hours of today (Tuesday).
A notification signed by assistant meteorologist of the Bangladesh Meteorological Department (BMD) Farzana Sultana said the earthquake struck at 4:36 am, reports</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 05:10:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Export earnings fall for sixth consecutive month</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/export-earnings-fall-for-sixth-consecutive-month</link><description>Bangladesh’s earnings from goods and services exports have fallen for the sixth month in a row compared with the same period a year earlier.
Latest figures reveal that the country earned $4.41 billion in January 2026, marking a 0.5 per cent dip from the $4.43 billion recorded in January 2025</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 06:11:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ctg port strike enters 4th day</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ctg-port-strike-enters-4th-day</link><description>The strike by Chittagong Port workers and employees in protest against the lease of the New Mooring Container Terminal (NCT) to a foreign company has entered its fourth day.
The 24-hour shutdown began at 8:00 am on Tuesday. Called by the Chittagong Port Protection Struggle Committee, it brought al</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 06:41:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Md Sanaullah Shahid elected chairman of exec committee of Shahjalal Islami Bank</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/md-sanaullah-shahid-elected-chairman-of-exec-committee-of-shahjalal-islami-bank</link><description>Md Sanaullah Shahid has been elected chairman of the executive committee of Shahjalal Islami Bank PLC at the bank’s 404th meeting of the board of directors.

At the same meeting, Mr. Khandaker Sakib Ahmed elected as vice-chairman of Executive Committee of the bank.
Mr Sanaullah was born in</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 06:56:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Election code violations lead to 176 cases, over Tk 1.8mn in fines</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/election-code-violations-lead-to-176-cases-over-tk-18mn-in-fines</link><description>Field-level officials of the Election Commission (EC) have lodged 176 cases and imposed fines totalling Tk 1.83 million for violations of the electoral code of conduct in the run-up to the parliamentary polls.
The figures were shared on Tuesday by Md Saiful Islam, member secretary of the central c</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 07:11:49 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>