<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 09:27:58 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Child deaths will rise this year as aid cuts reverse progress, says Gates</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/child-deaths-will-rise-this-year-as-aid-cuts-reverse-progress-says-gates</link><description>Around 200,000 more children will likely die before their fifth birthday this year than in 2024 as international aid cuts undermine decades of progress, the Gates Foundation said on Thursday.
The projected increase would mark the first rise in preventable child deaths this century, Gates said, fro</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 05:45:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US lawmakers want war powers vote after Trump pledges Venezuela attack 'soon'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/us-lawmakers-want-war-powers-vote-after-trump-pledges-venezuela-attack-soon</link><description>A group of Democratic and Republican US senators filed a resolution on Wednesday that would block US military action against Venezuela without congressional approval, after President Donald Trump said a land campaign would begin shortly.
US troops have carried out at least 21 strikes on alleged dr</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 06:00:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Maduro says call with Trump was 'respectful and cordial'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/maduro-says-call-with-trump-was-respectful-and-cordial</link><description>Venezuelan President Nicolas Maduro on Wednesday confirmed he held a "respectful and cordial" phone call with US President Donald Trump about 10 days ago, framing the conversation as a potential opening for diplomacy.
"If this call means steps are being taken toward a respectful dialogue between o</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 06:15:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CRAB holds 21st Annual General Meeting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/crab-holds-21st-annual-general-meeting</link><description>The Credit Rating Agency of Bangladesh Ltd. (CRAB) held its 21st Annual General Meeting on December 3, 2025. The meeting was chaired by CRAB’s Chairperson Noor A. Alam Chowdhury.Also present were Board Members Tapan Chowdhury (Managing Director, SQUARE Pharmaceuticals Ltd.);  Asif Ibrahi</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 06:30:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pakistan to sell national airline PIA for IMF loans</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/pakistan-to-sell-national-airline-pia-for-imf-loans</link><description>Pakistan has taken a major step to sell its state-owned airline, Pakistan International Airlines (PIA), one more time on December 23, according to state media.
The long-struggling carrier is being privatised under the country’s $7.0 billion International Monetary Fund (IMF) bailout plan, whi</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 06:45:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Over 50 Bangladeshi fishermen jailed in India</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/over-50-bangladeshi-fishermen-jailed-in-india</link><description>The families of more than 50 Bangladeshi fishermen claim that the Indian Coast Guard has arrested and sent them to jail for crossing into the country’s territorial waters while fishing in the Bay of Bengal.
Some of them have spoken to their families via video call from Indian prisons, provid</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 07:45:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Capital market indices dip at opening at DSE, CSE</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/capital-market-indices-dip-at-opening-at-dse-cse</link><description>Trading at both the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) and the Chittagong Stock Exchange (CSE) began on a downward note Thursday, with most listed companies seeing price declines.
At the DSE, the benchmark DSEX index dropped by 38 points in the first hour of trading.
The Shariah-based DSES index slid 9 p</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 08:00:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladeshi youth killed in BSF firing in Lalmonirhat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladeshi-youth-killed-in-bsf-firing-in-lalmonirhat</link><description>A Bangladeshi man was shot dead, allegedly by members of India’s Border Security Force (BSF) along the Patgram border in Lalmonirhat early Thursday.
The deceased was identified as Sabuj Mia, 29, son of Sirajul Islam of Pochabandar village under Jagatber union.
Locals said Sabuj and a group</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 08:15:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Child’s body found in Brahmanbaria; rape, murder alleged</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/childs-body-found-in-brahmanbaria-rape-murder-alleged</link><description>Police have recovered the bloodied body of an eight-year-old child from Nasirnagar upazila of Brahmanbaria.
The girl’s family alleges that she was raped and murdered. A case has been filed over the incident.
Nasirnagar Police Station OC Maksud Ahammad said on Thursday that the girl’s</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 08:30:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bureaucrats, not businessmen, have 'laundered the most money': Nasim Manzur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bureaucrats-not-businessmen-have-laundered-the-most-money-nasim-manzur</link><description>Bureaucrats, not businessmen, have “laundered the most money abroad”, says Apex Group Managing Director Syed Nasim Manzur.
He also highlighted that the entire business community does not want to take on the responsibility for the “theft and looting” conducted by a portion o</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 08:45:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khaleda may be taken to London on Friday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/khaleda-may-be-taken-to-london-on-friday</link><description>BNP Chairperson Begum Khaleda Zia, who has been undergoing treatment at Evercare Hospital’s CCU in Dhaka for the past 12 days, is set to be taken to London for advanced medical care.
According to local media reports, an air ambulance sent by Qatar is scheduled to depart for London on Friday,</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 09:00:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Crimes against humanity: Arrest warrant issued for Joy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/crimes-against-humanity-arrest-warrant-issued-for-joy</link><description>The International Crimes Tribunal has issued an arrest warrant against Sajeeb Wazed Joy, the son of deposed prime minister Sheikh Hasina, in a case over crimes against humanity for shutting off the internet and causing mass killings during the July Uprising.
A three-member Tribunal-1 bench led by</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 09:15:22 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>