<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 16:34:36 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>CA for building democratic social system with spirit of 1969 Mass Uprising</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ca-for-building-democratic-social-system-with-spirit-of-1969-mass-uprising</link><description>Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus today urged all to come forward towards building a truly democratic social system, imbued with the values of the 1969 mass uprising.
"Let us all dedicate ourselves to building a truly democratic social system respecting the values of the 1969 mass uprising,"</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 12:31:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP to solve salt industry problems, if voted to power: Salahuddin</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-to-solve-salt-industry-problems-if-voted-to-power-salahuddin</link><description>BNP Standing Committee member Salahuddin Ahmed on Friday assured salt workers of resolving existing problems in the country’s salt industry once BNP is voted to power through the upcoming general elections.
He made the assurance during his surprise visit to a salt field located in Magnama La</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 12:46:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Child not beaten that way’: teacher in court</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/child-not-beaten-that-way-says-dhaka-school-teacher-facing-abuse-allegations</link><description>A teacher at Dhaka’s Sharmin Academy has appeared in court after being arrested over allegations of child abuse, with police seeking five days to question him.
Pabitra Kumar was arrested in Mirpur early on Friday and presented before a Dhaka Metropolitan Magistrate over accusations of abusin</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 13:01:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Farooki highlights Bangladesh cricket team's security concerns in India</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/cricket/farooki-highlights-bangladesh-cricket-teams-security-concerns-in-india</link><description>Cultural Affairs Adviser Mostofa Sarwar Farooki has raised concerns over the security of the national cricket team ahead of upcoming matches in India, citing recent attacks on people suspected to be Bangladeshis and political remarks warning against hosting Bangladesh in certain cities.
He urged t</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 13:16:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>LafargeHolcim Bangladesh gets Top Employer certification for 2026</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/lafargeholcim-bangladesh-gets-top-employer-certification-for-2026</link><description>LafargeHolcim Bangladesh Plc (LHB) has been certified as a Top Employer for 2026, the company said in a press release.
The certification was awarded by the Top Employers Institute, which describes itself as a global authority on HR strategies and certification, the release said.
The recognition r</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 13:31:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UK finance and business ministers to accompany PM Starmer on China visit</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/uk-finance-and-business-ministers-to-accompany-pm-starmer-on-china-visit</link><description>British finance minister Rachel Reeves will accompany Prime Minister Keir Starmer on his trip to China next week, underscoring UK efforts to strengthen ties with the world's second-largest economy at a time of strained transatlantic relations.
Reeves will join Starmer and business leaders on the t</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 14:30:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Russia, Ukraine to tackle land dispute at UAE talks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/russia-ukraine-to-tackle-land-dispute-at-uae-talks-no-sign-of-compromise</link><description>Ukrainian and Russian negotiators will tackle the vital issue of territory during two days of talks in Abu Dhabi starting on Friday, each side said, with no sign of a softening of their positions to end the four-year war.
Ukraine is under mounting US pressure to reach a peace deal in the war trigg</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 14:45:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rajshahi opener Tanzid hits century in BPL final</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/cricket/rajshahi-opener-tanzid-hits-century-in-bpl-final</link><description>Rajshahi Warriors opener Tanzid Hasan smashed a scintillating century to put his side firmly in contention for a maiden Bangladesh Premier League (BPL) title in the final against Chattogram Royals.
His innings held the innings together after early pressure, keeping Rajshahi on course in a tense ti</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 15:00:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mirza Fakhrul begins election campaign in Thakurgaon</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/mirza-fakhrul-begins-election-campaign-in-thakurgaon</link><description>BNP Secretary General and Thakurgaon-1 constituency candidate Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir formally started his election campaign on Friday afternoon with a road meeting and public outreach event at Sholthari Bazar in Debipur union, the constituency’s southernmost area.
Addressing a large gat</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 15:15:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh rejects Myanmar claims on Rohingya identity</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-rejects-myanmar-claims-on-rohingya-identity</link><description>Bangladesh has strongly rejected Myanmar’s recent submissions to the International Court of Justice, saying references to the Rohingya as “Bengalis” distort history, undermine their identity, and seek to justify atrocities committed during the 2016–17 violence.
“The G</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 15:30:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mother, nine-month-old son found dead in Bagerhat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/mother-nine-month-old-son-found-dead-in-bagerhat</link><description>Police recovered the bodies of a woman and her nine-month-old son in Bagerhat in Bagerhat.
The dead were identified as 22-year-old Subarna Swarnali and her son, identified by the single name Nazif, reports bdnews24.com.
Subarna’s husband, Jewel Hasan Saddam, is the president of the banned C</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 15:45:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rajshahi Warriors clinch BPL title</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/cricket/rajshahi-warriors-clinch-bpl-title</link><description>Rajshahi Warriors clinched the Bangladesh Premier League (BPL) title, beating Chattogram Royals by 63 runs, in the final match of the tournament on Friday.
The final was played at Sher-e-Bangla National Cricket Stadium in Mirpur, with Chattogram opting to field first after winning the toss in the</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 16:00:42 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>