<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 09:20:28 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Ex-MP of Naogaon-6 Omar Faruk held in Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ex-mp-of-naogaon-6-omar-faruk-held-in-dhaka</link><description>The Detective Branch (DB) of police has arrested a former member of parliament (MP) for Naogaon-6 constituency Md Omar Faruk, and four activists of the Awami League (AL)- whose activities remain banned- and its affiliated organisations from different parts of Dhaka in the last 24 hours.
Deputy Com</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 07:57:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ganatantra Mancha unveils first list of 140 candidates for national election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ganatantra-mancha-unveils-first-list-of-140-candidates-for-national-election</link><description>The Ganatantra Mancha alliance on Thursday announced its first list of 140 candidates, declaring its plan to contest all 300 constituencies in the upcoming national election.
The list was announced by the alliance’s coordinator and Rashtra Sangskar Andolon Chief Coordinator Hasnat Quaiyum at</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 07:35:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hartal called on Oct 13 in Bandarban to push for 8-point demand</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/hartal-called-on-oct-13-in-bandarban-to-push-for-8-point-demand</link><description>An organisation called the “Parbatya Nagorik Parishad” (Hill Tracts Citizens’ Council) has called a dawn-to-dusk hartal (general strike) in Bandarban Upazila on Oct 13 to push for an eight-point list of demands, including the scrapping of the Chittagong Hill-tracts Regulation la</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 08:05:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Enforced disappearances: Arrest warrants for Hasina, 29 others sent to law enforcers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/enforced-disappearances-arrest-warrants-for-hasina-29-others-sent-to-law-enforcers</link><description>The International Crimes Tribunal (ICT) has sent arrest warrants for 30 people, including former prime minister Sheikh Hasina, in two cases over enforced disappearances to the Inspector General of police.
Copies of the warrants were also sent to the offices of 12 senior figures in the government,</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 08:20:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Democracy means ensuring people’s freedom, basic rights: Tarique</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/democracy-means-ensuring-peoples-freedom-basic-rights-tarique</link><description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman has said democracy is not just about holding elections but about ensuring people's freedom and fundamental rights.
In a message issued on Thursday marking Shaheed Jihad Day and the 30th anniversary of the martyrdom of Nazir Uddin Ahmed Jihad, Tarique, however, sa</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 08:35:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ADB provides $100m to boost rural small enterprises in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/adb-provides-100m-to-boost-rural-small-enterprises-in-bangladesh</link><description>The Asian Development Bank (ADB) and the Government of Bangladesh on Tuesday signed a $100 million loan agreement to enhance access to medium- and long-term financing for cottage, micro, small, and medium-sized enterprises (CMSMEs) operating outside Dhaka and Chattogram metropolitan areas.
Md Shah</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 09:05:27 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>