<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 15:24:26 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Keep Feb 12 election unchanged: NCP to EC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/keep-feb-12-election-unchanged-ncp-to-ec</link><description>National Citizen Party (NCP) on Wednesday urged the Election Commission (EC) to reconsider the dates for the submission of nomination papers and withdrawal of candidacies, keeping the voting date unchanged for the upcoming national election and the referendum scheduled for February 12.
“They</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 13:30:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Internet shutdowns ruled out as NTMC dissolved</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/internet-shutdowns-ruled-out-as-ntmc-dissolved</link><description>The interim government has approved the final draft of the Bangladesh Telecommunications (Amendment) Ordinance 2025, paving the way for the dissolution of the National Telecommunications Monitoring Centre (NTMC).
The amendment explicitly says internet and telecommunications services cannot be shut</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 13:45:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC calls on banks to stay open on Saturday for nomination deposits</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-calls-on-banks-to-stay-open-on-saturday-for-nomination-deposits</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has asked the Bangladesh Bank to keep banks open across the country on the weekly holiday of Saturday.
In a letter sent on Wednesday, the EC said banks need to remain open for candidates to deposit money through pay orders for nomination deposits and the purchase of vo</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 14:00:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>3 more arrested over attack on two media offices</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/3-more-arrested-over-attack-on-two-media-offices</link><description>Dhaka Metropolitan Police (DMP) has arrested three more people in connection with the attack on the offices of The Daily Star and Prothom Alo in the capital’s Karwan Bazar area.
With the latest arrests, the total number of arrestees has risen to 31.
The arrestees are Mohammad Jakir Hossain</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 13:11:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DRU protests attacks on two dailies, harassment of Nurul Kabir</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dru-protests-attacks-on-prothom-alo-the-daily-star-and-harassment-of-new-age-editor</link><description>The Dhaka Reporters Unity (DRU) on Wednesday protested the arson attacks on Prothom Alo and The Daily Star, as well as the harassment of New Age Editor Nurul Kabir, giving a 72-hour ultimatum for the arrest of those involved.
Forming a human chain in front of the DRU premises in the capital, journ</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 13:26:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>FE planning editor wins Golden Silk Road Bangladesh Media Award</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fe-planning-editor-wins-golden-silk-road-bangladesh-media-award</link><description>Some 30 journalists from different print and electronic media received the Golden Silk Road Bangladesh Media Award.
The award-giving ceremony takes place at Shilpokola Academy in Dhaka on Wednesday (Dec 24) evening. Chinese Ambassador to Bangladesh Yao Wen delivered the ceremonial address at</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 13:41:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Registration deadline on ‘Postal Vote BD’ extended to Dec 31</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/registration-deadline-on-postal-vote-bd-extended-to-dec-31</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has extended the registration period for voting in the 13th National Parliament Election and Referendum through the ‘Postal Vote BD’ app until December 31.
The decision was announced on Wednesday, according to an EC handout.
As of 4:30pm on December 24, a</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 13:56:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UCB holds final meeting of its board of the year</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ucb-holds-final-meeting-of-its-board-of-the-year</link><description>The Board of Directors of United Commercial Bank PLC (UCB) expressed satisfaction over the bank’s deposit growth and conveyed thanks to all stakeholders at the board’s final meeting of the year, held on 23 December 2025 at the bank’s head office, according to a press release.
The</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 14:11:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘We will not step back from reform, even at the cost of life’: Hasnat Abdullah</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/we-will-not-step-back-from-reform-even-at-the-cost-of-life-hasnat-abdullah</link><description>Hasnat Abdullah, chief coordinator of the NCP’s southern region, said on Wednesday that their demand for political reform in Bangladesh will continue, and they will not step back even if it costs them their lives.
He made the remarks at a condolence and solidarity gathering organised by the</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 14:26:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Explosion from crude bomb thrown from flyover kills man in Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/explosion-from-crude-bomb-thrown-from-flyover-kills-man-in-dhaka</link><description>A man was killed in Dhaka after a crude bomb thrown from a flyover exploded on Wednesday night, according to police.
The incident occurred on Wednesday around 7:30pm under the Moghbazar flyover, said Ibne Mizan, deputy commissioner of Dhaka Metropolitan Police’s Tejgaon Division.
The victim</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 14:41:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Yunus urges religious leaders to help create election awareness</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/yunus-urges-religious-leaders-to-help-raise-public-awareness-about-election-referendum</link><description>Chief Advisor Muhammad Yunus has urged religious leaders to help raise awareness about the parliamentary polls and referendum scheduled for Feb 12.
He made the call while meeting the leaders of the Christian community on Christmas Eve on Wednesday evening at the State Guest House Jamuna.
The Chie</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 14:56:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Social Islami Bank’s administrator team meets branch managers, operation managers, sub-branch chiefs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/social-islami-banks-administrator-team-meets-branch-managers-operation-managers-sub-branch-chiefs</link><description>An exchange of views meeting between the Administrator Team of Social Islami Bank and the Branch Managers, Operation Managers, and Sub-Branch In-charges was held on 22 December 2025.
According to a press release, the meeting was conducted via the Zoom platform from the bank’s Head Office.
B</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 15:11:11 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>