<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 09:57:41 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Chattogram blast from ‘gas leak’: Death toll rises to 5</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/chattogram-blast-from-gas-leak-death-toll-rises-to-5</link><description>The death toll following a blast apparently from a gas leak at Halishahar in Chattogram has risen to five with the death of another victim on Wednesday morning.
Shawakhat Hossain,49, who sustained 100 per cent burns, breathed his last at 10:40 am, said Assistant Professor Dr Shawon Bin Rahman, a r</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 07:15:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BB officers’ welfare council threatens agitation over transfer of 3 members</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bb-officers-welfare-council-threatens-agitation-over-transfer-of-3-members</link><description>The Bangladesh Bank Officers' Welfare Council (BBOWC) has warned of launching a protest demanding the resignation of its governor, Dr Ahsan H Mansur, if he does not withdraw the transfer of its three members.
A day after issuing a show-cause notice for arranging a press conference without permissi</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 07:30:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Midland Bank appoints Imtiaz U Ahmed as MD and CEO</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/midland-bank-appoints-imtiaz-u-ahmed-as-md-and-ceo</link><description>Midland Bank PLC has appointed Imtiaz U Ahmed as its new Managing Director and Chief Executive Officer.
The bank announced the appointment in a press statement on Wednesday, saying Mr Ahmed joins the institution at a time when it is seeking to expand its market footprint and accelerate its digital</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 07:00:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DMP chief Sazzat Ali steps down</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dmp-chief-sazzat-ali-steps-down</link><description>Dhaka Metropolitan Police (DMP) Commissioner Sheikh Md Sazzat Ali has stepped down from his post amid a reshuffle in the police ranks after the new government assumed office.
Sazzat sent a letter to the Police Headquarters, requesting to be relieved of his duties, citing “personal and family</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 07:15:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NBR suspends eVAT services for system maintenance</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/nbr-suspends-evat-services-for-system-maintenance</link><description>The National Board of Revenue (NBR) has suspended its online VAT services due to technical maintenance work.
All services of the eVAT system will remain closed from 1:30 pm to 8:00 pm on February 25 to facilitate the migration of the Next Generation Firewall, said an official notice on Wednesday.</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 07:30:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No new probe commission over Pilkhana carnage: Home minister</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/no-new-probe-commission-over-pilkhana-carnage-home-minister</link><description>Home Minister Salahuddin Ahmed on Wednesday said the government will not form a new probe commission over the Pilkhana carnage, as a national independent commission is already in place.
Proper justice will be served for the Pilkhana carnage and necessary steps will be taken to make sure such an in</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 07:45:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat invites PM to its iftar event</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-invites-pm-to-its-iftar-event</link><description>Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami on Wednesday invited Prime Minister Tarique Rahman to attend the party’s iftar programme scheduled to be held on February 28.
Jamaat Secretary General Miah Golam Parwar and Assistant Secretary General Maulana Abdul Halim on Wednesday met Prime Minister Tarique Rahm</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 08:00:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Minimum Fitra fixed at Tk 110 per person</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/minimum-fitra-fixed-at-tk-110-per-person</link><description>The government has fixed the minimum Fitra at Tk 110 per person, while the maximum Fitra at Tk 2,805.
The decision was taken at a meeting of the National Fitra Determination Committee held on Wednesday morning at the Baitul Mukarram National Mosque conference hall.
The committee’s president</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 08:15:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Japan invites PM Tarique, eyes stronger ties with Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/japan-invites-pm-tarique-eyes-stronger-ties-with-bangladesh</link><description>Japan has invited Prime Minister Tarique Rahman to pay an official visit at a mutually convenient time as Tokyo reaffirmed its commitment to further strengthening bilateral relations with Dhaka.
Japanese Ambassador to Bangladesh Shinichi Saida, who met Foreign Minister Dr Khalilur Rahman at the Fo</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 08:30:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BB governor alleges conspiracy behind officers’ protest</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bb-governor-alleges-conspiracy-behind-officers-protest</link><description>Bangladesh Bank (BB) Governor Dr Ahsan H Mansur smells a conspiracy of a vested quarter behind the officers' ongoing protest against him.
In an urgent press briefing following the officers' protest rally on Wednesday afternoon, the central bank governor said a group of the officers are instigating</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 09:00:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>JCI Dhaka North announces new leadership for 2026</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/jci-dhaka-north-announces-new-leadership-for-2026</link><description>The annual general assembly of Junior Chamber International Dhaka North was held recently at Lakeshore Hotel in Dhaka, where the new board of directors for 2026 was formally announced.
The event also marked the 25th anniversary of JCI Dhaka North, according to a press release Wednesday.
Among tho</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 09:15:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nearly 69,000 students to get scholarships</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nearly-69000-students-to-get-scholarships</link><description>A total of 68,768 students have qualified for various scholarships across Bangladesh.
Education Minister ANM Ehsanul Hoque Milon and State Minister for Education Bobby Hajjaj announced the results at the Secretariat on Wednesday afternoon.
Of those selected, 46,200 students from nine general educ</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 09:30:56 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>