<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 01:42:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Govt increases honorarium for recruitment staff</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-increases-honorarium-for-recruitment-staff</link><description>The government has revised the honorarium and remuneration rates for staff involved in recruitment and promotion activities under ministries, divisions, directorates, and departments.
A circular issued by the Ministry of Finance on Monday announced the changes, which take immediate effect.
Accord</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 16:34:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two youths drown in Meherpur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/two-youths-drown-in-meherpur</link><description>The bodies of two young men who went missing while bathing in the Bhairab River near the Ratanpur–Rashikpur switchgate in Mujibnagar upazila of Meherpur have been recovered.
A diving team from the Khulna Fire Service retrieved the bodies between 7:30 pm and 8:30 pm on Monday, officials said.</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 17:19:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Motorcyclist killed in road accident in Sylhet</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/motorcyclist-killed-in-road-accident-in-sylhet</link><description>A 22-year-old motorcyclist, Nazrul Islam, was killed in a road accident on the Tamabil-Sylhet highway in Gowaighat upazila of Sylhet on Monday evening.
The incident occurred near Purbo Mohammadpur Shromikghat area, while Nazrul was traveling from Jaflong Mama Bazar toward Tamabil, reports UNB.
Na</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 16:42:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt retires nine OSD secretaries</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-retires-nine-osd-secretaries</link><description>The interim government has sent nine secretaries, who were previously made officers on special duty (OSD) at various times following the power shift, into retirement.
The list includes senior secretaries Monjur Hossain and Mashiur Rahman, and secretaries Md Shamsul Arefin, Md Mizanur Rahman, Md Az</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 16:57:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>'Make America Produce Again'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/make-america-produce-again</link><description>For four decades, the United States (US) embraced free trade, globalization, and lean supply chains. Offshoring was justified as a path to lower consumer prices while American firms concentrated on so-called “high-value” innovation. That approach delivered short-term gains but left behi</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 17:27:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Should every fire take us by surprise?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/should-every-fire-take-us-by-surprise</link><description>Probe committees by separate government bodies, namely, the Civil Aviation ministry, the Internal Resources Division of the finance ministry and Biman Bangladesh Airlines, have, reportedly, been formed to investigate Saturday (October 18)'s fire incident at the import cargo section called, the carg</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 17:42:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sabotage or gross negligence?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/sabotage-or-gross-negligence</link><description>When the cargo complex of Dhaka's Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport (HSIA) went up in flames last Saturday afternoon, the skies above Bangladesh's busiest gateway turned into a symbol of something far larger than a single accident. The orange glow rising over the capital was not just fire -- i</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 17:57:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>From blazes to infernos</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/from-blazes-to-infernos</link><description>First, the fire originating from a chemical warehouse at Shialbari, Mirpur on Tuesday last gulped 16 lives in an adjacent four-storey apparel factory to which it spread. Then on Thursday a fire gutted Adams Caps and Textile Ltd housed in a seven-storey building in the Chittagong Export Processing Z</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 18:12:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Statistics bureau be made an independent body</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/statistics-bureau-be-made-an-independent-body</link><description>A government taskforce has recommended transforming the Bangladesh Bureau of Statistics (BBS) into an independent statutory body to reduce bureaucratic control by the Statistical and Informatics Division (SID).



On Monday, the taskforce, led by Dr Hossain Zillur Rahman, executive chairman of</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 18:27:57 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>