<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 12:41:58 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Prime Bank holds training on AML &amp; CFT Compliance in Jashore</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/prime-bank-holds-training-on-aml-cft-compliance-in-jashore</link><description>Prime Bank PLC. recently organized a day-long training program on Anti-Money Laundering (AML) and Combating the Financing of Terrorism (CFT) compliance in Jashore.
The training was arranged by the bank’s AML &amp; CFT Division in collaboration with the South Regional Office and Jashore Branch, a</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 09:51:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Police reveal identities of three killed in Khagrachhari violence</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/police-reveal-identities-of-three-killed-in-khagrachhari-violence</link><description>Police have disclosed the identities of three men who were killed in Khagrachhari's Guimara during clashes sparked by the alleged gang rape of a Marma schoolgirl.
The victims, all aged between 20 and 22, were residents of Halfchhari Union in Guimara Upazila. They were named as Teiching Marma, 20,</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 10:21:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Myanmar Army razed Rohingya villages to build security outposts, UN-backed report says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/myanmar-army-razed-rohingya-villages-to-build-security-outposts-un-backed-report-says</link><description>After the 2017 expulsion of the Muslim minority Rohingya from Myanmar's Rakhine state, the military destroyed villages and mosques and repurposed their lands for security outposts, according to a UN-backed investigation released on Monday.
Violence against the Rohingya escalated dramatically in Au</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 10:36:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Customers to get e-bike, sure discounts on purchasing Walton IT products, accessories</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/customers-to-get-e-bike-sure-discounts-on-purchasing-walton-it-products-accessories</link><description>Country’s Superbrand and tech giant Walton has announced ‘Double Dhamaka Offer’ for the customers of Walton desktop, laptop, all-in-one PC, tablet, printer and speaker.
Under this campaign, customers are likely to get Walton Takyon Leo E-bike along with up to 50% sure discounts o</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 10:51:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rizvi alleges ‘deep conspiracies’ surrounding Puja celebrations</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rizvi-alleges-deep-conspiracies-surrounding-puja-celebrations</link><description>BNP Senior Joint Secretary General Ruhul Kabir Rizvi on Tuesday alleged that deep conspiracies are at play in the country centring Durga Puja celebrations.
“Sudden signs of turmoil are being noticed in the hills. These issues are making people anxious and creating concern. At the same time,</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 11:21:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Legal notice sent to Aarong over charging customers for shopping bags</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/legal-notice-sent-to-aarong-over-charging-customers-for-shopping-bags</link><description>A lawyer sent a legal notice to fashion retailer Aarong on Monday, urging the company to stop charging customers for paper shopping bags.
Nishat Farzana, a lawyer of the Supreme Court, sent the notice to Aarong authorities, describing herself as a regular Aarong customer, local news portals said.</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 11:36:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EU confirms it has reinstated sanctions against Iran</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/eu-confirms-it-has-reinstated-sanctions-against-iran</link><description>The European Union confirmed on Monday that it had reinstated sanctions against Iran, following a similar move against Iran by the United Nations.
"Today, the EU reinstated sanctions against Iran in response to its continued non-compliance with the nuclear agreement. The door for diplomatic negoti</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 11:51:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dr Salehuddin warns against misinformation to safeguard economy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/dr-salehuddin-warns-against-misinformation-to-safeguard-economy</link><description>Finance Adviser Dr Salehuddin Ahmed on Monday warned against economic misinformation and stressed the need for greater transparency, stronger auditing and enhanced training for journalists and investigators to safeguard Bangladesh’s economic interests and bolster public trust.
Addressing the</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 12:06:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Israeli forces advance ahead of Trump-Netanyahu Gaza war talks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/israeli-forces-advance-ahead-of-trump-netanyahu-gaza-war-talks</link><description>Israeli tanks thrust closer to the heart of Gaza City on Monday in the hours before Donald Trump was due to host Benjamin Netanyahu at the White House, where the US president has promised "SOMETHING SPECIAL" in his latest bid to end the war.
After nearly two years of failed diplomacy, Washington p</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 12:36:45 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>