<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 05:23:17 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>158 UNOs transferred</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/158-unos-transferred</link><description>The government has transferred upazila nirbahi officers (UNOs) of 158 upazilas across the country's eight divisions ahead of the national election.
The Ministry of Public Administration issued a gazette notification in this regard on Wednesday night (November 26).
The transfers, involving senior</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 02:02:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pope Leo warns of conflicts endangering humanity on first overseas trip</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/pope-leo-warns-of-conflicts-endangering-humanity-on-first-overseas-trip</link><description>Pope Leo lamented during his first trip outside Italy as Catholic leader on Thursday that the world was seeing an unusual number of bloody conflicts, and warned that a third world war was being "fought piecemeal" with humanity's future at risk.
In his first speech given overseas since his election</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 02:17:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump says US will soon take action against Venezuelan drug traffickers on land</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/trump-says-us-will-soon-take-action-against-venezuelan-drug-traffickers-on-land</link><description>The US will "very soon" start taking action to stop suspected Venezuelan drug traffickers on land, US President Donald Trump said on Thursday.
"You probably noticed that people aren't wanting to be delivering by sea, and we'll be starting to stop them by land also. The land is easier, but that's g</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 02:32:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>National Guard member dies as ambush in US capital becomes political flashpoint</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/national-guard-member-dies-as-ambush-in-us-capital-becomes-political-flashpoint</link><description>A National Guard member died on Thursday after being shot near the White House in an ambush that investigators say was carried out by an Afghan national, an attack President Donald Trump blamed on Biden-era immigration vetting failures as he ordered a sweeping review of asylum cases.
Sarah Beckstr</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 02:47:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt school teachers threaten tougher movement from Dec</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-school-teachers-threaten-tougher-movement-from-dec</link><description>The teachers of government secondary schools threatened to wage tougher movement from next month (December), if their demands are not realised.
They issued the warning at a rally on the premises of Shikkha Bhaban, the headquarters of the Directorate of Secondary and Higher Education (DSHE), on Abd</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 03:02:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump administration to carry out sweeping immigration review after National Guard shooting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/trump-administration-to-carry-out-sweeping-immigration-review-after-national-guard-shooting</link><description>US President Donald Trump has ordered a widespread review of asylum cases approved under former President Joe Biden's administration and Green Cards issued to citizens of 19 countries, Department of Homeland Security officials said on Thursday.
Officials say the Afghan immigrant suspected of shoot</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 03:17:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Farewell address of CJ scheduled for Dec 14</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/farewell-address-of-cj-scheduled-for-dec-14</link><description>Chief Justice (CJ) Dr Syed Refaat Ahmed will deliver his farewell address on December 14 at the Supreme Court (SC) auditorium in the capital.
For this purpose, he has convened a session to be attended by senior judicial officers, including district judges, metropolitan sessions judges, chief judic</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 03:32:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sylhet Central Bus Terminal becomes shabby barely three years after opening</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/sylhet-central-bus-terminal-becomes-shabby-barely-three-years-after-opening</link><description>Lights and ceiling fans are falling apart while many chairs have got stolen or broken around. This is the picture of the passenger waiting room at the Sylhet Central Bus Terminal at Kodomtoli where the bathrooms are also in a deplorable state, and plaster on the walls is peeling off.
The central b</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 03:47:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chinese orange cultivation brings success to Jhenaidah grower</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/chinese-orange-cultivation-brings-success-to-jhenaidah-grower</link><description>Habibur Rahman, a grower of Begampur village in Jhenaidah's Maheshpur, will make Tk 2 million this year from his Chinese orange cultivation on five bighas, after an investment of only half a million.
Inspired by YouTube videos, he started growing the citrus fruit four years ago. Now, rows of orang</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 04:02:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>General sworn in as new Guinea-Bissau leader, ousted president arrives in Senegal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/africa/general-sworn-in-as-new-guinea-bissau-leader-ousted-president-arrives-in-senegal</link><description>Guinea-Bissau’s military installed Major-General Horta Inta-a as transitional president on Thursday, a day after soldiers toppled the civilian leadership in a swift power grab made before the results of a weekend election could be announced.
The president who was ousted in the coup, Umaro Si</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 04:17:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Capitalise on BD's ceramics industry's potential: Commerce adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/capitalise-on-bds-ceramics-industrys-potential-commerce-adviser</link><description>Commerce Adviser Sk Bashir Uddin urged businesspersons on Thursday to capitalise on the growing potential of Bangladesh's ceramics industry.
"The government remains supportive of the private sector, but businesses must come forward with logical, acceptable and realistic proposals," he said while i</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 04:32:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NEIR won’t push up handset prices: BTRC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/neir-wont-push-up-handset-prices-btrc</link><description>The Bangladesh Telecommunication Regulatory Commission (BTRC) has reiterated its assurance in ensuring that the introduction of the National Equipment Identity Register (NEIR) on 16 December would not lead to an increase in mobile handset prices, despite persistent concerns among buyers and section</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 04:47:52 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>