<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 07:21:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Large-scale manufacturing down 0.78pc in Oct</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/large-scale-manufacturing-down-078pc-in-oct</link><description>The large-scale manufacturing (LSM) sector contracted by 0.78 per cent in October year on year due to a sharp slowdown in the garment industry, according to the latest Bangladesh Bureau of Statistics (BBS) data. LSM, which accounts for about 11 per cent of the gross domestic product (GDP), was drag</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 02:49:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Weekly Market Review: Stocks gain amid major political developments</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/weekly-market-review-stocks-gain-amid-major-political-developments</link><description>The benchmark equity index of Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) rebounded this week, driven by a wave of optimism among investors following growing political clarity surrounding the upcoming national elections.
Market analysts said the investors' optimism over evolving political developments offered some</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 04:20:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Some 767,591 expats, individuals register for postal voting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/some-767591-expats-individuals-register-for-postal-voting</link><description>A total of 767,591 individuals have registered with the 'Postal Vote BD' system to exercise their voting rights remotely for Bangladesh's parliamentary election scheduled for 12 February 2026.
Of the total, 5,42,942 are Bangladeshis living abroad (NRB) while the remaining 2,24,649 are individuals</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 04:35:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>St Martin’s-bound vessel in Cox’s Bazar catches fire</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/st-martins-bound-vessel-in-coxs-bazar-catches-fire</link><description>A fire broke out on a passenger vessel bound for St Martin’s Island in Cox’s Bazar on Saturday morning.
Hossain Islam Bahadur, general secretary of the Sea Cruise Operator Owners' Association of Bangladesh (SCOAB), said the fire broke out on The Atlantic Cruise around 7:00 am while it</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 04:50:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Man dies in fire on St Martin’s-bound vessel in Cox’s Bazar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/man-dies-in-fire-on-st-martins-bound-vessel-in-coxs-bazar</link><description>A man has been killed after a fire broke out on a St Martin's Island-bound vessel anchored in Cox’s Bazar.
The fire started around 6:30 am on Saturday on the Atlantic Cruise ship while it was anchored on the Bakkhali River near the Nunia Chhara BIWTA jetty, according to Syed Muhammad Morshed</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 05:07:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Inquilab Moncho clears Shahbagh for Tarique Rahman’s visit to Osman Hadi’s grave</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/inquilab-moncho-shifts-shahbagh-blockade-for-tarique-rahmans-visit-to-osman-hadis-grave</link><description>Inquilab Moncho on Saturday moved its blockade from Shahbagh to in front of Aziz Super Market ahead of the arrival of BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman.
The platform withdrew the blockade from Shahbagh around 8:30 am and took position near Aziz Super Market.
In a post on its official Facebook pa</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 05:22:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Myanmar goes to the polls amid civil war and humanitarian crisis</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/myanmar-goes-to-the-polls-amid-civil-war-and-humanitarian-crisis</link><description>Myanmar heads to the polls on Sunday as it battles a civil war that has ravaged parts of the country as well as one of Asia's worst humanitarian crises.
Already one of Southeast Asia's poorest countries, Myanmar has been hammered by a conflict triggered by a 2021 coup in which the military ousted</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 05:37:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Zelenskiy to hold talks with Trump on Sunday on ending Ukraine war</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/zelenskiy-to-hold-talks-with-trump-on-sunday-on-ending-ukraine-war</link><description>Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelenskiy wants to discuss territorial issues, the main stumbling block in talks to end the war, with US President Donald Trump in Florida on Sunday, as a 20-point peace framework and a security guarantee deal near completion.
Announcing the meeting, Zelenskiy said "a</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 05:52:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique Rahman offers prayers at graves of Osman Hadi, Kazi Nazrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-rahman-offers-prayers-at-graves-of-osman-hadi-kazi-nazrul-at-du</link><description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman on Saturday visited Dhaka University and offered prayers at the grave of Sharif Osman Hadi, spokesperson of Inquilab Moncho, on the third day of his return to the country.
He also offered prayers at the grave of National Poet Kazi Nazrul Islam, located beside the</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 06:09:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Thailand and Cambodia sign truce to halt fierce border conflict</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/thailand-and-cambodia-sign-truce-to-halt-fierce-border-conflict</link><description>Thailand and Cambodia agreed on Saturday to halt weeks of fierce border clashes, the worst fighting in years between the Southeast Asian countries that has included fighter jets sorties, exchange of rocket fire and artillery barrages.
"Both sides agree to maintain current troop deployments without</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 06:24:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique heads to Election Commision to enrol as voter</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-heads-to-election-commision-to-enrol-as-voter</link><description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman has set off for the Election Commission headquarters to register as a voter after visiting the graves of slain Inquilab Moncho leader Osman Hadi and National Poet Kazi Nazrul Islam.
His motorcade departed from the National Poet’s Mausoleum complex at Dhaka</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 06:39:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dense fog disrupts flights at Dhaka airport</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/dense-fog-disrupts-flights-at-dhaka-airport</link><description>Several international flights were unable to land at Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport on Saturday morning due to dense fog, airport sources said.
The flights were diverted to Chattogram, Kolkata, and Bangkok as visibility dropped sharply over the capital, Civil Aviation Authority of Banglade</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 06:54:26 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>