<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 14:34:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Toyota Bangladesh Limited &amp; BIDA hold meeting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/toyota-bangladesh-limited-bida-hold-meeting</link><description>The management of Toyota Bangladesh Limited (TBL), a 100% subsidiary of Toyota Tsusho Asia Pacific and Toyota Tsusho Japan, recently met with Ashik Chowdhury, Chairman of the Bangladesh Investment Development Authority (BIDA), to discuss the sustainable future of the automotive industry in Banglade</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 12:25:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt approves sweeping administrative reforms</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-approves-sweeping-administrative-reforms</link><description>The interim government has approved a wide-ranging set of administrative reforms aimed at improving transparency, efficiency and accountability across key state institutions, as preparations intensify for the next national election.
At the meeting of the National Implementation Committee on Admini</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 12:40:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat lays out development roadmap if elected</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-chief-pledges-better-education-tax-cuts-and-social-security-if-elected</link><description>Jamaat-e-Islami has outlined an ambitious development agenda it says it will pursue if the party is given power in the next parliament, with Shafiqur Rahman pledging sweeping reforms across education, health, jobs, welfare and governance.
On Tuesday, Ameer Shafiqur presented the party’s elec</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 11:26:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Meghna Bank launches Visa Direct for Account, a first in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/meghna-bank-launches-visa-direct-for-account-a-first-in-bangladesh</link><description>Meghna Bank PLC has become the first bank in Bangladesh to launch Visa Direct for Account (VDA), a fast, secure, and cost-effective digital payment solution for near real-time outward remittances, according to a press release.
Introduced in partnership with Visa, the global leader in money movemen</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 11:41:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Telling again, no uncertainty over election: Press Secretary</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/telling-again-no-uncertainty-over-election-press-secretary</link><description>The interim government on Tuesday ruled out any uncertainty over the February-12 national election, urging the media to scrutinise the motives of individuals spreading confusions about the polls through social media, which it described as part of propaganda.
“There is no uncertainty regardin</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 11:56:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pay Commission recommendations need review before implementation: Dr Salehuddin</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/pay-commission-recommendations-need-review-before-implementation-dr-salehuddin</link><description>Finance Adviser Dr Salehuddin Ahmed on Tuesday said the government would not immediately implement the Pay Commission’s recommendations once its report is submitted, as the proposals would first undergo scrutiny by relevant committees.
“The report will be examined by various committees</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 12:11:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Government allocates Tk 10m to secure Dhaka flat for Hadi’s widow, child</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/government-allocates-tk-10m-to-secure-dhaka-flat-for-hadis-widow-child</link><description>The government is providing a special allocation of Tk 10 million to secure a flat for the family of Sharif Osman bin Hadi.
The funds will cover the purchase and furnishing of a 1,215sqft flat in Doel Tower, Lalmatia, Dhaka, bdnews24.com reports. 
The allocation was approved by the finance m</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 12:26:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump, sharing leaked texts and AI mock-ups, vows ‘no going back’ on Greenland</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-sharing-leaked-texts-and-ai-mock-ups-vows-no-going-back-on-greenland</link><description>U.S. President Donald Trump on Tuesday vowed there was “no going back” on his goal to control Greenland, refusing to rule out taking the Arctic island by force and rounding on allies as European leaders struggled to respond.
Trump’s ambition - spelled out in social media posts an</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 12:41:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>RAB vows joint raids in Jungle Salimpur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rab-chief-pledges-joint-raids-to-clear-jungle-salimpur-safe-haven-for-criminals-after-nayek-motaleb-murder</link><description>Rapid Action Battalion (RAB) Director General AKM Shahidur Rahman has announced joint operations to clear Jungle Salimpur of “criminals and illegal occupation”, a day after a member of the force was killed there.
Speaking to journalists at the RAB‑7 headquarters in Patenga on Tuesday a</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 12:56:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pubali Bank achieves international PCI-DSS certification</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/pubali-bank-achieves-international-pci-dss-certification</link><description>Pubali Bank PLC has been serving as a symbol of trust, service excellence, and ethical banking in Bangladesh’s financial sector for nearly seven decades. In its continued commitment to customer data protection, ethical banking practices, and adherence to international standards, the bank has</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 13:11:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NRBC Bank observes 6th anniversary of Al-Amin Islamic Banking</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/nrbc-bank-observes-6th-anniversary-of-al-amin-islamic-banking</link><description>NRBC Bank PLC celebrated the 6th anniversary of the launch of its fully Shariah-compliant “Al-Amin Islamic Banking” window.
According to a press release, a special prayer ceremony was held at the bank’s head office to mark the occasion, according to a press release.
The Chairman</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 13:26:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rescue workers clearing Karachi inferno ruins, 57 missing feared dead</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/rescue-workers-clearing-karachi-inferno-ruins-57-missing-feared-dead</link><description>Firefighters were clearing the charred ruins of a Karachi mall on Tuesday as they tried to locate nearly 60 people still missing and feared dead after a fire that burned for nearly two days and killed 27 people.
The Pakistani port city’s largest fire in over a decade began late on Saturday a</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 13:41:53 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>