<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 12:45:20 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Morocco win U-20 World Cup after beating Argentina in final</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/football/morocco-win-u-20-world-cup-after-beating-argentina-in-final</link><description>Morocco became the first Arab nation to win the under-20 World Cup after beating Argentina 2-0 in the final in Santiago on Sunday.
Yassir Zabiri opened the scoring in the 12th minute with a free kick and doubled Morocco's lead 17 minutes later from a close-range shot.
Argentina, who hold the reco</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 09:42:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dengue: 4 more die; 942 hospitalised</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/dengue-4-more-die-942-hospitalised</link><description>Four more deaths from dengue were reported in the 24 hours till Monday morning, raising the total number of deaths from the mosquito-borne disease to 249 this year.
During this period, 942 more patients were hospitalised with viral fever, bringing the total number of cases to 60,791, according to</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 09:57:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>German ambassador meets Mahfuj Alam</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/german-ambassador-meets-mahfuj-alam</link><description>German Ambassador to Dhaka Ruediger Lotz today (Monday) met Information and Broadcasting Adviser Md Mahfuj Alam at his office at Secretariat.
During the meeting, Mahfuj Alam said that the government is working towards holding the national elections in the first half of February 2026. There is no u</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 10:12:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Home adviser reiterates govt’s readiness to hold upcoming polls in February</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/home-adviser-reiterates-govts-readiness-to-hold-upcoming-polls-in-february</link><description>Home Adviser Lieutenant General (Retd) Md Jahangir Alam Chowdhury today (Monday) reiterated the government’s readiness to hold the next general election slated for February next.
“We will face no problem in holding the next polls,” he said while replying to a question from journa</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 10:27:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt plans to lower passport costs for overseas Bangladeshis</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-plans-to-lower-passport-costs-for-overseas-bangladeshis</link><description>The government plans to reduce passport issuance fees for Bangladeshi expatriates living abroad, Home Affairs Adviser Lieutenant General (retd) Md Jahangir Alam Chowdhury said on Monday.
The announcement came following a meeting of the core committee on law and order at the Secretariat, reports UN</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 10:42:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cyber defenders sound the alarm as F5 hack exposes broad risks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/cyber-defenders-sound-the-alarm-as-f5-hack-exposes-broad-risks</link><description>A more than year-long digital intrusion into cybersecurity company F5, publicized last week and blamed on Chinese spies, has defenders across the industry hunting for signs of compromise among the many corporate networks that use its products.
Several worry that more disclosures are coming.
So fa</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 11:12:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No concerns over poll security: EC secretary</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/no-security-concerns-ahead-of-february-polls-says-ec-secretary</link><description>Election Commission Secretary Akhtar Ahmed has said law-enforcing agencies do not find the current situation “worrying” ahead of the parliamentary polls, expected in the first half of February.
On Monday, he said a “conducive environment” exists for holding the polls, repor</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 11:27:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka Bank empowers IUB students through 'Financial Literacy &amp; Career Counselling Program'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/dhaka-bank-empowers-iub-students-through-financial-literacy-career-counselling-program</link><description>Dhaka Bank PLC successfully organized a “Financial Literacy &amp; Career Counselling Program for the Young Students of Independent University, Bangladesh (IUB)” on 14 October 2025 at the IUB Campus, Bashundhara R/A, collaborated by the Office of Career Guidance, Placement and Alumni Relatio</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 11:42:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pakistan says Afghan Taliban must rein in militants for ceasefire to hold</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/pakistan-says-afghan-taliban-must-rein-in-militants-for-ceasefire-to-hold</link><description>Pakistan's ceasefire agreement with the Afghan Taliban hinges on their ability to rein in militant attacks on Islamabad from their soil, Defence Minister Khawaja Muhammad Asif told Reuters on Monday.
A Taliban spokesperson and its defence ministry did not immediately respond to a request for comme</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 12:12:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>72nd Risk Management Committee meeting of Shahjalal Islami Bank held</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/72nd-risk-management-committee-meeting-of-shahjalal-islami-bank-held</link><description>The 72nd meeting of the Risk Management Committee (RMC) of Shahjalal Islami Bank PLC was held on 15th October 2025 at its Corporate Head Office of the bank.
The meeting was presided over by Engineer Md. Towhidur Rahman, Chairman of the Risk Management Committee of the bank, according to a media re</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 12:27:20 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>