<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 07:16:13 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>UK police say officers accidentally shot victim who died in synagogue attack</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/uk-police-say-officers-accidentally-shot-victim-who-died-in-synagogue-attack</link><description>British police said on Friday they accidentally shot a victim who died in the attack on a synagogue in Manchester, as well as one of the survivors, as they attempted to stop an attacker who appeared to be wearing an explosive belt.
In Thursday's attack two men, Adrian Daulby, 53, and Melvin Cravit</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 04:38:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prices of essentials jump in Khulna kitchen markets amid rains</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/prices-of-essentials-jump-in-khulna-kitchen-markets-amid-rains</link><description>Prices of daily essentials have increased unusually in Khulna kitchen markets due to a supply shortage and incessant rain, leaving low- and middle-income people struggling.
Visiting different city markets on Friday, it was found that vegetables are not available for less than Tk 60 per kg while th</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 04:53:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Former leader of banned BCL, two others held with Yaba in Savar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/former-leader-of-banned-bcl-two-others-held-with-yaba-in-savar</link><description>Police in a drive arrested three people including a former leader of the banned Bangladesh Chhatra League (BCL) along with 22 Yaba pills from Bhabanipur in Savar early Saturday.
The arrestees were Mazedul Islam alias Molla Hridoy, 27, former deputy social welfare affairs secretary of Savar Governm</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 05:08:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prices of essentials jump in Khulna kitchen markets amid rains</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/prices-of-essentials-jump-in-khulna-kitchen-markets-amid-rains-1</link><description>Prices of daily essentials have increased unusually in Khulna kitchen markets due to a supply shortage and incessant rain, leaving low- and middle-income people struggling.
Visiting different city markets on Friday, it was found that vegetables are not available for less than Tk 60 per kg while th</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 05:38:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Exploring Chattogram’s rural charm and history on Nazirhat Commuter</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/exploring-chattograms-rural-charm-and-history-on-nazirhat-commuter</link><description>Jhal muri, jhal muri (spicy puffed rice) - the man in an off-white shirt and checked lungi chanted. Holding a finger of her father, a toddler walked around, her pink squeaky shoes making the adorable sound. Several bare-chested and lungi-clad men slept on kanthas on the floor.
The scenes unfolded</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 05:15:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>11 fall ill with anthrax symptoms in Gaibandha</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/11-fall-ill-with-anthrax-symptoms-in-gaibandha</link><description>At least 11 people in Gaibandha’s Sundarganj Upazila have developed symptoms of anthrax after butchering the meat of a diseased cow.
The affected are all residents of Kishamat Sadar village in Belka Union, according to Upazila Health and Family Planning Officer Dibakar Basak.
Belka Union co</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 05:30:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka's air quality still in 'moderate' range</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dhakas-air-quality-still-in-moderate-range</link><description>Dhaka's air quality continued to be in the 'moderate' zone on Saturday morning.
With an air quality index (AQI) score of 66 at 9:14 am, Dhaka ranked 32nd on the list of cities worldwide with the worst air quality.
Pakistan's Lahore, India's Delhi and Uzbekistan's Tashkent occupied the first three</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 05:45:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Japan's Koizumi, Takaichi face off in race to be next PM</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/japans-koizumi-takaichi-face-off-in-race-to-be-next-pm</link><description>Japan's next prime minister is likely to be the nation's first female leader or the youngest premier in 140 years as the ruling party held a runoff vote for leader on Saturday.
The Liberal Democratic Party was choosing between hardline nationalist Sanae Takaichi, 64, and the telegenic political sc</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 06:15:41 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>