<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 11:47:26 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>JCI Dhaka North announces new leadership for 2026</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/jci-dhaka-north-announces-new-leadership-for-2026</link><description>The annual general assembly of Junior Chamber International Dhaka North was held recently at Lakeshore Hotel in Dhaka, where the new board of directors for 2026 was formally announced.
The event also marked the 25th anniversary of JCI Dhaka North, according to a press release Wednesday.
Among tho</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 09:15:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nearly 69,000 students to get scholarships</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nearly-69000-students-to-get-scholarships</link><description>A total of 68,768 students have qualified for various scholarships across Bangladesh.
Education Minister ANM Ehsanul Hoque Milon and State Minister for Education Bobby Hajjaj announced the results at the Secretariat on Wednesday afternoon.
Of those selected, 46,200 students from nine general educ</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 09:30:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Three of a family burnt in Chandpur gas cylinder explosion</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/three-of-a-family-burnt-in-chandpur-gas-cylinder-explosion</link><description>Three members of a family have been burnt in an explosion caused by a gas cylinder leak in Chandpur’s Kachua Upazila.
The incident occurred around 4am on Wednesday at a house in Hossainpur village, said Kachua South Union Administrative Officer (Additional Duty) Md Nasir Hossain, bdnews24.co</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 09:22:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>JU student ‘confined’ in house, hand burnt in alleged assault</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ju-student-confined-in-house-hand-burnt-in-alleged-assault</link><description>A female student of Jahangirnagar University has allegedly been confined at a property near the campus and subjected to assault, leaving her hand burnt.
The incident took place on Tuesday around 11:30pm in Islamnagar near the campus, according to University Proctor Prof AKM Rashidul Alam, bdnews24</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 09:37:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mostaqur Rahman new governor of central bank</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/mostaqur-rahman-new-governor-of-central-bank</link><description>The government has appointed Md Mostaqur Rahman as the next governor of the central bank.
Financial Institutions Division (FID) of the Ministry of Finance issued a notification in this regard on Wednesday.
He will replace Dr Ahsan H Mansur, the present governor appointed by the interim government</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 09:52:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>PM adorns new IGP with rank badge</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/pm-adorns-new-igp-with-rank-badge</link><description>Prime Minister Tarique Rahman on Wednesday formally adorned the rank badge on newly appointed Inspector General of Police (IGP) Md Ali Hossain Fakir at his office in the Cabinet Division of the Bangladesh Secretariat.
Home Minister Salahuddin Ahmed and Home Secretary Monjur Morshed Chowdhury were</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 10:07:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh seeks more Chinese investments, security cooperation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-seeks-more-chinese-investments-security-cooperation</link><description>Home Minister Salahuddin Ahmed on Wednesday called on Chinese investors to increase their presence in Bangladesh, highlighting the role of security and stability in attracting foreign capital.
The request came during a meeting with China’s Ambassador to Bangladesh Yao Wen at the Ministry of</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 10:22:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US tariff issue still evolving: Commerce Minister</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/us-tariff-issue-still-evolving-commerce-minister</link><description>The issue of reciprocal tariffs imposed by the United States and related trade agreements is still evolving, Commerce Minister Khandaker Abdul Moktadir has said, noting that the government will review the matter further before taking any decision.
He made the remarks in the context of the recent r</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 10:37:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Free voting, acceptance of results key achievements of election: SHUJAN</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/free-voting-acceptance-of-results-key-achievements-of-election-shujan</link><description>The most notable achievement of the recent parliamentary election was that voters were able to cast their ballots freely and that political parties accepted the results, said Badiul Alam Majumdar, secretary of Shushashoner Jonno Nagorik (SHUJAN), on Wednesday.
“Despite various questions surr</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 10:52:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fakhrul wants ‘impartial’ probe into Pilkhana killings</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/mirza-fakhrul-calls-for-impartial-probe-into-pilkhana-killings</link><description>BNP Secretary General and Local Government Minister Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir has called for an “impartial” investigation into the 2009 Pilkhana killings.
He made the call on Wednesday after laying wreaths at the memorial for the slain Army officers at the Banani Military Graveyard.</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 11:07:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Written exams for 50th BCS to begin on Apr 9</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/written-exams-for-50th-bcs-to-begin-on-apr-9</link><description>The written exams for the 50th Bangladesh Civil Service (BCS) will begin on Apr 9, the Public Service Commission (PSC) has announced.
In a notice issued on Wednesday, the commission said it has decided to proceed with the written tests on the previously announced tentative date.
Candidates requir</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 11:22:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Eid travel: Advance train tickets go online Mar 3</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/eid-travel-advance-train-tickets-go-online-mar-3</link><description>Advance train tickets for Eid-ul-Fitr travel will go on sale from Mar 3, with all tickets to be sold online, the railway ministry has announced.
Return tickets will be available from Mar 13, bdnews24.com reports. 
Bangladesh Railway will operate five pairs of special trains alongside regular</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 11:37:07 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>