<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 19:37:32 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Parts of Dhaka waterlogged after evening showers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/parts-of-dhaka-waterlogged-after-evening-showers</link><description>Intense rainfall on Tuesday evening led to waterlogging in some parts of Dhaka, causing immense suffering for commuters.
Streets in areas such as Mouchak, Malibagh, Shantinagar, Moghbazar, Dainik Bangla Intersection, and Kakrail were submerged, forcing residents to wade through water while trying</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 16:32:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Reversing the slide in service export</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/reversing-the-slide-in-service-export</link><description>While a lack of government initiative is often blamed for the sluggish performance of the country's export of services, absence of innovative approaches by the private sector is considered no less responsible. The combined effect of these two factors appears to be keeping the country's service expo</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 16:47:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tackling irregularities, corruption in health sector</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/tackling-irregularities-corruption-in-health-sector</link><description>Hospitals and other health service providers in the public sector have long earned infamy for corruption as well as substandard services. Reports on such irregularities abound. One might recall here the Transparency International Bangladesh (TI,B)'s study report of November 2020 during the outbreak</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 17:02:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khagrachhari blockade suspended until Oct 5</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/khagrachhari-blockade-suspended-until-oct-5</link><description>The Jumma Chhatra Janata has suspended its blockade in Khagrachhari until Oct 5, following four days of protests.
In a media statement issued at 9pm on Tuesday via their Facebook page, the group announced the decision, bdnews24.com reports. 
The statement said the suspension came after recei</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 17:17:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UN assures support for Bangladesh's LDC graduation, democratic transition thru polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/un-assures-support-for-bangladeshs-ldc-graduation-democratic-transition-thru-polls</link><description>United Nations Secretary-General António Guterres has extended his full support for and solidarity with Bangladesh’s ongoing reform initiatives and democratic transition  through upcoming elections. 
In separate meetings with Chief Adviser Dr Muhammad Yunus, top UN officials</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 18:22:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Palestinian Ambassador meets Khaleda Zia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/palestinian-ambassador-meets-khaleda-zia</link><description>Palestinian Ambassador to Bangladesh, Mr. Yousef S. Y. Ramadan today (Tuesday) met BNP Chairperson and former Prime Minister Begum Khaleda Zia at her Gulshan residence in the capital.
BNP Media Cell member Shayrul Kabir Khan confirmed the meeting, saying it lasted around an hour, BSS reports.&amp;nbsp</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 18:37:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP’s Moyeen Khan urges recognition of changed political reality</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnps-moyeen-khan-urges-recognition-of-changed-political-reality</link><description>While visiting the Durga Puja mandap at Seba Sangha in Narsingdi town on Tuesday night, BNP Standing Committee member Dr Abdul Moyeen Khan said that Bangladesh’s political and social reality has changed within the last year and people must remain alert to ensure justice and democracy.
&amp;ldquo</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 18:52:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Farashuddin finds 15 rogue companies imperilling economy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/farashuddin-finds-15-rogue-companies-imperilling-economy</link><description>When political power converges with economic interests, the result is the rise of corporations that function much like the East India Company of colonial times, warns Dr. Mohammed Farashuddin.
Speaking at a Policy Research Institute (PRI) event in Dhaka on Tuesday, the former Bangladesh Bank Gov</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 19:37:32 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>