<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 04:23:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>BD to get $3.0b in SDR for job-centric development</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bd-to-get-30b-in-sdr-for-job-centric-development</link><description>Bangladesh is going to get US$3.0 billion in special drawing right (SDR) credits from the World Bank for its job-centric development works, officials say.
However, the Bank has offered both soft-and hard-term lending under its 3-year aid package, categorizing Bangladesh as a 'Blend Country' on the</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 18:21:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt nod for 5 Islamic banks’ merger today</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/govt-nod-for-5-islamic-banks-merger-today</link><description>Final government nod to the formation of a new bank by merging financially distressed five Islamic banks is set to be given today, officials say about a major development in reforms spearheaded by the interim regime.
The Advisory Council, in its meeting today (Thursday) with Chief Adviser of the p</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 01:53:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Revenue boss berates field staff for ignoring instructions</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/revenue-boss-berates-field-staff-for-ignoring-instructions</link><description>National Board of Revenue (NBR) Chairman Md Abdur Rahman Khan Wednesday berated field-level officials for disregarding directives on matters of tax collection and urged businesspeople to act as whistleblowers against wrongdoings.
"We often receive complaints that even after we issue instructions,</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 01:32:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCC to place its final recommendations on July Charter by Oct 15</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ncc-to-place-its-final-recommendations-on-july-charter-by-october-15</link><description>The National Consensus Commission (NCC) will give its final recommendations to the government by October 15, based on a five-point proposal from its expert panel for the implementation of the July National Charter 2025.
The announcement came on Wednesday after the commission concluded its fifth me</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 02:02:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt appoints administrator at Nassa Group to clear workers' dues</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/govt-appoints-administrator-at-nassa-group-to-clear-workers-dues</link><description>The government has appointed Arif Ahmed Khan, Additional Inspector-General of the Department of Inspection for Factories and Establishments (DIFE), as the administrator of Nassa Group to oversee the payment of dues to its workers.
The Ministry of Labour and Employment issued on Wednesday a circula</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 02:17:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Local govt expert Prof Tofail Ahmed passes away</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/local-govt-expert-prof-tofail-ahmed-passes-away</link><description>Eminent local government expert and distinguished academic Professor Tofail Ahmed passed away at a hospital in the capital on Wednesday night. He was 71.
Professor Ahmed breathed his last at United Hospital in Dhaka around 9:30 pm, his son-in-law Lieutenant Colonel Sarwar Jahan confirmed to the me</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 02:32:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gold price surges by Tk 6,906 per bhori to new record of Tk 2,09,101</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/gold-price-surges-by-tk-6906-per-bhori-to-new-record-of-tk-209101</link><description>The price of gold in Bangladesh has reached a new record high, as the Bangladesh Jewellers Association (BAJUS) raised the rate of 22-carat gold by Tk 6,906 per bhori (11.664 grams) within just 24 hours.
In a notification issued on Wednesday night, BAJUS announced that the new price of 22-carat gol</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 03:02:22 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>