<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 14:22:20 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>BAJF four-day intl conference begins</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bajf-four-day-intl-conference-begins</link><description>The government is preparing a 25-year master plan to make Bangladesh’s agriculture modern and sustainable in the long term. Work on this integrated plan — considering future risks and technological progress — is almost complete, and the final draft is expected by this December.
A</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 10:45:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh health DG praises MASTUL Foundation’s lifesaving work for Palestinians in Gaza</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-health-dg-praises-mastul-foundations-lifesaving-work-for-palestinians-in-gaza</link><description>During his visit to observe the ongoing humanitarian crisis in Gaza and Palestine, Professor Dr Abu Jafar, Director General of the Directorate General of Health Services (DGHS), inspected the activities of the MASTUL Foundation’s Egypt branch. He traveled to Cairo to attend the international</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 11:00:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Administrator team of SIBL meets with Agent Outlet Representatives</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/administrator-team-of-sibl-meets-with-agent-outlet-representatives</link><description>Social Islami Bank PLC held a meeting with its agent outlet representatives on 27 November 2025.
The session, organized at the Bank’s Head Office, was attended by the Administrator of Social Islami Bank Mr. Md. Salah Uddin, as the chief guest, according to a press release.
Among others, Ass</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 11:15:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EBL opens sub-branch at Mirpur-10</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ebl-opens-sub-branch-at-mirpur-10</link><description>Eastern Bank (EBL) has expanded its retail footprint with the opening of its sub-branch at Mirpur-10 yesterday (26 November).
The new sub-branch located at Central Plaza on Begum Rokeya Sarani was formally inaugurated by EBL Deputy Managing Director and Head of Retail and SME Banking M. Khorshed A</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 11:30:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ACC opens probe against DNCC administrator</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/acc-investigating-dncc-administrator-azaz-over-alleged-power-abuse-bribery</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) has launched an inquiry against Mohammad Azaz, the administrator of the Dhaka North City Corporation (DNCC), on allegations of abuse of power, irregularities, corruption, and bribery.
A letter signed by Ishita Rony, director of the ACC's Daily and Recent Compla</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 11:45:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pubali Bank launches Co-Branded Card with Dhaka University</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/pubali-bank-launches-co-branded-card-with-dhaka-university</link><description>Pubali Bank PLC launched a Co-Branded Card with the University of Dhaka recently at Nawab Ali Chowdhury Senate Bhaban Seminar Room of the University.
Professor Dr. Niaz Ahmed Khan, Vice-Chancellor of Dhaka University, was present as the Chief Guest, according to a press release.
Mohammad Ali, Man</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 12:00:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prime Bank Foundation supports free eye care camp in Kulaura</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/prime-bank-foundation-supports-free-eye-care-camp-in-kulaura</link><description>A day-long free eye treatment and follow-up service camp was organized in Kulaura, Moulvibazar, with the support of Prime Bank Foundation (Sister Concern of Prime Bank PLC.).
The camp was held at the premises of Kulaura Girls’ High School recently (22 November), according to a media release.</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 12:15:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>National Finance Ltd is now National Finance PLC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/national-finance-ltd-is-now-national-finance-plc</link><description>Bangladesh Bank has announced that National Finance Limited has changed its name and will henceforth operate as National Finance PLC.
The name change has been approved under Section 63 of the Finance Companies Act, 2023, and will take effect from 24 November 2025, according to a press release.</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 12:30:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chief Justice Refaat to give farewell address Dec 14</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/chief-justice-refaat-to-give-farewell-address-dec-14</link><description>Chief Justice Syed Refaat Ahmed will deliver his farewell speech to the nation’s judges on Dec 14, ahead of his retirement later that month.
A media statement issued on Thursday by the Appellate Division of the Supreme Court confirmed that he will retire on Dec 27.
The statement said this w</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 12:45:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Recitation event by Charukontho on the Poetry of Eminent Poet &amp; Thinker Fayaz Alam</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/recitation-event-by-charukontho-on-the-poetry-of-eminent-poet-thinker-fayaz-alam</link><description>Charukontho Abritti Sangsad has organised its quarterly recitation event titled ‘Binomro Roder Chhaya’ for the 37th time, featuring the poetry of eminent poet and thinker Md. Foyez Alam.
The event was held at the Bishwo Shahitto Kendro in the capital, according to a press release.
On</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 13:00:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>General sworn in as Guinea-Bissau transitional president, army statement says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/africa/general-sworn-in-as-guinea-bissau-transitional-president-army-statement-says</link><description>Guinea-Bissau’s military installed General Horta Nta Na Man as transitional president on Thursday, an army statement said, a day after soldiers toppled President Umaro Sissoco Embalo in a swift power grab that followed a disputed election.
The self-styled "High Military Command for the Resto</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 13:15:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Oil steadies as investors await peace talk direction</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/oil-steadies-as-investors-await-peace-talk-direction</link><description>Oil prices steadied on Thursday as market participants weighed talks to end the war in Ukraine against the impact of Western sanctions against Russian supply, though trading was set to remain thin due to the US Thanksgiving holiday.
Brent crude futures rose 9 cents or 0.1 per cent to stand at $63.</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 13:30:49 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>