<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 07:28:38 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nepal's former rapper to run for PM in key vote after Gen Z protests</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/nepals-former-rapper-to-run-for-pm-in-key-vote-after-gen-z-protests</link><description>Two popular leaders have formed an alliance ahead of March parliamentary elections in Nepal that will challenge the older parties which have dominated the Himalayan nation's politics for over three decades, party officials and analysts said on Monday.
Rapper turned-Kathmandu mayor Balendra Shah, k</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 04:38:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India claims $30 billion from Reliance Industries, BP</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/india-claims-30-billion-from-reliance-industries-bp-for-underproduction-from-gas-field-sources-say</link><description>India is seeking over $30 billion in compensation from Reliance Industries and BP in an arbitration case for gas it says the companies failed to produce from offshore fields, according to three people with knowledge of the matter.
A tribunal has been hearing the dispute in India since 20</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 04:53:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Railway tracks removed; rail services suspended on Dhaka–M’singh route</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/railway-tracks-removed-rail-services-suspended-on-dhaka-msingh-route</link><description>Train services on the Dhaka–Mymensingh route have remained suspended since early Monday after two bogies of the Agnibina Express derailed in Gafargaon upazila of Mymensingh district, allegedly due to the removal of a section of the railway track by miscreants.
No casualties were reported in</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 05:08:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Kyrgios beats Sabalenka in 'Battle of the Sexes' showdown</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/kyrgios-beats-sabalenka-in-battle-of-the-sexes-showdown</link><description>Nick Kyrgios beat Aryna Sabalenka 6‑3 6‑3 on Sunday in a "Battle of the Sexes" exhibition match billed as a modern take on Billie Jean King's famous win over Bobby Riggs over 50 years ago, but one that ignited controversy over its relevance and meaning.
The clash between four-times Grand Sla</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 05:23:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Acute Air Pollution: Increasing number of patients hospitalised with diseases</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/acute-air-pollution-increasing-number-of-patients-hospitalised-with-diseases</link><description>The present poor air quality and unabated pollution continue to cause various diseases and breathing difficulties among people. As a result, an increasing number of patients are getting admitted to hospitals. The air continues to remain unhealthy or severely unhealthy in the city, forcing residents</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 05:38:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>What happens to Beximco Pharma after London trade suspension</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/what-happens-to-beximco-pharma-after-london-trade-suspension</link><description>Beximco Pharmaceuticals' stock plunged 2 per cent on Sunday on the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) following news that trading of the stock is set to be suspended on the London Stock Exchange on January 2 next year.
The pharmaceutical company was listed in Bangladesh in 1986, while it issued Global Dep</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 05:53:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique Rahman submits nomination papers for Dhaka-17</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-rahman-submits-nomination-papers-for-dhaka-17</link><description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman’s nomination papers for the Dhaka-17 constituency were submitted on Monday to contest the upcoming national election, alongside Bogura-6.
On behalf of Tarique Rahman, a BNP delegation led by BNP Chairperson’s Advisory Council member Abdus Salam submit</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 06:08:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BGB must maintain strategic relation with neighbouring countries: Home adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bgb-must-maintain-strategic-relation-with-neighbouring-countries-while-performing-duty-home-adviser</link><description>Home Affairs Adviser Lt Gen (retd) Jahangir Alam Chowdhury on Monday said the Border Guard Bangladesh (BGB) must maintain strategic relations with neighbouring countries while performing duties along the borders.
He made the remarks while addressing the BGB’s annual day programme at Shaheed</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 06:23:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Another NCP leader pulls out of election race</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/another-ncp-leader-pulls-out-of-election-race</link><description>Monjila Jhuma has become the latest National Citizen Party (NCP) leader to pull out of the upcoming parliamentary elections, adding to a series of withdrawals from the youth-led party.
Despite having collected nomination papers for the Khagrachhari constituency, Jhuma, the NCP’s central comm</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 06:38:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh's telecom overhaul faces acid test</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/bangladeshs-telecom-overhaul-faces-acid-test</link><description>In a move that has sent ripples across South Asia's technology and investment landscape, Bangladesh interim government's advisory council has given the final approval for the Bangladesh Telecommunication (Amendment) Ordinance 2025. Framed by the government as a long-overdue modernisation of the cou</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 06:53:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How digital power is strengthening industrial resilience in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/how-digital-power-is-strengthening-industrial-resilience-in-bangladesh</link><description>Bangladesh's industrial sector is entering a critical phase in its energy transition. The central question is no longer whether renewable energy will be adopted, but how reliably it can support industrial operations in the long run. Rising fuel costs, grid instability, and sustainability expectatio</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 07:08:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Top court clears way for Nagorik Oikko's Manna to contest polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/loan-default-top-court-clears-way-for-nagorik-oikkos-manna-to-contest-polls</link><description>The Supreme Court has cleared the way for Nagorik Oikko President Mahmudur Rahman Manna to contest the upcoming parliamentary election by suspending a High Court order that had barred him from running.
The Appellate Division’s Chamber Court stayed the High Court ruling that had denied Manna&amp;</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 07:23:58 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>