<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 05:23:59 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Education reform remains an unfulfilled promise of July Revolution</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/education-reform-remains-an-unfulfilled-promise-of-july-revolution-1</link><description>When the authoritarian government of Sheikh Hasina was challenged in the summer of 2024, the largest demographic that was at the forefront against it was the youth of the country. The frustration that gave rise to their heroic stand against tyranny has definite links with the lacklustre economy of</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 20:08:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Refiners seek sharp hike in edible oil prices</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/refiners-seek-sharp-hike-in-edible-oil-prices</link><description>Edible-oil refiners have proposed increasing the prices of soybean and palm oils by Tk 10 and Tk 19 per litre respectively, citing rising import costs and international market volatility, sources said.
The Bangladesh Vegetable Oil Refiners and Vanaspati Manufacturers Association (BVORVMA) has subm</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 01:55:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Consumption-led economic dynamism in sight</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/consumption-led-economic-dynamism-in-sight</link><description>Rising consumption of goods spurs economic activity and demand-driven imports particularly amid some spending splurge on upcoming national elections, in a rebound from persisting slumps.
Consumption contracted in fiscal years 2023 and FY 2024 consecutively amid persistent high inflation, but indus</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 02:10:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>'Bangladesh struggles to balance big-power pressures'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-struggles-to-balance-big-power-pressures</link><description>Bangladesh's foreign policy is increasingly defined by the challenge of navigating great-power rivalry while managing domestic political pressures, analysts said at a major policy forum on Sunday.
They argued that Dhaka's engagement with India, China, and the United States reflects not a single al</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 02:25:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>T-bill yields see mixed trend</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/t-bill-yields-see-mixed-trend</link><description>The yields on treasury bills (T-bills) showed a mixed trend on Sunday as banks appeared reluctant to invest their excess liquidity in risk-free government securities ahead of the year-end closing.
The cut-off yield, generally regarded as the interest rate, on 91-day T-bills rose to 10.14 per cent</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 02:40:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Experts welcome move to appoint foreign port operators but call for transparency</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/experts-welcome-move-to-appoint-foreign-port-operators-but-call-for-transparency</link><description>Economists and business leaders have cautiously hailed the selection of reputed foreign companies by the interim government to develop and operate two Bangladeshi ports, saying this will uplift the country's capacity.
Experienced and well-known foreign firms handling the ports will not only boost</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 02:55:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt mulls app for earthquake warning</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-mulls-app-for-earthquake-warning</link><description>The government is mulling over introducing an app for providing early warning of earthquakes in the country, said Home Affairs Adviser Lt Gen (retd) Jahangir Alam Chowdhury on Sunday.
He said several countries have developed applications, capable of issuing alerts around 10 seconds before tremors</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 03:10:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Curricular upgrade, skills building must for new jobs, economy: Experts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/curricular-upgrade-skills-building-must-for-new-jobs-economy-experts</link><description>An evolving global order is disrupting supply systems across countries, prompting a shift from a bipolar world to a multipolar framework, when nations can no longer rely solely on the West and must widen their focus. 
Speakers at a function in Dhaka Sunday sounded the alert, and recommended d</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 03:25:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IEB experts flag alarming structural faults in several quake-hit Dhaka buildings</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ieb-experts-flag-alarming-structural-faults-in-several-quake-hit-dhaka-buildings</link><description>The Institution of Engineers, Bangladesh (IEB), has identified a series of critical structural and engineering faults in several buildings across Dhaka that were damaged in the recent earthquake, raising fresh concerns about construction quality, building code compliance, and Dhaka’s long-ter</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 03:40:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>United Power's quarterly profit falls as revenue drops, costs climb</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/united-powers-quarterly-profit-falls-as-revenue-drops-costs-climb</link><description>After reporting its highest-ever annual profit in FY25, United Power Generation &amp; Distribution Company's first-quarter profit plunged 30 per cent year-on-year to Tk 2.92 billion in the three months to September, due to lower revenue and higher production costs.
The power generation company's conso</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 04:12:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gunmen attack Pakistan paramilitary force headquarters</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/gunmen-attack-pakistan-paramilitary-force-headquarters-police-say</link><description>Gunmen attacked a paramilitary force headquarters in Pakistan's northwestern city of Peshawar on Monday, police said.
The complex, the headquarters of the frontier constabulary paramilitary force, was also hit by two suicide bombers, sources told Reuters news agency, adding that three people had b</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 04:27:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Canada, India agree to restart trade talks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/canada-india-agree-to-restart-trade-talks</link><description>Canada and India have agreed to restart stalled talks for a new trade deal, the Indian government said on Sunday, after discussions between the two countries paused following a diplomatic spat two years ago.
Prime Minister Mark Carney met with India's Prime Minister Narendra Modi for a bilateral d</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 04:42:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>