<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 08:30:44 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Youth killed in Jhenaidah road accident</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/youth-killed-in-jhenaidah-road-accident</link><description>A young driver of a makeshift motorised vehicle (locally known as Alam sadhu gari) was killed when a speeding pickup van hit his vehicle in Jhenaidah district on Wednesday.
The deceased was identified as Abu Bakar Kallol, 30, son of Mir Abul Kashem of Jibne village under Chuadanga Sadar upazila, r</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 05:33:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fire at Bosnia home for the elderly kills at least 10</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/fire-at-bosnia-home-for-the-elderly-kills-at-least-10</link><description>At least 10 people died and several were injured in a fire that broke out in a home for the elderly in the town of Tuzla in northern Bosnia late on Tuesday evening, Bosnian media reported.
The fire broke out around 9:00 pm (2000 GMT) and was put out around 10:00 pm, Federalna TV reported on its we</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 06:03:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tanzanian opposition claims security forces are secretly dumping bodies after election violence</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/tanzanian-opposition-claims-security-forces-are-secretly-dumping-bodies-after-election-violence</link><description>Authorities in Tanzania faced mounting concern Tuesday over killings during crackdowns on protests surrounding last week’s election, with the largest opposition party alleging that security forces were secretly dumping bodies of hundreds killed in the violence.
Demonstrations spread across t</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 06:18:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Five of a family killed Cox’s Bazar road crash</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/five-of-a-family-killed-coxs-bazar-road-crash</link><description>Five members of the same family were killed and two others injured in a head-on collision between a bus and a microbus in Chakaria upazila of Cox’s Bazar on Wednesday.
Four women and one child are among the deceased, but their identities could not be ascertained immediately, said Mehedi Hasa</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 05:52:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaica sees 30pc GDP hit from Hurricane Melissa</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/jamaica-sees-30pc-gdp-hit-from-hurricane-melissa</link><description>Jamaican Prime Minister Andrew Holness on Tuesday said that last week's Hurricane Melissa, the strongest-ever storm to hit its shores, caused damage to homes and key infrastructure roughly equivalent to 28 per cent to 32 per cent of last year's gross domestic product.
Holness told the Caribbean na</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 06:07:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rain, thundershowers likely</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rain-thundershowers-likely-1565</link><description>The Bangladesh Meteorological Department (BMD) forecast that light to moderate rain or thundershowers is likely to occur at many places across the country, beginning at 9:00 am today (Wednesday).
"Light to moderate rain or thundershowers is likely to occur at most places over Chattogram and Sylhet</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 06:22:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Elderly man ‘killed by cousins’ over land feud in Chattogram</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/elderly-man-killed-by-cousins-over-land-feud-in-chattograms-banshkhali</link><description>A man has allegedly been killed with sharp weapons in an attack by his cousins over a land feud in Chattogram.
he victim, 65-year-old Zakir Hossain, was a resident of Banshkhali Upazila’s Puro Ilsha village. He was injured in the attack on Tuesday morning and died while undergoing treatment</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 07:22:52 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>