<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 09:37:35 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Scrapping bonded yarn imports may hurt RMG exports: BGBA</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/scrapping-bonded-yarn-imports-may-hurt-rmg-exports-bgba</link><description>The Bangladesh Garment Buying House Association (BGBA) has warned that scrapping the bonded warehouse facility for yarn imports could disrupt the supply chain, push up production costs and undermine apparel exports, urging the government to withdraw what it described as a "self-destructive" decisio</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 06:18:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nilphamari Bangladesh-China hospital will reduce patient flow to Dhaka, Rangpur: CA</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/nilphamari-bangladesh-china-hospital-will-reduce-patient-flow-to-dhaka-rangpur-ca</link><description>A new Bangladesh–China Friendship General Hospital in Nilphamari will play a key role in decentralising healthcare and easing the pressure on hospitals centred in Rangpur and Dhaka, says Chief Adviser Muhammad Yunus.
His remarks came on Sunday while approving the project to establish the 100</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 06:33:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Thailand releases endangered leopard sharks in conservation push</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/thailand-releases-endangered-leopard-sharks-in-conservation-push</link><description>After a brief countdown by conservationists, a young Indo-Pacific leopard shark glided into the blue waters off Maiton Island in southern Thailand, released in the country's first efforts to "rewild" the endangered species.
Once a familiar sight for snorkellers and divers, the spotted sharks have</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 07:22:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mark Tully, BBC correspondent known as the 'voice of India,' dies at 90</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/mark-tully-bbc-correspondent-known-as-the-voice-of-india-dies-at-90</link><description>Mark Tully, a longtime BBC correspondent who was widely known as the “voice of India” for his reporting on the South Asian nation, has died, the broadcaster said. He was 90.
Tully died Sunday at a New Delhi hospital after a brief illness.
Born in India's Kolkata city in 1935, Tu</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 07:37:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Woman 'kills herself while on video call with boyfriend in Barishal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/woman-kills-herself-while-on-video-call-with-boyfriend-in-barishal</link><description>A 21-year-old woman allegedly committed suicide while keeping her boyfriend on a video call at a rented flat in Nahar Mansion on Baptist Mission Road in Barishal on Sunday.
The deceased was identified as Sharmin Akter Mim, who worked at a clothing showroom on Police Lines Road in the city.
She ha</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 07:52:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Over 55,000 domestic observers to monitor national election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/over-55000-domestic-observers-to-monitor-national-election</link><description>More than 55,000 domestic observers will be deployed to monitor the 13th parliamentary election and the accompanying referendum, the Election Commission (EC) has revealed.
According to the commission, a total of 55,454 observers from 81 registered domestic organisations will be involved.
Md Ashad</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 08:07:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Armed attackers kill 11 at soccer field in Mexico's Salamanca</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/armed-attackers-kill-11-at-soccer-field-in-mexicos-salamanca</link><description>A group of armed attackers killed 11 people and injured 12 at a soccer sports field after a match in the Mexican city of Salamanca, its mayor, Cesar Prieto, said on Facebook on Sunday, but a motive was not immediately clear.
A woman and a child were among those injured in the "regrettable and cowa</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 08:22:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Habibur, two others sentenced to death in Chankharpul killings case</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/habibur-two-others-sentenced-to-death-in-chankharpul-killings-case</link><description>The International Crimes Tribunal (ICT)-1 on Monday convicted and sentenced three people, including former Dhaka Metropolitan Police (DMP) commissioner Habibur Rahman, to death and handed down various jail terms to five others in the Chankharpul crimes against humanity case. 
The three-member</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 08:37:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Three killed in Rajshahi road crash</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/three-killed-in-rajshahi-road-crash-1546</link><description>Three people, including a university student, were killed in a head-on collision between a passenger bus and a battery-run auto-rickshaw in Puthia upazila of Rajshahi.
The deceased student was identified as Shanto Islam, a student of the Electrical and Electronic Engineering (EEE) department at Ba</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 08:52:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Stocks mixed at midday as DSE falls, CSE rises</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/stocks-mixed-at-midday-as-dse-falls-cse-rises</link><description>Trading at the country’s stock markets showed a mixed trend in the first half of the second trading day of the week, with indices falling on the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) while rising on the Chittagong Stock Exchange (CSE).
At the DSE, the market opened on a negative note. The benchmark DSE</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 09:07:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt declares 3-day holiday for election; gazette issued</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-declares-3-day-holiday-for-election-gazette-issued</link><description>The government has declared a three-day holiday, aiming to facilitate voter participation in the 13th parliamentary election.
The Ministry of Public Administration issued a gazette in this regard on Sunday.
According to the gazette, the government has declared public holidays on February 11 and 1</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 09:22:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Corporate borrowing from banks to be reduced: BB governor</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/corporate-borrowing-from-banks-to-be-reduced-bb-governor</link><description>The central bank plans to reduce the volume of large corporate loans from the banking sector as part of efforts to rein in defaulted loans and develop the bond market, says Bangladesh Bank Governor Ahsan H Mansur.
Speaking at a seminar titled “Bond Market Development in Bangladesh: Challenge</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 09:37:35 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>