<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 14:23:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>148 tonnes of waste cleared from Tarique rally venue</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/dncc-clears-148-tonnes-of-waste-from-tarqiue-rahmans-rally-venue-in-purbachal</link><description>Dhaka North City Corporation has cleared 148 tonnes of waste from Purbachal’s July 36 Expressway, commonly known as the 300 Feet Road, where BNP’s Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman attended a reception upon returning home after 17 years in exile.
In a statement on Friday, the DNCC said it</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 11:24:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Meta takes down Asif Mahmud’s official Facebook page</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/meta-takes-down-asif-mahmuds-official-facebook-page</link><description>Meta has removed the verified Facebook page of Asif Mahmud Shojib Bhuyain, who recently stepped down from his role as an advisor to the interim government to contest the upcoming general election.
In a post on his personal Facebook account on Friday, Asif said that his official page, which had mor</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 11:39:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Thai defence minister to attend truce talks with Cambodia, PM says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/thai-defence-minister-to-attend-truce-talks-with-cambodia-pm-says</link><description>Thailand's defence minister will join ongoing talks with Cambodia on Saturday that could lead to a truce, the Thai premier said on Friday, as border clashes between the two Southeast Asian neighbours continued for a third week.
If the defence minister is able to come to an agreement with his Cambo</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 11:54:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fire at Gulistan market</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fire-at-gulistan-market</link><description>A fire has broken out on the roof of the eight-storey Gulistan Khaddar Bazar Super Complex in Dhaka.
The incident was reported at 5:28pm on Friday, according to Fire Service duty officer Ruzina Akter.
“Six units have been deployed to control the blaze,” she added.
The cause of the fi</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 12:09:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sakhawat announces compensation for launch accident victim</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/sakhawat-announces-compensation-for-launch-accident-victim</link><description>Shipping Adviser Brigadier General (retd) Dr M Sakhawat Hossain today said the government will provide Tk 150,000 each to the families of the persons died in a lunch accident at Chandpur on Friday.
Families of the each injured persons will get Taka 50,000, he said while talking to reporters after</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 12:24:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nurul elected new Chhatra Shibir president, Sibgatullah secretary</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/nurul-elected-new-chhatra-shibir-president-sibgatullah-secretary</link><description>Nurul Islam Saddam has been elected as the central president of Bangladesh Islami Chhatra Shibir for the 2026 term, with Sibgatullah elected as the secretary general.
They were elected on Friday based on the votes of Shibir members at the Bangladesh-China Friendship Conference Centre in Agargaon.</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 11:56:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jatiya Party threatens polls boycott</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jatiya-party-threatens-to-pull-out-of-polls-over-law-and-order-situation-absence-of-level-playing-field</link><description>After announcing candidates for 243 constituencies in the general election, the Jatiya Party faction led by GM Quader has threatened to withdraw from the election if their two conditions are not met.
The threat came at a press conference hosted by the party at the Lakeshore Hotel in Gulshan on Fri</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 12:11:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP delegation pays homage to Liberation War martyrs on behalf of Tarique</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-delegation-pays-homage-to-liberation-war-martyrs-on-behalf-of-tarique</link><description>A BNP delegation on Friday paid tributes to the martyrs of the Liberation War by placing a wreath at the National Memorial in Savar on behalf of the party’s Acting Chairman, Tarique Rahman, as he was unable to reach the site before sunset.
“A BNP delegation paid homage on behalf of BNP</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 12:26:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC redraws 4 Pabna, Faridpur seats</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/election-commission-redraws-boundaries-of-four-constituencies-in-pabna-faridpur</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has issued a gazette redefining the boundaries of four parliamentary constituencies in Pabna and Faridpur districts.
The four seats are Pabna-1, Pabna-2, Faridpur-2 and Faridpur-4.
The decision follows an order from the High Court division to revise the boundaries.
A</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 12:41:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DCCI lauds move to set up commercial court</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/dcci-lauds-move-to-set-up-commercial-court</link><description>Dhaka Chamber of Commerce &amp; Industry (DCCI) President Taskeen Ahmed has lauded the government initiative to set up the commercial court, calling it a timely step to strengthen commercial dispute resolution and improve Bangladesh’s pro-business climate.
Taskeen made the comments when he met C</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 12:56:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BB clarifies withdrawal limits for five merging banks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bb-clarifies-withdrawal-limits-for-five-merging-banks</link><description>Bangladesh Bank (BB) on Friday issued a clarification regarding the withdrawal of funds by depositors of five banks currently undergoing a merger process, cautioning the public against misinformation circulating in various media outlets.
“The process to allow depositors of these five banks t</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 13:11:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US says it struck Islamic State militants in northwest Nigeria</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-says-it-struck-islamic-state-militants-in-northwest-nigeria</link><description>The United States carried out a strike against Islamic State militants in northwest Nigeria at the request of Nigeria’s government, President Donald Trump and the U.S. military said on Thursday, claiming the group had been targeting Christians in the region.
“Tonight, at my direction a</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 13:26:59 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>