<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 10:42:38 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Pakistan's military says its forces killed 30 militants involved in an attack that killed 11 soldiers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/pakistans-military-says-its-forces-killed-30-militants-involved-in-an-attack-that-killed-11-soldiers-1</link><description>Pakistan's military said on Friday that its security forces had killed 30 militants involved in the Oct 7 ambush on a Pakistani military convoy near the Afghan border, which killed nine soldiers and two officers.
The militant group Tehreek-e-Taliban Pakistan, which has been fighting to overthrow t</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 07:23:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Obama won Nobel for ‘doing nothing’: Trump</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/obama-won-nobel-for-doing-nothing-trump</link><description>US President Donald Trump, in his fervid pursuit of the Nobel Peace Prize, has criticised his predecessor Barack Obama's achievements, accusing him of "doing nothing" and "destroying our country".
Speaking to reporters at the White House, Trump touted his achievement in securing peace in Gaza</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 07:38:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India to reopen its embassy in Kabul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/india-to-reopen-its-embassy-in-kabul</link><description>India will reopen its embassy in the Afghan capital Kabul that was shut four years ago, Indian Foreign Minister Subrahmanyam Jaishankar said on Friday, a significant move that expands the diplomatic links of the country governed by the Taliban.
India had closed its embassy in Kabul after the Talib</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 07:44:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DU fine arts faculty suspends ‘Sharot Utsab’ amid objections</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/du-fine-arts-faculty-suspends-sharot-utsab-amid-objections</link><description>The Faculty of Fine Arts at Dhaka University has suspended the annual ‘Sharot Utsab’ organised by Satyen Sen Shilpigosthi, citing objections and concerns about potential unrest.
However, the event has not been cancelled, said Dean Professor Azharul Islam.
He told a local daily that th</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 07:59:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Israeli forces start pulling back from parts of Gaza under ceasefire deal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/israeli-forces-start-pulling-back-from-parts-of-gaza-under-ceasefire-deal</link><description>Israeli troops began pulling back from some parts of Gaza on Friday under a ceasefire deal with Hamas, and some residents returned to shattered neighbourhoods amid confusion over when hostilities will be suspended after two years of warfare.
"Thank God my house is still standing," said Ismail Zayd</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 08:29:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>JU jointly tops Bangladesh in THE World University Rankings 2026</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ju-jointly-tops-bangladesh-in-the-world-university-rankings-2026</link><description>Jahangirnagar University (JU) has once again been named among Bangladesh's leading higher education institutions, jointly securing the top position in the country according to the Times Higher Education (THE) World University Rankings 2026.
The UK-based organisation, in collaboration with Elsevier</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 09:42:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Venezuela's Maria Corina Machado wins 2025 Nobel Peace Prize</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/venezuelas-maria-corina-machado-wins-2025-nobel-peace-prize</link><description>Venezuelan opposition leader Maria Corina Machado won the Nobel Peace Prize on Friday for promoting democratic rights in her country and her struggle to achieve a transition to democracy, the Norwegian Nobel Committee said.
"When authoritarians seize power, it is crucial to recognise courageous de</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 09:57:27 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>