<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 10:07:17 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Move to equip IDRA with 'search and seizing' power</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/move-to-equip-idra-with-search-and-seizing-power</link><description>The government has moved to give the Insurance Development and Regulatory Authority (IDRA) 'search and seizing' powers in a bid to curb fraudulence, malpractice and irregularities in the insurance sector.
The proposed amendments to the existing law have been put forward to the Ministry of Finance</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 08:30:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rice trader hacked to death at store in Mymensingh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/rice-trader-hacked-to-death-at-store-in-mymensingh</link><description>A rice trader has been hacked to death inside his shop in Trishal upazila of Mymensingh. The killers left the victim inside the shop and closed the shutters before fleeing.
The murder took place around 11:00 pm on Monday at the Bogar Bazar intersection in the Upazila, said Trishal Police Station c</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 08:45:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CTG PORT STRIKE: BGMEA, BKMEA seek info on losses from members</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ctg-port-strike-bgmea-bkmea-seek-info-on-losses-from-members</link><description>The apex bodies for the country's apparel sector have asked their respective members to provide information on possible losses incurred due to the workers' strike at the Chittagong Port.
Bangladesh Garment Manufacturers and Exporters Association (BGMEA) and Bangladesh Knitwear Manufacturers and Ex</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 09:00:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rising tobacco cultivation poses serious risks in Ramu, Chakaria</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/rising-tobacco-cultivation-poses-serious-risks-in-ramu-chakaria</link><description>COX'S BAZAR, Feb 09: Tobacco cultivation is increasing at an alarming rate in Ramu and Chakaria upazilas of Cox's Bazar, raising serious concerns among agriculturalists, environmentalists and public health experts.
Fertile farmlands once used for rice, vegetables and pulses are now being overtaken</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 08:05:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Writ seeks cancellation of Nahid's candidature</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/writ-seeks-cancellation-of-nahids-candidature</link><description>A writ petition has been filed with the High Court (HC) seeking the cancellation of National Citizen Party (NCP) Convener Nahid Islam's candidature for the Dhaka-11 constituency, alleging that he holds dual citizenship of the Commonwealth of Dominica.
Shamim Ahmed, a Jatiya Party nominee for the c</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 08:20:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>80pc parties, candidates have trust in EC: AFED</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/80pc-parties-candidates-have-trust-in-ec-afed</link><description>With the preparations for the upcoming 13th Jatiya Sangsad election gathering pace across the country, more than 80 per cent political parties and candidates have voiced strong trust in the Election Commission (EC), according to a report.
The Alliance for Fair Election and Democracy () held talks</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 08:35:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Major shift from roads to rail, water targeted by 2040</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/major-shift-from-roads-to-rail-water-targeted-by-2040</link><description>A multimodal transportation plan has been finalised at the fag end of the interim government's term to guide all related agencies in implementing future infrastructure development projects aimed at improved connectivity for both passengers and freight.

However, experts say the obligation to abid</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 08:50:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Focus on poverty alleviation, job creation to curb graft</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/focus-on-poverty-alleviation-job-creation-to-curb-graft</link><description>Speakers at a 'National Convention' emphasised the urgent need for poverty alleviation and employment generation as the key measures to reduce corruption in the society.
They noted that unemployment and economic insecurity often push individuals towards unethical practices, making strong social an</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 09:05:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Security force's 'intrusion' into media outlets</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/security-forces-intrusion-into-media-outlets</link><description>The Editors' Council has expressed deep concern over what it described as unwarranted intrusion by security forces into media organisations, warning that such incidents send a negative message ahead of the upcoming election.
In a statement issued on Monday, the Editors' Council said it had obser</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 09:20:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Unaware of ministerial offer, may return to academia: Salehuddin</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/unaware-of-ministerial-offer-may-return-to-academia-salehuddin</link><description>Finance Adviser Dr Salehuddin Ahmed on Tuesday said he is unaware of any proposal for him to join a future political government as a minister.
 “I do not know anything about this,” he said, responding to questions from reporters after a meeting of the Cabinet Committee on Governme</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 09:35:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IGP doesn’t rule out militant attack risk during election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/igp-doesnt-rule-out-militant-attack-risk-during-election</link><description>Although the risk of militant attacks during the election campaign has eased, it still cannot be ruled out ahead of the 13th parliamentary election, says Inspector General of Police (IGP) Baharul Alam.
He shared his perspective at a press conference at the Police Headquarters’ Media Centre o</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 09:50:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Compensation planned for shareholders of five merged banks: Salehuddin</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/compensation-planned-for-shareholders-of-five-merged-banks-salehuddin</link><description>The interim government has moved towards arranging compensation for shareholders affected by the merger of five Shariah-based banks, with Finance Advisor Salehuddin Ahmed indicating that the process will be “complex” and carried out in phases.
Speaking at the Secretariat after a meetin</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 10:05:17 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>