<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 10:27:43 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>India orders crisis-hit IndiGo to cut flights by 5%</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/india-orders-crisis-hit-indigo-to-cut-flights-by-5</link><description>India's aviation regulator has ordered crisis-hit IndiGo to cut its number of planned flights by 5 percent to stabilise its operations.
In a notice dated on Monday but disclosed on Tuesday, the Directorate General of Civil Aviation asked IndiGo to submit a revised schedule by Wednesday.</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 07:28:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Global pilots warn India's rest rule exemption for IndiGo raises safety concerns</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/global-pilots-warn-indias-rest-rule-exemption-for-indigo-raises-safety-concerns</link><description>India's decision to ease stricter rules on pilot rest following a wave of flight cancellations by the country's largest carrier should be reversed due to the adverse effect of fatigue on safety, the head of global pilot union group IFALPA said.
IndiGo, which controls about 65 percent of India's do</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 07:43:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Constable accused of beating Barishal journalist with hammer</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/constable-accused-of-beating-barishal-journalist-with-hammer</link><description>A police constable has been accused of entering a flat in Barishal and beating Asian TV's Barishal bureau chief, Firoz Mostafa, with a hammer.
The incident took place on Monday night at his rented home on Gorachand Das Road, according to Barishal Kotwali Model Police Station chief (OC) Al Mamun Ul</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 07:31:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>RMG factory closure sparks protests in Gazipur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rmg-factory-closure-sparks-protests-in-gazipur</link><description>Workers of a garment factory staged a demonstration in front of PN Composite Ltd at Ambagh in Konabari, Gazipur on Tuesday, protesting the sudden closure of the factory.
“The authorities hung a closure notice on the main gate on Monday evening. When workers arrived for duty on Tuesday mornin</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 07:46:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Woman killed in road crash on Dhaka-Mawa Expressway</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/woman-killed-in-road-crash-on-dhaka-mawa-expressway</link><description>A 50-year-old woman was killed and three others injured when a microbus crashed into an auto-rickshaw on the Dhaka-Mawa Expressway at Ompara in Sreenagar upazila of Munshiganj district on Tuesday. 
The deceased was identified as Zobaida Begum, wife of Ekhlas Uddin of Baroikhali Shibrampur are</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 08:01:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mobile technology fuels AI adoption in Bangladesh, Telenor Asia study finds</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/mobile-technology-fuels-ai-adoption-in-bangladesh-telenor-asia-study-finds</link><description>Mobile phones are at the heart of Bangladesh’s digital transformation, from accessing online learning and financial services to managing daily tasks and staying informed, according to the latest Telenor Asia study.
Increasingly, these everyday conveniences are powered by artificial intellige</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 08:16:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NBR chief calls for expanded VAT registration to cut reliance on imports</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/nbr-chief-calls-for-expanded-vat-registration-to-cut-reliance-on-imports</link><description>National Board of Revenue (NBR) Chairman Md Abdur Rahman Khan on Tuesday underscored the urgent need to expand the country’s VAT and income tax base to reduce reliance on import-based revenue, strengthen fiscal stability, and support Bangladesh’s development ambitions.
“Developme</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 08:31:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NBR to develop automated system linking return submission with banks: Chairman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/nbr-to-develop-automated-system-linking-return-submission-with-banks-chairman</link><description>National Board of Revenue (NBR) Chairman Md Abdur Rahman Khan on Tuesday said the revenue authority is developing an automated system that will integrate taxpayers’ annual return submission with banks.
It will ease eliminate the need for individuals to collect multiple bank certificates from</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 08:46:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Accused escapes stabbing CID official in Sylhet</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/accused-escapes-stabbing-cid-official-in-sylhet</link><description>An accused in a Cybercrime case fled the police custody after stabbing an officer of the Criminal Investigation Department (CID) at Sagardighi Par in Sylhet city on Monday midnight.
The victim, Khurshed Alam, a sub-inspector of CID,  was admitted to Osmani Medical College and Hospital.
Sugya</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 09:01:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DMP bans rallies, processions around CJ’s residence, Judges Complex</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dmp-bans-rallies-processions-around-cjs-residence-judges-complex-1</link><description>Dhaka Metropolitan Police (DMP) has imposed a ban on rallies, processions, demonstrations and gatherings around Chief Justice’s residence, Judges Complex, the main gate of Bangladesh Supreme court, Mazar Gate, Jam-e-Mosque gate, the main gates of International Crimes Tribunal 1 and 2 and Bang</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 09:39:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fakhrul calls for unity to uphold gains of July mass uprising</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/fakhrul-calls-for-unity-to-uphold-gains-of-july-mass-uprising</link><description>BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir on Tuesday urged political leaders and people to remain united in safeguarding the gains of last year’s July mass uprising, saying the sacrifices of the young people who lost their lives must not go in vain.
“Let us work together to con</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 09:54:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BTRC says ‘no’ to used mobile imports, traders stand firm</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/btrc-says-no-to-used-mobile-imports-traders-refuse-to-budge</link><description>After protests, building sieges, and arson attacks, the Bangladesh Telecommunication Regulatory Commission (BTRC) has remained adamant on its decision to ban unauthorised mobile phones.
Following a meeting with officials on Tuesday, grey market mobile phone traders said a compromise has not been r</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 10:09:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>