<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 15:28:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Italy to upgrade relations with Venezuela as two more Italians freed</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/italy-to-upgrade-relations-with-venezuela-as-two-more-italians-freed</link><description>Venezuela has released Italian citizens Alberto Trentini and Mario Burlo from prison, Italy said on Monday, pledging to upgrade relations with Caracas in response.
Foreign Minister Antonio Tajani said no other citizens with solely Italian nationality remained in prison, after Venezuela freed two o</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 12:15:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP gears up in Sylhet as Tarique Rahman set to launch election campaign</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bnp-gears-up-in-sylhet-as-tarique-rahman-set-to-launch-election-campaign</link><description>With banners going up, leaders mobilising at ward level and expectations running high among grassroots activists, Sylhet’s district and city BNP units are leaving no stone unturned ahead of party chairman Tarique Rahman’s visit, where he will kick off the BNP’s election campaign o</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 12:30:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Iran says communications open with US</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/iran-says-communications-open-with-us</link><description>Iran said on Monday it is keeping communications open with the U.S. as President Donald Trump weighed responses to a deadly crackdown on nationwide protests, which pose one of the stiffest challenges to clerical rule since the 1979 Islamic Revolution.
 
Trump said on Sunday the U.S. may meet</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 12:45:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New US ambassador Brent Christensen arrives in Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/new-us-ambassador-brent-christensen-arrives-in-dhaka-to-boost-bilateral-ties-economic-engagement</link><description>Brent Christensen, the newly appointed United States ambassador to Bangladesh, has arrived in Dhaka.
This marks Christensen’s return to Bangladesh, having previously served as political and economic counsellor at the US Embassy from 2019 to 2021.</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 13:00:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC hearings reopen race for 41 more election candidates</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-hearings-reopen-race-for-41-more-election-candidates</link><description>The Election Commission on Monday allowed 41 previously rejected aspirants to contest the February 12 national election after hearings, while a Jamaat candidate for Chattogram-9 was declared invalid and a BNP aspirant for Sherpur-2 was kept pending.
But the EC, as the Electoral Appeal Tribunal tur</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 13:15:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EU commissioner warns US takeover of Greenland would end NATO</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/european-commissioner-says-us-military-takeover-of-greenland-would-be-end-of-nato</link><description>It would be the end of NATO if the US took Greenland by force and European Union member states are under obligation to come to Denmark's assistance if it was faced with military aggression, the European Commissioner for Defence and Space said on Monday.
Trump has said the  must own Greenland,</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 13:30:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Citizens call for action beyond employment promises</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/citizens-call-for-action-beyond-employment-promises</link><description>Employment continues to rank among the top concerns for citizens in Bangladesh, with growing expectations that political parties will present clear and actionable plans ahead of the upcoming national election, speakers said at a dialogue.
The dialogue was jointly organized by Democracy Internation</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 13:45:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hadi Murder: Court sets Jan 15 for hearing charges</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hadi-murder-court-sets-jan-15-for-hearing-charges</link><description>A Dhaka court has fixed January 15 for a hearing on the acceptance of charges submitted in the murder case of Inqilab Moncho spokesperson Sharif Osman bin Hadi.
Dhaka Additional Chief Metropolitan Magistrate Jashita Islam set the date on Monday after the plaintiff, Inqilab Moncho member secretary</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 14:00:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Yunus vows to prevent repeat of ‘election robbery’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/yunus-vows-to-prevent-repeat-of-election-robbery</link><description>Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus has pledged to put in place safeguards to ensure that what he described as “election robbery” can never happen again, after a high-level inquiry concluded that the country’s last three national elections were systematically manipulated to kee</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 14:15:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ikhtiar Uddin appointed new head of BFIU</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ikhtiar-uddin-appointed-new-head-of-bfiu</link><description>The government has appointed Ikhtiar Uddin Mohammad Mamun as the new head of the Bangladesh Financial Intelligence Unit (BFIU).
According to a notification issued today (Monday) by the Financial Institutions Division of the Ministry of Finance, Ikhtiar, who previously served as a Tax Commissioner</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 14:30:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nahid meets Khelafat Majlish Ameer Mamunul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/nahid-meets-khelafat-majlish-ameer-mamunul</link><description>National Citizen Party (NCP) Convener Nahid Islam on Monday held a meeting with Ameer of Bangladesh Khelafat Majlish Maulana Muhammad Mamunul Haque.
The hour-long meeting took place at around 2:00 pm today at the Khelafat Majlish Ameer’s office in Mohammadpur, said a press release.
During t</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 14:45:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>MPs siphon off 50pc of development funds, says Rumeen Farhana</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/mps-siphon-off-50pc-of-development-funds-says-rumeen-farhana</link><description>Independent candidate Rumeen Farhana has alleged that members of parliament siphon off half of the government development allocations meant for their constituencies, leaving only a fraction for actual work.
Addressing a views-exchange meeting on Monday afternoon in Ward No. 2 of Panishor Union in</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 15:00:42 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>