<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 16:27:35 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>BNP leader Noman’s son secures party nomination for Chattogram-10 seat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-leader-nomans-son-secures-party-nomination-for-chattogram-10-seat</link><description>Sayeed Al Noman, son of Bangladesh Nationalist Party leader Abdullah Al Noman, who passed away in February, has secured the BNP nomination to run in the general election from the Chattogram-10 constituency.
Senior BNP leader Amir Khosru Mahmud Chowdhury, who was initially nominated for the seat, h</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 12:37:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka Capitals assistant coach Zaki dies</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/dhaka-capitals-assistant-coach-zaki-dies-after-collapsing-before-bpl-game</link><description>Dhaka Capitals assistant coach Mahbub Ali Zaki died on Saturday after collapsing on the field ahead of his team's Bangladesh Premier League game against Rajshahi Warriors in Sylhet, with local media reporting he suffered a heart attack.
Zaki, 59, fell while the teams were warming up. He was rushed</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 12:52:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Touhid calls for cooperation among political parties during elections</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/touhid-calls-for-cooperation-among-political-parties-during-elections</link><description>The interim administration will step aside after handing over power to a government elected through a peaceful parliamentary election, according to Foreign Advisor Touhid Hossain.
Speaking on Saturday afternoon at the inauguration of a voter awareness vehicle caravan at Bhola Government School gro</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 13:07:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>2025: Revenue pressure, reforms, unrest put NBR at crossroads</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/2025-revenue-pressure-reforms-unrest-put-nbr-at-crossroads</link><description>The National Board of Revenue (NBR) ended 2025 at the centre of Bangladesh’s growing fiscal challenge, struggling to raise higher revenue in a slowing economy while attempting long-promised reforms of a tax system criticised for inefficiency, discretion and a narrow base.
The year unfolded a</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 13:22:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Citizens Bank inaugurates its Bogura Branch</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/citizens-bank-inaugurates-its-bogura-branch</link><description>Citizens Bank PLC formally inaugurated the Bogura Branch at Borogola in Bogura on December 24, 2025, according to a press release.
Mr. Alamgir Hossain, Managing Director of the bank, inaugurated the branch in presence of Deputy Managing Directors Mr. Md. Mostafizur Rahman and Mr. Md. Abdul Latif a</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 13:37:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No immediate funds for merged bank depositors, cenbank clarifies</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/no-immediate-funds-for-merged-bank-depositors-bangladesh-bank-clarifies</link><description>Depositors of the five banks currently undergoing a merger will have to wait longer to withdraw their funds.
Arif Hossain Khan, Executive Director and spokesperson of Bangladesh Bank confirmed on Saturday that there is no possibility of releasing funds to these depositors within the current year,</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 13:52:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BSF pushes 14 Indian nationals into Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bsf-pushes-14-indian-nationals-into-bangladesh</link><description>The Indian Border Security Force (BSF) allegedly pushed 14 Indian nationals, including women, elderly persons and children from the same family, into Bangladesh through the Darshana border in Chuadanga, identifying them as Bangladeshis.
The incident occurred late Friday night, and the group is cur</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 14:07:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tasnim Jara resigns from NCP</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tasnim-jara-resigns-from-ncp</link><description>National Citizen Party (NCP) Senior Joint Member Secretary Tasnim Jara has announced her resignation from her post in the party.
In a Facebook post on Saturday, Tasnim Jara said she will run as an independent candidate in the upcoming 13th parliamentary election from the Dhaka-9 constituency, repo</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 14:22:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>High prices temper festive cheer at Cox’s Bazar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/high-prices-temper-festive-cheer-at-coxs-bazar</link><description>Cox’s Bazar, the country’s leading tourist destination, has drawn tourists in droves during the combined Christmas and weekend holidays, with hotel rooms fully booked and the shoreline crowded even on foggy mornings.
From Sugandha Point to Kolatali, the beach has been lined with touris</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 14:37:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UIU holds 8th convocation on its campus</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/uiu-holds-8th-convocation-at-its-campus</link><description>The 8th Convocation of United International University (UIU) was held on Saturday at UIU Campus, United City, Madani Avenue, in the city.
Prof. Dr. Abu Borhan Mohammad Badruzzaman, Vice Chancellor of Bangladesh University of Engineering and Technology (BUET) presided over the ceremony on behalf of</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 14:52:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh cricket mourns beloved pace coach Zaki</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/cricket/bangladesh-cricket-mourns-beloved-pace-coach-zaki</link><description>Mahbub Ali Zaki arrived at the ground in the team bus in the afternoon. Even during the warm-up, he remained involved, moving with purpose and familiarity.
By evening, that same man returned from the hospital sealed in a coffin. The ground where he had collapsed before his team’s match becam</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 15:07:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chief Justice Syed Refaat Ahmed retires</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/chief-justice-syed-refaat-ahmed-retires</link><description>The country's 25th Chief Justice Dr Syed Refaat Ahmed retired on Saturday upon attaining the age of 67, as mandated by the Constitution.
Meanwhile, Justice Zubayer Rahman Chowdhury of the Appellate Division of the Supreme Court has already been appointed as the country's 26th Chief Justice. He wil</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 16:08:17 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>