<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 06:35:18 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>'Shuponno' outlet opens in city, promotes agroecological farming</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/shuponno-outlet-opens-in-city-promotes-agroecological-farming</link><description>Agroecological farming was hailed as a sustainable solution for ensuring safe, nutritious and environmentally friendly food, as 'Shuponno' opened its first outlet of such produce at Lalmatia in Dhaka on Friday.
Speakers at the inauguration of the outlet said there is no alternative to consuming ch</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 03:34:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump wants nations to pay $1b to stay on his peace board, report says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/trump-wants-nations-to-pay-1b-to-stay-on-his-peace-board-report-says</link><description>The Trump administration wants nations to pay $1 billion to stay on his peace board, Bloomberg News reported on Saturday, citing a draft charter.
US President Donald Trump would serve as its inaugural chairman and each member state shall serve a term of no more than three years from this charter's</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 03:49:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Protesters rally in Denmark and Greenland against Trump annexation threat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/protesters-rally-in-denmark-and-greenland-against-trump-annexation-threat</link><description>Protesters in Denmark and Greenland demonstrated on Saturday against President Donald Trump's demand that the Arctic island be ceded to the US and called for it to be left to determine its own future.
Trump says Greenland is vital to US security because of its strategic location and large mineral</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 04:04:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Changing power balance: banks &amp; regulators</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/changing-power-balance-banks-regulators</link><description>Risk-based supervision reshapes the relationship between banks and regulators. Under compliance-based supervision, power was largely mechanical. Banks were assessed against ratios, exposure limits, and reporting standards. If these thresholds were met, supervisory intervention was limited. Action u</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 04:19:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Overcoming the adoption barriers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/overcoming-the-adoption-barriers</link><description>(This is the last of the two-part articles on the QR-based payment system by the writers)
In line with the global trend, MFS providers in Bangladesh introduced their own proprietary Quick Response (QR) coded or QR-based payment systems in 2018. However, these early models were merchant-specific, m</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 04:34:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Seven-college issues demand urgent action</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/seven-college-issues-demand-urgent-action</link><description>The government’s initiative to establish a new public university – Dhaka Central University – by bringing together the seven colleges de-affiliated from Dhaka University has stuck in limbo for nearly a year. Disagreements over the proposed institutional structure and the draft ord</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 04:49:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Building a repository of Other Financial Corporations</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/building-a-repository-of-other-financial-corporations</link><description>To improve the quality of financial statistics, Bangladesh Bank has started conducting quarterly surveys on Other Financial Corporations (OFCs). The first report has been released, presenting the sector’s status by the end of fiscal year 2024-25 (FY25). The findings show that the sector remai</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 05:04:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Next test for microfinance</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/next-test-for-microfinance</link><description>Few countries have shaped the global discourse on microfinance as profoundly as Bangladesh has, where the model emerged as a tool for poverty alleviation and social empowerment. Over decades, it has extended credit and basic financial services to millions excluded from conventional banking, attract</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 05:19:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ICC rejects Bangladesh's proposal for group swap</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/icc-rejects-bangladeshs-proposal-for-group-swap</link><description>Bangladesh are unwilling to travel to India to play in the upcoming World Cup and have formally conveyed their position to the International Cricket Council (ICC), the Bangladesh Cricket Board (BCB) has said.
Following this, discussions emerged over a possible group swap between Bangladesh and Ire</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 05:34:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Three die from electrocution in Gopalganj</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/three-die-from-electrocution-in-gopalganj</link><description>Three people, including a grandmother and her grandson, died from electrocution in Kashiani upazila of Gopalganj district last night.
The incident occurred around 8:30 pm at Tetulia village under Rajpat union of the upazila.
The deceased were identified as Rahela Begum, 50, wife of Mosarraf Shikd</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 05:49:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Demand to reinstate Biman’s Manchester–Sylhet route debated in British parliament</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/demand-to-reinstate-bimans-manchester-sylhet-route-debated-in-british-parliament</link><description>A demand to reconsider Biman Bangladesh Airlines’ decision to suspend regular flights on the Manchester–Sylhet route has been raised in the British parliament, as concerns grow over higher travel costs and disrupted links between the UK and Bangladesh.
Speaking in the House of Common</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 06:04:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Purbachal plot graft: Verdict against Hasina, Tulip, Bobby on Feb 2</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/purbachal-plot-graft-verdict-against-hasina-tulip-bobby-on-feb-2</link><description>A Dhaka court will deliver its verdict in a case over corruption in the allocation of plots in Purbachal against Radwan Mujib Siddiq Bobby, the nephew of ousted prime minister Sheikh Hasina, on Feb 2.
A total of 18 suspects, including Hasina and her niece and British MP Tulip Siddiq, are accused i</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 06:19:36 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>