<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 13:29:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Scan to Cash–Bank Asia’s QR Code–based cash withdrawal service</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/scan-to-cash-bank-asias-qr-code-based-cash-withdrawal-service</link><description>Bank Asia PLC has launched “Scan to Cash”, an advanced QR code–based cash withdrawal service for its customers. With this facility, customers can easily withdraw cash from any Bank Asia branch without cheque or debit card.
With Scan to Cash, a unique QR code is displayed at the c</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 10:44:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>SriLankan Holidays offers exclusive privileges for EBL cardholders</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/srilankan-holidays-offers-exclusive-privileges-for-ebl-cardholders</link><description>SriLankan Holidays, the leisure arm of SriLankan Airlines, has partnered with Eastern Bank PLC (EBL) to offer exclusive travel benefits to EBL cardholders, according to a press release.
M. Khorshed Anowar, DMD and Head of Retail and SME Banking of EBL, and Ashfia Jannat Saleh, DMD of Saimon Holida</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 10:59:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>National Finance and Rupayan Group sign MoU for home loan services</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/national-finance-and-rupayan-group-sign-mou-for-home-loan-services</link><description>National Finance Limited and Rupayan Group have signed a Memorandum of Understanding (MoU) on October 5, 2025, at Rupayan City, Uttara.
Under this agreement, Rupayan Group’s home loan customers will now enjoy special loan rates and priority financial services from National Finance Limited, a</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 11:14:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pension Authority to study feasibility of insurance benefit under Universal Pension Scheme</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/pension-authority-to-study-feasibility-of-insurance-benefit-under-universal-pension-scheme</link><description>The Board of Directors of the National Pension Authority on Monday asked the officials concerned to urgently prepare a concept paper based on an actuarial analysis to assess the feasibility of introducing an insurance benefit under the Universal Pension Scheme.
The directive came at the 3rd meetin</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 11:29:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>MoU signing ceremony between Trust Bank and AirArabia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/mou-signing-ceremony-between-trust-bank-and-airarabia</link><description>A MoU has been signed between Trust Bank PLC and AirArabia, where Md. Mostafa Musharrof, Head of Card Division, Trust Bank PLC and Syed Md Mobin Rashid Country Manager, AirArabia, signed the MoU on behalf of their respective organisations.
Under this MoU, Trust Bank Debit &amp;amp;Credit Card holders will</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 11:44:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Lankabangla Securities participates in AI training for capital market professionals at IRIIC, UIU</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/lankabangla-securities-participates-in-ai-training-for-capital-market-professionals-at-iriic-uiu</link><description>Institute of Research, Innovation, Incubation, and Commercialization (IRIIC) of United International University (UIU), in collaboration with AI Forum Bangladesh, organized a two-day training on “AI Essentials for Capital Market Professionals”.
The training was concluded yesterday at th</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 12:14:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tofail Ahmed shows signs of ‘recovery’, condition still ‘critical’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tofail-ahmed-shows-signs-of-recovery-condition-still-critical</link><description>Iconic political and influential leader of the Awami League Tofail Ahmed is showing signs of “improvement”, her family has said, though doctors report that his condition remains “critical”.
His health had deteriorated due to different age-related complications, but recent r</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 12:29:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shimanto Bank signs participatory agreement with Bangladesh Bank for Financial Inclusion Credit Guarantee Scheme</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/shimanto-bank-signs-participatory-agreement-with-bangladesh-bank-for-financial-inclusion-credit-guarantee-scheme</link><description>Shimanto Bank has recently signed a participatory agreement with Bangladesh Bank under the "Financial Inclusion Credit Guarantee Scheme" to provide a guarantee facility under inclusive financing.
Under this agreement, small depositors such as TK 10/50/100 account holders, marginal and landless far</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 12:44:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prime Bank partners with Saimon Holidays to offer discount on Sri Lankan holiday packages</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/prime-bank-partners-with-saimon-holidays-to-offer-discount-on-sri-lankan-holiday-packages</link><description>Prime Bank PLC has signed a strategic agreement with Saimon Holidays, enabling the bank’s Customers &amp; employees to enjoy exclusive discounts on travel packages.
In this regard, a signing ceremony was held recently at the bank’s corporate office in Gulshan, according to a press release.</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 12:59:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BRAC Bank hosts workshop on seamless trade and payment solutions for shipping agents in Chattogram</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/brac-bank-hosts-workshop-on-seamless-trade-and-payment-solutions-for-shipping-agents-in-chattogram</link><description>BRAC Bank, in collaboration with the Bangladesh Shipping Agents Association (BSAA), organised a workshop in Chattogram to promote seamless trade and payment solutions for the shipping industry.
Titled “Seamless Trade &amp; Payment Solutions: Regulatory Compliance and Central Bank Reporting for S</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 13:14:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>President of International Federation for Human Rights meets Prof Yunus</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/president-of-international-federation-for-human-rights-meets-prof-yunus</link><description>Alice Mogwe, President of the International Federation for Human Rights (FIDH), met with Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus on Monday at the Guest House Jamuna on Monday.
The two leaders held a wide-ranging discussion on the human rights situation in Bangladesh and across the globe, reports UN</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 13:29:02 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>