<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 17:15:31 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Jagannath JCD leader found dead on building stairs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jagannath-jcd-leader-found-dead-on-building-stairs</link><description>The bloodied body of Zobayed Hossain, a leader of Jagannath University’s Jatiyatabadi Chhatra Dal, has been recovered from the stairs of a building at Old Dhaka’s Armanitola.
Around 6pm on Sunday, Banshal Police chief Rafiqul Islam said his body was found in the house on Panir Pump Lan</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 13:36:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh Bank amends loan write-off policy, mandates 30-day notice</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh-bank-amends-loan-write-off-policy-mandates-30-day-notice</link><description>The Bangladesh Bank (BB) has introduced key amendments to its loan write-off policy, making it mandatory for banks to notify defaulting borrowers before removing bad loans from their balance sheets.
Under the amended rules, banks must ensure that the borrower is notified about the loan write-off d</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 13:51:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Film festival to honour Shah Rukh Khan’s on his 60th birthday announced</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/entertainment/film-festival-to-honour-shah-rukh-khans-on-his-60th-birthday-announced</link><description>PVR INOX announced the Shah Rukh Khan Film Festival on Friday to celebrate the Bollywood icon. Know when and where to watch the films.
Multiplex giant PVR INOX announced a special film festival on Friday to honour the legacy of Shah Rukh Khan ahead of his 60th birthday. The Bollywood star, who rec</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 14:21:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Executive committee of Bangladesh Charu Shilpi Sangsad formed</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/entertainment/executive-committee-of-bangladesh-charu-shilpi-sangsad-formed</link><description>A full-fledged executive committee of Bangladesh Charu Shilpi Sangsad (BCSS) for the tenure 2025-2027 was announced on Saturday (October 18) with Artist Syed Mohammad Ali Pappu as president and Artist Mizanur Rahman Mizan as general secretary through its council.
The committee comprising 73 member</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 14:36:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>30 hurt as Shibir, Jubo Dal clash in Noakhali</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/30-injured-as-chhatra-shibir-jubo-dal-clash-over-mosque-event-in-noakhali</link><description>At least 30 people have been injured when activists of Islami Chhatra Shibir and Jatiyatabadi Jubo Dal clashed over a planned event at a mosque in Noakhali’s Sadar Upazila.
The violence broke out on Sunday afternoon in the area around Kashem Bazar Jame Masjid in Neazpur Union, said Sudharam</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 14:51:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Woman’s hanging body recovered at Dhaka’s Sobhanbagh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/womans-hanging-body-recovered-at-dhakas-sobhanbagh</link><description>A young woman's hanging body was recovered from her residence in the Sobhanbagh area of Dhaka on Saturday evening.
The deceased was identified as Sornomoye Biswas (28). She was a trainee graphic designer at the online news outlet Dhaka Stream.
Sher-e-Bangla Nagar Police Station Sub-Inspector Saif</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 15:21:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>12-member core committee formed over HSIA fire</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/12-member-core-committee-formed-over-hsia-fire</link><description>The government has formed a core committee headed by senior secretary of Home Ministry Nasimul Ghani to probe into the devastating fire at the Cargo Village of Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport (HSIA), Dhaka.
The committee has been asked to submit its report before its next meeting on Novembe</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 15:51:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Frequent fires prompt govt probe</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/government-forms-core-committee-to-examine-three-major-fires-prevent-future-disasters</link><description>Following several major fires recently, the interim government has formed a seven-strong “core committee” to investigate their causes, helmed by the home secretary.
Disaster Management Advisor Faruk E Azam confirmed the development on Sunday, adding that the committee may expand in the</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 16:21:25 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>