<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 14:25:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Promises beyond capacity are betrayal of people: Rizvi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/promises-beyond-capacity-are-betrayal-of-people-rizvi</link><description>With the national election on the horizon, BNP Senior Joint Secretary General Ruhul Kabir Rizvi on Monday stressed that political promises must remain within realistic bounds, warning that pledges beyond capacity amount to a betrayal of the people.
Rizvi made the remarks at a policy-focused town h</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 12:16:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Five Chinese killed in cross-border attacks from Afghanistan: Tajikistan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/tajikistan-says-five-chinese-nationals-killed-in-cross-border-attacks-from-afghanistan-in-past-week</link><description>Five Chinese nationals have been killed and five more injured in Tajikistan in attacks launched from neighbouring Afghanistan over the past week, Tajik authorities and China's embassy in the Central Asian country said on Monday.
China's embassy in Dushanbe, the capital, advised Chinese companies a</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 12:31:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Apparel sector may face same consequence jute industry did: BKMEA President</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/apparel-sector-may-face-same-consequence-jute-industry-did-bkmea-president</link><description>Bangladesh Knitwear Manufacturers and Exporters Association (BKMEA) President Mohammad Hatem has warned that the country’s apparel industry may face a crisis similar to the consequences once seen in the jute sector.
He expressed his concern on Monday at a seminar titled “The Potential</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 11:22:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>173 more Bangladeshis return home from war-torn Libya</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/173-more-bangladeshis-return-home-from-war-torn-libya</link><description>Another 173 Bangladeshi nationals returned home from Libya on Monday.
They arrived at Dhaka at 6am on a Burak Air chartered flight, according to the Ministry of Foreign Affairs.
The repatriation was coordinated by the Bangladesh Embassy in Libya, the Ministry of Foreign Affairs, the Ministry of E</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 11:37:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chawkbazar building fire under control</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/chawkbazar-building-fire-under-control</link><description>The fire that broke out in a three-storey building in Old Dhaka’s Chawkbazar on Monday afternoon has been brought under control.
The blaze started on the top floor of the building around 4:40pm, said Anwarul Islam, warehouse inspector of the Fire Service and Civil Defence.
Upon receiving th</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 11:52:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Spain mobilises military against swine fever, says contaminated sandwich could be cause</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/spain-mobilises-military-against-swine-fever-says-contaminated-sandwich-could-be-cause</link><description>Spain's military was deployed on Monday to contain an African swine fever outbreak near Barcelona which officials suspect may have been triggered by a wild boar eating contaminated food such as a sandwich, sparking a chain of events now disrupting the country's multibillion-euro pork export industr</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 12:07:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>22 officers promoted to assistant secretary</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/22-officers-promoted-to-assistant-secretary</link><description>The government has promoted 22 administrative officers to the rank of assistant secretary (non-cadre) posts.
“The government has promoted them, following the instruction of the Bangladesh Public Service Commission (BPSC), and appointed officer on special duty (OSD) to the public administrati</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 12:22:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Australia house prices rise but growth slows in Sydney and Melbourne</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/australia-house-prices-rise-but-growth-slows-in-sydney-and-melbourne</link><description>Australian home prices jumped in November but gains in Sydney and Melbourne slowed, as expectations there would be no interest rate cuts anytime soon undermined sentiment in those already expensive markets, property consultant Cotality said on Monday.
Home prices nationwide increased 1 per cent in</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 12:37:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Oil rises on supply worries after CPC attack</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/oil-rises-on-supply-worries-after-cpc-attack</link><description>Oil prices rose 1 per cent on Monday as the Caspian Pipeline Consortium halted exports after a major drone attack and US-Venezuela tensions raised concerns about supply, while OPEC+ agreed to leave oil output levels unchanged for the first quarter of 2026.
Brent crude futures advanced 71 cents, or</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 12:52:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Expat voters can register till Dec 25: EC Secretary</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/expat-voters-can-register-till-dec-25-ec-secretary</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has extended the deadline by seven days for expatriate Bangladeshis to register through the ‘Postal Vote BD’ app to cast their ballots in the upcoming national election and referendum to be held in early February 2026.
“The deadline for ‘out-of-</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 13:07:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ACC to launch probe against its former chairman Iqbal Mahmood</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/acc-to-launch-probe-against-its-former-chairman-iqbal-mahmood</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) has decided to launch an investigation against its former chairman Iqbal Mahmood.
The investigation will cover allegations of bribery, abuse of power and money laundering brought against Iqbal during the preliminary inquiry.
This is the first time a former ACC</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 13:22:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nvidia invests $2 billion in chip design software provider Synopsys</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/nvidia-invests-2-billion-in-chip-design-software-provider-synopsys</link><description>AI chip leader Nvidia (NVDA.O) has invested $2 billion in semiconductor design software provider Synopsys (SNPS.O), adding to its slew of new partnerships in the artificial intelligence ecosystem amid concerns of increasingly circular deals.
The world's most valuable firm has invested billions of</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 13:37:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>