<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 04:40:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Taka appreciates with trade implications</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/taka-appreciates-with-trade-implications</link><description>Bangladesh's exports are set to lose competitiveness to foreign buyers while imports getting cheaper as the local currency appears increasingly overvalued in the foreign-exchange basket in real terms.
Economists explain that this economic paradox appears for sluggish import demand, weak private-se</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 01:30:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka will be made a livable city if Jamaat comes to power: Dr Shafiqur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/dhaka-will-be-made-a-livable-city-if-jamaat-comes-to-power-dr-shafiqur</link><description>Bangladesh Jamaat-e- Islami Ameer Dr Shafiqur Rahman has said if his party is voted to power, it would turn Dhaka into a livable and safe city.
He made the promise while carrying out electoral campaign as the party candidate for Dhaka -15 constituency in the upcoming 13th Jatiya Sangsad elections.</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 01:45:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Soaring aid repayments create fiscal pressure</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/soaring-aid-repayments-create-fiscal-pressure</link><description>Bangladesh is facing a fiscal squeeze as foreign aid receipts declined during the first half (H1) of the current fiscal year, while the burden of repaying international debts reached new heights.
The country now faces a new challenge marked by a significant drop in new funding commitments and esca</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 02:00:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Meghna Petroleum's Q2 profit down as demand for furnace oil drops</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/meghna-petroleums-q2-profit-down-as-demand-for-furnace-oil-drops</link><description>Meghna Petroleum Limited (MPL) saw a marginal decline of 5.25 per cent in profit to Tk 1.55 billion in the second quarter of FY26 as furnace oil sales dropped.
In the October-December quarter of FY26, earnings per share fell to Tk 14.30 from Tk 15.09 in the same period of the previous year.
"Sale</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 02:15:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Runner slips back into losses in Q2 amid freight delivery disruptions</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/runner-slips-back-into-losses-in-q2-amid-freight-delivery-disruptions</link><description>Runner Automobiles endured a loss of Tk 14 million in the second quarter through December of FY26, due mainly to lower sales in the three-wheeler segment amid temporary supply chain disruption.
The country's pioneering motorcycle manufacturer had earned a consolidated profit of Tk 40 million in th</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 02:30:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>MoF weighs stock market listing of CDBL</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/mof-weighs-stock-market-listing-of-cdbl</link><description>The Ministry of Finance (MoF) has opened discussions on a potential stock-market listing of the Central Depository Bangladesh Limited (CDBL), a move that could reshape the governance and transparency of a key institution underpinning the country's capital markets.
The issue was raised at a high-le</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 02:45:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Berger Paints' Q3 profit rises 26pc on higher sales</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/berger-paints-q3-profit-rises-26pc-on-higher-sales</link><description>Berger Paints has secured a 26 per cent year-on-year growth in profit to Tk 1.18 billion in the third quarter through December last year, driven by higher sales amid a reduction in foreign exchange losses.
Berger, which follows the April-March financial year, posted a 5 per cent growth in sales to</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 03:00:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Recognition, valuation of women's unpaid care work stressed</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/recognition-valuation-of-womens-unpaid-care-work-stressed</link><description>Speakers at a seminar emphasised the importance of women's financial empowerment in Bangladesh and called for the recognition and valuation of unpaid care and domestic work through public-service infrastructure and social-protection policies.
They also stressed the need to ensure equal opportuniti</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 03:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No campaign to motivate public about referendum</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/no-campaign-to-motivate-public-about-referendum</link><description>There has not yet been launched any formal campaign in the Char areas of Gaibandha district to help the public understand the upcoming 2026 referendum, its purpose, and what a "Yes" vote signifies.
Awareness about the referendum is very limited, especially among the people of the Char area near th</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 03:20:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Under-construction bridge woes for Manikganj residents</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/under-construction-bridge-woes-for-manikganj-residents</link><description>The under-construction bridge over the Solai River at Baldhara Union in Singair Upazila has become a major cause of sufferings for local residents, rather than providing the intended relief.
Despite nearly one and a half decades of waiting for the project to begin, repeated delays and the failure</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 03:35:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Int'l plastic, packaging fair begins in city</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/intl-plastic-packaging-fair-begins-in-city</link><description>The 18th edition of the Bangladesh International Plastic, Packaging and Printing Industrial Fair-2026 kicked off at the International Convention City Bashundhara in Dhaka on Wednesday.
Organised jointly by the Bangladesh Plastic Goods Manufacturers and Exporters Association (BPGMEA) and Yorkers Tr</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 03:50:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Over Tk 161b stuck as BASIC Bank litigations pile up</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/over-tk-161b-stuck-as-basic-bank-litigations-pile-up</link><description>More than Tk 161 billion of BASIC Bank's funds remain locked in prolonged litigation, reflecting deep-rooted weaknesses in loan recovery and legal resolution, sources say.
They say the state-owned bank is currently involved in 1,230 pending cases, with a total claim value of Tk 161.58 billion, the</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 04:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>