<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 13:43:41 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Iran official says 2,000 people have been killed in unrest</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/iran-official-says-2000-people-have-been-killed-in-unrest</link><description>About 2,000 people including security personnel have been killed in protests in Iran, an Iranian official said on Tuesday, the first time authorities have acknowledged the high death toll from an intense crackdown on two weeks of nationwide unrest.
The Iranian official, speaking to Reuters, said t</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 11:18:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump's Iran tariff threat risks reopening China rift</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trumps-iran-tariff-threat-risks-reopening-china-rift</link><description>Donald Trump's threat to slap a 25 per cent tariff on countries that trade with Iran risks reopening old wounds with Beijing, Tehran's top partner, challenging Chinese leader Xi Jinping's global image and resolve to defend China's commercial interests.
Iran became a major flashpoint in US-China ti</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 11:33:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Move to clear Hasina, 112 others: what PBI says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/what-pbi-says-about-urging-court-to-drop-charges-against-hasina-112-others</link><description>The Police Bureau of Investigation (PBI) has said it is “facing pressure” over its recommendation to clear former prime minister Sheikh Hasina and 112 others over “attempted murder” during the July Uprising, insisting that the case itself was riddled with factual flaws.
In</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 11:48:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Educational institutions asked to conduct extensive campaign on referendum</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/educational-institutions-asked-to-conduct-extensive-campaign-on-referendum</link><description>The Directorate of Secondary and Higher Education (DSHE) and the Directorate of Madrasha Education (DME) have instructed conducting comprehensive campaigns in all government and private schools, colleges and madrasas to create public awareness among voters about the referendum to be held on Februar</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 12:03:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Denmark, Greenland to meet Vance, Rubio on Wednesday amid Trump’s takeover threat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/denmark-greenland-to-meet-vance-rubio-on-wednesday-amid-trumps-takeover-threat</link><description>The foreign ministers of Denmark and Greenland will meet U.S. Vice President JD Vance and Secretary of State Marco Rubio on Wednesday, the Danish foreign minister said, amid President Donald Trump’s push to take control of the Arctic island.
Danish Foreign Minister Lars Lokke Rasmussen and h</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 12:18:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump’s exercise of raw power upends world order</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trumps-exercise-of-raw-power-upends-world-order-sending-friends-and-foes-reeling</link><description>He has toppled Venezuela’s leader, vowed to control its vast oil reserves and threatened other Latin American countries with similar military action. He has talked openly about annexing Greenland, even by force. And, beyond the Western Hemisphere, he has warned Iran that the US could strike i</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 12:00:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CA confident party of young people will win seats in February polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ca-confident-party-of-young-people-will-win-seats-in-february-polls</link><description>Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus, on Tuesday, expressed optimism that some of the candidates of a newly formed political party, launched by young people, will secure seats in the upcoming national elections to be held on February 12.
Speaking at the opening of a regional higher education con</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 12:15:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Looted firearms no threat before polls: Ctg DIG</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/chattogram-dig-says-unrecovered-firearms-no-threat-ahead-of-elections</link><description>Chattogram Range Deputy Inspector General (DIG) Ahsan Habib Palash has said those holding the unrecovered looted weapons are unlikely to use them before the parliamentary elections.
He shared his view at a press conference on Tuesday afternoon at the superintendent’s office in Nasirabad, Cha</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 12:30:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Speakers urge action to protect domestic workers’ rights</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/speakers-urge-action-to-protect-domestic-workers-rights</link><description>Speakers at a discussion in Dhaka on Tuesday called for effective measures to ensure the dignity, safety and rights of domestic workers, including stronger safeguards for their welfare.
The call came at the “Policy Dialogue and Consultation Meeting 2026 on the Dignity, Safety and Rights of D</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 12:45:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fakhrul seeks army chief’s intervention over Chuadanga BNP leader’s killing</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/fakhrul-seeks-army-chiefs-intervention-over-chuadanga-bnp-leaders-killing</link><description>BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir on Tuesday sought the intervention of the Army Chief over the alleged killing of Shamsuzzaman Dablu, general secretary of Jibannagar Municipal unit BNP in Chuadanga, by members of the security forces.
In a statement, Fakhrul said incidents involvin</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 13:00:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Anti-minority hate speech in India rose by 13% in 2025, US research group says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/anti-minority-hate-speech-in-india-rose-by-13-in-2025-us-research-group-says</link><description>Hate speech against minorities including Muslims and Christians in India rose by 13 percent in 2025, with most incidents occurring in states governed by Prime Minister Narendra Modi’s Hindu nationalist Bharatiya Janata Party, a Washington-based research group said on Tuesday.
India Hate Lab</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 13:15:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The BBC seeks to dismiss Trump’s $10b defamation lawsuit in a Florida court</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/the-bbc-seeks-to-dismiss-trumps-10b-defamation-lawsuit-in-a-florida-court</link><description>The BBC plans to ask a court to throw out U.S. President Donald Trump’s $10 billion lawsuit against the British broadcaster, court papers show.
Trump filed a lawsuit in December over the way the BBC edited a speech he gave on Jan. 6, 2021. The claim, filed in a Florida federal court, seeks $</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 13:30:48 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>