<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 06:26:56 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>3 Afghan cricketers among 8 killed in Pakistani airstrike</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/3-afghan-cricketers-among-8-killed-in-pakistani-airstrike</link><description>At least three Afghan cricketers have been killed in a Pakistani airstrike in Afghanistan’s eastern Paktika province, according to the Afghanistan Cricket Board (ACB).
The ACB said the players, whom they identified by single names as Kabeer, Sibghatullah and Haroon, had travelled from Urgun</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 04:21:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>South Koreans return from Cambodia facing investigation over online scams</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/south-koreans-return-from-cambodia-facing-investigation-over-online-scams</link><description>A group of 64 South Koreans detained in Cambodia over alleged online scam operations returned home on Saturday with most expected to face investigation, South Korean authorities said.
Their return followed the alleged murder of a South Korean college student who was tortured in Cambodia in August</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 03:24:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump says Maduro 'doesn't want to f*ck around' with US</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-says-maduro-doesnt-want-to-fck-around-with-us</link><description>US President Donald Trump said on Friday that Venezuelan President Nicolas Maduro does not want to “f*ck around” with the United States, amid escalating tensions between Washington and Caracas.
Trump's comments followed a Reuters report, citing three sources, that the US military was h</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 03:39:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Index Agro declares lower dividend despite steady profit growth</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/index-agro-declares-lower-dividend-despite-steady-profit-growth</link><description>Index Agro Industries Ltd, a manufacturer of poultry, fish and cattle feed, has recommended a 12 per cent cash and 5 per cent stock dividend for FY25.
The announcement came following a board meeting held on Thursday.
The company reported a profit of Tk 261 million in FY25, up 0.80 per cent from T</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 03:54:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Visitors throng furniture fair to explore latest trends</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/visitors-throng-furniture-fair-to-explore-latest-trends</link><description>A major furniture fair in the capital drew a huge crowd on Friday as visitors flocked to the venue to check out the latest trends offered under one roof.
With the theme "My country, my hope - let's decorate homes with local furniture", the five-day fair began at the International Convention City B</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 04:09:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Multiple factors ‘weaken BD's macroeconomic stability’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/multiple-factors-weaken-bds-macroeconomic-stability</link><description>Factors like subdued investment, inflationary pressure, financial sector vulnerabilities and political impasse have weakened Bangladesh's macroeconomic stability despite having decades of rapid expansion, economists and private sector entrepreneurs have said.
They also highlighted several key chal</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 04:24:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bay Terminal construction to begin this year</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bay-terminal-construction-to-begin-this-year</link><description>CHATTOGRAM, Oct 17: Construction of the Bay Terminal at Chittagong Port is set to begin this year, with the authority calling it the future gateway of Bangladesh's maritime trade.
Chittagong Port Authority (CPA) officials said the long-awaited mega project would be completed by 2031. An agreement</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 04:39:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A deep dive into Pahartali locomotive shed</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/analysis/a-deep-dive-into-pahartali-locomotive-shed-1</link><description>"There goes the Meghna Express power," says Anik Bal, pointing at the blue-yellow locomotive slowly moving away.
Standing at a safe distance from the tracks, I notice the locomotive number - 2938. Built by South Korea's Hyundai Rotem, it is a 1,500-horsepower engine with a top speed of 107 kilomet</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 04:54:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A quantum leap for local art</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/analysis/a-quantum-leap-for-local-art</link><description>It's a declaration of belief that uncertainty can be beautiful and that questioning can lead to discovery. Such moral is vivified through a medley of artworks in Edge Gallery's '9+ONE: Interdimensional Journeys Part II'. It embraces uncertainty as the motif--its multidimensional effect on life in e</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 05:24:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>RHD facing challenges due to uncontrolled traffic hike</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rhd-facing-challenges-due-to-uncontrolled-traffic-hike</link><description>The Roads and Highways Department (RHD) is facing tremendous challenges in carrying out road development and maintenance work due to what its officials said 'uncontrolled increase in traffic with vehicles of different speeds and spaces'.
The state agency is facing pressure to manage 13 types of ve</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 05:39:19 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>