<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 11:19:29 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>EC restores Nagorik Oikko chief Manna’s candidacy on appeal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ec-restores-nagorik-oikko-chief-mannas-candidacy-on-appeal</link><description>The Election Commission has reinstated the candidacy of Nagorik Oikko chief Mahmudur Rahman Manna for the Bogura-2 (Shibganj) constituency in the upcoming 13th parliamentary election.
The decision was made on Sunday after the commission heard Manna’s appeal against the rejection of his nomin</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 10:00:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BTCL boosts internet speeds without raising prices</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/btcl-boosts-internet-speeds-without-raising-prices</link><description>Bangladesh Telecommunications Company Limited (BTCL) has increased the speed of all its existing internet packages by up to three times, while keeping monthly charges unchanged, aiming to provide faster and more digital-friendly services for its customers.
The Ministry of Posts, Telecommunications</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 08:49:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>RAB arrests another suspect in murder of lawyer Alif</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rab-arrests-another-suspect-in-murder-of-lawyer-alif</link><description>The Rapid Action Battalion has arrested another suspect in the murder of lawyer Saiful Islam Alif in Chattogram.
The arrest was announced in a statement signed by RAB-7 Assistant Director (Media) and Assistant Superintendent of Police ARM Mozaffar Hossain on Sunday afternoon.
The arrestee, identi</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 09:04:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh increases spending for LNG import</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladesh-increases-spending-for-lng-import</link><description>Bangladesh’s interim government in 2025 paid around US$3,877.74 million to import 109 LNG-filled cargoes against an amount of $3,022.32 million for 86 cargos in 2024 amid increased demand for the liquefied gas in industries amid plans to import more in current year.
“We spent US$ 855.4</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 09:19:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hasina couldn’t have contested 2008 polls if ACC, EC worked properly: ACC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hasinas-candidacy-for-2008-polls-wouldve-been-scrapped-if-acc-ec-functioned-properly-acc-chief</link><description>Awami League President Sheikh Hasina’s asset statement submitted alongside her affidavit for the ninth general elections in 2008 differed significantly from the assets she was subsequently found to own, claims Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) Chairman Mohammad Abdul Momen.
He said, “If</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 09:34:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No negative impact on Bangladesh–India trade from IPL issue: Commerce Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/no-negative-impact-on-bangladesh-india-trade-from-ipl-issue-commerce-adviser</link><description>Bangladesh’s Interim Government Commerce Adviser Sheikh Bashiruddin has said that the IPL-related issue has had no adverse impact on trade between Bangladesh and India, noting that bilateral commercial activities are continuing as usual.
He made the remarks on Sunday (January 11) while speak</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 09:49:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EU mission spells out criteria for inclusive elections</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/what-does-an-inclusive-and-participatory-election-mean-eu-observers-explain</link><description>An inclusive and participatory election means ensuring that all groups in Bangladeshi society are able to vote and that citizens turn out in credible numbers to shape their future, according to the head of the European Union’s election observation mission.
Speaking at a media briefing in Dha</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 10:04:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Interim government to campaign for 'Yes' vote: press secretary</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/interim-government-to-campaign-for-yes-vote-press-secretary</link><description>Bangladesh will officially kick off campaigning for the upcoming general election and referendum from January 22, and the interim government will be campaigning for a “Yes” vote in the referendum, says Shafiqul Alam, press secretary to the chief advisor.
He made the remarks at a press</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 10:19:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EU to send large election observation team to Bangladesh: Mission head tells CA</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/eu-to-send-large-election-observation-team-to-bangladesh-mission-head-tells-ca</link><description>Chief Observer of the European Union Election Observation Mission (EU EOM) Ivars Ijabs on Sunday said the EU is going to send a large election observation team to Bangladesh, noting that the forthcoming election will be historic for the country.
Ijabs said this at a meeting with Chief Adviser Prof</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 10:34:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UAE president pardons 25 convicted Bangladeshi citizens</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/uae-president-pardons-25-convicted-bangladeshi-citizens</link><description>The president of the United Arab Emirates, Sheikh Mohamed bin Zayed Al Nahyan, has pardoned 25 Bangladeshi citizens who were previously convicted by courts in the UAE, following a formal request from the government of Bangladesh.
The clemency was granted to Bangladeshi nationals who had been arres</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 10:49:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>International law applies to everyone, including US: German minister</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/international-law-applies-to-everyone-including-us-says-german-finance-minister</link><description>The principles of international law apply to everyone, including the United States, German Finance Minister and Vice Chancellor Lars Klingbeil said on Sunday, in reference to President Donald Trump's threats to seize Greenland.
"It is solely up to Denmark and Greenland to decide about Greenland's</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 11:04:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ICT prosecutors seek charges against Joy, Palak</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ict-prosecutors-seek-charges-against-joy-palak</link><description>Prosecutors at the International Crimes Tribunal have applied for the framing of charges against Sajeeb Wazed Joy, the son of ousted prime minister Sheikh Hasina, and former ICT state minister Zunaid Ahmed Palak, accusing them of involvement in crimes against humanity by shutting down internet se</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 11:19:29 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>