<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 09:41:49 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Indices mixed at mid-session: DSE down, CSE up</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/indices-mixed-at-mid-session-dse-down-cse-up</link><description>The country’s stock markets showed a mixed trend in the first half of Monday’s trading, with indices falling in Dhaka while gaining in Chattogram.
During the first hour of trading, the key index of the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSEX) dropped by 2 points, while the Shariah-based DSES and th</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 07:02:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ICT takes cognisance of charges against AL leader Hanif</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ict-takes-cognisance-of-charges-against-al-leader-hanif</link><description>The International Crimes Tribunal (ICT) has taken cognisance of three charges of crimes against humanity, accusing Mahbub Ul Islam Hanif, joint general secretary of the ousted Awami League, and three others of attempting to suppress the July Uprising.
The ICT also ordered the suspects to be arrest</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 07:17:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No sustainable solution to Rohingya crisis without repatriation: RRRC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/no-sustainable-solution-to-rohingya-crisis-without-repatriation-rrrc</link><description>There is no prospect of resolving the Rohingya crisis unless repatriation to Myanmar begins, said Mohammed Mizanur Rahman, Additional Secretary and Refugee Relief and Repatriation Commissioner (RRRC). He made the remark as the chief guest while speaking at an event organised by ActionAid Bangladesh</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 07:32:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CEC seeks media support for fair election environment in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cec-seeks-media-support-for-fair-election-environment-in-bangladesh</link><description>Chief Election Commissioner (CEC) AMM Nasir Uddin on Monday said that they seek cooperation from the media to ensure a level playing field for all during the national election.
"We are committed to the nation for a credible election. This dialogue is not a ceremonial one; we want to move forward w</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 08:02:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hasina’s stay in India a legal matter requiring bilateral engagement: Misri</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hasinas-stay-in-india-a-legal-matter-requiring-bilateral-engagement-misri</link><description>Explaining former Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina's presence in India and its impact on bilateral relations, Indian Foreign Secretary Vikram Misri on Monday said this is a “judicial legal process” and it requires “engagement and consultations” between the two governments.
&amp;ldq</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 08:08:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Defence counsel cross-examines IO in Hasina's crimes against humanity case</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/defence-counsel-cross-examines-io-in-hasinas-crimes-against-humanity-case</link><description>The state-appointed defence counsel on Monday began cross-examining the investigation officer (IO) in a case against three individuals, including ousted prime minister Sheikh Hasina, over alleged crimes against humanity committed during the July–August Mass Uprising.
Advocate Amir Hossain, t</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 08:38:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Swiss Gaza flotilla activists allege 'inhumane detention conditions' in Israel</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/swiss-gaza-flotilla-activists-allege-inhumane-detention-conditions-in-israel</link><description>Nine members of the Gaza aid flotilla arrived home in Switzerland on Sunday after being deported by Israel, with some alleging they had been subject to inhumane conditions whilst in detention there, the group representing them said.
Israel did not immediately comment on the new allegations.
Its f</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 08:53:32 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>