<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 13:31:34 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Sonali Bank holds workshop on Smart Case Management</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/sonali-bank-holds-workshop-on-smart-case-management</link><description>Sonali Bank PLC organised a training workshop on the newly added modules in the Smart Case Management System at its head office IT Lab on Thursday.
Md Shawkat Ali Khan, Managing Director and CEO of Sonali Bank PLC, inaugurated the workshop, according to a press release.
Farida Yasmin, Joint Secre</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 09:57:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>905th executive committee meeting of Shahjalal Islami Bank held</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/905th-executive-committee-meeting-of-shahjalal-islami-bank-held</link><description>The 905th meeting of the executive committee of Shahjalal Islami Bank PLC (SJIB PLC) was held on Wednesday, 15 October 2025, at the bank’s corporate head office.
The meeting was presided over by Mr Akkas Uddin Mollah, chairman of the executive committee, says a press release.
The committee</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 10:12:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Drukair Holidays offer exclusive benefits for EBL cardholders</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/drukair-holidays-offer-exclusive-benefits-for-ebl-cardholders</link><description>Drukair Holidays, the holiday management wing of Drukair, will provide exclusive privileges to Eastern Bank Plc (EBL) cardholders.
M Khorshed Anowar, Deputy Managing Director and Head of Retail and SME Banking at EBL;  Ashfia Jannat Saleh, Deputy Managing Director of Saimon Holidays; and the</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 10:27:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The militant leader stirring conflict between Pakistan and Afghanistan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/the-militant-leader-stirring-conflict-between-pakistan-and-afghanistan</link><description>Hanging over the recent eruption of fighting between Pakistan and Afghanistan, the most serious clash between the neighbours in decades, is the spectre of a militant leader Islamabad accuses of directing near-daily attacks on its soil.
An uneasy ceasefire took hold on Wednesday, but Pakistan&amp;rsquo</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 10:42:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dengue: 1 dies, 755 hospitalised</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/bangladesh-records-one-more-dengue-death-755-hospital-admissions-in-a-day</link><description>Over the past 24 hours, dengue has claimed one more life in Bangladesh, raising this year’s toll to 243, while 755 people were admitted to hospitals around the country.
According to Thursday’s Directorate General of Health Services (DGHS) bulletin, a woman aged 40 died from the mosquit</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 11:12:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gold smuggling surges in India as price spikes before festivals</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/gold-smuggling-surges-in-india-as-price-spikes-before-festivals</link><description>Gold smuggling into India has spiked ahead of key festivals, government and industry officials told Reuters, in response to record-high prices and a supply crunch.
Smuggling of gold into the world's second biggest buyer of the precious metal had fallen after the government slashed import taxes on</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 11:27:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Asif Mahmud calls for justice in Chankharpul killings</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/asif-mahmud-seeks-exemplary-punishment-over-chankharpul-murders</link><description>In the July Uprising case over the killing of six people, including student Anas, in Chankharpul, testimony from Asif Mahmud Shojib Bhuyain—one of the movement’s key coordinators and now an interim government advisor—has concluded.
He testified on Thursday before the three-member</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 11:57:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>HSC 2025: Nine Kurigram colleges witness zero pass</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/hsc-2025-nine-kurigram-colleges-witness-zero-pass</link><description>Not a single student from nine colleges in Kurigram district managed to pass the 2025 Higher Secondary Certificate (HSC) examination.
The nine colleges are Singar Dabrihat College in Rajarhat upazila, Char Shoulmari Adarsha Mohila College in Roumari, Bagua Anantapur School and College in Ulipur, R</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 12:12:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Election 2026: AB announces candidates for 108 constituencies</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/election-2026-ab-announces-candidates-for-108-constituencies</link><description>The Amar Bangladesh Party (AB Party) on Thursday announced the names of its candidates for 108 constituencies as part of its first phase list for the upcoming 12th parliamentary election.
AB Party Chairman Mojibur Rahman Monju announced the names at a press conference held at the Far East Tower au</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 12:42:05 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>