<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 11:16:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Hundreds missing after migrant vessel sinks off Malaysia-Thailand border</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/hundreds-missing-after-migrant-vessel-sinks-off-malaysia-thailand-border</link><description>Hundreds were missing on Sunday after a boat sank near the Thailand-Malaysia border, as 10 survivors and one body were recovered, the Malaysian maritime authority said.
More victims might still be found at sea some three days after the sinking of the vessel, which left Buthidaung, Myanmar, with ab</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 07:56:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>1 dead, 10 rescued after migrant boat capsizes off Malaysia-Thailand waters</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/1-dead-10-rescued-after-migrant-boat-capsizes-off-malaysia-thailand-waters</link><description>At least one individual has been found dead and 10 others have been rescued after a boat carrying nearly 100 undocumented migrants sank in waters near the Malaysia-Thailand maritime border, Malaysia's national news agency Bernama quoted local police as saying on Sunday.
Malaysia's Kedah police chi</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 08:11:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No confusion about upcoming parliament election: Asif Nazrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/no-confusion-about-upcoming-parliament-election-asif-nazrul</link><description>Law, Justice and Parliamentary Affairs Adviser Dr Asif Nazrul on Sunday said there is no reason for confusion over the upcoming parliamentary election. 
He said the interim government is fully committed to holding the election in early February, and all necessary measures will be taken to ens</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 08:26:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fire at Mohammadpur garage sparked by ‘bomb attack’, police say</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fire-at-mohammadpur-garage-sparked-by-bomb-attack-police-say</link><description>Police have uncovered initial evidence that a fire that broke out at a car garage in Dhaka’s Mohammadpur was sparked by a crude bomb thrown from a motorcycle.
The incident occurred at Mohammadpur’s Beribadh area at a garage near the University of Liberal Arts, Bangladesh campus, around</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 08:30:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt to buy Aman rice at Tk 50 per kg</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-to-buy-aman-rice-at-tk-50-per-kg</link><description>The government has set a target of procuring 700,000 tonnes of rice for the upcoming Aman season, raising the price by a maximum of Tk 3 per kg compared to last year.
The decision was taken at a meeting of the Food Planning and Procurement Committee on Sunday, according to bdnews24.com.
Accordi</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 08:45:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Economic Affairs Committee okays import of crude oil</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/economic-affairs-committee-okays-import-of-crude-oil</link><description>The Economic Affairs Committee on Sunday approved a proposal to import crude oil through a government-to-government (G2G) arrangement under the direct procurement method for processing at Eastern Refinery Limited (ERL) in 2026.
 
The proposal was placed by the Energy and Mineral Resources Di</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 09:00:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Education boards instruct colleges to put HSC test exams 'on hold'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/education-boards-instruct-colleges-to-put-hsc-test-exams-on-hold</link><description>Education boards have directed colleges not to hold the test exams for Higher Secondary Certificate students for now, reports bdnews24.com.
Colleges have instead been asked to continue with regular classes, with the boards saying that the schedule for the 2024–25 session’s selection te</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 09:15:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh October PMI records faster expansion rate at 61.8</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh-october-pmi-records-faster-expansion-rate-at-618</link><description>The October reading of the Bangladesh Purchasing Managers’ Index (PMI) gained 2.7 points from the previous month to post a faster expansion rate at 61.8.
This latest PMI reading was attributed to a faster expansion rate for all the key sectors of agriculture, manufacturing, construction and</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 09:30:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BGMEA RSC at loggerheads over monitoring of labour rights issues</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bgmea-rsc-at-loggerheads-over-monitoring-of-labour-rights-issues</link><description>The apparel apex body — BGMEA — on Sunday asked its members to refrain from adhering to the requirements of the non-safety-related complaint mechanism proposed by the RMG Sustainability Council (RSC).
The Bangladesh Garment Manufacturers and Exporters Association (BGMEA), in a circular</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 09:45:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Teachers should adopt creative methods to make learning enjoyable: Bidhan Ranjan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/teachers-should-adopt-creative-methods-to-make-learning-enjoyable-bidhan-ranjan</link><description>Adviser to the Ministry of Primary and Mass Education Professor Dr. Bidhan Ranjan Roy Poddar has stressed that teachers should adopt more creative teaching methods to make learning enjoyable and engaging for children.
He made the remarks as the chief guest at a views-exchange meeting on "Enhancing</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 10:00:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IMF to decide Bangladesh’s next loan instalment after formation of political govt: Salehuddin</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/imf-to-decide-bangladeshs-next-loan-instalment-after-formation-of-political-govt-salehuddin</link><description>Finance Adviser Dr Salehuddin Ahmed on Sunday said the International Monetary Fund (IMF) is continuing its review of Bangladesh's progress under the ongoing loan programme, and a final decision regarding the next instalment is expected only after the formation of the next political government.
"Th</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 10:15:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Next government to decide on new Pay Commission: Salehuddin</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/next-government-to-decide-on-new-pay-commission-salehuddin</link><description>Finance Adviser Dr. Salehuddin Ahmed on Sunday said that the formation and implementation of a new Pay Commission will be decided by the next elected government.
The interim government will only carry out ongoing reforms to a reasonable stage before handing over a consolidated framework for the in</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 10:30:01 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>