<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 12:40:31 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>NCP delegation joins meeting with CEC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ncp-delegation-joins-meeting-with-cec</link><description>A delegation of National Citizen Party (NCP) on Thursday joined a meeting with Chief Election Commissioner (CEC) AMM Nasir Uddin.
A three-member delegation led by NCP Chief Coordinator Nasir Uddin Patwary joined the meeting with the CEC at his office at 3:40 pm.
NCP Joint Convener Khaled Saifulla</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 09:04:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Australian high commissioner meets Jamaat chief Shafiqur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/australian-high-commissioner-meets-jamaat-chief-shafiqur</link><description>Australian High Commissioner Susan Ryle has met with Jamaat-e-Islami Amir Shafiqur Rahman.
She went to the Shafiqur’s office in Bashundhara at 9 am on Thursday. She was accompanied by Deputy High Commissioner Clinton Pobke, Political First Secretary Anna Peterson, and several other represent</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 09:19:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>RMG exports attain 4.79pc growth in July-September of FY26</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/rmg-exports-attain-479pc-growth-in-july-september-of-fy26</link><description>The export of Ready-Made Garment (RMG) items showed a positive trend during the July-September period of the current fiscal year (FY26), fetching $9.97 billion, a marginal increase of 4.79%.
According to the Export Promotion Bureau (EPB’s) recently published country-wise export data for Bang</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 09:49:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New members appointed to board of Directors of Community Bank</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/new-members-appointed-to-board-of-directors-of-community-bank</link><description>Community Bank Bangladesh PLC is pleased to announce that Bangladesh Bank has approved the appointment of six new Directors and three Independent Directors to its Board, in accordance with regulatory requirements.
According to the official notification, the newly appointed Directors are: Mr. A.K.M</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 10:04:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hungarian writer László Krasznahorkai wins Nobel Prize in literature</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/hungarian-writer-laszlo-krasznahorkai-wins-the-nobel-prize-in-literature</link><description>Hungarian writer László Krasznahorkai, whose philosophical, bleakly funny novels often unfold in single sentences, won the Nobel Prize in literature Thursday for his “compelling and visionary oeuvre.”
Several works including his debut, “Satantango” a</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 10:19:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EA locks and loads 'Battlefield 6' to take on 'Call of Duty' before going private</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/entertainment/ea-locks-and-loads-battlefield-6-to-take-on-call-of-duty-before-going-private</link><description>lectronic Arts (EA.O) is betting on the latest "Battlefield" title to do what the last one could not - restore the franchise's reputation and loosen the dominance of "Call of Duty" on the first-person shooter genre.
Releasing on Friday, "Battlefield 6" will test the ability of EA's intellectual pr</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 11:04:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Advisory Council approves 4 ordinances, one proposal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/advisory-council-approves-4-ordinances-one-proposal</link><description>The Advisory Council on Thursday gave final and in principal approval to drafts of four ordinances and one proposal with Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus in the chair at his office.
At the meeting, the Advisory Council approved the drafts of the National Data Governance Ordinance-2025, Perso</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 11:19:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh has only 465 psychiatrists for 40 million patients, roundtable told</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-has-only-465-psychiatrists-for-40-million-patients-roundtable-told</link><description>FE ONLINE REPORT
Bangladesh has just 465 psychiatrists to serve an estimated 40 million people suffering from mental health problems, speakers said at a roundtable in Dhaka city on Thursday.
The discussion, held a day before World Mental Health Day 2025, urged immediate action to expand access to</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 11:49:52 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>