<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 11:25:32 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Plane crash in South Australia kills three</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/plane-crash-in-south-australia-kills-three</link><description>Three people were killed when a light aircraft crashed south of Adelaide on Friday afternoon, South Australia Police said on Saturday.
Police said they received reports of a light plane crashing into the ocean at about 4:20 p.m. local time and responded immediately, according to a statement.
All</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 09:07:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two Begum Rokeya Univ teachers suspended over sexual harassment allegations</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/two-begum-rokeya-university-teachers-suspended-over-sexual-harassment-allegations</link><description>Two associate professors at Begum Rokeya University, Rangpur (BRUR), have been suspended following allegations of sexual harassment, university authorities said.
The action was taken against Shamim Hossain, an associate professor in the Department of Geography and Environmental Science and assista</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 09:22:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EBL signs agreement with United Healthcare Services</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ebl-signs-agreement-with-united-healthcare-services</link><description>Eastern Bank PLC (EBL) customers will now enjoy exclusive healthcare benefits at United Medical College Hospital, Medix, and M A Rashid Hospital, Jamalpur, following a new agreement between EBL and United Healthcare Services Ltd (UHSL).
Farzana Qader, Head of Retail Alliance, EBL, and Mohammad Fai</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 08:15:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No chance of vote rigging, reaffirms Home Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/no-chance-of-vote-rigging-reaffirms-home-adviser</link><description>Home Affairs Adviser Lt Gen (retd) Md Jahangir Alam Chowdhury on Sunday said there is no possibility of vote rigging in the national election, expressing confidence that the polls will be peaceful, fair and festive ones.
“There is no scope for vote rigging. You cooperate with us. If any irre</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 08:30:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh eyes purchase of rail coaches, wagons from Pakistan: Report</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-eyes-purchase-of-rail-coaches-wagons-from-pakistan-report</link><description>Bangladesh has reportedly expressed keen interest in buying freight wagons and passenger coaches from Pakistan after being offered rolling stock at prices lower than those quoted by other international suppliers.
A two-member Bangladeshi delegation recently visited key Pakistan Railways facilities</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 08:45:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh to buy Boeing jets in bid to cut US tariffs, trade gap: Advisor</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladesh-to-buy-boeing-jets-in-bid-to-cut-us-tariffs-trade-gap-advisor</link><description>The interim government is planning to buy aircraft from Boeing as part of efforts to reduce tariffs imposed by the United States and narrow the trade deficit between the two countries, according to Civil Aviation and Tourism Advisor Sheikh Bashir Uddin.
He made the comments at a media briefing in</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 09:00:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Political parties must ensure women’s safety: Zaima Rahman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/political-parties-must-ensure-womens-safety-zaima-rahman</link><description>Barrister Zaima Rahman, daughter of BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman, on Sunday said political parties must take greater responsibility for ensuring women’s security—both online and offline—as well as within their own organisations.
“I think political parties should take more re</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 09:15:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP to remain uncompromising in protecting people’s rights: Fakhrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-to-remain-uncompromising-in-protecting-peoples-rights-fakhrul</link><description>BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir on Sunday said that BNP will always protect the rights of all people, regardless of religion, especially that of women.
“I firmly believe that no one is a minority in this country. There are no minorities in this country. Everyone is a citize</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 09:30:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NZ to hear Christchurch mosque shooter's appeal against sentence</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/new-zealand-to-hear-christchurch-mosque-shooters-appeal-against-sentence</link><description>A white supremacist who killed 51 Muslim worshippers and injured dozens at two mosques in New Zealand will begin an appeal hearing against his sentence on Monday.
Brenton Tarrant, 35, opened fire on two mosques in Christchurch in March 2019, in the worst mass shooting in the country's histor</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 09:45:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka seeks UN support for fair probe into Hadi murder</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dhaka-seeks-un-support-for-fair-probe-into-hadi-murder</link><description>The interim government has officially sought support from the Office of the United Nations High Commissioner for Human Rights (OHCHR) for a fair and transparent investigation into the assassination of Shaheed Sharif Osman Hadi.
OHCHR, headquartered in Geneva, is the principal UN entity dedicated t</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 10:00:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Over one-third of candidates breached election campaign spending limits: TIB</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/over-one-third-of-candidates-breached-election-campaign-spending-limits-tib</link><description>Transparency International Bangladesh (TIB) has found that more than one-third of election candidates exceeded the legally permitted campaign spending limit, with average expenditure reaching Tk 11.9 million even before the official campaign period ended.
The findings were disclosed at a press con</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 10:15:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh, China sign framework agreement for procurement of 4 vessels</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-china-sign-framework-agreement-for-procurement-of-4-vessels</link><description>The governments of Bangladesh and China on Sunday signed a framework agreement worth RMB 1.67 billion (equivalent to about Tk 2486.31 crore) for procuring four new vessels for the Bangladesh Shipping Corporation (BSC).
Secretary of the Economic Relations Division (ERD) Md Shahriar Kader Siddique s</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 10:30:30 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>