<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 13:47:50 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>CA for armed forces' role in ensuring free and fair polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ca-for-armed-forces-role-in-ensuring-free-and-fair-polls</link><description>Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus today (Monday) instructed the Armed Forces to perform their duties with professionalism, neutrality, and inter-institutional coordination to ensure participatory, fear-free and fair national elections.
The Chief Adviser gave the instruction at a views exchang</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 10:45:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Former MPs make up 85 of BNP’s 292 election candidates</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/former-mps-make-up-85-of-bnps-292-election-candidates</link><description>The Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) has nominated candidates in 292 constituencies for the upcoming 13th parliamentary election.
Speaking at a media briefing at the BNP’s Gulshan office on Monday, Mahdi Amin, spokesperson for the party’s Election Steering Committee, said 85 of the c</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 11:00:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No official bound to carry out illegal orders: ICT chief prosecutor</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/no-official-required-to-carry-out-illegal-orders-says-ict-chief-prosecutor</link><description>International Crimes Tribunal (ICT) Chief Prosecutor Tajul Islam has said no state official or employee is obligated to obey any unlawful order issued by the government.
He made the remarks on Monday afternoon after the ICT delivered its verdict against eight policemen over the killing of six peop</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 11:15:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DUCSU member Sarba Mitra Chakma announces resignation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/ducsu-member-sarba-mitra-chakma-announces-resignation-as-video-draws-backlash</link><description>In the face of criticism, Sarba Mitra Chakma has announced his resignation from the post of executive member of the Dhaka University Central Students' Union (DUCSU) in a Facebook post.
On Monday afternoon, he wrote: “I have decided to resign. My decision was not taken out of spite or due to</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 11:30:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>United Finance Plc, United Healthcare Services Ltd announce strategic partnership to enhance customer wellbeing</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/united-finance-plc-united-healthcare-services-ltd-announce-strategic-partnership-to-enhance-customer-wellbeing</link><description>United Finance PLC and United Healthcare Services Ltd. have entered into a strategic partnership aimed at enhancing customer wellbeing through a range of value‑added healthcare services, exclusive discounts, and tailored wellness packages.
The agreement was signed by Mohammad Faizur Rahman, Chief</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 11:45:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EU countries give final approval to Russian gas ban</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/eu-countries-give-final-approval-to-russian-gas-ban</link><description>European Union countries on Monday gave their final approval to ban Russian gas imports by late 2027, making their vow to cut ties with their former top supplier legally binding, nearly four years after Moscow's full-scale invasion of Ukraine.
Ministers from EU countries approved the law at a meet</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 12:00:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pakistan weighs boycotting India match in solidarity with Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/pakistan-weighs-boycotting-india-match-in-solidarity-with-bangladesh</link><description>The crisis surrounding the 2026 T20 World Cup has escalated further, with reports emerging that Pakistan is seriously considering boycotting its blockbuster group-stage match against arch-rivals India.
The move is being weighed by the Pakistan Cricket Board (PCB) as a major protest against the Int</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 11:45:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Over 400,000 expats cast their votes through postal ballot till Monday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/over-400000-expats-cast-their-votes-through-postal-ballot-till-monday</link><description>A total of 4,05,164 Bangladeshi expatriates cast their votes through postal ballot as of 1:30 pm on Monday, according to the Election Commission.
Among them, 3,44,993 voters submitted their ballots at post offices or ballot boxes in their respective countries. Meanwhile, 19,388 ballots were cast w</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 12:00:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IDCOL hosts climate action consultation with Korean delegation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/idcol-hosts-climate-action-consultation-with-korean-delegation</link><description>Infrastructure Development Company Limited (IDCOL) hosted a stakeholder consultation meeting with a visiting delegation from the Korea Environmental Industry &amp; Technology Institute (KEITI) to discuss renewable energy, energy efficiency technologies, and Bangladesh’s climate action mechanisms.</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 12:15:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mirsarai to host Bangladesh’s first defence manufacturing zone</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/mirsarai-to-host-bangladeshs-first-defence-manufacturing-zone</link><description>The Bangladesh Economic Zones Authority (BEZA) will set up the country’s first Defence Industrial Zone in Mirsarai, Chattogram, to produce military equipment for domestic use and export.
The decision was taken at a meeting of the Investment Promotion Agency (IPA) on Monday, chaired by Chief</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 12:30:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US Ambassador visits Ctg Port as major US wheat shipment arrives</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/us-ambassador-visits-ctg-port-as-major-us-wheat-shipment-arrives</link><description>U.S. Ambassador to Bangladesh Brent T. Christensen visited Chattogram port to reinforce commercial cooperation and strengthen bilateral ties.   
On Monday, Ambassador Christensen joined Chattogram Port Authority Chairman Rear Admiral S. M. Moniruzzaman and Secretary of Food Md. Firoz Sar</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 12:45:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Man dies in Mugda kitchen fire</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/man-dies-in-mugda-kitchen-fire</link><description>A young man has died after suffering burn injuries in a gas fire at a flat in the capital’s Mugda.
He died around 1:30pm on Monday at the National Institute of Burn and Plastic Surgery in Dhaka, police said.
The victim, 30-year-old Ujjal Hossain, lived in a rented flat in Mugda. He is origi</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 13:00:58 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>