<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 14:24:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Fakhrul announces schedule for Khaleda’s funeral prayers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fakhrul-announces-khaledas-funeral-prayer-schedule-calls-for-order</link><description>BNP Chairperson Khaleda Zia’s funeral prayers will be held at 2pm on Wednesday at Parliament’s South Plaza, according to the BNP. She will later be laid to rest beside her husband, former president Ziaur Rahman.
BNP’s Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir announced the sc</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 11:15:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khaleda to be buried with state honours, bags banned at funeral prayers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/khaleda-to-be-buried-with-state-honours-bags-banned-at-funeral-prayers</link><description>Authorities have announced security restrictions for the funeral prayers and burial of former prime minister Khaleda Zia, including a ban on bags at the funeral prayer venue and limited access to the burial ceremony.
In a notice on Tuesday, the Chief Advisor’s Office said mourners attending</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 11:30:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DCCI mourns Khaleda Zia’s demise</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/dcci-mourns-khaleda-zias-demise</link><description>Dhaka Chamber of Commerce &amp; Industry (DCCI) has expressed grief and deepest condolences at the death of former Prime Minister Khaleda Zia.
On behalf of the business body and members of the Board of Directors, its President Taskeen Ahmed conveyed the condolences, according to a DCCI media release.</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 11:45:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jagannath University students’ union election rescheduled on Jan 6</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/jagannath-university-students-union-election-rescheduled-on-jan-6</link><description>The Jagannath University Central Students’ Union (JnUCSU) and hall council elections, postponed following the death of Khaleda Zia, will be held on Jan 6.
The decision came at an urgent meeting, said JnU Syndicate member Professor Mohammad Bilal Hossain.
Earlier in the morning, the universi</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 12:00:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India’s Jaishankar to attend Khaleda’s funeral</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/indian-foreign-minister-jaishankar-to-join-khaledas-final-farewell-in-dhaka</link><description>Indian Minister of External Affairs S Jaishankar will fly to Dhaka to attend BNP chief Khaleda Zia’s last rites.
Officials at the foreign ministry and Indian High Commission in Dhaka confirmed the matter on Tuesday.</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 12:15:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>SAARC Chamber mourns death of Khaleda Zia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/saarc-chamber-mourns-death-of-khaleda-zia</link><description>The SAARC Chamber of Commerce and Industries has expressed its deepest condolences on the passing of Begum Khaleda Zia, former Prime Minister of Bangladesh and Chairperson of the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP).
In a message of condolence issued on Tuesday, Begum Khaleda Zia was a pioneering po</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 12:30:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DB arrests listed terror suspect with firearms in Pallabi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/db-arrests-listed-terror-suspect-with-firearms-in-pallabi</link><description>Detective Branch (DB) of Dhaka Metropolitan Police (DMP) arrested a listed criminal and recovered two firearms and ammunition during a drive in the Pallabi area of the capital late Monday night.
The arrestee was identified as Ashikur Islam Shanto, 20.
Based on secret information, a team of DB (Mi</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 12:45:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BPSC postpones 46th BCS viva voce scheduled for Dec 31, Jan 1</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bpsc-postpones-46th-bcs-viva-voce-scheduled-for-dec-31-jan-1</link><description>The Bangladesh Public Service Commission (BPSC) on Tuesday postponed the viva voce of the 46th Bangladesh Civil Service (BCS), scheduled for December 31 and January 1, in respect of the demise of former Prime Minister and Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) Chairperson Begum Khaleda Zia.
The BPSC i</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 13:00:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DMTCL to operate special services on Dec 31 for Khaleda’s janaza</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dmtcl-to-operate-special-services-on-dec-31-for-khaledas-janaza</link><description>Dhaka Mass Transit Company Limited (DMTCL) on Tuesday said it would operate special metro services along with the scheduled time tomorrow to facilitate commuters to join former prime minister Begum Khaleda Zia’s Namaj-e-Janaza.
A DMTCL statement issued by its director AKM Khairul Alam said t</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 13:15:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DITF 2026 opening rescheduled to January 3</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ditf-2026-opening-rescheduled-to-january-3</link><description>The opening ceremony of the Dhaka International Trade Fair (DITF) 2026 has been rescheduled to Saturday, following the death of former Prime Minister and BNP Chairperson Begum Khaleda Zia.
The event was originally slated to begin on Thursday, said a press release issued by the Export Promotion Bur</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 13:30:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP expels Rumeen Farhana, 8 others for violating party decision</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-expels-rumeen-farhana-8-others-for-violating-party-decision</link><description>BNP on Tuesday expelled nine leaders at different levels for violating party discipline by carrying out organisational activities against its decisions.
The decision was announced in a media release signed by BNP Senior Joint Secretary General Ruhul Kabir Rizvi.
The expelled leaders are BNP Assis</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 13:45:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Biting cold to stay put for 2 more days</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/intense-cold-to-linger-for-two-more-days-with-patchy-drizzle</link><description>The Bangladesh Meteorological Department (BMD) says the biting cold gripping the country is set to persist through Wednesday, as dense fog continues to block sunlight across large swathes of Bangladesh.
After a brief easing, temperatures could dip again, the BMD warned, raising the prospect of ano</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 14:00:54 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>