<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 11:22:04 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>ADB doubles Bangladesh financing to $2.57 billion in 2025</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/adb-doubles-bangladesh-financing-to-257-billion-in-2025</link><description>The Asian Development Bank (ADB) committed $2.57 billion in new sovereign financing to Bangladesh in 2025, more than double its 2024 commitment of $1.18 billion.
The 2025 programme targets priority investments in energy, transport, banking reforms, urban services, climate resilience, small and med</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 07:45:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt orders TV channels to suspend IPL broadcast in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-orders-tv-channels-to-suspend-ipl-broadcast-in-bangladesh</link><description>The government has instructed television channels to suspend the broadcast of Indian Premier League (IPL) matches in Bangladesh.
In a letter sent to television channels on Monday (January 5), the Ministry of Information and Broadcasting issued the directive.
According to the letter, the ministry</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 08:00:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC is confident holding a neutral election: CEC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-is-confident-holding-a-neutral-election-cec</link><description>Chief Election Commissioner A M M Nasir Uddin on Monday said the Election Commission (EC) remains confident and committed to holding a free, fair and neutral election.
He made the remarks this morning after visiting the appeal centre set up at the Election Commission building in Agargaon to receiv</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 08:30:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CID confirms identities of eight July Uprising martyrs through DNA profiling</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cid-confirms-identities-of-eight-july-uprising-martyrs-through-dna-profiling</link><description>The Criminal Investigation Department (CID) on Monday released the names and addresses of eight martyrs of the July Uprising 2024 after confirming their identities through DNA profiling and forensic examination.
The bodies were exhumed from Rayerbazar Graveyard as part of a state-led initiative to</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 08:45:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NBR launches e-VAT module for paper-based returns</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/nbr-launches-e-vat-module-for-paper-based-returns</link><description>The National Board of Revenue (NBR) has taken a step towards fully digitising the country's VAT administration by introducing a new initiative that allows taxpayers to bring all previously submitted paper-based VAT returns under the e-VAT system.
It has added a sub-module titled "Hard Copy Return</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 09:00:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khaleda Zia a unique figure in Bangladesh’s democratic journey: Moyeen Khan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/khaleda-zia-a-unique-figure-in-bangladeshs-democratic-journey-moyeen-khan</link><description>BNP senior leader Dr Abdul Moyeen Khan on Monday described Khaleda Zia as an exceptional leader whose name is closely linked with Bangladesh’s political journey, democratic movement, and the long struggle to establish people’s voting and fundamental rights.
“Khaleda Zia is a uniq</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 08:57:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Writ filed challenging legality of election, referendum on same day</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/writ-filed-challenging-legality-of-election-referendum-on-same-day</link><description>A writ petition has been filed with the High Court challenging the legality of announcing the schedule for the national election and a referendum on the same day.
The writ petition also sought a stay order on the effectiveness of the gazette notification issued on December 11 on the schedule for b</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 09:12:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Indictment hearing in sedition case against Hasina, 285 others deferred</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/indictment-hearing-in-sedition-case-against-ex-pm-hasina-285-others-deferred</link><description>A Dhaka court has deferred the charge-framing hearing in a sedition case filed against ousted prime minister Sheikh Hasina and 285 others, as one of the arrested accused was not produced before the court.
On Monday, Judge Abdus Salam of Dhaka Special Judge’s Court-9 set Jan 21 as the new dat</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 09:27:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Venezuela's interim president offers US cooperation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/venezuelas-interim-president-offers-us-cooperation-after-trump-says-further-strike-possible</link><description>Venezuela's acting president offered on Sunday to collaborate with the United States on an agenda focused on "shared development", striking a conciliatory tone for the first time since US forces captured the oil-rich nation's president, Nicolas Maduro.
In a statement posted on social media, Acting</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 09:42:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Paris court to rule in case involving alleged cyberbullying of Brigitte Macron</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/paris-court-to-rule-in-case-involving-alleged-cyberbullying-of-brigitte-macron</link><description>A Paris court is to rule on Monday in a case involving 10 people accused of cyberbullying French first lady Brigitte Macron by spreading false online claims about her gender and sexuality, allegations her daughter said damaged her health and family life.
The defendants, eight men and two women age</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 09:57:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hadi murder chargesheet on Jan 7, says home advisor</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hadi-murder-chargesheet-on-jan-7-says-home-advisor-1</link><description>Home Advisor Jahangir Alam Chowdhury has said the final chargesheet in the murder case of Inqilab Moncho convenor Sharif Osman bin Hadi will be submitted on Jan 7.
He made the remarks while speaking to reporters after a meeting of the Advisory Council on law and order at the Secretariat on Monday.</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 10:12:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>8 July martyrs buried at Rayerbazar identified: Adviser Farooq-e-Azam</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/8-july-martyrs-buried-at-rayerbazar-identified-adviser-farooq-e-azam</link><description>Liberation War Affairs Adviser Farooq-e-Azam on Monday said identities of eight July uprising martyrs who were buried at Rayerbazar Graveyard as unidentified have been confirmed through DNA test.
Both local and international experts were involved in the highly sensitive process and it was done mai</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 10:27:58 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>