<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 11:17:43 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>US becomes major source of gun violence in Caribbean: report</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/us-becomes-major-source-of-gun-violence-in-caribbean-report</link><description>The United States has become a major source of high-level firearm-related violence plaguing the Caribbean region, according to a recent report jointly released by multiple regional and international organisations.
The region's violence-related activities are on the rise, including the recruitment</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 07:42:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khaleda's condition ‘unchanged’, say doctors</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/khaledas-condition-unchanged-say-doctors</link><description>Doctors treating BNP chief Khaleda Zia say her condition remains “largely unchanged” amid plans to fly the former prime minister to London for advanced treatment.
The 79-year-old has been in Dhaka’s Evercare Hospital since November 23 and remains under close observation in the Cr</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 07:57:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>National election will be major test for law enforcers: Touhid</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/national-election-will-be-major-test-for-law-enforcers-touhid</link><description>Highlighting the role of law enforcers in holding a fair election, Foreign Affairs Adviser Md Touhid Hossain said on Saturday that the upcoming parliamentary polls will be a major test for law enforcement agencies.
"Although there were initial challenges, the police have now organised themselves e</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 08:12:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khaleda's condition remains ‘unchanged’, say doctors</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/khaledas-condition-remains-unchanged-say-doctors</link><description>Doctors treating BNP chief Khaleda Zia say her condition remains “largely unchanged” amid plans to fly the former prime minister to London for advanced treatment.
The 79-year-old has been in Dhaka’s Evercare Hospital since Nov 23 and remains under close observation in the Criti</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 08:27:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two govt offices set on fire in Magura</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/two-govt-offices-set-on-fire-in-magura</link><description>Miscreants set fire to the Assistant Commissioner (AC-Land) office and Registry office in Magura Sadar by throwing petrol on Saturday.
AC (Land) Asma Akter said the perpetrators broke a window at the back of the building and hurled petrol bombs around 3:00 am, reports UNB.
The fire engulfed a roo</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 09:00:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prisoner dies at Jashore Jail hospital</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/prisoner-dies-at-jashore-jail-hospital</link><description>A prisoner who was arrested during a joint forces’ operation in Keshabpur upazila of Jashore district on Thursday died at Jashore Central Jail hospital on Friday.
The deceased was identified as Ujjal Biswas, 39, son of Najir Biswas of Altapole in Keshabpur upazila, reports UNB.
Abid Ahmed,</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 09:15:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Onion prices jump to Tk 150 per kg in two days</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/onion-prices-jump-to-tk-150-per-kg-in-two-days</link><description>Onion prices have surged by Tk 40–50 per kg within just two days, with the kitchen markets in Dhaka now selling it at Tk 140–150 per kg.
A visit to several city markets on Saturday found wholesalers charging Tk 650–680 for a palla (5 kg), pushing retail prices up sharply.</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 09:30:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rizvi lauds NIBPS doctors for replanting youth’s hand</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/rizvi-lauds-nibps-doctors-for-replanting-youths-hand</link><description>BNP Senior Joint Secretary General Ruhul Kabir Rizvi today (Saturday) said the replantation of hand of 20-year-old Tasfin Ferdous of Tongi who lost his hand in a terrorist attack on November 9, is a rare success.
Praising the doctors at the National Institute of Burn and Plastic Surgery (NIBPS), R</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 09:55:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Malaysia targets 300,000 Bangladeshi tourists in 2026: Envoy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/malaysia-targets-300000-bangladeshi-tourists-in-2026-envoy</link><description>Malaysian High Commissioner Mohd Shuhada Othman today said Malaysia aims to attract 300,000 Bangladeshi tourists in 2026 under its Visit Malaysia Year campaign, stressing that stronger tourism ties and proper use of the official e-Visa system will ensure smoother travel.
The envoy made the remarks</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 10:10:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mitigation setback at COP30 triggers warning from Bangladesh climate advocates</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/mitigation-setback-at-cop30-triggers-warning-from-bangladesh-climate-advocates</link><description>Mitigation ambitions suffered a setback at COP30 as negotiators pushed the Fossil Fuel Phaseout Roadmap further into the future, prompting climate justice advocates in Bangladesh to warn of widening gaps between political promises and real action.
 
These concerns came into sharp focus at</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 10:25:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>'She has to make up her mind': Jaishankar on Sheikh Hasina's India stay</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/she-has-to-make-up-her-mind-jaishankar-on-sheikh-hasinas-india-stay</link><description>External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar on Saturday said that former Bangladeshi Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina's stay in India is her personal decision influenced by the "circumstances" that led her to the country, NDTV reports. 
Hasina fled to India in August last year, when her 15-year rule e</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 10:40:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Envoy Textiles’ former MD Salam’s dividend frozen by Tax Intelligence Unit</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/envoy-textiles-former-md-salams-dividend-frozen-by-tax-intelligence-unit</link><description>The National Board of Revenue’s (NBR) Tax Intelligence and Investigation Unit has frozen the dividend of Envoy Textiles Limited’s former managing director, Abdus Salam Murshedy.
NBR officials said the move comes amid an ongoing tax evasion case and aims to recover BDT 220 million in ou</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 10:55:06 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>