<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 04:42:13 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Health, education allocations face staggering cut</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/health-education-allocations-face-staggering-cut</link><description>Health and education sectors have taken the major brunt of a sizeable cut in the current development budget halfway through the fiscal year.   
The ongoing Annual Development Programme (ADP) outlay for the fiscal year 2025-26 has been cut by 13.04 per cent to Tk 2.0 trillion.
With</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 18:16:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Beyond open tendering</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/beyond-open-tendering</link><description>As Chairman of the Chittagong Port Authority, I welcome the decisive shift of the Nobel Laureate Dr Muhammad Yunus-led government towards port-centred maritime development as a foundation of Bangladesh's economic transformation. More than 92 per cent of our international trade passes through Chitta</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 18:17:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>When ideology, power, and sport collide</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/reviews/when-ideology-power-and-sport-collide</link><description>The T20 Men's ICC World Cup has transcended being a mere celebration of sporting success. In the Global South, particularly in South Asia, it has become one of the most ardent expressions in this age. It is in this context that the realms of sport and the construction of the post-colony become impo</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 18:32:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BD in troubled waters  of tomorrow</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/bd-in-troubled-waters-of-tomorrow</link><description>As is the usual practice every year, economists and experts on business trends locally and globally have been making their projections and predictions about how the country's as well as the world's economy will fare in the coming year (s). So far as Bangladesh's economy is concerned, much cannot be</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 18:47:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Protecting the deep-sea ecosystem of the Bay</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/protecting-the-deep-sea-ecosystem-of-the-bay</link><description>The deep sea is often imagined as distant, dark and detached from everyday life. In reality, it is one of the planet's most vital ecological frontiers -- and in the Bay of Bengal it is now under serious threat. Bangladesh's deep-sea ecosystem, once resilient and largely unexplored, is showing unmis</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 19:02:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Overcoming economic malaises</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/overcoming-economic-malaises</link><description>The Centre for Policy Dialogue (CPD), a local think tank, has pinpointed the weaknesses of the country's economy and also recommended various measures to overcome those. In fact, the very title of the paper, "State of the Bangladesh Economy in FY2025-26" amply clarifies the objectives of the briefi</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 19:17:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BSEC urges caution as DSE pushes for share netting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/bsec-urges-caution-as-dse-pushes-for-share-netting</link><description>The Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) has recently proposed introducing share netting to boost liquidity in the secondary market, but the market watchdog wants risk-minimising infrastructure to be in place before approving it.
Share netting offers investors an opportunity to adjust their position in a si</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 03:03:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Health, education allocations face staggering cut</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/health-education-allocations-face-staggering-cut-1</link><description>Health and education sectors have taken the major brunt of a sizeable cut in the current development budget halfway through the fiscal year.
The ongoing Annual Development Programme (ADP) outlay for the fiscal year 2025-26 has been cut by 13.04 per cent to Tk 2.0 trillion.
With Chief Adviser Prof</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 03:18:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Miracle Industries posts deeper Q2 loss despite higher sales</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/miracle-industries-posts-deeper-q2-loss-despite-higher-sales</link><description>Miracle Industries, a plastic packaging manufacturer, posted a deeper loss in the second quarter (October-December) of FY26, amounting to Tk 21.48 million, compared with a loss of Tk 6.34 million in the same period of the previous year.
The company incurred higher losses despite increased sales vo</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 03:33:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Envisioned transition from kleptocracy to democracy derailed</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/envisioned-transition-from-kleptocracy-to-democracy-derailed</link><description>An envisioned post-uprising transition from "authoritarian kleptocracy" to democracy is derailed by reform-reactionaries and a section of the bureaucracy, says Transparency International Bangladesh (TIB).
In its highly critical analysis of the latest situation with declared governance reform, the</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 03:48:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No repeat of election robbery, CA pledges</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/no-repeat-of-election-robbery-ca-pledges</link><description>Chief Adviser of the interim government Professor Muhammad Yunus has pledged safeguards so that "election robbery" can never ever again happen in Bangladesh, as a fresh poll is ahead.
He expressed the resolve Monday after a high-level inquiry concluded that the country's last three national electi</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 04:03:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BB relaxes LPG import rules</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bb-relaxes-lpg-import-rules</link><description>Bangladesh Bank (BB) has relaxed import rules for liquefied petroleum gas (LPG) in an effort to ease the ongoing supply crisis and stabilise the domestic market.
The move is intended to reduce financing pressure on importers and ensure smoother availability of bottled gas for households and busine</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 04:18:17 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>