<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 05:22:38 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Uncertainty looms over subsidiaries of NBFIs facing liquidation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/uncertainty-looms-over-subsidiaries-of-nbfis-facing-liquidation</link><description>The central bank's decision to liquidate nine non-bank financial institutions (NBFIs) has raised questions about the fate of their subsidiaries and associate companies operating in the secondary market, as well as their clients who are also investors.
Eight of the NBFIs are listed on the stock mar</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 02:17:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chevron restarts delayed JBC project</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/chevron-restarts-delayed-jbc-project</link><description>Chevron Bangladesh has finally moved to revive its long-delayed Jalalabad Compression Project (JBC), breaking nearly two years of uncertainty over one of the country's most-anticipated gas-sector investments.
The restart comes at a time when domestic output is declining and the government is scram</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 02:32:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Climate pressures slow farm productivity</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/climate-pressures-slow-farm-productivity</link><description>Bangladesh's long-standing gains in agricultural productivity are beginning to lose momentum as climate stresses, rising input costs and shrinking arable land erode farmers' profitability.
A new study by the Bangladesh Institute of Development Studies (BIDS) warns that the country's agrifood syste</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 02:47:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>12kg LPG cylinder price rises by Tk 38</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/12kg-lpg-cylinder-price-rises-by-tk-38</link><description>The Bangladesh Energy Regulatory Commission (BERC) has increased the retail price of the widely-used 12-kg liquefied petroleum gas (LPG) cylinder by Tk 38, setting the new rate at Tk 1,253 for December.
The commission also raised the pump price of auto-gas -- LPG used in vehicles -- by Tk 1.74 per</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 03:02:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US pauses all immigration applications from 19 countries</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-pauses-all-immigration-applications-from-19-non-european-countries</link><description>The Trump administration on Tuesday said it paused all immigration applications, including green card and US citizenship processing, filed by immigrants from 19 non-European countries, citing concerns over national security and public safety.
The pause applies to people from 19 countries that were</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 03:17:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt to buy 0.22m tonnes of wheat to boost import from US</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/govt-to-buy-022m-tonnes-of-wheat-to-boost-import-from-us</link><description>The Advisers' Council on Government Purchase approved Tuesday procurement of another 0.22 million tonnes of wheat from the United States under a government-to-government arrangement.
This is the third time the government will purchase wheat from the US.
The Food Ministry earlier signed two contra</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 03:32:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>YouTube says it will comply with Australia's teen social media ban</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/youtube-says-it-will-comply-with-australias-teen-social-media-ban</link><description>Google's YouTube shared a "disappointing update" to millions of Australian users and content creators on Wednesday, saying it will comply with a world-first teen social media ban by locking out users aged under 16 from their accounts within days.
The decision ends a stand-off between the internet</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 03:47:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>We’re ready for war with Europe: Putin</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/were-ready-for-war-with-europe-putin</link><description>President Vladimir Putin on Tuesday warned European powers that if they started a war with Russia then Moscow was ready to fight and that the defeat of European powers would be so absolute that there would be no one left to even negotiate a peace deal.
Four years into the Ukraine war, the deadlies</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 04:02:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Third UK–Saudi Arabia aid dialogue: Stronger ties and global impact</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/third-uk-saudi-arabia-aid-dialogue-stronger-ties-and-global-impact</link><description>The UK and Saudi Arabia have agreed on new projects in Yemen and Bangladesh, and they pledged deeper cooperation on aid delivery, financing and global reforms.
The UK and Saudi Arabia hosted their two-day-long third Strategic Dialogue on international development and humanitarian assistance beginn</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 04:17:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trendy outfits shape fashion this winter</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/trendy-outfits-shape-fashion-this-winter</link><description>The winter shopping season has started early this year. Young people are already out in the markets in search of new looks for the colder days. Many shops in Dhaka report a rise in customers from mid-November. The rush is more pronounced in popular youth zones like Noor Jahan Market, New Market, an</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 04:32:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Against the odds, Bangladeshi female e-gamers claim their space in e-sports</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/against-the-odds-bangladeshi-female-e-gamers-claim-their-space-in-e-sports</link><description>"Women are not good with technology, let alone gaming. Gaming is for 'boys' only."- A common phrase to strike against younger girls who want to play online games. Since the advent of Artificial Intelligence, we have gone beyond many of its uses. Recently, people have been pursuing e-gaming as a car</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 04:47:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Seven terrorists killed in NW Pakistan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/seven-terrorists-killed-in-nw-pakistan</link><description>Seven terrorists were killed during intelligence-based operations in Pakistan's northwest Khyber Pakhtunkhwa province, the military said on Tuesday.
The security forces conducted the operations in two different areas of the North Waziristan district of the province, the Inter-Services Public Relat</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 05:02:05 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>