<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 08:43:35 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Samsung Electronics family to sell $1.2b stake amid share rally</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/samsung-electronics-family-to-sell-12b-stake-amid-share-rally</link><description>The mother and two sisters of Samsung Electronics Chairman Jay Y. Lee plan to sell some 1.73 trillion won ($1.22 billion) worth of shares in the South Korean tech firm, the company said in a regulatory filing.
The purpose of the sale of 17.7 million shares, or a 0.3 per cent stake in Samsung Elect</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 05:45:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>One to three low-pressure systems likely over Bay of Bengal this month</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/one-to-three-low-pressure-systems-likely-over-bay-of-bengal-this-month</link><description>One to three low-pressure systems are likely to develop over the Bay of Bengal in October, and one of them may intensify into a depression or a cyclone, according to the long-range weather forecast for October.
The forecast by the Bangladesh Meteorological Department, prepared after analysing regi</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 06:00:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EU hails 'July Charter' as a milestone in Bangladesh's political transition</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/eu-hails-july-charter-as-a-milestone-in-bangladeshs-political-transition</link><description>European Union (EU) Ambassador to Bangladesh Michael Miller has described the signing of the "July Charter" as a significant step toward political consensus and reform in Bangladesh, as the country advances toward national elections slated for early 2026.
"I was delighted to join the signing cerem</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 06:15:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Britain's Prince Andrew gives up title of Duke of York</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/britains-prince-andrew-gives-up-title-of-duke-of-york</link><description>Britain's Prince Andrew said on Friday he would give up using his title of Duke of York following years of criticism about his behaviour and connections to the late US sex offender Jeffrey Epstein.
The reputation of Andrew, the younger brother of King Charles and second son of the late Queen Eliza</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 06:30:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP backs teachers’ demands, warns against attempts to disrupt election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-backs-teachers-demands-warns-against-attempts-to-disrupt-election</link><description>BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir on Saturday said their party fully supports the justified demands of teachers but warned that it will not tolerate any attempt to create chaos or hinder the democratic transition through the upcoming national election.
“As a responsible polit</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 06:45:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IDCOL resumes financing for solar irrigation pumps to boost green farming</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/idcol-resumes-financing-for-solar-irrigation-pumps-to-boost-green-farming</link><description>Infrastructure Development Company Limited (IDCOL) has resumed its financing support for solar irrigation pumps (SIPs) with a renewed strategy and structure.The initiative reaffirms IDCOL's role in advancing Bangladesh’s clean energy transition in agriculture, said a press release. 
A s</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 07:00:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Faridpur, Rajbari fishermen defy hilsa fishing ban over delayed aid, loan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/faridpur-rajbari-fishermen-defy-hilsa-fishing-ban-over-delayed-aid-loan</link><description>Defying the government ban on catching hilsa during the breeding season, many fishermen in Faridpur and Rajbari have continued fishing in the Padma River, citing delays in receiving government assistance and pressure to repay loans.
A visit to the riverbanks revealed a scene that hardly reflected</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 07:30:18 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>