<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 07:21:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Horse meat seized in Gazipur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/horse-meat-seized-in-gazipur</link><description>Law enforcement agencies have seized a large quantity of horse meat and rescued 37 diseased horses during a late-night operation in the Hyderabad area of Gazipur City Corporation. 
The sale of horse meat is prohibited in Bangladesh.
The drive, led by Executive Magistrate Ishtiaque Ahmed of t</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 03:48:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US proposes that the UN authorise a Gaza stabilisation force for 2 years</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-proposes-that-the-un-authorise-a-gaza-stabilisation-force-for-2-years</link><description>The United States has circulated draft text for a UN Security Council resolution that would provide a mandate for an international stabilisation force in Gaza for at least two years, marking the next step in President Donald Trump’s plan to halt two years of war between Israel and Hamas.
The</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 04:33:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat not to form any election alliance, says Ameer Shafiqur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-not-to-form-any-election-alliance-says-ameer-shafiqur</link><description>Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami Ameer Dr. Shafiqur Rahman on Wednesday said they would not form any alliance for the upcoming national election, as it will contest the polls independently.
Shafiqur made the remarks while speaking to reporters at Sylhet Osmani International Airport on Wed</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 04:48:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Australia adds Reddit to social media platforms banning children under 16</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/australia-adds-reddit-and-kick-to-social-media-platforms-banning-children-under-16</link><description>Australia has added message board Reddit and livestreaming service Kick to its list of social media platforms that must ban children younger than 16 from holding accounts.
The platforms join Facebook, Instagram, Snapchat, Threads, TikTok, X and YouTube in facing a world-first legal obligation to s</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 05:18:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Youth killed in Jhenaidah road accident</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/youth-killed-in-jhenaidah-road-accident</link><description>A young driver of a makeshift motorised vehicle (locally known as Alam sadhu gari) was killed when a speeding pickup van hit his vehicle in Jhenaidah district on Wednesday.
The deceased was identified as Abu Bakar Kallol, 30, son of Mir Abul Kashem of Jibne village under Chuadanga Sadar upazila, r</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 05:33:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fire at Bosnia home for the elderly kills at least 10</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/fire-at-bosnia-home-for-the-elderly-kills-at-least-10</link><description>At least 10 people died and several were injured in a fire that broke out in a home for the elderly in the town of Tuzla in northern Bosnia late on Tuesday evening, Bosnian media reported.
The fire broke out around 9:00 pm (2000 GMT) and was put out around 10:00 pm, Federalna TV reported on its we</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 06:03:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tanzanian opposition claims security forces are secretly dumping bodies after election violence</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/tanzanian-opposition-claims-security-forces-are-secretly-dumping-bodies-after-election-violence</link><description>Authorities in Tanzania faced mounting concern Tuesday over killings during crackdowns on protests surrounding last week’s election, with the largest opposition party alleging that security forces were secretly dumping bodies of hundreds killed in the violence.
Demonstrations spread across t</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 06:18:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Five of a family killed Cox’s Bazar road crash</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/five-of-a-family-killed-coxs-bazar-road-crash</link><description>Five members of the same family were killed and two others injured in a head-on collision between a bus and a microbus in Chakaria upazila of Cox’s Bazar on Wednesday.
The accident took place around 9:00 am on the Cox’s Bazar–Chattogram highway in the Malumghat area, said Mehedi</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 06:33:14 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>