<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 14:22:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Credit card use jumps domestically and overseas: Bangladesh Bank</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/credit-card-use-jumps-domestically-and-overseas-bangladesh-bank</link><description>Credit card use in Bangladesh recorded a sharp rise in October, with both domestic transactions and spending by Bangladeshis overseas increasing significantly compared to the previous month, says the Bangladesh Bank.
According to its latest report, transactions within the country, expenditures by</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 11:44:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prime Bank signs payroll agreement with Fame Group</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/prime-bank-signs-payroll-agreement-with-fame-group</link><description>Prime Bank PLC, one of the leading private commercial banks in Bangladesh, renowned for its innovative and customer-centric financial solutions, has recently signed a Payroll Agreement with Fame Group at the Bank’s Corporate Office in Dhaka.
Under this agreement, employees of Fame Group will</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 11:59:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BRAC Bank installs ATMs at 5 MRT stations to provide banking convenience to commuters</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/brac-bank-installs-atms-at-5-mrt-stations-to-provide-banking-convenience-to-commuters</link><description>BRAC Bank has expanded its alternate banking footprint by installing ATMs at five key stations of Dhaka’s MRT Line-6, bringing fast and seamless banking services closer to daily commuters. 
The ATMs are now operational at Pallabi, Mirpur-10, Farmgate, Shahbagh, and Bangladesh Secretaria</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 12:14:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique Rahman: A true reformist and visionary leader</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/tarique-rahman-a-true-reformist-and-visionary-leader</link><description>The mass uprising of July-August (2024) not only led to the downfall of the fascist Awami League government, but also brought a profound transformation in the collective psyche of the people of this country. That powerful mass movement revived the mental strength of the countrymen that had been cru</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 12:29:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rickshawpuller testifies in Hadi murder case</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/driver-of-rickshaw-on-which-hadi-was-shot-delivers-court-statement</link><description>Kamal Hossain, the driver of the battery-powered rickshaw on which Sharif Osman bin Hadi was shot, has given a statement in court as a witness.
On Thursday, the investigation officer DB Police Inspector Faisal Ahmed produced Kamal in court and applied for recording his statement as a witness.
Acc</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 12:01:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Case filed over Moghbazar crude bomb blast</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/case-filed-over-moghbazar-crude-bomb-blast</link><description>A case has been filed in connection with the death of a man in a crude bomb explosion in the Moghbazar area of the capital.
Ali Akbar Majumdar, father of the victim, filed the case with Hatirjheel Police Station against some unidentified people early Thursday, said Golam Mortuza, officer-in-charge</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 12:16:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Smith back as Australia prepare an all-pace attack</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/smith-returns-as-australia-prepare-an-all-pace-attack-for-boxing-day-test</link><description>Steve Smith returns to action in the Boxing Day Test against England as Australia opted to include four fast bowlers in their 12-man squad, with spinner Todd Murphy, who was brought into the fold to replace Nathan Lyon, not finding a spot.
Fast bowler Jhye Richardson, who has not played in the lon</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 12:31:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique’s return to strengthen democratic practice: Nahid</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tariques-return-to-strengthen-democratic-practice-nahid</link><description>National Citizen Party Convener Nahid Islam on Thursday welcomed the return of BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman to Bangladesh, saying his homecoming would further consolidate Bangladesh’s multiparty democratic practice.
In a message posted on his verified Facebook account in the evening, N</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 12:46:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Zubaida, Zaima see Khaleda at Evercare Hospital</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/zubaida-zaima-at-khaledas-bedside-on-evercare-hospital-visit</link><description>After about two hours of rest at their Gulshan residence, Zubaida Rahman, the daughter-in-law of former prime minister Khaleda Zia, and her daughter Zaima Rahman have arrived at Evercare Hospital in Dhaka.
Khaleda has been receiving intensive care at the hospital since Nov 23.
The mother and daug</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 13:01:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique Rahman’s return expected to boost confidence in democracy: Mahfuj Alam</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-rahmans-return-expected-to-boost-confidence-in-democracy-mahfuj-alam</link><description>Former adviser and a frontline July uprising leader Mahfuj Alam, on Thursday said the return of BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman is expected to strengthen public trust and confidence in Bangladesh’s democratic system.
“Tarique Rahman’s return after 17 years of exile is expected</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 13:16:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>My grandfather encouraged me to play for Algeria, Luca Zidane says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/football/my-grandfather-encouraged-me-to-play-for-algeria-luca-zidane-says</link><description>Luca Zidane, son of French World Cup-winner Zinedine, said his grandfather had supported him in switching international allegiance to Algeria, after playing for France at junior level.
Zinedine Zidane is widely regarded as one of the greatest French footballers, inspiring his country to their firs</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 13:31:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>China accuses US of trying to thwart improved China-India ties</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/china-accuses-us-of-trying-to-thwart-improved-china-india-ties</link><description>China accused the US on Thursday of distorting its defence policy in an effort to thwart an improvement in China-India ties.
Foreign ministry spokesperson Lin Jian was responding to a question at a press briefing on whether China might exploit a recent easing of tensions with India over disputed b</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 13:46:50 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>