<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 04:41:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Mid-year tax hike: Sudden fiscal measure draws more ire than revenues</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/mid-year-tax-hike-thru-ordinance-sudden-fiscal-measure-draws-more-ire-than-revenues</link><description>A much-debated mid-year fiscal measure hiking taxes earns more ire than additional revenue income to uplift Bangladesh's low tax-to-GDP ratio in the past fiscal year.
Fearing a large shortfall in tax-revenue collection in the bygone year, the interim government imposed increased taxes on a range o</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 01:38:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Israeli military boards several Sumud flotilla aid boats bound for Gaza</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/israeli-military-boards-several-sumud-flotilla-aid-boats-bound-for-gaza</link><description>Israeli forces boarded several boats carrying foreign activists and aid bound for Gaza and took them to an Israeli port on Wednesday, disrupting a protest that had become one of the most high-profile symbols of opposition to Israel's blockade of the enclave.
A video from the Israeli foreign minist</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 02:08:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Forex swap deals shrink as BB pushes spot market</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/forex-swap-deals-shrink-as-bb-pushes-spot-market</link><description>Foreign-exchange swap transactions on the interbank market dropped in August compared with the previous month, even as the Bangladesh Bank pressed ahead with its strategy to promote spot-market trading over swaps.
The move is intended to make the market more transparent and reflective of real dema</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 02:23:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Move underway to import refined soybean oil in bulk</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/move-underway-to-import-refined-soybean-oil-in-bulk</link><description>A move is underway to import refined soybean oil in the bulk form to be sold in bottles at subsidised prices under the TCB's sale drives.
The state-run Trading Corporation of Bangladesh (TCB) in a recent letter sought consent from the Ministry of Commerce to this effect.
The corporation has initi</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 02:38:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Puja holiday fuels boom in domestic tourism</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/puja-holiday-fuels-boom-in-domestic-tourism</link><description>This year's Durga Puja holiday has turned into a windfall for domestic tourism industry.
With an unusually long break on offer, families, friends, and office groups packed their bags and headed for beaches, forests, and hill tracts rather than looking abroad.
Travel agents say the rush has been h</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 03:38:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Israel stops 13 Sumud flotilla aid boats, 30 continue toward Gaza</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/israel-stops-13-sumud-flotilla-aid-boats-30-continue-toward-gaza</link><description>Israeli forces have stopped 13 boats carrying foreign activists and aid bound for Gaza, but 30 boats are continuing to sail towards the war-ravaged Palestinian enclave, flotilla organisers said on Thursday.
A video the from the Israeli foreign ministry verified by Reuters showed the most prominent</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 03:54:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CA returns home after 9-day visit to New York</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ca-returns-home-after-9-day-visit-to-new-york</link><description>Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus returned home on Thursday, concluding his nine-day visit to New York to attend the 80th session of the United Nations General Assembly (UNGA).
An Emirates Airlines flight carrying the Chief Adviser and his delegation landed at Hazrat Shahjalal International A</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 04:09:27 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>