<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 09:47:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Plane crashes in Colombia, killing all 15 on board</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/plane-crashes-in-colombia-killing-all-15-on-board</link><description>A passenger plane has crashed in northern Colombia, killing all 15 people on board, the country's state-run airline Satena confirmed.
In a statement, it said its aircraft - a Beechcraft 1900 - "suffered a fatal accident", but gave no further details. The wreckage has now been located in a mountain</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 07:07:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>TIME magazine calls Tarique Rahman “clear front runner” in upcoming polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/time-magazine-calls-tarique-rahman-clear-front-runner-in-upcoming-polls</link><description>The US-based TIME magazine in its latest issue published today called BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman the “clear front runner” in the upcoming February 12 elections as it carried an analysis ahead of the polls.
“Rahman is the clear front runner in Feb. 12 elections, which were called</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 07:22:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Stocks slide in early trade at DSE, CSE</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/stocks-slide-in-early-trade-at-dse-cse1256</link><description>Bangladesh’s stock markets posted losses in the first half of trading on Thursday, with key indices of both the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) and the Chittagong Stock Exchange (CSE) moving lower.
On the last trading day of the week, the DSE’s benchmark index DSEX shed 13 points.
The Shar</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 07:16:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique reaches Rajshahi to launch fourth phase of BNP campaign</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-reaches-rajshahi-to-launch-fourth-phase-of-bnp-campaign</link><description>BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman reached Rajshahi on Thursday to begin the fourth phase of his election campaign, launching a three-day tour in the northern region aimed at mobilising voters in favour of BNP and its alliance candidates.
Tarique reached Rajshahi by air at 12:24 pm, BNP Media Cell member</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 07:31:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC orders printing presses not to print election posters</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-orders-printing-presses-not-to-print-election-posters</link><description>The Election Commission has directed printing presses across the country not to print any posters for the 13th parliamentary election.
The directive was sent to returning officers on Wednesday by Election Commission Deputy Secretary Monir Hossain.
It said candidates have already begun electioneer</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 07:46:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Parties must show responsibility, restraint: interim govt</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/parties-must-show-responsibility-restraint-interim-govt</link><description>The interim government has expressed deep concern over the recent violence in Sherpur that resulted in the death of a Jamaat-e-Islami activist.
Any loss of life linked to violence is unacceptable and deeply regrettable, the Chief Advisor’s Office said in a statement on Thursday.
With the na</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 08:01:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India’s textile exporters pin hopes on EU deal after US tariff blow</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/indias-textile-exporters-pin-hopes-on-eu-deal-after-us-tariff-blow</link><description>India’s textile and apparel exporters, hit by 50 per cent US tariffs imposed late in August, are banking on this week's trade agreement with the European Union to offset part of the damage, while urging New Delhi to secure a quick deal with Washington.
Under the pact, which will be implement</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 08:16:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No case yet over killing of Sherpur Jamaat leader</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/no-case-filed-yet-over-killing-of-jamaat-upazila-secretary-in-sherpur</link><description>No case has yet been filed over the death of Rezaual Karim, the Sreebordi Upazila secretary for Jamaat-e-Islami, who was killed following a clash between rival political groups during an election programme in Sherpur.
The situation remains tense in the Jhenaigati and Sreebordi Upazilas of the Sher</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 08:31:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP calls Sherpur killing ‘unwarranted,’ demands quick probe</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-calls-sherpur-killing-unwarranted-demands-quick-probe</link><description>BNP Election Steering Committee spokesperson Mahdi Amin on Thursday described the clash between BNP and Jamaat-e-Islami in Sherpur, which left one person dead, as “unwarranted” and called for a swift and impartial investigation.
“Why did one party occupy all the chairs before the</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 08:46:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Commonwealth, EU to deploy large observer teams for Bangladesh election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/commonwealth-eu-to-deploy-large-observer-teams-for-bangladesh-election</link><description>The Commonwealth and the European Union are set to deploy large election observation missions for Bangladesh’s general election and the referendum on the July reform charter, both scheduled for February 12.
Lamiya Morshed, Senior Secretary and SDGs Affairs Principal Coordinator, who is suppo</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 09:01:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>128 Bangladeshi fishermen return home from India</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/128-bangladeshi-fishermen-return-home-from-india</link><description>Bangladesh on Thursday brought back 128 Bangladeshi fishermen who had been detained in India, while simultaneously repatriating 23 Indian fishermen held in Bangladesh, under a mutual repatriation arrangement between the two neighbouring countries.
The Bangladesh Coast Guard received the 128 fisher</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 09:16:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique launches northern campaign</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-launches-northern-campaign</link><description>BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman has begun his election campaign in northern Bangladesh with a visit to the shrine of the revered Sufi saint Shah Makhdum (R.) in Rajshahi.
He arrived at the shrine in the city’s Dargah Para around 1:15 pm on Thursday, where he paid his respects and later signed th</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 09:31:17 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>