<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 07:51:16 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>BSEC seeks ACC probe into RACE over disputed tax reporting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/bsec-seeks-acc-probe-into-race-over-disputed-tax-reporting</link><description>The country's largest asset manager, RACE Management, has been found to have reported a fictitious tax charge of Tk 96.8 million in the FY24 financial statements of six funds under its management.
Following the discovery, the Bangladesh Securities and Exchange Commission (BSEC) referred the matter</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 05:42:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Stocks cross 5,600 mark on increased appetite for bank stocks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/stocks-cross-5600-mark-on-increased-appetite-for-bank-stocks</link><description>The benchmark index of the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) surpassed the 5,600-point threshold once again after six months as investors showed buying appetite in bank stocks amid improved post-election sentiment.
Market analysts cited the ongoing market recovery as being driven by broad-based investor</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 05:57:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pakistan bombs targets in Afghan cities, minister calls it 'open war'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/pakistan-bombs-targets-in-afghan-cities-minister-calls-it-open-war</link><description>Pakistan bombed Taliban government targets in Afghanistan's major cities overnight, officials from both countries said on Friday, with Pakistan's defence minister describing the conflict as "open war".
Security sources in Pakistan said the strikes involved air and ground strikes against Taliban po</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 06:12:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Third language push aims to boost global job prospects for Bangladeshis</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/third-language-push-aims-to-boost-global-job-prospects-for-bangladeshis</link><description>For decades, Bangladeshi migrant workers have been known for their resilience and hard work in foreign lands.
But in an increasingly competitive global labour market, physical endurance alone is no longer enough. Communication is fast becoming the decisive factor.
Foreign language proficiency is</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 05:12:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Researchers in Australia decode new TB antibiotics' mechanism</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/researchers-in-australia-decode-new-tb-antibiotics-mechanism</link><description>Researchers in Australia have discovered how a promising class of experimental antibiotics disrupts the bacterium that causes tuberculosis (TB), raising hopes for improved treatments against drug-resistant strains.
TB remains one of the world's deadliest infectious diseases, killing about 1.2 mill</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 05:27:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>FM holds key OIC sidelines meetings</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fm-holds-key-oic-sidelines-meetings</link><description>Foreign Minister Dr Khalilur Rahman held a series of bilateral meetings with key counterparts on the sidelines of the OIC Executive Meeting on Palestine in Jeddah, reaffirming Bangladesh’s stance on Palestine and boosting diplomatic engagement.
The Foreign Minister met Deputy Prime Minister</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 05:42:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rural Road Maintenance: LGD proposes Tk 12.3b scheme to employ 79,680 women</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/rural-road-maintenance-lgd-proposes-tk-123b-scheme-to-employ-79680-women</link><description>The Local Government Division (LGD), under the Ministry of Local Government, Rural Development and Cooperatives, has proposed a new Tk 12.3-billion scheme aimed at keeping 70,440 kilometres of rural roads motorable through regular and systematic maintenance, officials said.
According to sources at</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 05:57:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bridge Tolls: E-payment system expanded</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bridge-tolls-e-payment-system-expanded</link><description>All vehicle users will now be able to pay tolls on road bridges electronically as the Roads and Highways Department (RHD) has opened its e-payment system to all banks and mobile banking platforms, aiming for a more efficient, transparent, and faster toll collection process.
Officials said that aft</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 06:12:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India, Israel to boost defence cooperation: Modi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/india-israel-to-boost-defence-cooperation-modi</link><description>India and Israel will pursue joint development, production and transfer of technology in defence, as well as work on a free trade agreement, Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi said on Thursday.
Here are some details on what the two countries agreed upon during Modi's two-day visit to Israel.
● T</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 06:27:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US–Iran nuclear talks end without agreement</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-iran-nuclear-talks-end-without-agreement</link><description>Iran and the United States held hours of indirect negotiations Thursday over Tehran's nuclear program but walked away without a deal, leaving the danger of another Mideast war on the table as the U.S. has gathered a massive fleet of aircraft and warships in the region.
Oman's Foreign Minister Badr</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 06:42:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bus catches fire after collision with motorcycle in Gazipur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bus-catches-fire-after-collision-with-motorcycle-in-gazipur</link><description>A passenger bus caught fire after colliding with a motorcycle in the Board Bazar area of Gazipur on Friday morning.
The motorcyclist was injured in the incident.
Hiron Mia, Station Officer of Bhogra Modern Fire Service, said the Dhaka-bound bus was travelling from Tangail when it reached the Boar</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 06:57:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>171 bodies found in mass graves in eastern Congo</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/africa/171-bodies-found-in-mass-graves-in-eastern-congo</link><description>Congolese authorities and a civil society group said Thursday that mass graves were found in part of eastern Congo that the M23 rebel group has recently withdrawn from, as fighting in the region escalates despite a U.S.-mediated peace deal.
The governor of South-Kivu province, Jean-Jacques Purusi,</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 07:12:39 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>