<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 17:23:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Al-Arafah Islami Bank’s Bandarban Branch distributes blankets among helpless people</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/al-arafah-islami-banks-bandarban-branch-distributes-blankets-among-helpless-people</link><description>Bandarban Branch of Al-Arafah Islami Bank PLC has distributed blankets to the underprivileged people, according to a press release.
Muhammad Ali, Bandarban District Representative of Al-Arafah Islami Bank PLC, Bandarban branch organised the blanket distribution program for helpless people amid the</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 15:17:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Agrani Bank mourns death of Khaleda Zia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/agrani-bank-mourns-death-of-khaleda-zia</link><description>Agrani Bank PLC has expressed deep sorrow at the death of former Prime Minister and BNP Chairperson Begum Khaleda Zia.
According to a press release, a prayer gathering (Doa Mahfil) was held after Zuhr prayers on Tuesday at the Central Prayer Hall of Agrani Bank’s Head Office, seeking eternal</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 15:32:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh Polls: Registration time for postal voting extended till Jan 5</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-polls-registration-time-for-postal-voting-extended-till-jan-5</link><description>The Election Commission has extended the registration time by five days till January 5 next for expatriates and other entitled voters to vote through the postal ballots during the upcoming national election and referendum, slated for February 12, 2026.
“Now the deadline for the postal ballot</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 15:47:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ICC Bangladesh president condoles death of Khaleda Zia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/icc-bangladesh-president-condoles-death-of-khaleda-zia</link><description>ICC Bangladesh President Mr Mahbubur Rahman has expressed deepest condolences at the demise of former Prime Minister of Bangladesh and BNP Chairperson Begum Khaleda Zia.
In a condolence letter sent to BNP’s Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman, also the son of Begum Khaleda Zia, on Wednesday, the</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 16:02:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>3 million submit income tax returns online</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/3-million-submit-income-tax-returns-online</link><description>More than 3 million individual taxpayers have so far submitted their income tax returns online for the current 2025–26 tax year, reflecting a sharp rise in the use of Bangladesh’s e-return system, according to the National Board of Revenue (NBR).
The NBR said around 4.5 million taxpaye</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 16:17:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Institutional deposits to be converted into shares as Bangladesh Bank finalises 'Sammilito Islami Bank' merger</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/institutional-deposits-to-be-converted-into-shares-as-bangladesh-bank-finalises-sammilito-islami-bank-merger</link><description>Bangladesh Bank has finalised the scheme to merge five troubled Shariah-based banks into a single entity named ‘Sammilito Islami Bank PLC’.
This newly formed bank will acquire First Security Islami Bank, Social Islami Bank, Union Bank, Global Islami Bank, and EXIM Bank.
The central ba</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 15:53:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Japanese PM, FM mourn Khaleda Zia’s demise</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/japanese-pm-fm-mourn-khaleda-zias-demise</link><description>Japanese Prime Minister and Foreign Minister Takaichi Sanae and Motegi Toshimitsu have expressed condolence at the passing of former Prime Minister Khaleda Zia.
Takaichi Sanae and Motegi Toshimitsu extended their messages of condolences to Chief Adviser Prof Muhammad Yunus and Foreign Affairs Advi</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 16:08:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gaza humanitarian deterioration of serious concern, say UK, Canada, France and others</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/gaza-humanitarian-deterioration-of-serious-concern-say-uk-canada-france-and-others</link><description>The humanitarian situation in Gaza has worsened again and is of serious concern, Britain, Canada, France and others said in a joint statement on Tuesday that also called on Israel to take urgent action.
The statement, published online by the British Foreign Office, said Israel should allow non-gov</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 16:23:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nepalese FM to attend state funeral of ex-PM Khaleda, pay last respects</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nepalese-fm-to-attend-state-funeral-of-ex-pm-khaleda-pay-last-respects</link><description>Nepalese Foreign Affairs Minister Bala Nanda Sharma will attend the state funeral of former Prime Minister and Chairperson of the Bangladesh Nationalist Party Begum Khaleda Zia and pay last respects on behalf of the government and the people of Nepal.
The Foreign Minister’s visit reflects Ne</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 16:38:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rising medicine prices threaten healthcare for marginalised communities, warns study</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rising-medicine-prices-threaten-healthcare-for-marginalised-communities-warns-study</link><description>Marginalised and low-income communities in Bangladesh face a severe healthcare crisis as potential medicine price hikes following the country’s LDC graduation threaten to halt their access to essential treatment.
The findings were revealed in a research report presented today by ‘Bangl</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 16:53:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US issues sanctions related to Iran and Venezuela weapons trade</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/us-issues-sanctions-related-to-iran-and-venezuela-weapons-trade</link><description>The US Treasury said on Tuesday it has added 10 individuals and entities based in Iran and Venezuela to its sanctions list, citing their aggressive weapons program.
The US Treasury has designated Venezuela-based Empresa Aeronautica Nacional SA and its chair, Jose Jesus Urdaneta Gonzalez, who it sa</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 17:08:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Home Ministry bars Bishwa Ijtema gatherings before national election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/home-ministry-bars-bishwa-ijtema-gatherings-before-national-election</link><description>The Ministry of Home Affairs has directed that no assemblies or programmes, including the Bishwa Ijtema, be held at the Tongi Ijtema ground during the pre-election period to ensure the smooth conduct of the 13th Jatiya Sangsad election and the 2026 referendum.
The directive was issued on Tuesday t</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 17:23:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>