<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 14:42:11 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Salahuddin hopes for most productive parliament since independence</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/salahuddin-hopes-for-most-productive-parliament-since-independence</link><description>BNP Standing Committee Member Salahuddin Ahmed on Friday hoped that the newly formed Jatiya Sangsad would be the most productive law-making house since the country’s independence and take steps to amend the Constitution.
He also sought cooperation from people from all walks of life to build</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 11:56:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP racks up five seats in Chattogram</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bnp-racks-up-five-seats-in-chattogram</link><description>Five BNP candidates have been declared unofficial winners in Chattogram, as returning officers announced results for five of the district’s 16 seats.
On Friday, Md Zia Uddin, returning officer and divisional commissioner for Chattogram-5, 8, 9 and 10 constituencies, declared the BNP nominees</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 12:11:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Seven women elected, but female representation stays below 5pc</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/seven-women-elected-but-female-representation-stays-below-5pc</link><description>Seven women have been elected to parliament through direct votes in the 2026 election, marking a modest presence in a race where female participation remained strikingly low.
According to the Election Commission (EC), 81 of the 1,981 candidates who contested were women -- just 4.08 percent of the</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 12:26:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Malaysia congratulates BNP on election victory</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/malaysia-congratulates-bnp-on-election-victory</link><description>Malaysia has congratulated the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) after its sweeping victory in Bangladesh’s 13th parliamentary elections, signalling early diplomatic engagement with the party’s chairman, Tarique Rahman, who is set to become the country’s next prime minister.
Mal</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 12:41:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>China greets BNP on election success</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/china-greets-bnp-on-election-success</link><description>China has congratulated the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) after its sweeping victory in the 13th parliamentary elections, taking note of what it described as a steady and smooth general election in Bangladesh.
In a statement issued on Friday, a Chinese government spokesperson said China, call</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 12:56:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fakhrul outlines three immediate challenges for next government</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/fakhrul-outlines-three-immediate-challenges-for-next-government</link><description>BNP secretary general Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir has outlined three immediate challenges for the next government after his party secured an absolute majority in the election.
He made the comment at the Shahjalal International Airport after returning from his Thakurgaon-1 constituency, where he de</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 13:11:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCP alleges attacks on leaders, activists of its 11-party alliance</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ncp-alleges-attacks-on-leaders-activists-of-its</link><description>The National Citizen Party (NCP) on Friday alleged that leaders and activists of its 11-party alliance are being attacked in different parts of the country.
In a Facebook post, the party also claimed that the homes and families of its leaders and activists are facing threats.
Addressing the winne</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 13:26:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique thanks supporters for helping BNP win landslide victory</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-thanks-supporters-for-helping-bnp-win-landslide-victory</link><description>BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman on Friday expressed gratitude to his supporters for their affection and for helping secure a landslide victory for his party.
“I am grateful for the love you have shown me. Please pray for me,” he said while talking to people gathered outside his Gulshan res</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 13:41:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Winning as an independent was ‘not easy’, Rumeen Farhana says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/winning-as-an-independent-was-not-easy-rumeen-farhana-says</link><description>Rumeen Farhana, elected with the Duck symbol in Brahmanbaria-2, has said it was not easy to win as an independent after being denied a BNP nomination.
Speaking at a press conference at her Shahbazpur home in Sarail on Friday, the barrister said the struggle had been even harder for her supporters.</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 13:56:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India cenbank allows banks higher acquisition financing limit</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/global/india-cenbank-allows-banks-higher-acquisition-financing-limit</link><description>Indian lenders will be allowed to finance acquisitions up to 20 per cent of their eligible capital base, the Reserve Bank of India said in its final rules following a review of bank exposure to capital markets.
The RBI had suggested a cap of 10 per cent of a bank's tier-1 capital for acquisition f</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 14:11:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>150,000 ballots scrapped: Massive invalidation hits Gazipur seats</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/150000-ballots-scrapped-massive-invalidation-hits-gazipur-seats</link><description>Nearly 150,000 ballots across Gazipur’s five constituencies have been declared invalid.
These include both parliamentary and referendum ballots, though the cancellation rate for the referendum has been significantly higher.
Official records show that the highest number of referendum ballots</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 14:26:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Zimbabwe stun Australia by 23 runs in T20 World Cup</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/cricket/zimbabwe-stun-australia-by-23-runs-in-t20-world-cup</link><description>Zimbabwe caused a seismic shock at the T20 World Cup on Friday, defeating heavyweights Australia by 23 runs at the R. Premadasa Stadium.
This is only the second win of Zimbabwe over Australia in the T20 World Cup history, UNB reports. 
Defending a total of 169 for 2, the Zimbabwean bowling a</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 14:41:33 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>