<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 04:30:46 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Government secondary school teachers suspend strike</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/government-secondary-school-teachers-suspend-strike</link><description>Government secondary school teachers have suspended their ongoing work stoppage, which was held over four demands including salary scale for ninth grade and the formation of an independent secondary education directorate.
They announced that annual examinations will be held “from Wednesday&amp;r</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 17:45:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Salahuddin commences his campaigning at Chakaria-Pekua</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/salahuddin-commences-his-campaigning-at-chakaria-pekua</link><description>BNP senior leader Salahuddin Ahmed has started electioneering in his constituency Cox’s Bazar-1 (Chakaria-Pekua).
On Tuesday morning, he arrived in Cox’s Bazar on a five-day visit to woo voters in favour of him ahead of the national election, UNB reports. 
On the first day, Salah</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 18:00:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Army officer killed in Natore road accident</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/army-officer-killed-in-natore-road-accident</link><description>An army officer was killed in a road accident in Baraigram, Natore on Tuesday evening.The deceased, Sergeant Mamunur Rashid, was posted at Ramu Cantonment, UNB reports. Inspector Suman Chandra Das, in charge of the Bonpara Police Investigation Center, said that Sergeant Rashid, serving in the</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 18:15:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat chief Shafiqur visits Khaleda at Evercare Hospital</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-chief-shafiqur-visits-khaleda-at-evercare-hospital</link><description>Jamaat-e-Islami chief Shafiqur Rahman has paid a visit to BNP Chairperson Khaleda Zia at Evercare Hospital.
Shafiqur arrived at the hospital around 10pm on Tuesday, bdnews24.com. 
“Everything is in the hands of Allah,” he said. “He can take away the living and give life to</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 18:30:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Polls, MPO allowance hike, new Islamic Bank capital to cost Tk 270b</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/polls-mpo-allowance-hike-new-islamic-bank-capital-to-cost-tk-270b</link><description>Current crunch time comes as a reminder to ministries and divisions concerned to make realistic fund demand from this year's revised budget to help the government avoid higher bank borrowings and interest payments.



The direction comes from finance division while holding consultation with t</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 19:37:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Imran Khan healthy but cut off in jail, sister says as family seeks access</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/imran-khan-healthy-but-cut-off-in-jail-sister-says-as-family-seeks-access</link><description>Imran Khan, Pakistan's jailed former prime minister, is in good physical health but facing isolation and psychological strain, his sister said on Tuesday, after a rare supervised visit following weeks in which his family said access had been blocked.
Uzma Khanum, one of Khan's three sisters, was t</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 19:52:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Banks fear profitability squeeze as new operational peril</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/banks-fear-profitability-squeeze-as-new-operational-peril</link><description>Already smarting under loads of bad loans, banks in Bangladesh worry about a new operational peril from profitability squeeze for narrowing interest spread that came to 5.74 per cent in September.
According to Bangladesh Bank statistics, the spread between weighted average interest rate (WAIR) on</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 01:46:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Falling Domestic Gas Output: Chevron restarts delayed JBC project</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/falling-domestic-gas-output-chevron-restarts-delayed-jbc-project</link><description>Chevron Bangladesh has finally moved to revive its long-delayed Jalalabad Compression Project (JBC), breaking nearly two years of uncertainty over one of the country's most-anticipated gas-sector investments.
The restart comes at a time when domestic output is declining and the government is scram</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 02:01:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Apparel Sector Digital Ecosystem: Call for greater coordination among stakeholders to foster data sharing</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/call-for-greater-coordination-among-stakeholders-to-foster-data-sharing</link><description>Speakers at a discussion on Tuesday called for greater coordination and collaboration among ministries, the National Board of Revenue (NBR), trade bodies and global brands to foster data sharing and help develop a digital ecosystem for the country's apparel sector.
The observation came at a sessio</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 02:16:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>GPH Ispat reports first-time loss as demand for steel shrinks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/gph-ispat-reports-first-time-loss-as-demand-for-steel-shrinks</link><description>GPH Ispat reported a loss of Tk 246.78 million in FY25, the first since its listing, as demand for its products declined and production and finance costs increased.
According to a filing on Tuesday, the company's earnings per share fell to negative Tk 0.51 per share from a profit of Tk 1.77 per sh</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 02:31:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>11 more firms granted extra time to adjust negative equity</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/11-more-firms-granted-extra-time-to-adjust-negative-equity</link><description>The securities regulator has granted additional time to 11 more market intermediaries to ensure compliance with provisioning requirements for unrealised losses and to adjust negative equity.
The extension will take effect after December 31 this year, when the current deadline expires. Some institu</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 02:46:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Case filed against woman for drowning eight puppies in Pabna</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/case-filed-against-woman-for-drowning-eight-puppies-in-pabna</link><description>A case has been filed at Ishwardi Police Station in Pabna over the killing of eight puppies, who were tied in a sack and drowned in a pond on the Ishwardi Upazila Parishad premises.
Upazila Livestock Officer Aklima Khatun filed the case on Tuesday night.
Abdun Noor, officer-in-charge of Ishwardi</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 03:01:13 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>