<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 17:14:31 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Bank Asia partners with Momen Real Estates to offer exclusive home loan service</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bank-asia-partners-with-momen-real-estates-to-offer-exclusive-home-loan-service</link><description>Bank Asia PLC has entered into a strategic partnership with Momen Real Estates Limited to offer exclusive privileges for its home loan customers, according to a press release.
Through this collaboration, Bank Asia will provide home financing facilities to clients of Momen Real Estates Limited on a</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 15:01:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC registration: Further verification required on info provided by 10 parties</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-registration-further-verification-required-on-info-provided-by-10-parties</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has decided to conduct a fresh field-level investigation of information submitted by ten new political parties, as it continues to hold off on decisions over their registration status.
According to an EC letter signed by senior assistant secretary Nazmul Kabir on Sunda</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 15:16:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hasnat tells MPO teachers to remain on streets until demands met</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hasnat-tells-mpo-teachers-to-remain-on-streets-until-demands-met</link><description>Hasnat Abdullah, chief organiser of the National Citizen Party (South), labelled the interim government “hypocritical” and urged MPO-registered teachers to remain on the streets until their demands are met.
He addressed teachers and staff gathered at the Central Shaheed Minar on Sunday</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 14:05:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CEC hopes NCP won’t hinder democratic transition over ‘Water Lily’ row</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cec-hopes-ncp-wont-hinder-democratic-transition-over-water-lily-row</link><description>Chief Election Commissioner (CEC) AMM Nasir Uddin has expressed optimism that the Nationalist Citizen Party (NCP) will not stand in the way of the country’s democratic transition, despite the ongoing dispute over the allocation of the ‘Water Lily’ (Shapla) election symbol.
Talkin</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 14:20:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat to hold human-chain protest</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-e-islami-to-hold-nationwide-human-chain-protests-over-five-demands</link><description>The Jamaat-e-Islami has announced a two-day human-chain demonstration to press its five-point demands, including the legal recognition of the July Charter, also known as National Charter.
The party’s Secretary General Mia Golam Parwar announced the programme in a statement on Sunday.
Accord</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 14:50:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Foundation stone of ‘July Memorial’ laid at Osmani Udyan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/foundation-stone-of-july-memorial-laid-at-osmani-udyan</link><description>The foundation stone of the ‘July Memorial’, to be built in memory of the martyrs of the historic July 2024 student-people uprising, was laid today at Osmani Udyan in Dhaka.
Local Government, Rural Development and Cooperatives Adviser Asif Mahmud Shojib Bhuiyan formally laid the founda</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 15:20:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Palestinian Authority ready to help Trump’s Gaza effort succeed, says official</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/palestinian-authority-ready-to-help-trumps-gaza-effort-succeed-says-official</link><description>The Palestinian Authority is ready to work with US President Donald Trump and former British Prime Minister Tony Blair on their effort to consolidate the Gaza ceasefire and start rebuilding, a senior Palestinian official told Blair on Sunday.
Trump’s plan for ending the Gaza war holds out th</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 15:50:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Four dead, at least 20 injured in South Carolina island shooting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/four-dead-at-least-20-injured-in-south-carolina-island-shooting</link><description>Four people were killed and at least 20 injured in a shooting at a restaurant in a South Carolina island town on Sunday, the Beaufort County Sheriff’s Office said.
Deputies were called to Willie’s Bar and Grill on St. Helena Island just before 1 a.m. and found several people suffering</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 16:05:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CA arrives in Rome to join WFF event</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ca-arrives-in-rome-to-join-wff-event</link><description>Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus arrived here around 5:00 pm (local time) on Sunday to join the annual World Food Forum (WFF), the flagship event of the Food and Agricultural Organisation (FAO).
Ambassador of Bangladesh to Italy ATM Rokebul Haque received the Chief Adviser at Rome Fiumicino</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 16:20:46 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>