<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 14:22:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>BB clarifies gross weight for frozen fish export subsidies</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bb-clarifies-gross-weight-for-frozen-fish-export-subsidies</link><description>Bangladesh Bank (BB) has clarified the calculation process for cash assistance or export subsidies provided against the export of frozen shrimp and other fish.
“The ‘Gross Weight' will be understood to mean the weight of the fish including the glaze,” said a BB circular issued on</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 11:22:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Death sentence is 'appropriate justice' for Sheikh Hasina: Akhter</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/death-sentence-is-appropriate-justice-for-sheikh-hasina-akhter</link><description>National Citizen Party (NCP) Member-Secretary Akhter Hossain said the death sentence handed down to Sheikh Hasina for crimes against humanity represents 'appropriate justice,' urging both the Bangladesh government to swiftly enforce the verdict and the Indian government to return her to Dhaka.
"Th</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 11:37:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Satyajit Ray: The Calcutta Trilogy offers a fresh perspective on Ray</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/entertainment/satyajit-ray-the-calcutta-trilogy-offers-a-fresh-perspective-on-ray</link><description>Many of us have seen, discussed, and written reviews of Satyajit Ray's films; in fact, no film student's education would be complete without seeing his work. We rediscover Ray, his empathy, his social awareness, and his capacity to portray the human condition in a way that is unparalleled in simpli</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 11:52:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>TSC crowds cheer Hasina’s death penalty</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jubilation-sweets-distribution-as-hasina-verdict-sends-tsc-into-raptures</link><description>Crowds at Dhaka University’s TSC have erupted into celebration after Sheikh Hasina was handed a death sentence over the deadly crackdown on the July Uprising.
On Monday afternoon, the scene turns festive at about 3pm, with students distributing sweets and launching a celebratory march from t</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 12:07:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Int’l media reports on verdict in Sheikh Hasina’s case</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/intl-media-reports-on-verdict-in-sheikh-hasinas-case</link><description>International media outlets are reporting over the verdict with giving utmost importance in the first case against three defendants, including ousted former prime minister Sheikh Hasina, for crimes against humanity committed during the July Uprising in 2024.
BBC has broadcast live under the headli</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 12:22:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka to send letter seeking repatriation of Hasina, Kamal from India: Touhid</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dhaka-to-send-letter-seeking-repatriation-of-hasina-kamal-from-india-touhid</link><description>The foreign affairs ministry will formally send a letter to New Delhi seeking the repatriation of fugitive convicts Sheikh Hasina and Asaduzzaman Khan Kamal, Foreign Affairs Adviser Md Touhid Hossain said today (Monday).
“We will officially communicate our position to India. Whether the lett</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 12:37:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Final voter list to be unveiled Tuesday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/final-voter-list-to-be-unveiled-tuesday</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) will publish the country’s final electoral rolls on Tuesday, listing around 128 million voters for the 13th parliamentary election to be held in early February.
Earlier, on November 3, the Commission released the draft updated voter lists and invited objections o</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 12:52:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt: India 'obliged' to return Hasina</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/after-court-verdict-bangladesh-says-india-has-an-obligation-to-extradiate-hasina</link><description>The government has once again requested India to extradite former prime minister Sheikh Hasina and her home minister Asaduzzaman Khan Kamal, who have both been sentenced to death in a case of crime against humanity during the July Uprising.
The Ministry of Foreign Affairs made the call in a statem</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 13:07:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hasina verdict reflects justice: Islami Andolan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/islami-andolan-hails-hasina-verdict-as-fair-judgment</link><description>Islami Andolan Bangladesh has said the death sentence handed to former prime minister Sheikh Hasina in the July Uprising crimes against humanity case “fulfilled the expectations of the oppressed”.
On Monday, Secretary General Yunus Ahmad said the verdict reflects justice and will stand</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 13:37:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Administrator, associate administrators assume responsibility at Union Bank</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/administrator-associate-administrators-assume-responsibility-at-union-bank</link><description>Mr. Mohammad Abul Hashem, Director of Bangladesh Bank, has joined as Administrator on 05 November 2025to supervise and manage the overall activities of Union Bank PLC.
In addition, Additional Directors of Bangladesh Bank Mr. Kazi Abdul Mannan, Mr. Md. Al-Mehedi Hasan and Joint Directors Mr. Md. Ta</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 13:52:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ONE Bank holds Agent Banking Conference 2025</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/one-bank-holds-agent-banking-conference-2025</link><description>ONE Bank successfully organized Agent Banking Conference 2025 and Training session for Agent Banking Outlet Proprietors &amp; their users on November 8, 2025, at the Bangladesh Military Museum, Dhaka.
According to a press release, the day-long event brought together outlet proprietors, their users, an</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 14:07:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Russia adds ex-PM Kasyanov, economist Guriev to ‘extremists and terrorists’ list</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/russia-adds-ex-pm-kasyanov-economist-guriev-to-extremists-and-terrorists-list</link><description>Russia’s financial watchdog has added former prime minister Mikhail Kasyanov and leading economist Sergei Guriev to its list of “extremists and terrorists” in its latest moves against prominent exiled critics of the Kremlin.
The watchdog, Rosfinmonitoring, added the two men to a</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 14:22:42 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>