<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 14:27:36 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Jewellery maker Pandora's growth hit by weak US market</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/jewellery-maker-pandoras-growth-hit-by-weak-us-market</link><description>Danish jewellery brand Pandora (PNDORA.CO) warned of weaker 2025 sales growth on Friday, denting its shares, after US shoppers spent less than expected in the key holiday season.
Pandora, which sells $80 charm bracelets and lab-grown diamond jewellery made at its own factories in Thailand, is grap</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 12:14:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Lebanon signs gas exploration deal with international consortium</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/lebanon-signs-gas-exploration-deal-with-international-consortium-amid-economic-crisis</link><description>Lebanon 's government on Friday signed a deal with an international consortium to explore gas in an offshore area bordering Israel.
The deal for exploration at the so-called Block 8 off the coast of southern Lebanon comes after Lebanon and Israel signed a 2022 agreement over their maritime border.</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 12:29:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC publishes new Bangla version of RPO</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-publishes-new-bangla-version-of-rpo</link><description>Election Commission (EC) Secretariat has published an updated and authentic full Bangla version of the “Representation of the People Order (RPO), 1972”.
The gazette of the Bangla version of the RPO, which is available in the website of the BG Press, has been published ahead of the upco</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 12:44:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DMTCL hands over Anwara Udyan to DNCC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dmtcl-hands-over-anwara-udyan-to-dncc</link><description>Dhaka Mass Transit Company Limited (DMTCL) on Friday officially handed over the documents of Anwara Udyan, adjacent to the Farmgate Metro Rail Station, to Dhaka North City Corporation (DNCC).
DMTCL Managing Director Faruk Ahmed handed the park’s documents to DNCC Administrator Mohammad Ejaz</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 12:00:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>'Cumilla accident follows driver-passenger quarrell'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bus-passengers-recall-argument-with-driver-before-cumilla-accident-that-killed-4</link><description>Survivors of the Cumilla road accident that has killed four have said they argued with the bus driver minutes before the crash.
The bus was initially moving very slowly, making frequent stops and taking passengers, the survivors recalled.
After the passengers protested and locked in an argument w</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 12:15:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pakistan nears $1.5bn deal to supply weapons, jets to Sudan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/pakistan-nears-15bn-deal-to-supply-weapons-jets-to-sudan-sources-say</link><description>Pakistan is in the final phases of striking a $1.5-billion deal to supply weapons and jets to Sudan, a former top air force official and three sources said, promising a major boost for Sudan's army, battling the paramilitary Rapid Support Forces.
Their conflict has stoked the world's worst humanit</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 12:30:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pakistan envoy meets Tarique Rahman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/pakistan-envoy-meets-tarique-rahman</link><description>Pakistan High Commissioner to Bangladesh Imran Haider on Friday paid a courtesy call on BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman.
The meeting was held at the BNP Chairperson’s Gulshan office at around 4:30pm, said BNP Media Cell member Sayrul Kabir Khan.
BNP central leaders welcomed the Pakistani</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 12:45:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Comprehensive security preparations underway ahead of next general election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/comprehensive-security-preparations-underway-ahead-of-next-general-election</link><description>As Bangladesh prepares for the 13th national election, scheduled for February 12 next, the interim government has intensified security measures to ensure a peaceful, orderly, and credible polls.
Home Adviser Lieutenant General (Retd) Md. Jahangir Alam Chowdhury reaffirmed the government’s co</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 13:00:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC dismisses reports on suspension of Pabna-1, Pabna-2 polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-dismisses-reports-on-suspension-of-pabna-1-pabna-2-polls</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) on Friday dismissed media reports claiming that it has decided to suspend elections in the Pabna-1 and Pabna-2 constituencies, saying the information is incorrect.
In a clarification message, the EC said the reports circulated in the media quoting the commission on the</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 13:15:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EU envoys provisionally approve signing of record Mercosur trade deal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/eu-envoys-provisionally-approve-signing-of-record-mercosur-trade-deal</link><description>EU ambassadors gave provisional approval on Friday to the signing of the bloc's largest ever free trade accord with South American group Mercosur, over 25 years since negotiations began and after months of wrangling to secure key member states' backing, according to three EU diplomats and sources.</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 13:30:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP warns rebel candidates to withdraw before deadline, or face action</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-warns-rebel-candidates-to-withdraw-before-deadline-or-face-action</link><description>BNP senior leader Nazrul Islam Khan on Friday hoped that their party’s rebel candidates would withdraw from the race within the deadline set in the election schedule; otherwise, the party would take organisational action.
“The withdrawal period has not ended yet. We have asked them to</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 13:45:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique Rahman takes a quiet walk to BNP’s Gulshan office</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-rahman-takes-a-quiet-walk-to-bnps-gulshan-office</link><description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman on Friday walked to the party’s chairperson’s Gulshan office, drawing attention for the unusual mode of travel.
He reached the office at around 4:00pm, according to BNP Gulshan office sources and eyewitnesses.
Earlier in the day, Tarique Rahman perfo</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 14:00:49 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>