<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 11:37:20 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Bangladesh braces for flooding in 5 districts as rivers rise amid rains</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-braces-for-flooding-in-5-districts-as-rivers-rise-amid-rains</link><description>Low-lying areas along rivers in five districts could face temporary flooding over the coming days, the Flood Forecasting and Warning Centre (FFWC) has warned.
The vulnerable districts are Lalmonirhat, Nilphamari, Sherpur, Mymensingh and Netrokona, according to the FFWC's latest bulletin issued on</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 09:03:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh reports 263 more dengue cases in 24 hours</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-reports-263-more-dengue-cases-in-24-hours</link><description>Two hundred and sixty-three more new dengue cases were reported in the 24 hours leading up to Friday morning, bringing the total number of cases to 48, 491 this year.
According to the Directorate General of Health Services (DGHS), new cases were reported as follows: 56 in Barishal Division (Out of</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 09:33:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Italians take to the streets for Gaza flotilla general strike</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/italians-take-to-the-streets-for-gaza-flotilla-general-strike</link><description>Tens of thousands of Italians took to the streets across the country on Friday, as part of a day-long general strike called by unions in support of an aid flotilla carrying food to Gaza that was intercepted by Israel this week.
“After what I saw with the flotilla, I thought I couldn’t</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 10:03:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat fully prepared with candidates in all 300 seats: Mia Parwar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-fully-prepared-with-candidates-in-all-300-seats-mia-parwar</link><description>Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami has completed selecting candidates for contesting in all 300 constituencies in the upcoming national elections, announced the party’s secretary general and former MP Mia Golam Parwar on Friday.
“Every Jamaat worker must now go on the ground and work with full</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 10:18:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Saudi Arabia launches new licensing system for Hajis’ accommodation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/saudi-arabia-launches-new-licensing-system-for-hajis-accommodation</link><description>The Ministry of Hajj and Umrah of Saudi Arabia has announced a new licensing system for pilgrim accommodations in Makkah and Medina for the 2026 Hajj season.
Licences will now be issued through the temporary hostel licensing service, developed in collaboration with the Ministry of Tourism and the</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 10:48:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat protests Israeli attack on Gaza flotilla</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jamaat-rallies-in-dhaka-to-protest-israeli-attack-on-gaza-aid-flotilla</link><description>Jamaat-e-Islami has staged a protest march in Dhaka to condemn the Israeli attack on a flotilla carrying aid to Gaza.
The demonstration began with a brief gathering on Friday at the north gate of Baitul Mukarram National Mosque after Jummah prayers and ended near Shantinagar. The march was organis</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 11:03:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No legal barrier to implementing the July Charter: Attorney General</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/no-legal-barrier-to-implementing-the-july-charter-attorney-general</link><description>Attorney General Md Asaduzzaman on Friday said there is no legal barrier to implementing the July Charter and that it can proceed in line with the recommendations of the National Consensus Commission.
He made the remarks while talking to journalists following a view-exchange meeting with local med</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 11:33:21 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>