<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 16:34:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Indian Parliament Speaker, Saarc dignitaries to attend Bangladesh cabinet swearing-in</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/indian-parliament-speaker-saarc-dignitaries-to-attend-bangladesh-cabinet-swearing-in</link><description>India’s Lok Sabha Speaker Om Birla will represent New Delhi at the swearing-in ceremony of Bangladesh’s newly elected government in Dhaka on Tuesday, India’s Ministry of External Affairs has confirmed.
In a statement issued on Sunday, the ministry said Birla would attend the inau</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 14:04:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Modhumoti Bank holds 93rd meeting of board of directors</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/modhumoti-bank-holds-93rd-meeting-of-board-of-directors</link><description>The 93rd Meeting of the Board of Directors of Modhumoti Bank PLC was held on Sunday, according to a press release.
Mr. Humayun Kabir, Chairman of the Board of Directors, among the members of the Board of Directors, Mr. Mohammad Ismail Hossain Mr. Nemai Kumar Saha, Mr. Salahuddin Alamgir, Mr. Mosta</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 14:19:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BRAC Bank inaugurates sub-branch in Dhaka’s Monipuri Para</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/brac-bank-inaugurates-sub-branch-in-dhakas-monipuri-para</link><description>BRAC Bank has inaugurated a new sub-branch at Monipuri Para in Dhaka. With this addition, the bank’s sub-branch network now stands at 116, according to a press release.
Tareq Refat Ullah Khan, Managing Director and CEO of BRAC Bank, formally inaugurated the sub-branch at JDPC Bhaban, 145, Mo</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 14:34:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bank Asia partners with Chef’s Table for exclusive Ramadan privileges for cardholders</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bank-asia-partners-with-chefs-table-for-exclusive-ramadan-privileges-for-cardholders</link><description>Bank Asia PLC has partnered with Chef’s Table to offer exclusive Ramadan privileges for its debit and credit cardholders. Under this agreement, Bank Asia’s cardholders will enjoy a 10 per cent discount at all Chef’s Table outlets throughout the holy month of Ramadan, according to</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 14:49:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Al-Arafah Islami Bank opens training program on leadership and communication skills</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/al-arafah-islami-bank-opens-training-program-on-leadership-and-communication-skills</link><description>A two-day training course on ‘Connect, Influence, Grow: Leadership, Communication and Interpersonal Excellence’ has begun at the Bank’s Training Institute, according to a press release.
Managing Director and CEO of the bank Mohd. Rafat Ullah Khan inaugurated the training workshop</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 15:04:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IGP Baharul dismisses resignation rumours</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/igp-baharul-dismisses-resignation-rumours</link><description>Inspector General of Police Baharul Alam has dismissed reports that he is preparing to resign, amid political transition following the general election.
Baharul on Sunday afternoon said succinctly: “No, nothing like that has happened.”
Speculation about his future surfaced two days af</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 14:34:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>SAARC Journalist Forum felicitates Tarique Rahman on BNP’s electoral victory</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/saarc-journalist-forum-felicitates-tarique-rahman-on-bnps-electoral-victory</link><description>The Bangladesh Chapter of the SAARC Journalist Forum (SJF) has congratulated Chairman of the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) Tarique Rahman on the party’s sweeping victory in the country’s 13th parliamentary election held on Thursday.
In a joint statement, SJF Bangladesh Chapter Pre</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 14:49:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>After meeting Jamaat Ameer, Tarique meets NCP chief Nahid</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/after-meeting-jamaat-ameer-tarique-meets-ncp-chief-nahid</link><description>BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman on Sunday night paid a courtesy call on National Citizen Party (NCP) Convener Nahid Islam, shortly after holding a meeting with Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami Ameer Shafiqur Rahman.
Tarique reached Nahid’s residence in the capital’s Bailey Road area around 8:30p</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 15:04:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique assures Jamaat chief of protection for opposition activists</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-assures-jamaat-chief-of-protection-for-opposition-activists</link><description>Bangladesh’s prime minister-in-waiting, Tarique Rahman, has assured the leader of Jamaat-e-Islami that he has instructed party members to protect minority communities and opposition activists amid concerns over post-election reprisals.
Rahman, the chairman of the Bangladesh Nationalist Party</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 15:19:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Army to return to barracks after new govt’s oath: Waker-Uz-Zaman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/army-to-return-to-barracks-after-new-govts-oath-waker-uz-zaman</link><description>Chief of Army Staff General Waker-Uz-Zaman on Sunday said the Army will return to barracks once the newly elected government assumes office.
He, however, said a portion of the Army will remain deployed in the field to assist in maintaining law and order until the police regain full control of the</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 15:34:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC: Take complaints to High Court</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-take-complaints-about-gazette-of-poll-results-to-high-court</link><description>Election Commissioner Anwarul Islam Sarker has dismissed allegations of “undue haste” over the publication of the official gazette following the recent general election.
He said the gazette listing the names of elected candidates was issued in due course after the announcement of unoff</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 15:49:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No handshake as Pakistan elect to field against India</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/no-handshake-as-pakistan-elect-to-field-against-india</link><description>Pakistan’s Salman Agha chose to field after winning the toss against India but there was no handshake between the captains before the Twenty20 World Cup Group A blockbuster on Sunday.
The match between the bitter rivals went ahead after Pakistan earlier reversed their decision to boycott the</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 16:04:52 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>