<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 04:29:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nutritional transition in South Asia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/nutritional-transition-in-south-asia</link><description>Because of a major shift in dietary patterns and lifestyle changes due to urbanisation and rising incomes, low- and middle-income countries are experiencing a rapid nutrition transition, leading to 'double burden of malnutrition', with under nutrition co-existing with obesity. The poorest populatio</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 17:25:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Korail slum blaze tamed after five hours as inhabitants watch homes collapse</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/korail-slum-blaze-tamed-after-five-hours-as-inhabitants-watch-homes-collapse</link><description>A devastating fire that raged for more than five hours in the Korail slum of Dhaka’s Mohakhali has finally been brought under control, while the air filled with the cries of residents who watched their homes collapse into ashes.
Fire Service spokesman Anwar Bin Sattar confirmed at 10:35pm on</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 17:40:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Why Savar leather park cannot go global</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/why-savar-leather-park-cannot-go-global</link><description>The recent findings about the Leather Industrial Park in Savar by the Implementation Monitoring and Evaluation Division (IMED) have once again brought Bangladesh's struggle with industrial governance, environmental compliance and export competitiveness into sharp focus. What was once envisioned as</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 17:55:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Recalibration of education for skill development</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/recalibration-of-education-for-skill-development</link><description>In today's world of ever-shifting balance of power, global trade and economy are getting fragmented and, in some cases, protectionist and regionalised, while supply chains are facing disruptions.  Amid these developments, the economies of countries so far bracketed as Least Developed Countries</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 18:41:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Spectrum auction to fetch Tk 2.37 billion per unit</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/spectrum-auction-to-fetch-tk-237-billion-per-unit</link><description>Bangladesh plans to earn Tk 2.37 billion per unit from 700MHz spectrum auction as the government approves the long-awaited financial terms for selling the highly coveted telecommunications backbone. 
The Finance Division has endorsed the modus operandi, clearing a major regulatory hurdle and</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 02:15:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Paddy prices slightly lower as import continues, millers dominate market</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/paddy-prices-slightly-lower-as-import-continues-millers-dominate-market</link><description>Paddy prices during the ongoing Aman harvest season are slightly lower than last year’s, with farmers and market observers attributing the decline to continued rice imports and the strong presence of millers in the market.
According to the Department of Agricultural Marketing, dry guti swarn</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 02:30:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Exchange rate rise erodes export competiveness</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/exchange-rate-rise-erodes-export-competiveness</link><description>Bangladesh's exports may get costlier to foreign buyers while imports cheaper as the local currency, taka, appears increasingly overvalued in the foreign-exchange basket in real terms.
Economists explain that this economic paradox appears for sluggish import demand, weak private-sector credit grow</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 02:45:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Disaster-induced emergency: Finance ministry asked to keep specific allocations for rescue operations</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/disaster-induced-emergency-finance-ministry-asked-to-keep-specific-allocations-for-rescue-operations</link><description>Instead of keeping funds in the form of block allocations, the finance ministry has been requested to keep specific budgetary allocations to carry out rescue operations in case of disaster-related emergencies, officials say.
It has also been requested to keep allocations for fiscal rescue operatio</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 03:00:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ACC files 512 cases, freezes Tk 222b worth of bank accounts in a year</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/acc-files-512-cases-freezes-tk-222b-worth-of-bank-accounts-in-a-year</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) filed a total of 512 cases and froze Tk 222 billion worth of bank accounts between December 2024 and October 2025.
The figures were revealed at a view-exchange meeting on the occasion of the Commission's 21st anniversary at its headquarters in Dhaka on Tuesday.</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 03:15:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CIC unlocks 2 bank lockers of Hasina</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cic-unlocks-2-bank-lockers-of-hasina</link><description>The Central Intelligence Cell unlocked two lockers of ousted Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina on Tuesday at Agrani Bank's principal branch.
CIC, accompanied by magistrates, bank officials, broke open the locker nos. 751 and 753 as per Bangladesh Bank Guidelines.
Official sources said they found a con</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 03:30:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Petrobangla to import 7 more LNG cargoes annually to boost fertiliser production</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/petrobangla-to-import-7-more-lng-cargoes-annually-to-boost-fertiliser-production</link><description>State-run Petrobangla has decided to import at least seven additional LNG cargoes annually-preferably from the spot market-using the proceeds from the recent tariff hike in order to feed the gas-starved fertilizer factories.
"We'll include the plan for additional liquefied natural gas (LNG) cargo</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 03:45:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fortune Shoes' profit nosedives as non-operating income dries up</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/fortune-shoes-profit-nosedives-as-non-operating-income-dries-up</link><description>Fortune Shoes' profit nosedived to Tk 19 million in FY25 as non-operating income shrank significantly.
The shoe manufacturer's profit tumbled 77 per cent year-on-year in FY25, according to a stock exchange filing on Tuesday.
Fortune Shoes, based mainly in the southern division of Barishal, report</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 04:00:44 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>