<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 15:24:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Maj Gen Osman Sarwar made new DG of NTMC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/maj-gen-osman-sarwar-made-new-dg-of-ntmc</link><description>The government has appointed Major General Mohammad Osman Sarwar as the new Director General of the National Telecommunication Monitoring Center (NTMC).
The Ministry of Public Administration issued a notification in this regard on Sunday.
According to the notification, Major General Osman Sarwar</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 12:15:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>City Bank and UNICEF partner to empower marginalized youth with green skills</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/city-bank-and-unicef-partner-to-empower-marginalized-youth-with-green-skills</link><description>City Bank and UNICEF recently announced a new partnership to equip marginalized adolescents and young people, particularly the girls with green and entrepreneurship skills under the pilot project, Skills4Youth.
The partnership was formalized at a signing ceremony held recently in Dhaka, according</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 12:30:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Verdict nears as testimonies conclude in ‘plot graft’ case against Hasina</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/verdict-nears-as-testimonies-conclude-in-plot-graft-case-against-hasina</link><description>Testimonies have concluded in the corruption case filed against former prime minister Sheikh Hasina and 11 others over the alleged illegal allocation of plots.
On Monday, Dhaka Special Judge Mohammad Abdullah Al Mamun set Nov 17 for the defendants to present their statements in self-defence.
Cros</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 12:45:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ex-minister Muktadir ordered to appear before ICT</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/former-minister-obaidul-muktadir-ordered-to-appear-before-ict</link><description>The International Crimes Tribunal (ICT) has ordered former housing and public works minister RAM Obaidul Muktadir Chowdhury to appear before it on Dec 14 over allegations of killings of Hifazat-e Islam leaders in Brahmanbaria.
The directive was issued on Monday by a single-member bench of Tribunal</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 13:00:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC’s decision declared ‘Illegal’, 4 Bagerhat seats restored</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ecs-decision-declared-illegal-4-bagerhat-seats-restored</link><description>The High Court has declared illegal the gazette notification issued by the Election Commission (EC) that reduced Bagerhat's four parliamentary seats to three.
A bench of Justice Sashanka Shekhar Sarkar and Justice Faysal Hasan Arif directed that the previous four seats be reinstated.
The court de</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 13:15:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DMP bans police on duty in Dhaka from using mobile phones</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dmp-bans-police-on-duty-in-dhaka-from-using-mobile-phones</link><description>The Dhaka Metropolitan Police (DMP) has banned the use of mobile phones by on-duty personnel as security measures tighten surrounding programmes announced by the outlawed Awami League.
The directive was issued on Monday by Police Commissioner Sheikh Md Sazzat Ali, Joint Commissioner (Crime) Md Far</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 13:30:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>INSEE Cement wins Innovation Leader Award</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/insee-cement-wins-innovation-leader-award</link><description>INSEE ECO PLUS+, with the lowest Product Carbon Footprint (PCF) from Siam City Cement (Bangladesh) Ltd., became the Champion in the "Innovation Leader of the Year" category at the Foreign Investors’ Chamber of Commerce and Industry (FICCI) Sustainability and Innovation Awards 2025.
The compa</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 13:18:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BBC in turmoil as top bosses quit over Trump speech edit, bias allegations</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/bbc-in-turmoil-as-top-bosses-quit-over-trump-speech-edit-bias-allegations</link><description>The BBC plunged into a leadership crisis on Monday after its Director-General Tim Davie and head of news Deborah Turness resigned over the controversial editing of a speech by U.S. President Donald Trump, amid mounting accusations of political bias.
Their resignations followed revelations that a P</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 13:33:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Postal Vote BD’ app launches on Nov 18 to facilitate postal voting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/postal-vote-bd-app-launches-on-nov-18-to-facilitate-postal-voting</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) will launch the ‘Postal Vote BD’ app on Nov 18, enabling registration for postal voting in the general elections.
Election Commissioner Abul Fazal Md Sanaullah shared the information on Monday afternoon during a meeting on the “Voting Procedure throug</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 13:48:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No action to be taken on speculation over harassment claims: BCB</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/no-action-to-be-taken-on-speculation-over-harassment-claims-bcb</link><description>The Bangladesh Cricket Board (BCB) has said it will not take any decision based on speculation or emotion over the sexual harassment allegations made by former national cricketer Jahanara Alam.
The board insisted that only a full and independent investigation will determine the outcome.
Speaking</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 14:03:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>School admissions again through lottery, applications start Nov 21</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/school-admissions-again-through-lottery-applications-start-nov-21</link><description>Admissions to both government and non-government secondary schools will take place through the lottery system used last year for the same purpose.
Students can apply for admission from Nov 21, with the deadline set for Dec 5.
The digital lottery is tentatively scheduled for Dec 14.
After attendi</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 14:18:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Operation Devil Hunt: 9 arrested in Kuakata</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/operation-devil-hunt-9-arrested-in-kuakata</link><description>Police have arrested nine individuals, including Awami League activists and suspects wanted in various cases, during the ongoing `Operation Devil Hunt’ in Kalapara upazila of Patuakhali.
Jewel Islam, Officer-in-Charge of Kalapara Police Station, said the operation was conducted on Sunday nig</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 14:33:17 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>