<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 15:20:26 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Global airlines affected by major Airbus A320 recall</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/global-airlines-affected-by-major-airbus-a320-recall</link><description>Europe's Airbus ordered immediate repairs to 6,000 of its widely used A320 jets in a sweeping recall affecting more than half the global fleet, threatening upheaval during the busiest travel weekend of the year in the US and sparking disruption worldwide.
The fix mainly involves reverting to earli</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 13:30:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>87,000 Bangladeshi expats registered so far to vote</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/87000-bangladeshi-expats-registered-so-far-to-vote</link><description>Nearly 87,000 expatriate Bangladeshi voters from different countries across the world have so far registered through a mobile app, ‘Postal Vote Bd’, in the past 10 days to vote in the upcoming national election and the referendum.
The Election Commission (EC) on November 19 opened the</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 13:45:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>1.4 million now jobless due to stalled industrialisation: A.K. Azad at economic conference</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/14-million-now-jobless-due-to-stalled-industrialisation-ak-azad-at-economic-conference</link><description>Industrial stagnation and shrinking private investment have caused 1.4 million (14 lakh) people to lose jobs, leaving them “wandering on the streets without employment,” Ha-Meem Group Managing Director and former FBCCI president A.K. Azad said on Saturday.
Speaking at the opening sessi</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 14:00:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Myanmar junta invites citizens abroad to return</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/myanmar-junta-invites-citizens-abroad-to-return</link><description>Myanmar junta leader has said citizens living in the United States and other countries will be welcomed if they wish to return.
The announcement came after the United States ended temporary protected status for nearly 4,000 Myanmar nationals earlier this week.
Irrawaddy reported that speaking at</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 13:00:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Myanmar citizens abroad ‘welcome to return’, junta chief says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/myanmar-citizens-abroad-welcome-to-return-junta-chief-says</link><description>Myanmar junta leader has said citizens living in the United States and other countries will be welcomed if they wish to return.
The announcement came after the United States ended temporary protected status for nearly 4,000 Myanmar nationals earlier this week.
Irrawaddy reported that speaking at</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 13:15:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NRBC Bank achieves ‘Silver Rank’ in Asia Sustainability Reporting Rating-2025</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/nrbc-bank-achieves-silver-rank-in-asia-sustainability-reporting-rating-2025</link><description>NRBC Bank PLC achieved ‘SILVER RANK’ in Asia Sustainability Reporting Rating-2025 by National Centre for Corporate Reporting (NCCR), Indonesia, collaboration with the Institute of Certified Sustainability Practitioners (ICSP). 
Dr. Md. Touhidul Alam Khan, Managing Director &amp; CEO o</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 13:30:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Such uprisings may recur if people’s aspirations continue to be denied: NCP's Nahid at BEC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/such-uprisings-may-recur-if-peoples-aspirations-continue-to-be-denied-ncps-nahid-at-bec</link><description>National Citizen Party (NCP) Convener Nahid Islam on Saturday said If people’s aspirations continue to be denied, such uprisings may recur as young people fight to reclaim their rightful prospects and future.
“The previous ‘fascist government' had entrenched a discriminatory syst</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 13:45:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khaleda’s health condition still fragile, doctors report no improvement</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/khaledas-health-condition-still-fragile-doctors-report-no-improvement</link><description>The health condition of BNP Chairperson Begum Khaleda Zia, now undergoing treatment at Evercare Hospital in the capital, has not shown any significant improvement, according to her medical board members and senior party leaders.
Doctors say the former prime minister is still suffering from pneumon</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 14:00:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BRAC Bank and Sheba Merchants partner to empower SMEs through financing and technology</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/brac-bank-and-sheba-merchants-partner-to-empower-smes-through-financing-and-technology</link><description>BRAC Bank has entered into a partnership with Sheba Merchants Limited to enable access to finance for SMEs associated with the Sheba Platform.
Under this collaboration, BRAC Bank will extend SME digital micro-loan facilities to eligible merchants registered on the platform, helping them access cap</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 14:15:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Meghna Bank celebrates achievements of chairperson, vice chairman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/meghna-bank-celebrates-achievements-of-chairperson-vice-chairman</link><description>Recently, Uzma Chowdhury, Chairperson of Meghna Bank PLC and Director, Finance of PRAN-RFL Group, has been awarded Bangladesh C-Suite Awards under the category of "Chief Finance Officer (CFO)/ Finance Director of the Year 2025".
This recognition reflects her exceptional leadership in financial gov</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 14:30:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka Bank launches Bangladesh’s first-ever youth-focused dual currency prepaid card 'Spark' in partnership with Mastercard</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/dhaka-bank-launches-bangladeshs-first-ever-youth-focused-dual-currency-prepaid-card-spark-in-partnership-with-mastercard</link><description>Dhaka Bank PLC.  in collaboration with Mastercard, has officially launched Bangladesh's first-everyouth-centric dual currency prepaid card, branded as “Spark”, at a grand launching ceremony held at a hotel at Gulshan on Monday, 24 November 2025.
The Spark Card of Dhaka Bank design</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 14:45:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP to stage ‘Victory Torch Roadshow’, grand rally on Dec 16</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-to-stage-victory-torch-roadshow-grand-rally-on-dec-16</link><description>BNP will organise a nationwide ‘Victory Torch Roadshow’ along with a ‘grand  rally’ on December 16 at Manik Mia Avenue in the capital to mark the Month of Victory.
BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir made the announcement at a press conference at the Part</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 15:00:46 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>