<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 20:19:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>UP Chairman Alfu Mia, suspect linked to ‘Sada Pathor loot’, arrested</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/up-chairman-alfu-mia-suspect-linked-to-sada-pathor-loot-arrested</link><description>Kazi Abdul Wadud Alfu Mia, the chairman of Telikhal Union and a prominent figure in the local Awami League, has been arrested over alleged connections with the illegal sand and stone theft from Sada Pathor in Sylhet’s Companiganj.
He was arrested near the Agricultural Bank in the town on Sat</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 16:11:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh seeks further reduction in US tariffs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-seeks-further-reduction-in-us-tariffs</link><description>National Security Adviser and High Representative for the Rohingya issue Dr Khalilur Rahman has requested Assistant US Trade Representative Brendan Lynch to consider further reduction in tariffs as the trade gap becomes narrower between the two countries.
Dr Rahman made the request at a meeting wi</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 16:26:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh closely monitoring safety of Shahidul Alam: CA</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-closely-monitoring-safety-of-shahidul-alam-ca</link><description>Bangladesh is closely monitoring the status and safety of those participating in the historic flotilla for Gaza, especially world-renowned photographer and human rights activist Shahidul Alam, Chief Adviser Prof Muhammad Yunus said in a statement today (Saturday). 
“Shahidul has approac</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 16:56:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A saga of wastage and despair</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/a-saga-of-wastage-and-despair</link><description>The news appeared in newspapers rather quietly - and it did not attract much public attention either. May be, it was not an exciting issue or it did not represent a loud emergency. But in the absolute analysis, it reflects an impending danger. In Bangladesh, about nine lakh young people with univer</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 17:11:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hold Ekushey book fair in February</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/hold-ekushey-book-fair-in-february</link><description>The Bangla Academy's decision to reschedule the upcoming Amar Ekushey Book Fair 2026, which has traditionally been held throughout the month of February, has sparked controversy and caused profound dismay among booklovers and publishers. The row began when the Academy proposed holding the fair from</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 17:24:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gearing up for WTO MC14</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/gearing-up-for-wto-mc14</link><description>With just six months to go, the World Trade Organisation (WTO) is gearing up for its 14th Ministerial Conference (MC14), a crucial event that most members appear indifferent to. Scheduled to take place in Yaoundé, Cameroon, from March 26 to 29, 2026, this conference carries a complex agenda</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 17:39:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Back from Singapore, Nur finally vents on attack that left him seriously injured; calls it 'assassination attempt'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/back-from-singapore-nur-finally-vents-on-attack-that-left-him-seriously-injured-calls-it-assassination-attempt</link><description>Gono Odhikar Parishad (GOP) President Nurul Haque Nur has alleged that he was the target of a planned assassination attempt during the attack in front of his party’s central office last August 29 that left him seriously injured.
Speaking to the media on Saturday evening upon his return from</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 17:54:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rebuilding trust in credit ratings</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/rebuilding-trust-in-credit-ratings</link><description>Confidence in any economy is contingent upon the fair assessments provided by credit rating agencies and on investors' trust in the financial information guiding their decisions. This, thus, places a fundamental duty on these agencies to act as an impartial voice and call the risks as they see them</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 18:09:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Central bank about to attain long-cherished autonomy as regulator</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/central-bank-about-to-attain-long-cherished-autonomy-as-regulator</link><description>Bangladesh Bank is set to become a much-envisaged independent regulatory body for the banking sector as the central bank prepares to place the agenda to the advisory council of the interim government this week.
Along with the bank mergers-related roadmap, the banking regulator has taken all ne</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 18:24:16 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>