<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 07:51:29 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Cold wave may push temperatures down to 8.0°C in February</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cold-wave-may-push-temperatures-down-to-80c-in-february</link><description>A mild cold wave is likely to affect parts of northern, western and northwestern Bangladesh during the first half of February, according to the Bangladesh Meteorological Department.
The cold wave may push temperatures down to between 8.0°C and 10.0°C in some areas, it said, though no sever</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 04:25:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India to travel to Sri Lanka, follow ICC protocol despite Pakistan's boycott</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/india-to-travel-to-sri-lanka-follow-icc-protocol-despite-pakistans-boycott</link><description>India has decided to proceed with all formal requirements for its T20 World Cup match against Pakistan, despite Islamabad's announcement that it would boycott the fixture.
The Indian team will travel to Sri Lanka, hold training sessions, attend the pre-match press conference and be present at the</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 04:40:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BanglaBiz 2.0 launched for seamless investor services</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/banglabiz-20-launched-for-seamless-investor-services</link><description>The Bangladesh Investment Development Authority (BIDA), in partnership with the Japan International Cooperation Agency (JICA), launched BanglaBiz 2.0 on Sunday, in a significant step towards enhancing the ease of doing business and attracting both domestic and foreign investment.
This upgraded dig</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 04:55:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Election ballot papers being sent out to districts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/election-ballot-papers-being-sent-out-to-districts</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has started sending ballot papers to returning officers, along with the names and symbols of the candidates, for the parliamentary elections.
On Monday, EC Deputy Secretary Rashedul Islam said: "Ballot papers were sent from Dhaka to 12 districts on Sunday. They are bei</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 05:10:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ctg port strike enters 3rd day</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ctg-port-strike-enters-3rd-day</link><description>Dock workers and terminal staff have continued their work stoppage for a third consecutive day to protest the handover of the New Mooring Container Terminal (NCT) to the UAE-based firm DP World.
The strike called by the “Bandar Rokkha Sangram Parishad” (Port Protection Struggle Council</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 05:25:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Graft case: ACC takes Salman F Rahman into custody for four days</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/graft-case-acc-takes-salman-f-rahman-into-custody-for-four-days</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) has taken Salman F Rahman, former advisor to ousted Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina, into its custody for four days to interrogate him in a corruption case.
Muhammad Zainal Abedin, Deputy Director of the ACC, received him from Keraniganj Central Jail in Dhaka on S</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 05:40:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Locate RAB members who shot Limon</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/locate-rab-members-who-shot-limon</link><description>The High Court (HC) on Sunday directed government bodies to locate seven RAB-8 officials, who were involved in the shooting and maiming of Limon Hossen in Jhalakathi in 2011.
The government bodies have also been ordered to communicate their address to the court.
Home affairs ministry, law minis</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 05:55:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nearly 465,000 expats case vote, 195,000 postal ballots reach Bangladesh so far</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nearly-465000-expats-case-vote-195000-postal-ballots-reach-bangladesh-so-far</link><description>Almost 465,000 expatriate Bangladeshis have cast their votes by post, with around 195,000 ballots so far reaching Bangladesh, according to the Election Commission (EC).
Salim Ahmad Khan, team leader of the commission’s OCV-SDI project, said 194,914 postal ballots had been received as of 11:0</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 06:10:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>300-metre stretch of paved road collapses into river</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/300-metre-stretch-of-paved-road-collapses-into-river</link><description>RAJSHAHI, Jan 01: A 300-metre stretch of a metalled road from Mohanganj in Bagmara upazila of Rajshahi to Nowhata in Paba upazila has collapsed into the Baranai River in Bagmara upazila, severely disrupting communication for residents of nearly 50 surrounding villages.
According to locals, the r</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 06:25:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Textile, spinning firms witness Q2 slowdown</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/textile-spinning-firms-witness-q2-slowdown</link><description>Bangladesh's leading textile and spinning companies saw business momentum weaken sharply in the October-December quarter, as subdued global demand, cautious buying by international apparel brands and persistent cost pressures took a toll on revenues and profits.
The typical peak export season de</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 06:40:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gold prices fall again as BAJUS revises rates</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/gold-prices-fall-again-as-bajus-revises-rates</link><description>Gold prices in Bangladesh have been cut by Tk 6,590 per bhori, with the new rates taking effect immediately, the Bangladesh Jewellers Association (BAJUS) said on Monday.
In a morning notice, BAJUS said the decision followed a decline in the local price of pure gold (tejabi), prompting a review of</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 06:55:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bobby, Ruponti now get jail terms alongside Hasina and Tulip in Purbachal plot graft cases</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bobby-ruponti-now-get-jail-terms-alongside-hasina-and-tulip-in-purbachal-plot-graft-cases</link><description>Ousted prime minister Sheikh Hasina has been sentenced to jail in two more cases over corruption involving plot allocations to her family. This time, her nephew Radwan Mujib Siddique Bobby and niece Azmina Siddiq Ruponti have also received prison sentences.
The Awami League president was accused i</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 07:10:33 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>