<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 03:19:20 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Fast-tracking land dispute resolution</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/fast-tracking-land-dispute-resolution</link><description>The Land Crime Prevention and Remedy Act, 2023 was enacted to expedite the resolution of land-related disputes outside the courtroom through an administrative process. However, its enforcement remains pending so far. It is heartening to know from a recent Financial Express report that the present g</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 18:26:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UN chief Guterres urges govts worldwide to ensure press freedom</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/un-chief-guterres-urges-govts-worldwide-to-ensure-press-freedom</link><description>United Nations Secretary-General António Guterres has called on governments across the world to ensure that journalists can carry out their work freely and safely everywhere.
In a statement marking the 11th International Day to End Impunity for Crimes against Journalists, he wrote media pro</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 19:40:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Probe finds glaring graft, bloated payouts to power plant owners</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/probe-finds-glaring-graft-bloated-payouts-to-power-plant-owners</link><description>Most private-sector power plants implemented during the previous Awami League government's tenure were steeped in blatant "corruption, fraud and irregularities" in the process of executing deals, investigators found.



A national committee formed after the fall of the past government in a stud</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 19:55:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Private credit growth hits historic low of 6.29pc in September</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/private-credit-growth-hits-historic-low-of-629pc-in-september</link><description>Formal credit growth for the private sector fell to a historical low of 6.29 per cent in September, signalling a deep slowdown in the country's business activities.
The decline is attributed to banks becoming more cautious amid rising non-performing loans (NPLs) and private borrowers losing their</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 01:29:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>COP30 SUMMIT IN BRAZIL: Bangladesh to present 'Just Transition' agenda</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/cop30-summit-in-brazil-bangladesh-to-present-just-transition-agenda</link><description>For the first time, Bangladesh will introduce the concept of a 'Just Transition', a framework that integrates climate-affected communities into decent employment, at the upcoming COP30 summit in Belém, Brazil, on November 10-21.
The move signals a shift in Bangladesh's climate strategy towa</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 01:44:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mobile, internet subscription fall continues in Sept</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/mobile-internet-subscription-fall-continues-in-sept</link><description>Bangladesh saw a continued decline in both mobile and mobile internet subscribers in September 2025, according to the latest data released by the telecom regulator.
The figures show a downward trend in subscriber numbers across major operators and internet service categories, extending a slowdown</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 01:59:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>91-day T-bill yield jumps to 10.24pc</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/91-day-t-bill-yield-jumps-to-1024pc</link><description>The yields on treasury bills (T-bills), particularly the short-term ones, rose sharply on Sunday as banks appeared reluctant to invest their excess liquidity in risk-free government securities ahead of the year-end closing.
The cut-off yield, generally referred to as the interest rate, on the 91-d</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 02:29:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India win maiden Women's World Cup title after Verma-Sharma show</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/india-win-maiden-womens-world-cup-title-after-verma-sharma-show</link><description>India's agonising wait for a maiden Women's World Cup title finally came to an end as Harmanpreet Kaur and her teary-eyed teammates clinched the trophy by beating South Africa in a dramatic final at the DY Patil Stadium on Sunday.
Their 52-run victory before a full house was the perfect culminatio</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 02:59:15 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>