<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 08:51:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>US, Iran set for nuclear talks in Geneva</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-iran-set-for-nuclear-talks-in-geneva</link><description>The US and Iran hold indirect talks in Geneva on Tuesday aimed at resolving their long-running nuclear dispute, with little clear indication of compromise as Washington masses a battle force in the region.
US envoys Steve Witkoff and Jared Kushner will take part in the negotiations, which are bein</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 06:18:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat, NCP threaten oath boycott</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jamaat-ncp-threaten-oath-boycott</link><description>Jamaat-e-Islami and its alliance partner the National Citizen Party (NCP) have threatened to boycott the swearing-in ceremony for lawmakers after the BNP declined to take oath as members of the Constitution Reform Council.
Although BNP lawmakers were sworn in as members of the 13th National Parlia</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 06:33:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP MPs opt against duty-free cars, government plots</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bnp-mps-opt-against-duty-free-cars-government-plots</link><description>BNP lawmakers have decided not to accept duty-free cars or government plots after taking oath as members of the 13th national parliament.
The decision was taken on Tuesday during the party’s first parliamentary meeting following the swearing-in ceremony, according BNP Media Cell member Shair</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 06:48:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique Rahman elected parliamentary party leader</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-rahman-elected-parliamentary-party-leader</link><description>BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman has been elected as the leader of the parliamentary party.
He was elected parliamentary party leader in a meeting of BNP’s parliamentary party at the meeting room in Jatiya Sangsad Bhaban at about 11.30 am on Tuesday, BNP media cell member Shairul Kabir Khan told</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 07:03:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Expatriate’s wife, two children found dead in Cumilla</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/expatriates-wife-two-children-found-dead-in-cumilla</link><description>Police recovered the bodies of a woman and two children with their throats slit at Uttar Manipur village in Homna upazila of Cumilla early Tuesday.
The deceased were identified as Sukhi Akter, wife of Saudi Arabia expatriate Zahirul Islam, their four-year-old son Hossain and six-year-old Zobaid, s</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 07:18:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat MPs take oath</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-mps-take-oath</link><description>Jamaat-e-Islami lawmakers have taken their oath as members of the 13th national parliament, despite earlier threatening to boycott the ceremony after the BNP declined to be sworn in as members of the Constitution Reform Council.
Jamaat MPs and independents began taking the oath shortly after noon</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 07:33:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka Metro Rail unveils updated train timings for Ramadan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dhaka-metro-rail-unveils-updated-train-timings-for-ramadan</link><description>The Dhaka Mass Transit Company Limited (DMTCL) has introduced a fresh Metro Rail timetable for the holy month of Ramadan.
According to a notice on Tuesday, the updated timetable will remain in effect from the first day of Ramadan until the day before Eid-ul-Fitr, adjusting train timings in line wi</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 07:20:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique taps ex-state minister Milon for cabinet</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-taps-ex-state-minister-milon-for-cabinet</link><description>ANM Ehsanul Hoque Milon, the BNP MP from Chandpur-1 and a former state minister for education, has been invited to join the cabinet of the incoming government led by Tarique Rahman.
Milon’s personal aide, MA Foyez, confirmed the development on Tuesday.
“The cabinet secretary called a</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 07:35:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UK Minister Seema to attend Bangladesh govt’s swearing-in ceremony</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/uk-minister-seema-to-attend-bangladesh-govts-swearing-in-ceremony</link><description>British Minister Seema Malhotra will attend the swearing-in ceremony of the newly elected government of Bangladesh later today.
She paid a courtesy call on Chief Adviser Prof Muhammad Yunus at the State Guest House Jamuna on Tuesday.
British High Commissioner to Bangladesh Sarah Cooke and Senior</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 07:50:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gold price drops by Tk 2,216 per bhori in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/gold-price-drops-by-tk-2216-per-bhori-in-bangladesh</link><description>The price of gold in Bangladesh has been reduced by Tk 2,216 per bhori, with the new rate for 22-carat gold set at Tk 258,824 per bhori (11.664 grams), Bangladesh Jewellers Association (BAJUS) announced on Tuesday.
In a morning notification, BAJUS said the price of pure gold (tejabi gold) declined</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 08:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Air Chief calls on CA</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/air-chief-calls-on-ca</link><description>Air Chief Marshal Hasan Mahmood Khan paid a courtesy call on Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus at the State Guest House Jamuna  in Dhaka on Tuesday said the Chief Adviser’s Press Wing.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 08:20:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique’s first cabinet: Who makes the cut?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tariques-first-cabinet-who-makes-the-cut</link><description>BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir, Standing Committee members Salahuddin Ahmed and Iqbal Hasan Mahmud, and several other leaders have received calls to take oath as members of the cabinet in the incoming government led by Tarique Rahman.
Officials at the BNP chairperson’s off</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 08:35:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>