<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 08:34:43 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>38th AGM of Kohinoor Chemical held</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/38th-agm-of-kohinoor-chemical-held</link><description>The 38th Annual General Meeting (AGM) of Kohinoor Chemical Company (BD) Limited was held at 3:15 pm on Sunday on a digital platform.
Md Rezaul Karim, managing director of Kohinoor Chemical Company, was present at the meeting, says a media release.
Md Ebadul Karim, director, Prof Dr Anwar Hossain,</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 05:18:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt set to implement new project to digitise medical, nursing education</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/govt-set-to-implement-new-project-to-digitise-medical-nursing-education</link><description>The government has taken a project aimed at streamlining and strengthening the management of medical, population and nursing education services across the country.
The project “Integrated Improvement in the Management of Activities of the Directorate General of Medical Education (DGME), NIPO</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 05:33:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two Bangladeshi workers die in Maldives</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/two-bangladeshi-workers-die-in-maldives</link><description>Two Bangladeshi migrant workers have reportedly died from cardiac complications within a span of 12 hours in the Maldives.
The men, Ahmed Kamal, 48, and Selim Uddin, 64, were both from Moulvibazar district, reports bdnews24.com.
Md Jasim Uddin, welfare assistant at the Bangladesh High Commission,</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 05:48:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Thailand launches air strikes at Cambodia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/thailand-launches-air-strikes-at-cambodia</link><description>Thailand has launched air strikes along its disputed border with Cambodia, the Thai military said on Monday, after both countries accused the other of breaching a ceasefire agreement brokered by US President Donald Trump.
At least one Thai soldier has been killed, and four wounded in the fresh cla</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 06:03:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shakib Al Hasan cancels retirement</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/cricket/shakib-al-hasan-cancels-retirement</link><description>Bangladesh all-rounder Shakib Al Hasan has rowed back on his decision to retire from Tests and T20Is, saying he now intends to play in all three formats at home before drawing the curtain on his illustrious international career.
He made the remarks during an appearance on the Beard Before Wicket p</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 06:33:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Seven fishermen kidnapped, ransom demanded</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/seven-fishermen-kidnapped-ransom-demanded</link><description>Seven fishermen were abducted allegedly by a group of pirates from different areas of the Sundarbans on Sunday.
The abductors are now charging Tk 50, 000 as ransom for each fisherman.
The incident occurred on Sunday morning in the Malancha River of the Satkhira range, including Hanskhali, Chelaka</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 06:48:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC, Jamaat meet ahead of polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ec-jamaat-meet-ahead-of-polls</link><description>A delegation from Jamaat-e-Islami has sat down for talks with the Election Commission amid preparations to announce the schedule of the 13th parliamentary election and the planned national referendum, expected to take place simultaneously in early February next year.
The meeting began around 11:30</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 07:03:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mother, daughter found dead in Mohammadpur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/mother-daughter-found-dead-in-mohammadpur</link><description>Police have recovered the bodies of a woman and her teenage daughter, both bearing stab wounds, from a house in the Mohammadpur area of Dhaka.
The gruesome scene was discovered on Monday morning on Shahjahan Road opposite the Residential College, police say.
The dead have been identified as 48-ye</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 07:30:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Seven college students continue sit-in outside Education Ministry</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/seven-college-students-continue-sit-in-outside-education-ministry</link><description>Students of the seven government colleges continued their sit-in protest in front of the Education Ministry on Monday, demanding that the colleges be turned into a university. They said the protest would continue until the government met their one-point demand.
Around 150–200 students were s</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 07:45:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh economy under pressure despite signs of gradual rebound: Report</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/bangladesh-economy-under-pressure-despite-signs-of-gradual-rebound-report</link><description>Bangladesh's economy continues to face significant stress from persistent inflation, weak investor confidence, limited fiscal space and external uncertainties, even as some indicators point to the prospect of a gradual recovery in the coming months, according to the Bangladesh State of the Economy</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 08:00:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jatiya Party factions of Anisul, Manju come together in new alliance</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jatiya-party-factions-of-anisul-manju-come-together-in-new-alliance</link><description>A new alliance called the National Democratic Front (NDF) has been formed, which includes the Jatiya Party faction led by Anisul Islam Mahmud and as well as Anwar Hossain Manju’s Jatiya party-JP.
Anisul announced the formation of the new alliance at a press briefing on Monday, reports bdnews</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 08:15:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two secretaries to lead new NBR divisions under current govt, says Chairman Khan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/two-secretaries-to-lead-new-nbr-divisions-under-current-govt-says-chairman-khan</link><description>The two divisions of the National Board of Revenue (NBR) -- Revenue Policy and Revenue Management – will be introduced during the tenure of the interim government, NBR Chairman Md Abdur Rahman Khan says.
He expects the two divisions to begin operating soon once the remaining bureaucratic pro</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 08:30:46 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>