<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 04:59:17 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>A world without the UN?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/a-world-without-the-un</link><description>As the World War I or WWI ended, the victors of the war made the Covenant of the League of Nations, in short, League, in January 1920, wherein the Treaty of Versailles was included. The mission was to maintain world peace. But it failed in its mission because the vanquished in the WWI was treated l</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 18:15:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rationalising microcredit interest rates</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/rationalising-microcredit-interest-rates</link><description>As the government seeks to reform the microfinance sector, which has long been plagued by irregularities and high interest rates, a crucial question has emerged: should lending rates of microfinance banks be capped? The newly promulgated Microfinance Bank Ordinance proposes transforming eligible mi</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 18:30:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CA directs opening FTA talks with EU</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/ca-directs-opening-fta-talks-with-eu</link><description>Chief Adviser Prof Muhammad Yunus Sunday directed opening free-trade agreement (FTA) negotiations with the European Union forthwith to safeguard Bangladesh's trade preferences in its largest export market as the current duty-free access is set to expire.
The head of interim government stressed the</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 19:33:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Revenue board bifurcation loses way in legal labyrinth</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/revenue-board-bifurcation-loses-way-in-legal-labyrinth</link><description>Much-hyped bifurcation of the National Board of Revenue (NBR) is unlikely to complete during the tenure of the interim government as the major reform gets into legal and procedural labyrinth.
Officials and experts vent such despair in view of latest complications facing the major revenue reform.</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 02:13:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh set to sign a trade deal with US on Feb 9</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladesh-set-to-sign-a-trade-deal-with-us-on-feb-9</link><description>Bangladesh and the United States are set to open a new chapter in bilateral commercial relations with the signing of a trade agreement on February 9.
The initiative is aimed at easing Washington's "reciprocal tariff" and expanding mutual market access between the two countries.
Commerce Secretary</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 02:28:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Editors' Council airs concern about two draft ordinances</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/editors-council-airs-concern-about-two-draft-ordinances</link><description>The Editors' Council has expressed deep concern about the process and timing of two draft ordinances on the National Media Commission and the Broadcasting Commission, recently published on the website of the Ministry of Information and Broadcasting.
With the national election approaching, the coun</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 02:43:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ICC warns Pakistan over India match boycott</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/icc-warns-pakistan-over-india-match-boycott-at-t20-world-cup</link><description>The International Cricket Council (ICC) has issued a sharp warning to the Pakistan Cricket Board (PCB) after Pakistan’s government cleared the national team to play in the 2026 Men’s T20 World Cup but barred it from taking the field against India.
In a post on X on Sunday, the Pakistan</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 02:58:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>RMG exports to US fall in value and volume amid higher tariffs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/rmg-exports-to-us-fall-in-value-and-volume-amid-higher-tariffs</link><description>Bangladesh's ready-made garment (RMG) exports to its largest destination, the United States, declined both in value and volume year on year in November 2025 as higher tariffs dampened demand and forced changes in work-order patterns.
Although overall apparel export growth during the January-Novemb</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 03:00:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rampal plant seeks approval to import 2.35m tonnes of coal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/rampal-plant-seeks-approval-to-import-235m-tonnes-of-coal</link><description>The Bangladesh-India Friendship Power Company (Pvt.) Limited (BIFPCL) has sought special approval from the Ministry of Commerce (MoC) to import the remaining 2.353 million tonnes of coal under CIF (Cost, Insurance and Freight) Incoterms, sources said.
The move is aimed at ensuring uninterrupted po</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 03:15:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Majority PPP projects stall along with committed FDIs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/majority-ppp-projects-stall-along-with-committed-fdis</link><description>Over 50 per cent of the projects taken under the public-private partnership (PPP) development model since 2009, mostly involving foreign investment, stay put despite having been enlisted as potential ones for Bangladesh's uplift.
The Public-Private Partnership Authority (PPPA) has a projection of</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 03:30:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>2nd day’s strike at Ctg port hits maritime trade</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/2nd-days-strike-at-ctg-port-hits-maritime-trade</link><description>CHATTOGRAM: The strike of Chittagong port workers has hampered the maritime trade in the country.
The operational activities of Chittagong Port, the prime sea port of the country, remained suspended for a second consecutive day on Sunday as the port workers continued a work stoppage protesting the</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 03:45:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>T-bill yields climb after new PD guidelines</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/t-bill-yields-climb-after-new-pd-guidelines</link><description>The yields on treasury bills (T-bills) rose on Sunday following the implementation of new primary dealer (PD) guidelines aimed at injecting greater dynamism into both the primary and secondary markets.
The cut-off yield, generally regarded as the interest rate, on the 91-day T-bills increased to 1</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 04:00:45 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>