<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 07:50:11 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Regulator urges compensation for shareholders before NBFI liquidation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/regulator-urges-compensation-for-shareholders-before-nbfi-liquidation</link><description>The securities regulator has sought a compensation package for investors before delisting the non-bank financial institutions (NBFIs) that are set to be liquidated.
A committee from the Bangladesh Securities and Exchange Commission (BSEC) met representatives of the central bank a few days before t</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 01:53:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Stocks extend slide as investors await policy signals from new govt</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/stocks-extend-slide-as-investors-await-policy-signals-from-new-govt</link><description>Stocks plunged for another session on Wednesday as investors cautiously assessed the potential policy direction and regulatory environment under the newly elected government.
The BNP-led government formed after oath-taking on Tuesday is yet to disclose any work plan regarding the capital market, s</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 02:08:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sub-branch loan growth outpaces banking sector average</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/sub-branch-loan-growth-outpaces-banking-sector-average</link><description>Outstanding loans and advances disbursed through sub-branches of scheduled banks recorded a notable rise in July-September 2025, outpacing overall growth in the banking sector, according to the latest data from Bangladesh Bank (BB).
Total outstanding loans through sub-branches increased from Tk 17</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 02:23:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two dead as Army truck, bus collide head-on in Mymensingh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/two-dead-as-army-truck-bus-collide-head-on-in-mymensingh</link><description>Two people have been killed and at least 12 others injured in a head-on collision between an Army truck and a bus in Mymensingh’s Phulpur upazila.
The accident occurred around 10:45am on Wednesday at the Balia intersection on the Sherpur–Mymensingh regional highway, according to Rashed</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 03:37:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BB buys $109m more from eight banks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bb-buys-109m-more-from-eight-banks</link><description>The central bank purchased US$109 million more through auction from eight banks in the interbank spot market on Wednesday aiming to keep the exchange rate of the US dollar against the local currency stable.
The amount was bought under the Multiple Price Auction method and the cutoff rate was Tk 12</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 03:52:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Corruption in major projects quadruples debt, wastes 40pc of funds: Experts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/corruption-in-major-projects-quadruples-debt-wastes-40pc-of-funds-experts</link><description>Corrupt masterminds in Bangladesh's infrastructure and energy sectors have hijacked the national master plan, experts warned on Tuesday, saying mismanaged projects have quadrupled the country's debt while wasting 40 per cent of allocated funds.
The remarks came during a roundtable at the CIRDAP au</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 04:07:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>TIB calls for annual asset disclosure by MPs, public officials</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tib-calls-for-annual-asset-disclosure-by-mps-public-officials</link><description>Transparency International Bangladesh (TIB) has called for mandatory annual disclosure of income, expenditure and asset statements by members of parliament and all public office holders to ensure transparency and accountability in governance.
It also urged the formulation and adoption of an integr</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 04:22:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>HC petition challenges July Charter</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hc-petition-challenges-july-charter</link><description>A writ petition has been filed with the High Court challenging the legality of the July National Charter 2025, a sweeping reform agenda introduced by the now-dissolved interim government led by Prof Dr Muhammad Yunus.
The petitioner argues that key provisions of the Charter, including proposals fo</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 04:37:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Long queues form as subsidised TCB sales begin for Ramadan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/long-queues-form-as-subsidised-tcb-sales-begin-for-ramadan</link><description>Long queues of consumers, mainly from low- and lower-middle-income groups, were spotted across the capital on Wednesday to buy essential goods at subsidised rate from the Trading Corporation of Bangladesh (TCB).
The TCB launched its special subsidised sales programme in the capital and across the</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 04:52:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>10 lakh families to get affordable protein-rich food during Ramadan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/10-lakh-families-to-get-affordable-protein-rich-food-during-ramadan</link><description>The government will provide protein-rich food at subsidised prices to around 10 lakh low-income families across the country during the holy month of Ramadan, said State Minister for Fisheries and Livestock Sultan Salauddin Tuku on Thursday.
He said the initiative, taken in line with the government</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 05:07:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Poor dairy farmers fall in debt in Pabna due to 'Dadan trap'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/poor-dairy-farmers-fall-in-debt-in-pabna-due-to-dadan-trap</link><description>PABNA, FEB 18: Impoverished dairy farmers in Pabna's Bera Char said they have been sustaining serious losses and falling in debt due to cattle traders' conditions on milk selling after the traders' provided them investment to buy and raise dairy cows.
Farmers said they have been considering changi</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 05:22:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Million taka growth centre defunct for 18 years in Sunamganj</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/million-taka-growth-centre-defunct-for-18-years-in-sunamganj</link><description>SYLHET, Feb 18: Sunamganj's Dowarabazar Upazila growth centre, built to be used as the commercial hub for the sale and marketing of kitchen and other items, remained non-operational for nearly two decades.
Sources said "over unknown reasons", the authorities had failed to launch operations at the</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 05:37:37 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>