<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 11:21:39 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Chargesheet filed against British MP Tulip Siddiq for illegal possession of Gulshan flat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/chargesheet-filed-against-british-mp-tulip-siddiq-for-illegal-possession-of-gulshan-flat</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) on Thursday approved a chargesheet against British MP Tulip Rizwana Siddiq and former RAJUK official Sarder Mosharraf Hossain, accusing them of illegal possession and transfer of a flat in Gulshan, Dhaka, through abuse of power and criminal conspiracy.
Accordin</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 08:36:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pakistan's ex-spy chief jailed for 14 years in rare military rebuke</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/pakistans-ex-spy-chief-jailed-for-14-years-in-rare-military-rebuke</link><description>A military court in Pakistan jailed former spy chief Faiz Hamid for 14 years on four charges including interference in politics, the army said on Thursday, in a rare conviction of a once-powerful general in the South Asian nation.
Hamid, in custody and under trial since August last year, was the c</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 08:51:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>At least 30 killed in Myanmar after junta airstrike hits hospital</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/at-least-30-killed-in-myanmar-after-junta-airstrike-hits-hospital</link><description>At least 30 people were killed, including patients, after an airstrike by the country's ruling junta hit a major hospital in Myanmar's western Rakhine state, according to a rebel group, an aid worker and a witness said on Thursday.
More than 70 people were injured, they said.
The hospital in Ra</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 09:06:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Portugal general strike stalls transport, closes schools in labour reform protest</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/portugal-general-strike-stalls-transport-closes-schools-in-labour-reform-protest</link><description>Train services ground to a halt across Portugal on Thursday, hundreds of flights were cancelled, and schools closed as unions launched a first general strike in more than a decade, in protest against proposed labour reforms.
The minority centre-right government says the proposed changes - amending</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 09:21:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump plans to appoint US general to lead Gaza security force, Axios reports</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-plans-to-appoint-us-general-to-lead-gaza-security-force-axios-reports</link><description>The Trump administration is planning to appoint an American two-star general to command the International Stabilization Force in Gaza, Axios reported on Thursday, citing two US officials and two Israeli officials.
Reuters could not immediately confirm the report.</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 09:36:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Anti-graft platform demands wealth disclosure of advisers Asif, Mahfuj</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/anti-graft-platform-demands-wealth-disclosure-of-advisers-asif-mahfuj</link><description>A youth-led anti-graft platform on Thursday demanded that two advisers Asif Mahmud Shojib Bhuiyan and Mahfuj Alam, who stepped down on Wednesday, disclose their assets.
The platform under the banner of ‘Anti-Graft Students and People’ made the demand at a human chain formed in front of</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 09:51:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Thousands rally again in Bulgaria to demand government's resignation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/thousands-rally-again-in-bulgaria-to-demand-governments-resignation</link><description>Thousands of Bulgarians rallied on Wednesday evening against the country's minority government and what they say is its failure to tackle endemic corruption in the European Union's poorest member state.
The protests in the capital Sofia and dozens of other towns and cities across the Black Sea nat</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 10:06:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Kremlin says Russia is interested in foreign investment after report of major US plans</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/kremlin-says-russia-is-interested-in-foreign-investment-after-report-of-major-us-plans</link><description>The Kremlin said on Thursday that Russia was interested in attracting additional foreign investment after the Wall Street Journal reported that the US plan for peace in Ukraine includes proposals to invest in Russian rare earths and energy.
The Journal said the plans, detailed in appendices to pea</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 10:21:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>VAT paid by public often fails to reach treasury, warns Finance Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/vat-paid-by-public-often-fails-to-reach-treasury-warns-finance-adviser</link><description>Finance Adviser Dr Salehuddin Ahmed has expressed concern that, in many cases, VAT paid by the public fails to reach the government treasury.
He described this as “unfortunate” and stressed the need to simplify procedures to ensure that VAT is properly deposited.
"VAT is a modern and</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 10:36:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>VAT paid by public often fails to reach treasury, says Finance Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/vat-paid-by-public-often-fails-to-reach-treasury-says-finance-adviser</link><description>Finance Adviser Dr Salehuddin Ahmed has expressed concern that, in many cases, VAT paid by the public fails to reach the government treasury.
He described this as “unfortunate” and stressed the need to simplify procedures to ensure that VAT is properly deposited. "VAT is a modern and p</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 10:51:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shaukat Mahmood put on five-day remand</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dhaka-court-grants-police-five-days-to-question-shaukat-mahmood-in-custody</link><description>A Dhaka court has granted police five days to interrogate Shaukat Mahmood, a former Jatiya Press Club president and Janata Party Bangladesh general secretary, in their custody.
Dhaka Metropolitan Magistrate Fahmina Khandakar Anna passed the remand order on Thursday.
Sub-Inspector Jinnat Ali of th</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 11:06:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Mango emerges as Bangladesh’s next high-potential export’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/mango-emerges-as-bangladeshs-next-high-potential-export</link><description>Bangladesh has achieved remarkable export growth in recent years, with the agricultural products steadily gaining traction. As the country prepares for graduation from the Least Developed Country (LDC) status, diversification of agricultural exports has become increasingly essential to strengthen g</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 11:21:39 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>