<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 06:26:06 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Garment exports to non-traditional markets stall amid global slowdown</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/garment-exports-to-non-traditional-markets-stall-amid-global-slowdown</link><description>Bangladesh's readymade garment (RMG) exports to non-traditional markets recorded sluggish growth in the first quarter of the current fiscal year, reflecting persistent global demand weakness and economic uncertainty across key economies.
Official data show that exports to new destinations - includ</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 02:48:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Less than 20pc register as Hajj deadline ends today</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/less-than-20pc-register-as-hajj-deadline-ends-today</link><description>The deadline for Hajj -2026 registration will end today (Sunday) as less than 20 per cent have so far completed their registration against the allocated quota of 127,198 for Bangladeshi pilgrims.
Until 7:30 pm on Sunday a total of 21,826 completed their Hajj registration accounting for only 17.16</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 03:03:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Raw jute shortage deepens despite limited exports</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/raw-jute-shortage-deepens-despite-limited-exports</link><description>Even with the government's recent restrictions on export of raw jute, the commodity has almost disappeared from local markets, leaving mills struggling to find supplies.
After prices surged sharply in August and September, the government imposed limits on raw jute exports following the main tradin</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 03:18:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Net sales of savings certificates plummet 86.3pc in Aug</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/net-sales-of-savings-certificates-plummet-863pc-in-aug</link><description>Net sales of national savings certificates recorded a steep 86.3 per cent year-on-year decline in August 2025, as tighter liquidity conditions and rising living costs dampened small investors' interest in government savings instruments.
According to the Bangladesh Bank (BB) data, the net sales of</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 03:33:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Md Ehsanul Hoque appointed public administration secretary</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/md-ehsanul-hoque-appointed-public-administration-secretary</link><description>The interim government has finally filled the vacant post of secretary of public administration, appointing Md Ehsanul Hoque to the position.
Ehsanul had been serving as the senior secretary in the Road Transport and Highways Division for a long time.
In a notice on Sunday, the Ministry of Public</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 05:04:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Afghanistan attacks Pakistani border posts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/afghanistan-attacks-pakistani-border-posts</link><description>Afghan security forces attacked Pakistani border posts late Saturday in response to what the Taliban government called repeated violations of its territory and airspace, underscoring deepening security tensions between the neighbors.
Earlier in the week, Afghan authorities accused Pakistan of bomb</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 05:19:51 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>