<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 16:27:56 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Quake ‘tilts’ ex-mayor Manjur’s seven-storey building in Chattogram</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/quake-tilts-ex-mayor-manjurs-seven-storey-building-in-chattogram</link><description>A seven-storey building in Chattogram has “tilted” towards a neighbouring structure following a 5.7-magnitude earthquake.
The building, located on Miyabari Road in Mansurabad under Double Mooring Police Station, is owned by former Chattogram City mayor M Manjur Alam.
Station chief Bab</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 13:02:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Attacks in Nigeria: What's behind the latest kidnappings, church raid?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/africa/attacks-in-nigeria-whats-behind-the-latest-kidnappings-church-raid</link><description>Nigeria has grabbed global headlines again following a spate of attacks by gunmen involving the kidnapping of dozens of students from two schools and a deadly assault on a church service.
This week's incidents have piled more pressure on the Nigerian government following U.S. President Donald Trum</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 13:17:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique mourns quake deaths, slams lack of precautions</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-mourns-quake-deaths-slams-lack-of-precautions</link><description>Expressing profound sorrow over the loss of lives in Friday’s earthquake, BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman said the casualties and damage could have been reduced had proper precautionary measures been taken in advance.
“A devastating earthquake today caused extensive damage to severa</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 13:32:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chief of Army Staff Waker receives ‘Senabahini Padak’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/chief-of-army-staff-waker-receives-senabahini-padak</link><description>Army chief General Waker-Uz-Zaman has received the “Senabahini Padak”.
The medal was handed over by Chief Advisor Muhammad Yunus during the Armed Forces Day reception at Dhaka Cantonment on Friday, according to the Press Information Department.
Bangladesh observes Armed Forces Day on</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 13:47:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>436 hospitalised with dengue in 24 hours</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/436-hospitalised-with-dengue-in-24-hours</link><description>A total of 436 new dengue patients were hospitalised across the country in the past 24 hours, according to a press release issued by the Directorate General of Health Services (DGHS).
Of them, 63 were admitted to hospitals in Barishal division (outside City Corporation), 98 in Chattogram division</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 14:02:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Minor plaster falls at HSIA after Dhaka quake</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/minor-plaster-falls-at-hsia-after-dhaka-quake</link><description>Minor plaster fell from a ceiling joint on the departure driveway of Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport (HSIA) after this morning’s earthquake in Dhaka, prompting brief movement restrictions as a precaution, officials said.
Executive Director of HSIA Group Captain SM Ragib Samad told BSS</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 14:17:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Primary teachers set Nov 29 deadline to implement ‘assurances’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/primary-teachers-set-nov-29-deadline-to-implement-assurances</link><description>Government primary school assistant teachers have set a Nov 29 deadline for authorities to implement “assurances” on salary increase and higher-grade promotion.
On Friday, the teachers also demanded state compensation and full pension for the family of Fatema Akter, who fell ill and di</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 14:32:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UN, US express solidarity after earthquake in Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/un-us-express-solidarity-after-earthquake-in-dhaka</link><description>The United Nations and the United States on Friday expressed deep sympathy and solidarity with those affected by a strong earthquake in Dhaka, as both conveyed support while authorities continue assessing the tremor’s impact.
In a statement shared on social media, the UN in Bangladesh said i</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 14:47:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Earthquake upends Narayanganj couple’s life</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/father-misses-daughters-funeral-rushes-between-hospitals-with-injured-wife</link><description>The 5.7 magnitude earthquake that rattled Bangladesh on Friday has upended the lives of Abdul Haque and Kulsum Begum, a couple from Narayanganj, who lost their 10-month-old daughter in the disaster.
The daughter, Fatema, identified with a single name, was in her mother’s lap when a wall coll</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 15:02:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mastermind of fake visa scam arrested in city</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/mastermind-of-fake-visa-scam-arrested-in-city</link><description>The Criminal Investigation Department (CID) arrested the mastermind of an organised fraud ring that embezzled Tk 12.2 million from 28 people by promising jobs, visas and air tickets to Russia.
The accused Abdullah, 45, was detained on Thursday from Lalmatia in Mohammadpur, said a CID press release</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 15:17:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Earthquake epicentre Narsingdi sees five deaths, scores of injuries</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/earthquake-epicentre-narsingdi-sees-five-deaths-scores-of-injuries</link><description>The worst earthquake in decades in Bangladesh has killed five people and injured more than 100 in its epicentre — Narsingdi.
The fatalities included a father and his son, who were crushed to death after an eave collapsed on them.
A wall collapsed on a man, killing him. Another man died fall</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 15:32:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Watchman dies in railing collapse during quake</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/security-guard-struck-by-falling-railing-during-quake-dies-in-dhaka</link><description>A security guard has died in Dhaka’s Mugda after a railing from the roof of an under-construction building collapsed during the earthquake.
The guard, identified with a single name Maksud, was critically injured when the 5.7 magnitude earthquake struck on Friday.
He was taken to Mugda Gener</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 15:47:21 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>