<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 07:21:38 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Fires break out on two buses in Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fires-break-out-on-two-buses-in-dhaka</link><description>Fires have broken out on two buses in Dhaka’s Shahjadpur and Merul Badda areas.
One of the buses is owned by Victor Paribahan, while the other is owned by Akash Paribahan. The incidents occurred early on Monday morning.
However, their causes have yet to be determined, bdnews24.com reports.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 04:36:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NBR launches online VAT refund module</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/nbr-launches-online-vat-refund-module</link><description>The National Board of Revenue (NBR) has launched an Online VAT Refund Module to facilitate the online submission, processing, and direct transfer of VAT refund amounts to taxpayers’ bank accounts.
With the introduction of the new module, a digital linkage has been established between the exi</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 04:51:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Commando forces to be stationed nationwide before polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/commando-forces-to-be-stationed-nationwide-before-polls</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has instructed law-enforcing agencies to take early action to maintain law and order around the upcoming 13th parliamentary elections.
The directives include recovering illegal firearms, arresting identified and listed criminals, setting up check-posts and conducting s</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 05:06:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Baira union alone produces sugarcane worth Tk300m</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/baira-union-alone-produces-sugarcane-worth-tk300m</link><description>MANIKGANJ: Manikganj's Singair upazila has witnessed remarkable success in sugarcane farming, particularly in Baira union, with local farmers earning substantial profits from cultivating other companion crops like mustard and maize alongside as well.
Farmer Alkas Hossain from Nayabari village in B</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 05:21:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Brahmaputra's mineral-rich sand seen as promising revenue source in Gaibandha</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/brahmaputras-mineral-rich-sand-seen-as-promising-revenue-source-in-gaibandha</link><description>GAIBANDHA: As Bangladesh recently started technically examining the commercial potential of mineral-rich sand found in the rivers of northern regions, the high-value minerals of Brahmaputra River's sand in Gaibandha would be a promising source of revenue if environment-friendly extraction process a</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 05:36:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IDRA seeks to reform reinsurance rules to fix poor claim settlement record</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/idra-seeks-to-reform-reinsurance-rules-to-fix-poor-claim-settlement-record</link><description>The proposal to remove the provision that makes Sadharan Bima Corporation (SBC) a mandatory reinsurer is intended to improve the claim settlement ratio of general insurers, not to undermine SBC's significance, said the insurance sector watchdog.
The country had only a 35.54 per cent claim settleme</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 05:51:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cyclone, 3-6 days of rain forecast in November</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/cyclone-3-6-days-of-rain-forecast-in-november</link><description>The Bangladesh Meteorological Department has forecast that two to three more low-pressure systems are to form in the Bay of Bengal during the rest of November.
At least one of them can intensify into a depression or a cyclone, bdnews24.com reports.
In addition, the remainder of the month could al</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 06:06:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Man shot dead in broad daylight near Dhaka lower courts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/man-shot-dead-in-broad-daylight-near-dhaka-lower-courts</link><description>A man has been shot dead in front of the National Medical College gate near Dhaka’s lower courts.
He was then declared dead from the gunshot wound at Dhaka Medical College Hospital after 11:00 am, bdnews24.com reports.
Initially, authorities have yet to identify him.
Faruk Hossain, officer</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 06:21:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Crude bomb detonated in front of Grameen Bank headquarters</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crude-bomb-detonated-in-front-of-grameen-bank-headquarters</link><description>A crude explosive has been detonated in front of the Garmeen Bank main branch in Dhaka’s Mirpur, reports bdnews24.com.
The incident occurred around 3:45am on Monday, according to Sajjad Roman, chief of Mirpur Model Police Station.
“We looked at the CCTV footage and saw two people come</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 06:36:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Indonesia grants national hero status to late strongman President Suharto</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/indonesia-grants-national-hero-status-to-late-strongman-president-suharto</link><description>Indonesia awarded the title of national hero on Monday to late President Suharto, who was forced out of office in 1998 by violent protests that ended a three-decade rule marred by accusations of mass human rights violations, corruption and nepotism.
The title was conferred in a ceremony presided o</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 06:51:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No records of JUCSU fund kept for 30 years</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/no-records-of-jucsu-fund-kept-for-30-years</link><description>For nearly three decades, students of Jahangirnagar University have been contributing fees to the Jahangirnagar University Central Students' Union (JUCSU) fund, but the university treasury holds no comprehensive financial records of the fund, states JUCSU General Secretary Mazharul Islam.
He made</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 07:06:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Delhi police detain dozens in anti-pollution protests</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/delhi-police-detain-dozens-in-anti-pollution-protests</link><description>Indian police detained dozens of people during a rare protest at the famed India Gate monument in New Delhi demanding action to curb an annual scourge of toxic air swathing the capital and its surrounding region.
Sunday's protest by crowds of all ages holding banners and chanting slogans before po</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 07:21:38 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>