<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 06:35:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>General sworn in as new Guinea-Bissau leader, ousted president arrives in Senegal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/africa/general-sworn-in-as-new-guinea-bissau-leader-ousted-president-arrives-in-senegal</link><description>Guinea-Bissau’s military installed Major-General Horta Inta-a as transitional president on Thursday, a day after soldiers toppled the civilian leadership in a swift power grab made before the results of a weekend election could be announced.
The president who was ousted in the coup, Umaro Si</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 04:17:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Capitalise on BD's ceramics industry's potential: Commerce adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/capitalise-on-bds-ceramics-industrys-potential-commerce-adviser</link><description>Commerce Adviser Sk Bashir Uddin urged businesspersons on Thursday to capitalise on the growing potential of Bangladesh's ceramics industry.
"The government remains supportive of the private sector, but businesses must come forward with logical, acceptable and realistic proposals," he said while i</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 04:32:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NEIR won’t push up handset prices: BTRC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/neir-wont-push-up-handset-prices-btrc</link><description>The Bangladesh Telecommunication Regulatory Commission (BTRC) has reiterated its assurance in ensuring that the introduction of the National Equipment Identity Register (NEIR) on 16 December would not lead to an increase in mobile handset prices, despite persistent concerns among buyers and section</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 04:47:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Man kills friend, surrenders in Mymensingh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/man-kills-friend-surrenders-in-mymensingh</link><description>A young man has surrendered to police with “a blood-stained Chinese axe” after killing his friend in Trishal upazila of Mymensingh.
The incident took place at Trishal Government Nazrul Academy grounds at 8.30 pm on Thursday.
The dead, Muntasir Fahim, 22, had been studying in Malaysia</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 04:16:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UN appreciates Bangladesh for leading with courage in global peacekeeping</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/un-appreciates-bangladesh-for-leading-with-courage-in-global-peacekeeping</link><description>The United Nations has expressed profound gratitude to Bangladesh as its peacekeepers continue to serve with unwavering dedication across seven missions worldwide.
Bangladesh is the third-largest contributor of UN peacekeepers, with more than 5,600 military and police personnel currently deployed</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 04:31:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cyclone Ditwah forms over Bay of Bengal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cyclone-ditwah-forms-over-bay-of-bengal</link><description>A low-pressure system located in the southwest Bay of Bengal and the adjacent Sri Lankan coast has intensified into a cyclone, which has been named “Ditwah”.
The Bangladesh Meteorological Department (BMD) has asked seaports to display distant warning signal No. 2, highlighting rough se</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 04:46:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UAE halts visas for Pakistanis</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/uae-halts-visas-for-pakistanis</link><description>The United Arab Emirates (UAE) has stopped issuing visas to Pakistani citizens, Interior Ministry official Salman Chaudhry has told a Senate committee, citing concerns over “misuse” of visit visas.
Dawn reported Chaudhry’s remarks to the Senate Functional Committee on Human Right</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 05:01:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BGB seeks public, media support to curb rumours, smuggling in Lalmonirhat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/bgb-seeks-public-media-support-to-curb-rumours-smuggling-in-lalmonirhat</link><description>Border Guard Bangladesh (BGB–Teesta Battalion) has urged the media and local residents of Lalmonirhat to help prevent rumours and smuggling along the district’s border areas, stressing that community cooperation is vital for strengthening border security.
Brigadier General ASM Naser, R</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 05:16:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>4th GolfHouse Corporate Cup kicks off in Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/4th-golfhouse-corporate-cup-kicks-off-in-dhaka</link><description>The fourth annual GolfHouse Corporate Cup Golf Tournament 2025 began on Friday at Kurmitola Golf Club (KGC) in Dhaka.
Lieutenant General Mohammad Shaheenul Haque, commandant, National Defence College and also vice president of Kurmitola Golf Club, along with A M M Nazrul Hosen, founder and editor</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 05:31:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>At least 56 dead as severe floods, landslides batter Sri Lanka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/at-least-56-dead-as-severe-floods-landslides-batter-sri-lanka</link><description>At least 56 people have died and 21 remain missing after days of torrential rain triggered widespread flooding and landslides across Sri Lanka, one of the country’s worst weather disasters in recent years.
The central district of Badulla, known for its sprawling tea estates, was among the ha</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 05:46:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US to permanently pause migration from 'Third World Countries'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-says-us-will-permanently-pause-migration-from-third-world-countries</link><description>US President Donald Trump said on Thursday that his administration will work to "permanently pause" migration from all "Third World Countries" to allow the US system to fully recover.
Trump did not identify any countries by name or explain what he meant by third-world countries or "permanently pau</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 06:01:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Youth fatally stabbed amid ‘teen gang feud’ in Khulna</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/youth-fatally-stabbed-amid-teen-gang-feud-in-khulna</link><description>A young man has been stabbed to death during a clash between rival youth gangs in Khulna.
The victim, identified as 21-year-old Ishan, was attacked on Thursday evening near the Khalishpur Fair Clinic intersection, according to Khalishpur Police Station chief Mir Atahar Ali.
He died on the way to</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 06:16:23 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>