<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 11:30:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Jamaat pledges business protection, end to red tape and extortion</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-pledges-business-protection-end-to-red-tape-and-extortion</link><description>Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami has pledged to protect businesses and eliminate bureaucratic red tape and extortion if it comes to power, party Ameer Dr Shafiqur Rahman said at a dialogue with business leaders held ahead of the national election.
The dialogue, titled "Strategic Thoughts for Industry an</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 07:17:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt paves way to compensation for victims of enforced disappearances, torture</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-paves-way-to-compensation-for-victims-of-enforced-disappearances-torture</link><description>The interim government has taken a key step towards allowing compensation and rehabilitation for victims of torture and enforced disappearance by withdrawing a long-standing declaration linked to a United Nations anti-torture treaty.
The decision, approved on Thursday at a meeting of the Advisory</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 07:32:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Navy member dies in Ctg road crash</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/navy-member-killed-as-bus-hits-motorcycle-in-chattograms-patiya</link><description>A member of the Bangladesh Navy has been killed and another injured after a bus hit their motorcycle in Chattogram's Patiya.
The accident happened on Friday at the Patiya bypass on the Chattogram–Cox’s Bazar Highway, according to police.
The dead man was identified as 38-year-old Nazm</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 08:33:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Myanmar election delivers victory for military-backed party</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/myanmar-election-delivers-victory-for-military-backed-party</link><description>Myanmar's military-backed party has completed a sweeping victory in the country's three-phase general election, state media said, cementing an outcome long expected after a tightly controlled political process held during civil war and widespread repression.
The Union and Solidarity Party (USDP) d</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 08:35:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rangpur awaits Tarique as BNP prepares for rally ahead of election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/rangpur-awaits-tarique-as-bnp-prepares-for-rally-ahead-of-election</link><description>Rangpur is preparing to welcome BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman as he returns to the city after about two decades ahead of the Feb 12 elections.
Tarique is scheduled to arrive in Rangpur on Friday and address a public rally at the Collectorate Eidgah Field in the evening as part of his election campai</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 08:50:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gold price drops by Tk 14,638 per bhori in Bangladesh a day after record high</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/gold-price-drops-by-tk-14638-per-bhori-in-bangladesh-a-day-after-record-high</link><description>A day after hitting a record high, gold prices in Bangladesh fell sharply on Friday, with the Bangladesh Jewellers Association (BAJUS) cutting the rate by Tk 14,638 per bhori.
In a notification, BAJUS said it has fixed the price of 22-carat gold at Tk 271,363 per bhori (11.664 grams), effective im</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 09:05:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US Embassy issues security alert ahead of Feb election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/us-embassy-issues-security-alert-ahead-of-feb-election</link><description>The US Embassy in Dhaka has issued a security alert, urging US citizens in Bangladesh to remain vigilant, avoid demonstrations and exercise caution around large gatherings.
“US citizens should remain vigilant, avoid demonstrations, and exercise caution in the vicinity of any large gatherings</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 09:20:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>16 countries to send 57 observers for Feb 12 election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/16-countries-to-send-57-observers-for-feb-12-election</link><description>At least 16 countries have accepted Bangladesh’s invitations to send a total of 57 election observers for the country’s 13th general election and the referendum on the July Charter, both scheduled to be held concurrently on February 12.
These observers will join several hundred interna</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 09:35:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Euro zone economy ends 2025 on solid footing, confirming resilience</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/global/euro-zone-economy-ends-2025-on-solid-footing-confirming-resilience</link><description>The euro zone's largest economies grew at a modest but steady pace last quarter as consumption and investments kicked into higher gear to offset low exports and exceptional uncertainty from erratic US trade policy, national data showed on Friday.
The figures signal remarkable resilience for a bloc</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 09:50:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US military destroyer docks at Israel's Eilat port, Israeli media reports</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-military-destroyer-docks-at-israels-eilat-port-israeli-media-reports</link><description>A US Navy destroyer has docked at the Israeli port of Eilat, Israel's Ynet news website reported on Friday, citing the military, as tensions between Washington and Iran escalate.
Ynet said the arrival of the destroyer at the southern port on the Gulf of Aqaba, near Israel's borders with Egypt and</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 10:05:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rangpur set for Tarique Rahman’s election rally</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/rangpur-set-for-tarique-rahmans-election-rally</link><description>BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman is scheduled to address an election rally at the Collectorate Eidgah ground in Rangpur on Friday afternoon as part of his ongoing campaign tour of the northern region.
Ahead of the rally, he will visit Pirganj upazila, where he is set to pay homage at the grave of Shahe</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 10:20:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Improved coordination, speedy decisions key to economic edge: Govt</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/improved-coordination-speedy-decisions-key-to-economic-edge-govt</link><description>The interim government has noted ‘tangible progress’ in streamlining investment and trade processes, citing improved inter-agency coordination and faster decision-making as key drivers of economic competitiveness.
The updates were presented at the 7th meeting of the Investment Coordina</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 10:35:27 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>