<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 16:33:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>NCP warns of resistance if corrupt EC officials are not removed: Nahid Islam</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ncp-warns-of-resistance-if-corrupt-ec-officials-are-not-removed-nahid-islam</link><description>National Citizen Party (NCP) Convener Nahid Islam on Wednesday warned that the party will “resist” if immediate action is not taken against corrupt officials still working inside the Election Commission (EC).
He issued the warning after a meeting with the Chief Election Commissioner at</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 13:08:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CA Yunus visits Khaleda Zia in Evercare Hospital</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ca-yunus-visits-khaleda-zia-in-evercare-hospital</link><description>Chief Advisor Muhammad Yunus has visited BNP Chairperson Khaleda Zia at Evercare Hospital.

His motorcade entered the hospital at 7:07pm on Wednesday. BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir received him, bdnews24.com reports. 
The chief advisor was then taken to the fourth-floor</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 13:23:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tenure of independent investigation commission on BDR carnage extended</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tenure-of-independent-investigation-commission-on-bdr-carnage-extended</link><description>The government has extended the tenure of the National Independent Investigation Commission formed to reinvestigate the BDR carnage till December 7.
Cabinet Division issued a notification in this regard on Wednesday.
The interim government formed the independent commission on December 24 last yea</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 13:38:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Supply shortfall results in sudden onion price-hike</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/supply-shortfall-results-in-sudden-onion-price-hike</link><description>The country produced 4.4 million tonnes of onion in the 2024-25 growing season, exceeding the estimated demand of 3.5 million tonnes. However, there is now a shortage of onions, and the price has increased.
The prices of locally produced onions have surged recently at both farm and retail levels.</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 13:53:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Probe report in July crimes against humanity case against Joy, others received</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/probe-report-in-july-crimes-against-humanity-case-against-joy-others-received</link><description>The prosecution of the International Crimes Tribunal (ICT) has received the probe report in a case filed over crimes against humanity committed during the July Mass Uprising against Sajeeb Wazed Joy and three others.
"We have received the probe report over July Mass Uprising crimes against humanit</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 14:08:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Standard Chartered and Channel i honour agricultural innovators at 10th Agrow Award</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/standard-chartered-and-channel-i-honour-agricultural-innovators-at-10th-agrow-award</link><description>Standard Chartered Bangladesh and Channel i celebrated the remarkable achievements and pioneering spirit of individuals and organisations shaping the future of the nation’s agriculture sector at the Standard Chartered–Channel i Agrow Award 2025, marking its landmark 10th season.
Hosted</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 14:23:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BRAC Bank leaders stress future-focused risk strategy at Annual Risk Conference 2025</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/brac-bank-leaders-stress-future-focused-risk-strategy-at-annual-risk-conference-2025</link><description>BRAC Bank’s senior leadership has underscored the need for stronger governance, strict compliance, and proactive preparedness to address the risks that may emerge in the coming years.
The call came during the bank’s Annual Risk Conference 2025, according to a media release. 
Vete</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 14:38:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Traders hike edible oil prices ‘without govt approval’: Commerce Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/traders-hike-edible-oil-prices-without-govt-approval-says-commerce-adviser</link><description>Traders have raised edible oil prices without the government’s knowledge, the commerce adviser has said.
There is no legal basis for this, Sheikh Bashir Uddin told reporters at the Secretariat on Wednesday.
He said he had learned of the hike only an hour earlier and that the ministry would</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 14:40:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Court filing of reinvestigation report on Viqarunnisa’s Aritry death Jan 8</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/court-filing-of-reinvestigation-report-on-viqarunnisas-aritry-death-jan-8</link><description>A Dhaka court has set Jan 8 for the submission of the reinvestigation report in the case over the suicide of Aritry Adhikary, a ninth grader at Viqarunnisa Noon School and College.
Additional Chief Metropolitan Magistrate Jashita Islam passed the order on Wednesday, bdnews24.com reports. 
Th</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 14:55:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Netanyahu's coalition skips parliamentary vote backing Trump's Gaza plan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/netanyahus-coalition-skips-parliamentary-vote-backing-trumps-gaza-plan</link><description>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu's governing coalition skipped a parliamentary vote on Wednesday endorsing US President Donald Trump's plan to end the two-year war in Gaza.
The vote, proposed by opposition leader Yair Lapid, was largely symbolic as Netanyahu had already publicly backed th</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 15:10:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Writ petition filed seeking stay on election activities</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/writ-petition-filed-seeking-stay-on-election-activities</link><description>A writ petition was filed on Wednesday with the High Court seeking its directives to issue a stay order on the activities related to the upcoming national election.
General Secretary of the Bangladesh Congress Md. Earul Islam filed the writ petition with the HC bench concerned.
The petition also</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 15:25:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Primary teachers asked to withdraw work abstention, exam boycott programmes</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/primary-teachers-asked-to-withdraw-work-abstention-exam-boycott-programmes</link><description>Primary and Mass Education Ministry has directed the several organizations of assistant teachers of government primary schools to withdraw their work abstention and examination boycott programmes and return to duty.
An official handout issued here said the ministry has been informed about the work</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 15:40:29 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>