<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 15:52:06 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Property dispute among sons delays father’s funeral for 30 hours in Kurigram</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/property-dispute-among-sons-delays-fathers-funeral-for-30-hours-in-kurigram</link><description>A family feud over property inheritance has delayed a father’s funeral for nearly 30 hours in Kurigram's Nageshwari Upazila.
The funeral was later held following a written agreement mediated by village elders.
According to local residents, 75-year-old Azizar Rahman passed away due to old ag</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 12:59:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>'Curriculum review, technical modernisation among three education priorities'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/curriculum-review-technical-modernisation-among-three-education-priorities</link><description>Education Minister ANM Ehsanul Hoque Milon has announced three immediate priorities for the sector: creating conditions to bring students back to classrooms, reviewing the national curriculum and modernising technical education.
He revealed the plans while speaking to reporters at the Secretariat</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 13:14:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>British PM eyes next chapter in Dhaka-London partnership</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/british-pm-eyes-next-chapter-in-dhaka-london-partnership</link><description>British Prime Minister Keir Starmer has said he looks forward to working closely with Bangladesh Prime Minister Tarique Rahman to strengthen their partnership and advance shared priorities.
“I look forward to this next chapter in the partnership between our two countries,” he said in a</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 13:29:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Abul Kasem Khan appointed BUILD chairperson</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/abul-kasem-khan-appointed-build-chairperson</link><description>Abul Kasem Khan, Vice Chairman of AK Khan and Company Ltd, has been appointed the chairperson of Business Initiative Leading Development (BUILD) for the 2026-27 tenure.
Mr Khan, a member of the BUILD Trustee Board since 2020, assumed this leadership responsibility following a formal resolution by</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 13:44:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cultural Ministry takes elaborate programs on Shahid dibash</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cultural-ministry-takes-elaborate-programs-on-shahid-dibash</link><description>Cultural Affairs Ministry has taken elaborate programmes marking the Shahid Dibash and International Mother Language Day.
On the day the national flag will remain half mast at all government, semi-government, autonomous and private buildings and educational institutes on February 21.
Bangladesh T</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 13:59:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pakistan, US sign pact to redevelop New York's Roosevelt Hotel</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/pakistan-us-sign-pact-to-redevelop-new-yorks-roosevelt-hotel</link><description>Pakistan has signed an agreement with the United States to jointly redevelop New York's Roosevelt Hotel, according to four official documents reviewed by Reuters and two sources, in a deal between the two governments that will allow Islamabad to unlock the value of one its most prized overseas inve</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 14:14:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two killed, 10 injured in Madaripur road accident</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/two-killed-10-injured-in-madaripur-road-accident</link><description>Two people were killed and 10 others injured in a road accident in Melkai area of Dasar upazila in Madaripur district on Thursday afternoon.
According to eyewitnesses and police, a passenger bus of Imran Paribahan, traveling from Dhaka to Barishal, collided head-on with a BRTC bus coming from the</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 14:29:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Health Minister for on-site monitoring to ensure quality healthcare services</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/health-minister-for-on-site-monitoring-to-ensure-quality-healthcare-services</link><description>Health and Family Welfare Minister Sardar Md Sakhawat Hossain today (Thursday) announced that the government will conduct on-site monitoring at hospitals to ensure that doctors are providing proper and timely services to patients.
He made the announcement while speaking as the chief guest at an or</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 14:44:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Russia warns of escalating Iran tensions amid US military build up</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/russia-warns-of-escalating-iran-tensions-amid-us-military-build-up</link><description>Russia warned against an “unprecedented escalation of tension” around Iran on Thursday and urged restraint amid a US military build-up in the region that a senior American official said should be complete by mid-March.
US threats to bomb Iran, with the two sides far apart in talks on T</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 15:01:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>After Milano Cortina, Veneto's former governor pushes Venice bid for 2036, 2040 Games</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/after-milano-cortina-venetos-former-governor-pushes-venice-bid-for-2036-2040-games</link><description>In the wake of the Milano Cortina Olympics, the former governor of the Veneto region wants to put forward the city of Venice and the surrounding Italian regions as candidates to host the 2036 or 2040 Summer Olympics, with a focus on preserving the lagoon city.
The Winter Olympics were the first ex</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 15:16:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Consensus collections not extortion’: Rabiul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/consensual-roadside-collections-not-extortion-transport-minister</link><description>Road Transport and Communications Minister Shaikh Rabiul Alam has said that money collected from transport operators “on a consensual basis” should not be considered extortion.
Speaking to reporters at his office in the Secretariat on Thursday, he clarified: “What is called extor</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 15:31:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt initiates 'family card' pilot in 8 divisions</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/government-launched-family-card-pilot-in-8-divisions</link><description>The government has moved to launch the “family card” programme on a pilot basis across eight Upazilas in as many divisions of the country, fulfilling a key electoral pledge to strengthen social security for low-income households.
A 15-member ministerial committee, headed by New Finance</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 15:46:23 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>