<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 20:31:20 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Dozens of journalists honoured with South Asian Hero Award 2026</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/others/dozens-of-journalists-honoured-with-south-asian-hero-award-2026</link><description>The SAARC Foundation established in Sri Lanka has honoured various individuals from Nepal, India, Bangladesh and Sri Lanka who have contributed to democracy, human rights and freedom of the press and expression with the South Asian Hero Award 2026.
They were honoured during a special program organ</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 15:18:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chattogram-bound cargo ship sinks near Thailand’s Phuket, crew rescued</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/chattogram-bound-cargo-ship-sinks-near-thailands-phuket-crew-rescued</link><description>MV SEALLOYD ARC, a Chittagong Port-bound Panama-flagged vessel carrying cargo from Malaysia, has sunk off the coast of Thailand’s Phuket.
The vessel sank on Saturday afternoon.
All 16 Bangladeshi crew members aboard were rescued.
According to the ship’s Bangladeshi agent Alvi Lines B</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 15:33:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Voters secretly decided whom they’ll vote: Nahid</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/voters-secretly-decided-whom-theyll-vote-nahid</link><description>National Citizen Party (NCP) Convener Nahid Islam said on Sunday that the people of Bangladesh have already decided in secret whom they will vote for and are set to carry out that ‘great act’ on Thursday.
In a televised address on Bangladesh Television in the evening, Nahid, also a can</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 15:48:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India-EU trade deal: a brief review</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/india-eu-trade-deal-a-brief-review</link><description>The European Union (EU) and India is signing free trade agreement that both sides have hailed as 'the mother of all deals'. The agreement came together after over nearly two decades of intermittent negotiations and during a geo-economic crisis triggered by United States President Donald Trump's tra</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 16:19:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Partnership for a new global AI discourse</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/reviews/partnership-for-a-new-global-ai-discourse</link><description>The advent of artificial intelligence marks a consequential inflection point in the trajectory of technological evolution. With AI-powered capabilities now available in the palms of our hand, breakthroughs across sectors are reshaping how societies function, economies grow, and governments deliver</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 16:34:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Penchant for last-minute sensitive deals</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/penchant-for-last-minute-sensitive-deals</link><description>The Japan-Bangladesh Economic Partnership Agreement (EPA) signed between the two countries on Friday last is likely to take the bilateral cooperation and collaboration to a new high. From duty-free access to several thousands of Bangladeshi products and the vice versa to technology transfer as ensh</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 16:49:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>What sways the voter perception</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/what-sways-the-voter-perception</link><description>A local think tank, the Centre for Policy Dialogue (CPD), last Saturday (February 9) presented the findings of a survey it conducted on what the voters as well as political party representatives and candidates understood by the word 'development'. The result of the survey, as expected, was like thi</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 17:04:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Flagship EPA with Japan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/flagship-epa-with-japan</link><description>The Economic Partnership Agreement (EPA) between Bangladesh and Japan is significant not only because it marks Dhaka's first such deal with any country, but also because it offers a blueprint for trade diplomacy in the run-up to the LDC graduation. It appears that Bangladesh has managed to negotiat</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 17:19:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>14,000 selected as primary teachers after fast-track exams</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/14000-selected-as-primary-teachers-after-fast-track-exams</link><description>The Directorate of Primary Education has published the final results of recruitment for assistant teachers in government primary schools, appointing 14,384 candidates across 61 districts.
The results were released on Sunday night on the directorate’s website, just a week after the oral exams</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 17:34:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Interim govt defers dealing with power, energy graft to next govt</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/energy-advisor-fouzul-says-final-decisions-on-power-energy-sector-graft-left-to-next-government</link><description>Energy Advisor Muhammad Fouzul Kabir Khan has said the interim government has sent documents and information on corruption in the power and energy sector to the relevant authorities, leaving final decisions on the matter to the next government.
He spoke to reporters on Sunday evening at the Bidyut</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 17:49:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Polls spur money flows into mkt heightening inflation fear</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/polls-spur-money-flows-into-mkt-heightening-inflation-fear</link><description>Election-centric money flows from and into the banking system surge as Bangladesh goes to the polls soon, with a domino effect on the economy.As the money market and public wallets fatten, a worrisome major macroeconomic parameter-inflation-takes in some new heat, analysts say.



Apart from th</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 18:36:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique Rahman calls vigilance to protect voting rights</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-rahman-calls-vigilance-to-protect-voting-rights</link><description>BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman on Sunday urged people across the country to remain alert so that no one can snatch away their voting rights or manipulate the results of the national election through conspiracies.
“You must remain alert so that no one can turn your vote into a dummy election and</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 18:51:43 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>