<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 13:12:46 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Education ministry to announce junior scholarship results Wednesday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/education-ministry-to-announce-junior-scholarship-results-wednesday</link><description>The results of the junior scholarship examination will be published on Wednesday.
The Secondary and Higher Education Division will officially announce the results in the afternoon, bdnews24.com reports. 
Simultaneously, all education boards will release official gazettes listing students sel</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 11:00:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BB Governor assures policy support to resolve RMG crisis</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bb-governor-assures-policy-support-to-resolve-rmg-crisis</link><description>Bangladesh Bank (BB) Governor Dr Ahsan H. Mansur on Tuesday assured the leaders of the Bangladesh Garment Manufacturers and Exporters Association (BGMEA) of providing necessary policy support to overcome the current challenges facing the Ready-Made Garment (RMG) sector.
The governor gave the assur</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 11:15:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>FM Dr Khalilur set to leave for Saudi Arabia Wednesday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fm-dr-khalilur-set-to-leave-for-saudi-arabia-wednesday</link><description>Foreign Minister Dr Khalilur Rahman is scheduled to leave for Saudi Arabia early Wednesday, the first foreign trip since his appointment as the Foreign Minister.
Humayun Kabir, Adviser to Prime Minister Tarique Rahman, will also be part of the visit.
The Foreign Minister will attend a Foreign Min</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 11:30:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NBR intelligence gets new chief</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nbr-intelligence-gets-new-chief</link><description>In a major administrative reshuffle after the BNP took administrative office, the National Board of Revenue (NBR) has appointed a new director general to its Central Intelligence Cell (CIC).
The Commissioner of Taxes, Income Tax Intelligence and Investigation Unit, Mohammod Abdur Raquib, will lead</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 11:45:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Civil Aviation Minister orders measures to curb mosquito at airports</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/civil-aviation-minister-orders-measures-to-curb-mosquito-at-airports</link><description>Civil Aviation and Tourism Minister Afroza Khanam on Tuesday directed the authorities concerned to take steps immediately for mosquito control in and around airports in the country.
She also instructed the authorities to strengthen cleanliness measures at all airports across the country to ensure</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 12:00:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh reaffirms commitment to revitalise SAARC process</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-reaffirms-commitment-to-revitalise-saarc-process</link><description>Foreign Minister Dr Khalilur Rahman has reaffirmed Bangladesh’s unwavering support and commitment to revitalise SAARC process.
The Minister expressed Bangladesh’s readiness to take proactive initiatives to strengthen and revitalise SAARC.
He made the remarks when Secretary General of</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 11:31:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chinese envoy meets Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/chinese-envoy-meets-mirza-fakhrul-islam-alamgir</link><description>Chinese Ambassador to Dhaka Yao Wen on Tuesday met LGRD and Cooperatives Minister Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir at his office at the Secretariat.
Various bilateral issues of mutual interest were discussed during the meeting.
Local Government Division Secretary Md Rezaul Maksud Jahedi was present.</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 11:46:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Illegal gas line suspected in Cumilla blast</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/illegal-gas-line-suspected-in-cumilla-blast</link><description>A family’s Ramadan morning turned into a nightmare when an explosion tore through their Cumilla home before dawn, leaving two adults critically burned and a toddler among the injured. Authorities believe an illegal gas line running into the building may have caused the blast.
The incident oc</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 12:01:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>LPG price cut by Tk 15 for 12kg cylinder</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/lpg-price-cut-by-tk-15-for-12kg-cylinder</link><description>The price of a 12kg cylinder of liquefied petroleum gas (LPG), widely used for household cooking, has been reduced by Tk 15.
The new pricing sets the 12kg cylinder at Tk1,341 in retail, down from the previous price of Tk 1,356.
The Bangladesh Energy Regulatory Commission (BERC) said the new price</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 12:16:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Withdrawal of 1,202 more politically motivated cases approved: Home Minister</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/withdrawal-of-1202-more-politically-motivated-cases-approved-home-minister</link><description>Home Minister Salahuddin Ahmed on Tuesday said the government has approved the withdrawal of 1,202 more politically motivated cases filed over the past 17 years against opposition leaders, party activists and others.
Earlier approval was given for withdrawal 1,006 politically motivated cases, he t</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 12:31:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NBR forms committee to prepare budget for 2026-27 fiscal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/nbr-forms-committee-to-prepare-budget-for-2026-27-fiscal</link><description>The National Board of Revenue (NBR) has formed a budget committee by assigning additional responsibilities to four senior officials to support the preparation and coordination of the national budget for the 2026–27 fiscal year.
According to an official order issued on February 23 by the NBR</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 12:46:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chattogram-1 MP Nurul Amin hurt in car crash</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/chattogram-1-mp-nurul-amin-hurt-in-car-crash</link><description>Nurul Amin, the member of parliament from Chattogram-1 (Mirsarai), has been injured in a road accident in Feni while returning from Cumilla.
The accident occurred around 3:00 pm on Tuesday in Feni Sadar Upazila on the Dhaka-Chattogram Highway.
Locals rescued him after the accident and took him to</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 13:01:03 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>