<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 21:26:31 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Expat Bangladeshi Hajj pilgrims advised for health check-ups, vaccination</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/expat-bangladeshi-hajj-pilgrims-advised-for-health-check-ups-vaccination</link><description>The Ministry of Religious Affairs has issued directives regarding health check-ups and vaccination for registered expatriate Bangladeshi Hajj pilgrims for the 2026 Hajj.
For ensuring smooth Hajj management, registered expatriate Bangladeshi pilgrims intending to perform Hajj in 2026 must undergo t</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 15:59:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pakistan high commissioner meets Home Minister Salahuddin Ahmed</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/pakistan-high-commissioner-meets-home-minister-salahuddin-ahmed</link><description>Pakistan High Commissioner Imran Haider has met Home Minister Salahuddin Ahmed on the same day as the Indian envoy’s visit.
Indian High Commissioner Pranay Verma held talks with the minister at the home ministry on Sunday morning, and Imran met him at his office in the afternoon.
An evening</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 16:14:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gulshan, Mirpur, and Lalbagh get new DCs in DMP shake-up</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/gulshan-mirpur-and-lalbagh-get-new-dcs-in-dmp-shake-up</link><description>The Dhaka Metropolitan Police (DMP) has reshuffled the responsibilities of four officers with the rank of deputy commissioner.
Acting DMP Commissioner Md Sarwar issued an order to this effect on Sunday.
This marks the first internal shake-up in the DMP leadership since the newly elected governmen</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 16:29:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh may see heatwaves, Kalbaishakhi storms by late March</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/environment/bangladesh-may-see-heatwaves-kalbaishakhi-storms-by-late-march</link><description>Bangladesh is likely to experience its first heatwaves of the year in late March, coupled with the threat of severe nor'westers, commonly known as Kalbaishakhi storms.
The Bangladesh Meteorological Department (BMD) on Sunday forecast that one or two mild to moderate heatwaves might sweep over the</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 16:44:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Power supply to remain suspended in parts of Sylhet Monday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/power-supply-to-remain-suspended-in-parts-of-sylhet-monday</link><description>Power supply will remain suspended in various areas of Sylhet from 6:15 am to 11:00 am on Monday (March 2) due to reconductoring work on a transmission line.
Bangladesh Power Development Board (BPDB), Sylhet Sales and Distribution Division-3, disclosed the information on Sunday.
According to the</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 16:59:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No room for corrupt officials in Housing Ministry: Minister</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/no-room-for-corrupt-officials-in-housing-ministry-minister-zakaria-taher-sumon</link><description>Housing and Public Works Minister Zakaria Taher Sumon on Sunday warned that there is no room for corrupt officials in his ministry.
“The proper use of people’s tax money must be ensured, and development work must be completed within the stipulated time while maintaining quality standar</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 17:14:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Central bank and monetary policy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/central-bank-and-monetary-policy</link><description>For monetary policymakers, a Ph.D. in economics-by itself-is not enough; in fact, a formal degree in economics is not even the decisive criterion. The issue is not the title but the mastery of the craft. The current Federal Reserve Chair, Jerome Powell, is not an academic economist in the tradition</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 17:23:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Extortion, subscription and donation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/extortion-subscription-and-donation</link><description>Not all extortions are extortions. Collection of mutually agreed money from transport operators, according to a minister of the newly installed cabinet, is not extortion. He explains, "What is described as extortion on the roads" cannot be considered extortion because transport owners' association</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 17:38:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>War of attrition or for regime change?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/war-of-attrition-or-for-regime-change</link><description>The much-anticipated attack on Iran by the US finally took place last Saturday morning when people on the streets of Tehran, the country's capital, were on their way to work. But it was not only in Tehran, the attacks were carried out across the nation. As the air strike hit an elementary girls' sc</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 17:53:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Compensating small investors of merged banks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/compensating-small-investors-of-merged-banks</link><description>The government's decision to compensate small investors who purchased shares in the five distressed banks later merged into Sammilito Islami Bank is welcome. These private banks had been pushed to the brink of bankruptcy after years of systematic plundering of the bank loans during the Awami League</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 18:08:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US military says three of its troops killed in first Iran operation casualties</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/us-military-says-three-of-its-troops-killed-in-first-iran-operation-casualties</link><description>Three US service members have been killed and another five have been seriously wounded, in the first casualties of the unfolding US operations against Iran, the US military said on Sunday.
The casualties were announced on the second day of strikes by the US and Israel against Iran, which have plun</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 18:23:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Managing bad assets, reopening closed factories stressed</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/managing-bad-assets-reopening-closed-factories-stressed</link><description>Bangladesh Bank's new governor rolls out a to-do list focused on continued reforms to manage banking sector's distressed assets and reopen closed factories for economic pickup and job generation.
Bangladesh Bank will continue its reform programme to make banking services faster and more efficien</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 20:26:24 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>