<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 05:47:46 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Fire breaks out at AL office in Chandpur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/fire-breaks-out-at-al-office-in-chandpur</link><description>A fire broke out at a local office of the Bangladesh Awami League in Chandpur on Friday night.
The incident occurred around 10:00 pm at the party’s office located in the Kalibari area of the town.
Being informed, members of the Fire Service rushed to the spot brought the fire under control</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 23:59:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khosru, Moyeen, Reza Kibria among choices for fin min</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/khosru-moyeen-reza-kibria-among-choices-for-fin-min</link><description>A number of names have surfaced as finance minister of the new government set to be formed in a couple of days, led by chairman of Bangladesh Nationalists Party (BNP) Tarique Rahman.
The ministry of finance, the second-most-powerful government organ after the office of prime minister, is usually m</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 02:35:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Business leaders look to elected govt with cautious optimism</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/business-leaders-look-to-elected-govt-with-cautious-optimism</link><description>Business leaders look to the oncoming political government with cautious optimism that the transition would restore confidence among local and foreign investors and international buyers.
They expressed such optimism as the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) prepares to form the government with a c</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 02:50:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Daunting socioeconomic tasks await new govt</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/daunting-socioeconomic-tasks-await-new-govt</link><description>The Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP)-led alliance is going to form a new government with heavy socioeconomic burdens after its landslide victory in the 13th national election.
The $462 billion economy has recently been passing through a sluggish state due to the absence of an elected and democra</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 03:05:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>11 from apparel sector bag JS seats in 13th national polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/11-from-apparel-sector-bag-js-seats-in-13th-national-polls</link><description>At least 11 apparel and textile owners and their family members have won seats in the 13th Jatiya Sangsad (JS) elections, according to unofficial results, highlighting the growing political influence of business leaders from the country's readymade garment and textile sectors.
Most of the newly el</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 03:27:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat reviews party's performance after polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-reviews-partys-performance-after-polls</link><description>Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami (BJI) convened on Friday evening an emergency meeting of its Central Executive Council to review party's electoral performance and post-poll developments.
The BJI convened the meeting following growing internal pressure within the party over its electoral performance and</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 03:42:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gazette issued for newly elected MPs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/gazette-issued-for-newly-elected-members-of-parliament</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has gazetted all 297 declared winners of the general election, paving the way for their swearing-in as members of parliament.
On Friday night, after approving the results, the commission led by AMM Nasir Uddin authorised the notification, with EC Secretary Akhtar Ahmed</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 03:57:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two killed 'while making bombs' in Chapainawabganj</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/two-killed-while-making-bombs-in-chapainawabganj</link><description>Two people were killed and three others injured in an explosion while they were allegedly making bombs in Sadar upazila of Chapainawabganj district early Saturday.
The identities of the deceased could not be known immediately, according to a UNB report.
The explosion occurred around 5:00 am in Bh</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 04:12:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Why Bangladesh needs an AI-driven primary healthcare revolution</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/analysis/why-bangladesh-needs-an-ai-driven-primary-healthcare-revolution</link><description>Bangladesh's healthcare system has achieved notable success over the decades, particularly in immunization, maternal health, and infectious disease control. These accomplishments are widely recognized both nationally and internationally. Yet, despite this progress, foundational weakness continues t</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 04:27:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The affable relationship between crows and humans</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/analysis/the-affable-relationship-between-crows-and-humans</link><description>Of the birds that live close to human habitation, crow is one. Although unlike sparrows which fabricate their nests in strategic corner of a house, the clever crows build their nests not exactly within a residence but at more strategic points such as on a tree or electric poles. Not far from human</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 04:42:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Refiners seek further upward adjustment of edible oil prices</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/refiners-seek-further-upward-adjustment-of-edible-oil-prices</link><description>Local refiners have sought an upward adjustment of edible oil prices amid forecast of decline in prices of the item in the international market, sources said.
In a letter sent to Ministry of Commerce (MoC), the Bangladesh Vegetable Oil Refiners' and Vanaspati Manufacturers' Association (BVORVMA) s</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 04:57:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Weekly market review: Investor optimism drives stocks higher</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/weekly-market-review-investor-optimism-drives-stocks-higher-1</link><description>The benchmark index of the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) extended its bullish run for a fourth week in a row, driven by expectations of a favourable market outlook amid anticipated post-election political clarity.
Market analysts said investor sentiment remained upbeat just before the national electi</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 05:12:27 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>