<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 10:26:37 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>MOHAMMADPUR DOUBLE MURDER: Burn mark, past record help police arrest killer</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/mohammadpur-double-murder-burn-mark-past-record-help-police-arrest-killer</link><description>The Dhaka Metropolitan Police (DMP) said burn mark and previous theft record helped police to identify and arrest domestic help Ayesha. She allegedly killed her employer, Laila Afroz, and her 15-year-old daughter, Nafisa Nawal Binte Aziz, at their Mohammadpur home following a confrontation over ste</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 04:08:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tk 94.28b loan fraud: ACC to sue S Alam, Janata officials</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tk-9428b-loan-fraud-acc-to-sue-s-alam-janata-officials</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) Thursday approved five separate cases against multiple S Alam Group entities and their officials, as well as Janata Bank officials, for allegedly embezzling Tk 94.28 billion through loan irregularities, misuse of authority, and criminal breach of trust.
Accordi</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 04:23:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Godkhali florists dream big as new season approaching</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/godkhali-florists-dream-big-as-new-season-approaching</link><description>BENAPOLE, Dec 11: Known as the "Flower Capital" of Bangladesh, Godkhali in Jashore is once again buzzing with activities as the new season bringing along five back-to-back special occasions like Victory Day, Christmas, Thirty First Night, Valentine's Day and Mother Langue Day is approaching.
With</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 04:38:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Aman paddy harvest in Sylhet nearing end, 80pc already done</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/aman-paddy-harvest-in-sylhet-nearing-end-80pc-already-done</link><description>SYLHET, Dec 11: Farmers in the Sylhet region are in the midst of a busy and successful Aman paddy harvest. Over 80 per cent of the crop has already been harvested, according to farmers and officials from various upazilas.
Ataur Rahman Mia, a farmer from Baushi in Golapganj upazila, said that this</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 04:53:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Thai PM moves to dissolve parliament</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/thai-pm-moves-to-dissolve-parliament</link><description>Thailand's Prime Minister Anutin Charnvirakul announced on Thursday that he is "returning power to the people," moving to dissolve parliament and clear the way for elections earlier than previously anticipated.
Government spokesperson Siripong Angkasakulkiat told Reuters the move followed a disagr</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 05:08:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Suspect in Charlie Kirk killing appears in court, judge mulls media access</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/suspect-in-charlie-kirk-killing-appears-in-court-judge-mulls-media-access</link><description>Tyler Robinson, the accused killer of conservative activist Charlie Kirk, made his first in-person court appearance on Thursday as a judge heard arguments on what level of media access should be allowed in the high-profile criminal case.
Robinson, wearing a dress shirt and striped tie, talked with</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 05:23:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Deepal Abeywickrema elected Senior Vice President of FICCI</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/deepal-abeywickrema-elected-senior-vice-president-of-ficci</link><description>Mr. Deepal Abeywickrema, Chairman and Managing Director of Nestlé Bangladesh PLC, has been elected as Senior Vice-President of the Foreign Investors' Chamber of Commerce &amp; Industry (FICCI).
This marks his second tenure in this leadership role, following his impactful service in the same pos</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 06:15:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ADB approves 100m USD loan to boost financial access for women entrepreneurs in India</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/adb-approves-100m-usd-loan-to-boost-financial-access-for-women-entrepreneurs-in-india</link><description>The Asian Development Bank (ADB) on Friday said it has signed a 100-million-U.S.-dollar loan agreement with Five-Star Business Finance Limited (FBFL) to expand access to micro, small, and medium-sized enterprises (MSMEs) business loans for women borrowers from lower-income groups in India.
T</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 06:30:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Asif Mahmud announces independent bid for Dhaka-10 in upcoming election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/asif-mahmud-announces-independent-bid-for-dhaka-10-in-upcoming-election</link><description>Asif Mahmud Shojib Bhuyain, who recently resigned as a student advisor to the interim government, has announced that he will contest the upcoming 13th national election as an independent candidate from the Dhaka-10 constituency.
He announced in a video posted on his Facebook page on Saturday, repo</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 07:15:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two Bangladeshis die after 'drinking petrol' on migrant boat bound for Greece</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/two-bangladeshis-die-after-drinking-petrol-on-migrant-boat-bound-for-greece</link><description>Two Bangladeshi migrants have reportedly died after mistakenly drinking petrol during a journey by sea from Libya to Greece.
According to the Bangladesh Embassy in Athens, the group had gone without food for nearly two days and, in a state of extreme hunger and thirst, drank petrol, believing it t</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 07:30:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Candidates must file nomination in person</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/candidates-must-file-nomination-in-person</link><description>Intending candidates of the 13th Jatiya Sangsad election must submit their nomination papers to the returning officers (ROs) or assistant returning officers (AROs) in person, said the Election Commission (EC) in a circular.
The circular, issued on Friday, said the candidates must appear in person</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 08:31:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Osman Hadi, Inquilab Mancha member and Dhaka-8 hopeful, shot in Bijoynagar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/osman-hadi-inquilab-mancha-member-and-dhaka-8-hopeful-shot-in-bijoynagar</link><description>Osman Hadi, an independent candidate who planned to contest the Dhaka-8 parliamentary seat in the upcoming national election, has been shot.
The incident occurred in Dhaka's Bijoynagar after Jummah prayers on Friday. He has been taken to Dhaka Medical College Hospital for treatment, reports bdnews</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 09:46:28 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>