<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 15:25:11 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Russian air attack on Ukraine kills three and sparks sweeping outages</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/russian-air-attack-on-ukraine-kills-three-and-sparks-sweeping-outages</link><description>Russian missile and drone attacks killed at least three Ukrainians including a child on Tuesday, triggering widespread emergency power cuts and prompting neighbouring Poland to scramble jets.
The attacks, days after another round of U.S.-led talks to end the nearly four-year-old war, hit energy fa</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 13:12:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh separates trade from politics in managing ties with India: Finance adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-separates-trade-from-politics-in-managing-ties-with-india-finance-adviser</link><description>Finance Adviser Dr Salehuddin Ahmed on Tuesday said Bangladesh manages its relationship with India by clearly separating economic interests from political rhetoric, stressing that trade decisions are guided by competitiveness and national interest rather than diplomatic sensitivities.
“Our t</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 13:27:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pay rise for primary headteachers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/government-approves-grade-10-pay-for-headteachers</link><description>The government has raised the salaries of headteachers at government primary schools to grade 10, granting them the rank of gazetted officers.
The Ministry of Primary and Mass Education moved their pay one step up from grade 11, according to a media statement on Tuesday.
The new pay scale will be</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 13:42:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NRBC Bank holds workshop on reporting under Bangladesh Bank’s online monitoring system</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/nrbc-bank-holds-workshop-on-reporting-under-bangladesh-banks-online-monitoring-system</link><description>NRBC Bank organized a workshop on Reporting to Online Import Monitoring System (OIMS) and Online Export Monitoring System (OEMS) introduced by Bangladesh Bank, according to a press release.
The workshop was held on Sunday, 21 December 2025, at the Human Resource and Training Development Centre (HR</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 13:57:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt approves import of 1 lakh tonnes rice from India, Pakistan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/govt-approves-import-of-1-lakh-tonnes-rice-from-india-pakistan</link><description>The government has approved several proposals including imports of rice, edible oil and lentils to strengthen food security and stabilise prices ahead of the holy month of Ramadan.
The approvals were given at a meeting of the Advisers Council Committee on Government Purchase, on Tuesday at the Cab</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 13:14:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka presses Delhi on mission security</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-seeks-swift-action-after-india-pledges-protection-of-diplomatic-missions</link><description>In response to protests targeting Bangladesh’s diplomatic missions in India, Dhaka has sought tangible follow-up to a security pledge from New Delhi.
On Tuesday afternoon, foreign ministry spokesperson SM Mahbubul Alam said the high commissioner of India in Dhaka was summoned, and the interi</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 13:29:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IFIC Bank holds day-long event on ‘Cashless Bangladesh Initiative’ in Jashore</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ific-bank-holds-day-long-event-on-cashless-bangladesh-initiative-in-jashore</link><description>Under the initiative of Bangladesh Bank, and with IFIC Bank PLC as the lead bank, a series of day-long programs were organized in Jeshore to expand the activities of the “Cashless Bangladesh Initiative.”
According to a press release, the event was held on Tuesday at the Jeshore Softwar</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 13:44:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DSE fails to sustain early gains, CSE extends rally</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/dse-fails-to-sustain-early-gains-cse-extends-rally</link><description>Bangladesh’s stock market opened on a positive note on Tuesday, the third trading day of the week, but the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) failed to hold the gains by the end of the session, while the upward trend continued at the Chittagong Stock Exchange (CSE).
At the DSE, the benchmark index D</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 13:59:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Iraq says gas supplies from Iran have been halted</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/iraq-says-gas-supplies-from-iran-have-been-halted</link><description>Iraq’s supply of gas from Iran has been halted, the electricity ministry said on Tuesday, adding that the stoppage was due to the shutdown of some generating units and load shedding at others.
The ministry reported that 4,000 to 4,500 megawatts of power has been lost from the electrical syst</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 14:14:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BRAC Bank completes month-long intensive training for CMSMEs in Sirajganj</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/brac-bank-completes-month-long-intensive-training-for-cmsmes-in-sirajganj</link><description>BRAC Bank, with support from the Ministry of Finance and Bangladesh Bank, has completed a month-long intensive training for the promising entrepreneurs in the cottage, micro, small and medium enterprises (CMSMEs) sector in Sirajganj.
The Finance Division of the Ministry of Finance has initiated a</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 14:29:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh received $2.46b remittance in 22 days of December</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh-received-246-billion-remittance-in-22-days-of-december</link><description>The upward trend in remittances sent by Bangladesh expatriates has continued in December, with receiving over US $2.42 billion in 22 days of the month.
Bangladesh received $15.46 billion inward remittance so far in the current fiscal year FY 2025-26.
Blessings on the remittance, the gross forex r</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 14:44:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Education adviser visits family of Dipu Chandra Das</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/education-adviser-visits-family-of-dipu-chandra-das</link><description>The Office of the Chief Adviser has expressed its profound sorrow over the killing of factory worker Dipu Chandra Das in Mymensingh and extended its deepest condolences to his family.
On behalf of the government, Education Adviser Professor C R Abrar visited the bereaved family in Mymensingh on Tu</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 14:59:11 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>