<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 11:16:43 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>EC to begin political dialogues this week</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-to-begin-political-dialogues-this-week</link><description>Moving into the election mode, the Election Commission will start a series of dialogues with registered political parties this week to lay the groundwork for the upcoming national election scheduled for February.
But the political parties would be invited in groups to join the discussions due to t</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 07:55:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US sold sniper rifles to Brazil police unit tied to deadly raid</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/us-sold-sniper-rifles-to-brazil-police-unit-tied-to-deadly-raid</link><description>The US government approved a sale of sniper rifles to a deadly police unit in Brazil last year, overriding concerns from the US ambassador and other diplomats that the arms could be used in extrajudicial killings, according to three current and former US officials and documents seen by Reuters.
Th</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 08:10:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Primary teachers begin nonstop sit-in for 10th grade pay</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/primary-teachers-begin-nonstop-sit-in-for-10th-grade-pay</link><description>Assistant teachers from government primary schools have launched a continuous sit-in in Dhaka, demanding salaries under the 10th pay grade, along with two other demands.
The programme began on Saturday morning at the Central Shaheed Minar, where teachers from across the country converged to press</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 08:25:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Amir Khosru urges political parties not to take to streets over referendum demand</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/amir-khosru-urges-political-parties-not-to-take-to-streets-over-referendum-demand</link><description>BNP Standing Committee member Amir Khosru Mahmud Chowdhury has said that the interim government was formed under the existing Constitution, which does not allow for a referendum.
He said political parties should focus on winning the next general election and, once in Parliament, amend the Constitu</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 08:10:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Investigation underway after blast in front of St Mary’s Cathedral Church: Police</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/investigation-underway-after-blast-in-front-of-st-marys-cathedral-church-police</link><description>Law enforcement agencies are investigating the crude bomb blasts outside St Mary’s Cathedral in Dhaka’s Kakrail area, DMP’s DC (Media) Talebur Rahman said on Saturday.
Police are reviewing CCTV footage from nearby areas to trace the perpetrators, he added.
A bomb disposal team a</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 08:25:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Political parties must take firm stance on AL: Shafiqul Alam</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/political-parties-must-take-firm-stance-on-al-shafiqul-alam</link><description>Chief Adviser's Press Secretary Shafiqul Alam today said political parties must adopt a firm and unified stance on the fallen fascist Awami League, calling its recent move an "existential threat" to the nation's democratic future.
"It's time for all political parties to take a clear position regar</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 08:40:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US judge rules Trump illegally ordered National Guard to Portland, Oregon</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/us-judge-rules-trump-illegally-ordered-national-guard-to-portland-oregon</link><description>US President Donald Trump unlawfully ordered National Guard troops to Portland, Oregon, a federal judge ruled Friday in a legal setback to the administration's use of the military in American cities.
The ruling by US District Judge Karin Immergut is the first to permanently block Trump's use of mi</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 08:55:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tongi cotton warehouse fire under control after 1.5 hours</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tongi-cotton-warehouse-fire-under-control-after-15-hours</link><description>Emergency workers have taken control of a fire that broke out at a cotton warehouse in Gazipur's Tongi.
The fire reportedly broke out at 11:45am on Saturday. Seven firefighting units from Tongi, Uttara and Gazipur subsequently rushed to the tin-roofed warehouse and doused the flames around 1:30p</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 09:10:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shammo 'killed while trying to stop drug dealers from selling marijuana' at Suhrawardy Udyan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/shammo-killed-while-trying-to-stop-drug-dealers-from-selling-marijuana-at-suhrawardy-udyan</link><description>Six months after the fatal stabbing of Dhaka University student SM Shahriar Alam Shammo, investigators have found drug peddlers responsible for the killing.
In its chargesheet over the incident, police said Shammo, a leader of the Jatiyatabadi Chhatra Dal, and his friends were attacked by drug dea</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 09:25:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump says no US government official will attend G20 summit in South Africa</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/trump-says-no-us-government-official-will-attend-g20-summit-in-south-africa</link><description>President Donald Trump said on Friday that no US government official would attend the Group of 20 summit in South Africa later this month, because of what he said were "human rights abuses" taking place in the country.
South Africa's foreign ministry described the decision as "regrettable" and rep</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 09:57:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ADB to organize Business Opportunities Seminar on Nov 12</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/adb-to-organize-business-opportunities-seminar-on-nov-12</link><description>The Asian Development Bank (ADB) will organize a Business Opportunities Seminar (BOS) on November 12, 2025, at the Bangladesh China Friendship Conference Center (BCFCC) in the capital.
The BOS will be held in Dhaka with active support from the Economic Relations Division (ERD) in collaboration wit</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 10:12:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Attorney General seeks political parties' pledge for formulating anti-discrimination act</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/attorney-general-seeks-political-parties-pledge-for-formulating-anti-discrimination-act</link><description>Attorney General (AG) Md Asaduzzaman at a programme today (Saturday) sought political parties' pledge for formulating an anti-discrimination act. "Political parties will not get our votes unless they make a commitment to formulate this act. We need a strong act as a vague act cannot provide a</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 10:27:15 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>