<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 01:45:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>NCP, Samajtantrik Dal get final registration from EC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ncp-samajtantrik-dal-get-final-registration-from-ec</link><description>The National Citizen Party and Bangladesh Samajtantrik Dal (Marxist) have received final registration from the Election Commission (EC).
As no objections were filed against the parties, the EC issued the official gazette on Monday.
With this, both parties will be able to contest the upcoming elec</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 16:00:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>35.2pc growth of remittance inflow till Nov 16</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/352pc-growth-of-remittance-inflow-till-nov-16</link><description>Inflow of remittances witnessed a year-on-year growth of 35.2 percent reaching US$1,697 million in the 16 days of November, according to the latest data of Bangladesh Bank (BB) issued on Monday.
Last year, during the same period, the country's remittance inflow was $1,255 million, reports BSS.
Du</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 16:15:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Political parties say EC lacks resolve, independence to deliver credible polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/political-parties-say-ec-lacks-resolve-independence-to-deliver-credible-polls</link><description>Political parties taking part in the Election Commission’s ongoing dialogues have delivered a blunt warning: without independence and resolve, the commission cannot hope to deliver a credible national election.
Their criticism on Monday laid bare a widening crisis of confidence in the body e</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 16:30:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>As Mamdani rises, Bangladeshi diaspora shines in America</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/as-mamdani-rises-bangladeshi-diaspora-shines-in-america</link><description>When Zohran Kwame Mamdani, a 34-year-old Democratic Socialist steps before a crowd in Queens-microphone in hand, voice steady-the moment feels bigger than a rally. Behind him stand tenants, students, taxi drivers, and small business owners, many sharing immigrant roots like his own. The son of Indi</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 16:30:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Grabbing public land with impunity</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/grabbing-public-land-with-impunity</link><description>One may recall the fury of the forest grabbers when they attacked government officials including members of the joint-forces in November last year as the latter carried out an eviction drive at Rajbari in Sreepur upazila of Gazipur to recover forestland. During the attack, 10 people including an as</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 16:45:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Misuse of climate fund must be stopped</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/misuse-of-climate-fund-must-be-stopped</link><description>Bangladesh, one of the world's most climate-exposed nations, has recently got a sobering reminder how vulnerable its own governance systems remains in the face of an unfolding planetary emergency. The latest findings of the Transparency International Bangladesh (TIB) reveal that more than half of t</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 17:00:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Child labour and development parameter</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/child-labour-and-development-parameter</link><description>The multiple indicator cluster survey (MICS) carried out by the Bangladesh Bureau of statistics (BBS) has presented an alarming picture of child labour and various negative aspects related to it. As high as 9.2 per cent children in the age bracket of 5-17 are compelled to perform tasks requiring ph</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 17:15:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UN rights body regrets Hasina’s death sentence, calls verdict important for victims</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/un-rights-body-regrets-hasinas-death-sentence-calls-verdict-important-for-victims</link><description>The United Nations human rights body on Monday said they "regret" the imposition of the death penalty, which they oppose in all circumstances but described the verdict as an important moment for victims of the grave violations committed during the suppression of protests last year.
“The hand</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 17:30:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP hails Hasina’s death sentence verdict, says justice served</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-hails-hasinas-death-sentence-verdict-says-justice-served</link><description>BNP on Monday night said it believes justice has been served through the International Crimes Tribunal’s verdict sentencing deposed Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina to death for crimes against humanity committed during the July-August Uprising.
“After a long judicial process, following int</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 18:01:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCSA urges media not to air speeches of convicted persons</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ncsa-urges-media-not-to-air-speeches-of-convicted-persons</link><description>National Cyber Security Agency (NCSA) has requested not to air the speech of the convicted persons on the media for the interest of the national security.
Post, Telecommunication and Information Technology Affairs Ministry’s release said today (Monday), BSS reports. 
The release said,</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 18:16:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ousted PM Hasina sentenced to death</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ousted-pm-hasina-sentenced-to-death</link><description>Bangladesh's ousted prime minister Sheikh Hasina was Monday sentenced to death for the "crimes against humanity" committed during the July-August mass uprising last year that toppled her government. In its verdict telecast live, the International Crimes Tribunal-1 (ICT-1) in Dhaka also handed dow</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 18:31:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Swiss logistics giant to operate Pangaon Inland Container Terminal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/swiss-logistics-giant-to-operate-pangaon-inland-container-terminal</link><description>MEDLOG, a Switzerland-based world leader in inland logistics, will to manage and operate the Pangaon Inland Container Terminal (PICT) near Dhaka for 22 years.
A concession agreement was signed to this end between Chittagong Port Authority (CPA) and MEDLOG Bangladesh Private Ltd on Monday (November</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 20:00:09 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>