<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 09:23:52 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>MPO teachers’ housing allowance hiked to 7.5% of salary from Nov, set to double in July</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/mpo-teachers-housing-allowance-hiked-to-75-of-salary-from-nov-set-to-double-in-july</link><description>The government has once again hiked the house rent allowance for teachers and employees at educational institutions under the monthly pay order (MPO) scheme in the face of protests, reports bdnews24.com.
On Tuesday, the Ministry of Finance announced that it had agreed to raise the housing allowanc</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 06:38:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC plans central cell to combat AI misuse during polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ec-plans-central-cell-to-combat-ai-misuse-during-polls</link><description>Chief Election Commissioner (CEC) A M M Nasir Uddin today said the Election Commission (EC) has planned to establish a central cell to combat artificial intelligence (AI) generated misinformation and disinformation during the upcoming national elections.
He said a centrally coordinated cell would</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 06:53:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Road crashes claim 116,726 lives in 12 years</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/road-crashes-claim-116726-lives-in-12-years</link><description>Bangladesh has witnessed a staggering 116,726 deaths and 165,021 injuries in 67,890 road accidents over the past 12 years, according to the Bangladesh Jatri Kalyan Samiti (BJKS).
The organisation blamed widespread corruption, policy failures, and chronic mismanagement in the transport sector for w</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 07:08:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Stocks witness early gains at both bourses</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/stocks-witness-early-gains-at-both-bourses</link><description>Indices at both the Dhaka and Chattogram stock exchanges witnessed an upward trend in the first hour of trading on Tuesday, with most companies seeing price gains.
During the first hour of trading, the key index of the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE), DSEX, rose by 40 points.
The Shariah-based index,</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 07:38:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BRSN calls for road management reform commission, presents 20-point demand</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/brsn-calls-for-road-management-reform-commission-presents-20-point-demand</link><description>The Bangladesh Road Safety Network (BRSN) has urged the government to form a Road Management Reform Commission to ensure sustainable and safe transport systems across the country, saying that the country’s road sector remains plagued by mismanagement, corruption, and poor coordination even af</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 07:53:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>MPO teachers ‘satisfied’ with house rent hike, suspend protests</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/mpo-teachers-satisfied-with-house-rent-hike-suspend-protests</link><description>The interim government has decided to increase the house rent allowance of teachers and employees of MPO-listed (Monthly Pay Order) non-government educational institutions to 15 per cent, following continuous demonstrations by teachers pressing for a three-point demand.
After an understanding was</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 08:38:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pharma industry fears Tk 40 billion lose in Dhaka airport fire</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/pharma-industry-fears-tk-40-billion-lose-in-dhaka-airport-fire</link><description>The Bangladesh Association of Pharmaceutical Industries (BAPI) has said the country's pharmaceutical industry faces a potential financial loss of around Tk 40 billion due to the fire in the Cargo Village at Dhaka's Shahjalal International Airport.
Leaders of the organisation presented the figure</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 08:53:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CAAB chief sidesteps responsibility for Dhaka airport blaze</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/caab-chief-sidesteps-responsibility-for-dhaka-airport-blaze</link><description>Air Vice Marshal Md Mostafa Mahmood Siddiq, chairman of the Civil Aviation Authority of Bangladesh (CAAB), has refused to take the blame for the blaze at the import cargo complex of Dhaka's Shahjalal International Airport.
Although the building belongs to the CAAB, operations inside are conducted</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 09:23:52 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>