<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 09:20:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Temporary market makes a comeback in Sylhet city</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/temporary-market-makes-a-comeback-in-sylhet-city</link><description>Lighting, water, sanitation and security arrangements have been ensured at the Laldighirpar field (market) in Sylhet city, so that street vendors can continue their trade operations there, clearing all the busy footpaths and streets of the city - but very few were seen relocating on Monday.
Vendor</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 07:38:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CMSMEs struggle to realise full potential</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/cmsmes-struggle-to-realise-full-potential</link><description>Limited access to finance, inadequate infrastructure, shortage of skilled manpower, insufficient policy support coupled with stringent conditions are the main bottlenecks to utilise the full potential of Bangladesh's Cottage, Micro, Small and Medium Enterprises (CMSME), said speakers at a programme</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 06:08:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Saudi-Bangladesh trade body gets licence</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/saudi-bangladesh-trade-body-gets-licence</link><description>The government has approved a licence for a new trade body named "Saudi Arabia-Bangladesh Chamber of Commerce &amp; Industry" which is expected to further strengthen the bilateral ties between the two nations.
The commerce ministry recently issued a notification in this regard, according to an officia</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 06:23:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Steelmakers reel from setbacks yet foresee rebound</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/steelmakers-reel-from-setbacks-yet-foresee-rebound</link><description>Bangladesh's steelmakers face a short-term setback as a domino effect of a sluggish growth in the national economy and a draught in investment. The steel industry is passing through a gamut of adversities like higher operational costs, weak demand and tax burden, insiders say.
Yet, this downside d</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 06:38:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Repatriation of Rohingyas is ‘only viable solution’, CA tells UN envoy on Myanmar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/repatriation-of-rohingyas-is-only-viable-solution-ca-tells-un-envoy-on-myanmar</link><description>Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus has said that the repatriation of the Rohingya people to their homeland is the only viable solution to the protracted crisis.
“The return of the Rohingya people to their homeland is the only viable solution. There is no alternative,” he said durin</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 06:53:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US deports 100 Iranians after deal with Tehran, NYT says</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/us-deports-100-iranians-after-deal-with-tehran-nyt-says</link><description>The United States is deporting around 100 Iranians back to Iran, the New York Times reported on Tuesday, citing two senior Iranian officials involved in the negotiations and a US official with knowledge of the plans.
A US-chartered flight took off from Louisiana on Monday and was scheduled to arri</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 07:08:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hasina mass murderer, evidence against her overwhelming: Shafiqul Alam</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hasina-mass-murderer-evidence-against-her-overwhelming-shafiqul-alam</link><description>Chief Adviser’s Press Secretary Shafiqul Alam on Tuesday accused former Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina of mass murder, citing overwhelming evidence, and defended the ban on Awami League activities while warning that her defenders bear blood on their hands.
"Sooner or later, this public v</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 07:23:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Six-month wait and no payout yet for unitholders</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/six-month-wait-and-no-payout-yet-for-unitholders</link><description>Unitholders of Asian Tiger Sandhani Life Growth Fund have yet to receive their dues, even six months after the fund's closure, with uncertainty deepening as the delay drags on.
The trustee of the mutual fund said the payment could not be made earlier because it took time to secure regulatory appro</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 07:53:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hindu community celebrates Kumari Puja</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hindu-community-celebrates-kumari-puja</link><description>Hindus across the country celebrated Kumari Puja on the Maha Ashtami on Tuesday as part of the five-day Durga Puja.
The main attraction of Maha Ashtami is Kumari Puja where a pre-pubescent girl is worshipped as “Mother Goddess”.
In the capital city, hundreds of Hindu devotees offered</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 08:23:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Peaceful election is now biggest challenge for police, says IGP Baharul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/peaceful-election-is-now-biggest-challenge-for-police-says-igp-baharul</link><description>Inspector General of Police (IGP) Baharul Alam believes successfully conducting the parliamentary election is the force’s biggest challenge right now.
He made the statement on Tuesday in response to a question from journalists at a briefing held at the Police Headquarters.
The police chief</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 08:38:47 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>