<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 05:40:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>UK PM Starmer visits India to build business ties after clinching trade deal</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/uk-pm-starmer-visits-india-to-build-business-ties-after-clinching-trade-deal</link><description>British Prime Minister Keir Starmer begins a two-day visit to India on Wednesday, joined by over a hundred leaders from the business, culture and university sectors in an effort to promote a recently signed trade deal.
Britain and India signed a free trade agreement in July during a visit by India</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 02:27:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gold builds on historic rally, soars past $4,000 an ounce for first time</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/gold-builds-on-historic-rally-soars-past-4000-an-ounce-for-first-time</link><description>Gold pushed through $4,000 an ounce to hit a record on Wednesday, driven by investors seeking safety from mounting economic and geopolitical uncertainty, alongside expectations of further interest rate cuts by the US Federal Reserve.
Spot gold was up 0.7% at $4,011.18 per ounce by 0300 GMT US gold</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 03:12:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Why new era of fitness more focused on rewards and badges than burning calories</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/why-new-era-of-fitness-more-focused-on-rewards-and-badges-than-burning-calories</link><description>The halls of gymnasiums have been the ultimate location for fitness enthusiasts for decades. With rows of treadmills and racks of weights, the gym stood as the temple of fitness. However, fitness centres and high-energy group classes have undergone a radical transformation in recent years.
There h</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 03:27:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka's changes seen through lenses of young artists</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/dhakas-changes-seen-through-lenses-of-young-artists</link><description>Dhaka has never stood still. It has grown, shifted, and reinvented itself through the rise and fall of empires, the flow of trade, and the everyday lives of its people. One can read its story in history books, but perhaps more vividly, can see it on canvas - in paintings that hold the city's memori</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 03:42:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ichamati River on its last leg for encroachment, pollution</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/ichamati-river-on-its-last-leg-for-encroachment-pollution</link><description>MANIKGANJ, Oct 07: The Ichamati River, which was once a lifeline for farmers and fishermen, is now battling to exist in Harirampur upazila of Manikganj district due to
unhindered encroachment and pollution by an unscrupulous quarter.
Once its flowing waters irrigated paddy fields and filled fishe</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 03:57:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Flood situation improves in Lalmonirhat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/flood-situation-improves-in-lalmonirhat</link><description>LALMONIRHAT, Oct 07: Flood situation in Lalmonirhat's five upazilas has significantly improved in the last 24 hours to Tuesday as water receded in the Teesta and Dharla river basin areas and also due to no rainfall, or onrush of upstream waters in the greater Rangpur region.
Sources at the Teesta</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 04:12:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ecuador president's motorcade attacked by crowd throwing rocks, five detained</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/ecuador-presidents-motorcade-attacked-by-crowd-throwing-rocks-five-detained</link><description>Ecuadorean President Daniel Noboa escaped injury after his car was attacked by a crowd throwing rocks on Tuesday, in what a top minister said was an assassination attempt that had left signs of bullet damage on the vehicle.
Environment and Energy Minister Ines Manzano, who filed a formal report of</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 04:27:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>All stranded Everest hikers evacuated from remote Tibetan valley</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/all-stranded-everest-hikers-evacuated-from-remote-tibetan-valley</link><description>Rescuers guided all of the remaining trekkers near the east face of Everest in Tibet to safety on Tuesday, including hundreds of local guides and yak herders, authorities said, ending one of the largest search-and-rescue operations in the region.
Hundreds of hikers were stranded in deep snow over</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 04:42:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shahidul Alam kidnapped by Israeli forces</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/shahidul-alam-kidnapped-by-israeli-forces</link><description>Shahidul Alam, a Bangladeshi photographer, writer and managing director of Drik, has been kidnapped by Israeli forces from the Freedom Flotilla Coalition heading to Gaza.
He announced this in a video message on his verified Facebook page on Wednesday (October 8). according to local news reports.&amp;n</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 04:57:44 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>