<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 17:19:17 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Chief Adviser seeks prayers for Khaleda Zia’s recovery</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/chief-adviser-seeks-prayers-for-khaleda-zias-recovery</link><description>Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus has expressed deep concern over the current health condition of former Prime Minister and BNP Chairperson Begum Khaleda Zia and sought prayers from the nation for her quick recovery.
Professor Yunus has been regularly monitoring Khaleda Zia’s health upd</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 14:30:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two killed as bus hits truck on Dhaka-Chattogram highway</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/two-killed-as-bus-hits-truck-on-dhaka-chattogram-highway</link><description>Two people were killed and two others seriously injured Friday afternoon when a passenger bus collided with a truck carrying bricks on the Dhaka-Chattogram Highway in Daudkandi, Cumilla police said.
The accident occurred in the Hugulia area of Daudkandi while a Starline bus traveling toward Chatto</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 14:45:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Belarus leader visits Myanmar ahead of disputed election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/belarus-leader-visits-myanmar-ahead-of-disputed-election</link><description>Belarusian President Alexander Lukashenko arrived in Myanmar on a goodwill visit, state media reported Friday, becoming only the second foreign leader to set foot in the country since the military seized power in 2021.
The trip comes weeks before a national election widely dismissed by critics as</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 15:00:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shift 20pc of transport to rail, waterways to reduce road pressure: Fouzul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/shift-20pc-of-transport-to-rail-waterways-to-reduce-road-pressure-fouzul</link><description>Railways, Road Transport and Bridges Adviser Muhammad Fouzul Kabir Khan on Friday said traffic congestion cannot be solved simply by widening roads and at least 20 percent of passenger and goods transport should be shifted to rail and waterways to ease pressure on highways,.
He made the remarks at</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 15:01:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Attorney general for collective efforts to overcome judicial delays</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/attorney-general-for-collective-efforts-to-overcome-judicial-delays</link><description>Attorney General of Bangladesh Md Asaduzzaman emphasised the need for collective efforts to end the culture of delayed justice, saying that justice is undermined when justice is delayed.
He made the remarks while addressing the Sylhet District Bar Association’s annual dinner as the chief gue</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 15:16:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Detainee beaten to death inside Jamalpur jail</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/detainee-beaten-to-death-inside-jamalpur-jail</link><description>A detainee has been beaten to death inside Jamalpur District Jail.
Jail Superintendent Golam Dastagir said the detainee, 25-year-old Pagla Hazrat, was bludgeoned on the head while asleep early on Thursday.
He died on Friday morning at Dhaka Medical College Hospital.
Hazrat had been remanded in j</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 15:31:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat: Old politics won’t shape new Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-chief-shafiqur-says-new-bangladesh-wont-run-on-old-political-formula</link><description>Jamaat-e-Islami chief Shafiqur Rahman has called for a break from “old, stagnant” politics, saying Bangladesh must now move forward under a new formula.
On Friday, at a public rally in Dhaka’s Bhasantek, he noted that the people of the country “no longer want outdated, corr</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 15:46:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bogura-4 BNP candidate accused of forging undergraduate certificate</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bogura-4-bnp-candidate-accused-of-forging-undergraduate-certificate</link><description>BNP nominated candidate for Bogura-4 (Kahaloo-Nondigram) Md Mosharraf Hossain has been accused of forging an undergraduate certificate.
On Thursday afternoon, following a hearing, a Natore Court judge assigned the Police Bureau of Investigation (PBI) to investigate the case, according to Masud Ran</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 16:01:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Russia threatens full ban on WhatsApp</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sci-tech/russia-threatens-full-ban-on-whatsapp</link><description>Russia's state communications watchdog threatened on Friday to block WhatsApp entirely if it fails to comply with Russian law, news agencies reported.
In August, Russia began limiting some calls on WhatsApp, owned by Meta Platforms (META.O), opens new tab, and on Telegram, accusing the foreign-own</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 16:24:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Showdown with Mexican billionaire Salinas tests Sheinbaum's power</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/showdown-with-mexican-billionaire-salinas-tests-sheinbaums-power</link><description>Ricardo Salinas Pliego, one of Mexico's wealthiest tycoons, commands an empire that stretches from banking to media, and casts himself as an anti-corruption crusader.
To Mexico's President Claudia Sheinbaum, Salinas is something altogether different: a tax dodger and right-wing agitator whos</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 16:39:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>China calls on UK to uphold 'one-China' principle</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/china-calls-on-uk-to-uphold-one-china-principle</link><description>China's Foreign Minister Wang Yi called on Britain on Friday to uphold the "one-China" principle, as Beijing seeks to rally support in its worst diplomatic dispute with Tokyo in years over democratically-governed Taiwan.
The "One China" principle, which Beijing views as meaning both sides of the T</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 16:54:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump vows migration freeze after DC attack</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-vows-to-freeze-migration-from-third-world-countries-after-dc-attack-1</link><description>US President Donald Trump said on Thursday his administration will "permanently pause" migration from all "Third World Countries", following the death of a National Guard member in an attack near the White House.
The comments mark a further escalation of migration measures Trump has ordered since</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 17:09:14 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>