<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 17:16:44 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Islami Bank inks with Pundra University and TMSS institutions</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/islami-bank-inks-with-pundra-university-and-tmss-institutions</link><description>Islami Bank Bangladesh PLC and Pundra University, Bogura, along with TMSS Medical College and 14 other educational institutions operated under TMSS, signed a Memorandum of Understanding (MoU) at the university auditorium regarding fee payments through CellFin and mCash.
Under this agreement, stude</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 15:39:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>HSBC holds discussion on Cotton Ecosystem: Strengthening Bangladesh’s Apparel Value Chain</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/hsbc-holds-discussion-on-cotton-ecosystem-strengthening-bangladeshs-apparel-value-chain</link><description>The Hongkong and Shanghai Banking Corporation Limited (HSBC) Bangladesh has recently hosted a roundtable discussion titled “Cotton Ecosystem: Strengthening Bangladesh’s Apparel Value Chain”at a local hotel in Dhaka, Bangladesh.
Moderated by Md Mahbub ur Rahman, Chief Executive Of</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 14:30:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Administrators exchange views with FSIB clients</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/administrators-exchange-views-with-fsib-clients</link><description>Muhommad Badiuzzaman Dider, Administrator and Executive Director of Bangladesh Bank, exchanged views with the clients of First Security Islami Bank PLC at its Corporate Branch on Sunday, according to a press release.
Muhammad Ansarul Kabir, Associate Administrator and Additional Director of Bangla</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 14:45:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EBL opens a sub-branch in Pahartali, Chattogram</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ebl-opens-a-sub-branch-in-pahartali-chattogram</link><description>Eastern Bank PLC (EBL) inaugurated a new sub-branch at Foysal Dastagir Complex, Pahartali CDA Market, in Pahartali, Chattogram, on Sunday, according to a press release.
M. Khorshed Anowar, DMD and Head of Retail and SME Banking; Mesbah Uddin Ahmed, Area Head, Chattogram; and Md. Rezaul Karim Shari</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 15:00:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Citizens Bank holds training on CMSME Financing: Guidelines, Appraisal, Documentation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/citizens-bank-holds-training-on-cmsme-financing-guidelines-appraisal-documentation</link><description>Citizens Bank organised a day-long Training on CMSME Financing: Guidelines, Appraisal and Documentation at its Training Academy recently, according to a press release.
Mr. Md. Mostafizur Rahman, Deputy Managing Director of the bank, inaugurated the program.
Mr. Masum Billah, Joint Director, SME &amp;</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 15:15:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BRAC Bank posts strong results in nine months of 2025</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/brac-bank-posts-strong-results-in-nine-months-of-2025</link><description>BRAC Bank grew its assets and revenue at an annualized rate of 26 per cent and 41 per cent respectively and achieved a 52 per cent growth in its Net Profit After-Tax (NPAT) on a consolidated basis in the first nine months of 2025.
The bank's consolidated financials, which include all its subsidiar</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 15:30:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bank Asia wins ʻFinTech Innovation of the year-Financial Inclusionʼ award</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bank-asia-wins-fintech-innovation-of-the-year-financial-inclusion-award</link><description>Bank Asia PLC has secured the FinTech Innovation of the Year- Financial Inclusion award at the 3rd Bangladesh FinTech Award 2025, earning national recognition for its Micro Merchant initiative that has significantly expanded digital payment access and strengthened financial inclusion at the grassro</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 15:45:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Al-Arafah Islami Bank holds day-long workshop on ready-made garments financing</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/al-arafah-islami-bank-holds-day-long-workshop-on-ready-made-garments-financing</link><description>A day-long workshop titled “Ready-Made Garments (RMG) Financing” was held at Al-Arafah Islami Bank on November 8, 2025, according to a press release.
Managing Director (Acting) of the bank Mohd Rafat Ullah Khan attended the program as chief guest. Deputy Managing Director Abdullah Al M</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 16:00:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>HC stays Chittagong Port Authority’s tariff hike for one month</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/hc-stays-chittagong-port-authoritys-tariff-hike-for-one-month</link><description>The High Court has suspended for one month the implementation of the Chittagong Port Authority's (CPA) decision to collect increased tariffs, which was set to take effect following a circular issued on September 30.
The High Court bench of Justice Qazi Zinat Haque and Justice Ainun Nahar Siddiqa p</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 16:15:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AKIJ Resource launches smart lifestyle brand ‘Enovar’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/akij-resource-launches-smart-lifestyle-brand-enovar</link><description>AKIJ Resource has launched its new brand Enovar, offering smart and modern lifestyle products to make daily life easier and more efficient.
The launch event, held at the United Convention Centre in Dhaka, marked the company’s move into the home appliance and consumer technology market. Enova</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 16:30:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP withdraws expulsion orders against 40 Sylhet city leaders</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-withdraws-expulsion-orders-against-40-sylhet-city-leaders</link><description>BNP has withdrawn the expulsion orders against its 40 leaders from different wards under the Sylhet City Corporation.
In a press release issued on Sunday and signed by party Senior Joint Secretary General Ruhul Kabir Rizvi, it was said that the decision was taken following applications submitted b</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 16:45:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Primary teachers suspend work stoppage</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/primary-teachers-suspend-work-stoppage</link><description>Assistant teachers from the government primary schools, who are demanding 10th-grade pay among three demands, have suspended their work stoppage, according to bdnews24.com.
Following a meeting with government representatives at the Secretariat, Shamsuddin Masud, convenor of the “Primary Teac</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 17:00:47 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>