<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 10:20:44 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>DSE opens higher, CSE sees early decline</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/dse-opens-higher-cse-sees-early-decline</link><description>Trading at the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE) began on a positive note on Thursday, while the Chittagong Stock Exchange (CSE) opened lower.
During the first hour, DSE's key index, DSEX, gained 7 points, as per a UNB report.
The Shariah-based DSES also edged up by 2 points, while the blue-chip DS30 in</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 07:17:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khaleda will recover with 'divine blessings', hopes Fakhrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/khaleda-will-recover-with-divine-blessings-hopes-fakhrul</link><description>BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir on Sunday expressed the hope that their critically ill party chairperson Khaleda Zia will recover with 'divine blessings'.
"People all over the country are praying for her, regardless of their political affiliation. We have faith in Allah, and we b</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 07:32:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New three-party alliance to emerge ahead of 13th National Election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/new-three-party-alliance-to-emerge-ahead-of-13th-national-election</link><description>A new political alliance comprising three parties, including the National Citizens Party (NCP), is set to be launched ahead of the upcoming 13th National Parliamentary Election. The other two parties in the coalition are the Rashtra Sangskar Andolon (Movement for State Reform) and the Amar Banglade</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 07:47:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mobile traders block road outside BTRC to protest phone registration rules</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/mobile-traders-block-road-outside-btrc-to-protest-phone-registration-rules</link><description>Mobile phone traders have blocked the road in front of the Bangladesh Telecommunication Regulatory Commission (BTRC) headquarters in Dhaka to protest the government’s decision to deactivate unregistered handsets.
Several hundred traders and their employees gathered outside the BTRC buildin</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 08:02:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Quality of democracy cannot improve without behavioural change: Planning Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/quality-of-democracy-cannot-improve-without-behavioural-change-planning-adviser</link><description>Planning Adviser Dr Wahiduddin Mahmud on Sunday said democratic institutions alone cannot guarantee the quality of democracy unless political behaviour and political culture change.
"A parliament elected by people, a government accountable to that parliament, and independent watchdog institutions</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 08:17:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India's Goa state orders probe after nightclub fire kills 25</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/indias-goa-state-orders-probe-after-nightclub-fire-kills-25</link><description>Indian authorities ordered an investigation and offered compensation to victims on Sunday after a fire ripped through a nightclub in the western state of Goa, killing 25.
"I have ordered a magisterial inquiry into the entire incident to identify the cause and fix responsibility" for the fire in th</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 08:32:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mass shooting at a South African bar leaves 12 dead, including 3 children</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/africa/mass-shooting-at-a-south-african-bar-leaves-12-dead-including-3-children</link><description>A mass shooting carried out Saturday by multiple suspects in an unlicensed bar near the South African capital left at least 12 people dead, police said. The victims included three children aged 3, 12 and 16.
Another 13 people were wounded and being treated in the hospital. Police didn’</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 08:47:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Criminology: The discipline we need but rarely discuss</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/criminology-the-discipline-we-need-but-rarely-discuss</link><description>In Bangladesh, academic subjects often come with their own established social stereotypes. Mention engineering, and people nod with approval. Say 'medicine,' and everyone smiles proudly; even Business or Law tends to inspire confident expectations. But mention 'Criminology,' and the expressions shi</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 08:49:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Inflation rises to 8.29pc in November</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/inflation-rises-to-829pc-in-november</link><description>The rate of inflation has edged up by 0.12 percentage point to 8.29 per cent in November on point to point basis, even though the central bank has been pursuing a tight monetary stance.
 
In October ,the inflation was 8.17 per cent.
 
This is mainly due to higher food inflation that p</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 09:04:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How Bangladesh's youths are rediscovering social connection</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/youth-and-entrepreneurship/how-bangladeshs-youths-are-rediscovering-social-connection-1</link><description>Every Eid afternoon tells the same story in households across Dhaka. Several cousins gather in the drawing room, phones in hand, scrolling through feeds whilst sitting shoulder to shoulder. Someone suggests Uno, a card game. A few agree half-heartedly, but within twenty minutes, everyone's back on</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 09:19:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>PulseTech secures US$ 3.0m to transform Bangladesh's pharmaceutical supply chain</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/youth-and-entrepreneurship/startups/pulsetech-secures-us-30m-to-transform-bangladeshs-pharmaceutical-supply-chain-1</link><description>PulseTech, a B2B healthtech platform operating in Bangladesh, has successfully closed a US$ 3.0 million Pre-Series A funding round. The investment was co-led by Iterative and AVV, marking AVV's inaugural investment in the country. The capital will support PulseTech's ambitious plans to reshape ph</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 09:34:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh's bold undergrad founders</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/youth-and-entrepreneurship/bangladeshs-bold-undergrad-founders-2</link><description>For university students with a business idea scribbled in a notebook or a prototype built in their hostel room, the wait is over. The Undergrad Startup Challenge 2025, Bangladesh's largest startup competition exclusively for undergraduate students, has officially opened registration.
Organised b</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 09:49:19 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>