<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 15:18:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Prime Bank signs payroll agreement with SQ Lights Ltd</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/prime-bank-signs-payroll-agreement-with-sq-lights-ltd</link><description>Prime Bank PLC, one of the leading private commercial banks in Bangladesh renowned for its innovative and customer-centric financial solutions, has recently signed a Payroll Agreement with SQ Lights Ltd. at the bank’s Corporate Office in Dhaka.
Under this agreement, employees of SQ Lights Lt</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 13:09:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Standard Bank holds its 419th board meeting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/standard-bank-holds-its-419th-board-meeting</link><description>The 419th Board Meeting of Shari'ah-based bank, Standard Bank PLC. was held on 30 October 2025 at the bank’s Boardroom, Head Office, Dhaka.
Chairman of the Board of Directors Mohammed Abdul Aziz presided over the meeting, according to a press release. 
It was attended by Vice Chairman</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 13:24:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>53 citizens urge Consensus Commission to maintain unity</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/53-citizens-urge-consensus-commission-to-maintain-unity</link><description>The National Consensus Commission has handed over its set of recommendations for implementing the July National Charter to the Chief Adviser.
This much-talked-about charter is the outcome of months of sincere effort by a group of dedicated people — and they deserve appreciation for that.
Ho</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 12:34:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Only four tourists attempt St Martin’s trip</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/only-four-tourists-attempt-st-martins-trip</link><description>The revival of St Martin’s Island has fallen flat on reopening day.
Despite the government reopening the coral island to tourists from Saturday, not a single ship departed from Cox’s Bazar on the first day.
Silence prevailed throughout the morning at the BIWTA jetty in Nuniachhara, an</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 12:49:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka takes note of Indian remarks on Islamic scholar's possible visit</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dhaka-takes-note-of-indian-remarks-on-islamic-scholars-possible-visit</link><description>Dhaka today (Saturday) said that it has taken note of the remarks made by the spokesperson of the Indian Ministry of External Affairs regarding the possible visit of a prominent Islamic scholar to Bangladesh.
"We have taken note of the remarks made by the Spokesperson of the Ministry of External A</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 13:19:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Digital transformation: How business is reshaping in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/digital-transformation-how-business-is-reshaping-in-bangladesh</link><description>Bangladesh has evolved into one of the most rapidly expanding economies in South Asia. Over the years, it has transitioned from an agrarian structure to a diversified economy characterised by robust manufacturing, service, and export sectors. At present, Bangladesh's economy and business growth are</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 13:34:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt committed to keeping electricity prices stable, says Farida Akhter</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-committed-to-stable-electricity-prices-says-farida-akhter-1</link><description>Fisheries and Livestock Affairs Adviser Farida Akhter has said the government is committed to keeping electricity prices stable for citizens, even if it requires providing subsidies.
Speaking at the closing ceremony of the ‘CAB Youth Parliament 2025’ organised by the Consumers Associat</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 14:04:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Salahuddin warns against politicising Islam</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/salahuddin-warns-against-politicising-islam</link><description>BNP Standing Committee member Salahuddin Ahmed on Saturday urged people to remain vigilant against those who attempt to create political confusion by misusing religion, particularly Islam.
“When elections approach in our country, we often see attempts to use religion in politics,” he s</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 14:34:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Yunus must issue referendum order as formal decree, says Hasnat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/yunus-must-issue-referendum-order-as-formal-decree-says-hasnat</link><description>Hasnat Abdullah, chief organiser of the National Citizen Party (South), has said Chief Adviser Muhammad Yunus must issue the order for the referendum.
Speaking on Saturday afternoon after attending an NCP coordination meeting in Barguna, he said the matter should be resolved “quickly”,</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 14:49:16 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>