<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 10:24:05 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Monetary policy under duress: The imperative for a facilitative Bangladesh Bank</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/monetary-policy-under-duress-the-imperative-for-a-facilitative-bangladesh-bank</link><description>The Bangladesh banking sector is experiencing its most severe crisis in decades, marked by a debilitating capital shortfall of approximately $15.5 billion and the unfortunate distinction of having the highest rate of non-performing loans (NPLs) in Asia. This alarming situation has been starkly reve</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 07:44:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>JnU announces two-day mourning over student Zobayed’s murder</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jnu-announces-two-day-mourning-over-student-zobayeds-murder</link><description>Jagannath University (JnU) authorities on Monday announced a two-day mourning programme in condolence of the brutal murder of student Zobayed Hossain.
The university has also postponed all events marking 'University Day', which was scheduled for October 22.
The decisions came from a virtual meeti</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 07:59:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Canada hails 'July Charter'`</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/canada-hails-july-charter</link><description>Canada has reiterated its firm support for Bangladesh as the country moves towards a peaceful democratic transition through free, fair, inclusive, and participatory elections. 
"Canada stands with Bangladesh as it moves towards a peaceful transition through free, fair, inclusive, and particip</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 08:29:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Defence begins arguments in Hasina's crimes against humanity case</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/defence-begins-arguments-in-hasinas-crimes-against-humanity-case</link><description>The defence on Monday began placing arguments before the International Crimes Tribunal (ICT)-1 in a case filed against three accused, including ousted prime minister Sheikh Hasina, over their alleged role in orchestrating crimes against humanity during the July-August Mass Uprising.
Advocate Md Am</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 08:59:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC mulls 8-day deployment of security forces during upcoming polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/exporters-alarmed-foreign-buyers-anxious-after-cargo-village-fire-says-eab</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has received a proposal to deploy law-enforcing agencies for eight days around the upcoming 13th parliamentary election.
EC Secretary Akhtar Ahmed shared the information after a preparatory meeting with top law enforcement officials in Dhaka’s Agargaon on Monday,</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 09:29:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fakhrul laments growing political rifts despite July uprising</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/fakhrul-laments-growing-political-rifts-despite-july-uprising</link><description>BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul on Monday lamented that political divisions are widening despite the July mass uprising offering a chance for national unity.
Speaking at a discussion-cum-reception, he said politics can never be beautiful or meaningful without honesty, integrity and a genuine d</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 09:44:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Exporters demand safety measures, compensation after HSIA cargo zone fire</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/exporters-demand-safety-measures-compensation-after-hsia-cargo-zone-fire</link><description>Leaders of the country’s export-oriented sectors have demanded stronger safety measures at the import cargo zone of Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport (HSIA), holding the lack of adequate precautions responsible for the recent massive fire there.
They also urged the government to provide</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 10:14:15 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>