<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 13:34:52 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>3 ex-AL leaders to contest in polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/three-former-awami-league-leaders-enter-election-race-as-jp-jatiya-party-independent-candidates</link><description>Ahead of the parliamentary polls, three former Awami League leaders have filed nominations to contest under different banners, signalling a shift in loyalties and ambitions.
They are participating as Jatiya Party, JP, and independent candidates.
Two of the trio had previously sought Awami League</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 11:19:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>South Asian nations’ gesture highlights Khaleda’s respect, stature: Foreign Adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/south-asian-nations-gesture-highlights-khaledas-respect-stature-foreign-adviser</link><description>Foreign Affairs Adviser Md Touhid Hossain on Thursday said it was a ‘positive gesture’ from the South Asian countries towards former Prime Minister Khaleda Zia who earned a kind of accessibility, respect and dignity among people at home and in South Asia.
“I think it’s a ve</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 11:34:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hasan Tarek Chowdhury joins DSE as GM</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/hasan-tarek-chowdhury-joins-dse-as-gm</link><description>Hasan Tarek Chowdhury on Thursday joined the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE), the country’s premier stock market, as the General Manager of HR and Admin.
Before taking on this leadership role at the DSE, he served as the Head of People and Culture Business Partnering at Japan Tobacco Internationa</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 11:49:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NEIR launched, mobile traders attack BTRC</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/mobile-traders-clash-with-regulators-at-btrc-in-protest-against-neir-launch</link><description>The launch of the National Equipment Identification Register (NEIR) has been met with attack and vandalism at the BTRC office in Agargaon.
The service was kicked off as part of mandatory mobile handset registration on Thursday.
In protest, mobile traders resorted to violence in the afternoon as p</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 12:04:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mursalin quits NCP over ‘ideological rift’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/mursalin-quits-ncp-over-ideological-rift</link><description>Khan Muhammad Mursalin, joint chief coordinator of the National Citizen Party (NCP), resigned from the party on Thursday, citing ideological differences and disillusionment over its political direction.  Mursalin announced the decision in a Facebook post in the afternoon, saying he had st</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 12:19:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>RAB was never used politically under BNP: Babar</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/former-minister-lutfozzaman-babar-says-rab-was-not-used-politically-during-bnp-rule</link><description>Former BNP home minister Lutfozzaman Babar has asserted that the Rapid Action Battalion (RAB) was “never politically exploited” during the party’s tenure from 2001 to 2006.
Speaking to reporters on Thursday after visiting the grave of former prime minister Khaleda Zia in Sher-e-B</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 12:00:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Islami Bank welcomes 1,000 trainee officers in mega orientation program</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/islami-bank-welcomes-1000-trainee-officers-in-mega-orientation-program</link><description>Islami Bank Bangladesh organised a grand orientation program on Thursday for 1,000 newly recruited Trainee Assistant Officers at the Institution of Diploma Engineers, Bangladesh (IDEB) in the capital.
Professor Dr. M. Zubaidur Rahman, Chairman of Islami Bank, attended the ceremony as the Chief Gue</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 12:15:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fakhrul visits graves of Ziaur Rahman, Khaleda Zia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/fakhrul-visits-graves-of-ziaur-rahman-khaleda-zia</link><description>BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir on Thursday visited the graves of Shaheed President Ziaur Rahman and former Prime Minister Begum Khaleda Zia to offer prayers.
The BNP leader arrived at Ziaur Rahman’s mausoleum in Sher-e-Bangla Nagar’s Chandrima Uddyan at 5:15 pm. Upon</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 12:30:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Eight unidentified July martyrs’ bodies identified: Shafiqul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/eight-unidentified-july-martyrs-bodies-identified-shafiqul</link><description>Chief Adviser’s Press Secretary Shafiqul Alam on Thursday said that bodies of eight July martyrs, who were buried at Rayerbazar Graveyard in the city as unclaimed ones, have so far been identified.
“The Ministry of Liberation War Affairs will inform media in detail on this matter very</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 12:45:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gas supply to remain low in 15 Dhaka areas for 10 hours Friday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/gas-supply-to-remain-low-in-15-dhaka-areas-for-10-hours-friday</link><description>Gas supply will remain under low pressure in 15 areas of the capital for 10 hours on Friday due to emergency repair work, Titas Gas Transmission and Distribution PLC said on Thursday.
In a media release, Titas said the low-pressure situation will persist from 10:00am to 8:00pm in the affected area</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 13:00:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sanjay, Faisal confess to killing Hadi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/sanjay-faisal-give-confessional-statement-in-court-over-hadi-murder</link><description>Sanjay Chisim and Faisal Karim Masud, who were arrested in connection with the murder of Inqilab Moncho leader Sharif Osman bin Hadi, have provided statements in court “confessing to their guilt”.
They agreed to give their statements following the end of a three-day interrogation under</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 13:15:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>SAARC spirit alive, it needs to be revived: Prof Yunus</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/saarc-spirit-alive-it-needs-to-be-revived-prof-yunus</link><description>Chief Adviser Prof Muhammad Yunus on Wednesday said SAARC must be revived at any cost, as the presence of high-level dignitaries from member states at the funeral of former Prime Minister Khaleda Zia proves the regional body’s spirit is still alive.
“He (Prof Yunus) conveyed the same m</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 13:30:51 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>