<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 04:11:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>NBR rolls out MFS corporate tax payments</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/nbr-rolls-out-mfs-corporate-tax-payments</link><description>The National Board of Revenue (NBR) on Sunday launched large-value tax payment facilities through mobile financial services (MFS) to make corporate tax payment easier, faster and more digital.
As part of the inauguration, trial transactions were conducted through bKash Limited's online merchant</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 01:05:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tk 2.0t revised ADP to be tabled today</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/tk-20t-revised-adp-to-be-tabled-today</link><description>A proposed Tk 2.0-trillion Revised Annual Development Programme (RADP) for the current fiscal year will be placed before the National Economic Council (NEC) today for approval, marking a 7.41-percent decline from the FY25 RADP and the lowest revised development outlay in the past five years.
Pla</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 01:20:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Graft-free leadership key to Bangladesh's progress</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/graft-free-leadership-key-to-bangladeshs-progress</link><description>Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) Chairman Mohammad Abdul Momen on Sunday said establishing a fair and integrity-based state is essential to ensure justice for all.
He, however, warned that even if the current political crisis is resolved, corruption would remain Bangladesh's one of the biggest cha</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 01:35:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Yields on treasury bills decline further</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/yields-on-treasury-bills-decline-further</link><description>Yields on treasury bills  (T-bills) declined further on Sunday with banks channelling their excess liquidity into risk-free securities, amid subdued private-sector credit demand ahead of the upcoming polls.
The cut-off yield, generally known as interest rate, on the 91-Day T-bills fell to 1</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 01:50:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCP's Nahid calls on Jamaat ameer</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ncps-nahid-calls-on-jamaat-ameer</link><description>National Citizen Party (NCP) Convener Nahid Islam called on Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami Ameer Dr Shafiqur Rahman in the capital on Sunday.
He disclosed the information on his verified Facebook page.
Sources say they discussed the existing situation of the country and the upcoming national election</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 02:05:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC declares 58 nominations valid on second day of hearings</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ec-declares-58-nominations-valid-on-second-day-of-hearings</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) approved 58 more appeals on the nomination papers rejected by the returning officers on Sunday, the second day of hearings.
Besides, seven appeals were ruled out and six others kept pending to give verdict on them later after the appellants meet the requirements sugges</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 02:20:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCP to appoint 'ambassadors' in 270 constituencies</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ncp-to-appoint-ambassadors-in-270-constituencies</link><description>The National Citizen Party (NCP) has announced constituency-based programmes across the country to ensure a "yes" vote in the upcoming referendum.
In this regard, it will appoint "ambassadors" in 270 constituencies, particularly in areas where the party does not have its own candidates.
Mahabub A</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 02:35:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Users can now recharge rapid pass cards via mobile app</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/users-can-now-recharge-rapid-pass-cards-via-mobile-app</link><description>Rapid pass users can now recharge their cards through a dedicated mobile application, as the Dhaka Transport Coordination Authority (DTCA) has made the app, titled "Rapid Pass," available on Google Play.
Officials said around 20,000 users have been using the app since it was unofficially released</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 02:50:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>One person shot dead, another injured in Ctg</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/one-person-shot-dead-another-injured-in-ctg</link><description>One person was shot dead and another sustained gunshot wounds when unidentified assailants opened fire on them in Fatikchhari upazila of Chattogram district last night (10 January), police and local sources said.
The deceased was identified as Muhammad Jamal Uddin (38), a resident of Shahnagar vil</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 03:05:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BSEC launches "special investigation" into Haji Ahmed Brothers Securities</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/bsec-launches-special-investigation-into-haji-ahmed-brothers-securities</link><description>The securities regulator has ordered a "special investigation" into Haji Ahmed Brothers Securities Ltd, citing the need to protect the interests of the capital market and general investors.
Md Abul Kalam, spokesperson of the Bangladesh Securities and Exchange Commission (BSEC), told The FE that th</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 03:20:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka stocks slide as blue chips face selling pressure</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/dhaka-stocks-slide-as-blue-chips-face-selling-pressure</link><description>The Dhaka bourse on Sunday experienced a moderate loss in the broad index as the majority of blue-chip stocks declined amid day-long selling pressure.
Of the 30 blue-chip stocks, 28 declined, while the remaining two companies-Beacon Pharmaceuticals and Heidelberg Materials Bangladesh-advanced marg</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 03:35:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Aviation safety a concern as stray dogs on prowl</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/aviation-safety-a-concern-as-stray-dogs-on-prowl</link><description>Unhindered movement of stray dogs on the runway of Cox's Bazar Airport has emerged as a serious aviation safety concern, putting aircraft operations at risk and causing growing anxiety among passengers and airlines.
Over the past five months, at least two accidents were reported in which stray dog</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 03:50:46 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>