<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 09:18:56 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Youth shot dead in Brahmanbaria</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/youth-shot-dead-in-brahmanbaria</link><description>A youth was shot dead and three others were injured in a gun attack allegedly over establishing supremacy in Nabinagar upazila of Brahmanbaria on Saturday night.
The deceased was identified as Shipon Mia, 30, son of Monnaf Mia of Nurjahanpur area in the upazila, reports UNB.
Locals said Shipon an</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 05:39:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ACC prosecutes treasurer, ex-registrar of Ctg's Southern University</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/acc-prosecutes-treasurer-ex-registrar-of-ctgs-southern-university</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) has launched a case against the treasurer and former registrar of a private university in Chattogram for allegedly embezzling and misusing money from the teachers' provident fund.
The case was filed on Sunday by ACC Deputy Director Alamgir Hossain.
Southern Un</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 06:09:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Stocks at DSE, CSE open higher</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/bangladesh/stocks-at-dse-cse-open-higher</link><description>Indices at both the Dhaka and Chattogram stock exchanges opened higher in the first hour of trading on Sunday, as most company shares gained in price.
At the Dhaka Stock Exchange (DSE), the key index DSEX advanced by 5 points in early trading.
The Shariah-based DSES remained flat, while the</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 06:24:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>15 injured as bus overturns on Dhaka–Bhanga Expressway</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/15-injured-as-bus-overturns-on-dhaka-bhanga-expressway</link><description>At least 15 passengers were injured when a bus overturned amid heavy rain on the Dhaka–Bhanga Expressway in Shibchar upazila of Madaripur on Saturday night.
The accident disrupted traffic on the expressway for about an hour, said Zahurul Islam, officer-in-charge of Shibchar Highway Police St</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 06:39:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh wants Bahrain to reopen visa facilities for its citizens</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-wants-bahrain-to-reopen-visa-facilities-for-its-citizens</link><description>Foreign Adviser Md Touhid Hossain has urged Bahrain to reopen visa facilities for Bangladeshi citizens, including businesspeople, professionals, and skilled and semi-skilled workers, to boost people-to-people contact and economic engagement between the two countries.
He requested a meeting with Ba</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 06:54:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Biswa Ijtema to be held after national election: Khalid</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/biswa-ijtema-to-be-held-after-national-election-khalid</link><description>Religious Affairs Adviser Dr AFM Khalid Hossain on Sunday said Biswa Ijtema will be held in February after the national election.
The adviser came up with the information while talking to reporters after a meeting with the representatives of the two factions of the Tabligh Jamaat at the Secretaria</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 07:09:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shah Rukh Khan at 60: How Bollywood's 'King' reshaped global cinema</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/entertainment/shah-rukh-khan-at-60-how-bollywoods-king-reshaped-global-cinema</link><description>Holding a bottle like a trophy in one hand and a comb as a mic in another, a young man once said, "When you want something with all your heart, the whole universe conspires in helping you achieve it. Today, you all have united me with my desire. Thanks. Thanks very much. I feel like the king of the</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 08:09:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mandatory green building policy a must for sustainable cities: Rizwana</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/mandatory-green-building-policy-a-must-for-sustainable-cities-rizwana</link><description>Environment Adviser Syeda Rizwana Hasan on Sunday said that to build sustainable and livable cities, it is essential to make 'green building' policy mandatory in government infrastructures.
"Once the government ensures compliance in its projects, the private sector will follow," she said at a work</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 08:24:32 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>