<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 14:14:49 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Clashes erupt at Jatiya Party rally in Kakrail, police use batons</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/clashes-erupt-at-jatiya-party-rally-in-kakrail-police-use-batons</link><description>Pitched battles have erupted between Jatiya Party (JaPa) activists and police surrounding a workers' rally called outside the party's central office in Dhaka’s Kakrail.
The police dispersed the rally by using baton charges along with firing tear gas shells and sound grenades following the in</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 10:33:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shahidul Alam describes mental torture during detention by Israeli forces</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/shahidul-alam-describes-mental-torture-during-detention-by-israeli-forces</link><description>Photographer and Drik Managing Director Shahidul Alam has recounted harrowing experiences of mental abuse while detained by Israeli forces, saying detainees were subjected to intimidation, threats and harsh conditions.
Speaking at a press conference at Drik’s Patshala building on Saturday ev</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 10:48:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gazans stream back home as Israel-Hamas ceasefire holds</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/gazans-stream-back-home-as-israel-hamas-ceasefire-holds</link><description>Thousands of Palestinians streamed north along the coast of Gaza on Saturday, trekking by foot, car and cart back to their abandoned homes as a ceasefire between Israel and Palestinian militant group Hamas appeared to be holding.
Israeli troops pulled back under the first phase of a US-brokered ag</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 11:03:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Afghanistan bat against Bangladesh with eye on ODI series win</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/afghanistan-bat-against-bangladesh-with-eye-on-odi-series-win</link><description>Afghanistan opted to bat first against Bangladesh in the second ODI in their bid to seal the series in Abu Dhabi.
Bangladesh brought back Mustafizur Rahman and Rishad Hossain to replace Taskin Ahmed and Hasan Mahmud, while the Afghans remained unchanged at the Zayed Cricket Stadium on Saturday.
A</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 11:18:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bone marrow transplant service restarts at DMCH after 5 years</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/health/bone-marrow-transplant-service-restarts-at-dmch-after-5-years</link><description>Bone marrow transplant services have resumed at Dhaka Medical College Hospital (DMCH) after five years.
The service was inaugurated on Saturday at the hospital’s new 10-storey building by Health Adviser Nurjahan Begum.
She said, “The transplant services have restarted at DMCH. Patient</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 11:48:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Halal industry growth in Bangladesh needs concerted effort: DCCI</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/halal-industry-growth-in-bangladesh-needs-concerted-effort-dcci</link><description>A well-coordinated halal ecosystem is essential for unlocking Bangladesh’s potential in the global halal market, currently valued at around USD 3 trillion, speakers said at a focus group discussion organised by the Dhaka Chamber of Commerce &amp; Industry (DCCI) on Saturday.
The discussion title</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 12:03:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>3 children drown in a pond in Magura</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/3-children-drown-in-a-pond-in-magura</link><description>Three children tragically drowned while bathing in a pond in Chapatala village of Mohammadpur upazila, Magura on Saturday afternoon.
Abdur Rahman, officer-in-charge of Mohammadpur Police Station, confirmed that the the victims were Tarin, 8, daughter of Anarul Mia; Cynthia, 9, daughter of Sajjad M</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 12:18:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Army takes 15 military officers into custody over ‘crimes against humanity’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/army-takes-15-military-officers-into-custody-over-crimes-against-humanity</link><description>The Bangladesh Army has said it took 15 of its officers into custody following warrants issued against 30 over alleged involvement in enforced disappearances and crimes against humanity.
The information was revealed at a media briefing at the Army Headquarters on Saturday amid calls to arrest and</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 12:33:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Advisors need no ‘safe exit’: Asif Nazrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/advisors-do-not-need-safe-exit-but-nation-does-says-asif-nazrul</link><description>Law Advisor Asif Nazrul has dismissed claims that some advisors of the interim government are seeking a “safe exit”, saying none of the advisors require one.
“Our advisors do not need any safe exit,” he said, adding: “But as a nation, we do need a safe exit -- from a</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 13:03:46 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>