<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 16:41:04 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Bangladesh’s foreign debt repayment tops $2bn in first half of FY</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladeshs-foreign-debt-repayment-tops-2bn-in-first-half-of-fy</link><description>Bangladesh’s foreign debt repayment crossed the $2 billion mark in the first six months of the current fiscal year (FY), as the government continues to face mounting pressure from rising external liabilities.
According to the latest updated report published by the Economic Relations Division</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 13:58:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>4-year-old falls into borehole in Raozan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/4-year-old-trapped-in-abandoned-borehole-in-raozan-as-firefighters-race-to-rescue</link><description>A 4-year-old child has fallen into an abandoned deep tube well in Chattogram’s Raozan, prompting the Fire Service to launch a rescue operation.
Fire Service officials said they received information sometime after 5pm on Wednesday that a child had fallen into the borehole at Jaynagar of Kodol</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 14:13:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IPO ‘forgery’: Auditors under ACC scanner</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/acc-to-launch-investigation-into-auditing-firms-over-tk-122bn-embezzlement</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) is going to investigate the role auditing firms played in the “embezzlement” of Tk 122 billion through corruption and irregularities in banks, the share market, and financial institutions.
The anti-graft agency has called for documents from 10 CA fi</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 14:28:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bankers push for travel bans, public shaming of loan defaulters</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/bankers-push-for-travel-bans-public-shaming-of-loan-defaulters</link><description>Bangladesh’s top bankers have urged regulators to impose tougher restrictions on chronic loan defaulters, including overseas travel bans, public disclosure of identities and exclusion from trade body elections, as the country struggles with a mounting bad-loan crisis.
The Association of Bank</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 14:43:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Former CAAB chief engineer arrested for ‘corruption’ in Cox’s Bazar Airport project</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/former-caab-chief-engineer-arrested-for-corruption-in-coxs-bazar-airport-project</link><description>The Anti-Corruption Commission has arrested Md Habibur Rahman, a former chief engineer of the Civil Aviation Authority of Bangladesh (CAAB), on charges of corruption in the project to expand runways at Cox’s Bazar International Airport.
The arrest was confirmed by ACC Director General Akhtar</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 14:58:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Islami Bank conducts Shari‘ah Supervisory Committee meeting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/islami-bank-conducts-shariah-supervisory-committee-meeting</link><description>A meeting of the Shari‘ah Supervisory Committee of Islami Bank Bangladesh PLC was held on 27 January 2026, Tuesday at Islami Bank Tower.
Mufti Shamsuddin Zia, Chairman of the Committee, presided over the meeting, according to a media release. 
Professor Dr. Nakib Muhammad Nasrullah, Pr</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 15:13:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCC Bank launches Automated Environmental and Social Risk Management System</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ncc-bank-launches-automated-environmental-and-social-risk-management-system</link><description>NCC Bank has officially launched an advanced Automated Environmental and Social Risk Management (ESRM) system in line with its testament to eco-friendly financing and sustainable banking.
This technology-driven platform will embark an innovative shift in the bank's credit process, making Environme</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 14:59:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>MTB Foundation commemorates International Day of Education 2026</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/mtb-foundation-commemorates-international-day-of-education-2026</link><description>To commemorate the International Day of Education 2026, MTB Foundation celebrated this year's theme ‘The Power of Youth in Co-Creating Education’ by distributing free bicycles to the female underprivileged meritorious students of different schools in Mathbaria, Barishal under its &amp;lsquo</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 15:14:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Home Adviser Jahangir Alam pledges credible polls on Feb 12</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/home-adviser-jahangir-alam-pledges-credible-polls-on-feb-12</link><description>Home Affairs Adviser Lt Gen (retd) Md Jahangir Alam Chowdhury on Wednesday reaffirmed that all stakeholders are committed to ensuring a transparent, fair, and widely accepted election.
“There is no political bias among those involved in the election. There is no such thing as an Awami League</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 15:29:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique to launch 3-day northern region electioneering Thursday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-to-launch-3-day-northern-region-electioneering-thursday</link><description>BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman will kick off a three-day election campaign in the northern region starting on Thursday, aiming to rally support ahead of the polls.
Tarique will leave for Rajshahi at noon by air to formally launch the tour, BNP Media Cell member Sayrul Kabir Khan said on Wednesday.
H</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 15:44:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BGB to deploy 38 platoons in Dhaka sector ahead of national election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bgb-to-deploy-38-platoons-in-dhaka-sector-ahead-of-national-election</link><description>Border Guard Bangladesh (BGB) will deploy 38 platoons across 14 parliamentary constituencies under Dhaka Battalion (5 BGB) to maintain law and order, safeguard voters’ rights and ensure a peaceful environment during the upcoming national election.
According to BGB headquarters sources, 11 pl</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 15:59:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Party support, not lineage, drew me back to Bangladesh’, Tarique tells Time Magazine</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/party-support-not-lineage-drew-me-back-to-bangladesh-tarique-tells-time-magazine</link><description>BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman has said he is the right person to heal Bangladesh’s divisions, insisting his return is driven by party supporters rather than family lineage.
“It’s not because I’m the son of my father and mother,” he told the Time Magazine in his first ex</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 16:14:36 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>