<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 19:33:13 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>More than power transfer, it’s beginning of new journey for democracy: Prof Yunus</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/more-than-power-transfer-its-beginning-of-new-journey-for-democracy-prof-yunus</link><description>Chief Adviser Prof Muhammad Yunus on Monday said the just-held national election is not just a process of transferring power; rather it is the beginning of a new journey for the country’s democracy, the birth of a new Bangladesh.
“We have delivered a festive, free, impartial, peaceful,</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 16:02:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Woman ‘divorced for voting BNP’ in Feni; husband cites family dispute</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/woman-divorced-for-voting-bnp-in-feni-husband-cites-family-dispute</link><description>A 32-year-old woman in Feni’s Parshuram upazila has allegedly been divorced by her husband for voting for the BNP’s “Sheaf of Paddy” symbol in the 13th national election held on February 12.
The incident took place in Paglirkul village under Chithlia union and sparked a sti</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 16:17:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Development challenges in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/development-challenges-in-bangladesh</link><description>Dubbed as a “bottomless basket” and a “test case for development”, Bangladesh has come a long way in its journey towards economic growth. Since independence in 1971, Bangladesh’s gross domestic product (GDP) has increased by about 77 times from less than US$ 6 billion</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 16:32:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Will the winds of change blow?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/will-the-winds-of-change-blow</link><description>BNP chairman, Tarique Rahman paid a visit to Jamaat-e-Islami Ameer Shafiqur Rahman at the latter's Bashundhara residence last Sunday (February 15) evening.  Terming it 'a historic moment in national politics', the Jamaat leader, Shafiqur Rahman, reaffirmed his party's commitment, along with th</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 16:47:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>On BNP's pledge to respect fearless, unbiased journalism</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/on-bnps-pledge-to-respect-fearless-unbiased-journalism</link><description>A landslide victory brings with it not only power, but scrutiny. After the Bangladesh Nationalist Party's sweeping win in the 13th parliamentary elections on 12 February, public attention has swiftly shifted from celebration to expectation. Among the most pressing tests facing the incoming governme</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 17:02:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Saving Sundarbans from disintegration</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/saving-sundarbans-from-disintegration</link><description>That a number of environmental organisations have been observing the Sundarbans Day each year on February 14 since 2001 is not widely known. The reason for this is the limited publicity the day's observance receives with the government yet to recognise the day officially. So, the environmental grou</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 17:17:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh moves up 3 spots in Henley Passport Index, ranks 93rd</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-moves-up-3-spots-in-henley-passport-index-ranks-93rd</link><description>Bangladesh has climbed three places in the latest Henley Passport Index, moving up to 93rd position from 96th in the previous ranking.
According to the new list, Singapore remains at the top of the index, retaining its position as the world’s most powerful passport. Japan and South Korea joi</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 17:32:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chief advisor’s principal secretary resigns</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/chief-advisors-principal-secretary-resigns</link><description>The Chief Advisor’s Principal Secretary M Siraz Uddin Miah has resigned.
The chief advisor’s press aide Shafiqul Alam said the Ministry of Public Administration issued a gazette notification about the resignation on Monday.
Two days after the general election, the interim government o</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 17:47:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fire erupts at Karwan Bazar timber market</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fire-erupts-at-karwan-bazar-timber-market</link><description>A fire has broken out at Karwan Bazar timber market.
Fire Service duty officer Shahjahan Hossain said the fire was reported around 10:30pm on Monday.
"Eight units of the Fire Service are currently working to extinguish the flames," he said.
The cause of the fire could not be immediately known. N</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 18:02:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>MP oath hollow without reform council pledge: Asif Mahmud</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/skipping-constitution-reform-council-oath-would-void-mps-mandate-says-asif-mahmud</link><description>Former student advisor Asif Mahmud Shojib Bhuyain has said skipping the oath as a member of the Constitution Reform Council would render a parliamentary oath “meaningless”.
A day before the MP oath, on Monday, he made the remark in a Facebook post.
“The oath of the Constitution</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 18:17:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How much will Tarique earn as PM?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/how-much-will-tarique-earn-as-prime-minister-and-what-perks-come-with-the-office</link><description>If all goes as planned, BNP Chairperson Tarique Rahman is poised to assume office as Bangladesh’s next prime minister, completing a remarkable journey from years of exile to the very centre of state power.
As anticipation builds around his return to government, many are asking a simpler, mor</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 19:03:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Regulator's move for digital bank licensing flops amid protests</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/regulators-move-for-digital-bank-licensing-flops-amid-protests</link><description>A decisive regulatory move for licensing digital banks flops as an emergency board meeting of Bangladesh Bank backtracked following strong protest from officers against such last-minute decision during governmental transition.



Sources said a strong protest from the BB officers' platform upse</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 19:18:44 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>