<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 15:24:41 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Islami Bank welcomes 1,000 trainee officers in mega orientation program</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/islami-bank-welcomes-1000-trainee-officers-in-mega-orientation-program</link><description>Islami Bank Bangladesh organised a grand orientation program on Thursday for 1,000 newly recruited Trainee Assistant Officers at the Institution of Diploma Engineers, Bangladesh (IDEB) in the capital.
Professor Dr. M. Zubaidur Rahman, Chairman of Islami Bank, attended the ceremony as the Chief Gue</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 12:15:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fakhrul visits graves of Ziaur Rahman, Khaleda Zia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/fakhrul-visits-graves-of-ziaur-rahman-khaleda-zia</link><description>BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir on Thursday visited the graves of Shaheed President Ziaur Rahman and former Prime Minister Begum Khaleda Zia to offer prayers.
The BNP leader arrived at Ziaur Rahman’s mausoleum in Sher-e-Bangla Nagar’s Chandrima Uddyan at 5:15 pm. Upon</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 12:30:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Eight unidentified July martyrs’ bodies identified: Shafiqul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/eight-unidentified-july-martyrs-bodies-identified-shafiqul</link><description>Chief Adviser’s Press Secretary Shafiqul Alam on Thursday said that bodies of eight July martyrs, who were buried at Rayerbazar Graveyard in the city as unclaimed ones, have so far been identified.
“The Ministry of Liberation War Affairs will inform media in detail on this matter very</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 12:45:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gas supply to remain low in 15 Dhaka areas for 10 hours Friday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/gas-supply-to-remain-low-in-15-dhaka-areas-for-10-hours-friday</link><description>Gas supply will remain under low pressure in 15 areas of the capital for 10 hours on Friday due to emergency repair work, Titas Gas Transmission and Distribution PLC said on Thursday.
In a media release, Titas said the low-pressure situation will persist from 10:00am to 8:00pm in the affected area</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 13:00:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sanjay, Faisal confess to killing Hadi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/sanjay-faisal-give-confessional-statement-in-court-over-hadi-murder</link><description>Sanjay Chisim and Faisal Karim Masud, who were arrested in connection with the murder of Inqilab Moncho leader Sharif Osman bin Hadi, have provided statements in court “confessing to their guilt”.
They agreed to give their statements following the end of a three-day interrogation under</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 13:15:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>SAARC spirit alive, it needs to be revived: Prof Yunus</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/saarc-spirit-alive-it-needs-to-be-revived-prof-yunus</link><description>Chief Adviser Prof Muhammad Yunus on Wednesday said SAARC must be revived at any cost, as the presence of high-level dignitaries from member states at the funeral of former Prime Minister Khaleda Zia proves the regional body’s spirit is still alive.
“He (Prof Yunus) conveyed the same m</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 13:30:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Profit ceiling cut for savings certificates</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/maximum-returns-for-savings-certificates-lowered</link><description>The Department of National Savings has announced new profit rates for investment in savings certificates and bonds for the first half of the year.
Effective from the first day of 2026, the government’s notification sets a maximum return of 10.59 percent and a minimum of 8.74 percent for inve</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 13:32:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt cuts import, production duties for mobile phones</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/government-cuts-import-production-duties-for-mobile-phones</link><description>The government has reduced duties on domestically produced and imported mobile phones to lower handset prices.
The decision came during Thursday’s Advisory Council meeting amid calls from the businessmen, announced later by Chief Advisor’s Press Secretary Shafiqul Alam.
Customs duty o</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 13:47:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat Ameer meets Tarique Rahman</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jamaat-ameer-meets-tarique-rahman</link><description>Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami Ameer Dr Shafiqur Rahman met BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman on Thursday evening and expressed condolences over the death of his mother and former Prime Minister Khaleda Zia.
The Jamaat chief came to the BNP Chairperson’s Gulshan office around 7:00pm, a day afte</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 14:02:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique Rahman thanks officials, citizens for ‘historic farewell’ to Khaleda Zia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-rahman-thanks-officials-citizens-for-historic-farewell-to-khaleda-zia</link><description>BNP acting chairman Tarique Rahman has thanked everyone involved in the funeral prayers and burial of his mother, former prime minister and BNP chairperson Begum Khaleda Zia, describing her final farewell as “historic” and saying it was carried out with “due dignity and respect fo</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 14:17:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Iftekhar Enam Awal promoted to DMD at AB Bank</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/iftekhar-enam-awal-promoted-to-dmd-at-ab-bank</link><description>Mr. Iftekhar Enam Awal has been promoted to Deputy Managing Director of AB Bank PLC.
Mr. Iftekhar started his career with AB Bank PLC as 7th batch Probationary Officer in June 1994 after completing his Post graduation in Finance from the University of Dhaka, according to a press release.
He has p</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 14:32:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sabbir Hossain joins Bank Asia as AMD &amp; COO</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/sabbir-hossain-joins-bank-asia-as-amd-coo</link><description>Md. Sabbir Hossain, a seasoned banker with extensive banking experience, has joined Bank Asia PLC as Additional Managing Director (AMD) and Chief Operating Officer (COO), effective 01 January 2026.
Mr. Hossain brings with him more than three decades of successful banking experience, particularly i</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 14:47:37 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>