<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 12:45:05 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Iran eyes 'permanent split' from global internet, say digital rights activists</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/iran-eyes-permanent-split-from-global-internet-say-digital-rights-activists</link><description>Iran has planned a “permanent break” from the global internet, allowing only individuals vetted by the regime to connect online, according to digital rights activists.
Bdnews24.com, citing The Guardian, reported that a confidential plan is underway to make international internet access</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 09:16:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique urges vigilance, says BNP shows restraint despite EC controversy</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-urges-vigilance-says-bnp-shows-restraint-despite-ec-controversy</link><description>Urging all to remain vigilant against any attempts to obstruct the path of democratic transition, BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman on Saturday said his party still intends to show restraint despite what he described as the Election Commission's recent controversial roles and positions.
Speaking at a vi</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 09:31:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Taiwan says Chinese drone made 'provocative' flight over South China Sea island</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/taiwan-says-chinese-drone-made-provocative-flight-over-south-china-sea-island</link><description>A Chinese reconnaissance drone briefly flew over the Taiwan-controlled Pratas Islands at the top end of the South China Sea on Saturday, in what Taiwan's defence ministry called a "provocative and irresponsible" move.
Democratically governed Taiwan, which China claims as its own territory, reports</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 09:46:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>U-19 World Cup: Bangladesh-India captains avoid handshakes at toss</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/u-19-world-cup-bangladesh-india-captains-avoid-handshakes-at-toss</link><description>The diplomatic tension between Dhaka and New Delhi has spilled onto the cricket field, as the captains of the Bangladesh and India Under-19 teams refused to shake hands during the toss at the ICC U-19 World Cup on Saturday in Zimbabwe.
In a scene reminiscent of recent India-Pakistan encounters, Ba</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 10:01:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh reaffirms commitment to rules-based global order: Touhid</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-reaffirms-commitment-to-rules-based-global-order-touhid</link><description>Foreign Affairs Adviser Md Touhid Hossain, on Saturday, reaffirmed Bangladesh’s commitment to a rules-based international order and collective global action, emphasising dialogue and cooperation to address shared economic challenges.
“As a responsible neighbour and an active member of</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 10:16:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hindu Mohajote leader Gobinda regains candidacy in Gopalganj-3</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/hindu-mohajote-leader-gobinda-regains-candidacy-in-gopalganj-3</link><description>Gobinda Chandra Pramanik, secretary general of the Bangladesh Jatiya Hindu Mohajote, has had his nomination reinstated for the Gopalganj-3 constituency after filing an appeal with the Election Commission (EC).
On Friday, following a hearing on his appeal, the EC declared the independent candidate&amp;</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 10:31:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khamenei calls Trump criminal for causing casualties, damage, slander on Iranians</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/khamenei-calls-trump-criminal-for-causing-casualties-damage-slander-on-iranians</link><description>Iran's supreme leader Ali Khamenei said on Saturday that Iran considers US President Donald Trump a "criminal" for inflicting casualties, damage, and slander on the Iranian people during the protests.
"The latest anti-Iran sedition was different in that the US President personally became involved,</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 10:46:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC cancels BNP candidate’s nomination in Hasnat Abdullah’s constituency</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ec-cancels-bnp-candidates-nomination-in-hasnat-abdullahs-constituency</link><description>The Election Commission (EC) has cancelled the nomination of Manjurul Ahsan Munshi, the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) candidate in the Cumilla-4 constituency, over allegations of loan default.
The decision was announced on Saturday (January 17) after a hearing held at 4:00 pm at the Basement-</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 11:00:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Strong editorial institutions vital for journalistic standards: Mahfuz Anam</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/strong-editorial-institutions-key-to-upholding-journalistic-standards-mahfuz-anam</link><description>A robust editorial institution is essential for maintaining journalistic integrity in Bangladesh, said The Daily Star Editor Mahfuz Anam on Saturday.
“Now is the right time to practise ethical journalism in Bangladesh. If media editors can maintain the standards of editorial institutions, jo</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 11:15:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>American CEOs push back on Trump ... mildly</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/american-ceos-push-back-on-trump-mildly</link><description>Speaking before a darkened ballroom on Thursday, US Chamber of Commerce CEO Suzanne Clark called on executives to be "fearless" in defense of free markets over government control and said the US must remain "open to the world, open to the global exchange of talent and goods and ideas and innovation</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 11:30:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Assault on intern doctor at Syhet hospital sparks work stoppage</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/assault-on-intern-doctor-at-syhet-hospital-sparks-work-stoppage</link><description>An intern doctor has been assaulted at Sylhet MAG Osmani Medical College Hospital, prompting junior doctors to launch an indefinite work stoppage in protest.
The attack took place on Friday night. Police said three relatives of a patient had been detained in connection with the incident.
Intern d</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 11:45:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt tightens public asset oversight to curb fiscal risks</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-tightens-oversight-of-public-assets-to-curb-long-term-fiscal-risks</link><description>The government has introduced a new Property, Plant and Equipment (PPE) and Lease Manual aimed at strengthening asset governance and curbing long-term liabilities.
The move comes as the Finance Division revealed that Bangladesh’s total contingent liabilities have reached Tk 6.398 trillion (T</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 12:00:49 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>