<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 16:29:50 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nagad wins award at Eastern Bank Digital Excellence Awards 2025</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/nagad-wins-award-at-eastern-bank-digital-excellence-awards-2025</link><description>Nagad has received the Excellence in Business Payout award from Eastern Bank Limited (EBL), one of the country’s leading private commercial banks, according to a press release.
Under this initiative, the bank honored 40 partner merchant organisations for their significant contributions to th</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 14:13:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump appoints envoy to Greenland, stirs backlash</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/trump-appoints-envoy-to-greenland-stirs-backlash</link><description>US President Donald Trump named Louisiana Governor Jeff Landry on Sunday as his special envoy to Greenland, drawing renewed criticism from Denmark and Greenland over Washington’s interest in the mineral-rich Arctic island.
Trump has advocated for Greenland, a self-governing Danish territory,</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 14:28:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Petrobangla, BMTF sign deal to digitally monitor industrial gas supply</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/petrobangla-bmtf-sign-deal-to-digitally-monitor-industrial-gas-supply</link><description>In a major step toward digitising the nation’s energy infrastructure, Petrobangla, the state carbohydron agency, and the Bangladesh Machine Tools Factory Limited (BMTF) signed a contract on Monday to implement a sophisticated GPS-based monitoring system for gas metering stations.
The contrac</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 14:43:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mob violence is a threat to democracy: Rizvi</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/mob-violence-is-a-threat-to-democracy-rizvi</link><description>Expressing grave concern over the continued incidents of mob violence across the country, BNP Senior Joint Secretary General Ruhul Kabir Rizvi today said that the attacks being carried out by unruly mobs pose a serious threat to humanity and democratic values. He made these remarks while talki</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 14:58:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh ‘suspends’ visa services at Delhi, Agartala missions</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-suspends-visa-services-at-delhi-agartala-missions</link><description>Bangladesh has reportedly suspended visa services at its missions in India.
On Monday, the foreign ministry officials, who declined to be named, said notices about the suspension have been affixed at the Bangladesh High Commission in Delhi and the Assistant High Commission in Agartala, Tripura.</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 15:13:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pope Leo’s new US bishops are critics of Trump’s migrant crackdown</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/pope-leos-new-us-bishops-are-critics-of-trumps-migrant-crackdown</link><description>Most of Pope Leo’s appointments for Catholic bishops in the US have called for better treatment of immigrants in the country, in a trend that may shape how the national Church responds to the Trump administration’s divisive anti-immigration policies.
At least ten of the 13 selections m</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 14:46:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pakistan strikes $4 billion deal to sell weapons to Libyan force, officials say</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/pakistan-strikes-4-billion-deal-to-sell-weapons-to-libyan-force-officials-say</link><description>Pakistan has reached a deal worth over $4 billion to sell military equipment to the Libyan National Army, four Pakistani officials said, despite a U.N. arms embargo on the fractured North African country.
The deal, one of Pakistan’s largest-ever weapons sales, was finalised after a meeting l</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 15:01:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Lawyer Alif murder trial set to begin</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/lawyer-alif-murder-trial-set-to-begin</link><description>Following the completion of all legal procedures, the murder case of Chattogram lawyer Saiful Islam Alif is now ready to be sent to the trial court.
Assistant Public Prosecutor Md Raihanul Wazed Chowdhury confirmed the development on Monday.
“The case is scheduled for tomorrow, Tuesday. It</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 15:16:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>TV, fridge bought with looted money: Probe Officer</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/suspect-bought-tv-refrigerator-with-money-looted-from-prothom-alo-says-investigation-officer</link><description>The investigation officer of the case over the attack on the Prothom Alo office has claimed that one of the suspects used the money looted in the incident to buy a TV and a refrigerator.
The suspect, Naim Islam and his lawyer denied the allegations, saying the two products were purchased before th</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 15:31:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique’s homecoming: Special trains to operate on 10 routes, three services cancelled</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tariques-homecoming-special-trains-to-operate-on-10-routes-three-services-cancelled</link><description>Bangladesh Railway will operate special trains on 10 routes to mark the homecoming of Tarique Rahman in response to an application by the BNP.
To facilitate this, three short-distance train services have been cancelled.
The railway said in a media statement on Monday that the Rajbari Commuter (Ra</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 15:46:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCP, Chhatra Dal clash in Shariatpur leaves 5 injured</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ncp-chhatra-dal-clash-in-shariatpur-leaves-5-injured</link><description>At least five people were injured when a cocktail was hurled in a clash between the National Citizen Party (NCP) and the BNP’s student front, Chhatra Dal, in Shariatpur, police said.
The incident occurred on Monday evening during a protest procession by NCP leaders and activists through the</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 16:01:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fun to dream, harder to do the math</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/fun-to-dream-harder-to-do-the-math</link><description>It is often suggested—sometimes wistfully, sometimes with great confidence—that if Bangladesh simply adopts a specific policy (or a specific set of policies), it can “become the next Singapore.” This is an uplifting thought, but simple arithmetic delivers a gentle reality ch</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 16:16:08 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>