<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 16:29:35 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>CMP reshuffles OCs at Sadarghat, Chandgaon, Double Mooring stations</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cmp-reshuffles-ocs-at-sadarghat-chandgaon-double-mooring-stations</link><description>Chattogram Metropolitan Police (CMP) has transferred the officers-in-charge (OCs) of three more police stations within a month.
On Wednesday, CMP Commissioner Hasib Aziz issued the transfer orders following directives from the Police Headquarters.
The reshuffle affects Sadarghat, Chandgaon and Do</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 13:00:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh chapter of SAARC Journalist Forum condoles death of ex-PM Khaleda Zia</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-chapter-of-saarc-journalist-forum-condoles-death-of-ex-pm-khaleda-zia</link><description>The Bangladesh chapter of the SAARC Journalist Forum (SJF) has expressed its profound sorrow and deep condolences at the demise of Begum Khaleda Zia, former prime minister of Bangladesh and chairperson of the Bangladesh Nationalist Party. 
“As the country’s first woman prime minis</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 13:15:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DU Metro Station closed from evening for 31st night security</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/du-metro-station-closed-from-evening-for-31st-night-security</link><description>The Dhaka University (DU) Metro Rail Station was temporarily closed from 7:00 pm on Wednesday due to security measures ahead of Thirty-first Night celebrations.
The Dhaka Mass Transit Company Limited (DMTCL) said in a statement that the closure was implemented following a special request from Dhak</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 13:30:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Precious metals cash in on record run, stocks bask in year-end glow</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/stock/global/precious-metals-cash-in-on-record-run-stocks-bask-in-year-end-glow</link><description>There was a last-minute selloff in precious metals markets on Wednesday as investors cashed in some of the year's massive gains in gold, silver and platinum, while stocks quietly consolidated their best year since before the COVID pandemic.
Most markets were on end-of-year autopilot after a roller</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 13:45:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khaleda built BNP into a major force: Monju</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/khaleda-zia-made-bnp-a-major-political-force-muzzammil-husain</link><description>Senior journalist Muzzammil Husain Monju has described the leadership of former prime minister Khaleda Zia as “extraordinary”, saying it was under her stewardship that the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) emerged as a major political force.
The political analyst made the remarks whil</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 14:00:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dialogue with journalists on technology-facilitated gender-based violence held</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dialogue-with-journalists-on-technology-facilitated-gender-based-violence-held</link><description>A dialogue with journalists on technology-facilitated gender-based violence (TFGBV), focusing on prevention, response, and the promotion of inclusive digital development, was held in the city on Tuesday.
The programme was organised by the Bangladesh NGOs Network for Radio and Communication (BNNRC)</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 14:15:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Former home minister Mahmudul Hasan passes away</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/former-home-minister-mahmudul-hasan-passes-away</link><description>Former home minister and BNP vice chairman Major General (Retd.) Mahmudul Hasan passed away on Wednesday at the age of 90.
Mahmudul Hasan, former Member of Parliament (MP) from Tangail-5 constituency, breathed his last at 3 pm at his residence in the capital due to old age complications.
Mahmudul</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 14:30:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Man dies after falling ill at Khaleda’s funeral</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/mourner-dies-after-falling-ill-at-khaleda-zias-funeral</link><description>A man has died after he fell ill after attending the funeral prayers of former prime minister and BNP chairperson Khaleda Zia.
The dead, identified as 56-year-old Nirob Hossain, hailed from Patuakhali’s Bauphal Upazila.
According to police, he fell ill and collapsed on Wednesday afternoon w</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 14:44:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gold prices drop by Tk 2,741 per bhori on year’s last trading day</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/gold-prices-drop-by-tk-2741-per-bhori-on-years-last-trading-day</link><description>Gold prices in the domestic market fell sharply on the last day of the year on Wednesday, with the price of 22-carat gold reduced by Tk 2,741 per bhori, according to the Bangladesh Jewellers Association (BAJUS).
Following the latest adjustment, the price of 22-carat gold has been fixed at Tk 224,1</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 14:59:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A defining crossroads: Bangladesh’s journey through 2025</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/a-defining-crossroads-bangladeshs-journey-through-2025</link><description>Bangladesh bade farewell to 2025 standing at a crossroads expecting to lead the South Asian nation to a new political and social transition against the backdrop of renewed public expectations. The year unfolded amid post–July Uprising realities, with governance reforms, electoral preparedness</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 15:14:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No progress of human rights in 2025: MSF</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/no-progress-of-human-rights-in-2025-msf</link><description>The rights body Manabadhikar Songskriti Foundation (MSF) has said the outgoing year 2025 saw no progress in Bangladesh’s human rights situation.
In its year-end assessment, the rights body said the overall political, social, democratic and legal climate, along with the human rights situation</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 15:29:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique declares Tk 20 million assets, cleared in 77 cases</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-declares-tk-20-million-assets-cleared-in-77-cases</link><description>Acting BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman, running from the Bogura-6 (Sadar) seat in the parliamentary elections, has submitted an affidavit declaring assets worth approximately Tk 19.7 million.
Returning to Bangladesh on Thursday after more than 17 years in the UK, the 57-year-old leader also disclosed</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 15:44:23 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>