<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 09:35:51 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>BTRC moves to award 700 MHz spectrum to GP amid legal challenge</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/btrc-moves-to-award-700-mhz-spectrum-to-gp-amid-legal-challenge</link><description>Bangladesh's telecom regulator has moved forward with a controversial allocation of 700 MHz spectrum to Grameenphone (GP), despite unresolved legal disputes, objections from rival operators and mounting accusations of regulatory bias that critics warn could further entrench market imbalance.
The B</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 06:00:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh seek 'miracle' to secure T20 World Cup participation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/bangladesh-seek-miracle-to-secure-t20-world-cup-participation</link><description>The Bangladesh Cricket Board (BCB) will meet with the country's interim government in a last-ditch attempt to secure the team's participation in next month's Twenty20 World Cup, following the rejection of their demand to shift their matches outside India on Wednesday.
The International Cricket Cou</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 06:15:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique promises family cards for 40m households</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-promises-family-cards-for-40m-households</link><description>BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman has said his party would introduce family cards for 40 million households if his party comes to power.
He made the remarks on Thursday during an interactive discussion with youths at a hotel in Sylhet.
The BNP leader said the card would be issued in the name of the fem</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 06:30:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>59pc of BNP’s candidates facing financial liabilities, TIB finds</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/59pc-of-bnps-candidates-facing-financial-liabilities-tib-finds</link><description>Nearly 59 per cent of the BNP’s candidates contesting in the parliamentary polls have outstanding loans, according to Transparency International Bangladesh (TIB).
The findings were disclosed at a press conference in Dhaka on Thursday, where the local chapter of Berlin-based Transparency Inte</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 06:45:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tax compliance won't improve without transparency in expenditure: Experts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/tax-compliance-wont-improve-without-transparency-in-expenditure-experts</link><description>Tax compliance in Bangladesh will remain weak unless taxpayers can clearly see how their money is being spent, economists and business leaders said on Wednesday, highlighting transparency and fairness as key challenges in revenue administration.
They made the remarks at a seminar held at the BDBL</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 07:00:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Barapukuria Unit-I resumes power generation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/barapukuria-unit-i-resumes-power-generation</link><description>Electricity generation has resumed at Unit-1 of the Barapukuria coal-fired Thermal Power Plant in Dinajpur after a four-day shutdown caused by a boiler tube failure.
Chief Engineer of the Barapukuria Thermal Power Plant under Parbatipur upazila, Md Abu Bakar Siddique, confirmed the development las</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 07:58:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt to procure 27m litres of soybean oil, 30,000 tonnes of fertiliser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/govt-to-procure-27m-litres-of-soybean-oil-30000-tonnes-of-fertiliser</link><description>The government on Wednesday approved the procurement of 27.15 million litres of refined soybean oil and 30,000 tonnes of fertiliser, along with the construction of fertiliser warehouses.
The approvals came at a meeting of the Advisory Council Committee on Government Purchase, chaired by Finance</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 08:13:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Saudi Arabia,, Qatar and five other countries to join Trump's 'Board of Peace'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/saudi-arabia-qatar-and-five-other-countries-to-join-trumps-board-of-peace</link><description>Saudi Arabia, Turkey, Egypt, Jordan, Indonesia, Pakistan and Qatar have accepted invitations to join US President Donald Trump's "Board of Peace", the Saudi foreign ministry said in a joint statement that also included the United Arab Emirates.
The statement added that each country will sign acces</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 08:30:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Subsidised rice sale begins under additional OMS</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/subsidised-rice-sale-begins-under-additional-oms</link><description>The government has started selling rice at a subsidised rate of Tk 30 per kg under the additional Open Market Sale (OMS) programme in 419 upazilas to stabilise rice prices and provide price support to people.
Under the programme, one metric tonne of rice will be distributed in each upazila.
The a</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 08:45:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Spinning mill owners threaten indefinite shutdown from Feb 1</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/spinning-mill-owners-threaten-indefinite-shutdown-from-feb-1</link><description>Spinning mill owners warned of an indefinite shutdown of all mills from February 1 if the Ministry of Commerce does not implement its recommendation to withdraw the bond facility on the import of 10–30 count cotton yarn within the next seven days.
They also demanded incentives or equivalent</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 09:00:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique promises more support for farmers, canal dredging</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/tarique-promises-more-support-for-farmers-canal-dredging</link><description>BNP Chairperson Tarique Rahman on Thursday said his party wants to stand by farmers across Bangladesh and would restart canal excavation programme to improve irrigation and water management if BNP wins the election.
"BNP would be able to stand beside farmers if voters elect the party's 'Sheaf of P</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 09:15:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>FE roundtable on Banking Sector Reforms begins shortly</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/fe-roundtable-on-banking-sector-reforms-begins-shortly</link><description>A roundtable discussion titled ‘Banking Sector Reforms', organised by The Financial Express (FE), is set to begin shortly at Six Seasons Hotel in Dhaka.
The event will bring together policymakers, economists, bankers and industry experts to discuss key challenges facing the country’s b</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 09:30:46 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>