<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 03:16:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>BBC not ‘institutionally biased’: memo author</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/europe/bbc-is-not-institutionally-biased-says-author-of-critical-memo</link><description>The author of a report that plunged the BBC into crisis said the broadcaster was not "institutionally biased", and he had hoped his criticisms would lead to improvements.
Michael Prescott, a former editorial advisor, compiled a dossier on issues within BBC News, including failings in the editing o</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 16:27:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IU removes professor over unauthorized absence</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/iu-removes-professor-over-unauthorized-absence</link><description>The authorities of Islamic University in Kushtia dismissed Professor Bikash Chandra Singh of the Information and Communication Technology department, citing unauthorized absence and breaches of institutional discipline.
The decision was issued on Monday in an office order signed by acting registra</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 16:42:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh Bank extends loan rescheduling facility for defaulters</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladesh-bank-extends-loan-rescheduling-facility-for-defaulters</link><description>Bangladesh Bank (BB) has further expanded the scope of policy support available to classified loan borrowers.
All loans classified as adverse (defaulted) on upcoming November 30 will now be eligible for rescheduling under a special facility. This new concession aims to help restructure the busines</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 16:57:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>TIB voices concern over arrest of Baul Abul Sarkar, attack on supporters</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tib-voices-concern-over-arrest-of-baul-abul-sarkar-attack-on-supporters</link><description>Transparency International Bangladesh (TIB) has expressed deep concern over the arrest of Baul artiste Abul Sarkar in Manikganj and the mob attack on his supporters during a peaceful protest, warning that the incidents pose a serious threat to the country’s religious, social and cultural dive</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 17:12:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chattogram Port logs rise in cargo, container flow</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/chattogram-port-logs-rise-in-cargo-container-flow</link><description>Chattogram Port has recorded growth in both container and cargo handling in the first 10 months of the year, with improvements also seen in ship berthing time.
The port authority said in a statement on Monday that about 2.85 million TEUs (20-foot equivalent units) of import and export containers w</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 17:27:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Man hacked to death in front of home in Mohammadpur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/man-hacked-to-death-in-front-of-home-in-mohammadpur</link><description>Police have confirmed the death of a man from hacking at Dhaka Udyan in the capital’s Mohammadpur.
Mohammadpur Police Inspector Mofiz Uddin said the victim, identified as Billal Hossain alias Babu, 26, was hacked in front of his home at 7:45pm.
He was declared dead when taken to the hospita</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 17:58:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique warns against unchecked push for LDC graduation</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-warns-against-unchecked-push-for-bangladeshs-ldc-graduation</link><description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman has warned that Bangladesh’s planned graduation from Least Developed Country (LDC) status in 2026 should not proceed without open debate, warning that such a major decision carries long-term economic consequences
In a detailed Facebook post from London on M</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 18:13:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Banks can offer spl loan-rescheduling facility up to Nov 30</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/banks-can-offer-spl-loan-rescheduling-facility-up-to-nov-30</link><description>Commercial banks now can offer special rescheduling facility for up to 10 years with a two-year grace period to borrowers whose loans are classified as of November 30, under a generous government bailout package.
In a major regulatory policy shift, the central bank issued Monday a circular relaxin</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 18:28:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tax target revised upward by Tk 540b</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/tax-target-revised-upward-by-tk-540b</link><description>The government has reviser the tax-revenue-collection target upward by Tk 540 billion to meet a growing need for internal resources to manage budget deficit.
Debt service has become a major headache for the government as loans taken from foreign and domestic sources have reached an optimum level.</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 01:53:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Early signs of economic recovery emerge amid sluggish growth: MCCI</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/early-signs-of-economic-recovery-emerge-amid-sluggish-growth-mcci</link><description>The first quarter (Q1) of the current fiscal year shows early signs of economic recovery, though overall growth remains sluggish, the Metropolitan Chamber of Commerce and Industry, Dhaka (MCCI) has said.
"Improvements in exports, imports, inflation, and remittances have helped stabilise foreign-cu</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 02:08:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Agent banking loses steam amid new female participation rule</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/agent-banking-loses-steam-amid-new-female-participation-rule</link><description>The expansion of agent banking in Bangladesh has slowed, both in terms of outlets and agents, a development widely attributed to a new regulatory requirement aimed at increasing female participation in the sector.
Bangladesh Bank data shows the number of new agent bankers fell from 16,019 in Decem</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 02:23:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bhutan's first transit shipment thru Ctg port set for release today</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bhutans-first-transit-shipment-thru-ctg-port-set-for-release-today</link><description>CHATTOGRAM: Bhutan's maiden transit shipment through Chattogram port is scheduled for delivery today (Tuesday), two months after its arrival was delayed due to pending approvals from multiple agencies.
The container, unloaded in September, remained stuck as several clearances were not issued on ti</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 02:38:26 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>