<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 08:25:32 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Coach detachment disrupts train service on Dhaka–Mymensingh route</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/coach-detachment-disrupts-train-service-on-dhaka-mymensingh-route</link><description>Train movement on the Dhaka–Mymensingh route was disrupted for nearly half an hour on Saturday night after a coach of the Jamalpur Express got detached while running through Gafargaon upazila in Mymensingh district.
Sub-inspector Golam Kibria, in charge of the Gafargaon Railway outpost, said</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 06:19:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fire guts 13 shops in Bandarban</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/fire-guts-13-shops-in-bandarban</link><description>A fire has ripped through a market in Bandarban’s Thanchi Upazila, burning down at least 13 shops.
The fire broke out in the early hours of Sunday in Bolipara Union's Bolibazar, according to Peer Mohammad, chief of the Thanchi Thana Fire Station.
"We left for Bolibazar immediately after rec</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 06:49:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gas explosion leaves six workers injured in Narayanganj</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/gas-explosion-leaves-six-workers-injured-in-narayanganj</link><description>Six workers suffered burn injuries in a gas explosion while working at a dyeing factory in the BSCIC industrial area of Narayanganj on Sunday.
The explosion occurred around 8:30 am in the boiler room on the ground floor of the factory, reports UNB.
The injured workers --Al Amin, 30, Azizulla, 32,</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 05:52:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hilsa ban ends, fishermen start sailing for fishing</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/hilsa-ban-ends-fishermen-start-sailing-for-fishing</link><description>The fishermen across the country start heading back to rivers and the sea for fishing Hilsha as the 22-day nationwide ban on its catching, transporting, and selling ends last midnight.
With the ban lifting at midnight, trawlers sailed early Sunday, marking the resumption of Hilsa fishing across th</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 06:07:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Depression over Bay deepens, may turn into cyclone within 24 hours</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/depression-over-bay-deepens-may-turn-into-cyclone-within-24-hours</link><description>A low-pressure system over the southeast Bay of Bengal has intensified into a deep depression, with the Bangladesh Meteorological Department (BMD) warning that it could develop into a cyclonic storm within the next 24 hours.
In a special weather bulletin issued on Sunday, the BMD said that at 6 am</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 06:37:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump sets 10pc hike in tariffs on Canada</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/global/trump-sets-10pc-hike-in-tariffs-on-canada</link><description>US President Donald Trump said on Saturday he was increasing tariffs on Canada by an additional 10 per cent "above what they're paying now," as he reacted again to an ad by Canada's Ontario province, a day after it was aired during the World Series broadcast.
Trump on Thursday ended trade talks wi</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 06:52:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Another youth found dead on staircase</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/another-youth-found-dead-on-staircase</link><description>Within days of a similar gruesome discovery, another young man has been found dead in Old Dhaka, this time in the Bangshal area, with a GI cable wrapped tightly around his neck, raising alarm over a disturbing pattern of deaths in the capital’s old quarters.
The deceased, identified as Sajib</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 07:07:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Woman stabbed to death by husband in Gaibandha</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/woman-stabbed-to-death-by-husband-in-gaibandha</link><description>A woman, who was stabbed allegedly by her husband over a family feud in Gaibandha on Friday night, died while undergoing treatment on Saturday night.
The deceased was identified as Azeda Begum, 35, wife of Shamim Mia of MP Para under Gobindaganj municipality in the district, reports UNB.
Accordin</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 07:37:20 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>