<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 18:28:32 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>NCC Bank signs MoU with DNCC on collection of municipal charges</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ncc-bank-signs-mou-with-dncc-on-collection-of-municipal-charges</link><description>NCC Bank has recently signed a Memorandum of Understanding (MoU) with Dhaka North City Corporation (DNCC), enabling NCC Bank customers to conveniently pay various fees and taxes — including holding tax, trade license fee, hotel tax, market salami, wheel tax, other municipal charges — th</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 14:15:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BRAC Bank and IDCOL finance USD 67 million syndicated loan to BCRECL for large-scale solar power plant</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/brac-bank-and-idcol-finance-usd-67-million-syndicated-loan-to-bcrecl-for-large-scale-solar-power-plant</link><description>BRAC Bank PLC and Infrastructure Development Company Limited (IDCOL) have jointly financed a landmark renewable energy initiative,a 64.55 MW solar power plant, operated by Bangladesh China Renewable Energy Company Limited (BCRECL).
A ceremony was held on November 6, 2025at InterContinental Dhaka t</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 14:30:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chief justice calls for moral, not administrative, reform in judiciary</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/chief-justice-calls-for-moral-not-administrative-reform-in-judiciary</link><description>Chief Justice Syed Refaat Ahmed has said the judiciary must undergo reform to remain “relevant” with the times.
Speaking at a reunion event marking the 75th anniversary of Dhaka University’s Department of Islamic History and Culture on Saturday, he said the aim of reform is moral</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 15:00:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cop dies after falling ill in Cumilla</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/cop-dies-after-falling-ill-in-cumilla</link><description>A policeman in Cumilla died on Saturday after suddenly falling ill while on duty.
The deceased was identified as Md Ashraf, son of the late Kamrul Islam from Imrail village in Kasba upazila of Brahmanbaria, UNB reports. 
Ashraf was posted at the Debpur Police Outpost under Burichang Police S</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 15:15:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka Bank holds financial literacy, career counselling program for youth</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/dhaka-bank-holds-financial-literacy-career-counselling-program-for-youth</link><description>Dhaka Bank PLC successfully organized a “Financial Literacy &amp; Career Counselling Program for the Youth” on 26 October 2025 at Lalmatia Government Mohila College, Dhaka.
An interactive session, led by Mr. Md. Mostaque Ahmed, Deputy Managing Director of Dhaka Bank PLC, on Career Counsell</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 15:30:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Left Democratic Alliance warns of action if Chittagong Port lease not withdrawn</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/left-democratic-alliance-warns-of-action-if-chittagong-port-lease-not-withdrawn</link><description>The Left Democratic Alliance has warned that it will surround the State Guest House Jamuna, the official residence of the chief adviser, if the ‘plot to hand over the profitable Chittagong Port to foreigners’ is not stopped.
A two-week nationwide protest, mass mobilisation, and march p</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 15:45:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Jubo Dal’ attacks amaat-e-Islami rally in Jamalpur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/jubo-dal-attacks-amaat-e-islami-rally-in-jamalpur</link><description>Jamaat-e-Islami nominated MP candidate Abdus Sattar has accused the Jubo Dal of attacking his election rally in Jamalpur.
At least 10 Jamaat supporters were injured in the attack at Sadar Upazila on Saturday, party leaders claimed.
Meanwhile, the Jubo Dal has alleged a counter-attack, claiming Ja</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 16:00:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Over 125 primary teachers injured in police crackdown during pay protests</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/over-125-primary-teachers-injured-in-police-crackdown-during-pay-protests</link><description>At least 125 government primary school teachers have been injured and received treatment at Dhaka Medical College Hospital following a police crackdown on protesters demanding 10th-grade pay.
Several of the injured remain hospitalised, said Muhib Ullah, a teacher leading the protests, on Saturday,</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 16:30:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gaza death toll surpasses 69,000</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/gaza-death-toll-surpasses-69000</link><description>Health officials in Gaza said Saturday that more than 69,000 Palestinians have been killed since the start of the Israel-Hamas war, as both sides continued exchanging bodies under a shaky ceasefire agreement.
The increase in casualties comes as additional bodies are recovered from the rubble acros</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 16:45:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hasina branded July revolution supporters as extremists: Press Secretary</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/hasina-branded-july-revolution-supporters-as-extremists-press-secretary</link><description>Chief Adviser’s Press Secretary Shafiqul Alam has alleged that former Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina has branded millions who took part in or supported the July Revolution as “terrorists” and “Islamist extremists.”
“In effect, she is identifying nearly 180 million</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 17:00:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>60pc of mobile banking transactions done via feature phones</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/60pc-of-mobile-banking-transactions-done-via-feature-phones</link><description>Speakers at the Bangladesh Fintech Summit said about 60 per cent of mobile banking transactions in Bangladesh are made through feature phones, showing that simple devices still play a big role in financial inclusion.
They said digital banking is cutting costs and simplifying services, helping peop</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 17:45:46 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Telecom guidelines protect foreign interests, claim domestic entrepreneurs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/telecom-guidelines-protect-foreign-interests-claim-domestic-entrepreneurs</link><description>Local entrepreneurs have alleged that the four new guidelines formulated under the Telecommunications Ordinance favour foreign investors and telecom operators, sidelining domestic businesses.
They made the allegations at a meeting organised by the Telecom and Technology Reporters Network Banglades</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 18:00:46 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>