<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 23:20:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Tthree motorcyclists killed in Bagerhat road accident</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tthree-motorcyclists-killed-in-bagerhat-road-accident</link><description>Three motorcyclists were killed in a bus and truck collision at Belai Bridge on the Khulna-Mongla highway in Rampal upazila of Bagerhat on Tuesday.
The deceased were identified as Jamir Ijaddar, 50, Mizan Bepari, 45 and Haripada Roy, 40, all residents of Rajnagar Union under Rampal upazila, report</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 16:28:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat for referendum in Nov, election in Feb</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-for-referendum-in-nov-election-in-feb</link><description>Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami on Tuesday called on the interim government to hold the referendum on the July Charter within November and to ensure parliamentary elections in February next year. 
The demand was made at a meeting of the party's Central Executive Council chaired by Ameer Dr. Shafiq</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 16:43:41 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Vatican minister calls Rohingya plight 'a real shame'</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/vatican-minister-calls-rohingya-plight-a-real-shame</link><description>Visiting Vatican Minister Cardinal Michael Felix Czerny has described the prolonged suffering of the Rohingya people as "a real shame," expressing deep concern over the international community's failure to find a lasting solution to their crisis.
"The situation for the Rohingya in Cox's Bazar is v</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 17:28:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh firms ink $1b soybean deal with US</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/bangladesh-firms-ink-1b-soybean-deal-with-us</link><description>In a major boost to bilateral trade, a consortium of Bangladesh's top soy crushing companies, Meghna Group, City Group, and Delta Agro, has committed to purchasing $1 billion worth of U.S. soybeans over the next twelve months.

The landmark agreement with the U.S. Soybean Export Council (USSEC),</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 17:58:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BRUCSU polls: Six-member election commission formed</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/brucsu-polls-six-member-election-commission-formed</link><description>A six-member Election Commission has been formed for organizing the Begum Rokeya University Central Students' Union (BRUCSU) and Hall Students' Union (HTU) elections for the first time since establishment of the university. 
This decision was finalized at the 116th syndicate meeting held in t</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 18:13:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>On pre-approval regulations for high-value LCs</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/on-pre-approval-regulations-for-high-value-lcs</link><description>With the holy month of Ramadan coming closer, there is a growing need to import essential commodities. In the wake of the previous Ramadan, in January 2025, Bangladesh had imported US$1 billion worth of dates, sugar, wheat, lentils, onions, chickpeas, and raw palm and soybean oil. This year, a cong</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 18:14:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Three books that make English simple, smart, and practical</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/reviews/three-books-that-make-english-simple-smart-and-practical</link><description>Once feared as a difficult subject, English is now being embraced as a skill of empowerment. Khan, a seasoned teacher and English news presenter for Bangladesh Television and Betar, has translated his decades of experience into these three accessible and impactful books, according to a press statem</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 18:29:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Is restoration of Dhaka's rivers elusive?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/is-restoration-of-dhakas-rivers-elusive</link><description>While rivers across Bangladesh face grave vulnerabilities-encroachment, pollution, siltation, and declining navigability-the situation is particularly dire for the rivers surrounding Dhaka. A couple of them are practically lifeless, having lost their channels altogether. Despite repeated calls for</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 18:44:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Go ahead to transport master plan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/go-ahead-to-transport-master-plan</link><description>To say that the communication system of Bangladesh is in a chaotic state is to say the least. One need not be an expert to reach such a conclusion. In fact, it is obvious to anyone commuting within the city or travel to destinations closer or farther from any point in the country. To resolve the cr</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 18:59:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hopes fade for legal hurdles, interagency conflicts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/hopes-fade-for-legal-hurdles-interagency-conflicts</link><description>A much-hyped drive by the post-uprising interim government to recover a cache of stolen assets may not see success during its term as intelligence-insiders find no hope yet for formidable hurdles.



Even evaded tax-recovery steps have stagnated as legal barriers restrict the realisation of s</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 19:14:43 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>