<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 15:24:30 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Economy returns on positive track: CA</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/economy-returns-on-positive-track-ca</link><description>Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus on Thursday said all economic indicators, including exports, foreign investment and reserves, have returned to a positive trajectory after the July Uprising.
“After assuming the office following the uprising, rescuing the economy from a deep crisis was</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 11:45:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Judge’s son stabbed to death; wife injured in Rajshahi home attack</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/judges-son-stabbed-to-death-wife-injured-in-rajshahi-home-attack</link><description>Unidentified assailants stabbed and killed the son of Rajshahi Metropolitan and Sessions Judge Mohammad Abdur Rahman at their residence in Dabtala area of Rajshahi on Thursday afternoon.
The deceased was identified as Tawseef Rahman Suman, son of the judge.
Abdur Rahman's wife, Tasmin Nahar, was</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 12:00:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Al-Arafah Islami Bank signs Strategic Partnership with Deen Islamic</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/al-arafah-islami-bank-signs-strategic-partnership-with-deen-islamic</link><description>Al-Arafah Islami Bank PLC, the country’s leading Shariah-compliant financial institution has signed a Strategic Partnership Agreement with Maverick Enterprise Limited (Deen Islamic), one of the most dynamic and integrated Islamic digital platforms, to strengthen Islamic lifestyle solutions an</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 12:15:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BRAC Bank inaugurates new sub-branch in Bashundhara</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/brac-bank-inaugurates-new-sub-branch-in-bashundhara</link><description>BRAC Bank has opened a new sub-branch in Bashundhara Residential Area in Dhaka. 
Tareq Refat Ullah Khan, Managing Director &amp; CEO, BRAC Bank, formally inaugurated the sub-branch at JCX Tower at Block I in Bashundhara on November 9, 2025, according to a press release.
Sheikh Mohammad Ashfaque,</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 12:30:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh makes notable progress in maintaining macroeconomic stability: IMF</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh-makes-notable-progress-in-maintaining-macroeconomic-stability-imf</link><description>The International Monetary Fund (IMF) on Thursday observed that Bangladesh authorities have made progress in maintaining macroeconomic stability and advancing reforms.
“The authorities have made notable progress in maintaining macroeconomic stability. To ease external imbalances and contain</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 12:45:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>President issues order to implement July Charter; gazette published</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/president-issues-order-to-implement-july-charter-gazette-published</link><description>President Mohammed Shahabuddin has issued a formal order to implement the July National Charter (Constitution Reform), marking the completion of the July National Charter 2025 process.
The order was published in an official gazette on Thursday.
According to the gazette, a referendum will be held</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 13:00:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prof Ali Riaz appointed CA’s special assistant</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/prof-ali-riaz-appointed-cas-special-assistant</link><description>The government has appointed Professor Ali Riaz as Special Assistant to the Chief Adviser.
The Cabinet Division issued a notification in this regard on Thursday.
According to the notification, he will enjoy the rank, salary, allowances and other facilities equivalent to those of an Adviser during</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 13:15:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat holding emergency meeting after CA’s address</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jamaat-holding-emergency-meeting-after-cas-address</link><description>Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami’s central executive council is holding an emergency meeting to work out its next course of action following the chief adviser’s announcement that the national election and the referendum will be held on the same day.
The meeting began on Thursday evening at t</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 13:30:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nurul Kabir, Dewan Hanif Mahmud made president, GS of Editor’s Council</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/nurul-kabir-dewan-hanif-mahmud-made-president-gs-of-editors-council</link><description>The New Age Editor Nurul Kabir and the Editor and Publisher of the daily Banik Barta Dewan Hanif Mahmud have been elected as president and general secretary respectively of the Editor’s Council today for a two-year term.
Besides, the daily Ittefaq Editor Tasmima Hossain as vice president, th</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 13:45:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Afghans carried out two suicide bombings in Pakistan, says minister</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/afghans-carried-out-two-suicide-bombings-in-pakistan-says-minister</link><description>Afghan nationals carried out two suicide bombings in Pakistan this week, including one in the capital Islamabad, Interior Minister Mohsin Naqvi said on Thursday, amid sharpening tensions between the South Asian neighbours over militant violence.
Both the bombers involved in the attacks have been i</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 14:00:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Leftist parties reject referendum as ‘unnecessary’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/leftist-groups-outside-july-charter-reject-referendum-as-unconstitutional-redundant</link><description>Several left-leaning political parties that did not sign the July National Charter have labelled the referendum proposed by Chief Advisor Muhammad Yunus as “unnecessary and extra-constitutional”.
Immediately following Yunus’s address to the nation on Thursday, these parties expre</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 14:15:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Elected parliament will solve country’s impending issues: Fakhrul</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/elected-parliament-will-solve-countrys-impending-issues-fakhrul</link><description>BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam today (Thursday) said that  elected parliament will resolve the country's impending issues.
“The elected parliament will address and resolve the country’s unresolved issues through discussions,” he said while speaking at a discussion</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 14:30:52 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>