<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 19:06:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Salahuddin takes massive lead in Cox’s Bazar-1</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/salahuddin-takes-massive-lead-in-coxs-bazar-1</link><description>BNP leader Salahuddin Ahmed has taken a commanding lead in Cox’s Bazar-1 constituency.
Unofficial results show Salahuddin has secured 102,110 votes in 74 out of 177 polling centres, reports UNB.
His nearest rival, Jamaat-e-Islami candidate Abdullah Al Faruk received 45,073 votes in the same</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 18:06:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP sweeps Thakurgaon as Fakhrul praises peaceful polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bnp-sweeps-thakurgaon-as-fakhrul-praises-peaceful-polls</link><description>The Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) has won all three of Thakurgaon’s three parliamentary constituencies in the 13th National Election.
In Thakurgaon-1, the party's secretary general Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir, contesting on the BNP’s much-loved ‘Sheaf of Paddy’ symbol,</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 16:36:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tarique Rahman wins both Dhaka-17, Bogura-6 seats</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/tarique-rahman-wins-both-dhaka-17-bogura-6-seats</link><description>BNP Chairman Tarique Rahman has been unofficially declared elected from the Dhaka-17 and Bogura-6 constituencies in the country’s 13th national election.
BNP Election Steering Committee spokesperson Dr Mahdi Amin shared the information at a press briefing on Thursday night.
He, however, did</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 16:51:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AI challenges Bangladesh's promise of inclusion</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/ai-challenges-bangladeshs-promise-of-inclusion</link><description>For more than a decade, 'Digital Bangladesh' was not merely a political slogan; it functioned as a practical framework for governance, service delivery, and socio-economic transformation. Internet connectivity expanded rapidly, government services became digitised, and millions of citizens-many of</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 17:06:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>An evening in Riyadh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/reviews/an-evening-in-riyadh</link><description>"Welcome to Riyadh!" said the young immigration officer after stamping my passport with a smile. Before stamping, he wanted to know about my profession. Learning that I am a journalist and writer, he also wished to see if I am accustomed to travelling frequently and writing about my trips. His ques</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 17:21:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A poster-free election and a lesson for Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/a-poster-free-election-and-a-lesson-for-dhaka</link><description>Bangladesh voted in a national election without the familiar scene of posters plastered all over the wall, electric poles, footbridges, roadside trees, and public transports. This phenomenon is a first in the history of national elections in the country. The decision of the Election Commission in b</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 17:36:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP leader Fazlur Rahman wins Kishoreganj-4 seat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bnp-leader-fazlur-rahman-wins-kishoreganj-4-seat</link><description>BNP leader Fazlur Rahman emerged victorious with 132,553 votes in all 150 polling centres in Kishoreganj-4 (Itna-Mithamain-Austagram).
His closest competitor, Jamaat candidate Rokun Reza Sheikh, secured 55,646 votes.
Election officials confirmed that the results were final as counting in all cent</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 17:51:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Those responsible for low CPI ranking must be held accountable</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/those-responsible-for-low-cpi-ranking-must-be-held-accountable</link><description>That Bangladesh is world's 13th most corrupt country among the 182 states assessed by the Berlin-based Transparency International (TI) is disgraceful. Only more so because the improved ranking from 2006 to 2017 could not be maintained! The highest ever score for the country was 28 in 2017.  Du</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 18:06:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh-US trade deal: prospects and pitfalls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/bangladesh-us-trade-deal-prospects-and-pitfalls</link><description>The signing of a trade deal with the United States at the fag-end of the interim government's tenure has understandably raised many eyebrows, particularly because of its non-disclosure clauses. The limited information released so far suggests a mixed picture-one that promises new opportunities but</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 18:21:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP candidate Md Shariful Alam wins Kishoreganj-6 by huge margin</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bnp-candidate-md-shariful-alam-wins-kishoreganj-6-by-huge-margin</link><description>BNP candidate Md Shariful Alam won by a massive margin after securing 185,813 votes in all 142 polling centres In Kishoreganj-6 (Bhairab-Kuliarchar) constituency, according to unofficial results. 
His nearest rival, 11-party alliance candidate Maulana Ataullah Amin contesting with the ‘</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 18:36:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jamaat’s Golam Parwar defeated in Khulna-5</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/jamaats-golam-parwar-defeated-in-khulna-5</link><description>Khulna-5 constituency saw a closely contested race as Bangladesh Jamaat-e-Islami Secretary General Mia Golam Parwar was defeated in the parliamentary election.
Golam Parwar, who contested with the party’s electoral symbol 'Dandipalla' (scales), secured 144,956 votes.
The seat was won by BNP</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 18:51:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Lutfozzaman Babar wins Netrokona-4 seat</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/lutfozzaman-babar-wins-netrokona-4-seat</link><description>BNP-nominated candidate and former state minister for home affairs Lutfozzaman Babar has been unofficially elected from the Netrokona-4 constituency.
He secured 160,801 votes with the sheaf of paddy symbol, defeating his nearest rival, Jamaat-e-Islami candidate Md Al Helal, by a margin of 120,961</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 19:06:19 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>