<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 11:19:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Ex-minister Abdul Latif Siddique secures HC bail</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ex-minister-abdul-latif-siddique-secures-hc-bail</link><description>The High Court on Thursday granted bail to former minister Abdul Latif Siddique in a case filed under the Anti-Terrorism Act.
The HC bench of Justice ASM Abdul Mobin and Justice Md Sagir Hossain passed the order after hearing a petition seeking bail for him.
The court also granted bail to journal</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 09:10:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt plans ordinance to punish airline ticket syndicates in Bangladesh</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/govt-plans-ordinance-to-punish-airline-ticket-syndicates-in-bangladesh</link><description>The government is set to promulgate an ordinance amending the Civil Aviation Act, 2017, to curb the activities of airline ticket syndicates.
The Ministry of Civil Aviation and Tourism has drafted the Civil Aviation (Amendment) Ordinance, 2025, in this regard, according to sources at the ministry.</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 09:25:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP’s Mosharraf calls on people to unite for fair Feb election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnps-mosharraf-calls-on-people-to-unite-for-fair-feb-election</link><description>BNP senior leader Khandaker Mosharraf Hossain on Thursday urged people from all walks of life to extend their cooperation in holding the next national election in February next year, foiling all conspiracies to derail it.
“It seems to us that there is no scope for deferring the election from</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 09:55:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Former Bangladesh Bank deputy governor SK Sur indicted in graft case</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/former-bangladesh-bank-deputy-governor-sk-sur-indicted-graft-case</link><description>A court today (Thursday) framed charges against former deputy governor of Bangladesh Bank SK Sur Chowdhury in a case filed by the Anti-Corruption Commission (ACC) for not filing a wealth statement.
Judge Ayesha Nasrin of the Dhaka Special Judge Court-2 passed the order, initiating the trial offici</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 10:04:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Can we rediscover our love for books?</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/others/can-we-rediscover-our-love-for-books</link><description>"Reading stamina really is a thing. I used to read entire chapter books within a few days, but after a year-long break from reading, I can barely read for an hour and now finish books in a week or more." This isn't the story of one individual; it reflects the experience of many today. According to</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 10:19:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt okays draft ordinance on enforced disappearance with capital punishment</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-okays-draft-ordinance-on-enforced-disappearance-with-capital-punishment</link><description>The government today (Thursday) gave final approval to the draft of 'Enforced Disappearance Prevention and Redress Ordinance 2025', introducing capital punishment and other tough penalties for the offence.
The Council of Advisers gave the approval at its 47th meeting at the Chief Adviser's Office</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 11:04:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IPDC provides free eye check-up and spectacles for support staff</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ipdc-provides-free-eye-check-up-and-spectacles-for-support-staff</link><description>IPDC Finance PLC. successfully completed a free eye check-up campaign as part of its recently concluded Wellness Week.
Based on the assessment of the check-up, 17 support staff received free spectacles, according to a media release.  
During the campaign, all employees and support staff</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 11:19:26 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>