<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 19:11:54 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Four policemen ‘removed’ over assault on student, journalists at Suhrawardy Udyan</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/four-policemen-removed-over-assault-on-student-journalists-at-suhrawardy-udyan</link><description>Four policemen have been withdrawn from their duties following the alleged assault on a Dhaka University student and two journalists during a raid at the Suhrawardy Udyan.
The incident, which occurred on Monday night, sparked protests outside the Shahbagh Police Station on Tuesday.
Dhaka Universi</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 15:40:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Three BB officials ‘immediately transferred’</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/three-central-bank-officials-immediately-transferred-after-show-cause-notices</link><description>The Bangladesh Bank has ordered immediate transfer (stand release) of three officials who received show cause notices for breach of discipline.
The central bank had served them the notices two days ago for calling a press briefing alleging that digital banks were getting approval before the format</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 15:55:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Magura clash over local dominance leaves 10 injured</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/magura-clash-over-local-dominance-leaves-10-injured</link><description>At least 10 people were injured in a clash between two groups over local dominance in Shrikol Union, Shreepur Upazila, Magura, late Monday night.
The confrontation involved retaliatory attacks and a grenade explosion in the villages of Chonogacha and Doshtina.
The injured were admitted to Magura</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 16:10:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>No financial transaction or broker needed to get family card</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/no-financial-transaction-or-broker-needed-to-get-family-card</link><description>The government today said that any financial transaction through brokers or other intermediaries to obtain the Family Card is illegal.
The Family Card is a priority programme of the present government and it is firmly committed to implementing the initiative. 
The information was disclosed i</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 16:40:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Korean FM greets Khalilur Rahman; eyes enhanced ties with Dhaka</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/korean-fm-greets-khalilur-rahman-eyes-enhanced-ties-with-dhaka</link><description>South Korean Foreign Minister Cho Hyun has said he looks forward to working closely with his newly appointed Bangladesh counterpart Dr Khalilur rahman to further enhance the bilateral relations in the years to come.
“I would like to extend my heartfelt congratulations on your appointment as</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 16:55:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>'Family Card' completely free, no scope for demanding money: Zahid</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/family-card-completely-free-no-scope-for-demanding-money-zahid</link><description>Social Welfare and Women and Children Affairs Minister Dr AZM Zahid today (Tuesday) said the government's 'Family Card' programme will be implemented entirely free of cost, with no scope for anyone to demand money in exchange for the card.
"If anyone attempts to commit fraud in this regard, legal</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 17:10:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Alternative model of commercial banking</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/alternative-model-of-commercial-banking</link><description>Can we not look for an alternative model of banking business where   depositors would be placed in a new relationship, and lending conditionalities would change? Banks deal in money mostly owned by depositors while deposits are neither  termed  as  equity  fund  nor &amp;n</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 16:59:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How to revive WTO now in existential crisis</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/how-to-revive-wto-now-in-existential-crisis</link><description>That the World Trade Organisation (WTO) is facing an existential crisis is no longer a matter of debate. What was once the cornerstone of global trade governance has been rendered largely ineffective, raising serious questions about its continued relevance. Much of this stems from the shifting post</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 17:14:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Let the Family Card deliver</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/let-the-family-card-deliver</link><description>The proposed Family Card programme has become one of the most talked about policy initiatives of the present government, and for good reason. As reported, prime minister Tarique Rahman is going to formally launch the Family Card on March 10.  With this first major move, the newly formed BNP go</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 17:29:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bus service from Kolkata to Agartala via Dhaka operates for first time in 17 months</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bus-service-from-kolkata-to-agartala-via-dhaka-operates-for-first-time-in-17-months</link><description>The cross-border bus service linking West Bengal’s Kolkata with Tripura’s Agartala via Dhaka has resumed after being suspended for nearly 17 months.
Akhaura Land Port Immigration Police chief Abdus Sattar said an Indian bus carrying six people, including three passengers, crossed into</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 17:44:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Government appoints Monjur Morshed Chowdhury as home secretary</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/government-appoints-monjur-morshed-chowdhury-as-home-secretary</link><description>The government has appointed retired secretary Monjur Morshed Chowdhury as the secretary at the Ministry of Home Affairs on a one-year contract.
The Ministry of Public Administration issued a notification on Tuesday stating that the appointment was made under Section 49 of the Government Service A</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 17:59:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ECNEC formed with PM Tarique Rahman as Chairperson</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/bangladesh/ecnec-formed-with-pm-tarique-rahman-as-chairperson</link><description>The government has formed the Executive Committee of the National Economic Council (ECNEC) with Prime Minister Tarique Rahman as its chairperson.
The committee was constituted through a gazette notification issued on Tuesday. The notification was signed by Md. Humayun Kabir, Additional Secretary (</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 18:14:04 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>