<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 16:28:28 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Rastro Songskar’s Hasnat Kaiyum knocked out of Kishoreganj-5 race after scrutiny</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/rastro-songskars-hasnat-kaiyum-knocked-out-of-kishoreganj-5-race-after-scrutiny</link><description>Hasnat Kaiyum, chief coordinator of Rastro Songskar Andolan, has been ruled ineligible to run for parliament from the Kishoreganj-5 constituency.
Independent aspirant Sheikh Mujibur Rahman Iqbal, president of the Upazila unit of the BNP, has also been barred from standing for that seat, bdnews24.c</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 13:48:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Govt committed to ensuring justice in Osman Hadi murder: Foreign adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/govt-committed-to-ensuring-justice-in-osman-hadi-murder-foreign-adviser</link><description>Foreign Affairs Adviser Md Touhid Hossain has said that the government is committed to bringing those involved in the murder of Osman Hadi to justice.
The adviser said, "The process is continuing to complete the trial as quickly as possible."
“We cannot rush the judicial process. We are try</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 14:03:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Family moved by nation’s outpouring of grief for Khaleda Zia: Tarique</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/family-moved-by-nations-outpouring-of-grief-for-khaleda-zia-tarique</link><description>BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman said on Saturday his family has been deeply moved by the continued outpouring of condolences and prayers from across the country and abroad following the death of his mother and former Prime Minister Khaleda Zia.
In a post on his official Facebook page, “As</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 14:18:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Venezuela vice president Rodriguez in Russia, four sources say</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/venezuela-vice-president-rodriguez-in-russia-four-sources-say</link><description>Venezuelan Vice President Delcy Rodriguez is in Russia, four sources familiar with her movements said on Saturday, after President Donald Trump said President Nicolas Maduro had been seized by US forces after an attack on the country.
Her brother, Jorge Rodriguez, the head of the national assembly</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 14:22:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Wahiduzzaman promoted to director of Bangladesh Bank</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/wahiduzzaman-promoted-to-director-of-bangladesh-bank</link><description>Wahiduzzaman Sardar, previously serving as additional director, has been promoted to the position of director (Research) at Bangladesh Bank.
The central bank’s Human Resources Department-1 issued an official notification regarding the promotion on Thursday, January 1.
Wahiduzzaman began his</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 14:37:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Brazil says US crossed 'unacceptable line' over military strikes on Venezuela</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/brazil-says-us-crossed-unacceptable-line-over-military-strikes-on-venezuela</link><description>Brazil's President Luiz Inacio Lula da Silva on Saturday condemned the U.S. military attack on neighbor Venezuela and the capture of his Venezuelan counterpart Nicolas Maduro, saying it crossed "an unacceptable line."
 
"These acts represent a grave affront to Venezuela's sovereignty and yet</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 14:52:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Advisor Fouzul to meet stakeholders amid LPG market volatility</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/advisor-fouzul-to-meet-stakeholders-amid-lpg-market-volatility</link><description>The price of a 12 kg LPG cylinder, officially fixed at Tk 1,253, has climbed by nearly Tk 1,000 in parts of Dhaka, leaving household users struggling as supplies tighten across the capital.
Against this backdrop, Power and Energy Advisor Fouzul Kabir Khan has said he will sit in discussions with s</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 15:07:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>JCD vows to confront conspiracies under Tarique Rahman’s leadership</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/jcd-vows-to-confront-conspiracies-under-tarique-rahmans-leadership</link><description>Bangladesh Jatiyatabadi Chhatra Dal (JCD) President Rakibul Islam Rakib on Saturday said the organisation would firmly confront all ongoing conspiracies against the country under the leadership of BNP Acting Chairman Tarique Rahman.
He made the remarks after paying tribute and offering prayers at</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 15:22:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ordinance toughens penalties for travel agency violations</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ordinance-toughens-penalties-for-travel-agency-violations</link><description>The government has promulgated an ordinance strengthening the regulatory framework for travel agencies, introducing up to one year’s imprisonment and fine up to TK 1.0 million for violations to ensure fair ticket pricing and protect passengers.
Issued by order of the President, the ordinance</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 15:43:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>131 candidates cleared for 15 Dhaka city constituencies</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/131-candidates-cleared-for-15-dhaka-city-constituencies</link><description>The scrutiny of nominations for the 15 constituencies in Dhaka city has found 131 candidates valid to contest in the parliamentary polls scheduled to be held on Feb 12.
The Election Commission has cancelled 62 nomination papers and suspended one.
The scrutiny was done at the returning officer&amp;rsq</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 15:58:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Salahuddin warns against exploiting religion for votes</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/salahuddin-warns-against-exploiting-religion-for-votes</link><description>BNP Standing Committee Member Salahuddin Ahmed has said that religion should neither be exploited for worldly gains, nor should people be misled with promises of heaven in exchange for votes.
“It is a major responsibility of Alem-Olama to take a clear stand against those who spread confusion</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 16:13:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP leader shot dead in Jashore in motorcycle drive-by attack</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-leader-shot-dead-in-jashore-in-motorcycle-drive-by-attack</link><description>Assailants have gunned down a BNP leader in Jashore Sadar Upazila, sending shockwaves through the local political community.
The incident occurred at around 6:50pm in Shankarpur on Saturday, outside the office of former municipal councillor Shahed Hossain Nayan, according to Inspector (Operations)</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 16:28:28 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>