<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 18:37:26 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>BGB deployed in Mirpur</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/border-guards-deployed-in-mirpur-on-first-day-of-election-campaign</link><description>The Border Guard Bangladesh (BGB) has been deployed in Mirpur on the first day of the election campaign.
The BGB said in a message that the move aims to preserve law and order ahead of the parliamentary polls.
The BGB personnel have been deployed only in Mirpur.</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 15:53:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BKMEA chief for curbing deferred-payment exports</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bkmea-chief-urges-for-curbing-deferred-payment-exports</link><description>BKMEA President Mohammad Hatem has called on policymakers and the central bank to address what he described as worsening bottlenecks in export financing and payment recovery.
Deferred payment structures allow buyers to extract excessive advantages and contribute to large sums of export proceeds re</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 18:01:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump sends message to Putin 'war has to end' after good meeting with Zelensky</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-sends-message-to-putin-war-has-to-end-after-good-meeting-with-zelensky</link><description>US President Donald Trump said his message to Russian leader Vladimir Putin was that the war in Ukraine has to end, after what he said were "good" talks with Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky in Davos on Thursday.
US and Ukrainian officials have spent weeks in frenetic shuttle diplomacy as Ky</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 15:45:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Banking sector reforms unavoidable to restore stability: FE Editor</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/banking-sector-reforms-unavoidable-to-restore-stability-fe-editor</link><description>Shamsul Huq Zahid, Editor and CEO of The Financial Express, on Saturday emphasised the urgent need to stabilise the country’s banking sector to support economic recovery and put growth back on an upward trajectory.
Speaking at the MTB–FE roundtable titled “Banking Sector Reforms&amp;</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 16:00:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BCB chief says if Bangladesh miss T20 World Cup, ICC will be big losers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/bcb-chief-says-if-bangladesh-miss-t20-world-cup-icc-will-be-big-losers</link><description>Bangladesh Cricket Board (BCB) President Aminul Islam Bulbul believes that if Bangladesh is unable to participate in next month’s Twenty20 World Cup, the International Cricket Council (ICC) itself will feel remorseful.
He asserted that Bangladesh would continue their struggle to ensure they</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 16:15:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UCB Chairman calls on next govt to take action on known loan defaulters</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/ucb-chairman-calls-on-next-govt-to-take-action-on-known-loan-defaulters</link><description>Sharif Zahir, Chairman of United Commercial Bank (UCB) PLC, has called for a clear political commitment from the future elected government to address Bangladesh’s growing banking sector challenges, particularly non-performing loans and capital shortfalls.
He made the remarks at the MTB&amp;ndash</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 16:30:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The risks for energy sector</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/views/the-risks-for-energy-sector</link><description>On January 7, 2026, the Interim Government's Advisor for the Ministry of Power, Energy and Mineral Resources Muhammad Fauzul Kabir Khan submitted to the Chief Adviser Prof. Muhammad Yunus a new 25-year power and energy sector master plan to be implemented during 2026-2050. As reported, the master p</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 16:45:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Back to school, back to contentious fees</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/opinions/back-to-school-back-to-contentious-fees</link><description>With the opening of schools across the country for the 2026 academic year, one thing that parents are hit with is the notorious concept of the "readmission fee." Although the government has banned schools from charging this fee, many educational institutions in Bangladesh, particularly in Dhaka, co</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 17:00:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Consequences of interim govt's indifference to law and order</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/columns/consequences-of-interim-govts-indifference-to-law-and-order</link><description>The press wing of the Chief Adviser has admitted that 645 incidents of violence against members of the minority communities occurred in 2025 but it clarifies that of those 71 could be categorised as communal. Only recently did the Human Rights Watch (HRW) expressed its deep concern over the rising</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 17:15:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Restructuring for administrative efficiency</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/editorial/restructuring-for-administrative-efficiency</link><description>In a significant move aimed at streamlining administrative efficiency, the interim government has recently unveiled a set of restructuring decisions involving steps towards enhancing transparency, efficiency and accountability across key state institutions. Presided over by the Chief Adviser, the m</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 17:30:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP leader shot and injured in Keraniganj</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-leader-shot-and-injured-in-keraniganj</link><description>A local BNP leader was injured in a gun attack by miscreants in Keraniganj on Thursday night.The victim was identified as Hasan Mollah, secretary of Hazratpur Union BNP under the Dhaka-2 constituency, UNB reports. He was shot by unidentified assailants around 9:00pm, said M Saiful Alam, Office</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 18:16:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dhaka court rejects journalist Anis Alamgir’s bail in anti-terror case</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dhaka-court-rejects-journalist-anis-alamgirs-bail-in-anti-terror-case</link><description>A Dhaka court has rejected journalist Anis Alamgir’s bail petition in a case filed under the Anti-Terrorism Act.
Judge Md Alamgir of the Additional Metropolitan Sessions Judge’s Court-1 passed the order on Thursday, lawyer Taslima Jahan Popy confirmed, bdnews24.com reports.
The CMM co</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 18:31:02 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>