<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 07:20:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>IUB's ICEBTM 2025: A bold academic push against Bangladesh's jobless crisis</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/analysis/iubs-icebtm-2025-a-bold-academic-push-against-bangladeshs-jobless-crisis</link><description>One key reason behind China's rapid economic growth is its success in aligning the needs of industry with the skills produced by universities. China deliberately promoted close cooperation between academia and industry, creating mechanisms that move scientific research quickly into commercial use.</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 05:03:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>When civilisation ceases to exist</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/views/analysis/when-civilisation-ceases-to-exist</link><description>Evolution of civilisation is a long process. From its tentative beginning, a civilisation also ascends its summit at certain point and then the decline of the process also begins. Like human species or any other living being a civilisation sees many ups and downs and ultimately meets its end. Sever</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 05:18:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Zubaida flies back to London</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/zubaida-flies-back-to-london</link><description>Zubaida Rahman, the wife of BNP leader Tarique Rahman, has set off for London ahead of her husband’s planned return to Bangladesh after more than a decade in the UK.
She left Dhaka on a Biman Bangladesh Airlines flight from Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport around 8:30 am on Saturday, a</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 05:03:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>WEEKLY KITCHEN MARKET: Vegetables, chicken, eggs get cheaper</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/weekly-kitchen-market-vegetables-chicken-eggs-get-cheaper</link><description>Prices of vegetables, newly-harvested onions and potatoes, eggs and chicken declined in last week.
New onions are selling in Dhaka for Tk 80-100 per kg, which is about Tk 10 less than the previous week, according to market sources.
A visit to Shekhertek-8, Rayer Bazar and a few other markets on F</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 05:18:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chhayanaut students take to street to protest attack</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/chhayanaut-students-take-to-street-to-protest-attack</link><description>Students and alumni of Bengali cultural organisation Chhayanaut and its educational wing Nalonda took to the street outside its burnt and vandalised building in the capital on Friday, protesting the latest attack on the institution.
The gathering took place hours after assailants vandalised and se</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 05:33:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Admission test of DU Science unit postponed</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/education/admission-test-of-du-science-unit-postponed</link><description>Dhaka University (DU) on Friday postponed its Science unit admission test, scheduled for today (Saturday), as a mark of respect following the death of Sharif Osman Hadi.
Saturday will be observed as a day of mourning at the DU, a press note says.
The revised schedule for the postponed examination</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 05:48:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Christiansen confirmed as US envoy to BD</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/christiansen-confirmed-as-us-envoy-to-bd</link><description>Brent Christiansen has been confirmed as the next US Ambassador to Bangladesh at a time of political transitions and heightened regional sensitivity in the South Asian nation.
Sources say the US Senate, the upper house of the American parliament, Congress, has consented to his current diplomatic a</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 06:03:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Extortionist arrested with arms, ammo in Ctg</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/extortionist-arrested-with-arms-ammo-in-ctg</link><description>CHATTOGRAM Dec 19: Police arrested an alleged extortionist on Thursday night over an extortion attempt at a construction site in Chattogram's Panchlaish area, where a group of attackers allegedly opened fire after the project owner refused to pay Tk 5.0 million. The arrested person, Md Didar (36),</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 06:18:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Child dies as BNP leader's house locked and set on fire</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/child-dies-as-bnp-leaders-house-locked-and-set-on-fire</link><description>A seven-year-old girl of a local BNP leader was burnt to death after miscreants locked their house from outside and set it on fire in Bhabaniganj of Lakshmipur’s Sadar upazila on Friday night.
The deceased, Ayesha Begum Binti, 7, was the youngest daughter of Md Belal, assistant organising se</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 06:34:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ICT prosecutor Zoha's home 'set ablaze' in Magura</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ict-prosecutor-zohas-home-set-ablaze-in-magura</link><description>The family home of BTV Director-General (DG) Mahbubul Alam and Tanvir Hassan Zoha, a prosecutor at the International Crimes Tribunal (ICT), has been hit by an apparent arson attack in Magura.
The incident occurred shortly after 10:30pm on Friday at "Zoha Bhaban", located opposite the Magura Distri</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 06:49:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Netizens urged to report posts inciting violence</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/netizens-urged-to-report-posts-inciting-violence</link><description>The National Cyber Security Agency has called on the public to report social media posts that promote terrorism or incite violence amid heightened concerns over online content linked to unrest.
In a statement issued on Saturday, the Ministry of Posts and Telecommunications said such posts could be</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 07:04:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Additional police, BGB deployed in Dhaka for Hadi's funeral</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/additional-police-bgb-deployed-in-dhaka-for-hadis-funeral</link><description>Border Guard Bangladesh (BGB) personnel have been deployed at the Parliament complex and several other key locations across Dhaka ahead of the funeral prayers for slain political activist Sharif Osman Hadi.
The border security force shared this development in a message issued on Saturday.
In addi</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 07:19:58 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>