<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepaul.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 16:34:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Remittance tops $3b for 2 months before polls</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/remittance-inflows-exceed-3b-for-two-consecutive-months-before-election</link><description>Remittance inflows have crossed $3 billion for a second consecutive month with the parliamentary election looming, with expatriates sending $3.17 billion in January.
On Sunday, the latest Bangladesh Bank report showed remittance receipts in January were up 45.1 percent from a year earlier.
In Jan</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 13:53:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Boeing aircraft deal soon: Foreign adviser</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/boeing-aircraft-deal-soon-foreign-adviser</link><description>Bangladesh government is going to sign a deal with US aviation giant Boeing very soon to procure new aircraft for the state-owned carrier Biman Bangladesh Airlines, the country’s foreign affairs adviser has said, citing an acute shortage of planes that has forced the airline to suspend operat</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 14:08:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Banks to remain closed for 4 days</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/banks-to-remain-closed-for-4-days</link><description>All scheduled banks in Bangladesh will remain closed for four consecutive days from February 11 to 14 due to the national election and the regular weekend.
Bangladesh Bank on Sunday issued a notification announcing a holiday on February 11 and 12 (Wednesday and Thursday) to facilitate the election</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 14:23:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ICC Bangladesh holds workshop on International Trade Financing</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/icc-bangladesh-holds-workshop-on-international-trade-financing</link><description>ICC Bangladesh organized a day-long workshop on International Trade Financing following LDC Graduation at a local hotel in Dhaka on 31 January. 
Bangladesh Association of Banks (BAB) Chairman Abdul Hai Sarker attended as Chief Guest and distributed certificates among the participants at</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 14:54:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India halves Bangladesh grant in 2026–27 budget amid strained ties</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/economy/india-halves-bangladesh-grant-in-2026-27-budget-amid-strained-ties</link><description>India has halved its budget allocation for projects and cooperation with Bangladesh compared with the previous fiscal year amid rising bilateral tensions.
Union Minister for Finance and Corporate Affairs Nirmala Sitharaman presented the budget for the fiscal year 2026–27 in Lok Sabha on Sund</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 15:09:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Over 3,263 doctors join govt. service through 48th special BCS exam</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/over-3263-doctors-join-govt-service-through-48th-special-bcs-exam</link><description>The newly recruited 3,263 doctors and dentists on Sunday joined their new jobs through the 48th Special Bangladesh Civil Service (Health) exam, officials said.
Health ministry officials said 2,984 of the recruits joined as assistant medical surgeons and 279 as assistant dental surgeons following t</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 15:24:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pakistan confirms World Cup participation but to boycott India match</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/pakistan-confirms-world-cup-participation-but-to-boycott-india-match</link><description>Pakistan has announced that although its national team will take part in the ICC Men’s T20 World Cup 2026, it will boycott the high-profile group-stage match against India, a decision expected to stir strong reactions in the cricketing world.
The announcement puts an end to weeks of speculat</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 15:12:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BNP has ambitious plans for the country’s sports: Amir Khasru</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/bnp-has-ambitious-plans-for-the-countrys-sports-amir-khasru</link><description>Amir Khasru Mahmud Chowdhury, a member of the BNP’s standing committee and candidate for the paddy sheaf in Chattogram-11 constituency said BNP has ambitious plans for the country’s sports.
He said this during a discussion titled ‘Future of Sports in Chattogram’ on Sunday.</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 15:27:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Winter to bow out with chill, thunder</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladeshs-winter-set-to-end-with-mild-cold-wave-fog-late-february-storms</link><description>Bangladesh’s short winter is expected to bow out in February, but not before one last nip in the air and a burst of thunder at the month’s end, forecasters say.
The Bangladesh Meteorological Department (BMD) has warned of a mild cold wave over parts of the country in the first half of</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 15:42:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>57,500 tonnes of US wheat arrive at Mongla Port, unloading begins</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/57500-tonnes-of-us-wheat-arrive-at-mongla-port-unloading-begins</link><description>Commercial vessel MV Ultra Bulk, carrying 57,500 tonnes of wheat imported from the United States, anchored at Mongla Port on Sunday.
The ship entered the port in the morning and, following sample testing of the wheat, unloading operations commenced during the afternoon shift.
Earlier, on January</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 15:57:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Horns banned around Secretariat from Tuesday</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/honking-banned-in-and-around-secretariat-from-tuesday-police-warn-of-penalties</link><description>Drivers who honk their horns in and around the Bangladesh Secretariat will face punitive action from Tuesday, Dhaka Metropolitan Police (DMP) has warned, as the heart of government is formally declared a “silent zone”.
In a public notice issued on Sunday and signed by DMP Commissioner</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 16:12:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCT deal: 12 more staff moved after protests</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/nct-deal-12-more-staff-moved-after-protests</link><description>The Chittagong Port Authority (CPA) has transferred 12 more employees who joined the protests against leasing the New Mooring Container Terminal (NCT) to a foreign company.
They were transferred through an order signed by the chief personnel officer of the CPA on Sunday.
With the latest transfers</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 16:27:19 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>