<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 08:25:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Magnitude 7.5 earthquake hits southern Philippines</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/magnitude-75-earthquake-hits-southern-philippines</link><description>An offshore earthquake with a magnitude of 7.5 struck Davao Oriental province in the southern Philippines on Friday morning, prompting the Philippine Institute of Volcanology and Seismology to issue a tsunami warning for coastal areas in Mindanao.
In a report, the institute said that the quake, wh</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 04:53:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pakistan's military says its forces killed 30 militants involved in an attack that killed 11 soldiers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/pakistans-military-says-its-forces-killed-30-militants-involved-in-an-attack-that-killed-11-soldiers</link><description>Pakistan's military said on Friday that its security forces had killed 30 militants involved in the Oct 7 ambush on a Pakistani military convoy near the Afghan border, which killed nine soldiers and two officers.
The militant group Tehreek-e-Taliban Pakistan, which has been fighting to overthrow t</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 05:08:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘If they can’t fix it, let’s fish it’: Hasnat’s protest on dilapidated Cumilla road</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/if-they-cant-fix-it-lets-fish-it-hasnats-protest-on-dilapidated-cumilla-road</link><description>In a unique form of protest, chief organiser of South Region of National Citizen Party (NCP) Hasnat Abdullah released live fish into the pothole-ridden Debidwar–Chandina regional road in Debidwar upazila of Cumilla on Friday morning.
Hasnat staged the symbolic protest in Kachisar area</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 05:23:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Light to moderate rain likely in parts of country</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/light-to-moderate-rain-likely-in-parts-of-country-1982</link><description>The Bangladesh Meteorological Department (BMD) forecast light to moderate rain or thundershowers accompanied by temporary gusty wind at many places across the country over the next 24 hours, beginning at 9:00 am today (Friday).
"Light to moderate rain or thunder showers accompanied by temporary gu</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 05:38:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Messi could skip Venezuela friendly, says Scaloni</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/sports/football/messi-could-skip-venezuela-friendly-says-scaloni</link><description>Argentina manager Lionel Scaloni said Thursday he was still unsure if captain Lionel Messi would play in the Albiceleste's friendly against Venezuela.
Scaloni said that despite being fit, Messi could be rested for Friday's clash at Miami's Hard Rock Stadium to give opportunities to other players.</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 05:53:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Heavy rainfall intensifies dengue outbreak</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/heavy-rainfall-intensifies-dengue-outbreak</link><description>The dengue outbreak has worsened this year compared to previous years. Statistics show that both infections and fatalities in the first nine days of October have already surpassed those of the previous three months.
Analysis of dengue data from January to October 9, 2025, reveals a steady monthly</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 06:23:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Police bar ‘Sarat Utsob’ in Old Dhaka's Gandaria</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/police-bar-sarat-utsob-in-old-dhakas-gandaria</link><description>The Satyen Sen Shilpi Group has been unable to hold its "Sarat Utsob” in Old Dhaka’s Gandaria this year after police blocked the event, citing a lack of approval.
The annual festival, held for the past 19 years, was initially scheduled to take place at Bakultala of Dhaka University&amp;rsq</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 06:38:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh facing fresh crackdown under Anti-Terrorism Act: HRW</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-facing-fresh-crackdown-under-anti-terrorism-act-hrw</link><description>Human Rights Watch (HRW) has raised concerns over the growing use of Bangladesh’s amended counterterrorism law by the interim government led by Chief Advisor Muhammad Yunus, to arrest supporters of the deposed Awami League government.
The US-based human rights organisation says the UN human</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 06:53:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pakistan's military says its forces killed 30 militants involved in an attack that killed 11 soldiers</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/asia/pakistans-military-says-its-forces-killed-30-militants-involved-in-an-attack-that-killed-11-soldiers-1</link><description>Pakistan's military said on Friday that its security forces had killed 30 militants involved in the Oct 7 ambush on a Pakistani military convoy near the Afghan border, which killed nine soldiers and two officers.
The militant group Tehreek-e-Taliban Pakistan, which has been fighting to overthrow t</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 07:23:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Obama won Nobel for ‘doing nothing’: Trump</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/obama-won-nobel-for-doing-nothing-trump</link><description>US President Donald Trump, in his fervid pursuit of the Nobel Peace Prize, has criticised his predecessor Barack Obama's achievements, accusing him of "doing nothing" and "destroying our country".
Speaking to reporters at the White House, Trump touted his achievement in securing peace in Gaza</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 07:38:11 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>