<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 04:25:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>ILO offers to work with BD jointly on export, investment</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/ilo-offers-to-work-with-bd-jointly-on-export-investment</link><description>The International Labour Organisation (ILO) offers joint collaboration with Bangladesh for promoting investment and export.
New Country Director for the International Labour Organisation (ILO) Office in Bangladesh Max Tuñón made the overtures Wednesday as he assumed his responsibilit</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 01:04:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Majority of banks yet to adopt AI in cybersecurity: BIBM</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/majority-of-banks-yet-to-adopt-ai-in-cybersecurity-bibm</link><description>Application of artificial intelligence (AI) in disaster recovery (DR) planning remains almost entirely non-existent in Bangladesh's banking sector, according to a recent survey.
The Bangladesh Institute of Bank Management (BIBM) survey revealed that about 95 per cent of institutions admitted that</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 01:19:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Volatility foreseen in forex market</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/volatility-foreseen-in-forex-market</link><description>After weeks of regulatory-intervention-driven stability, Bangladesh's foreign-exchange market suddenly starts heating up with exchange rate recording over 50-paisa rise in a day, officials and bankers said.
They said the taka-greenback exchange rates had risen on the market for the last couple of</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 01:34:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chevron set to launch Jalalabad Gas Compression Project in ’26</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/chevron-set-to-launch-jalalabad-gas-compression-project-in-26</link><description>US energy-giant Chevron is set to begin work on the Jalalabad Compression Project (JBC) next year to harness additional natural gas.
"Chevron has submitted a budget of its works for the next year, where it included projected costs of the JBC for the first time," Petrobangla Director (Finance) AKM</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 02:19:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NCC meets NCC meets experts on July Charter execution on July Charter execution</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ncc-meets-ncc-meets-experts-on-july-charter-execution-on-july-charter-execution</link><description>The National Consensus Commission (NCC) on Wednesday met experts to review recommendations on the methods and procedures for implementing the July National Charter.
The Commission has continued its talks with the experts because some suggestions-including holding a referendum on the charter rather</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 02:34:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Doing everything possible to ensure peaceful election in February: CA</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/doing-everything-possible-to-ensure-peaceful-election-in-february-ca</link><description>Chief Adviser Professor Muhammad Yunus on Wednesday reiterated his government's commitment towards holding the upcoming national elections in February in a peaceful and joyful atmosphere.
"The National Consensus Commission did an excellent job by bringing major political parties together to sign t</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 03:04:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Airport fire deals major blow to export sectors</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/airport-fire-deals-major-blow-to-export-sectors</link><description>The devastating fire at the cargo village of Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport (HSIA) has inflicted immediate losses of more than US$8.0 million on Bangladesh's textile and readymade garment industry.
Sector leaders fear the blaze, which destroyed imported raw materials and samples, could dis</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 03:19:21 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dispute over Sonali Bank's holdings in Pubali Bank not resolved in 41 years</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/dispute-over-sonali-banks-holdings-in-pubali-bank-not-resolved-in-41-years</link><description>The dispute over the Sonali Bank PLC's holdings in the Pubali Bank could not be resolved in the last 41 years and now the Financial Institutions Division (FID) has sought the Finance Division's intervention to find out an amicable solution, officials said.
In 1959 the National Bank of Pakistan, no</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 03:34:21 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>