<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 09:20:05 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Bus torched on Dhaka-Chattogram highway in N’ganj</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/country/bus-torched-on-dhaka-chattogram-highway-in-nganj</link><description>Miscreants set a bus on fire on Dhaka-Chattogram Highway at Shimrail in Siddhirganj upazila of Narayanganj district early Saturday.
Shahinur Alam, officer-in-charge of Siddhirganj Police Station, said the miscreants set the stationary bus of ‘Naf Paribahan’ on fire around 6 am near the</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 05:30:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Extramarital affair’ led to trader Ashraful’s murder: DB, RAB</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/extramarital-affair-led-to-trader-ashrafuls-murder-db-rab</link><description>‘Extramarital affair’ was behind the murder of trader Ashraful Haque, according to Dhaka Metropolitan Police’s Detective Branch (DB) and the Rapid Action Battalion (RAB).
Law enforcement agencies arrest two suspects on Friday in connection with the murder, said DC (media) of DMP</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 05:45:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump says Cambodia, Thailand going to be fine after calls over conflict</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/trump-says-cambodia-thailand-going-to-be-fine-after-calls-over-conflict</link><description>US President Donald Trump said on Friday he thought Thailand and Cambodia were "going to be fine" after holding phone calls with the leaders of the two nations to help mediate the most recent flare-up in the conflict between them.
Thailand this week suspended a US-brokered ceasefire deal and deman</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 06:00:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Apple intensifies succession planning for CEO Tim Cook, FT reports</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/apple-intensifies-succession-planning-for-ceo-tim-cook-ft-reports</link><description>Apple is stepping up its succession planning efforts as it prepares for Tim Cook to step down as chief executive as soon as next year, the Financial Times reported on Friday.
John Ternus, Apple's senior vice president of hardware engineering, is widely seen as Cook's most likely successor, the FT</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 06:15:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump says he will likely sue the BBC for up to $5 billion</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/trump-says-he-will-likely-sue-the-bbc-for-up-to-5-billion-over-edited-speech</link><description>US President Donald Trump said on Friday he would likely sue the BBC next week for as much as $5 billion after the British broadcaster admitted it wrongly edited a video of a speech he gave but insisted there was no legal basis for his claim.
The British Broadcasting Corporation has been plunged i</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 06:30:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pakistan's army chief gets more powers and lifelong immunity</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/pakistans-army-chief-gets-more-powers-and-lifelong-immunity</link><description>Pakistan's parliament has voted to give army chief Field Marshal Asim Munir new powers and lifetime immunity from arrest and prosecution, a move that critics say paves the way towards autocracy.
The 27th constitutional amendment, which was signed into law on Thursday, will also make significant ch</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 07:10:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EU backs Bangladesh's democratic transition efforts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/eu-backs-bangladeshs-democratic-transition-efforts</link><description>The European Union (EU) has expressed support for Bangladesh's ongoing transition under the interim government, reaffirming its confidence in the country's leadership and encouraging political parties to participate constructively in the electoral process, reports BSS.
In a Facebook post, the EU s</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 07:25:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EC to hold talks with 12 parties, including Jamaat, on Monday ahead of general election</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/politics/ec-to-hold-talks-with-12-parties-including-jamaat-on-monday-ahead-of-general-election</link><description>The Election Commission is going to hold talks with 12 political parties, including the Jamaat-e-Islami, on Monday for its third day of dialogue with political stakeholders ahead of the parliamentary elections.
On Saturday, EC’s Public Relations Assistant Director, Md Ashadul Haque said the</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 07:40:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The lost magic of watching TV shows together</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/entertainment/the-lost-magic-of-watching-tv-shows-together</link><description>Television first arrived in Bangladesh in the 1960s; it was a wonder to the Bangalees. In those early days, owning a television was a privilege. 
My grandparents have told us that when someone in the neighbourhood had a TV set, people from nearby houses would gather to watch whatever was being bro</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 08:22:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>RAB CO tells how Jarez orchestrated trader Ashraful’s murder</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/crime/rab-co-tells-how-jarez-orchestrated-trader-ashrafuls-murder</link><description>Rangpur trader Ashraful Haque was allegedly lured to his death by his friend Jarez, who then killed and dismembered him in a planned manner, said Lt Col Fayezul Arefin, commanding officer of RAB-3.
"The brutal killing was the result of a calculated plot carried out under the guise of friendship,"</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 08:37:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bangladesh introduces new police uniform in phased distribution</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/bangladesh-introduces-new-police-uniform-in-phased-distribution</link><description>Bangladesh Police have begun distributing new uniforms, initially to a limited number of personnel, according to bdnews24.com.
Dhaka Metropolitan Police spokesperson Talebur Rahman said the uniform rollout began on Saturday and will be distributed to all members in phases.
Metropolitan police m</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 08:52:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The city we're forgetting: Dhaka's vanishing heritage</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/lifestyle/culture/the-city-were-forgetting-dhakas-vanishing-heritage</link><description>Dhaka is changing faster than it can remember itself. The city's skyline now tells two very different stories. One is written in the fading terracotta of old buildings and the shade of age-old trees. The other is spelt out in the reflective glass of new towers that define its growing ambition. 
Th</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 09:07:32 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>