<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>English News</title><link>https://politepol.com/fd/BNnVF6SFDNH6.xml</link><description>Filtered English News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 08:48:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>US government shutdown starts</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/world/america/us-government-shutdown-starts</link><description>Plunged into a government shutdown, the US is confronting a fresh cycle of uncertainty after President Donald Trump and Congress failed to strike an agreement to keep government programmes and services running by Wednesday’s deadline.
Roughly 750,000 federal workers are expected to be furlou</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 05:41:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Normalcy returns to Khagrachhari as blockade withdrawn after 4 days</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/normalcy-returns-to-khagrachhari-as-blockade-withdrawn-after-4-days</link><description>Life in Khagrachhari began returning to normal on Wednesday after a four-day disruption, following the suspension of a road blockade until October 5.
Although long-distance transport services have not fully resumed, a few vehicles left the district on Wednesday morning. Passenger numbers increased</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 05:56:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cautionary Signal No 3 issued for maritime ports</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/cautionary-signal-no-3-issued-for-maritime-ports</link><description>The Bangladesh Meteorological Department (BMD) has issued local cautionary Signal No. 3 for all maritime ports.
"Maritime ports of Chattogram, Cox's Bazar, Mongla and Payra have been advised to hoist local cautionary Signal No. 3 (R3)," said a special bulletin released by the BMD this morning.
Al</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 06:11:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Youth shot dead in Khulna while asleep</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/youth-shot-dead-in-khulna-while-asleep</link><description>A 29-year-old man was shot dead early Wednesday while asleep at his residence in Maheshwar Pasha under Daulatpur Police Station in Khulna city, police said.
The deceased was identified as Tanvir Hasan Shuvo, general manager of an international marketing company. Shuvo was preparing to go abroad, a</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 06:26:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fisherman killed in crocodile attack in Sundarbans</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/fisherman-killed-in-crocodile-attack-in-sundarbans</link><description>A fisherman was killed after being attacked by a crocodile while fishing in the Sundarbans on Tuesday afternoon, and his body was recovered nearly seven hours later.
The deceased was identified as Subrata Mondal, 32, son of Kumud Mondal, from Dhangmari area in Dakop upazila, Khulna, reports UNB.</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 06:56:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Indian court tells doctors to fix their handwriting</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/others/indian-court-tells-doctors-to-fix-their-handwriting</link><description>At a time when most people use keyboards to write, does handwriting really matter?
Yes, say Indian courts, if the writer is a doctor.
Jokes around the notoriously bad handwriting of many doctors that can only be deciphered by pharmacists are common in India, as around the world. But the latest or</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 07:26:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Malaysia targets 300,000 tourists from Bangladesh in 2026</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/trade/malaysia-targets-300000-tourists-from-bangladesh-in-2026</link><description>Malaysia has unveiled an ambitious plan to attract 47 million international visitors, including 300,000 from Bangladesh, next year under its flagship Visit Malaysia 2026 campaign, aiming to boost regional tourism and strengthen global connectivity.
Malaysian Deputy Minister of Tourism, Arts and Cu</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 07:41:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Wherever you are, be a part of history by voting': CEC tells expats</title><link>https://thefinancialexpress.com.bd/national/wherever-you-are-be-a-part-of-history-by-voting-cec-tells-bangladeshi-expats</link><description>For the first time, Bangladeshi expatriates will be able to cast their votes in national elections through a newly introduced digital system, Chief Election Commissioner (CEC) AMM Nasir Uddin has revealed.
In a video message to expatriates broadcast on the Election Commission’s YouTube chann</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 08:11:24 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>